<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Waldheim     02-22 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Waldheim,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Socialist Party Leadership Suggests Waldheim Must Resign</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leadership on Monday strongly suggested President <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> should step down but stopped short of calling for his resignation. Chancellor <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON>, party chief <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinowatz </PERSON> and other party leaders also renewed an indirect offer to support a conservative candidate to be nominated for presidential elections if <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> quits. The resolution adopted by the Socialist leadership meeting said the report of a historians' commission on <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>'s service in the German army during World War II had `` badly shaken the president's moral authority at home and abroad. It also said that a televised speech by <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> on Feb. 15 `` has raised doubts about his ability to integrate'' <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s opposing political camps In that speech, <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> said he would not step down and dismissed as wrong unspecified parts of the report earlier this month by the international panel of historians that probed his wartime past. <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>, 69, has consistently denied any wrongdoing as a first lieutenant serving in the German army in the <LOCATION> Balkans </LOCATION> during the war. The resolution said the Socialists are ready, together with the conservative <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, junior partner in the coalition government, to `` look for a way toward a new beginning in the office of federal president.'' Asked whether this meant that the Socialists would agree to a joint conservative presidential candidate, <PERSON> Sinowatz </PERSON> told reporters `` this certainly includes also the question whether a personnel change is possible.'' Economics Minister <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Graf </PERSON> and other leading officials of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> last week expressed increasing uneasiness in the party about the damage being done to the country if <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> clings to his post. <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON>, elected in 1986, ends his term in 1992. The historians' commission presented no evidence that would clearly back allegations <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> committed atrocities, but it left open the question of whether he was guilty of any crime. It said he was `` in close proximity'' to some Nazi atrocities in the <LOCATION> Balkans </LOCATION>, knew they were going on and made no attempt ot prevent them. It also said <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> concealed his wartime past and tried to make it seem harmless once he could no longer hide it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-SouthernPoll 2ndLd-Writethru a0821 02-22 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Southern Poll, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0821,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Polls Point to Wide Lead for Bush In South</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 4th graf pvs, Jackson and, to CLARIFY that CBS-Times
poll covers Southern and border Super Tuesday states, not all 20</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holds a 2-1 lead over chief rival Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in the 14 Southern and border states that hold primaries on March 8, Super Tuesday, a poll indicated Monday. On the Democratic side, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> were running roughly even in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> survey suggested. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was the nationwide favorite among Democrats, according to another poll, this one by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. According to that survey, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 21 percent; <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 13 percent; Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had 12 percent and former <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> 10 percent. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> were the leaders in the Southern and border Super Tuesday states, garnering 19 percent and 16 percent respectively, the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 13 percent; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> 11 percent and <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> 10 percent, the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-Times </ORGANIZATION> poll indicated. In the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> survey, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> by a 51-26 margin, with former television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was third with 11 percent. Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> trailed with 3 percent and 9 percent were undecided, the poll indicated. In the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll of Super Tuesday states plus <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, findings were similar: 51 percent for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to 20 percent for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. In the nationwide sampling the survey found 42 percent opting for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and 27 percent for <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. The Scripps Howard pollsters contacted 423 likely <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters Feb. 17-19, just after <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>'s Feb. 16 primary. The margin of error on the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> side was 5 percentage points, the news service said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, eight days after a bruising third-place finish in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses behind <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. Among Democrats, the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> survey gave <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 22 percent and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 19 percent _ within the poll's 4 percentage-point margin of error. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was the decisive winner of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, who has pinned his hopes on a strong showing in the South, and <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman who won the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses and placed second in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, each had 14 percent, and 21 percent were undecided, the news service said. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> had 6 percent, the <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> poll indicated, and Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> drew the backing of 5 percent. On the Democratic side, 597 voters were surveyed during the same time period as the Republican polling. The <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> survey involved voters in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, all of which hold primaries or caucuses on March 8. Six other states hold primaries or caucuses that day as well. The <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> survey was done in conjunction with the <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> -RRB- Post-Herald, The Commercial Appeal of <LOCATION> Memphia </LOCATION> and The <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Sentinel. The telephone poll of 2,734 adults nationwide for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and the Times was taken Feb. 17-21 has a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points on the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> side and four points for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> race. The CBS-Times Super Tuesday figures have a margin of error of four percentage points for the Democrats and five points for the Republicans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Grammys-Omissions     02-22 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Grammys-Omissions,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>THE GRAMMY AWARDS: Who Wasn't Nominated</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>No Bon Jovi, No REM _ Grammys Ignore Critics and Charts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight million Americans can be wrong. That's how many people bought <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jovi </PERSON>'s album `` Slippery When Wet,'' which spent 38 weeks in the Top 5 of the album charts and churned out three hit singles. But the boys from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> received a goose egg from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recording </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, which deemed `` Slippery When Wet'' worthy of zero Grammy nominations. And it's not just the platinum-haired, platinum-sellers the academy ignores: Critical favorites can and often do suffer the same fate The Beatles, one of the most popular and prolific musical entities of the century, were often ignored by the academy, winning only four <PERSON> Grammys </PERSON> as a group. The Rolling Stones have never won a Grammy. REM, the acclaimed band from <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, broke nationally with their `` Document'' album and its single, `` The One I Love''; their album also received no nominations. However, the LP cover was nominated for best album package. An assortment of artists, from <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cougar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mellencamp </PERSON> to The Beastie Boys, missed out on musical nominations for the March 2 show at <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>, passed over by a membership which `` once more opted for studio craft over originality and vision,'' wrote <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> music critic <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilburn </PERSON>. `` You know what it is? It's just the way it is. You ca n't fight city hall,'' said rocker <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, who was snubbed for a best new artist nomination on a technicality. `` It does tend to be the same kind of people every year,'' he said. `` A lot of times it's the people who've been on the cover of Time, or the real mainstream people. The artistic people are passed over many times.'' For <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, it was an obscure track he recorded for a B-movie soundtrack that prevented his new artist nomination. A similar controversy arose in 1986 when the academy refused to nominate <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> in the best new artist category because she had recorded duets with <PERSON> Jermaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Teddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pendergrass </PERSON>. She went on to win the best female pop vocal Grammy for `` Saving All My Love for You.'' But <LOCATION> Crosby </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Stills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Nash </PERSON>, who won the award in 1969, had been vocalists and songwriters in the <ORGANIZATION> Byrds </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> and the Hollies. <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON>, who won in 1985, recorded as lead vocalist with a group called Blue Angel before her `` She's So Unusual'' LP. And <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who was nominated in that category in 1986, had been a part of a recording group called Mystic <PERSON> Merlin </PERSON>. Nevertheless, singer <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Watley </PERSON> _ who scored several hits while recording with the band <ORGANIZATION> Shalimar </ORGANIZATION> _ was nominated as a new artist this year. `` I was upset for about five minutes when I found out. Then I thought, ` Well, no big deal. I'll get nominated for a Grammy someday,''' said <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, who wound up nominated this year for best rock vocal with his track, `` Do n't Mean Nothing.'' His competition in that category includes <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cocker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON> and superstar <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>. But even The Boss was a victim of the fickle Grammy selection process. <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s `` Tunnel of Love,'' his first studio album in three years, was passed over for album for the year honors. But `` Paradise by the C,'' an old tune recycled on <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s five-record live set, inexplicably received a best rock instrumental nomination In fact, <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> has received only one Grammy Award, despite such multimillion selling and critically hailed albums as `` Born to Run,'' `` The River'' and `` Born in the <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>.'' As for <PERSON> Mellencamp </PERSON>, his fine `` The Lonesome Jubilee'' received no nominations; <PERSON> Mellencamp </PERSON> received a co-nomination for producer of the year with his studio partner, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Gehman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s office has declined to comment on the nomination process, which is handled by the 5,000-member <ORGANIZATION> NARAS </ORGANIZATION>. The selection of nominees and the winners annually produces complaints from those passed over, although many artists remain philosophical about the whole process. `` Look at all the people who won in the best new artist category in the past _ the <ORGANIZATION> Starland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vocal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION>, A Taste of Honey,'' said <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>. `` That award can be the kiss of death.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Harold'sNewStart     02-22 0943</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Harold's New Start,0976</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Homeless Man Adjusting to New Life in New Mexico</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ANNE BUCKLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTALES, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> works in a junkyard six days a week, tearing apart old cars and rebuilding the engines. The other day is spent working in the fields at a church-run orphanage, where his benefactors have volunteered his service. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, 75, and his wife, <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON>, 68, gave him the job and a chance to leave the lean-to he was living in last month with other homeless men in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. They gave him the old 8-foot-by-30-foot trailer home at the junkyard that he shares with a stray cat he's named <PERSON> Cleo </PERSON>. They have their son <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> drive him to church on Sundays. They pay for his groceries, but they have n't paid him any wages yet. `` Those Gilmans believe in working,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> says, adding that a paycheck will probably come when business picks up. `` A month from now, it'll be planting season,'' he says. `` I think I'll do good. I'm fed, I'm healthy, I'm working.'' Room and board are <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>'s pay for now, <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> will be paid `` when he gets where he can do anything. ... I think we're going in the hole part of the time now.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is a stranger in a strange land, and the circumstances that brought him here on Jan. 16 were just as strange. Before he arrived in this ranching and farming community of about 11,000 people on the flat high plains of eastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> lived in a rotting wood and canvas shack along the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. He did n't have a job and he got his meals when he could. A 2-inch scar across his forehead is testimony to a fight he says started in a soup line in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The Gilmans read of <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' plight in an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> story published in the Portales News-Tribune in January, contacted the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and said if <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> was willing to work they'd provide him with a home and a job By the time <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, 35, was on a westbound Greyhound people had donated new clothes, new luggage and spending money. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is n't completely at ease in his new surroundings. He is n't quite sure how people will react to him. He shunned a suggestion of one restaurant for dinner, saying he'd heard `` rough cowboys'' hung out there. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> likes to talk about his past. He speaks with animation of his days as a wanderer, traveling through the South looking for work. He speaks also of a future when he will own his own ranch. But for now, he goes to work at the junkyard each day and says he enjoys the time he spends in the fields at the orphanage. When the director of the orphanage drives up to the remains of an old corral that <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is sawing into firewood, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> quickly extinguishes his cigarette in his calloused hand, saying putting it out is the respectful thing to do. `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is nice and warm,'' he says. `` I want to stay here and try to make something out of this opportunity. `` I ai n't getting no younger. I want to settle down.'' Since his arrival, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> has received dozens of letters: from women who've read of his good fortune and want to share life with him, from homeless people wishing him well in his new life, from 28 fifth graders in <LOCATION> Corrales </LOCATION>, N.M. The Gilmans also get letters _ mostly commending them for offering <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> the opportunity to work again and to have a roof over his head. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a burly 5-foot-10-inch former carpenter, answers his letters, particularly those from the women. `` I get lonely for a woman,'' he says. Mrs. <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> saves her letters in a notebook that she likes to show visitors. People in the community have been receptive to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, she says, but adds: `` So many people want his place if he does n't work out. If he does n't get started drinking, he'll be all right.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is n't drinking. He ca n't go out to bars at night because the 16-year-old car the Gilmans gave him does n't have an engine yet. But he's learning the skills he'll need to get it in working order. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> says <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> is a good worker but still needs time to adjust to his new job. `` Some things could be better,'' he says. `` I think there's a communication gap, but a bunch of that is probably my fault. He ca n't read my mind. `` A lot of it is the way he's lived,'' <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> says. `` His brain has worked on survival for the last couple of years. He's got to develop it for this now.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> begins each day at 8 a.m. by helping feed the half dozen cows that also live at the junkyard. When warm weather comes he'll help with ranching chores on the approximately 2,000 acres the Gilmans own in several tracts. `` He's not completely satisfied. I can tell,'' <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> says. `` Other days things are good. There's ups and downs.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> says the downs come mostly when he begins missing his longtime girlfriend and her 16-year-old daughter he helped raise. They live in a government housing project in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` I want to help my stepdaughter out, she's pregnant,'' he says. `` I'd like to try and save my money and do something for my own. I'd like to bring them down here. `` I never knew I'd end up like I did,'' he says. `` I hope I do n't end up in a slump like that again. That ai n't no kind of life for a man.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-22 0913</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0948</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British actor <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who staggered to fame as a lovable lush in the movie `` <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>,'' has married aspiring actress <PERSON> Brogan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, a week after his Valentine's Day proposal, his agent said. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 52, and Miss <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, 28, were married Sunday by a justice of the peace at The Little Church of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION>, said agent <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitt </PERSON>. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> met Miss <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> six years ago on the set of the film `` Six Weeks,'' according to publicist <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>. They were re-introduced three years ago at a restaurant and have been together since. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s marriages to actresses <PERSON> Suzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> and Tuesday Weld ended in divorce. It was Miss <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>'s second marriage. Each has a son. `` The two hope to star in a film together in the future and are looking for projects,'' said <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pianist <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> says he stopped playing in public in 1978 because he needed a short rest. <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> broke his long silence with a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> performance during December's summit meeting between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` To be honest, I never thought the ` intermission' would go on for 10 years,'' <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> said in an interview published in Sunday's Dallas Morning News `` I guess it went on so long because I felt relaxed and was having such a good time simply living.'' Since the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> performance, he has had numerous offers but has so far accepted only one _ conductor <PERSON> Zubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON>'s invitation to accompany the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philharmonic </ORGANIZATION> on its first tour of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 15 years <PERSON> Cliburn </PERSON> will appear as soloist with the orchestra in concerts in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> during May and June, 30 years after he won the <ORGANIZATION> Tchaikovsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Competition </ORGANIZATION>. He said he would perform in his home state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> next season.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Deaf actress <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON> is working with a speech pathologist to improve her speaking skills, according to People magazine. Miss <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON>, who won an Oscar for best actress for her portrayal of a deaf-mute in `` Children of a Lesser God,'' will be presenting this year's best actor award. She plans to say, `` The envelope, please,'' rather than use sign language, the magazine says in this week's edition. She also has a speaking role in the planned <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> movie with <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bancroft </PERSON>, `` The Bridge to Silence.'' `` She needed a lot of work,'' said her speech pathologist, Dr. <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Glass </PERSON>. `` Her voice was flat, monotone, and she talked too fast.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Filmmaker <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON> says there are similarities between his first PG-rated movie and his 1972 midnight classic `` Pink Flamingos,'' which is still outraging audiences. `` Hairspray,'' a comedy about an overweight girl who becomes a star on a local television dance show, makes its debut this week. Divine, the 300-pound transvestite star of `` Pink Flamingos'' plays the mother of the heroine of `` Hairspray.'' `` I knew this was one of the few obsessions I ever had that would be palatable to -LRB- general -RRB- movie executives,'' the 41-year-old Waters said of `` Hairspray'' in an interview published Sunday in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` The sensibility and sense of humor in ` Hairspray' is the same of ` Pink Flamingos.' The difference is that I do n't have the rage at 41. I'd be a jerk.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In her `` Saturday Night Live'' heyday, <PERSON> Gilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Radner </PERSON> poked fun at people and just about everything else, but when she learned 17 months ago that she had cancer she found life was not as funny. `` Cancer is about the most unfunny thing in the world,'' <PERSON> Radner </PERSON> said in an interview in March's Life magazine. `` But it does n't have to mean you die. Although <PERSON> Radner </PERSON> had lost much weight and hair during her chemotherapy, she has a new attitude today. `` Radner needs little provocation to yank up her sweater and show off her newly ` fat' stomach, and after eight months of baldness, her unruly brown hair -LRB- with a bit of gray at the temples -RRB- has grown back in a thick thatch,'' according to the magazine. She has also stopped smoking and eats more wholesome food. Twenty years ago, the average life expectancy of a patient with ovarian cancer was between six and seven months. It is still the most lethal of pelvic cancers, with less than a 30 percent recovery rate. Although <PERSON> Radner </PERSON>, 41, will not be considered well unless her remission continues for at least 1 -LCB- years, she said `` I think I've never been as healthy and as well as I am now. She credits her turnaround to her excruciating medical treatment, which included surgery, nine months of chemotherapy injections and 30 radiation sessions. Her 52-year-old husband, actor <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, said: `` Each time <PERSON> Gilda </PERSON> had to go through one more treatment, and she'd be vomiting and writhing in pain, I'd ask myself, ` How much can a human being take?''' Had Wilder not been around, <PERSON> Radner </PERSON> is certain she could not have taken so much, the magazine said. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> has not worked since she was diagnosed. <PERSON> Radner </PERSON> also credits meetings she's attending with the `` Wellness Community,'' a cancer self-help group. And she's working three hours a day on a book about cancer. `` That's what one of my favorite visualizations is about,'' she said. `` Every day ... I imagine myself sitting in Doubleday's, with people lined up to have me sign my book. I'm well. And I'm adorable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SwaggartProfile     02-22 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Swaggart Profile,0604</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swaggart Didn't Spare The Fire And Brimstone For Bakker, Gorman</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Swaggart, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN McGILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> did n't spare the fire-and-brimstone when fellow TV evangelists <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON> fell from power last year. He criticized them for their style as well as their sexual dalliances. `` God deliver us from these pompadour boys, hair done, nails done, fresh from the beauty shop, preaching the gospel,'' he thundered in March at a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> crusade. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>, who temporarily stepped down from his own ministry Sunday amid allegations of sexual misconduct, has a less polished, more explosive fundamentalist style. It sprang, perhaps, from his upbringing in <LOCATION> Ferriday </LOCATION>, a backwater town in northern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s Bible belt It was there, he has said, when he first heard the call of God _ a voice that gave him goose bumps and made his hair tingle. He was 8 years old. `` Everything seemed different after that day in front of the Arcade Theater,'' he said in a 1985 interview. `` I felt better inside. Almost like taking a bath.'' He grew up poor and learned to play the piano and sing along with two cousins who took different paths _ rock singer <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and country singer <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilley </PERSON>. Part-time preaching and part-time work in oil fields provided his living until he was 23, when he gave up the oil work. He preached, played piano and sang gospel songs with all the barrelhouse fervor of his cousin <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> at Assemblies of God revivals and camp meetings for 16 years before starting a radio show that launched his broadcast evangelism career. He was always outspoken. In literature issued by his ministry he calls Roman Catholicism `` a false religion. It is not the Christian way. Whosoever follows its errant doctrines will be deceived and end up eternally lost.'' Of Jews, he wrote that `` because of their rejection of Christ ... they have known sorrow and heartache like have no other people on the face of the Earth.'' `` If you do n't like what I say, talk to my boss!'' he shouted once as he strode in front of his congregation at his Family Worship Center, where his sermons often move listeners to stand up as though possessed by the Holy Spirit and start speaking in tongues. Offensive to some, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON>'s messages still moved many. Contributors built <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> Ministries into a growth industry that made an estimated $ 142 million in 1986. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> said in 1985 that his complex in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> _ including a worship center, <PERSON> Bible </PERSON> college and state-of-the-art broadcasting and recording facilities _ was worth up to $ 75 million. <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> has said the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> scandals of last year hurt fund-raising because the public painted all evangelists with a broad brush. As the scandal broke, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> assured his followers that he would n't fall into the same trap as <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> minister. In his <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> worship center in March he told his flock that if he were ever unfaithful to his wife, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON>, she would `` kill me before God could even get to me.'' On Sunday, <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> never specifially responded to reports that he, too, had been accused of sexual misconduct, specifically consorting with a prostitute. But, as his tearful followers looked on, he turned to his wife and said, `` God never gave a man a better helpmate, a companion to stand beside him. I have sinned against you and I beg your forgiveness.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Assemblies-Glance     02-22 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assemblies-Glance,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Assemblies of God At-A-Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Swaggart, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Some facts and figures on the Assemblies of God church: _ Founded in 1914 during a convention in <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, the Assemblies of God moved its headquarters to <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> in 1918. It employs more than 1,300 people in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>: at the headquarters, its seminary, three colleges and a retirement center. _ The Assemblies of God is pentecostal, a branch of Christianity emphasizing personal experience of God, manifested in `` gifts of the spirit'' such as speaking in tongues and healing. _ It is the largest pentecostal demonination if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, claiming nearly 2.5 million adherents, plus 14 million overseas _ 9 million of them in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. _ There are nearly 11,000 Assemblies of God churches in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and more than 30,000 ministers _ about 3,700 of them women, according to a 1987 survey. _ The church is composed of 57 districts, primarily broken down by geographic boundaries. _ Ordained ministers and church delegates form the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a body which meets biennially to conduct church business, formulate procedures and policies, and elect top executive officers to the 13-member Executive Presbytery. The general superintendent, who is the top executive officer, is elected to a four-year term; all others are elected to two-year terms. _ Ministers can be disciplined not only for moral indescretion but also for straying from church doctrines, inefficency, being contentious or non-cooperative, or trying to assume dictatorial power over a congregation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Byways-TempleTown     02-22 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Byways-Temple Town,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>WORLD BYWAYS: Temple Town _ An Indian Oasis of Tranquility</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra
   EDITOR'S NOTE _ This is one of a series of occasional reports by
Associated Press correspondents on life and customs in the byways
of the world.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SEEMA SIROHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PUSHKAR, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This town of cobblestone streets and sparkling white houses is a long way from anywhere in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, but millions cross a desert every year to get to it and wash away their sins in its holy lake. <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON> is a place revered by Hindus and even by some foreigners who seek out its tranquility. Its beginnings lie with <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON>, the creator of the universe in Hindu mythology. Hindu texts have it that when <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON> was seeking a place for a holy ceremony, he chose <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON>. He dropped a lotus from his hand and water spouted from the desert to form a lake, according to the texts that date from the 8th century B.C. In these modern times, as the sun rises, <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> pilgrims chant mantras and take a dip in <LOCATION> Pushkar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, believing all their sins will be washed away by the holy waters. Europeans and Americans often are seen by the lake, sharing the religious experience. They feed grain to pigeons and sweets to long-tailed monkeys who scramble across the pinnacles of the town's 400 temples where ascetics, Hindu monks and other holy men gather <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON>, a town of 9,000 people, is an oasis of tranquility, far removed from the bustling cities and teeming slums of <LOCATION> Bombay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>. The blazing sun soaks into everything. It was the sacred month of <PERSON> Kartik </PERSON>, signifying the onset of winter, when <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON> is said to have dropped his lotus blossom. <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON>, foremost in the Hindu trinity of supreme gods, had been looking for a suitable site to perform a major religious ceremony. But his wife, <PERSON> Savitri </PERSON>, could not attend the ritual. Angered, she decreed that henceforth <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON> would be worshiped at only one place. <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON> became the sole earthly home of the peaceful god of creation, while millions of shrines were erected across <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to Lord Shiva the destroyer and to ferocious goddesses like <PERSON> Kali </PERSON> and <PERSON> Durga </PERSON> who are often depicted as fire-spitting images carrying heads of evil men they had slain in battle. But this oasis in the desert emerged as a major holy town for the Hindus, almost equal in importance to <ORGANIZATION> Benaras </ORGANIZATION>, the `` eternal city.'' Hindus believe that one goes to heaven if one dies in <LOCATION> Benaras </LOCATION>. Pilgrims come by the thousands to <LOCATION> Pushkar </LOCATION>, 250 miles southwest of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, to bathe in the lake and revive the memory of <PERSON> Brahma </PERSON>'s majestic rite every year on <PERSON> Kartik </PERSON> <PERSON> Poornima </PERSON>, the full moon night in the month of November. Shielded by <PERSON> Nag </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahar </PERSON>, or <ORGANIZATION> Serpent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountain </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON> has <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s _ and perhaps the world's _ only temple to <LOCATION> Brahma </LOCATION> The town centers on the lake, where there are several steps for bathing. Signs warn foreigners `` not to wear shorts and other revealing clothes, not to smoke, drink near the lake or take photographs, not to kiss, embrace or indulge in other irreverent acts.'' The steps, called ghats, are controlled by vigilant and aggressive brahmin priests, who preside over religious ceremonies, armed with horoscopes. They watch every pilgrim approaching the lake and pounce on potential clients. Each visit is recorded in their bulky, cloth-covered books. A priest can easily tell a devotee when his grandfather visited <PERSON> Pushkar </PERSON> by referring to the dog-eared notebooks. Displeasing a priest can be unpleasant. He will pronounce curses on one's entire family, naming all _ the grandfather, father and sons. From the lake, the steps lead up to the main street, a favorite shopping center with the tourists. The shops are stacked with exotic handicrafts, peasant skirts and other clothes native to this part of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Velvet shirts and pajamas, musts for low-budget travelers, hang in vibrant displays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cyprus-Vassiliou     02-22 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cyprus-Vassiliou,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Newcomer Is Fourth Cyprus President Since Independence</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Cyprus-Election</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON>, elected as <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>' fourth president since independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> 28 years ago, had never belonged to a political party or been involved in political activity until he decided to run for office The 56-year-old millionaire businessmen ran as an independent backed by the Moscow-oriented <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> AKEL </ORGANIZATION>, which controls about one-third of the votes among the 363,000 voters on the <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cypriot </ORGANIZATION> side of the divided <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island. On Sunday, he defeated a veteran conservative politician to become the nation's leader. Until his campaign, <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON> concentrated on his research and marketing company, worth about $ 5 million. It is the largest in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The campaign was a first for the communists as well. Until this poll, the party had always supported centrist candidates, never fielding its own man. But the millionaire's endorsement by the communists was not as contradictory as it sounds. His parents, <PERSON> Vassos </PERSON>, an eye doctor, and <PERSON> Phofo </PERSON>, a dentist, were founding members of the party in 1941. His father took the family to <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> in 1945 to fight on the communist side in the civil war. The pro-European <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON> has stressed his political independence from the communists, particularly on foreign policy, and is expected to adhere to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>' non-aligned status. The election of the urbane <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON>, an economist who speaks seven languages, breaks the Greek Cypriot nationalists' grip on power since independence. The island's first president, Archbishop <PERSON> Makarios </PERSON>, hero of the independence struggle in the 1950s, was elected for three five-year terms with huge majorities. His successor, <PERSON> Spyros </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyprianou </PERSON>, was considered his political heir and served for two terms _ but only with <ORGANIZATION> AKEL </ORGANIZATION> support, which was withdrawn in 1985. <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON>'s election breaks the mold. He has said his first priority is to break the deadlock between <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> and Turkish Cypriots and seek to reunite the island. It has been divided since the Turkish army invaded in 1974, after a short-lived coup by militant supporters of union with <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> that installed <PERSON> Nicos </PERSON> <PERSON> Sampson </PERSON> as president for eight days. All efforts to find a political settlement have foundered. But <PERSON> Vassiliou </PERSON> has said he will form a national unity government and is willing to reopen negotiations without preconditions. <PERSON> Vassilou </PERSON>, who was born in <LOCATION> Famagusta </LOCATION>, now part of the breakaway Turkish Cypriot republic in the northern third of the island, was educated in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. He is married with three children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Warhol Bjt   02-22 0999</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Warhol, Bjt,1023</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Year After His Death, Warhol's Legacy Mirrors his Life</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop artist <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>, who gained fame by calling fame fleeting, has proved otherwise by his death. A year after his fatal heart attack in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> hospital, <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s legacy is a mirror of his life: a melange of high art, low kitsch, dramatic tension and, as much as ever, the gaze of a fascinated public. `` It's going to take a while still for his legacy to be sorted out,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourdon </PERSON>, an art critic and <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> biographer. `` But if anybody thought he was going to be a flash in the pan, they are quite mistaken.'' Artistically, scrutiny of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s work has risen to a level it probably never attained in his life. Major film and painting retrospectives are in the works, as are several biographies and the publication of his private journal. Socially, the cultish lifestyle in which <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> enveloped himself will be unwrapped this spring at a huge auction of the artist's possessions, from Old Master paintings to a Superman touch-tone phone. Commercially, the managers of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s estate have signed a licensing agreement that principals say could create a billion-dollar business in retail goods, from calendars to towels, bearing <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> images. And legally, in its least expected ramification, <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s death continues to reverberate in the medical world. The state has accused <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> of rendering him deficient care, and his estate has sued over his death. `` What would he think of all this? As far as the brouhaha is concerned, it's consistent with the way he lived _ action, tension, all those kinds of things,'' said <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, lawyer for the estate. `` But in terms of his death? He'd probably just think his death was stupid.'' <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>, 58, died in his hospital bed early Feb. 22, 1987, the day after a surgeon removed his gall bladder. Pathologically fearful of hospitals and distrustful of doctors, he had put off the surgery for years. His death remains an enigma. The city coroner was unable to say what caused <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s heart to stop, and the state <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, while citing deficient care, did not say the problems _ such as inadequate supervision of nurses and incomplete record-keeping _ harmed him. `` There are cases when cardiac arrest is unexplained. This will probably be one of those cases,'' said <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the hospital, which maintains that <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> was well cared for. In some ways, the inconclusiveness of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s death is fitting. His life was equally enigmatic, a mix of nightclubbing and reticence, public persona and intense privacy, counterculture innovation and determined marketing. The everyday object was his icon, the provocative phrase his byword. `` In the future,'' said <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s famous assertion in a 1968 exhibition catalog, `` everyone will be world-famous for 15 minutes.'' `` He was an incredible character,'' said <PERSON> Bourdon </PERSON>. `` There are just so many conflicting stories and irreconcilable anecdotes; I do n't think it can ever be sorted out. I think he's just going to evaporate into legend. He wanted it that way. Facts were always a little unglamorous to him.'' But in the absence of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s own brand of glamor _ his ethereal, black-draped, white-wigged presence _ what remains is the reality of his art. `` You take a look at the work and the personality becomes less of an issue,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON>, curator of the <ORGANIZATION> Whitney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>. `` The social presence that he projected is no longer part of the evaluation, and one can look at the work more clearly.'' That appraisal is going on intensively, as often happens after the death of an artist. The Whitney plans a spring retrospective of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> films. The Museum of Modern Art is preparing for a major show of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> art next year; it will tour worldwide. At least four books on his life are due out soon. `` He tried to cultivate a two-dimensional persona. Now, when one begins to see the depth of who he was, it becomes more intriguing,'' said <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON>. `` He is far more significant than he allowed his public to believe.'' There are some signs already of the increased value of <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s work At auction in October, a <LOCATION> Warhol </LOCATION> painting that was expected to sell for $ 70,000 went for $ 220,000; another with an estimate of $ 50,000 sold for $ 176,000. Those sums pale in comparison to the potential value of an agreement between <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s estate and <ORGANIZATION> Schlaifer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the marketing firm behind the Cabbage Patch Kids dolls. <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>, who often blurred the line between fine and commercial art, had started the discussions with <PERSON> Schlaifer </PERSON> two years ago. The company may put his name and images on bedding, cosmetics, paper goods, jewelry _ a huge range of retail items whose sales it has said could reach the billion-dollar level. <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> may have approved; `` Being good in business,'' he wrote in 1975, `` is the most fascinating kind of art.'' But for all the marketing schemes and planned art shows, <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s legacy may make its brashest statement in April and May, when <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s auction house sells the entire, eclectic assortment of artworks and knickknacks that cluttered his <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> townhouse. Proceeds will fund a foundation for the visual arts. The sale is classic Warhol: The six-volume catalog, selling for $ 95, is <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s costliest ever, and the first to be sold in advance in bookstores nationwide. The pieces include 134 pottery cookie jars, a Rolls <PERSON> Royce </PERSON>, a few important modern art works. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s forecasts a $ 10 million to $ 15 million sale; other estimates are more than twice that. The crowd of bidders is sure to glitter. The artist, his friends say, would have loved the fuss _ but in his own, unrevealing way. `` There's been a much heightened interest, naturally,'' said <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, his longtime manager and now executor of his estate. `` <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> was a hard guy to figure out his reaction. But I think he would have taken it in his stride.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Brazil-Rainstorms 2ndLd-Writethru a0824 02-22 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brazil-Rainstorms, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0824,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Driving Rains Hamper Brazilian Rescue Efforts</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to UPDATE with death toll raised to 74,
bodies recovered at collapsed nursing home. SUBS 2 grafs for grafs
7-8 pvs: `Civil defense ...' with details</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LISA GENASCI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rescue workers recovered eight victims and rescued 13 people late Sunday beneath a massive mudslide in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>, which has been hit by three days of pounding rains. At least 74 people died and 11,000 were left homeless by the violent storms since Friday, which turned streets into raging torrents, threw cars like toys and carried ramshackle homes roaring down hillsides, civil defense officials said early Monday. Authorities estimated 50,000 people eventually may have to be relocated. Throughout the city, army trucks and volunteers helped transport slum dwellers from precarious hillside homes to temporary shelters in schools, churches and public buildings. In some cases, people refused to leave their partially destroyed homes, preferring to ris being crushed beneath their homes than leave their worldly possession Health officials promised mass vaccinations against tetanus and typhoid and warned residents against an outbreak of leprosy, which followed a similar spate of rainstorms earlier this month. `` From above, one has the impression a giant stepped through the city, smashing homes and hillsides,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Saturnino </PERSON> <PERSON> Braga </PERSON>, who called the three-day onslaught the city's worst disaster. Civil defense officials estimated Saturday that as many as 150 people were killed in the rains that began late Friday, but the figure on Sunday lowered to 48 and later raised back to 74. Twenty more people were believed missing beneath mud and debris, including at least eight more people at the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Genoveva </LOCATION> hospital. Rescuers recovered the eight bodies and 13 people alive from the nursing home in the upscale hillside neighborhood of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teresa </LOCATION>, where a three-story wing of the hospital was crushed by a mudslide Saturday. `` It's hard to have an accurate view of the number of dead,'' said civil defense spokesman <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>. `` We have no idea how many people have been burried by their shanty town homes nor do we know exactly how many were in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Genoveva </LOCATION> hospital at the time it was stuck, though we imagine some 30 of the 350 patients died.'' Torrents raged down streets throughout the city, prompting some people to tie their cars to posts to prevent them from being swept away. Civil defense workers used amphibious vehicle and surfboards to pluck people from partially submerged cars. Rivers and drainage canals overflowed, pushing dozens of shanty homes from their precarious hillside perches. Much of the damage was inflicted on the slums that hold about 2 million of the city's 7 million residents, but wealthy areas also suffered heavy damage. In the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Teresa </LOCATION> district, an eight-floor apartment building was evacuated and threatened to topple, engineers said. Evacuations were ordered after flooding hit the wealthy <LOCATION> Gavea </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lagoa </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jardim </PERSON> <PERSON> Botanico </PERSON> districts. Vice Mayor <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rezende </PERSON> said he has asked the federal government for $ 4 million to clean up city streets, relocate slum dwellers and repair embankments and streets washed away by the waters. `` I ca n't even imagine what will happen to this city if the rains continue,'' <PERSON> Rezende </PERSON> told the Jornal do Brasil radio. `` The situation is desperate. We estimate 50,000 people will have to be given new housing in safer areas.'' Public schools were used as shelter for the estimated 10,000 homeless, <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> said. Supermarkets were asked to donate food and doctors were asked to report for duty. Globo, the country's biggest private television network, carried news flashes every 15 minutes to solicit donations of time, food and medication. Meteorologists said the downpour was caused by an <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> cold front that likely was to continue through Monday. Health Secretary <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Noronha </PERSON> told <PERSON> Rio </PERSON> residents to boil their drinking water and said the government would carry out vaccinations against typhoid and tetanus. He said 69 people had been hospitalized since the beginning of the month with leprosy, a disease carried by rats and contaminated water. Five have died of the disease, <PERSON> Noronha </PERSON> said on Jornal do Brasil radio. Earlier this month, 207 people died in flooding and mudslides around the state and 13,000 were left homless. The worst-hit area was <LOCATION> Petropolis </LOCATION>, a mountain resort town 40 miles north of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-ShipRescue     02-22 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Ship Rescue,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Korean Ship Sinks, 12 Saved, 3 Missing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Australian navy ship rescued 12 crewmen from a South Korean trawler that sank off <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, but gave up the search today for three missing crew members. The trawler, the Dong Chang No. 3, sank Sunday about 60 miles north of <LOCATION> Wellington </LOCATION> near the Western entrance of <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Australian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> training and support ship, rescued the 12 crewmen from a life raft, then searched for 17 hours in heavy seas for three crewmen who disappeared without life jackets. Maj. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fry </PERSON>, spokesman for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the missing crewmen's chances for survival `` were assessed as nil after 17 hours in the water.'' There was no immediate word on what caused the trawler to sink.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CommuterPlaneCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0841</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Commuter Plane Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0841,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Workers Search Pond For Clues in Fatal Commuter Plane Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to UPDATE with comment from NTSB
official, saying debris shows that plane hit water first, and that
officials believe first officer, not the plane's captain, may have
been flying the plane. Picks up 4th graf pvs, `About 25...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MEG REYNOLDS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORRISVILLE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investigators in motorboats raked the bottom of a shallow pond at <LOCATION> Raleigh-Durham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Sunday, pulling up debris that may be a clue to a commuter plane crash that killed 12 people. No one survived Friday night's crash of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> Flight 3378, which went down shortly after takeoff en route to <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Because of debris found in the water, investigators believe the twin-engine turboprop hit the pond before plunging into a wooded area and exploding, officials said Sunday evening Earlier, they had said the plane had barely skimmed the pond, a flood reservoir, before crashing. Parts of the plane, including a portion of the hydraulic system, were found within 40 feet of the bank, said <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON>. He also said that investigators believe the 28-year-old first officer, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Digan </PERSON>, was flying the plane when it crashed Friday, because the captain, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, was talking to the control tower when the plane took off. `` The person that does the flying does n't usually do the radio,'' <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Digan </PERSON>, who was hired by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> last May, had 2,150 total flying hours and 450 in the Metro-III, the craft type involved in the crash. `` She was qualified,'' <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said. `` There is no doubt about that.'' Weather at the time of the accident, although poor, was not so severe as to endanger the flight. Visibility on the runway was between 2,400 and 3,000 feet when the crash occurred. The flight could have taken off down to 1,600 feet, <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said. Earlier, <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON>, said officials hoped that the search of the reservoir would show `` how -LRB- the plane -RRB- broke up. It helps determine the sequence of events.'' About 25 investigators, including some from the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>, sifted through the roped-off wreckage site on the pond's bank, peering at small bits of debris and examining larger plane parts for signs of malfunction. Beyond them, men in lifejackets piloted two motorboats around the surface of the pond, using poles and hooks to retrieve small pieces of crash debris. The pond measured about 4 feet deep and 75 yards wide, officials said. The debris will be used to determine the state and angle of the plane when it struck the bank, since the aircraft carried no flight data or cockpit voice recorders, <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> said. Neither is currently required by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> on commuter aircraft, although they will be as of March 1989, he said. `` If it was flying upside-down, that tells you something,'' he said. Some trees were broken and others were skinned as much as 200 yards beyond the water when the aircraft hit the wooded bank. The wreckage, including the entire silver tail, was strewn over an area measuring about 50 feet by 150 feet, <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON> said. Rubble and bits of shiny metal still littered the tall grass. The largest plane piece, a red -, white - and blue-striped shard from the fuselage measuring about 15 feet, lay amid several broken pine tree Wheels from the landing gear had broken off their axle, while about 30 yards away, a piece of the aircraft's emergency door lay twisted in the mud The remains of the 10 passengers and two crew members were removed Saturday night from the crash site and taken to the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> medical examiner's laboratory in <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Damiano </PERSON>, an airport spokeswoman. Officials were using fingerprints to help identify the victims, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF-ShipCollision     02-22 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Ship Collision,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese, Soviet Cargo Vessels Collide, One Reported Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Japanese cargo ship capsized today after colliding with a Soviet freighter in <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. All five crewmen on the cargo ship were rescued and no one aboard the Soviet vessel was injured, a maritime official said. Two tug boats sent from <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION> rescued the five crew members from the 499-ton Ryusei-maru after it collided with the 10,152-ton Alisher-Navoi, said <PERSON> Mariko </PERSON> <PERSON> Sugai </PERSON>, spokeswoman of the local <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. There were no reports of injuries among the 32 crew members aboard the Alisher-Navoi, she said. Two Japanese crewmen, including skipper <PERSON> Takemitsu </PERSON> <PERSON> Masu </PERSON>, were taken to a hospital in <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION> for treatment of unspecified injuries. At the time of the accident, the Soviet vessel was making a turn in order to leave for <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> after unloading pig iron at an <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION> pier, while the Ryusei-maru, carrying a load of limestone, was heading toward the pier.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-America-InLights     02-22 0534</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-America-In Lights,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lights Of Western Maryland Community Form Outline Of United States</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEB RIECHMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LaVALE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For more than 20 years, the lights of this western <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> community have shimmered with national pride. As the lights of <PERSON> LaVale </PERSON> flicker at dusk, a near-perfect outline of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> begins to shine brightly from this residential community nestled in the foothills of the <ORGANIZATION> Alleghenies </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's an unusual happenstance. No one tried to make it,'' said <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON>, who has lived for 25 years atop <LOCATION> Haystack </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> where the map is best viewed on a cold, clear winter night. `` I'm not sure who discovered it My wife mentioned it to me. She could n't believe it.'' A shopping center forms the U.S.-Canadian border. A well-lighted thoroughfare around <PERSON> LaVale </PERSON> is the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> is about a mile of motels, fast food restaurants and stores along <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 40. `` It's beginning to get a litle busy and distorted because of all the development in the LaVale area,'' said <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, who also lives in the 124-home Sunset View development on the mountain. `` As you come down the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is starting to get a little out of proportion.'' `` Back five, 10 years ago, it was probably a little better,'' she said. `` We're not knocking the development, but we're losing our <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> is formed where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 48 disappears behind a mountain ridge. The southern edge of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> is a bowling alley. A disfigured <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> appears where <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 40 vanishes around <LOCATION> Haystack </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION>. And the Gulf Coast is a grouping of homes and other establishments. `` It's the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Sunset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> View </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON>, a planner with the <ORGANIZATION> Allegany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. `` I guess just about everyone has heard of it. I do n't know if everyone believes it.'' The residential community of more than 7,200 has experienced a rush of commercial and residential development, especially since the 1960s, <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> said. `` We were worried about the mall when it opened up -LRB- in 1981 -RRB-, but it's actually a big <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruddell </PERSON>, a businessman who lives in the area. `` There's no <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. We have to do some more development.'' <PERSON> Ruddell </PERSON>, past chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Sunset </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> View </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the map is best seen in the winter when leaves have fallen from trees on Haystack Mountain. About nine months ago, members of the association thought about topping some trees to provide a better view, but scrapped the idea in favor of more pressing needs, he said. Some residents expressed concern that publicity would attract sightseers to Sunset View and create traffic, but others said most local residents either have already seen it, or have no interest in getting a glimpse of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in lights. `` Sometimes at night people stop out in front and you wonder what they're doing,'' <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> said. `` But then you know what they're doing They're looking at the map.'' `` I remember one time _ it's been years ago _ one of my neighbors called and said, ` There's someone down in your garden with a tripod surveying,''' <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> said. `` They were n't surveying. They were down there taking pictures of the map.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HotlineCrisis     02-22 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hotline Crisis,0577</SECOND>
<HEAD>Half Of Crisis Hotline Staff Walks Out in Dispute</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After 30 years of handling people in crisis, the <ORGANIZATION> Suicide </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> has a crisis of its own. Half the telephone hotline workers have walked out in a dispute over layoffs and control of the center. The workers went out on Jan. 1 and it has been a sometimes noisy dispute, with striking counselors picketing the center's offices and chanting `` down with the board'' during a recent closed-door meeting of directors. Despite the walkout, the crisis line handled more calls in January than it did the same month a year earlier, Executive Director <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Halfon </PERSON> said. In fact, the strike has prompted people to come forward to ask if the center needed their help. `` We were deluged with calls from people who read about it and -LRB- asked -RRB- how could they volunteer,'' <PERSON> Halfon </PERSON> said. In addition to the crisis line, the center operates a substance abuse clinic, a halfway house, an AIDS research project, an art therapy program and an annual curriculum for schools on substance abuse and suicide. Before the layoffs, the center _ excluding crisis line workers _ had about 90 full - and part-time employees The crisis line was staffed by about 80 volunteers and consultants. The latter are workers who started out as volunteers but have begun to receive part-time, $ 6-an-hour shifts. The crisis line workers walked out when 27 of the non-crisis line staffers were laid off and the hours of 15 others were cut back late last year. The layoff was strictly a `` budgetary concern,'' <PERSON> Halfon </PERSON> asserted, though she admitted, `` the timing was terrible, you know, December.'' The center's budget in 1985-86 was about $ 3 million, including revenue from contracts, grants, clinic fees and donations, she said. But in the last year, some grants have ended and contracts that provided government funding have not been renewed, she said, estimating the current budget at about $ 1.5 million. `` We are concerned with fulfilling that,'' she said. `` The cutbacks in just the layoffs will result in a savings of half a million dollars.'' The strikers, however, are particularly upset that among those laid off was the center's first employee, social worker <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Heilig </PERSON>, who served as a clinical consultant. `` We ca n't function without a clinical person in control,'' <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Meisler </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the strikers, said recently. `` The dismissal of one of the most well known and most experienced persons in the area of suicide prevention does n't make much sense,'' said <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Farberow </PERSON>, a psychologist who co-founded the center in 1958. <PERSON> Heilig </PERSON> did not return a telephone call for comment. In 1984, <PERSON> Farberow </PERSON> and the other founder, Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Litman </PERSON>, turned the center over to a board of directors composed of local business people so that they could focus on research. But the founders, who have remained as clinicians, want to regain control of the center. The board of directors met Feb. 7 to deal with the center's problems <PERSON> Halfon </PERSON> said the directors favored putting a member of the crisis line staff on the board, but she would not reveal what moves the board would take to resolve the overall problem of `` ultimate administrative control'' of the organization. `` That's the part that's in question. What's the best way to preserve the integrity and assets of the organization?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FBIDismissal Bjt   02-22 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI Dismissal, Bjt,0706</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fired FBI Agent Seeks Reinstatement; Changes Lifestyle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL VOGRIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PEORIA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five months after the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> fired him, former agent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> is grappling with a religious renewal that caused him to question his past, challenge his supervisors and lose his job. Wholesale changes are taking place in the life of a man who was 10 months away from settling into a quiet retirement when he was dismissed Sept. 11. After carrying a gun every day during 21 years of loyal <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> service, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> now is a pacifist who denounces the `` immoral activities'' of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' involvement in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, 49, is selling his <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> home, where he and his wife, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON>, raised four children. And he's pondering a total change in lifestyle while searching for a way to support his family the next 12 years until he can collect his federal pension. `` It would be inconsistent for me to continue being a heavy consumer knowing how many victims the American lifestyle demands,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said recently. `` There's war in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> so we can continue to eat Big Macs, and I do n't want to contribute to that. We're scaling down our lifestyle to a more simplified life.'' His only income comes from speaking engagements and from teaching a sociology class at <ORGANIZATION> Bradley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Legal fees to fight his dismissal have eaten $ 13,000 out of the family savings _ perhaps part of the reason for the change in lifestyle. Clad in sneakers and jeans, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> hardly resembled the man who spent two decades in foreign counterintelligence, investigating organized crime in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and hunting fugitives like anti-war activist <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Berrigan </PERSON>. His work twice won him commendations, but something was missing from his life. A devout Roman Catholic who once studied for the priesthood, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> started taking religious study courses about 10 years ago. He earned his master's degree in 1985, and the transformation from a follower of <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> into a pacifist began to mature. It was then that <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> knew his beliefs would conflict with his role as chief counterintelligence operative in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s five-man office here. But he never really thought it would lead to his dismissal. `` Refusing an order was something I'd never done before, and I knew an act of insubordination would cost me some sort of disciplinary action,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. `` I have religious beliefs they are bound to accommodate. There are office jobs, places I could work in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. I would n't have to carry a gun. `` I think they overreacted in firing me. It was stupid. Look at all the notoriety it has caused.'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>'s life is in turmoil, but he seems content with his decision to refuse an order to investigate an anti-nuclear group suspected of vandalizing 11 Chicago-area military recruiting offices. `` I really feel I did the right thing,'' <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if I could have lived with myself had I done anything differently. His firing occurred 10 months before his 50th birthday in June, when he would have been eligible for full retirement with 20 years service. `` I could have simply ignored the order, but I chose not to. I felt what we were doing was clearly investigating peace groups with the obvious intention of intimidating and harassing them. I thought the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was ill-advised to do this and I told them.'' Despite his change of heart, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> negotiated with <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> and offered to reinstate him, with back pay, in December on the condition he never speak of the case again. He said he signed an agreement and mailed it to <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> headquarters but for some reason the deal collapsed. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> has refused to say why. This month, an administrative judge in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> ruled the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was justified in firing <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>. At a hearing, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said he could not take a human life, even if his or another person's life was endangered. He believes that was a key reason his dismissal was upheld. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> still hopes to reclaim his job and his pension, and an appeal is planned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shootings-Mother     02-22 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shootings-Mother,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspect's Mother Wants To Send Sympathy Cards To Victims' Families</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The mother of a man accused of bursting into a defense company and shooting seven people to death said she's saddened by the `` waste of life'' and wants to send sympathy cards to the victims' families. `` I wish those people would know how badly we feel,'' <PERSON> Mina </PERSON> <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON> said in an interview published Sunday. `` I do n't know if it would help -LRB- to send cards -RRB-, but we could tell them how sad we are about all of this.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, 70, also said she was shocked to learn that her son, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, was charged with seven counts of murder in Tuesday's shootings at <ORGANIZATION> ESL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> offices in nearby <LOCATION> Sunnyvale </LOCATION>. `` We'd never had any problems with <PERSON> Rick </PERSON>,'' she told the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview Saturday from her home in <LOCATION> Henderson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, about 100 miles east of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Farley </PERSON> and her husband, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, who is retired from a career in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, learned of the shootings and their oldest child's arrest the next day after they tried to contact him in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. Neither <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>'s parents nor any of his five brothers and sisters have heard from him since the attack, she said. `` We do n't communicate much,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, who has n't seen her son since a trip to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 1 -LCB- years ago. She also said her son never mentioned 26-year-old <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, an ESL employee who authorities describe as the unwilling object of <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>'s romantic fantasies. <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>'s four-year obsession with the electrical engineer is believed by authorities to be the reason for the rampage. He was fired in May 1986 for harassing <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, who went to court for a restraining order to stop him from following, calling and writing her, authorities said. Black was one of the three people who were shot during the rampage, but she survived. She remained in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where she is expected to remain for several more days. <PERSON> Farley </PERSON> remained under 24-hour surveillance at the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>. Sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Fine </PERSON> said he was quiet and polite. Besides the seven murder counts, <PERSON> Farley </PERSON> is charged with three counts of attempted murder. He could face execution if convicted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FatalFire 1stLd-Writethru a0846 02-22 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fatal Fire, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0846,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Killed, Four Injured In House Fire</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with quotes from fire chief, home's owner,
effort to reach social service officials, other detail, correcting
that home's owner was one of those injured, sted escaped unhurt. No
pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PHENIX, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire roared through a crowded house early Sunday, killing two children and three mentally retarded adults and injuring four other people, authorities said. The fire apparently started near a wood stove and the rural, two-story house was in flames by the time firefighters arrived, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> investigator W.H. <PERSON> Gholson </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Phenix </LOCATION> firefighters were aided by neighboring departments from <LOCATION> Redhouse </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Brookneal </PERSON>, but the blaze destroyed the house. There were 11 people in the house at the time the fire broke out, officials said. <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlett </PERSON>, one of the two who escaped unhurt, identified the victims as <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schofield </PERSON>, 49; <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 21; <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Berger </PERSON>, 64; <PERSON> Amir </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, 3; and <PERSON> Rashanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrington </PERSON>, 18 months. `` We tried to get the people out of there for 20 or 30 minutes,'' said Chief <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Phenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volunteer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` Then the fire and the heat got to be too much, and I had to pull everybody back.'' <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughan </PERSON>, 84, was listed in critical condition Sunday night at <ORGANIZATION> Lynchburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> with burn injuries. Three other occupants were treated and released, <PERSON> Gholson </PERSON> said. The home was owned by <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, who was among those who escaped with minor injuries, <PERSON> Gholson </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> said the three adults were mentally retarded wards of the state and she was paid by <ORGANIZATION> Charlotte </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> to take care of them. She said they had lived in her home for as much as 16 years and were relatively self-sufficient. <PERSON> Leddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, director of county social services, could not be reached for comment early Monday; telephone calls to her home went unanswered. <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said the fire apparently started after Ms. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> added wood to the stove and returned to bed. `` We do n't know if it was a defective flue or if there was combustible material near the stove right now. We think it probably came from a spark that flew out.'' Ms. <PERSON> Vaughan </PERSON> discovered the fire when she went downstairs to warm up, <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said. `` She got burned by the fire, and that's when <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> and -LRB- resident -RRB- <PERSON> Cathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlett </PERSON> came in and tried to put it out with a fire extinguisher. Then they started with buckets of water, but they could n't do anything to it.'' Ms. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlett </PERSON> went to a neighbor's house, where they called the fire department. They were both treated and released. Officials said <PERSON> Cathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamlett </PERSON> was Ms. <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>'s daughter, and some of the other people in the house were related, but they were n't sure of their exact relationship. They said the only retarded adults who were wards of the state were apparently the three adults who died. Four bodies were recovered, but the body of the younger child, who had been sleeping on the second floor, had not been found, <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Panama-Lobbyists Bjt   02-22 0888</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Lobbyists, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big-Money Lobbying On Panama's Behalf Was Rule Until Recently</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has spent hundreds of thousands of dollars since 1985 hiring American lobbyists to champion the country's cause in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and improve its image in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, records show. Among those who have registered as agents of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> are <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, a long-time political adviser to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>; M.B. <PERSON> Oglesby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> assistant for legislative affairs; <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, an executive with ties to Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s network, and <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the son of Rep. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, D-Miss The documents are filed at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in compliance with the Foreign Agents Registration Act. The law requires foreign agents to report their activities every six months. Many foreign governments hire lobbyists to help learn about the complicated <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bureaucracy. In recent years, the practice has attracted congressional scrutiny, particularly when former government officials sell their inside knowledge to foreigners. <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Malo </PERSON>, a spokesman at <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s embassy, said the government no longer employs any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> lobbyists, and the records indicate that many contracts have lapsed. Relations between the two countries have deteriorated sharply since Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the country's dominant figure, was indicted on drug smuggling charges in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> this month. One of the most recent filings _ covering the period through December 1987 _ was made by <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official and one-time business partner of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, an associate of North's. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>'s company, <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, was paid nearly $ 145,000 between July and December 1987 by a Panamanian business group set up in August 1986 to `` promote tourism, exports, investment and an improved image'' for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The group, <ORGANIZATION> Impulso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Turistico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> y </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financiera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION>, is headed by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> said <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> is a businessman with `` ties to people in the government.'' Panamanian opposition figures, including <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenmann </PERSON>, the editor of the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> is close to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Eisenmann </PERSON> lives in exile in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. For his money, <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> worked extensively with the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, the documents show. Among his duties: `` Edited articles written by embassy officials,'' and, `` Made copies of newspaper articles, speeches and letters as requested by the embassy.'' The $ 21,000 a month contract with <PERSON> Impulso </PERSON> was first signed in September 1986 by <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION>, a now-defunct firm run by <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who worked with <PERSON> North </PERSON> raising money for the Nicaraguan Contras in 1985 and 1986, has pleaded guilty to tax violations in soliciting contributions for the rebels. There is no indication that <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> worked with <PERSON> North </PERSON>. North, an ex-National <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, was fired in November 1986 for his role in using money secured through the sale of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to help the Nicaraguan Contra rebels. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> said his relationship with the Panamanian group has ended, and he no longer works with <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. Some major firms, such as <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, which employed <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Oglesby </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> Daniel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> J. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edelman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, lost their contracts with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in 1986, a year in which <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> came under increasing attack from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> registered concern in June 1986 about allegations that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> engaged in drug-trafficking and gun-running. And Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, called <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> the `` head of the biggest drug trafficking operation in the Western Hemisphere.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> ceased in late 1987. The law firm of <PERSON> Lipsen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hamberger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hamberger </PERSON>, which did lobbying work for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, last worked for the country in late 1985, according to <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamberger </PERSON>. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s close friends, worked for the <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> firm, which signed a $ 25,000-a-month contract with the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> government in late 1985, shortly after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> installed President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>. The Hecht firm's contract, which expired in November 1986, called for discussions with members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, their staffs and the executive branch about the `` political, economic and social situation'' in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>, whose home address is <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, flew to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at least twice, staying at the El <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION> or the Marriott, records show. The documents do not explain exactly what <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> did for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> did not return two telephone calls, and <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> said it is against his policy to discuss relations with clients. But Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, D-Wash., recalled a luncheon at the <ORGANIZATION> Capitol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> _ a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> haunt _ that he went to in January 1986 at the invitation of the <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> staff The <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> people wanted to explore arranging better contacts between <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> legislators and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, he said. They also discussed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, he said. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> shut off all aid to the country in December 1987. <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>, an aide to Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., said he could n't recall the topic of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> coming up at a luncheon with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, a lobbyist from the Hecht `` We talked about banking,'' <PERSON> Moss </PERSON> said. The $ 36.10 meal was charged to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, a representative of <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON>, said his firm did press work for <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> officials roughly between November 1985 and May 1986. One project involved setting up interviews for <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s wife at an anti-drug conference in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, he said <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, a lawyer with <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lohnes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albertson </PERSON>, said he has represented the Panamanian government on some legal matters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MontanaFire     02-22 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Montana Fire,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wildfire Jumps River, Burns Homes Near Whitehall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHITEHALL, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wildfire whipped by winds of up to 50 mph raced through a mountain valley south of here Sunday, destroying at least three homes and burning hundreds of acres of grassland, witnesses said. No injuries were reported. Firefighters from at least 10 volunteer fire departments in the rural area northwest of <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> battled the blaze, assisted by volunteers from the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lands </ORGANIZATION> and two mining companies. <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Giono </PERSON>, a dispatcher for the <ORGANIZATION> Jefferson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the fire was first reported in early afternoon and had grown to 500 acres by early evening It remained uncontrolled, and those on the scene reported at least three homes destroyed, she said. The fire was centered about five miles south of this town of 1,000 and was headed eastward, not toward the town, officials said. The homes that burned were scattered rural residences. The wind `` is as bad as I've ever seen it,'' said <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, a trapper who lives on the south edge of town. `` The ... stuff was going faster than you could run.'' `` A lot of people lost their homes,'' <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> said, but noted he did not know exactly how many homes were destroyed. Authorities said it was believed that the fire was caused by a downed power line, but that had not been confirmed. Strong winds raked much of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> east of the Continental Divide on Sunday. There were widespread reports of damaged roofs, downed power lines, uprooted trees and toppled billboards and signs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880222-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-22-88 0124EST</FILEID>
