<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Robertson 2ndLd-Writethru a0906 08-16 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Robertson, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0906,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson Works to Inject Followers Into Bush Camp</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: UPDATES throughout with speech delivered; color, additional
quotes</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE GLOVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vanquished presidential candidate <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> appealed to his conservative, largely fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> supporters Tuesday and urged them to `` rally with wholehearted support'' behind <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` This party is about to nominate a man that I have come to respect and admire,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> told the Republican National Convention in television prime time. `` This man can and will lead our nation proudly into the future.'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, the TV evangelist whose presidential star faded quickly in an often-acrimonious primary campaign, described <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as `` a principled conservative'' and dismissed suggestions that his backers would sit out this election. `` We care because it does matter,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. As expected, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s backers, who had hoped to make the convention their own, staged only a brief demonstration waving blue and white signs and brightly colored umbrellas. His late-night speech came as many attending the convention began slipping out of the hall for the evening, leaving big blocks of empty seats. Two of the networks cut away from his speech in favor of other convention coverage as <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> went several minutes past prime time. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has spent the convention's opening days preaching party unity, and praising the conservative direction the party charted in its platform. Now, he said, it's time for conservatives and fundamentalists to join the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. `` I release my delegates and alternates who have come to this convention and urge you and all of my friends across <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to give your enthusiastic support to our party, our candidates and our presidential nominee,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` It matters to us and our children whether we vote Democrat or whether we vote Republican,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> also attacked <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as `` the most liberal candidate ever put forward for the presidency by any major party in American history'' and said Democrats `` do not speak for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today.'' In one of the sharpest attacks of the convention on Democrats who held their convention last month, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> insisted `` the liberal mind set reigns supreme'' in that party. `` Now the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has discovered the family,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` But let's keep in mind that they want you and me to be in one family with <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> as the daddy, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON> as the momma and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> as the big brother. `` They offer unlimited government, massive transfers of wealth from the productive sector of society to the non-productive, and ever-increasing regulation of the daily lives of the people and their children.'' In his prime-time speech and in a joint appearance with <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the vice president's son, earlier Tuesday, <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> sought not only to bring his supporters into the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp but also to cement his role as a leader of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s conservative wing and guarantee a future that might include another run for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, backers said. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s presidential hopes died early this year in an often bruising campaign, and some strategists worried that his backers, many of them fundamentalist Christians involved for the first time in politics, would simply drift away without strong urging from <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a card-carrying member of the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, an organization dedicated to removing all public affirmation of religious faith in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. `` As president, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will pack the federal courts with <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> radicals.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HeatWave 1stLd-Writethru a0834 08-16 0892</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Heat Wave, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0834,0909</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hottest Weather Of The Summer In Kentucky, But Northeast Gets A
Break</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 10th graf `Some other' with 4 grafs to UPDATE with
later, higher record temperatures at Fargo, Huron, Indianapolis and
Madison; other records and quotes. Updates final graf with Tuesday
TVA record.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AM-Killer Heat Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto RHD1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The big summer heat wave rolled on Tuesday with temperatures boiling past 100 to record highs from the eastern Plains to the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, but the steamy Northeast finally got a break with a surge of cooler, drier air from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. Utilities posted more records for demand for electricity as air conditioners and fans were turned on full blast. Some school districts in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> plan to open schools early and reduce class periods by almost half when school opens next week to avoid the hottest part of the day. `` By noon during summer school, it was very uncomfortable. If it was 90 outside, it was 95 to 100 in the classrooms. That's not a good atmosphere for learning,'' said associate principal <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Tokarski </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rantoul </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- High School. `` I think this will be the hottest weather of the summer, taking both temperature and humidity into account,'' said <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Reitmeyer </PERSON>, a meteorologist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> `` We've had an oppressively hot and humid summer without a doubt,'' <PERSON> Reitmeyer </PERSON> said. `` But particular days such as this or tomorrow are rare.'' The temperature at <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, reached 102 degrees and <PERSON> Reitmeyer </PERSON> said that and the humidity would push the heat index, a measure of how hot it feels, the opposite of winter's wind chill factor, to 115. He said that is near life-threatening for some people. <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> has had a total of 48 days of above-90 degrees this summer. <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> reached a record high of 100 degrees, and that made it a record five times the city has hit 100 or higher this year. The old record was four times in 1936. Some other records included 90 at <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>; 104 at <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>; 103 at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dodge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; 103 at <LOCATION> Huron </LOCATION>, S.D.; 102 at <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>; 102 at <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>; 101 at <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, S.D.; and 102 at <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. The 103 degrees at <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, was the hottest reading since July 27, 1955. <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crosse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, marked the 44th day that the temperature achieved the 90 degree mark, another record. The 102-degree heat wilted about 10,000 competitors wearing heavy uniforms and carrying musical instruments at the <ORGANIZATION> Drum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Championships </ORGANIZATION> on the artificial turf at <LOCATION> Arrowhead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. `` You can feel it right through your tennis shoes,'' said <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> MacDougall </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Edmonton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strutters </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. `` One of our melophone players almost passed out.'' The 136th <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> State Fair opened Tuesday with livestock exhibitors taking extra precautions, like putting ice in front of large fans to keep animals cool. Four chickens that were to be entered died when their owners left them in cars with the windows rolled up, fair officials said. The official high in the 48 contiguous states at 3 p.m. EDT was 105 degrees, not in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> or southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> but at <LOCATION> Chamberlin </LOCATION>, S.D. But nature's own air-conditioning _ in the form of a cool front from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ settled over the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION>. Unfortunately, forecasts said the heat would soon return. After 32 days of 90-degree temperatures and swamp-like humidity, including a high of 97 Monday, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> had a high Tuesday of merely 86 degrees. And the humidity was only around 39 to 42 percent, making it feel almost like early autumn compared to preceding weeks. `` The downturn in temperatures is certainly going to help not only <PERSON> Con </PERSON> <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> but all <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> utilities,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, spokesman for the utility that supplies <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s power. <PERSON> Con </PERSON> <PERSON> Edison </PERSON> had a record demand Monday of 10,160 megawatts of electricity. The failure of several feeder cables on <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> knocked out service to more than 13,000 customers. And earlier Monday, the utility cut off power to 16 large apartment buildings on <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION> to prevent a wider blackout after several feeder cables failed, blacking out some 10,000 residents. The cooler air also brought relief for utilities in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> was forced to impose a 5 percent voltage reduction Monday. But the clash of the hot and cool air also touched off thunderstorms, which knocked out power to thousands of customers across the state Monday. Farther south, utilities across <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> reported record electrical demand Monday and expected to exceed those amounts Tuesday, but no problems were reported. `` We've been going wild this summer,'' said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovegrove </PERSON>, a spokesman for Ashland-based <ORGANIZATION> Kentucky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>, which had records for power use almost every day during the past week. <ORGANIZATION> Louisville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> has set all-time peaks 13 times this summer, said spokesman <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, the big federal utility, hit another record peak summer demand Tuesday of 21,304 megawatts. A record Monday of 20,618 megawatts forced the utility to buy about 2,500 megawatts from neighboring utilities, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steffy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, senior vice president of power for <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s all-time power peak was in the winter of 1983 at 22,478 megawatts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Ford 2ndLd-Writethru a0928 08-16 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Ford, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0928,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ford Charges Democrats Distorted Bush Record</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Top 5 grafs new with speech delivered, color; picks up 3rd
graf pvs, ``Obviously stung xxx</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> said Tuesday that Democratic chants of `` Where Was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' unfairly distorted and belittled <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s accomplishments in a long career of government service. In a speech to the Republican National Convention, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> praised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his experience and competence, saying, `` For 45 years <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been at the center of the action in the service of this great republic.'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does not deserve to have Democrats ask: `` Where Was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' The 38th president was joined at the lectern by his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, who said she was delighted to work to send <PERSON> George </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` to the White House where they belong.'' The convention was a half hour behind schedule when <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> began and many of the delegates had already left the hall. But the television networks, who had been scheduled to end their coverage at 11 p.m. EDT, stayed with the convention. Obviously stung by the chanted question at last month's Democratic convention when Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., questioned <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s influence in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> offered this retort: `` I'll be damned if I will stand by and let anyone with a smirk and a sneer discredit the honor, service, accountability and competence of <PERSON> George </PERSON> `` If the three Democratic standard-bearers in this campaign think it is about competence,'' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said, `` let any one of them _ or all three of them put together _ top the demonstrated competence of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' The former president was referring to <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and former presidential contender <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Ford accused the Democrats of attempting to steal the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream at their convention _ a dream he said belongs to the nation and all of its people. `` No party, no politician has a patent on our dream,'' he said. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream belongs to you and nobody can take it away from you.'' In an echo of his losing campaign against <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> in 1976, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> asked his audience, `` Do we really want to go back to the days of spend and spend and tax and tax _ of a government in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with its head in the clouds and its hand in your pocket? `` I can put it no plainer than this: This year's Democratic ticket is a tax increase waiting to happen,'' he said. In a backhanded slap at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was `` pretty solid on defense matters.'' Rhetorically addressing <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> said: `` Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says you'll be the kind of vice president who will march into the Oval Office and tell him: ` Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, that is a perfectly ridiculous policy.''' <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> added, `` Lloyd, with all the differences between the Democratic leaders, why wait? Speak up now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-16 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0539</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>IOWA CITY, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A `` swat'' team is out to attack a bat problem. But the specials weapons in this case are tennis rackets, brooms and nightsticks, which police are using to swat the flying creatures in a running battle with them. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police officer <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Brotherton </PERSON> bagged a bat early Sunday and said it was the 10th bat call city police have gotten in five days. <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Wegner </PERSON> had fallen asleep watching TV and awoke to see her dog's head going back and forth as it watched a bat circle the living room. She called police. `` I'm petrified of bats,'' she said. `` It seemed to like where I was sleeping, so I grabbed a blanket and waited on the porch. I was wearing my pajamas.'' When <PERSON> Brotherton </PERSON> arrived, he turned on the lights to coax the bat to sleep. The bat landed on a wall where <PERSON> Brotherton </PERSON> pinned it with his nightstick. The bat slid into a paper bag, he said. `` Usually at night they keep flying, and you have to pin them with a broom or swat them with a tennis racket,'' he said. `` Normally I can get them by the third swing.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FRUITPORT, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bride wore white lace, the groom wore a top hat, and both had tails. But that was OK, for the wedding was for the dogs. When <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fruitport </LOCATION> bought a female Pomeranian puppy, Foxy Lady, to breed with their 5-year-old male Pomeranian, Tiny, their daughter thought something was amiss. `` My 10-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Majorie </PERSON>, thought that they should be married before they had puppies, so we decided to go ahead and do it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> said. And as long as there was going to be a wedding, Mrs. <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> figured it should be done right. She rented a tuxedo for Tiny and a dress for Foxy, decorated the front porch with flowers and invited neighborhood children to Saturday's ceremony. The bride and groom were led by leash to the altar to the tune of the `` Wedding March,'' and Mrs. <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> performed the ceremony. The couple's honeymoon will be in <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION>, a town where the <ORGANIZATION> McGregors </ORGANIZATION> spent their honeymoon. But the newlyweds will be chaperoned by the <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> family, who'll be vacationing. Mrs. <PERSON> McGregor </PERSON> expressed relief when the wedding was over. `` Tiny's really been showing that he's interested in Foxy, and we did n't want a shotgun wedding,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SONOMA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The charity <LOCATION> Sonoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Wine Auction drew nearly $ 100,000 in bids over a wine-soaked weekend, but the most astonishing sale of the event was of a large bottle of water. Through a proxy, <PERSON> Koichiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Ikawa </PERSON>, executive of the <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, paid $ 950 for a redwood-packed, 3-liter bottle of <ORGANIZATION> Mendocino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beverage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> mineral water. Bidding on the big bottle started at $ 200, and <PERSON> Ikawa </PERSON>'s bidder and an unidentified <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> man pushed the price up to levels that drew gasps from the audience. The water, besides the qualities usually attributed to mineral water, contained a special essence _ truffle juice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-GazaSettlers Bjt   08-16 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gaza Settlers, Bjt,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Settlers In Gaza Digging In Heels</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN IZENBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEVE DEKALIM, Occupied Gaza Strip (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jewish settlers are digging in their heels, determined to stay in this seaside strip even in the face of resurgent <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> violence that led the army to clamp an indefinite curfew. They say they are drawn by an improved quality of life in their tiny, closeknit communities and a pioneering spirit. But heightened violence in the Israeli-occupied territory has taken its toll. Six Israelis leaving <PERSON> Neve </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekalim </PERSON> after a visit this week were injured in a firebomb attack. From the settlement, Israelis can often see tires burning and hear gunfire in the nearby <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yunis </PERSON> refugee camp. Jewish settlers here, however, say they will not be frightened away. `` We must not let the situation change the normal course of our lives. That's just what the Arabs want,'' <PERSON> Shimshon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahilker </PERSON>, a 21-year-old seminary student, said in an interview Tuesday. The Palestinian uprising against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 21-year occupation began in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> eight months ago and tensions have remained high. Of the more than 240 Palestinians killed in the rebellion, about a third were in the strip. Four Israelis also have died. About 2,000 Jewish settlers share <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> with 650,000 Palestinians, about two-thirds of whom are refugees living in poverty in overcrowded camps. If the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> is a hurricane, then the Jewish settlements are its eye. <PERSON> Neve </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekalim </PERSON> could be a pleasant suburb if one forgot its location. Some families in this settlement about a mile from the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> live in homes with manicured lawns and palm trees. Whereas the Arabs have been confined round-the-clock to their homes during a curfew that began Sunday night, the small community of Jewish settlers in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> can come and go as they please. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Tasa </PERSON> sat outside the municipal building selling plastic chairs, coolers and umbrellas for the beach. Security concerns, however, are prevalent. <PERSON> Neve </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekalim </PERSON> is circled by barbed wire fences and regularly patroled by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops. An armed soldier rode in the front seat of a bus bringing settlers home. `` Two weeks ago I was driving with my children in a car and someone threw a gigantic rock which broke the window,'' said <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizur </PERSON>, a 28-year-old teacher and mother of three who moved to <PERSON> Neve </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekalim </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> two weeks ago. `` Immediately after that we saw a burning tire blocking the road. It was a frightening drive. I shook all over,'' she said. But Mrs. <PERSON> Elizur </PERSON> said she had no intention of leaving `` because the settlement offers me the kind of life I want.'' `` It's wonderful for children,'' agreed <PERSON> Sima </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmaliach </PERSON>, 28. `` They have an excellent religious education.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Elmaliach </PERSON> said the latest firebomb attack troubled her, `` but we very much believe in God, and we believe that if something has to happen to somebody, it will happen anywhere.'' Far fewer settlers live in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> than in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> has suggested resolving the Palestinian conflict by giving up the strip in return for a negotiated settlement. But <PERSON> Bini </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesel </PERSON>, a settler who has lived here for 3 -LCB- years, opposes any such solution. `` The numbers do n't matter,'' said the 32-year-old music teacher and father of six. `` The question is whether we have a right to live in our country _ all of it. Any Arab who accepts that can stay, and those who do n't should leave.'' <PERSON> Elyada </PERSON> <PERSON> Yovel </PERSON>, a 14-year-old from <PERSON> Neve </PERSON> <PERSON> Dekalim </PERSON>, also opposes moving. He said he never thinks of the rebellion on busy schooldays, `` but on Saturdays, we go up on the hill to see the action. We hear shooting in the refugee camp.'' `` But I still go to the beach'' near the refugee camp, he said. `` What's there to be afraid of? Where could you find such quality of life, except in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DroughtConditions     08-16 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Conditions,0553</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latest Reports On Crop, Soil Conditions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Following are the latest soil and crop conditions in some of the states hardest hit by the drought, based on an <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey of Monday's weekly reports by state agricultural offices. Percentages relate to the number of reporting stations listing a particular soil or crop condition.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALABAMA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 12 percent very short, 50 percent short, 34 percent adequate, 4 percent surplus. KEY CROP: Soybeans 19 percent poor, 31 percent fair, 50 percent good. Cotton 11 percent very poor, 20 percent poor, 45 percent fair, 19 percent good, 5 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>GEORGIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 12 percent very short, 52 percent short, 33 percent adequate, 3 percent surplus. KEY CROP: Peanuts 35 percent good, 51 percent fair, 10 percent poor, 4 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ILLINOIS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SOIL MOISTURE: 92 percent short, 8 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 3 percent good, 30 percent fair, 50 percent poor, 17 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 35 percent adequate, 65 percent short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 9 percent adequate, 91 percent short. KEY CROP: Corn 7 percent good, 48 percent fair, 32 percent poor, 13 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IOWA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 6 percent adequate, 94 percent short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 2 percent adequate, 98 percent short. KEY CROP: Corn 4 percent good, 29 percent fair, 44 percent poor and 23 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KANSAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 65 percent short, 33 percent adequate, 2 percent surplus. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 63 percent short, 37 percent adequate.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSOURI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 81 percent short, 18 percent adequate, 1 percent surplus. KEY CROPS: Corn 29 percent very poor, 38 percent poor, 25 percent fair, 8 percent good. Soybeans 16 percent very poor, 21 percent poor, 44 percent fair, 18 percent good, 1 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KENTUCKY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 8 percent very short, 73 percent short and 19 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Tobacco 1 percent very poor, 6 percent poor, 36 percent fair, 56 percent good, 1 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MICHIGAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 65 percent short, 35 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 2 percent excellent, 18 percent good, 35 percent fair, 30 percent poor, 15 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MINNESOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 35 percent very short, 50 percent short, 15 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 30 percent very poor, 41 percent poor, 25 percent fair, 4 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 60 percent very short, 33 percent short, 7 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 74 percent very short, 21 percent short, 5 percent adequate.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 34 percent adequate, 66 percent short. KEY CROPS: Corn 10 percent good, 33 percent fair, 35 percent poor, 22 percent very poor. Soybeans 1 percent excellent, 16 percent good, 40 percent fair, 28 percent poor, 15 percent ery poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WISCONSIN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 90 percent short, 10 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 14 percent good, 30 percent fair, 41 percent poor, 15 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Romania-UN     08-16 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Romania-UN,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Panel Votes For Investigation Of Romanian's Disappearance</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> human rights panel voted Monday to have the secretary-general investigate the case of a Romanian specialist who disappeared without completing a report on youth and human rights. <PERSON> Dumitru </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> had been given a mandate by the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommission </ORGANIZATION> on the Prevention of Discrimination and Protection of Minorities to present a report to the panel's current meeting in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. In a letter sent to the subcommission last April and distributed by members, <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> said the Romanian government had pressured him to drop the study, forced him to retire from a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> post, confiscated his passport and put him under police surveillance. By a vote of 16-2, the subcommission asked Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> to inform <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s communist authorities of the `` urgent need to establish personal contact'' with <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> and to report back by Wednesday. The motion, sponsored by the French and Norwegian delegates, also urged <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> to establish <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON>'s whereabouts and arrange a visit to him by a member of the subcommission. Romanian officials told the subcommision that <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> could not complete the report or attend the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> meeting because of a heart condition. They said <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> recently left <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION>, the Romanian capital, to undergo treatment at a health resort, but they did not identify the resort. After several days of debate the motion was passed with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> voting against it, four delegates abstaining and three not voting. Soviet delegate <PERSON> Stanislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Chernichenko </PERSON> said the case was an administrative matter that had `` nothing to do with human rights'' and the subcommission had overstepped its mandate by attempting to give <PERSON> Mazilu </PERSON> `` quasi-diplomatic status.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-Ranking Bjt   08-16 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Ranking, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS 15th Among Causes of Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 AIDS would rank as the 15th leading cause of death in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> if it were counted as a separate category, according to new figures from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION>. Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome killed between 12,450 and 13,820 Americans last year, the center estimated in its first annual summary including separate figures for the disease. While AIDS has not yet been added to the rankings of major causes of death published by the agency, the 1987 toll would have placed it 15th on the list, ahead of birth defects, the agency noted. The center's annual summary of vital statistics also disclosed that in 1987, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> had the most births in nearly 25 years and the most deaths ever, and that marriage and divorce rates were at the lowest level in more than a decade. The report said that 65 percent of AIDS victims were white males and 25 percent black males with between 4 percent and 5 percent each being black and white females. The age groups most affected were 25 to 34 and 35 to 44, the study added. AIDS is a contagious disease that attacks the body's immune system, rendering it incapable of resisting other diseases and infections. The disease is spread most often through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, infected blood or blood products, and from infected pregnant women to their offspring. The chief victims have been homosexual men and intravenous drug users. As of Aug. 8, AIDS had been diagnosed in 70,208 Americans, of whom more than half, or 39,620, have died, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. A slight increase in fertility, coupled with the huge number of women in their prime childbearing years, resulted in the estimated 3,829,000 babies born last year, the most since 1964, the report showed. Millions of people born in the post World War II Baby Boom are now in their 20s and 30s and, after completing school and launching careers, have begun families. That has led to a sharp increase in total births in recent years, although the nation's fertility rate of 66.1 births per 1,000 women aged 15 to 44 remains about half that of the late 1950s when the Baby Boom was at its peak. Social scientists have begun referring to the recent surge as an `` echo'' of the Baby Boom. Deaths in 1987 totaled 2,127,000, up from 2,099,000 a year earlier and the most ever recorded for a single year in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Record numbers of deaths have become common in recent years as the nation's population includes an ever larger share of elderly people. The national death rate of 8.7 per 1,000 people in 1987 was unchanged from a year earlier, the report noted. Life expectancy at birth also was unchanged at 74.9 years. The report disclosed small increases in life expectancy last year for white men and black women, and small declines for white women and black men. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON> of the center's mortality branch said statisticians wo n't be able to determine a reason for those changes until they have more time to study the detailed figures. Among causes of death, heart disease declined somewhat last year, as it has for the last several years, the report found. There also was a decline in the rate for accidents, other than those involving motor vehicles. Death rates for other major causes of death did not show statistically significant changes. The nation's marriage rate for 1987 was 9.9 weddings per 1,000 people, the lowest since 1977 when it was also 9.9. Divorce also was low last year, at a rate of 4.8 per 1,000 people, the lowest since 1975. It peaked at 5.3 in 1979 and again in 1981. Here is a rundown of the estimated number of deaths in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year for the 15 leading causes. AIDS is included under the category of `` all other infectious and parasitic diseases,'' which showed a growth in deaths from 9,030 in 1986 to 19,160 last year, but such `` all other'' generalized categories were not part of the ranking system.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Cause Deaths Heart 762,820 Cancer 477,190 Cerebrovascular 149,220 Accidents 94,840 Lung -LRB- chronic -RRB- 78,270 Pneumonia-flu 70,120 Diabetes 37,900 Suicide 30,980 Liver -LRB- chronic -RRB- 26,050 Atherosclerosis 23,200 Kidney 23,040 Homicide 20,580 Blood poisoning 19,810 Infant deaths 18,460 Birth defects 12,130
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RadioSignals Bjt   08-16 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Radio Signals, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Clutter Of Signals Obscures Heavens For Radio Astronomers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Electromagnetic clatter from millions of manmade sources is drowning out whispers from the heavens and crippling research by radio astronomers who probe distant stars, scientists say. <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, a radio astronomer at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION>, says the machines of modern <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ from car engines, to computers, to automatic garage door openers _ are helping to pollute the airwaves with electromagnetic garbage. `` The radio spectrum is a natural resource and, as with any natural resource, it can get polluted,'' Price said in an interview while attending an astronomy conference Monday. `` It's not like air or water pollution because you ca n't see it, but it's there.'' For that reason, he said, astronomers are anxious that unnecessary uses of radio signals be eliminated. In many cases, gross radio interference sources could be controlled with the use of filters or shields that would add only a dollar or two to manufacturing costs, he said. `` The radio spectrum is a vital part of our everyday life,'' said Price. `` Every time you order a pizza or call for an ambulance, it's probably radio dispatched and there's another signal. That's why we worry about this limited resource being used for frivolous purposes.'' Electromagnetic gridlock is only one type of pollution affecting astronomers. At a meeting this week sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astronomical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, astronomers from around the world said their work also is hampered by manmade light, and by debris left in space that reflects sunlight and causes streaks on astronomy photographs. For radio astronomers, the electromagnetic spectrum can help unlock secrets of star formation millions of light years away. Each type of molecule, when excited by heat, puts out a unique radio signal. By capturing and analyzing these signals, radio astronomers can determine the chemical composition of processes taking place at points in the universe not even visible to optical telescopes. This work has defined the shape of <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s home galaxy, discovered key components in the lives of stars, and confirmed formation of complex chemicals within galaxies and stars. Radio astronomers explore virtually every portion of the spectrum to catch the faint, distant star symphony, but <PERSON> Price </PERSON> said continuation of this work is threatened now by the sudden rise of manmade radio signals. `` In the last five years, we've seen an explosion of use of the radio spectrum for consumer devices,'' he said. Many of these signals could be shielded from the environment. Spark plugs in automobiles, for instance, he said, create a slight radio signal every time they fire. This could be corrected for about $ 2 per vehicle, said Price. Cellular telephones, computers, handheld calculators and electronic toys all add to the clutter, he said, and all could be filtered and shielded for small cost. Price said radar signals used for defense, air traffic control and even highway speed-checking guns all put out signals in portions of the spectrum important to astronomy. So do television stations. A new Soviet navigation system is threatening to blot out study of the hydroxyl radical, a key part of the chemistry of water and of some organic chemicals. Research on this molecule could give important clues to the existence of life beyond the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Radio astronomers are able to detect the hydroxyl radical at 1600 to 1700 megahertz on the spectrum. A system of navigation satellites now being deployed by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would operate constantly at this same portion of the radio band. `` It is impossible to study this molecule when they -LRB- the satellites -RRB- are above your horizon,'' he said. The strong Soviet navigation signal simply blots out everything else in that portion of the spectrum, said Price. `` Eventually, the navigation system will cover the whole Earth and we could lose the ability to study the hydroxyl radical,'' he said. `` This robs you of considerable information.'' Price said astronomers recognize that little can be done to control the growing use of the spectrum for important services such as aircraft control and communications. But the scientists hope that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the world community will take measures to control the `` unnecessary and frivolous use of a diminishing resource.'' And, Price said, astronomers recognize that eventually they'll have to leave the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> and its cacophony of electronic noise, if they are to continue studying the dim electronic voice of the universe But where would they go? `` The backside of the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> has been designated as a quiet zone,'' he said. `` It would be shielded against the signals from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. That's about our only choice.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-InterestRates Bjt   08-16 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Interest Rates, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Americans with Variable Loans in for More Shocks</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Fed meeting is private; May stand for PMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of Americans with adjustable mortgages and other variable-rate loans are in for further shocks this year if the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> keeps up its anti-inflation campaign as many economists are predicting. Many Americans already have seen their credit costs rise this year because of credit tightening on the part of the central bank. As <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> policy-makers gathered to map monetary strategy behind closed doors today, some economists were predicting that the central bank already has decided that even higher rates are necessary to slow an economy being buffeted by rising inflationary threats. The meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Open </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Market </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> comes one week after the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>, in a surprise move, boosted its discount rate by one-half percentage point to 6.5 percent, its highest level since July 1986. An increase in the discount rate, the interest the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> charges to make loans to commercial banks, is the most dramatic signal the central bank can send of its intention to push interest rates higher as a way of dampening demand and thus fighting inflationary pressures. The timing of the discount rate increase was a surprise for many economists who had expected the all-Republican <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> board, led by Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, to shy away from such an overt credit-tightening move in an election year. While analysts said they do n't expect another boost in the discount rate until after the November election, they said the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> very likely will continue tightening credit by more subtle means. Since late March, the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> has been reducing the reserves banks have available for making loans, driving up a variety of short-term interest rates. The federal funds rate, which is the interest banks charge to make overnight loans to each other, has now risen to 8 percent and many economists predicted it would climb by another one-half percentage point in coming weeks. Major banks followed the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s lead last week and boosted their prime lending rate from 9.5 percent to 10 percent, a three-year high. Analysts predicted that with further <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> pressure, the prime rate will climb to 10.5 percent in the next two months. `` I am looking for further tightening steps based on a perception by <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> policy-makers that the economy is growing too strongly,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, an economist at <ORGANIZATION> Aubrey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a government securities dealer. Because the prime rate is used to calculate a wide range of consumer loans, from adjustable mortgages to home equity loans, the rate hikes will be felt quickly by consumers, analysts said. They also predicted further increases in traditional fixed-rate mortgages. A national survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said fixed-rate mortgages jumped to 10.57 percent at the end of last week, up almost a percentage point from their February low. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinai </PERSON>, chief economist at the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said fixed-rate mortgages will hit 11 percent within a month with the only question being how much higher they may go before the end of the year. `` The economy has a tremendous head of steam, particularly in the industrial sector,'' he said. `` History has shown us that once our economy develops boom-like conditions, it takes tougher restrictive policies to bring accelerating inflation under control.'' Analysts pointed to a variety of recent statistics which indicate inflation is a growing problem. The government reported last week that wholesale prices shot up at an annual rate of 5.7 percent in July, compared with an increase of 2.2 percent in 1987. Some economists predicted that consumer prices could be climbing at a 6 percent annual rate within six months. And on Monday, the government said industrial output climbed 0.8 percent in July, the biggest increase since last October and an advance which put further strains on many industries already operating at close to top capacity. `` If the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> does n't continue to tighten in this environment, at least in a moderate way, then it will have to tighten two or three times as much if it waits and inflation gets more out of hand,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jasinowski </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION>, said he believes the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> will wait awhile before it takes any further tightening moves. `` I think they wanted to send a signal to the markets last week that inflation was their top priority,'' he said. `` Now that they have done that, they will lay back on their oars and see how the economy develops in the third quarter.'' Many economists are predicting that overall economic growth, as measured by the gross national product, will slow somewhat in the last half of the year, compared with an annual rate of increase of 3.3 percent in the first half of 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-16 0917</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,000</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drought has brought mixed results to farm machinery sales this year, although preliminary readings by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> show that crop expansion plans for 1989 could have some effect. Spending on farm machinery rose in 1987 after seven years of decline to $ 5.77 billion from $ 4.61 billion in 1986, according to a report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Currently, largely because of brisk sales early in the year, the agency forecasts 1988 machinery expenditures may range from $ 5.7 billion to $ 6.2 billion. `` The farm machinery industry will be hurt if farmers with reduced cash receipts put off buying new equipment,'' the report said. `` Demand for harvesting, drying and storage equipment is most likely to be affected.'' However, the report added that the drought has prompted greater sales of irrigation equipment in some parts of the country. Farm machinery sales rose to a record of almost $ 12 billion in 1979 before staring a 60 percent slide to $ 4.61 billion in 1986, reflecting the crunch on farm income, high interest rates and tight credit in the early 1980s. Analysts said last year's improved sales stemmed from `` enhanced financial conditions for farmers'' in 1987, notably a record net cash income nationwide of $ 56 billion. Net cash income _ the difference between gross cash receipts and cash expenses _ is forecast at $ 53 billion to $ 59 billion this year. Despite the drought, analysts said there are some good signs: farmland values as of February were up 3 percent, on the average, from a year earlier, and total farm debt is at its lowest level since 1979. `` Higher interest rates and drought likely will repress some demand for machinery in the remainder of 1988, but sales are still likely to rise,'' the report said. Drought in the Corn Belt and spring wheat states probably will hurt machinery sales because of reduced cash flow to pay bills or take on new debt. `` However, those farmers who produce a crop will benefit from higher commodity prices,'' the report said. `` Farm machinery purchases not affected by the drought are expected to rise.'' Looking ahead at total `` input'' requirements, which includes machinery as well as other items for production, the report said prospects for spring planting in 1989 `` appear promising since the 1988 drought will reduce commodity stocks and increase commodity prices. This should increase planted acreage in 1989 and thereby increase input demand.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Higher grain prices are putting a crunch on cattle feeders and are helping to trim placement of cattle and calves in feedlots this summer, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts. As of Aug. 1, cattle being fed for the slaughter market in the seven major beef states totaled 6.84 million head, up 2 percent from a year ago and 8 percent more than inventories of two years ago, the department said Monday. The placement of new cattle and calves in fattening pens last month was reported at 1.25 million head, down 2 percent from a year ago and down 19 percent from two years ago. Marketings of `` fed'' cattle in July totaled 1.77 million head, up 4 percent from a year ago and also up 4 percent from two years ago. Officials said those were the most July feedlot marketings since the 7-state estimates began in 1972. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists, market prices of Choice steers on the <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, market are expected to average $ 65 to $ 69 per 100 pounds this summer, compared with $ 72.81 in the April-June quarter. Prices are projected at $ 66 to $ 72 in the fourth quarter. Meanwhile, drought has reduced grain production and sent prices higher, translating into higher cattle feeding costs. As it looks to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists, the forecasts of fed cattle prices are about $ 100 per head below break-even levels. As of Aug. 1, feedlot inventories were larger than a year earlier in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> but were less in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The seven states produce about three-fourths of the nation's beef. State feedlot cattle inventories are listed here for the seven states. The first number is the number of cattle, in thousands, as of Aug. 1, and the second number is the percentage of a year earlier.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> 200 84 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 435 102 <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> 705 110 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> 495 99 <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> 1,465 111 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 1,590 107 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 1,950 93
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The opening of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn sales last year was an encouraging development in a market historically dominated by <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, says a trade report by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` Although it is likely that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will have a hard time maintaining a market presence -LRB- in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> -RRB- once Thai supplies return to normal, the sales last year provided an opportunity for Malaysian users to become more familiar with the qualities of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> product,'' the report said. Malaysians liked <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn for its consistent quality, lower moisture and exporter reliability, among other reasons, the report said. But on the plus side for <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> corn was its shipment size of only 500 to 1,000 metric tons, already bagged, and its lesser shipping time. The brief report is included in a forthcoming issue of Foreign Agriculture magazine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LastJamSession     08-16 0257</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Last Jam Session,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dying Musician Throwing Himself A Party</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TRAVERSE CITY, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Trombone player <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON>, dying of cancer, has decided to be on hand for a celebration of big band-era music rather than throw the party posthumously. <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON>, 66, said he's dreamed for years that his musician friends would gather after his death for a `` big jam session.'' But in the six months since he was diagnosed as having inoperable lung and liver cancer, he's decided to hold the celebration while he's still around The Labor Day event at Grand Traverse Resort will feature the <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON>. Admission is free. `` I just made up my mind,'' said <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON>, who founded the Riverboat Six, a local Dixieland band, 30 years ago and is now in a nursing home. `` I've got no kids, I've had some money saved. I thought, ` What can I do for all the people who were so faithful coming to our dances?''' <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON>, a World War II bomber pilot and owner of a flower shop and mortuary here, has hired a lawyer to make sure the party goes on if he does n't survive until Labor Day, friends said. The party will realize <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON>'s dream that he `` go out <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> style,'' said <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Bechtold </PERSON>, who has known <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON> for 50 years. <PERSON> Hibbard </PERSON> said he booked the <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorsey </PERSON> Band because it plays the music he loves best. `` I wanted people to hear this band because they are one of the finest bands playing today,'' he said. `` It's happy music.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-16 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop singer <PERSON> Lulu </PERSON> is expecting her second child, but concedes that having another baby at age 39 is a `` daunting'' prospect. `` I'm surprised because really we had given up hope,'' said <PERSON> Lulu </PERSON>, born as <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrie </PERSON>. She and her husband, hairdresser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Frieda </PERSON>, have an 11-year-old son, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>. `` We waited for a long time after <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> was born before we thought seriously about adding to the family and now we're delighted,'' she said Monday `` It is daunting being a mum again at 40 but I feel better and more comfortable as I get older.'' <PERSON> Lulu </PERSON>, whose birthday is Nov. 3, is starring in the musical `` Peter Pan'' in west <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s theater district. But she said the baby, due in April, means she will have to pull out of a fall tour. <PERSON> Lulu </PERSON> rose to fame in 1964 with her hit, `` Shout,'' and her role in the 1969 <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Poitier </PERSON> film `` To Sir With Love.'' She was previously married to singer <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibb </PERSON> of the Bee Gees pop group.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON>'s wife and the singer's girlfriend met separately with hearing officers who will recommend whether to prosecute Mrs. <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> for allegedly beating the other woman. `` All the parties have met with the hearing officers, all of them have had their say and we should have a decision by the end of the week,'' Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Bobys </PERSON> said after Monday's hearings <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Richie </PERSON>, 35, was arrested June 29 after a brawl with her husband and dancer <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, 22, at Miss <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>'s apartment <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> and Miss <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> have known each other about four years. Mrs. <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> was released on $ 5,000 bail after she was booked for investigation of corporal injury to a spouse, resisting arrest, trespassing, vandalism, battery and disturbing the peace. <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> did n't show up for the hearing.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man is pressing an assault complaint against talk-show host <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> after being grabbed and pulled by the shirt during a confrontation in which the's man sister slapped <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>. Sunday night's scuffle occurred during a forum, modeled after <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>'s show, which attracted 2,000 people. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bass </PERSON>, 28, executive editor of The New Haven Independent, and his sister, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bass </PERSON>, battled verbally with <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> again Monday when they appeared on the `` <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Jessy </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON>'' TV show. `` I was foolish enough to think I could have an intellectual debate with him,'' <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> said Monday. Playing the peacemaker, <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> had Bass shake hands with an apologetic <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>. <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> hugged <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> and gave his still visibly angry sister an unwanted kiss on the cheek. <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> then announced he would not file civil charges against <PERSON> Bass </PERSON>, as he had <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> also said he would not pursue civil action. But <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> said he was not withdrawing his assault complaint. Sunday's confrontation erupted as <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> was challenging <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>'s claim that his show and philosophy represents the `` voice of the people. <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> said he grabbed Bass by the shirt, pulled him out of his chair and began pulling him across the stage after he told the newspaper editor he wanted him off the stage and <PERSON> Bass </PERSON> did n't move.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS OLIVOS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the coonskin hat fits, wear it. But while <PERSON> Fess </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, one-time `` king of the wild frontier,'' said he is pleased about <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studio </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>'' television revival, he wo n't play in the series. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who starred in the 1954-56 TV show, said Monday that the new series `` is a compliment to the man.'' `` He's durable, he's fun, he's exciting, and I hope they do him justice,'' the 64-year-old actor said. `` He stands for some very strong American values.'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who would have played an elder statesman in the remake, declined to say why he refused a role. The show is based on the life of <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, an expert frontiersman and marksman and a colonel in the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> militia. <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> also served in the <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> in the 1820s and 1830s. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said he was asked by the show's executive producer, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Blinn </PERSON>, to appear in the first two-hour segment, but declined the offer. `` It was very nice to be asked and I am a great fan of the producer,'' he said. `` However ... they're big boys and can run their own boat.'' <ORGANIZATION> Blinn </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday that <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> would appear in the first segment. The new `` <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>'' will be rotated on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s weekly `` The Magical World Of Disney'' with three other features.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FBI-Hispanics     08-16 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FBI-Hispanics,0350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hispanic FBI Agent Testifies Agency Turned Him Down for Nine
Promotions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent testified Monday he was turned down for nine promotions because he is Hispanic and that the agency kept a dossier on his wife because she started <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Paso </PERSON>'s first rape crisis center <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> supervisory special agent <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> also testified that his supervisor told him he was the first choice for one job but was turned down because he was a subject of an investigation into alleged illegal arms sales to the Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. He denied any such dealings, and said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> found no evidence to support the charge. <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> is among 311 Hispanic agents who have joined a class-action lawsuit before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Lucius </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunton </PERSON>. The lawsuit contends the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> discriminates against Hispanics in hiring, promoting and disciplinary matters. The non-jury trial is expected to last two weeks and about 100 witnesses are expected to be called. The lawsuit was filed in January 1987 by <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Matt </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, assistant agent in charge of the El Paso office. From 1979 until 1982, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> worked at the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, office _ a bureau considered an undesirable assignment by agents because of the island's high crime rate and isolation. Personnel Director <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rarity </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> testified the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> does not discriminate against Hispanics, and said Hispanic agents are transferred to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> because they are more likely than other agents to speak Spanish. <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> said he was heavily pressured into applying for a transfer from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>. After two months in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, he was transferred to isolated <LOCATION> Aguadilla </LOCATION> on the island's northwest coast. After five years there, <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> was transferred to <LOCATION> Gallup </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION> _ officially listed by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> as a hardship office because of the town's isolation and quality of life. <PERSON> Lara </PERSON> said the last time he was turned down for a promotion was after the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> became aware he was participating in the lawsuit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Sweet     08-16 0223</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Sweet,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Retired U.S. News &amp; World Report Chief Dead At 81</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BETHESDA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON>, longtime <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report executive who retired in 1982 as chairman of the magazine's board of directors, has died at age 81 Sweet, who also had served as publisher, president and chief executive officer of the news magazine, died Sunday of heart failure at a nursing home in this <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, suburb. Sweet came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1946 and joined the old <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Report </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> as its circulation manager. Two years later, when World Report merged with <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, he became circulation director of the new publication. Sweet later headed the advertising and the research and promotion departments before becoming executive vice president and publisher in 1951. He was named president of the magazine in 1958 and was promoted to board chairman and chief executive officer in 1973. He stepped down as CEO in 1981 and as board chairman the following year. During his years with the magazine, it grew from a circulation of 250,000 and revenue of $ 3.4 million to a circulation of more than 2 million and advertising revenue of more than $ 70 million a year. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>; one son, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Altos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; and one daughter, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ternes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN--Laxalt-Reagan     08-16 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Laxalt-Reagan,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Laxalt: High Praise for Presidential Friend</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> praised President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Monday as an uncomplaining gentleman who did n't lose touch with his friends once elected president <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>, longtime friend and ally of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, added during introductory comments prior to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech to the Republican National Convention that the president `` faithfully stuck to his conservative guns.'' He told the convention delegates that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> laid to rest the oft-repeated line that `` you ca n't be a nice guy and make it in this world of politics.'' <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>, who managed three <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidential campaigns and was a <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> governor when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> governed <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, also said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will leave the presidency with more friends than when he arrived in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> eight years ago. At the same time, he said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has kept his campaign promises and will continue long after he leaves the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to decry big government and high taxes. After his speech, <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> said of the president, `` <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has had more influence on the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> than any individual I've ever known.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ElvisAnniversary 1stLd-Writethru a0797 08-16 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Elvis Anniversary, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0797,0567</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elvis Fans Gather For Graveside Vigil</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 14 grafs to UPDATE with graveside vigil, quotes
and color; picks up 8th graf pvs, ``The estimates ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It took lots of drinking water and wet towels, but <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cousins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Fordin </PERSON> weathered a broiling, shadeless afternoon to be first in line Monday night for a candlelight procession past <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>'s grave. `` It's an honor to be first, and to look back and see all those candles lit is just unbelievable,'' said Ms. Cousins, 37, of <LOCATION> Winnipeg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The gates to <PERSON> Graceland </PERSON>, Presley's former <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> residence, opened at 10:30 p.m. for the procession expected to draw more than 5,000 fans marking the 11th anniversary of the singer's death. Ms. Cousins and Ms. <PERSON> Fordin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> took up their position at the Graceland gates at noon and waited through a humid afternoon with a high of 99 degrees. `` The thing is not to dehydrate,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Fordin </PERSON>, 37. `` I love <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON>. He will live forever in our hearts,'' she said. `` I bought an Elvis pillowcase and I ca n't wait to sleep on it.'' Presley died of heart disease at <LOCATION> Graceland </LOCATION> on Aug. 16, 1977, and the faithful return each year to mark the anniversary. With Presley recordings playing in the background, the fans queued up at the Graceland gates, touched candles to a torch lighted by an eternal flame and walked single file up a winding, 200-yard driveway past the singer's grave. `` It helps keep his memory alive,'' said <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Carothers </PERSON>, 37, of <LOCATION> Gnadenhutten </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, who sported an Elvis pompadour and a 6-inch-wide leather belt with dangling loops of chain. Before joining the procession, <PERSON> Carothers </PERSON> signed autographs and posed for pictures with other fans at a souvenir shopping center across the street from Graceland. `` It's just something to look back on,'' said <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarrants </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, who had her picture taken with <PERSON> Carothers </PERSON>. `` And besides, <PERSON> Mama </PERSON> said to take a lot of pictures.'' <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>, his mother, father and paternal grandmother are buried beside the swimming pool at Graceland in a small plot called `` Meditation Garden.'' The garden was covered with stands of flowers sent by fans, and many participants in the candlelight vigil carried flowers to leave at the grave. Presley originally was buried at a cemetery three miles from Graceland, but his body and his mother's were moved to the garden in October 1977. The singer's father and grandmother died after the grave site was established. No one takes a count of participants in the annual graveside procession which lasts into the early hours of Aug. 16, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Soden </PERSON>, Graceland manager. `` The estimates have always ranged from 5,000 to 10,000. I just do n't know -LRB- how many take part -RRB-, but I would say at least several thousand,'' he said. Many fans are upset this year by a recently published book called `` Is Elvis Alive?'' The book includes claims that Presley staged his death. `` It's a sad and cruel exploitation,'' <PERSON> Soden </PERSON> said. `` We've endured a lot of tasteless exploitation over the last 11 years. Graceland draws more than 600,000 tourists a year and for the past six years, <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> fans have been offered a nine-day series of events each August called `` Elvis International Tribute Week.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--GenericSpeeches Bjt   08-16 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Generic Speeches, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Speechwriters Ready To Write `Generic' Veep Speech</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE GLOVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even before <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced his choice of a running mate, aides were preparing to craft the words the mystery person will say while accepting the nomination. Speechwriters planned to write a `` generic'' speech that would be tailored at the last minute to fit the running mate, along with similar speeches to place that name in nomination. The name can be filled in later. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Malek </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s convention manager, said the draft speeches would set out broad themes the campaign wants to stress on the convention's closing night, with the running mate to polish the language later. `` By Wednesday morning ... we will have one or two writers working on a generic kind of acceptance speech which the nominee would then have to take and modify and put into his or her own style of words,'' said <PERSON> Malek </PERSON>. Organizers of the convention are orchestrating even the smallest detail in an effort to put on a polished television performance. Each speech delivered from the podium is reviewed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s speechwriters, who edit and revise it to fit that evening's chosen theme and to squeeze it into allotted time limits <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> insisted they need a head start on the running mate's Thursday speech to have the time necessary to prepare such a high-profile address `` It's a generic kind of a speech, it's a draft,'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said. `` The nominee will not learn of his or her selection until Thursday morning.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he wo n't reveal his selection until Thursday morning, only hours before that candidate must deliver the prime-time acceptance speech. In addition, organizers will be scrambling to line up another luminary to nominate the No. 2 candidate and still others to second the nomination and make the introduction. `` We've got two other, three other addresses, really, to go along with it,'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said. `` They will be also in the same sequence. We'll have one or two writers working on an acceptance speech and another working on a nominating speech. `` We wo n't start this until Wednesday,'' he said. `` They will have no clues, nor will I, on who it's going to be.'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said he would have been happier with more time for writers to work on the speech, but that it's not his decision. `` A good writer, with some general directions and general clues, can get a running start,'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said. He said organizers have n't decided yet who will give the nominating speeches, but `` we are developing some ideas of who are good speakers and could do it.'' Part of the problem, <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said, is that not only must those picked to introduce the vice presidential nominee be good speakers, they must also have some logical connection to the new candidate, or to the campaign theme that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signals with the pick. `` I think it's going to be all right, I think we have the caliber of people to do the nomination,'' he said. `` I do n't have any great trepidations about that. Obviously they could do a better job with more time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--Color Bjt   08-16 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Color, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>With This Ballot I Thee Wed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY SHULINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was n't exactly love at first sight. They are, after all, both conservatives. But what started as rhetoric blossomed into romance for <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kukuk </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> delegate, and <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Rungtranont </PERSON>, who was for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. They met following a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Republican convention, exchanged phone numbers at a delegates meeting, and courted at a <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> conference. What better place to pop the question, <PERSON> Kukak </PERSON> thought, than at the biggest shindig of them all, the Republican National Convention? The mingling of love and politics in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> seemed especially fitting to <PERSON> Kukuk </PERSON>, inspired as he was by the nation's first married vice presidential prospects, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> And so it came to pass, on a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> riverboat, with jazz music playing softly in the background and the entire <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> delegation on board, that <PERSON> Kukuk </PERSON>, a 51-year-old township supervisor, picked <PERSON> Rungtranont </PERSON>, a 45-year-old college registrar, to be his running mate. They'll be tying the knot in November, right after the election. They thought it best to wait; <LOCATION> Kukuk </LOCATION> is running for county commissioner. The morning after the big night, they strolled through the Superdome in matching Styrofoam campaign hats. There was no shortage of people taking the same walk in the same hats, but somehow, you just could n't miss them as they floated along bumping into the walls, each of them displaying a yard-and-a-half of teeth. `` When you get to be 51, you're so set in your ways,'' said <PERSON> Kukak </PERSON>, who's been single for 20 years. `` It gets harder and harder to find someone who'll put up with you.'' `` When you get to be 45, the odds of finding someone who's right for you diminish greatly,'' said his fiancee. `` I never thought I'd find the right man. She found him at a seafood restaurant just off the thruway. `` I stopped to eat on the way home from the state convention and in walked <PERSON> Al </PERSON>,'' she said. `` The place was empty except for us, and he figured out from the bumper stickers on my car where I'd been. My heart was n't going pitter-patter. But my heart was kind of curious.'' They met again at a delegates' meeting, where they arranged to attend the conservative conference. By this point, <PERSON> Rungtranont </PERSON>'s interest was no longer purely platonic `` I probably would n't have driven down to <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> if I had n't been getting interested,'' she said. After the conference, they had dinner. They talked mostly of politics. Still, there was something other than hot air in the air. On Easter, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> made the 160-mile round trip from his home in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clemens </LOCATION> to hers in <LOCATION> Caro </LOCATION>, where he met her three children. That clinched it. They have n't missed a weekend since. She had a feeling the proposal was coming. `` He dropped some pretty broad hints,'' she said. The `` hints'' included telling a reporter on board the boat that `` something big might happen tonight.'' Something did. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> took <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> to a quiet corner and presented her with a gold-and-diamond engagement ring. The rest of the delegation was off listening to the jazz musicians. `` All we heard was the flutter of the wind and the whoosh of the water,'' he said. That and the pitter-pat of their hearts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--KeanProfile     08-16 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Kean Profile,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>As Keynoter, Jersey's Kean Will Preach ``Inclusion''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McHUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was born with a silver spoon in his mouth, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> was born with a whole place setting. But despite wealth, blue blood and <ORGANIZATION> Ivy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> exterior, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> preaches a `` politics of inclusion'' unusual for his party. In promoting opportunities for the poor, workers, blacks and other minorities, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> has gotten Democrats to vote for him. The theme appears in <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s book, `` The Politics of Inclusion,'' and <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> will hit upon it in his keynote speech tonight at the Republican National Convention. Despite being a less-than-riveting speaker, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> was born to public life. He is the son of the late Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>, a 20-term House member, and his ancestors include several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s first constitutional governor. Forebear <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> was a contemporary of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who appointed him first cashier of the Bank of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, the family's influence is testified to by <ORGANIZATION> Kean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and the town of <LOCATION> Keansburg </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> first saw politics at his father's elbow. The boy commuted between the family's home in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and their estate in <LOCATION> Livingston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, where he still lives with his wife and their three children. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> attended <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, and earned a master's degree in history from <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He taught high school and later had a stint at running the family real-estate business. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> was elected to the state Assembly in 1967 and was picked its speaker in 1972 and 1973. He failed in his first bid to gain his party's gubernatorial nomination in 1977. But <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s election to the <LOCATION> Statehouse </LOCATION> four years later, and his 1985 re-election make one of the state's most dramatic political tales. In 1981, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> emerged from a field of eight would-be <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> governors to win the nomination by less than 40,000 votes. It was a landslide compared with what was to come. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> won a narrow victory in the general election over Democratic Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, eking out a win by 1,677 votes. <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> called for a recount, and both candidates set up transition teams in preparation for taking office. Weeks later, the recounted results confirmed <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s election by 1,797 votes, the smallest margin in state history. Four years later, voters retained <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> by the biggest-ever margin, with 70 percent of the vote and majorities in all but three of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s 567 municipalities. To accomplish the win, one aide said, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> attempted to tread every inch and shake every hand in his small but diverse state. As nervous aides fidgeted, the governor kept motorcades and planes waiting while stopping to answer every question his constant press following could come up with. With a style too awkward to be bogus, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> convinced voters he was for real. One staff members recalls a night when the governor tried to share a beer with his staff. But when the six-pack was passed, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> could n't figure out the screw-top bottles. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>, 53, has repeatedly said his programs are aimed at creating opportunity both for business owners and workers, as well as the poor. It's a political theme not unlike that of Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> has concentrated on the `` philosophy and history of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ a philosophy that allows Republicans to go beyond the country clubs and the suburbs,'' as he wrote in his book. Though mentioned as a possible <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> running mate, the moderate <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> has few admirers on the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s far right. While loyal to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the governor breaks often and openly with the White House. Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, one of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s most conservative members, has threatened to walk out on <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s speech because of the governor's ideologically impure stance on abortion. Though personally opposed, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> does not back a constitutional ban. Praise for <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> has come from unexpected places: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, joking in 1986, said that, `` He's the best Democrat in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Haig 1stLd-Writethru a0750 08-16 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Haig, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0750,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Haig Calls Dukakis ``Diminutive Clerk,'' Bush Seeks Distance</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: CORRECTS spelling of Diminutive in overline and 1st graf</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MIKE GLOVER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former presidential candidate <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> on Monday called <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a `` diminutive clerk'' in a sharp and personal convention speech that drew an immediate disclaimer for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign. When <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s presidential star faded early, he declared his support for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. In his convention speech Monday, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> endorsed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and then, despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s efforts to dissuade him, delivered a strong attack against <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> referred to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a `` diminutive clerk from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> also compared the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to a bat `` flying erratically for brief periods at low levels and hanging upside down for extended periods in dark, damp caves up to its navel in guano.'' In contrast, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> represented `` safe and progressive change, safe in that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will build on the solid accomplishments of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> presidency.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> workers were clearly unhappy with the tenor of <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s remarks `` We do n't think that was an appropriate sequence of words,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> convention manager <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Malek </PERSON>. `` That was <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s choice, it was n't ours. <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said organizers of the convention, who carefully review every word spoken from the podium, first saw <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s speech nearly a week ago and tried to convince him to tone down the rhetoric. `` We definitely told him we did not think that was a good thing to do,'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said. `` At one point, I thought he agreed with us but then he slept on it and decided it was what he wanted to do.'' In orchestrating this week's convention, GOP leaders have carefully chosen a theme for each night, and have insisted they want to stay away from personal assaults on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Monday night's theme was to highlight the successes of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration <PERSON> Malek </PERSON>'s criticism was echoed in somewhat milder terms by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> argued that there's a time and a place for harsh assaults and Monday's convention speech was neither. `` I do n't look upon that as the kind of campaign we would wage,'' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> said. `` Those were his words and his choice,'' <PERSON> Malek </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--ElizabethDole     08-16 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Elizabeth Dole,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mrs. Dole Acknowledges Gender Gap, Asks Women To Have Open Mind</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, confronting <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s gender gap with women voters, is urging women to `` have an open mind'' and work with the party for changes in child care and other matters affecting the family One of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s potential running mates, Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> was cheered as she spoke to the Republican National Convention on Monday night about the `` freedom'' women had achieved through job programs during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. `` Good jobs, not bad jobs. Real work, not make work. That's our freedom. Are we going to let them take it away?'' she asked, as the convention hall responded with a resounding `` No!'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> dealt head-on with one of the most troubling problems for the Republicans this year: polls show that female voters are disproportionately supporting Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` Today's strong economy means stronger families, and we affirm the woman who chooses to work in the home,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who spent seven years working in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, including four years as secretary of transportation. `` But our strong economy has also provided needed jobs for millions of women,'' she said, `` and let me say to the women of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: I respect the fact that some of you have questions. I also ask you to have an open mind.'' She said that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s `` incredible jobs machine'' has created more jobs for Americans, and two-thirds of the 17 million new jobs created since 1982 went to women. `` I ask you, women of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, not just to support us. ... Work with us to change what needs to be changed,'' she said. `` The future belongs to our children, and child care is one of those changes.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has endorsed the concept of the $ 2.5 billion `` better child bill'' now pending in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which would provide aid and impose new regulations for child care programs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants to give $ 2.2 billion in tax credits to families earning less than $ 20,000 a year to help them pay for child care in any setting they wish. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` wants to march our kids lock step to a government institution where <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> will set all the rules ... but people work part-time, full-time, night shift, day shift, swing shift. One size does not fit all,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has five children and 10 grandchildren, believes `` the parents should choose,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. She said he will `` give <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> parents what they want _ child care supervised by people who share their values: in a community-based setting, a relative's or neighbor's home, a church-sponsored center, or by the mother or father who works full-time at home. Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> ridiculed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for seeking `` to paint over his liberal policies with pretty rhetoric.'' `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' convention speech was just like the Democrat platform, hedging on defense, hedging on taxes, hedging on spending. We're not running against -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. We're running against <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hedges </PERSON>,'' she said, in a play on words with the name of a cigarette brand.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880816-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-16-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--LongShots     08-16 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Long Shots,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Longshot GOP Senate Candidates Profess Optimism</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
