<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Spain-Britain     10-18 0329</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spain-Britain,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Queen in Spain On First Visit Ever By British Monarch</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MADRID, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> paid homage to Spanish war dead, addressed parliament and accepted the keys to the capital Tuesday during a busy second day of her visit to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, the first ever by a reigning <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> monarch. The queen, in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> on a five-day visit, told a joint session of parliament that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> would play important roles in the future development of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. She praised <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> for 10 years of democracy following nearly four decades under the authoritarian regime of Gen. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>. In her speech, which received a standing ovation, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> did not mention the British colony of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>, the only major political dispute between the two countries. On Monday night, both the British monarch and her third cousin and Spanish host, King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>, said they believed the two countries would eventually resolve their differences over the colony that guards the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> entrance to the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> seeks sovereignty over <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>, which it ceded to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> by treaty in 1713 after losing the War of Spanish Succession. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has said <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> will remain British unless its 30,000 inhabitants decide otherwise. Earlier Tuesday a small but enthusiastic crowd waving <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> flags applauded as the queen and her husband, the Duke of <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>, placed a laurel wreath at a memorial to `` those who gave their lives for <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> then went to City Hall to accept the keys to <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> from Mayor <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Barranco </PERSON>. The visit brought normally heavy traffic in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> to a standstill as police blocked off streets along the motorcade's route The queen's visit is to include trips to <ORGANIZATION> Barcelona </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Seville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Escorial </LOCATION>, a palace built in the foothills of the <LOCATION> Guadarrama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> by King <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. The royal couple were also to spend two days on a private visit with <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Majorca </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OfficersKilled     10-18 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Officers Killed,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Policemen Killed In Separate Shootings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY NEUMEISTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An undercover policeman was shot and killed during a drug buy and a patrolman was slain while responding to a medical emergency in separate incidents Tuesday night, police said. The undercover officer was shot in the head and chest at 7:11 p.m. as he and another undercover officer tried to buy a gram of cocaine at an apartment just west of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. In a gunfight that followed, a drug suspect was killed, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> told a news conference. A second suspect was arrested as he fled the building and a third eluded police. The second officer was shot in the chest and stomach at 9:45 p.m. as he and his partner were getting out of their patrol car in <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> while responding to a medical emergency, said Officer <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Conde </LOCATION>, a police spokeswoman. Both of the officers died at hospitals, said Sgt. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>, a police spokesman. The dead policemen's identities were not released. In the first shooting, two men escorted the officers to the apartment to buy drugs from a third man, and one of the three accused the officers of being undercover police, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. One of the three pulled out a .357 - caliber handgun and shot the After the gunfight that ensued, the other officer ran into the street and alerted backup police. The officer slain in the drug case was 26 years old and had been a member of the force since 1984, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who accompanied <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> at the news conference, called the shooting `` an enormous tragedy. The partner -LRB- is -RRB- terribly shaken. It's really overwhelming.'' The officers had been attempting to carry out a buy-and-bust raid, in which police purchase drugs from suspects, then arrest them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CubanPrisoners 1st a0819 10-18 0057</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuban Prisoners, 1st, a0819,0056</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Prisoners Released From Cuban Jail</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Adds AP logo</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SANDRA WALEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three Cuban prisoners, jailed at least 20 years each for their political beliefs, arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Tuesday after they were released from a <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> prison.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Dozens of, 2nd graf</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMEConvention     10-18 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Convention,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>APME President Urges Editors: Fight Campaign Attempts To Manage
News</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEFAN FATSIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newspapers must fight attempts by presidential campaigns to orchestrate the news in hopes of getting good television coverage, says the president of the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors association. `` The most important journalism in this campaign is being delivered by the reporters who are going in after the candidates have been there and are talking to voters about impressions of the candidates and about the real problems of their regions,'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Giles </PERSON>, vice president and executive editor of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday, the first day of its annual convention. He told the newspaper editors: ` My premise is that newspaper editors are allowing television news directors and the campaign strategists for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to influence their Page 1 agendas.'' `` As a result,'' he added, `` we are the targets of criticism about biased or frivolous coverage that is more appropriately the fault of television.'' <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> suggested newspapers rely on wire services for much of the day-to-day campaign coverage, and concentrate on providing readers with `` issues stories.'' On the wide perception that the current campaign has been especially negative, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> vice president and executive editor, said contests in the 1960s, such as the Goldwater-Johnson race in 1964, were no less strident or less shaped by image-makers. `` We, meaning the people who report the campaign, have been telling the voters this is a campaign of sound bites, crafted by handlers and interpreted by spin-control specialists,'' he said. `` Those buzzwords make it sound as though these were all 1988 creations. I do n't think there's anything unique about it.'' More than 600 editors from around the country are attending the week-long annual convention. The AP, the largest newsgathering organization in the world, serves 1,467 daily newspapers. In his address to the editors, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President and General Manager <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> said the wire service is in the midst of its most extensive modernization in its photography, financial and technical delivery services. `` As our periodic announcements may have suggested to you, we are in the midst of the most thorough and concentrated rebuilding and modernizing of AP services that has been attempted in modern times,'' <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> said. Editors also heard presentations from <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> editors on developments in news and photography distribution, and discussions of changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and its press. <PERSON> Stanislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Menshikov </PERSON>, a Soviet economist who collaborated with <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> economist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> on a book about the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, told the editors that economic change is meeting some resistance from the Soviet bureaucracy. `` They still control most of the economy and make economic change a fiction and not a fact,'' <PERSON> Menshikov </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fears of communism and Soviet fears of capitalism have abated in recent years. `` We live in a time when both of those fears have evaporated, except on the paranoiac right,'' he said. At a session on the Soviet press, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Shalnev </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>, said Soviet newspapers reacted to greater press freedom with more negative stories about their country and more positive ones on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. He cited an `` upsurge in the inclination to write as many negative things as we could find out'' and said the boundaries on what is acceptable still are being defined. At a panel discussion on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyhan </PERSON>, political columnist for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>, advised the visiting editors to `` watch where you walk and how you drive.'' `` Driving is the most dangerous thing you can do in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, even more than taking advice from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Judson </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON>, editor of <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> magazine, said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s greatest export is its conscience `` The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> conscience never kept anyone from doing anything, but it does keep you from enjoying it,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writehru a0740 10-18 0980</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writehru, a0740,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Fighting Hard, Says Front-Running Bush Has ``No
Convictions''</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS one graf after 20th pvs, Among the..., to give report
on Dukakis request to purchase 30 minutes of air time.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> lashed at front-running <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a man with `` no convictions, no ideas and no plans'' Tuesday and blamed Republican policies for last year's stock market plunge. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tried to contain supporters' enthusiasm over polls showing him building a large lead. `` We're not going to lighten up,'' the Republican presidential nominee said while campaigning in <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. `` No votes can be taken for granted and I'm not taking any votes for granted. I will continue to campaign as an underdog.'' There was no question who was the real underdog _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. But he drew enthusiastic crowds as he campaigned through <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> with aides battling the growing perception that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had taken an insurmountable lead with just three weeks until the election. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> delivered a strongly worded response to the Republicans, accusing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of running `` one of the most outrageous displays of negative campaigning ever seen in the history of national politics.'' The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor sharpened his language as he focused on economic issues and portrayed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as the candidate of the wealthy. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cares about he people on Easy Street,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` I care about the people on Main Street. He's on their side. I'm on your side.'' `` <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duke </PERSON>,'' chanted the crowds. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also brought up the huge stock-market drop that occurred one year ago Wednesday. `` The trade deficit had soared,'' he said. `` Republican policies of borrow and spend and borrow and spend had done the damage.'' He pledged to eliminate the $ 150 billion trade deficit in four years by reducing the budget deficit, increasing foreign trade, investing in education and putting more emphasis on research. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would n't talk about his plans. `` He's got the flags and balloons, but no convictions, no ideas and no plans,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. The Democrat's aides disputed an <ORGANIZATION> NBC-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll showing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with a 17-point lead, his largest of the campaign. They pointed instead to other polls indicating about half that margin. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, trying to avoid overconfidence, campaigned in <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, and invoked the memory of <ORGANIZATION> Winston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churchill </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Westminster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> where <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> delivered his 1946 `` iron curtain'' speech warning of Soviet expansionism in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the demarcation between East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is now `` a rusting curtain.'' He said that if elected he would be wary of Soviet intentions, despite what he called more enlightened leadership under <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` Now is not the time to abandon realism about what moves the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign began airing tough new television commercials that ridicule <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and say he has `` opposed virtually every defense system we developed.'' The ad uses videotape of the helmeted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the turret of an M-1 tank, a ride the Democrat took in September in an attempt to show toughness on defense issues _ but which critics said made him look silly. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Voles </PERSON> called the ad `` more distortions from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign.'' The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign dispatched dozens of workers from his national headquarters in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> into the field, along with more than 1,300 new volunteers from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The campaign said 60 percent of the headquarters staff was being assigned to campaign duties in target states. Among the other volunteers are students, congressional aides and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorneys taking leaves for the final three weeks of the campaign. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday without attribution that in addition the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign has requested time from <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> for five 30-minute programs and hopes to air the shows at the same time on each network. The newspaper said the plan would cost about $ 5 million. Public polls ranged from bad to worse for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, though his aides pointed to what they said was a new <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> poll putting the gap at 9 points. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Winokur </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> would release a poll Wednesday but declined to comment on its results in advance. Two other surveys found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leads of about that size. One, of 1,002 registered voters polled Saturday through Monday, put the race at 49-39; another, of 1,201 likely voters Friday through Monday, put it at 49-40. Both were ongoing tracking polls _ in which the newest day's result is added to several days being covered and the oldest day's is dropped _ done by <ORGANIZATION> KRC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> @ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, They had three-point error margins. Republican vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> traveled by bus caravan through small <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> towns, accompanied by Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he felt `` a special obligation ... to help <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> define the needs of a new generation of Americans, their challenges, their responses.'' `` With <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> you get experience,'' the 41-year-old <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` With me you get the future, the future of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, denounced <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as `` an utterly vicious onslaught of distortion and character assassination.'' He said the Democrats have `` been a little too flabbergasted sometimes to make a proper response.'' `` They do n't seem to mind if what they say is untrue,'' he said. `` They do n't seem to worry if it's misleading. They do n't seem to care that what they do is downright mean. If it sounds good, say it. If it sells, package it. If it looks good, nominate it.'' Democrat <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> discounted suggestions he has not worked hard enough for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, his former rival for the Democratic nominamtion. `` No Democrat since <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> has traveled more miles, spoken to more people and registered more Democrats for the ticket than I have,'' the Democratic runnerup said in a telephone interview from his <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Grenada-Locusts     10-18 0234</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grenada-Locusts,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Locusts Sighted In Eastern Caribbean</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISTER HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. GEORGES, Grenada (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Insects believed to be African locusts have been discovered in <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> and are a threat to the island's agriculture, an agricultural official says. `` We are now making an intensive investigation as to the extent of the infestation,'' said a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. `` We can not say anymore now but, if what we fear is true, there is a serious threat to the agricultural industry.'' The first sighting was made on Thursday. Since then there have been several reports of sightings of the insects on the island's east coast, said the official who spoke on condition of anonymity A specimen of the insect at the Pest Control office of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> is about three inches long. The spokesman said it is not known how the insects came to <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, though he said they are believed to have been `` blown across from <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' They have also been sighted on the neighboring island of <LOCATION> Carriacou </LOCATION>. Agricultural officials in <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> are studying the insects to determine their origin. The locusts appeared in large numbers on the island following heavy rains last week. The locusts have been seen flying around <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> but so far no swarm has been seen. There are unconfirmed reports of sightings also in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vincent </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMECitations     10-18 1316</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Citations,1676</SECOND>
<HEAD>APME Recognizes 288 Papers, Stations For Contributions</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-APME Awards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Associated Press Managing Editors association has awarded 288 citations to newspapers and broadcast stations for outstanding contributions to the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> report. The awards were presented Tuesday by <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>, metro editor of The <LOCATION> Flint </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, at the annual APME convention. The <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> is made up of managing editors and other news executives of the 1,463 member newspapers of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest newsgathering organization The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> is a cooperative agency whose members provide coverage of news in their areas for distribution through AP bureaus in their states. The citations are in three categories _ news, newsphoto and news-newsphoto. Newspapers and broadcast stations cited in each category are:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>News Citations</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Antioch </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Ledger Ashland -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- WAFB-TV <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- WBRZ-TV Beaufort -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette Beaver -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Beaver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Times </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belleville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Democrat <PERSON> Benton </PERSON> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Courier Bloomington -LRB- Ind. -RRB- <PERSON> Herald-Telephone </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowie </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- KBAN Radio <LOCATION> Bradenton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Butte -LRB- Mont. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KBOW-KOPR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canton </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Repository Casper -LRB- <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. -RRB- Star-Tribune Catskill -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Mail Chillicothe -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Gazette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Enquirer <LOCATION> Clarksville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KLYR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> -RRB- Press Columbus -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Dispatch <LOCATION> Coshocton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune Deadwood -LRB- S.D. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KSQY </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Decatur </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Dispatch <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KDAL Radio <LOCATION> Durango </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dorado </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> News-Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KAMA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emporia </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- KVOE-AM Erie -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning News Erie -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Times <LOCATION> Escanaba </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Press Exeter -LRB- <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION> -RRB- WERZ Fargo -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- KFGO Fargo -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- WDAY-AM <LOCATION> Fergus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KBRF AM @ FM <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Sentinel and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myers </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> News-Press </PERSON> <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> Record Fremont -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- KJEO-TV Gary -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Post-Tribune <LOCATION> Gettysburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KLTZ-KLAN Radio Grand Rapids -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KNNS Radio Grand Rapids -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press Greenwood -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Commonwealth <PERSON> Harlan </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Enterprise <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Patriot-News <LOCATION> Hattiesburg </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- American <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KTVH-TV <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Sun-Tattler </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Daily News Kankakee -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charles </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- American Press Laurel -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Leader-Call <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News Mansfield -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News Journal <PERSON> Marianna </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Floridan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Marshfield -LRB- Mo. -RRB- KMRF-AM Meridian -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Star <LOCATION> Middlesboro </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Herald-Record <LOCATION> Minot </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- KMOT-TV Mountain Home -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Baxter Bulletin Natchez -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Democrat <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- Neb. -RRB- News-Press New Bedford -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Standard-Times <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Times-Herald Norman -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Transcript <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal Record <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> KOMA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Radio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- WKY Radio <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Report <LOCATION> Osakis </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KBHL-FM <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Radio WCAU-AM <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- KFYI <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- KOY <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Capital Journal <LOCATION> Ponca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Sunday Telegram <LOCATION> Potsdam </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WPDM <LOCATION> Poughkeepsie </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WKIP Prescott -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Courier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KTOQ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redlands </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Facts Reno -LRB- <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> KBUL </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Radio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press-Enterprise <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WNYR @ WEZO <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Union <LOCATION> Roseville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press-Tribune <LOCATION> Russellville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KARV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saginaw </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WSGW-AM <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Public </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Radio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> News-Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Tribune Sharon -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald Shreveport -LRB- La. -RRB- KWKH Shreveport -LRB- La. -RRB- Journal Sidney -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KSOO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sioux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- KXRB Radio <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- KVML @ KZSQ South Bend -LRB- Ind. -RRB- WSBT-TV <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tahoe </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- KOWL <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> -LRB- Mo. -RRB- KTTS-AM @ FM <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Democrat Tarentum -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News-Dispatch </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Blade Torrance -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Breeze </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Star </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Uniontown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Standard <LOCATION> Urbana </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Citizen <LOCATION> Vacaville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Reporter <LOCATION> Visalia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Delta Warren -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Record-Herald West Memphis -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Evening Times <LOCATION> Williamsport </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Gazette <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- KFDI-AM @ FM <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> -LRB- Del. -RRB- Morning News Winona -LRB- Minn. -RRB- Daily News Winona -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KWNO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Neb. -RRB- News-Times <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Vindicator </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Newsphoto Citations</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Biddeford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal Tribune Bowling Green -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News Corinth -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Daily Corinthian <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Press <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Fargo -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- Forum Flagstaff -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Sentinel <LOCATION> Greeley </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -RRB- Advertiser <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Bulletin <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- Mo. -RRB- Times Little Rock -LRB- Ark. -RRB- <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Democrat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Lowell -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Sun <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Tribune <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle <LOCATION> Norristown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Journal-Bulletin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Journal <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Times-Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salinas </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Californian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Tribune </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Tribune </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Union <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Examiner <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle Shreveport -LRB- La. -RRB- Times Sioux Falls -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Argus Leader <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Union-News <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> -LRB- Mo. -RRB- News-Leader <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Citizen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Star-Free </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Leader York -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Record
</TEXT>
<HEAD>News and Newsphoto Citations</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Beacon Journal <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> -LRB- Ore. -RRB- Democrat-Herald <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Daily Town Talk Allentown -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning Call Annapolis -LRB- Md. -RRB- Capital <LOCATION> Ardmore </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Ardmoreite <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Californian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> -LRB- Md. -RRB- Sun Baltimore -LRB- Md. -RRB- Evening Sun Bangor -LRB- <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Batesville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Guard Baton Rouge -LRB- La. -RRB- Morning Advocate and State Times Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Gazette Biloxi-Gulfport -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Sun Herald <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Daily Chronicle <LOCATION> Brainerd </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Dispatch <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald Butte -LRB- Mont. -RRB- <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Standard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News and <PERSON> Courier </PERSON> and The Evening Post Charlotte -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Observer <LOCATION> Charlottesville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Progress <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Times <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Post Cleveland -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer Columbus -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Telegram <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning News Dayton -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> News-Journal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Centro </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Imperial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elyria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle-Telegram <LOCATION> Emporia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette Enid -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning News & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evansville </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Courier <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times and <LOCATION> Observer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Journal-Gazette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fostoria </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Review Times <LOCATION> Fredericksburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Lance-Star <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Piedmont </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Times <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News Helena -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Independent Record <LOCATION> Hopkinsville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Era </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hyannis </LOCATION> -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Cape Cod Times <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> -RRB- Post-Register Independence -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Reporter <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- News <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Star Jackson -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Clarion-Ledger <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Times-Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Journal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Johnstown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune-Democrat <LOCATION> Kalispell </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lafayette </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Journal and Courier Lakeland -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Ledger </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> -RRB- Review-Journal <LOCATION> Lawton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Constitution and Morning Press <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Leader <LOCATION> Lompoc </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record <LOCATION> Lorain </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Journal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald Examiner <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Courier-Journal <LOCATION> Lynchburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- News & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massillon </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Evening Independent <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Today </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Tribune </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Herald </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- <LOCATION> Missoulian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Herald </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myrtle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bern </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Journal <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Times-Picayune <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Virginian-Pilot <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Ledger-Star <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Banner <PERSON> Ogden </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -RRB- Standard-Examiner <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sentinel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Owatonna </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- People's Press <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Tribune <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Journal <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal Star <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Post-Gazette <LOCATION> Pottsville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Republican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Journal Reading -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Eagle and Times Redding -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record Searchlight <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Leader <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Dispatch <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times & amp; World-News <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Post-Bulletin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald <LOCATION> Russellville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Courier Democrat <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Deseret </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Express-News <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sentinel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bend </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Tribune St. Cloud -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Stillwater </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- NewsPress Sumter -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Item <LOCATION> Thomasville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Tribune </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- World <LOCATION> Tuscaloosa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> -RRB- News <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Evening Post Wailuku, <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Costa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Post </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Willoughby </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Herald <PERSON> Woodbridge </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zanesville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Recorder
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RobberyHostage 1stLd-Writethru a0401 10-18 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Robbery Hostage, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0401,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robber Takes Bank Manager Hostage</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with four grafs to UPDATE with manager freed. Picks up
4th graf pvs, `A nearby...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>READING, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A gunman robbed a bank Tuesday, kidnapped the bank manager and drove off in the manager's car, only to be cornered by a police roadblock on an interstate, authorities said. The manager, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>, 61, was freed about seven hours after police closed Interstate 176, a spur from Interstate 76 leading to Reading, said <PERSON> Terrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, a police communications operator. Negotiations with the gunmman continued late Tuesday, Mrs. <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> said. A state police SWAT team and an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> tactical team arrived at the scene six hours after the standoff began about 10 miles south of this southeast <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> city, said a <LOCATION> Berks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> dispatch supervisor who declined to give her name. A nearby access road was closed because traffic seemed to startle the gunman, the supervisor said. The suspect's brother was brought to the scene in an effort to persuade him to surrender, but the robber asked his brother to leave, said the supervisor. Police asked the suspect to exchange the bank manager for an officer, but he turned the offer down, authorities said. The man was armed with a 9mm pistol, said <ORGANIZATION> Amity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Township </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Eschbach </PERSON>, who questioned several witnesses to the robbery. The robber, identified by police only as a 29-year-old from the <LOCATION> Pottstown </LOCATION> area, took the manager hostage at 4 p.m. at the <ORGANIZATION> Meridian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Amity </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, according to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent who spoke on condition of anonymity. Police believe less than $ 5,000 was taken, said the <LOCATION> Berks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> supervisor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:DeadlyWriters     10-18 0806</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Deadly Writers,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Murders Are Way of Life for These Authors</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RONALD POWERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>'s book is about a hippie-like New Age guru who allegedly killed his girlfriend and stuffed her in a trunk. <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>'s book is about a professor who battered his prostitute-mistress. When this husband and wife dine at night, does mayhem mingle with the meatloaf? Not necessarily, they say. `` It would be wrong to suggest -LRB- our conversations -RRB- were excessively morbid. They do n't tend to be morose,'' says <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> quickly adds, `` We could swap forensic stories and I could tell him who he should talk to in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>.'' For three years, <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>, 37, and <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>, 40, worked separately but simultaneously on these two accounts of similarly repulsive crimes. The experience of both writing at the same time turned out quite well, <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> said during a recent interview at the couple's Fifth Avenue apartment, a well-lighted, book-filled home In his book _ `` The Unicorn's Secret: Murder in the Age of Aquarius,'' to be published this month by <ORGANIZATION> Prentice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> examined the bizarre case of <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>'s enigmatic peace-and-love freak and parapsychology crusader who was charged in 1979 with killing his girlfriend, <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Maddux </PERSON> Eighteen months after <PERSON> Maddux </PERSON> was last seen alive, her decomposed, mummified body was found in a locked trunk in their apartment. <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON>, known about town as `` The Unicorn,'' shrugged off the allegations and accused the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and others of planting evidence in his home, but he skipped bail before trial. He remains a fugitive, likely living in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>'s book, `` Missing Beauty,'' published in June by <PERSON> W.W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON>, is the story of what led <ORGANIZATION> Tufts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> medical researcher <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> in 1983 to smash the skull of <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON>, the high-priced <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> prostitute with whom he'd fallen insanely in love. Even though the essentials of the stories are similar _ both victims were women trying to extract themselves from relationships with obsessively possessive men _ the two men could not be more unalike. The Unicorn was a brilliant and charismatic bear of a figure, a ladies' man extraordinaire and counterculture oddball given to such benign weirdness as answering his door stark naked. Though he dressed in a dashiki and dirty jeans, sported a full beard and shoulder-length hair and frequently smelled bad, <PERSON> Einhorn </PERSON> established an incredible global network of scientists, corporate sponsors and wealthy benefactors. `` Ira was the epitome of the guy who worked in fringe circles, was antiestablishment and still looked like a hippie when he was almost 40,'' says <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> was this traditional, respected man.'' Superficially, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> did appear to lead a normal life: He was a solidly middle-class family man with three children, an eminent medical school professor and acknowledged expert in cell culture. `` Everything about him was so normal, so stultifyingly normal. ... He was a man who one would never imagine could have gotten himself into a situation like this,'' <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> said. But then there was that other side, sufficiently dark, private and perverse to fascinate the Pulitzer Prize-winning reporter for four years. Carpenter received the award in 1981 for her crime coverage for The Village Voice. Here was `` a scientist who had been embezzling research funds to support a mistress _ who happened to be a hooker. He was living a double life ... That's what hooked me,'' she said. Researching her book, <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> spent weeks walking the streets and hanging out in the bars and strip joints of the Combat Zone, the netherworld that is <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s red-light district, talking to bartenders, pimps, whores and strippers who knew <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>' young victim. `` That was very difficult for me. I'm not a street person and never dared pose as one,'' she said. While <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> was exploring the gamy depths, <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> was having anxieties of his own as he waited for her nightly call from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, assuring him that she was safe. `` I was n't happy about it, but this is what <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> does. It's important for her to do the story right,'' <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> said `` Missing Beauty'' is <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>'s first book, but she was already a respected master of crime stories: She had reported on the killings of Playmate <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stratton </PERSON> and politician <PERSON> Allard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowenstein </PERSON>. `` The Unicorn's Secret'' is <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>'s first major excursion into the genre; his other book, `` Hackers,'' is about the personal computer revolution. <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> is a free-lance writer and contributing editor for Rolling Stone. So, what is the allure of the macabre? Says Levy: `` When something happens it gives you a window into the way people live, the way people are. ... It's like an archaeological dig. Like if someone unearths a civilization frozen by a volcano or something. That's what a murder does _ it freezes details of our lives.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ScuttlingCars     10-18 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scuttling Cars,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Portugal To Sink Grounded Ship and 5,400 Cars in Atlantic</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TONY SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LISBON, Portugal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> will send a new but wrecked ship and its cargo of 5,400 Japanese cars to the bottom of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, whatever the outrage of ecologists, because `` no practical alternative is available.'' That was the comment of Adm. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> <PERSON> Horta </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Portuguese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> against <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pollution </ORGANIZATION>, after returning last week from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where he reported on the case to the Convention on the Prevention of Marine Pollution by Dumping. The 58,000-ton Reijin ran aground April 27 in shallow water off the northern city of <LOCATION> Oporto </LOCATION>, the first stop on its maiden voyage from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. One sailor was killed. <ORGANIZATION> Emerald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipholding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SA </ORGANIZATION>, a Japanese-owned Panamanian company to which the ship belongs, said July 13 the Reijin was not recoverable and assumed responsibility for the wreck's removal. The new cars must be scuttled because they could be unsafe to drive. <PERSON> Horta </PERSON> said the company insisted on sinking the ship and its $ 100-million cargo at sea and threatened to abandon the wreck if <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> refused to cooperate. That would leave the <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> with disposal project costing millions of dollars. Environmentalists in <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> and elsewhere say the 173 tons of copper and lead, 115 tons of paint, 28 tons of oil and more than 1,000 tons of rubber, plastic and textiles could seriously damage marine life. Salvage workers are dismantling the Reijin's top decks and ferrying the scrap metal and some cars ashore. The rest of the ship will be refloated, towed out and sunk in at least 6,000 feet of water, <PERSON> Horta </PERSON> said in an interview. Cars now being unloaded will be dumped 40 miles off the coast, and the wreck, with the remaining cargo, will be scuttled 150 miles out by mid-November, the admiral said. The <ORGANIZATION> Robin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, an ecology group based in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, has called the decision `` an ecological crime'' and further criticism has come from the <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION> Convention, which monitors sea pollution. Portuguese environmentalists want action from the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, of which <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> has been a member since Jan. 1, 1986. `` It is indeed a crime, dangerous to the whole world, not just to <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, a German lecturer at <LOCATION> Oporto </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biomedical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview. `` Any ecology schoolbook will tell you that one liter of oil pollutes one million liters of water.'' Marine authorities feel they have no choice. If the government tried to salvage the wreck, it not only would have to pay the estimated cost of $ 15 million but might also face claims from Japanese automakers contending that their images were tarnished by the sale of potentially unsafe cars to bargain-hunters. `` We could not take over the task of removing the ship ourselves because we did not have the technical, financial or even legal means to do so before the autumn bad weather,'' <PERSON> Horta </PERSON> said. Coast guard officials say the first storm of the winter season probably would destroy the grounded vessel and spread the wreckage in Portuguese coastal waters. So, the admiral said, `` we consider the plan to dump at sea the lesser evil.'' Removal of another ship _ the <LOCATION> Tollan </LOCATION>, grounded in the Tagus estuary off <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION> in 1980 _ cost the government more than $ 1.4 million and officials want to avoid a far larger bill for the Reijin. Owners are required by <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> law to remove wrecks declared to be dangerous, but <PERSON> Horta </PERSON> said: `` It is, unfortunately, well-known that this obligation very often can not be enforced.'' Shipping companies that operate under the Panamanian flag of convenience often have little capital other than their vessels. <PERSON> Horta </PERSON> said the <PERSON> Reijin </PERSON> apparently was the only valuable asset of <ORGANIZATION> Emerald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipholding </ORGANIZATION>. Insurers are reluctant to talk about the case, but one based in <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION>, speaking privately, said he was `` mystified that such a modern, well-equipped ship could sink in shallow waters after making a long, tough voyage from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.'' One theory is that the computerized self-leveling system overreacted when about 200 cars were unloaded in <LOCATION> Oporto </LOCATION> and the crew was unable to adjust it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CampusRacism     10-18 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campus Racism,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Outbreaks Of Racial Insults Reported As Anniversary Of Clash
Nears</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Contents of 10th graf bgng ``At Stanford'' may be offensive
to readers.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New outbreaks of racial insults were reported at <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> as the second anniversary neared of a post-World Series brawl at the state school that injured 10 people. At <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Maples </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> sent a memo to the school's 2,722 undergraduates last week saying that notes with racial slurs had been slipped under a student's door and tacked onto a bulletin board. A separate memo from the Office of Student Affairs said other students had received four similar notes since mid-September. The school said an investigation was under way. A <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> administrator said he was looking into reports of racial slurs made over walkie-talkies two weeks ago, on a frequency reserved for foremen and supervisors of the <ORGANIZATION> Physical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on the <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> campus of 26,650 students. `` I've been working as dispatcher here 13 years and I've never heard anything like that,'' said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hmieleski </PERSON>, the radio dispatcher on duty at the time. `` You hear people joking around sometimes and you take it for that, but it was the tone of the voice. You could tell it was no joke.'' <PERSON> Hmieleski </PERSON> said he was n't certain who made the remarks. He said he and other workers reported them to their department's director, who said he expects to make his findings public later this week. There have been recent racial incidents at other schools in the nation. Six <ORGANIZATION> DePauw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> fraternities and sororities apologized for a `` ghetto party'' with decorations that included graffiti slurs against black and other minorities. Members of the six organizations at the <LOCATION> Greencastle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, campus staged a candlelight vigil Monday night and marched from the <LOCATION> Alpha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Omega </LOCATION> house, where the party was held Friday night, to the Association for Afro-American Students office. Members of the two groups conferred, shook hands and embraced. At <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, officials promised to look into two racist incidents in recent weeks. Last Friday, a poster at the predominantly black fraternity house <PERSON> Ujamaa </PERSON> was discovered emblazoned with the word `` niggers.'' Two weeks earlier a flier depicting <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON> as brown-skinned, with wild, curly hair, big lips and red eyes was left outside the room of a black freshman from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The reports of incidents at the western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> schools came as the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> prepared for a weeklong commemoration of a fight between white <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> fans and black <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> fans after the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> won the final game of the World Series on Oct. 27, 1986. Soon after the fight, racial epithets were found spray-painted on steps at <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. A year later, two black administrators and the first black woman to earn tenure at <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> resigned from their posts, saying the school had shut minorities out of decision making. Another fight between blacks and whites at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> last February sparked a six-day building takeover by more than 100 minority students protesting racial violence and what they said was a low minority enrollment. At least 8 percent of undergraduates at the school last year were minorities. The six students accused of fighting last winter are scheduled to appear in <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION> for a hearing Oct. 27. To mark the anniversary, the university plans a week of racism-awareness events beginning Friday. They include `` Hands Across UMass,'' a chain of students linking hands around the campus, and a lecture by civil rights activist and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> unveiled its plan to combat racism in a report released last week that, among other things, calls for a 20 percent minority faculty by mid-1999 and gives the college until 1995 to admit a first-year class with the same percentage of minority students as the population of high school graduates. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Debra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said 19 percent of this year's freshman class and 13.5 percent of the total student population are minorities A committee of <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> faculty, trustees, administrators and students came up with the plan after 200 students marched on the president's house in April with a list of grievances, including demands to be included in the hiring of an affirmative action officer. `` It's a good plan, especially when one considers it's coming in to fill a complete vacuum,'' said <PERSON> Wambui </PERSON> <PERSON> Mwangi </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PurgatoryAmendments     10-18 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Purgatory Amendments,720</SECOND>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON TODAY: ``Sorry, Senator. Your Amendment Was Sent to
Purgatory.''
^By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Is the amendment in purgatory? Only the category will tell. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, struggling to deal with hundreds of amendments to a bill providing new ammunition for the war on drugs, hammered together a system designed to speed its work and permit <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to adjourn for the year. At times it appeared that the labor-and-time-saving device might prove a tottering house of cards that would bring all progress to a halt. It worked this way: The amendments were assigned to categories. With some, the skids were greased. With others, the road ahead was rocky indeed. Still others faced a fate uncertain. Category 1 amendments were offered as a package containing scores of legislative initiatives and eventually all were approved on a single bloc vote. Category 2 amendments might stand a chance, but only if they were approved by a panel of senators from both parties. Decisions could be appealed to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> and Democratic leaders. `` Those are the purgatory amendments,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` They do not know where they are going. And they may not be going anywhere.'' Category 3 amendments could be offered individually and face their chances. Category 4 amendments did not make the cut and had no chance at all. It took unanimous consent of all 100 senators for the gears to mesh and the system to move forward. The spur to getting that consent was the desire of many senators facing re-election contests to leave the capital and get on with campaigning. Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, had a complaint. `` I had an amendment and I find it is not even on the purgatory list,'' he said. `` That raises the question to me whether my amendment went to heaven or hell,'' he said. `` How do I find that out?'' `` It went to hell,'' replied Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>: `` I know the senator from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> might want me to go there, but where did my amendment go? <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>: `` It is on list No. 4. `` What happens to list No. 4? <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> asked. `` Nothing,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> replied.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Bean soup, that enduring congressional culinary tradition, has been on the menu of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Restaurant for most of the days of this century, every day for the last 85 years at least. But being on the menu does not necessarily mean being on the stove or on the table. And one day 45 years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> recalled, the bean soup pots stopped bubbling for the first time ever. `` Even though bean soup was on the menu that day at 10 cents a cup, 15 cents a bowl, it was n't cooking on the stove,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. The day was Sept. 14, 1943, and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was beanless and therefore soupless. `` This was because war-time rationing had slashed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s supply of white <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> beans,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> explained `` Somehow, by the next day, more beans were found and bowls of bean soup have been ladled up without any interruption ever since,'' he said. Bean soup is on the menu in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> because it was ordered to be there. There is some question as to who gave the orders. Some attribute the decree to Sen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> DuBois </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. Bean soup was his favorite and he presided over the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> which in turn presided over the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> restaurant. Therefore, bean soup went on the menu. Others say the demand was made in 1903 by Sen. <PERSON> Knute </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. The rage for bean soup soon spread to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and in 1904 Speaker <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION>, was outraged that the menu of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> restaurant did not list it. For years Cannon's words on the subject were also printed on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> menu, along with a recipe for the now famous soup: `` Thunderation, I had my mouth set for bean soup. From now on, hot or cold, rain, snow or shine, I want it on the menu every day.'' There are many differences in the operating styles of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said that the preparation of bean soup is one of them. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> recipe calls for adding onions braised in butter. The House recipe calls for beans, beans, beans _ nothing but beans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-18 0981</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1023</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MADRID, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> and King <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> toasted a new era of good relations, saying they looked forward to bridging their countries' major point of contention _ the Rock of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>. The Queen, on the first-ever visit of a reigning <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> monarch to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, only alluded to the British colony at the southern tip of the <LOCATION> Iberian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. `` We are confident that our growing mutual understanding will enable us to deal with the one remaining problem which exists between us,'' she told the <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> king Monday at a state dinner. <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> was ceded to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1713 when <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> lost the War of Spanish Succession. In November 1984 both governments agreed to discuss the future of the fortress, including sovereignty, at ministerial-level meetings. <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON>, who is <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>'s third cousin, said, `` This route of dialogue and cooperaton between both our countries will eventually lead to a concrete end.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> says he hopes his parents will lie around a pool and relax once the new man takes over the White House. The younger <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 30, said in a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> television interview broadcast Monday that he expects his parents will write their memoirs. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who works for <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Good Morning America,'' taped his <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> interview in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he expects `` things will be a little more relaxed'' for him when his parents return to private life and that he expects his parents will follow their eight years in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> `` with a lot of laying around the pool, getting a tan.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> has re-entered St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s Hospital for X-rays to determine the progress of therapy on her back, her spokeswoman said. `` The X-rays are to see what improvement there has been with her physical therapy,'' spokeswoman <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> said by telephone Monday from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. In July, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, 56, was admitted to <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s for a compression fracture of the first lumbar vertebra that produced lower back muscle spasms. She hurt herself in June when she fell on the set of the film `` Young Toscannini'' in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, said Ms. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>. During that stay, she underwent physical therapy and had X-rays taken. She went back to the hospital in late September for more X-rays, she said. Miss <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> has suffered back problems since she fell of a horse and fractured her spine 30 years ago, Ms. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ROCHELLE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, says he believes in his `` heart and soul'' that he made the right choice by leaving his partnership in a law firm to work full time on creating housing for the homeless. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, 30, announced his decision Monday. He reportedly earned more than $ 225,000 annually at the firm of <PERSON> Blutrich </PERSON>, <PERSON> Falcone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, which he joined three years ago as a partner. His salary as head of HELP, a not-for-profit organization, will be between $ 50,000 and $ 60,000 annually, said <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Sachs </PERSON>, director of operations for the group. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> founded HELP three years ago to provide transitional housing for women with children as an alternative to welfare hotels. He said his resignation was effective immediately. `` I believe in my heart and soul this is the right thing to do,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said. `` I do n't want to do this forever, but for now, there's nothing I'd rather do.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> plans to play a haberdasher caught in a crime scandal in <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Wiseguy'' this season, an executive producer said. Producer <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON> also said Monday that the first villain of the season, a charismatic leader of a white supremacist sect, will be played by <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, best known for his 1970s television appearances as real-life minority counsel on the Watergate Committee. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> made his film debut in the 1985 movie `` Marie,'' starring <PERSON> Sissy </PERSON> <PERSON> Spacek </PERSON>. He played himself, the attorney for <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ragghianti </PERSON>, the parole board chairwoman who blew the whistle on a pardons-for-money scheme. <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON> was later cast as the head of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> in the movie `` No Way Out.'' <PERSON> Cannell </PERSON> said he decided to offer <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> the guest shot after he saw `` The King of Comedy'' again recently. In that film, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> had a rare dramatic role as a famous talk-show host held hostage by an aspiring comedian played by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Triola </PERSON> <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, who made headlines when she won a landmark `` palimony'' suit against former live-in boyfriend <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, was recuperating at her <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> home after suffering a heart attack. Ms. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> was released Saturday in good condition from <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where she was taken Oct. 7 after suffering a heart attack, hospital spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> said Monday. Doctors performed an angioplasty, in which a balloon is inserted into a clogged blood vessel and inflated, widening the vessel and restoring the blood flow, <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> said. `` She came through it real well,'' Wise said. In 1979, Ms. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> sued for half of the actor's fortune in a celebrated palimony case handled by divorce attorney <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>. Her right to sue was upheld, but her claim was ultimately rejected, though the actor was ordered to pay her a nominal sum for rehabilitation. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON>, the Oscar-winning actor of `` Cat Ballou'' died in August 1987 at age 63.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolte </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON>, are expecting the birth of their second child, his publicist said. The baby is due in March, spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> said Monday. The couple, who live in <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, married in 1984 and their son, <PERSON> Brawley </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolte </PERSON>, was born two years later. <PERSON> Nolte </PERSON>, whose films include `` 48 Hours,'' `` North Dallas Forty'' and `` Cannery Row,'' is currently working on the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorcese </PERSON> film `` New York Stories.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BusinessTaxes Bjt   10-18 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Business Taxes, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRS Failing To Collect Billions In Business Taxes, Report Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> could collect billions of dollars more a year by using the same aggressive enforcement tactics against businesses that it uses against individual taxpayers, a congressional report says. The report by the Government Operations subcommittee on commerce, consumer and monetary affairs comes amid a presidential campaign in which <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has made more aggressive collection of unpaid taxes a cornerstone of his economic proposals. The subcommittee report, released Monday, says the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> should develop a program to match `` information returns'' showing interest and dividend income paid to businesses with the actual tax returns filed by each company. The report estimated that between $ 3.2 billion and $ 8 billion a year in taxes on interest and dividends earned by businesses is never collected because the income is not reported to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> for years has been using its computers to compare information returns listing interest and dividend payments to individuals with the income tax returns filed by the individuals. The program produced $ 2.35 billion in additional tax revenue from individuals in fiscal 1985. Banks and corporations are not required to file such information returns, but the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> report said the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> still received 26 million such returns in 1985, showing income payments to 5 million businesses totaling $ 987 billion. Rep. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the subcommittee, has introduced legislation to mandate the filing of information returns by businesses He said the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> has n't even been using the corporate returns it has been receiving without such a requirement. `` By casting these information returns aside, <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> is not only missing the chance to assess many billions of dollars of unreported business tax liabilities but has created a double standard of enforcement that is more lenient by far toward businesses than individuals,'' <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> said Monday the agency has not seen the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> report and will not comment until agency officials review it. But at a hearing before Barnard's subcommittee last year, <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> said the additional tax revenue that would be generated by a document matching program for corporations would not justify the administrative costs. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> said those costs would be much higher than for the document matching program for individuals because corporations use different fiscal years, varying accounting methods and different names. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> report said the problems cited by <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> all `` pertain to the way income is reported'' to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> never considered the desirability of modifying the reporting requirements, nor assessed the feasibility of a partial document matching program encompassing those corporations to which the difficulties do not pertain,'' the report said. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> promised the subcommittee last year that the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> would begin using document matching to verify income reported on tax returns from single-owner businesses and would start a multiyear study to determine the extent of business under-reporting of interest and dividend income. He also said the agency would begin a test program using information returns to detect corporations and partnerships that do not file any income tax returns. That test program in one district office was so successful, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> report said, that the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> now has expanded it to nine more districts and could have a document matching program ready by next spring to identify nonfilers among corporations and partnerships nationwide. Despite such efforts, <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> still `` has not been sufficiently diligent in attempting to extend its sophisticated computer matching capabilities to businesses.'' `` Individuals, and now sole proprietors, who know that each and every one of their returns will be scrutinized by <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> computers for unreported income deserve to know why corporate and partnership returns are being excused from this automatic examination process,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AutoDefects     10-18 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Auto Defects,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Investigating Complaints Of Alleged GM Truck Defect</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government is investigating complaints that about 100,000 pickup trucks made by <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> may have a tendency to go out of control because of a defective bolt that harms the vehicles' braking system. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Monday it had opened an investigation into unconfirmed reports of brake problems involving 1988 Chevrolet and GMC half-ton pickup trucks. It also undertook six other probes involving major automakers. One person reportedly died when a <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> pickup truck's rear-brake backing bolt broke off and fell into the brake assembly, the agency said. The agency said it had received two other unconfirmed reports of the brake problem. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudgens </PERSON>, a spokesman at <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> headquarters, said the company would cooperate fully with the investigation. `` Just because there is an inquiry does n't mean there is a defect,'' he said. `` That would remain to be seen.'' The six other investigations started by the agency in September were in response to complaints of: _ Anti-lock braking failure in 43,000 1985-1987 <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Continentals </PERSON> The agency said it had received nine unconfirmed complaints, including one that involved an accident. _ Compartment fires in 1980-1988 Ford Crown Victorias equipped with the 5.8-liter V-8 engine The vehicles are used mainly by police departments. The agency reported eight complaints. _ Fires and loss of power steering caused by a power-steering hose in 90,000 1986-model Buick LeSabres The agency received two complaints, one of which involved a fire. _ Burned carpeting from overheated exhaust systems in 64,000 1987-1988 Chrysler Dodge Daytonas The agency received four complaints. _ Sudden separation of the steering wheel in 40,000 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> vehicles The agency received two complaints. _ Fuel expulsion in the <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s P-30 chassis, used by other manufacturers as a base for motor homes Engineers at the traffic safety agency found no defect trend in preliminary evaluations of four defect complaints involving major manufacturers and closed the investigations. The complaints involved: _ Throttle control problems in the 1987-1988 Chrysler Jeep _ Halfshaft failure in the 1984-1986 Ford Tempo and <PERSON> Topaz </PERSON> _ Defogger fires in the 1987 Toyota Corolla _ Frame cracking in the 1982-1985 GM Camaro and Firebird No defect trends were found in two engineering analyses, the next highest level of investigation, involving major manufacturers. The investigations were into complaints of rear-brake lockup on the 1981-1982 Chevette diesel car and the 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerostar </ORGANIZATION>. The agency closed an engineering analysis into allegations of defective power steering in <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>'s 1980-1986 A-body, J-body and X-body cars, concluding that any defect posed no unreasonable risk to motorists.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881018-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-18-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ContinentalCracks     10-18 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Continental Cracks,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Routine Painting Leads to Discovery of Airline Cracks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
