<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Anti-SemitismReport     05-31 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anti-Semitism Report,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>ADL Reports Upswing in Israel-Related Anti-Semitism</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There has been a sharp rise in anti-Semitic incidents that stem from opposition to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Anti-Defamation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> of B'nai B'rith reported Tuesday. So far this year, 88 out of 443 anti-Semitic incidents reported in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have had an element of anti-Israeli sentiment, according to a report by the <ORGANIZATION> ADL </ORGANIZATION>, which monitors outbreaks of racism and anti-Semitism. By contrast, there were only three such incidents out of 1,018 anti-Semitic episodes reported for all of last year. This year's anti-Israeli incidents appeared to be prompted by Palestinian unrest in the occupied territories, the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> ADL </ORGANIZATION> report said. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Foxman </PERSON>, the group's national director, said the incidents represented `` the first time since the founding of the state of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> 40 years ago that there has been a significant outbreak of Middle East-related anti-Semitic incidents in this country.'' The incidents included vandalism and arson attacks on synagogues, telephone threats to Jewish organizations and other forms of verbal harassment. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> led all states in reports of politically motivated anti-Semitism with 12 vandalism cases and 13 harassment incidents, followed by <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> ADL </ORGANIZATION> said. The figures are based on reports gathered by the <ORGANIZATION> ADL </ORGANIZATION>'s 31 regional offices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0448EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--LotteryThief     05-31 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Lottery Thief,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested, Charged With Stealing 1,500 Tickets</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A luckless man has been charged with a string of robberies in which he took 1,500 lottery tickets in hopes of winning the jackpot, police said. <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, 20, did n't get the $ 1 million winner. He did get booked on charges of armed robbery and grand theft in connection with three separate robberies of 7-Eleven stores last week, police said Monday. `` He did n't take cash, he did n't take food, he did n't take anything but the lottery tickets,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Metro-Dade </ORGANIZATION> detective <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Robson </PERSON>. The robberies occurred Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday mornings at two different 7-Elevens, police said. In each case, the robber, who brandished a gun in the first robbery, fled in a black Cadillac, they said. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, unarmed, was arrested Friday night after an officer spotted a black <PERSON> Cadillac </PERSON> at the first 7-Eleven that had been robbed, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0448EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--YosemiteClimbers     05-31 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Yosemite Climbers,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Strands Two Climbers on Half Dome</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YOSEMITE NATIONAL PARK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two climbers trapped overnight by a storm completed their ascent up Half Dome with the help of rescuers and then hiked 8 miles to the <LOCATION> Yosemite </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> floor, a park spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Charley </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampson </PERSON>, 33, and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Enger </PERSON>, 32, both of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, were 4,200 feet above the valley when they called for help about 10 a.m. Sunday, spokeswoman <PERSON> Mallory </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Monday. The men, who began a two-day climb of the rock's northwest face on Saturday, shouted to climbers above them to get help because the storm, which dumped rain and snow on them and froze their ropes overnight. A <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> helicopter lowered fresh ropes, sleeping bags, warm clothes and food by about 5 p.m. Sunday, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. It then lowered two rescue climbers who helped the two climb the remaining 600 feet to safety.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthSeasTurmoil     05-31 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Seas Turmoil,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disorders And Ethnic Tensions Bring Turmoil To South Seas</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD BILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Political disorders, ethnic tensions, poverty and international disputes are churning up the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seas </LOCATION> in an arc curving sharply northward from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and back down to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tahiti </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Papua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tonga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>, even <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> themselves, have had a taste of trouble in the past year. Most recently it was rioting in <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION> over land claims, and in the French territory of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> 19 native Kanaks were killed in a shootout with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> troops in ethnic and political disorders. <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> has seen two coups in the past year, and the former British island remains unstable in the aftermath. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> is concerned about what it sees as the speading influence of <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> in the area and the inroads made by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in what long has been seen as an `` American lake.'' A commentator in the <ORGANIZATION> Sydney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said the image of a South Seas paradise may have been permanently tarnished. The past year also has seen riots in <LOCATION> Tahiti </LOCATION> and political upheaval in <LOCATION> Papua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION> over the alleged corruption of Cabinet ministers. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> faces racial unrest as indigenous Maoris press the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government of Prime Minister <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> with a battery of land and fisheries claims. In <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, aborigines are using this year's bicentennial celebrations to highlight grievances they say grew out of European settlement 200 years ago. In early May, bloody violence erupted over territorial and French presidential elections in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>, culminating in the rescue of French hostages held in caves by Melanesian separatists; 21 people were killed. On May 16, a drunken mob ran riot through <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>'s capital, <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vila </LOCATION>, looting shops and smashing office windows. One man died, nine others were injured and police arrested 30 people in the rioting over land claims. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> responded to the crisis by airlifting riot-control gear to <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION> at Prime Minister <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lini </PERSON>'s request Prime Minister <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> linked <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> to the rioting and said <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> could not stand by as a friendly country's government is undermined by what he called a non-democratic process. `` There is no doubt about a <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> connection in <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said. `` In a city with a population of less than 20,000 it is clear that these disturbances have been on a very serious scale.'' <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>, formerly the <LOCATION> British-French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hebrides </LOCATION>, shocked the generally pro-Western <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> with its decision in 1986 to establish diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Since then, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has sought fishing agreements with <LOCATION> Papua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION> and impoverished <LOCATION> Kiribati </LOCATION>, creating concern in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> as well as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> about Soviet inroads in the region. More recently, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has approached <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> for fishing access to Australian ports for refueling purposes and to Australian airports for fishing crews in transit. <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said he would treat the request with caution. Elsewhere in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, such nations as <LOCATION> Tonga </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION> face poverty, overcrowding and unemployment. Many of the islanders have migrated to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> in search of jobs. `` All these are turning the once tranquil <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> into an increasingly complex set of real and potential troublespots,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Sydney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Sydney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> echoed that concern, calling the situation a powderkeg. `` The multiple problems of these islands has led to a rising discontent,'' the Telegraph said. `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has been making big efforts to gain a stronger foothold in every island group through fishery deals and aid.'' Racial and ethnic divisions remain a major underlying problem of many <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> islands, where populations are mainly Melanesian. <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> are examples. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> is the major power in the region and its largest aid donor. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> has expressed concern about Libyan activities, going as far as to close down <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s diplomatic mission in <LOCATION> Canberra </LOCATION> last year after an incident involving the aboriginal activist <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mansell </PERSON> had returned from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> saying <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> was prepared to bankroll a black revolution in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. The scattered violence in the South Seas has no single connective thread, although in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Polynesia </LOCATION> the crises erupted after <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> refused to follow the regional pattern of decolonization and independence. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> already suffers a major image problem in the South Seas with the bombing of the <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> vessel Rainbow Warrior in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> in 1985 and its continued underground nuclear testing on the Mururoa atoll over the objections of almost every island state in the region. The island states, supported by <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, have declared the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> a nuclear-free zone. In a major turnaround, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1986 designated the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> an area of concern because of a buildup of the Soviet Pacific fleet. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials believe the Soviet fleet consists of 755 ships and patrol craft, including 141 submarines.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WelfareEntrepreneurs     05-31 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Welfare Entrepreneurs,0728</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Welfare Recipients Become Entrepreneurs in Pilot Projects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA WILKINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A program targeted at low-income women in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> is helping welfare recipients create their own jobs and build successful businesses, and promoters hope its success will spread to the rest of the country. `` A lot of people told me this was going to fail miserably,'' said <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keeley </PERSON>, president of the 5-year-old Women's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which was graduating its first class of 18 fledgling entrepreneurs today Under the plan, welfare recipients receive training and then continue receiving public assistance while receiving subsidized loans to help them start businesses ranging from cleaning companies to hair-styling salons. `` The first hurdle we had to cross in this area was skepticism. Can poor women do it?'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. The organization began its first class for welfare entrepreneurs in March under the federal Self Employment Investment Demonstration. <PERSON> Keeley </PERSON> said she hopes 90 people will graduate by the end of the year. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> is the first of five states to launch the program, which is coordinated by the private, nonprofit <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. The other states are <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. The corporation persuaded federal officials to waive regulations which reduce or eliminate benefits when recipients get jobs, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. Participants continue receiving assistance even after they start their own businesses so they can re-invest profits. At the Women's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, recipients devise a business plan, learn about marketing, financial management and other skills and are encouraged to start thinking like entrepreneurs. They can borrow up to $ 5,000, to be loaned in small increments as their businesses progress at 1 percent above the prime lending rate, said <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON>, who directs the organization's pilot project known as the Self Employment Training Opportunities Program. Once a month for at least a year, recipients are required to work with the organization's accountant to do bookkeeping. `` The whole point of that is to get them off on the right foot,'' Ms. <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON> said. Women's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> received nearly all its current annual budget of $ 600,000 from foundations and other private sources, Ms. <PERSON> Keeley </PERSON> said. Organizers hope to help other states begin similar projects, she said. An aspiring filmmaker, one of the few men to complete the program, said welfare recipients face challenges other entrepreneurs do n't. `` Most of us who have been down and out have had our self-esteem shattered. They realized it was important to build that up,'' he said of the program, asking not to be identified for fear it might hurt his business. Promoters point out that the program is n't a cure-all for welfare problems. `` People get poor for different reasons. They are going to escape in different ways,'' <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> reasoned. Only 10 percent to 15 percent of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s 57,000 AFDC recipients are likely candidates for the program, said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, planning director for the state Office of Jobs Policy. Nationally, the percentage is 2 percent to 5 percent, he said. A forerunner to the current program was launched three years ago. In that time, 22 women started businesses and three have already repaid their loans, Ms. <PERSON> Keeley </PERSON> said. `` They do n't hand the business to you. You have to work for it,'' said <PERSON> Ellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, who has cleaned homes and businesses most of her life and started a janitorial service in late 1986. `` They give you the right contacts. If you do n't follow through, it's your fault.'' Ms. <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, who had been on and off assistance for 30 years, is self-supporting now and employs about 10 people. `` I'm glad I'm off Welfare makes you feel depressed and down,'' she said. Before the pilot program ends in 1992, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> hopes to persuade federal officials to waive permanently regulations that bar welfare recipients who turn a business profit from keeping their benefits while they get their companies off the ground. `` We need the federal government to let go a little to let it succeed,'' <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. `` I must say the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> has been very cooperative, but right now the waiver process is onerous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Wilder     05-31 0819</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wilder,0840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Home Of Confederacy May Produce Nation's First Black Governor</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOE TAYLOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Lt. Gov. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> was growing up in this former Confederate capital, he waited on tables at political dinners in the city's segregated clubs and hotels. Next year, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> could land a job in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s Executive Mansion as the host of such dinners _ and the nation's first elected black governor. The 57-year-old <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, whose grandparents were slaves, already is the highest-ranking black elected state official in the country. Although he has not yet announced his candidacy, he would be the favorite to win the Democratic nomination for governor next summer. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Rozell </PERSON>, a political scientist at <ORGANIZATION> Mary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fredericksburg </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> has no strong opposition within the party and, among potential <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> opponents next November, only Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Trible </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> seems at this point to pose a major threat to <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s election. <PERSON> Trible </PERSON> is not seeking re-election to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> this year and has not said whether he will run for governor in 1989. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>, the youngest of eight children, grew up in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>. He studied chemistry at <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, then enlisted in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and won a <ORGANIZATION> Bronze </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> for bravery in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. He went to law school at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and opened a law practice here in 1959. Ten years later, he ran for a <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vacancy when other local black leaders showed no interest. He became the first black to sit in the chamber since Reconstruction. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> was recognized as a skilled debater who quickly learned the rules of parliamentary procedure. Although his early image was that of a firebrand, he was never considered a militant. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> was instrumental in the state's adoption of a holiday honoring slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. He also lobbied unsuccessfully to change lyrics that blacks found offensive in the state song, `` Carry Me Back to <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> combined the role of maverick with that of an insider. In 1982, he single-handedly scuttled the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ambition of fellow Democrat <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON> because <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON> dared to invoke the name of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s conservative leader, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator who left the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1970 to become an independent. The Byrd organization had dominated the state for 50 years. Two years later, in July 1984, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> announced for the Democratic nomination for lieutenant governor. No serious opposition arose within the party during the next year, and he was nominated in June 1985. When <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Democrats also nominated a woman for attorney general, there were predictions that the party was headed for disaster. But <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> played down his race and offered the image of a moderate native son in the tradition of then-Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>. A combination of <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>'s popularity, mistakes by <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponent and a tour of the state by <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> helped turn the predicted disaster into the second straight Democratic sweep of the state's top three offices. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s performance in the administration of Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>, who can not by law succeed himself, has been mostly low-key. However, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> engaged in a well-publicized feud with <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> during his first year in office over how much credit <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> deserved for the 1985 victory. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> also has criticized the administration's tax increases for road construction and made a show this year of pushing, over <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>' objections, for a repeal of the sales tax on over-the-counter drugs. The lieutenant governor's major prospective competitor for the gubernatorial nomination stepped aside in March when Attorney General <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> announced that she would seek another term in office. <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> acknowledged this month in a college commencement address that <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> could make history next year by becoming the first black to lead the state's Democratic ticket. <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>' office said no endorsement was intended, but observers said the comment amounted to a warning to potential rivals to stay out of <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s way. <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> is expected to announce his political plans this summer. According to <PERSON> Rozell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s race may not prevent him from becoming governor of the Old Dominion because of changes over the past 20 years in the state's population and its attitudes. About 20 percent of Virginians are black, and the state also has a large, progressive-minded population in the northern corridor adjoining the nation's capital. No black has ever been elected governor in this country. In 1986 <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' Democratic Mayor <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, a Republican county executive in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, both were nominated by their parties but lost the election. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> also had failed in his first race for governor in 1982. The only black to serve as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> governor was <PERSON> Pinckney </PERSON> B.S. <PERSON> Pinchback </PERSON>, the lieutenant governor of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> who became acting governor for six weeks in 1872-1873 after the governor was impeached.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama     05-31 0829</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama,0853</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lack Of Alternative To Noriega Stymies Ouster</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Note contents of 12th graf `Noriega popularized'</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lack of an alternative to military rule, and a protest movement so well-mannered it apparently is no threat, have stymied <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attempts to force Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> from power. For his part, the general uses the populist appeal that has characterized 20 years of de facto military rule and deflects the spotlight from himself. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says the issue is not whether he stays or goes, but <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s dignity and self-determination. This plays well in a country that knows it was created in 1903 essentially for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s convenience and where a new nationalism sparked by the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> treaties burns brightly. In mid-May, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> consolidated support in the military by forming a <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> of 20 loyal officers. The council, most of whose members are from the middle ranks, appears to be at least on par with the senior officers who serve as chiefs of staff. Allegations of drug-running and of involvement in the decapitation murder of opposition figure <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Spadafora </PERSON>, which spurred the movement to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> a year ago, have all but evaporated as issues among Panamanians. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> engineered the departures of dictators during the past decade in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by convincing them that their positions were untenable and they could not expect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> help against popular uprisings. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> clearly does not feel threatened by his opposition, which comes from the genteel, educated middle and upper classes rather than oppressed masses. It is an uprising with good manners, a rare phenomenon in Central America. While dissidents in other countries form guerrilla armies, Panamanians bang pots and pans, wave white handkerchiefs and hold brief general strikes. `` If you want to see Panamanians dead in the streets of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, you will not see it,'' deposed President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> said in a recent meeting with reporters. `` Panamanians have risked as far as they are willing to risk.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has shut down opposition news media. His soldiers, who can crack heads with the best of them when the occasion arises, have blocked most street demonstrations with intimidation or force. Panamanian life is permeated by a `` them or us'' attitude that pits workers against the wealthy opposition, a small and struggling <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> against the Colossus of the North, and Panamanian independence against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> meddling. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> popularized the term `` rabi-blancos,'' which translates roughly to `` white butts,'' a reference to the lighter skin common to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s upper classes. In a recent speech the general said `` the establishment,'' as he has taken to calling the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, will be responsible if anything untoward happens to him. American economic sanctions have lowered the comparatively high living standard of many Panamanians but made no visible dent in <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s control. He has rejected the legitimacy of federal indictments in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> charging him with drug trafficking and money laundering. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> appeared to be negotiating on different levels _ the Panamanians wanting to talk about economic issues and American troop withdrawals, and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is willing to discuss only dropping the indictments in exchange for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s departure <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says he will not respond to ultimatums and will not deal until sanctions are lifted and the additional American soldiers troops sent to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in April are pulled out. The troops and sanctions remain in place. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says that, early in the talks, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators gave him 48 hours to be out of his country. Although Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said last week the talks had broken off, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is trying again, this time enlisting Latin American democracies. Panamanian opponents of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had been urging that approach for weeks. Military rule in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> began when Col. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> seized power in a 1968 coup. He banned partisan political activity for the next 10 years, and some party leaders went into exile or became inactive. The country has had eight civilian presidents and one civilian junta since 1968, but power always has resided in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, recently renamed the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> commands the 15,000-member force, which includes the military and police. Only <PERSON> Nicolas </PERSON> <PERSON> Ardito </PERSON> <PERSON> Barletta </PERSON>, in 1984, was elected by popular vote, and <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> forced him out in 1985. <PERSON> Ardito </PERSON> <PERSON> Barletta </PERSON> had run as a member of the military-dominated <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in an election many contend was fraudulent. Civilian parties have not produced an alternative to military rule around whom people will rally, and <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is not noted for presidential stability. Presidents sometimes hold office only a few weeks. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiari </PERSON> was president five times in 1960-1964 and earlier served four days as second vice president. The military and its <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> have proved more durable.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frazier </PERSON> has covered <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and its affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Television     05-31 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Television,0760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli TV Finds Comedy In Jewish-Arab Relations</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> version of <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunker </PERSON>, ca n't get used to having Arabs next-door. His Arab neighbor ca n't get used to <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON> The hotheaded pair are the central characters in `` Neighbors,'' a comedy series produced by Israeli television about a subject most people consider deadly serious: Jewish-Arab relations. The 70-minute pilot broadcast Friday night started off with <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON>, a Jewish insurance salesman, moving into a new apartment. He's happy until he notices the nameplate across the hall has a distinctly Arab ring: <PERSON> Medawar </PERSON>. A few minutes later, a middle-aged woman knocks on <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON>'s door to ask for help fixing a short circuit. <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON> asks her how she feels about `` the issue.'' `` Oh, I do n't mind having Jewish neighbors,'' replies <PERSON> Muna </PERSON> <PERSON> Medawar </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON> minds have Arabs next-door. When Mrs. <PERSON> Medawar </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON>, a garage owner, shows up in <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON>'s apartment with a tire, <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON> exclaims: `` Oh my God, a burning tire in the house!'' The Arab dubs <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON> `` Mr. Transfer.'' The references are clear. Burning tires have become a symbol of the six-month Palestinian uprising against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. And right-wing Israelis want to transfer all Arabs out of the occupied lands. <PERSON> Itzik </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Dorit </PERSON>, is more tolerant. Within minutes, she is visiting <PERSON> Muna </PERSON> for coffee and setting off a chain of neighborly interactions. `` The message is simple: we can live together,'' said <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamar </PERSON>, the Arab Israeli who directed the show. Producer <PERSON> Mika </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravid </PERSON> is Jewish, and the actors are Jews and Arabs. It was not so simple to produce a show on personal relations between Jewish and <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> citizens. `` Neighbors'' is <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>'s first entertainment show in 20 years to approach such sensitive subjects as racism, prejudice, mutual suspicion and political enmity. At least one previous attempt on <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> failed because critics feared the program's encouragement of peaceful coexistence might be interpreted as extending beyond friendly relations _ to romantic ties and interfaith marriages. `` We may just tiptoe around that bombshell,'' <PERSON> Ravid </PERSON> said. `` Neighbors,'' produced on a budget of a little more than $ 50,000, is considered the brainchild of <PERSON> Yosef </PERSON> <PERSON> Barel </PERSON>, manager of the television's Arabic Department. Nearly two years ago, he suggested a humorous show about `` the problem.'' `` We invested a tremendous amount of time and work,'' <PERSON> Ravid </PERSON> said. `` We sat down over every scene and every sensitive point so that it could touch on current issues but not offend anyone on either side.'' One technique that makes the show understandable to all is that the Israeli characters speak Hebrew, with Arabic subtitles, while the Arabs speak their own language, with Hebrew subtitles. The show is not directly about relations between Israelis and Palestinians from the occupied territories. Its message of tolerance is built around <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> citizens _ a community of 750,000 people who have lived in the state since its independence but who face discrimination despite their status as citizens. <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Zumot </PERSON>, a Palestinian from Israeli-annexed <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said he thought long and hard before accepting the lead role, because the theme did not touch on the issue of occupation. But the burly man, who portrays a character constantly battling his waistline as well as his wife's diet food is a key factor in making the program work. His range of facial expressions is one reason viewers can laugh at the painful topic that few Israelis and even fewer Palestinians feel free to joke about. When <PERSON> Muna </PERSON> warns him that the rich fried foods he loves will drive up his blood pressure, he says, `` That guy across the hall will give me high blood pressure.'' `` He just needs time to get used to us,'' <PERSON> Muna </PERSON> says. `` Get used to us? What are we, asthma?'' <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> retorts, sneaking a plateful of cookies to eat in the bathroom. The actor hopes the series, which will be ready for next winter's television season, will be `` a step on the road to peace.'' `` I want people to think more than laugh,'' <PERSON> Zumot </PERSON> said. `` I think of the apartment building as this region of the world. The Jewish apartment is <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and the Arab apartment is <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>. And I want the Israelis to learn that when there will be a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state, it will not be as dangerous as they think.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Yeltsin Bjt   05-31 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Yeltsin, Bjt,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ousted Moscow Party Chief Calls On Communist Party's No. 2 Man To
Quit</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, the ousted capital <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief, took the unprecedented step of using Western news media to insist that the party's No. 2 man, <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, resign because he is blocking reform. Never before has a fallen Soviet leader so sharply and publicly criticized a high-level party official still in power. In interviews Monday with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> said it was a mistake to say <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s efforts to remake Soviet society are going according to plan `` This is a dangerous thing to say,'' said <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, an outspoken advocate of reform. He told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> should resign because he is the main impediment to `` perestroika,'' the Russian word for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s restructuring. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> also said he was upset that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> did not rally to his defense when he was shunted aside. The interviews shed light on <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s fall from power that culminated in his removal Feb. 18 as a candidate, or non-voting, member of the ruling Politburo. They also were the most extensive he has granted the Western media since he was ousted as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party leader in November 1987. In addition, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> chose to speak out as <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seeks to boost his standing at home through his five-day summit with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> should go `` because processes in the party are too slow, because the party is still lagging behind, because the process of democratization in the party is not developing ... and <PERSON> Comrade </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> is the main person responsible for this.'' <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, 67, formally oversees <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ideology. In an interview published in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last year, he said he presides over the meetings of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secretariat </ORGANIZATION>, which runs this vast country from day-to-day. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, 57, told <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> the style of <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>'s leadership `` contradicts the spirit of perestroika.'' `` He's one of the opponents when it comes to questions of social justice,'' <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>. Pressed by the interviewer, he said he thought <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> should resign. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms have met stiff resistance. `` In the first period of perestroika, there was an excessive euphoria about how quickly change would come,'' he said. `` But three years have passed and there have been no basic changes. If there have n't been any changes in another three years, then people's faith in perestroika will decline.'' The stunning statements came as the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is embroiled in fierce struggles between conservatives and reform advocates in preparation for a party conference that opens June 28, the first such session since 1941. It was not known whether <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>'s comments were sanctioned, or even supported, by other high-ranking party members. CBS anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON>, who interviewed <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>: `` I ca n't believe he would do this ... unless he feels, right or wrong, he has a green light from above.'' However, Rather quoted <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> as saying in portions of the interview not broadcast by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> that he received no prior approval for his comments. As <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party boss, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> stood out for his brusque, attacking manner and populist style. He was popular among Muscovites for criticizing consumer shortages, sometimes striding into stores to take his complaints straight to shopkeepers. This style apparently got him into trouble when he made a still-unpublished speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 21, 1987. Reports said he criticized what he saw as the slow pace of reform and attacked <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> confirmed to the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> that he criticized <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> by name at that meeting. <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> was replaced as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> party chief by <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaikov </PERSON> following a meeting during which <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> put `` personal ambitions above the interests of the party'' and also lacked self-discipline. Removed from the Politburo, he was named to the Cabinet-level position of deputy head of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He was removed from the Presidium of the Supreme Soviet, the country's nominal legislature, on May 4 Asked if he was upset <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> did not defend him, <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>: `` I'm upset. He feels this, and I told him I'm dissatisfied with my present job. He said that when relieved of his <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> post, `` I was accused of being an ultraleftist, which I'm not. I'm simply in favor of energetic action for perestroika ... which would bring results. And so far the results are very, very insignificant.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Poll-Primaries Bjt   05-31 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Primaries, Bjt,0767</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Finds Dissatisfaction With Presidential Nomination System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most Americans favor major changes in the selection of presidential nominees, with six in 10 saying they would eliminate political conventions and let voters choose the candidates directly, a <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll has found. As the primary season winds down, with the final contests June 7, the survey found broad dissatisfaction with the selection system. A majority of respondents said they did not follow the campaigns regularly and only half believed the races provide a good discussion of the issues. Sizable minorities said the best candidates generally lose their bid for the nomination, particularly on the Democratic side. Fifty-two percent of the 1,204 adults in the national poll favored major changes in the way the parties pick nominees, while only 38 percent said the system works well enough now. Ten percent did n't know. The dissatisfaction evenly spanned ideologies and political affiliations. The most striking split was in age: The youngest adults, ages 18-29, thought by a narrow margin that the system works well enough, while the oldest, those older than 64, broadly favored major changes, by 56-28 percent. The age split was mirrored in levels of attentiveness to the races. Just 27 percent of the youngest group said they had been following the primary campaigns regularly, compared with 54 percent of the oldest group. There was majority agreement on another way to select candidates. Fifty-nine percent said they would prefer to have voters select the nominees, without any delegates to party conventions. Only 31 percent favored the party convention system. Though rules vary by state, generally voters select some delegates, the party selects others and the delegates meet to choose the nominee at conventions, where under some circumstances delegates can switch their allegiance. Just 3 percent liked the idea of letting party leaders select the nominee on their own. In another measure of unhappiness with the presidential nomination process, sizable minorities of Americans said the parties generally do not nominate their best candidate from among those running. The Democrats fared worse, to the point that a plurality of the men in the poll said the Democrats do not choose their best candidate. Overall, 46 percent of respondents said the Democrats generally do pick their best candidate from those who seek the nomination, and 40 percent said not. But while women by a 51-33 margin said the Democrats do take their best candidate, men by a 47-41 split said not. More respondents overall, 52 percent, said the Republicans nominate their best candidate from among those running, while 36 percent said not. Respondents who identified themselves as Republicans or Democrats tended to favor their party's choices. But the Democratic respondents said by 51-38 that the Republicans make their best choice, while the Republicans and the independents were split on whether the Democrats make their best pick. On the selection of vice presidential candidates, less than a quarter of the respondents said the second-place finisher should be the nominee, while a large majority favored leaving the choice to the presidential candidate. Fifty-one percent said the nomination campaigns usually provide a good discussion of the issues. But 40 percent disagreed, and college graduates and higher-income Americans were split on the question. Sixty-four percent of black respondents said the campaigns provide a good discussion of the issues, possibly a reflection of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s efforts as a candidate for the Democratic nomination. Despite criticisms of the Super Tuesday Southern regional primaries as largely a superficial media event, 55 percent of Southerners agreed that the campaigns provided a good discussion of the issues. A plurality of respondents overall and a majority of Southerners said Super Tuesday was a good idea, and 54 percent of all respondents said regional primaries should be held again. On attentiveness to the races, 41 percent said they have been following this year's primaries regularly, 50 percent said they paid occasional attention, and 9 percent followed the campaigns hardly at all or not at all. The Media General-Associated Press poll consisted of telephone interviews April 29-May 8 with a randomly selected sample of respondents. The margin of error was plus or minus 3 percentage points. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the Tampa -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION> -RRB-. Tribune and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Arson     05-31 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Arson,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Shopkeepers Sentenced to Death for Arson</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four shopkeepers have been sentenced to death for arson and 49 <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members disciplined for helping the merchants defraud insurance companies, an official report said today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said the four merchants, in two cities of the northeastern <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> province, set fire to their shops after taking out large insurance policies obtained through bribes to local officials. Five people were killed in one of the fires. The newspaper said two brothers, <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Guangcai </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Guangde </PERSON>, falsified documents in <LOCATION> Qitaihe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to insure their stationery store and restaurant for $ 224,000. Two days later, they set fire to a bag filled with gasoline, starting a blaze that killed five people and caused $ 27,000 in damage, the paper said. The report said <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuli </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Yichun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> took out insurance worth $ 192,000 on a hardware store he managed after the store lost $ 72,000 over a 10-month period as a result of waste and mismanagement. And it said <PERSON> Yu </PERSON> <PERSON> Xibin </PERSON> rented a storehouse from <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> and insured it for $ 84,000, although it had only two counters and a sofa. The two set fire to the stores five times in May and June of last year, damaging six nearby stores and causing $ 24,000 in losses, the report said. The four provided local officials with high-quality cigarettes, wine, refrigerators, motorcycles and other goods to obtain contracts for the stores and the expensive insurance policies, it said. The report did not say if the death sentences had been carried out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-WarRemembered Bjt   05-31 0977</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-War Remembered, Bjt,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Gorbachev and His Countrymen, War Is an Ever-Present Memory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VOLGOGRAD, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was 19 when he saw this city, and it was in ruins. It was then called <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION>, and it had been the scene of one of the bloodiest and most savage battles of the Second World War. It left an impression that was still vivid in <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s mind more than three and a half decades later. `` I went to study at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, and I traveled through <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION>, which had been destroyed, through <LOCATION> Voronezh </LOCATION>, which had been destroyed,'' he told an interviewer in 1986. `` Nothing but ruins everywhere ... the whole country was in ruins.'' World War II divided <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s family and devastated much of his home region in southern <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. By the time he saw <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION>, in 1950, war for the budding law student was no vague or distant concept, but a terrible reality that had hit close to home. Today, more than four decades after the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> struggled and defeated the invading <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> armies, the war continues to haunt the collective Soviet soul, and perhaps <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> himself. For Soviets, the conflict they call the `` Great Patriotic War'' is simultaneously a glorious chapter in their country's history, proof of the superiority of socialism, a convenient alibi when things go wrong, and a tragedy whose scars are felt even today. The wartime alliance between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> against the Axis is also cited by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, as proof that the superpowers need not be adversaries, but can be allies. `` When the time posed the question acutely, irrevocably and that question had to be answered, the Soviet and American peoples united,'' he told a group of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> schoolchildren who visited the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> earlier this month. `` The present time ... also makes vast demands, above all on our two great peoples.'' Virtually every Soviet family, including <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s, was touched by the four years of bitter fighting that ranged throughout the western <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and claimed the lives of 20 million Soviet soldiers and civilians. After the German armies drove across the Soviet border in June 1941, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON>, a tractor driver, was called to the front, and served for four years. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> was 10 years old when the fighting broke out. His native <LOCATION> Stavropol </LOCATION> region, 300 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Volgograd </LOCATION>, was overrun by the German 40th <ORGANIZATION> Panzer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> for seven months beginning in August 1942, just as the battle for <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION> was raging. From just one collective farm in the <LOCATION> Stavropol </LOCATION> region, in the village of <LOCATION> Beshpagir </LOCATION>, 417 young men and women went away to fight, and were killed in battle. The grip of World War II on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> mind, and the use made of the memories by authorities, are nowhere more evident than in the city once called <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION>. In the titanic battle that raged here, as many as 1 million Soviets may have perished and 1.5 million Germans were killed, wounded or taken prisoner. In this city situated on a bend in the <LOCATION> Volga </LOCATION> river 600 miles south of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, 90 percent of the buildings in the industrial and residential center were devastated by artillery strikes, dive bombing raids and months of dogged house-to-house fighting. President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> said the eight-month battle that ended in February 1943 with the surrender of encircled <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> units had marked `` the turning point in the war of the Allied Nations against the forces of aggression.'' At former Soviet battlefield sites like <LOCATION> Volgograd </LOCATION>, every day is Memorial Day. About 3 million Soviets visit a gigantic memorial complex here each year, many of them veterans returning to see the place where many of their comrades were killed. `` You feel a great weight in your soul,'' said <PERSON> Amazas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arutunyan </PERSON>, 63, an Armenian who served as a private in the 93rd Artillery Regiment until he was badly wounded. `` So many men fell in combat, some screaming, others just falling in silence, like leaves.'' The war medals worn by the wizened man thumped against his chest as he slowly climbed a half-mile to the top of <PERSON> Mamayev </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurgan </PERSON> hill, where a huge statue of <LOCATION> Mother </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>, slightly larger than the Statue of Liberty, brandishes a sword and calls on her children to smite the invader. In a cavernous hall dominated by an enormous white stone hand holding a blazing torch, 34 dipped red banners record the names of more than 7,000 Soviet men and women who died defending <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION>. A recording of solemn music plays over and over. The effect is overpowering. `` You can not come here without tears,'' said <PERSON> Nadezhda </PERSON> <PERSON> Denisova </PERSON>, 61, a Volgograder, who was 19 when the Battle of <LOCATION> Stalingrad </LOCATION> began. Her eyes welled. `` There were so many dead.'' A visitor's book is filled with poignant messages left by those who have come to the monument. One man wrote: `` Uncle Vasiya, I have found you at last. Your name is on one of the banners.'' The memorial complex on Mamayev Kurgan hill does not only stress the heroism and patriotism of the Soviets who fought here, but also the fact that they fought in the name of socialism and Soviet power. The name of <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, wartime generalissimo and Soviet dictator, was stripped from this city in 1961 when it was renamed <LOCATION> Volgograd </LOCATION>, but now the party as a whole is lauded as the organizer of World War II victory. <PERSON> Olga </PERSON> <PERSON> Sobelyova </PERSON> made that point as she slowly escorted a group of 24 orphans from the <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Sasovo </LOCATION> up the hill toward the giant statue of <LOCATION> Mother </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. `` Children, you must n't think that it was just our armies who won here,'' said the 41-year-old guide from <LOCATION> Volgograd </LOCATION>. `` It was our entire country, our socialist system, and our <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Transplants Bjt   05-31 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Transplants, Bjt,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>Organ Donation Down, Doctors And Consent Laws Blamed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCIA DUNN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With organ donations declining and more Americans than ever awaiting transplants, specialists are begging doctors to make better use of consent laws designed to persuade families to consider donations. `` There is a large faction of the profession that has never wanted to have anything to do with this -LRB- transplant -RRB- business,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunsicker </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transplant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physicians </ORGANIZATION>, whose annual meeting begins today. `` Over and over again, we hear from a donor's family that they are glad they gave and others say they wish they had had the chance,'' he said. `` And yet the profession is not responding.'' Federal law requires hospitals to have a protocol for approaching the families of brain-dead patients about the possibility of organ donation. Forty-four states also have versions of the statute. The overall results are not impressive. Fewer kidney and heart-lung transplants were performed nationwide in 1987 than in 1986, according to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. And although there were a record number of heart, liver and pancreas transplants in 1987, the increase did not keep pace with previous years. Figures for 1988 are not yet available, but organ donations appear to be down by up to 10 percent, said Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transplant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surgeons </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sharing </ORGANIZATION>. `` The problem is that they -LRB- hospitals -RRB- often have the wrong people asking in order to comply with the law,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, senior research scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> Battelle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. Doctors are big offenders, experts say. `` They've got to be the hardest group in the world to educate. Once they're out of medical school, it's like they're on remote control,'' said <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transplant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION>. `` You can not make a doctor do something he does n't want to do ... and there are lots of reasons why he does n't think it's appropriate to ask Mrs. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> for her husband's organs,'' <PERSON> Hunsicker </PERSON> said `` They think it takes a lot of time, that it will be a nuisance and they do n't get anything out of it.'' Some physicians tell patients' next of kin, `` ` I know you do n't want to do this, but the law says I have to ask you if you want to be a donor,''' Ms. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said Others approach distraught families too quickly. About 20 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transplant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Donor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s calls about potential donors, for instance, come from emergency rooms. `` That's awfully early to make a decision about a person being brain-dead,'' a condition in which the brain no longer functions but the body is sustained by machine, said <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, executive director of the San Francisco-based network. Part of the problem, in general, is that `` dying and death are taboo subjects'' among health-care professionals, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiernan </PERSON>, administrator of the organ recovery program for The <LOCATION> Presbyterian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` It seems to me we might do a better job of requesting donations if these requests are made within the context of an effective bereavement program,'' he said. In addition to poorly implemented consent laws, experts say, the supply of healthy organs has been reduced as recent safety measures _ including seat belt and motorcycle helmet laws _ have cut down on the number of premature deaths. The pool of potential organ donors also has been reduced in places by the growing number of people testing positive for the AIDS virus. Only about 4,000 of the estimated 22,000 to 25,000 potential organ donors actually become donors each year, <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. A record 14,720 people, meanwhile, are awaiting transplants in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaughn </PERSON>, technical services director for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sharing </ORGANIZATION>. `` It may well be that we will never meet the need,'' <PERSON> Kiernan </PERSON> said, `` no matter what we do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-RefusenikShowdown     05-31 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Refusenik Showdown,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sources: Soviet Official Warned Reagan Party About Refusenik Visit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President and Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> agonized over whether to visit a Jewish refusenik family after a top <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official warned that it would ruin the family's chances to emigrate, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources say. In the end, the visit never came off. And a 12-year-old girl who calls herself `` a lifelong refusenik'' was disappointed. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources speaking on condition of anonymity said Monday that Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Alexandr </PERSON> <PERSON> Bessmertnykh </PERSON> warned <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON> during a summit planning meeting last week that the <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON> family would never be permitted to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> visited. `` It went back and forth several times'' as the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aides considered the dilemma, one source said. `` They did n't want to knuckle under to intimidation, but they did n't want to hurt the Ziemans, either.'' Instead of making the visit, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> toured the Arbat mall in downtown <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The Ziemans waited patiently until it was clear the president would not be coming. The Ziemans' 12-year-old daughter <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> had appealed to the Reagans for help in getting her and her family out of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Americans who meet her unfailingly note <PERSON> Vera </PERSON>'s uncanny resemblance to Little Orphan <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> with her curly hair and cherub cheeks. She speaks English with a British accent, as taught by her mother. She calls herself a `` lifelong refusenik'' because the family has been refused permission to emigrate virtually since her birth. `` My name is <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON>,'' she wrote the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> last month, `` but everybody calls me ` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Orphan <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>.''' `` My elder sister, who lives in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> now, tries desperately to help us get permission to leave the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Vera </PERSON> wrote the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>. `` I wish and wish I could do something too. So I made up my mind to venture to ask you for help.'' She told of her family's efforts to emigrate and of the hardships her parents have suffered since becoming refuseniks. Her father, who has worked as a plumber since losing his scientific post, recently suffered a mysterious brain ailment that has affected his vision and balance. During his hospitalization for that condition, he contracted hepatitis and has been confined to bed, although he got up to attend the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> reception on Monday. <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>, a career diplomat who has dealt with the Soviets throughout much of his professional career, refused to respond to queries about the incident. But other sources who participated in planning the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' visit said the blunt warning came from <PERSON> Bessmertnykh </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>'s principal contacts in the Soviet government. Several sources confirmed all or part of this account on condition they not be identified by name. A White House spokesman, <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON>, said the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would not comment on the report, and <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> responded only indirectly, saying the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> were free to meet with whom they please. <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vera </PERSON>'s father, was asked at a reception <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gave for Soviet dissidents and refuseniks Monday whether he thought a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> visit would have made it more difficult for them to emigrate, a goal they have sought since 1977. `` How do we know?'' he told reporters. `` That's a very Soviet-like statement, like ` Do n't try to emigrate; do n't believe in God.' A White House advance party made a discreet visit to the Ziemans' home in a shabby apartment building in southwest <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to let them know the Reagans might come to see them. They made no commitment. It was not clear how the Soviets learned of the plan, although the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> keeps close watch on American diplomats, Soviet dissidents and refuseniks, Soviet Jews who have been refused permission to leave the country. <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON>, a former computer scientist who lost his job when he applied for an exit visa 11 years ago, has been told he is not allowed to leave for security reasons, although he contends he never had access to state secrets and has no information that could threaten Soviet security.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChurchillBiography     05-31 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Churchill Biography,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Origins of Summitry Recounted in Last Volume of Epic Churchill
Biography</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In 1953, they scoffed when Sir <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> proposed a summit conference between East and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. Today, as Britons buy the final volume of his biography, they're not scoffing. The last volume of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s `` Winston S. Churchill,'' which goes on sale today, illustrates the foresight that often placed the British statesman so far ahead of events that he invited ridicule. The work recounts how <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> tried to bring about a summit meeting similar to the one this week in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s wartime prime minister even coined the term `` summit.'' Yet he was rebuffed by his own Cabinet and President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> _ who also foresaw the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> threat, the end of British global pre-eminence and the atomic bomb _ wrote to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> in 1953 pleading for a summit with the Soviet leadership that took over after <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> died. But it was the height of the Cold War, and <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> replied that a summit would serve only the Soviet `` propaganda mill.'' In a speech to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> envisioned a summit, held in a secluded setting, in which `` there might be a general feeling among those gathered together that they might do something better than tear the human race, including themselves, to bits.'' <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Eden </PERSON>, <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>'s foreign secretary, viewed the summit offer as a signal of weakness to the Soviets and wrote in his diary: `` It must be long in history since any one speech did so much damage to its own side.'' <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> also asked <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> to approve a message to <PERSON> Vyacheslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Molotov </PERSON>, the Soviet foreign minister, offering to go to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for informal talks. The president rejected the idea, expressing `` a bit of astonishment'' and the `` suspicion that anything the Kremlin could misinterpret as weakness or over-eagerness on our part would militate against success in negotiation.'' <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> left office in 1955 and died 10 years later, aged 91, having failed to bring about a summit. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said in an intervew: `` Churchill had a belief which is now, if you like, fulfilled in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> ... a belief that if only the leaders could sit down together, progress could be made. `` This was belittled by all the politicians as absurd and fanciful, and yet <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> are sitting down, new agreements have been signed, a whole new atmosphere has been created, and <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> set it all out in 1953, 1954 and 1955 to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>.'' Critics have acclaimed `` Never Despair,'' the final volume, and compared the biography to `` The Rise and Fall of the Roman Empire.'' It fills eight volumes and 8,664 pages and took 25 years to write. Still to come are 13 companion volumes of documents. With the companion volumes, `` Winston S. Churchill'' was in the Guinness Book of Records as the world's longest biography even before the final 1,359-page installment was published in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mifflin </LOCATION> soon will issue it in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>, 51, is an <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> historian. He began as an assistant to <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON>, who wrote the first two volumes, and took over when <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> died in 1967. Shining through the final volume covering <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>'s last 20 years are his qualities of doggedness, eloquence, sense of history and unflagging gallantry to his monarch, colleagues and even political foes. He was a prodigious author but never one to `` kiss and tell.'' He sent the manuscript of his wartime memoirs to <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> asking if there was anything <PERSON> Ike </PERSON> did not want mentioned. The final lines of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s book, quoting a letter to <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> from his daughter <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Soames </PERSON>, are a fitting commentary on his leadership in the dark years of World War II: `` In addition to all the feelings a daughter has for a loving, generous father, I owe you what every Englishman, woman and child does _ Liberty itself.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Summit-Schedule     05-31 0100</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Summit-Schedule,100</SECOND>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 10 a.m. -LRB- 2 a.m. EDT -RRB- _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> arrives Kremlin. 11:55 a.m. -LRB- 3:55 a.m. EDT -RRB- _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> arrives at <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Men </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Letters </ORGANIZATION> for lunch with artists. 1:25 p.m. -LRB- 5:25 a.m. EDT -RRB- _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> arrives <ORGANIZATION> Spaso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. 3:45 p.m. -LRB- 7:45 a.m. EDT -RRB- _ <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> arrives <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- speech at 4:05 p.m. _ 8:05 a.m. EDT -RRB- -RRB- 8 p.m. -LRB- Noon EDT -RRB- _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> reciprocal dinner at <LOCATION> Spaso </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CommunistTaxBreaks 1stLd-Writethru a0426 05-31 0979</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Communist Tax Breaks, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0426,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: These People Are Communists, But Some of Them Are
Acting Like ...</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 15th graf pvs, bgng, For the, to delete extraneous
words, capitalize Western and delete dollar sign before rubles;
subs 17th graf pvs, bgng, One new, to capitalize West; picks up
18th graf, Prices at xxx.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You fly in on the state airline, <ORGANIZATION> Aeroflot </ORGANIZATION>, make your way through <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> passport and customs control and catch a ride downtown with a driver from the state travel monopoly, Intourist. GUM, the huge state-owned department store, is packed _ but not because there's a sale on. There are no sales, the prices are fixed by ... that's right, the state. That's life in the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION>. This is, after all, a communist state. But less so, it seems, every day that perestroika survives. If the buzzword of the 1980s in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has been entrepreneurship, the key word here is cooperatives. Under the banner of perestroika, the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> campaign to restructure the nation's stagnant economy, authorities last week acted on new laws that will encourage the expansion of cooperatives, economic units akin in many ways to the small business sector of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, except that all employees are co-owners and thus share in the profits. Profits? Profits have come to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and thus profit motive. Soviet Premier <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryzhkov </PERSON> said last week that 14,000 cooperatives were formed in the first 18 months they were permitted, with another 6,000 formed in the past three months. The cooperative system, he said optimistically, `` in a short time can solve the most severe problems of perestroika, the demand of the population for goods and services.'' Perestroika signals a dramatic evolution in the communist economy that has built a huge military might and an ominous bureaucracy, but little in the way of consumer services that people in the West have come to take for granted. Foreigners who live here send out to <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> for the finer things in life. When the train from <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> arrives at <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> here, it is loaded down with the fruits of the capitalist West, such as dishwashing detergent, modern ranges, fresh produce and Big Macs. Soviet citizens have neither the income, nor the hard currency nor the authority to order out. Instead, they shop in state-owned shops where variety is rare and the stock is either overpriced or depleted. As a rule, quality is nothing to brag about either. Perestroika is already in deep trouble, not the least because economic restructuring has brought the uncertainties of layoffs and future price increases, without any of the rewards of a true consumer economy. Change has been a long time coming to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The local press has come to dismiss the Brezhnev-to-Chernenko era, 1964-1985, as the `` period of stagnation.'' That said, the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> News _ a state-controlled paper that takes advantage of glasnost -LRB- the democratic companion of perestroika -RRB- to push the economic reforms on the front page _ has run reams about cooperatives. It's the hot topic in town, at least among the intellectuals and the foreign community. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, you ask a cabbie to take you to <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s maybe. In <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, you ask for a cooperative and if you're lucky, you make your way to one of the new restaurants _ owned by its employees, who pocket the profit and thus have an incentive to create an attractive dinner or sew an attractive dress For the past six months, the way to the <LOCATION> Vavilova </LOCATION> market has become lined with wooden stalls and card tables, as vendors sell whatever they can make or get their hands on. One young lady is modeling a red-and-white striped apron and has a dozen on the table starting at 30 rubles -LRB- about $ 50 -RRB-. A fellow across the way has got his hands on some stylish Western blue jeans _ for sale, he says, at 130 rubles -LRB- $ 200, a month's pay for many Muscovites -RRB-. After dinner, walk through the Arbat shopping mall _ or even <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> _ and you see artists selling their portraits of St. Basil's Cathedral or the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mausoleum </ORGANIZATION> They implore. They barter. They discount. They would be capitalists or eccentrics at the <LOCATION> Pontevecchio </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, or in <LOCATION> Ghirardelli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, but in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> they call themselves cooperatives. One new co-op restaurant in the northern section of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> displays the stickers of major credit cards familiar in the West and tries to make foreigners pay with plastic, an open violation of currency laws that forbid practically all private trade in hard currency. Prices at the restaurant double at midnight, and one unwary foursome found themselves stuck with a 98-ruble -LRB- $ 170 -RRB- bill for dinner, outrageous by Soviet standards but more and more common as co-ops learn the demand is there at practically any price in this supply-starved economy. This turn in the local economy is not without controversy or opposition, and many are the residents who recall Khrushchev-era reform efforts and expect this go-round to go-round, too. The current edition of the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> has a piece whose front-page teaser says, `` Worker Demands A Revision of the Law on State Enterprise.'' The worker, identified as steelmaker <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Koptev </PERSON>, complained in an open letter to the Supreme Soviet that there are people putting roadblocks before the cooperative economy. Last week, the Supreme Soviet _ always your basic rubber stamp in this one-party society _ rebelled against a proposal to encourage cooperatives and insisted on a shift in the tax laws that would allow employees to keep a greater percentage of the profits. That's right, they were considering tax breaks. Tax breaks? It seems like curious business for Soviet communists.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITORS NOTE: <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is assistant chief of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Soviet-Rights     05-31 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Soviet-Rights,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Media Highlighting US Human Rights Abuses</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit-Dissidents</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN FRIEDMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet media are highlighting cases the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION> perceives as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> human rights abuses, in an apparent bid to counterbalance President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s meeting with dissidents and refuseniks. The official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> carried a critical commentary in advance of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s meeting Monday at <ORGANIZATION> Spaso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, quoting Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrovsky </PERSON> as saying such an action `` is hardly aimed at improving understanding between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper Pravda told its readers that although the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is a land of scientific and technological marvels, it is also a land of homelessness, hunger and repression of minorities. On a day when news of the summit meeting dominated the pages of the newspaper, it printed a photograph of blacks in shabby clothes lining up for a free Thanksgiving Day meal at <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, noting it was across the street from the White House. On the bottom of the same page, it printed a story about <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>, an American Indian convicted of killing two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents in 1975 at the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>'s case has been cited by Soviet officials as an example of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> human rights violations. Civil rights lawyer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunstler </PERSON> said recently that the treatment of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should be raised as a human rights issue at the summit. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in one of its newscasts Monday mentioned a May 23 report by a panel of 40 prominent Americans that said minorities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> were failing to make progress in efforts to achieve full participation `` in the life and prosperity of the nation.'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> also publicized a news conference Monday by four Americans who came to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to speak about alleged <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> human rights abuses involving minorities. The four `` wanted to make human rights part of the agenda'' at the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit and provide `` a balanced view,'' said one of the participants, lawyer <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> commentary said the Soviet government is `` seriously concerned'' about the human rights situation in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, especially `` discrimination against national minorities, persecution of people because of their political views and the passing of death sentences on minors.'' It also said that ideological disputes between the superpowers are inevitable, but `` one can not put up with the fact that the subject of human rights is exploited for purposes of whipping up hostility in inter-state relations, for impeding the processes of disarmament and detente.'' The Soviet Peace Committee was the setting for the news conference by the four American human rights activists, but <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said they all paid their own way to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> and Indian rights activist <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzales </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said that besides <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>, the activists wanted to publicize the human rights cases of racial minorities, the homeless, the hungry, institutionalized disabled people, and those refugees and asylum-seekers who have been forcibly returned to the country from which they fled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Dissidents     05-31 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Dissidents,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Reagan Meets With Dissidents, Gorbachev Cautions Against
`Sermonizing'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At the end of a day in which President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> demonstrated his sympathy with Soviet dissidents, Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> cautioned against `` sermonizing'' that could sour superpower relations. The general secretary's comments came at a state dinner, hours after the president's meeting with dissidents and Jewish refuseniks drew terse comments from other Soviet officials. <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, the Soviet foreign ministry spokesman, said those who attended the emotion-laden session with the president at the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> ambassador's home were `` not the best of the Soviet people.'' He dismissed a question about whether the dissidents could face reprisals as a result of the meeting: `` I met Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> today, but I do n't think I am going to be harmed in any way by just meeting him.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, in his toast at the dinner for the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> Monday night, said, `` We want to build contacts among people in all forms, to expand and improve the quality of information, and to develop ties in the spheres of science, culture, education, sports, and any other human endeavor.'' `` But this should be done without interfering in domestic affairs, without sermonizing, or imposing one's views and ways, without turning family or personal problems into a pretext for confrontation between states,'' the Soviet leader said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> expressed hope that his push for improvements in human rights in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would get results under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s leadership `` I've come to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> with this human rights agenda because, as I suggested, it is our belief that this is a moment of hope. The new Soviet leaders appear to grasp the connection between certain freedoms and economic growth,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said at <LOCATION> Spaso </LOCATION> house during the meeting with dissidents and refuseniks. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also visited the 13th century <LOCATION> Danilov </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monastery </LOCATION> where monks practice the Russian Orthodox faith in the communist country. There, he told the monks, `` The faith of your people has been tested and tempered in the crucible of hardship. We may hope that perestroika will be accompanied by a deeper restructuring ... and that glasnost, which means giving voice, will also let loose a new chorus of belief.'' `` Our people feel it keenly when religious freedom is denied to anyone anywhere, and hope with you that soon all the many Soviet religious communities ... including the Ukrainian Catholic and Orthodox Churches, will soon be able to practice their religion freely and openly,'' he said. At the meeting of prominent dissidents, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sat next to <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Stollar </PERSON>, the 73-year-old American who came to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as a child in the 1930s and has battled since 1975 to get himself and his family out of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Those at his table included <PERSON> Lev </PERSON> <PERSON> Timofeyev </PERSON>, an activist released from prison last February; <PERSON> Tatyana </PERSON> <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON>, a Jewish refusenik; the Rev. Modris Plate, a Lutheran minister from <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Pytras </PERSON> <PERSON> Pakenas </PERSON>, a Lithuanian who is married to an American but can not leave the country. Both <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrovsky </PERSON>, the deputy foreign minister, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was free to do what he wanted in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Petrovsky </PERSON> implied <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had breached protocol by seeing the 100 or so Soviets who are at odds with their country's policies. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> could have seen anyone at the U.S.-Soviet summit in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last December, but `` took into account all nuances'' so the summit would be a success, <PERSON> Petrovsky </PERSON> said in remarks quoted by the news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION>. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> action of this kind is hardly aimed at improving understanding between the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> six months ago, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> reacted heatedly when he was pressed by newspaper editors on his stand on human rights. Soviet officials have long told Americans to mind their own business on the issue. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, signed autographs during the session at which a few children roamed around the large dining room. `` We are not so used to hearing such human words without any political statement,'' said <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON>, a former computer scientist who lost his job when he applied for an exit visa 11 years ago. <PERSON> Zieman </PERSON> said there was no telling whether the session with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would expedite emigration. `` How do we know?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880531-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-31-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Drugs     05-31 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Drugs,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Priest Can't Get Mrs. Reagan Interested In `Just Say Nyet'
Campaign</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
