<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0556EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Clark-Hope     09-10 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Clark-Hope,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bob Hope Host of Fund-Raiser for Roy Clark's Trip to USSR</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> wants to send country singer <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> `` to <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> with love,'' and played host of a fund-raising dinner in pursuit of that goal. At Friday's dinner, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said he was eager to return to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on his second goodwill tour. `` I guess I was the first person to introduce country music to the Russians, and they loved it,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` I, in turn, loved them. They're just people, not so different from us.'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said work songs like `` Sixteen Tons'' were the most-requested tunes when he first toured the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1976. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who stars on the television show `` <PERSON> Hee </PERSON> <PERSON> Haw </PERSON>,'' will give 12 concerts in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> on this tour, which is partially funded by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the official Soviet talent agency Gosconcert. Tennessee Sens. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> joined <PERSON> Hee </PERSON> <PERSON> Haw </PERSON> co-star <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON> at the fund-raiser, which included some light jabs at Clark by <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>. `` I send him to <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>, with love,'' <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> said. `` It's either send him, or deport him. Who else would want him, except maybe his wife?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0621 09-10 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0621,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Storm Gilbert Becomes Hurricane In Caribbean</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE WITH Gilbert upgraded to
hurricane. Picks up 7th graf pvs `Two weeks...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical Storm <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> strengthened into a hurricane Saturday night in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, boasting maximum sustained winds of nearly 75 mph, forecasters said. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was expected drop 5 to 10 inches of rain on <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> by Sunday, the National Hurricane Center said. At 10:30 p.m. EDT Saturday, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was centered 225 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Santo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Domingo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. It was near latitude 16.0 north, longitude 67.3 west. Forecasters expected the storm to continue to strengthen. `` The system is becoming better organized,'' said <PERSON> Lixion </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>, hurricane center meteorologist. `` The convection is becoming concentrated in the center.'' The storm was expected to continue moving west at near 15 mph for the next 24 hours. The government of the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> issued a hurricane warning for the <PERSON> Barahona </PERSON> peninsula. Two weeks ago, a depression that later became Tropical Storm <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> dumped 6.6 inches of rain on <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, causing mudslides and flooding blamed for three deaths and damage to more than 100 homes. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> came ashore Aug. 28 at <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, destroying more than a dozen mobile homes, killing one person, and leaving thousands temporarily without power before losing steam over land. Meanwhile, the remnants of hurricane <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> moved into <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> on Saturday while thousands of evacuated <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> residents returned to their homes. Most found little damage from the storm's 80 mph wind. Officials blamed <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> for one death. The 1988 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season has had eight named storms, two of which strengthened into short-lived hurricanes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Fires-Animals     09-10 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fires-Animals,0309</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least Two Large Animals Confirmed Killed</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Forest Fires Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COOKE CITY, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A black bear and a mule deer buck are the first large animals confirmed killed by the forest fires in and near <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, and firefighters have been warned to avoid any injured animals. Yellowstone National Park officials had repeatedly said that larger animals such as deer, elk, bison and bear can easily sidestep fires that advance normally. However, fires in the <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> area have not behaved normally. Veteran firefighters in and around the park say they have never seen fire move so far, so quickly. The black bear was suffering from deep burns on its feet and was unable to do more than lift its head Friday evening, said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Safford </PERSON>, a highway patrolman who was given permission by state and local officials to shoot and kill the suffering animal about a half mile east of Silver Gate. `` All four pads were burned off the feet and down to the bone. He must have run through a bunch of hot coals. It looked to me like he would have been permanently immobile,'' <PERSON> Safford </PERSON> said. The bear, about 4 years old, had been seen lying in a marsh about 200 yards above a highway for about 24 hours before it was killed. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Folenius </PERSON>, safety officer on the Storm Creek fire, told firefighters at Saturday's 6 a.m. briefing that there had been sightings of some hurt bears and cautioned firefighters to be careful around them if they were spotted. About seven miles west of where the bear was killed, the charred carcass of a mature buck deer lay beside the road to <LOCATION> Daisy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>. Fire scoured the area Wednesday. Another carcass was reported to be nearby, but could not be located.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0656EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CarFishing     09-10 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Car Fishing,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Go Fishing, Catch Six Vehicles</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fishing expedition in the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> netted city and state police five cars and a late-model truck. Acting on a tip, police divers searched the river Thursday and found the vehicles at the end of a pier near the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>. They used a crane to raise them from the river. At least 10 more vehicles rest on the bottom of that part of the river, police said. The truck had the name and telephone number of a <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> pizzeria on its side. Owner <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohr </PERSON> said the truck was stolen early Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0601EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Rebels     09-10 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Rebels,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burma Rebel Leader Quoted As Supporting Student Demonstrators</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Burma</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Burmese rebel leader was quoted today as saying his group would provide military support to student protesters if fighting broke out with the armed forces in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brang </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON> said the support would include weapons, training and sanctuary if needed, according to a report in the English-language <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> Standard. <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> has been wracked by weeks of unrest. Students have led demonstrations seeking to replace one-party rule with a democratic government. In the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> capital of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> today, the ruling party announced it would end its 26-year monopoly on power and hold general elections under a multiparty system. The newspaper said <LOCATION> Brang </LOCATION> Seng, a key figure in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, had predicted today's action in an interview in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> earlier this week. `` The fact is that they have to abdicate, to leave, to relinquish,'' he was quoted as saying. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> could not stay in power much longer. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> is an alliance of 10 rebel groups, all ethnic minorities, fighting the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> Brang </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON> told the Standard that the front had adopted a `` wait and see'' attitude as anti-government demonstrations swept the country. But he said student leaders had been promised support from the rebels. `` We will provide provisions, we will accept them in areas that are totally liberated by us, and we will, if the need arises, train and equip them to be ready for that eventuality -LRB- of military confrontation -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Brang </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON> was quoted as saying. The Standard said <PERSON> Brang </PERSON> <PERSON> Seng </PERSON>, who belongs to an organization of the <LOCATION> Kachin </LOCATION> minority group, had left the British colony, but it did not say where he went.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-China Bjt   09-10 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-China, Bjt,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sale of Satellites to China Seen Harming U.S. Security, Space
Industry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration wins final approval of its plan to allow <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to launch U.S.-made communications satellites, national security will be damaged and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial space industry will be `` cut off at the knees,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congressman says. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., whose district includes the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space launch center at <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, told reporters that chances to overturn the decision in the few remaining days of the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are `` very slim. `` We'll give it the old college try, but it will be very difficult to beat them back,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. Friday's announcement represented a victory for the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which overrode contentions by the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and private industry that the deal will place <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producers of satellite launchers at a competitive disadvantage. The plan was denounced by <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which makes rockets for commercial use. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said the transaction is the first of its kind involving a `` non-Western'' destination. Another official, speaking only on condition of anonymity, said President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made the final decision because of the inter-agency conflict. The transaction is subject to approval by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and by a group of Western allies that monitor high-technology transfers. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said he believes national security will be damaged if the deal goes through because `` when we allow them to integrate one of the most sophisticated satellites known to planet <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> onto a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> rocket we have just given away a great part of the American advantage.'' He said the sale will enable the Chinese to learn technology in which the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has the world's leading edge. `` We're giving away American jobs and the technology needed to keep those jobs,'' the congressman asserted. `` The nation is ill served by this decision because it cuts the fledgling American rocket industry off at the knees.'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said a license application was submitted by <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the Chinese launch of two of its satellites which have been ordered by an Australian consortium, <ORGANIZATION> AUSSAT </ORGANIZATION>. He also announced the conditional approval of a license for the launch of a third U.S.-made satellite on a Chinese launch vehicle. Known as AsiaSat, the satellite will be launched on behalf of a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong-based </LOCATION> consortium with Chinese and British ownership. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said that in reaching its decision, the administration was trying to assure the ability of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial launch industry `` to compete on an equal footing with launches from a non-market economy, while continuing to promote increased U.S.-China trade.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PostalCutbacks Bjt   09-10 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Postal Cutbacks, Bjt,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Postal Window Service Restored</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Postal Service today is restoring the window services it cut last February in a move that saved $ 40 million and helped cushion an expected $ 500 million deficit this year for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mail system. Hours at post offices wo n't necessarily be the same as before the cuts were imposed, however, with local managers allowed to make changes that they think best serve their customers. Ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to cut out $ 160 million in spending, the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> made a series of changes, including reducing window hours at most offices by a half-day per week. The reduction in hours drew heavy criticism, coming just two months before postage rates were increased. Postmaster General <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> has struggled to explain that the two events were not related. The rate increase was in response to a rising deficit, and had been in the works for more than a year. The service cuts were necessitated when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> unexpectedly ordered the spending reduction. It was part of an effort to reduce the overall federal budget, even though the post office no longer receives a taxpayer subsidy. In restoring the window hours, local managers were given the option to adjust hours to suit the needs of their communities. For example, Saturday hours will not be restored in heavily Jewish sections of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where little business was done on that day anyway because of the sabbath. Instead, managers will experiment with staying open later some days or perhaps having some Sunday office hours. In other areas, instead of extending hours overall, managers will add more clerks to handle business during peak times. While the hours of window clerk service are returning, other money-saving cuts imposed in February remain in effect, including curtailment of Sunday mail collection and sorting and a moratorium on construction of new post offices. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, is considering bills to remove the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> from the federal budget as a way to avoid similar service reductions in the future. The window closings saved about $ 40 million, officials reported. Unless action is taken, the <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> faces another $ 270 million in spending cuts in the fiscal year that starts Oct. 1. That will not mean that hours will be cut again, however. Postal managers say they have found ways to cut spending _ although at the cost of slower service _ by such things as switching some mail from airplanes to trucks, changing trucking schedules, reducing management travel and training spending and cutting research and development. The <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> expects to finish the current fiscal year at the end of this month with a deficit of between $ 500 million and $ 550 million. Higher postage rates which took effect April 4 are expected to help boost the agency into the black in fiscal 1989, however. The <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has managed to break even over the last decade, losing money in some years and showing a surplus in others.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Opium     09-10 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Opium,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scavenger Sentenced To Death For Opium Possession</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The High Court sentenced a 78-year-old scavenger to death by hanging after convicting him of possessing 6.4 pounds of opium. <PERSON> Teng </PERSON> <PERSON> Soi </PERSON> told the court he had just picked up the bag containing the opium at a dump when he was arrested Nov. 24, 1984. He said he did not know what was in the bag. Justice K.C. <PERSON> Vohrah </PERSON>, in passing the death sentence, said it was improbable anyone would throw into the garbage that amount of cocaine. <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> in 1975 passed laws providing the death penalty for drug trafficking. Since then, 184 people have been sentenced to death and 62 have been executed by hanging. The others are awaiting appeals or execution dates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EltonJohn     09-10 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elton John,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four-Day Elton John Sale Reaps More Than $8 Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Small spenders were out in force for the final day of an auction of <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s belongings, purchasing the rock star's soap dish, chamber pot and even the posters advertising the sale. The sale, which ended Friday, reaped a total of $ 8.17 million. `` A lot of this stuff was cheap, and small private buyers could afford it,'' said <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s auction house. `` Lots of them were <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> fans.'' The sale started Tuesday and consisted of 1,922 lots, including <PERSON> Rembrandt </PERSON> etchings, an umbrella with a large `` E'' for the handle, a replica of Egyptian <PERSON> Pharoah </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutankhamun </PERSON>'s throne, and the singer's stilt-like boots from the 1975 film `` <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s had expected the sale to bring in $ 5 million. Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said the final two days brought in $ 2.63 million, but she could not provide a figure for Friday alone. Small and unusual items went on the block Friday, Ms. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said. Among them were a pair of silver Cartier bowls, one of which <PERSON> John </PERSON> used as a soap dish in his bathroom. They sold for about $ 1,030. A chamber pot fetched $ 270. One American fan paid about $ 930 for the plastic banners advertising the sale. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s cassette-tape player, in a miniature grand piano, sold for $ 1,765 while a penny-operated amusement machine fetched $ 820. Top prices went to statuettes by the French artist <PERSON> Erte </PERSON>. One, of a woman holding a globe, sold for $ 14,315, almost five times the expected price. <PERSON> John </PERSON>, 41, has said he wants to make room in his mansion near <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>, west of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, to start new collections. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s said he kept up with the auction proceedings by telephone from <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. The singer's varied art collection sold for $ 1.3 million Thursday. His stage costumes, memorabilia, furniture, ornaments and jewelry were sold Tuesday and Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--GangKilling     09-10 0079</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Gang Killing,0079</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lumber Industrialist Killed, Two Wounded</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GUARDAVALLE, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen killed a lumber industrialist in an apparent gangland reprisal and wounded two men who went to his aid, police said. <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> <PERSON> Emanuele </PERSON>, 45, was shot Thursday night outside his home in the hills of southern <LOCATION> Calabria </LOCATION>, police reported Friday. He was the third businessmen killed in the town since April in what investigators believe were reprisals for refusing to pay extortion money to underworld gangs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r m PM-BRF--Iran-Nuclear     09-10 0105</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Iran-Nuclear,0107</SECOND>
<HEAD>International Team to Inspect Iranian Nuclear Plant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A team from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> arrived in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> to survey the effects of Iraqi attacks on an atomic power plant on the eastern <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Tehran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> reported. The state-run radio, monitored Friday in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said the team was invited by the <ORGANIZATION> Iranian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to inspect the <LOCATION> Bushehr </LOCATION> plant. The radio quoted one agency official as saying the <ORGANIZATION> IAEA </ORGANIZATION> condemns military attacks against atomic installations. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> reported several attacks on the plant shortly before a U.N.-sponsored cease-fire between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> took effect on Aug. 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Spain-AirCrash     09-10 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spain-Air Crash,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spanish Plane Crashes, Killing All Four Occupants</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A plane used in fighting forest fires crashed near an airport outside this northwestern <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> city, killing all four of its occupants, airport officials said. Officials said one of the motors of the plane apparently failed shortly after the aircraft took off Friday from <LOCATION> Labacolla </LOCATION> airport. The plane crashed into a forest nearby. The victims were two captains, one lieutenant and one non-commissioned officer of the Spanish <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. The Labacolla-based plane had been taking part in efforts to combat a forest fire in <LOCATION> Orense </LOCATION> province in northwestern <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen     09-10 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>VP Nominee Courts Labor, Law and Order Votes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is fighting for votes in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> by blasting the Republicans on labor issues and trying to show strength where the Democrats have a weak image: law and order. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> today planned to visit Operation Safe Streets, a <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> program in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Carson </LOCATION> to combat crime, including gang violence. The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator has criticized the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for cutting money to help local law enforcement efforts. He also planned to attend a rally today in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> before returning to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> for a dinner honoring <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. On Friday in <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION> east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> attended a rally in a union hall to where he took part in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> campaign to give 60 days notice to the Republicans before election day. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told the cheering crowd, many waving giant `` pink slips'' for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, that `` We're here today to give the Republicans a better break than they give the American worker.'' `` Sure, we could provide notice the Republican way,'' he said. `` We could go there election eve and we could change the locks on the door. `` We could take the vice president's <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> mess card and cancel that. And we could take away <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Two </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` But we agree with the vast majority of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people who say 60 days notice is fair.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, digging at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as he mined for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s 47 electoral votes, said the vice president has had many `` conversions'' on issues lately. `` He's like a successful missionary. He has a conversion every day,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` But the only problem -LRB- is -RRB- he's converting himself. Last week he discovered the environment. This week he discovered the minimum wage and said well maybe, maybe it should be raised. And the next day he really was n't so sure.'' Earlier Friday, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told farmers in Amana, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his running mate, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, do n't understand rural needs. Asked by reporters about <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' controversial statement during the primaries suggesting that farmers grow Belgian endives to help solve their problems, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor now has a better understanding. `` I'm sure he does,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-TextileBill-Glance     09-10 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Textile Bill-Glance,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Textile Bill Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here at a glance are provisions of the textile trade legislation approved Friday by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>: TEXTILE AND APPAREL IMPORTS Freezes overall textile and apparel imports this year at 1987 levels and limits future growth to one percent annually. NONRUBBER FOOTWEAR IMPORTS Freezes overall imports of nonrubber footwear at 1987 levels with no provision for increases in the future. AGRICULTURAL PROVISION Provides for preferred trade treatment for countries that increase their purchases of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural goods. AUCTIONED QUOTAS Requires the government to auction off import quotas among American importing companies. COMPENSATION Authorizes the president to negotiate reduced tariffs to compensate countries hurt by tightened import restraints.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-SenateTextileRollCall     09-10 0379</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Senate Textile Roll Call,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Textile Bill Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 57-32 roll call Friday by which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved new curbs on textile, apparel and non-rubber footwear imports. On this vote, a yes vote was a vote to impose the import restraints, while a no vote was a vote against doing so. Voting yes were 40 Democrats and 17 Republicans. Voting no were 9 Democrats and 23 Republicans. xxx denotes senators not voting. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., no; <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION>, R-Colo., no; <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., no; <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., yes; <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, R-Mo., yes; <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn., no; <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Miss </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., no; <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., xxx; Dodd, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., yes; <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., no; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., no; <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, D-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., yes; <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., xxx; <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, R-Nev., xxx; <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes; <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., yes; <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, R-Neb., xxx; <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan., no; <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., yes; <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., yes; <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., yes; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., yes; <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, R-Ind., no; <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>, D-Mont., yes; <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON>, D-Md., yes; <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., no; <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, R-Ind., xxx; <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, D-Nev., yes; <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, R-Del., yes; <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, yes; <LOCATION> Sanford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., yes; <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., yes; <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., yes; <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., yes; <LOCATION> Stafford </LOCATION>, R-Vt., xxx
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicaidAbortions     09-10 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicaid Abortions,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Effort To Amend Medicaid Abortion Rules Seems Doomed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first attempt to liberalize Medicaid abortion restrictions in seven years appears doomed to failure in the wake of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote to continue paying for abortions only when a woman's life is endangered. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 216-166 Friday to stand by existing policy rather than go along with a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> plan to permit government-financed abortions for poor victims of rape and incest. The abortion controversy arose in connection with a $ 140 billion spending bill for the departments of labor, education and health and human services that also included funds for AIDS and student financial aid. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators came to agreement on every other element of the massive fiscal 1989 appropriations bill, but were stymied on abortion. The House action added to mounting pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to back off its amendment. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said repeatedly he would veto the entire spending bill if abortion policy is liberalized. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> could act on the bill and the abortion question as early as Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, indicated `` We are disappointed but not defeated,'' said <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, in a statement after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote. Apparently anticipating a similar setback in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, she added, `` we shall redouble our efforts with the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the new administration and we'll try again.'' Under an amendment authored by Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., Medicaid pays only for abortions needed to save the life of a woman It had been seven years since either chamber had voted to liberalize the policy until the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> adopted the rape and incest provision on July 27. Specifically, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> measure said Medicaid would pay for abortions in cases of promptly reported rape or incest. States still would have the option of barring payments for all abortions except those necessary to save a woman's life. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, legislative director for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right-to-Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, issued a statement saying `` the groups pushing for these changes really want to restore federal funding of abortion on demand.'' Much of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> debate centered on the fundamental morality of abortion, despite the narrow focus of the amendment. `` You ca n't avoid injustice in a rape situation. You ca n't avoid injustice in an incest situation. But why compound the injustice by putting on top of it exterminating an innocent human life?'' <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> said. `` Do n't make us a part of that double tragedy. ... Out of great, great tragedy, some good can come.'' Lawmakers on the other side argued with equal passion that poor women victimized by brutal crimes are entitled to a full range of medical options. `` The consequences to individuals are very substantial,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Steny </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyer </PERSON>, D-Md. `` This is the appropriate and sensitive and humane step for us to take.'' <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Wattleton </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Planned </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parenthood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, accused the House of treating poor women callously. `` To force a woman to bear her rapist's child because she is poor is the cruelest insult imaginable,'' <PERSON> Wattleton </PERSON> said in a statement. However, some <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON> allies noted that medical procedures are available to prevent conception after rapes or incest. Others said the proposed exceptions would create problems for law enforcement officers confronted with reports of rape. `` What we're going to do is make liars out of women so that they can get an abortion funded by the government,'' contended Rep. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, D-Mo. Before moving to the abortion debate, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 335-60 to approve the other portions of the three-agency spending bill. The measure includes $ 1.2 billion for AIDS research, treatment, prevention and education; $ 4.3 billion in education grants for disadvantaged students; $ 5.5 billion in college student financial assistance, and $ 3.7 billion for the Job Training Partnership Act.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0634EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ThinBlueLine     09-10 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thin Blue Line,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Movie Provides New Look At Police Shooting</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EVAN RAMSTAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> has spent 12 years fighting to prove he did n't kill the policeman for whose murder he nearly was executed. The key witness now supports him, and a new movie based on <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' case has prompted petition drives demanding his freedom. `` The Thin Blue Line,'' directed by <PERSON> Errol </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, strongly suggests the wrong man was tried and petitions are circulating in theaters calling for a pardon. <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> District Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said he is unimpressed by the film, which is now playing in more than 200 cities, and sees no reason to reopen the case. `` Nothing in there convinces me we have the wrong man in jail,'' <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said this week. However, evidence <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> gathered in nearly three years of investigation, including prosecution witnesses who told him on camera that they lied in <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' 1977 trial, is being used by attorneys to prepare a motion for a new trial. `` The Thin Blue Line'' uses both real interviews with most of the key people in the case and re-enactments of the shooting from the perspectives of different characters. `` I'm not a reporter,'' <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said, adding he prefers to call the movie a `` non-fiction feature.'' On Nov. 28, 1976, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, then 27, ran out of gas driving home from work. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a teen-ager who'd stolen a car and driven to <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, helped <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> get gas and the pair spent the rest of the day drinking and smoking marijuana. That night, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> policeman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> was shot and killed after he and a partner stopped a car being driven with only its parking lights on. A month later, when police arrested <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> for an unrelated crime in his hometown of <LOCATION> Vidor </LOCATION>, in southeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, they learned he had bragged to friends about killing a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police officer. But when questioned by <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, who had no criminal record. With <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> the star prosecution witness, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was convicted of <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>'s slaying in 1977 and sentenced to die in the electric chair. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> received a stay three days before his May 1979 execution date. In 1980, his death sentence was commuted to life in prison after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that his trial jury had been improperly selected. The film ends with <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, now on death row himself for another murder, saying <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> did not kill <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>. In recent weeks, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> made similar statements to <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> news organizations. After <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>' statements appeared in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> newspapers, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said, `` Maybe now people will start to listen a little closer to what I've been saying for 12 years.'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> has not seen the movie. `` The ball is now in <PERSON> Vance </PERSON>'s court,'' said <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaffer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> lawyer. He said he expects to hear within two weeks whether the prosecutor will contest a motion on <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' behalf or seek a pardon from the governor. The motion `` basically has to do with suppression of favorable evidence, perjury by witnesses, favorable documents and reports that were supposed to be turned over to defense that were not,'' said <PERSON> Schaffer </PERSON>. `` And we have evidence with regard to -LRB- <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' -RRB- innocence.'' <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> said, `` It's not unusual for a man on death row to say the things <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> is saying.'' He wo n't say how he'll respond to the motion. Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON> was out of town Friday, but his aide, <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON>, said the office has gotten a number of letters about the case. He would not say what the governor's opinion was of the case. Petitions seeking a pardon initially were distributed by <PERSON> Miramax </PERSON>, the film's distribution company, said <ORGANIZATION> Miramax </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Christina </PERSON> <PERSON> Kounelias </PERSON>. Now the petitions are being handled by an Albany-based group called Solace, a support group for murder victim's families and a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. There was no immediate tally on how many signatures had been collected. Solace is also spearheading two fund-raisers for <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, one in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> next week and another in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> the following week. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> met <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> while interviewing inmates for another project. Intrigued, he arranged to meet <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, before <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> was arrested and convicted. `` That first night <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> told me that he would never forget the look in that cop's eyes, which was completely to the contrary to what he'd said at the trial, where he said he'd been in the passenger's seat slumped way down,'' <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said former District Attorney <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> `` provided me with evidence that <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> did not receive a fair trial in 1977, that it was an illegal trial.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0634EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseAbortionRollCall 3Takes   09-10 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Abortion Roll Call, 3 Takes,</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Medicaid Abortions</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 216-166 roll call Friday by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> refused to go along with a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> amendment expanding Medicaid abortions to rape and incest victims. A `` yes'' vote is a vote to keep existing law, which limits Medicaid payments to abortions needed to save a woman's life. A `` no'' vote was to change the law. Voting yes were 90 Democrats and 126 Republicans. Voting no were 136 Democrats and 30 Republicans. X denotes those not voting. Present denotes those who voted they were `` present'' at the time of the vote but did not vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on the issue. There are three vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, Y; Stump, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Anderson, Y; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON> N; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, N; Stark, X; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Badham </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Konnyu </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, Y; Packard, X; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, X, <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, N; MacKay, X; <PERSON> Mica </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, Y; Pepper, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, Y; Shaw, Y; Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, X; Costello, Y; <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lipinski </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Yates </LOCATION>, N. Republicans _ Crane, Y; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fawell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hastert </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Visclosky </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, Y; Coats, Y; <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>, Y; Myers, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Nagle </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Landlsides     09-10 0100</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Landlsides,0102</SECOND>
<HEAD>Landslides Bury 13</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KATMANDU, Nepal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thirteen people have been buried in landslides caused by torrential rains in a village west of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, officials said. The landslides occurred Wednesday in <LOCATION> Pangrang </LOCATION> village, 112 miles west of <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>. Assistant Minister of Works and Transport <PERSON> Chhetra </PERSON> <PERSON> Bahadur </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurung </PERSON> said Friday that only five bodies had been recovered from the debris, and rescuers were workin to find the other eight known to have died, including a pregnant woman. <PERSON> Gurung </PERSON> said 30 villagers were injured in the landslides, including three who were airlifted to nearby <LOCATION> Pokhara </LOCATION> town for medical treatment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0634EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseAbortionRollCall 1stAdd   09-10 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Abortion Roll Call, 1st Add,</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Whittaker, N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>KENTUCKY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Natcher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bunning </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>LOUISIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ Baker, Y; <LOCATION> Holloway </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAINE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MARYLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Cardin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hoyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McMillen </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mfume </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Morella </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MASSACHUSETTS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Boland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, Y; Early, Y; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, X. Republican _ <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Hertel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kildee </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Traxler </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wolpe </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Broomfield </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schuette </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Upton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagt </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MINNESOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Penny </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Sabo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Stangeland </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSISSIPPI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Dowdy, X; <PERSON> Espy </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSOURI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Clay, N; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, Y; Wheat, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Emerson </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MONTANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Williams, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Marlenee </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Bereuter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Daub </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEVADA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Bilbray </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Vucanovich </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW HAMPSHIRE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Guarini </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roukema </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Saxton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW MEXICO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Y. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republicans </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Lujan </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Skeen </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW YORK</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Hochbrueckner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> LaFalce </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Manton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McHugh </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, N; Slaughter, N; <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Stratton </LOCATION>, Y; Towns, X; <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> DioGuardi </PERSON>, Y; Fish, X; <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, X; Lent, Y; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wortley </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, N; Price, N; <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, N; Valentine, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ballenger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McMillan </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseAbortionRollCall 2ndAdd   09-10 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Abortion Roll Call, 2nd Add,</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: In Rhode Island section, St Germain, no period, is CQ</NOTE>
<HEAD>WASHN: Dorgan, Y.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>OHIO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, N; Hall, Y; <PERSON> Kaptur </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, Y; Oakar, Y; <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> DeWine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gradison </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> McEwen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Oxley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Regula </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OKLAHOMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ English, Y; <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Inhofe </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OREGON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> AuCoin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Borski, Y; <PERSON> Coyne </PERSON>, N; Foglietta, N; <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Kanjorski </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Kolter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Walgren </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Yatron </LOCATION>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gekas </PERSON>, N; Goodling, X; <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Shuster </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>RHODE ISLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <ORGANIZATION> St </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germain </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Derrick </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ravenel </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Spence </LOCATION>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TENNESSEE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lloyd </LOCATION>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sundquist </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TEXAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Andrews, N; <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, N; de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, N; Hall, Y; <PERSON> Leath </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Leland </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, Y; Pickle, N; <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, X -LRB- by tradition, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker seldom votes -RRB-. Republicans _ <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>, Y; DeLay, Y; Fields, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Sweeney </LOCATION>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>UTAH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Nielson </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VERMONT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sisisky </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bliley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, Y; Slaughter, Y; <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonker </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Chandler </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WEST VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Mollohan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON>, Y; Staggers, Y; Wise, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WISCONSIN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kleczka </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION>, N; Obey, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Petri </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WYOMING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>, X.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>END OF HOUSE ABORTION ROLL CALL _ 3 TAKES</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DeathRowTV     09-10 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Death Row TV,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>Slayer In Hurry To Hit Death Row</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man convicted of murdering his 20-year-old daughter asked a judge to confirm his death sentence as soon as possible so he can watch television in his cell, a prison spokesman says. `` Please bring me in and sentence me,'' <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, 47, of <PERSON> Moon </PERSON> <PERSON> Township </PERSON> said in a letter filed with <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Judge <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>'s office Friday. `` I thought the jury already sentenced me to death.'' <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> requested the quick action because it will put him in a section of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> where televisions are permitted, according to prison spokesman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Seiverling </PERSON>. A jury Aug. 23 sentenced <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> to die for the Feb. 19 stabbing death of daughter <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, also of <LOCATION> Moon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>. The murder occurred after <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>, a former apartment complex manager, confronted his daughter about stolen rent money. During his trial, <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> admitted having a 6-year incestuous relationship with the woman. Sixteen years ago, he was convicted of shooting his wife <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> to death as she slept. He served 8 -LCB- years in prison for that crime. <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is housed in an area of the prison where televisions are prohibited, <PERSON> Seiverling </PERSON> said. After <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> is sentenced by <PERSON> Manning </PERSON>, he will be housed in a restricted area of the prison reserved for inmates facing execution. Prisoners there are locked in their cells for all but 20 minutes each day, but are allowed to watch television. The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> automatically will review <PERSON> Starr </PERSON>'s death sentence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DogMeat     09-10 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dog Meat,0677</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumption Of Dogs, Snakes And Worms Continues Despite Ban</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First Available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> gourmets continue to enjoy dog stew and Korean Olympic stars have been consuming barrels of snake soup despite government attempts to ban the traditional delicacies during the Summer Games. The government has outlawed sales in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> of dog meat, snake, blood worm soup and other exotic dishes to avoid offending foreigners during the Olympics, which begin Sept. 17. Officials said visitors might be disgusted by the unusual culinary offerings and Koreans would be called barbaric. But the ban has had little or no effect on <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> restaurants or the eating habits of their customers. Dog meat is still a lunchtime favorite in many backstreet eateries. `` Even the government officials eat it. They just tell us not to let foreigners see,'' said one restaurant owner who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` The number of customers for dog has not dwindled. Not at all,'' he said with a big smile. Korean athletes training for the Olympics have been eating dog, snakes and deer antlers to help build up their strength and stamina. Boxers, wrestlers and others believe eating dog and snake will give them the endurance and strength of the animals. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> newspapers reported the <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amateur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> provided the country's womens' Olympic team with $ 28,000 worth of snake soup. Association officials declined to comment. Star player <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kye-sook </PERSON> was quoted by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> as saying, `` I was so surprised when the association officials brought the snake soup to us. But after taking the soup, I felt much stronger.'' Olympic soccer star <PERSON> Choi </PERSON> <PERSON> Soon-ho </PERSON> was quoted as saying he ate 500 snakes as part of his summer training. The Korean Amateur Wrestling Federation provided funds to the Olympic wrestling team to buy snake soup and `` kaesoju,'' a mixture of dog meat and herbs that builds strength, newspapers reported. Officials say a ban was imposed on dog meat in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> about five years ago because the government feared dog restaurants would offend Westerners and create an image of Koreans eating lovable pets. Sales continued, and restaurant owners say city officials recently repeated warnings not to serve dog during the Olympics. But they said officials told them restrictions would be eased after the Games. A senior official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the ban backfired by focusing attention on the dog meat issue. He said it also stirred protests from many Koreans about ridiculing national tradition. `` The French eat snails and horses and everyone says they are great eaters. Why should n't we eat dogmeat?'' he said. Koreans say dogs used for eating are specially raised just like cattle. They bridle at suggestions that pets are eaten and say they love and care for dogs as much as anyone. A restaurant owner, who takes pride in his own special recipe for dog stew, said the food was a traditional part of Korean cooking and a part of the nation's culture. The meat is seasoned with garlic and other spices and usually served as stew. `` How can our indigenous habits be cast away in a day,'' the man said. `` I'm sure this will not perish forever by any means.'' <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> municipal officials conceded the ban was very difficult to impose and it has had little impact. Dog meat restaurants are still legal in the rest of the country. Restaurant owners caught selling dog meat three times in a year have their licenses confiscated, officials said. No statistics were available on the number of cases prosecuted by the city. `` You tell us where they are selling dog food and we will send an inspector,'' said a Health Department official. Some foreigners, far from being appalled by dog meat, have tried the dish and found it agreeable. `` It's good. Much better than roast pork,'' said one visiting journalist.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CavazosHearing     09-10 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cavazos Hearing,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nominee for Education Secretary Assured of Easy Confirmation</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> says it's time Americans `` start caring'' about the educational needs of all citizens, and he is promising to put the focus on the issue if confirmed as the next education secretary. `` I know this wo n't be turned around in a decade. We ca n't wait any longer. We've waited too long,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> as it considered his nomination Friday to replace outgoing Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. If sworn in, <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> would become the first Hispanic member of a president's <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, 61, appeared headed for an easy confirmation, with senators praising the son of a cattle foreman on the King Ranch in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> who went on to become president of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He became the first Hispanic and the first graduate of the school to hold the post with his selection in 1980. `` He is eminently qualified for this appointment with considerable experience in higher education,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION> `` And in view of the fact that he has 10 children between the ages of 21 and 31, he has also had a central investment in elementary and secondary education.'' <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., said he was impressed and reassured by <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>' testimony that he would fight for increased spending and for making the <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> a vigorous advocate of education for all `` Your responses have been enormously helpful and I look forward to supporting you now,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. `` I'm going to do everything we can to assure an early confirmation.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said a vote by the committee may be taken Tuesday. `` It seems like you're the type of person who can come in here and heal any wounds that might exist, and build that consensus,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> last month nominated <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> to replace the often-confrontational <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, during questioning by <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, said he disagreed with some of <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s positions, including the secretary's claim that bilingual education had been a failure. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> declared in 1985 there was no evidence that the Bilingual Education Act had helped children, but <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said: `` I believe there has been a tremendous amount of success across a long period of time.'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and the administration's leadership in education, however, saying that in the past seven years `` we have arrested the decline in American education, but ... we still have much to accomplish.'' `` We must do everything in our power to help each student reach his or her potential,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said. `` To remain a great nation, we must ensure that no human resource is left untapped. ... We must keep our young people in school, make our citizens literate, provide opportunity to our minority students, and foster independence for handicapped students. <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> needs the full participation of every individual and the only way to ensure this is through quality education.'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> has a bachelor's degree in zoology and a master's degree in cytology _ the study of cells _ from <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> and a 1954 doctorate in physiology from <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Koch-Sludge     09-10 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koch-Sludge,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koch Seeks Compromise on Sludge-Dumping Bills</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> has characterized as `` savage'' and `` less savage'' a pair of bills that would call for an end to sludge dumping in the ocean by 1993, but he urged the two be rolled into one to make the city's fight easier. `` We hope that when the bill comes to the floor it will be one bill, the two -LRB- committee -RRB- chairs will compromise out their differences and that we do n't have to fight on every level, front and back and on all sides,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said Friday. `` We would like to be able to deal with one bill.'' The mayor met with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>. Pepper is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which could order that the two bills be combined <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and Pepper indicated `` they will consider the request on merits,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said. The two bills _ one sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, the other by Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> _ both mandate that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and eight other sewage authorities stop dumping sludge in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> by Dec. 31, 1992. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, which produces 3.8 million wet tons of sludge a year, has said it can not meet that deadline and needs until at least 1998 to find disposal alternatives. The other authorities that are dumping sludge 106 miles offshore are: <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION> counties in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; and in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Middlesex </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Passaic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meeting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Essex </ORGANIZATION> and Union Counties; <LOCATION> Bergen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Rahway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Linden-Roselle </PERSON>. Those authorities that fail to meet the deadline would be fined on a scale that could subject <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to paying somewhere between $ 146 million and $ 730 million a year, according to <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Chesser </PERSON>, the city's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> representative. The city does not like either bill; <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> called the Hughes version `` savage'' and the <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> bill `` less savage.'' The key difference between the two is the <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> bill would allow the city to enter a consent decree with the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> which could stipulate that the dumping end by a date later than 1992, although the fines would still go into effect, <PERSON> Chesser </PERSON> said. `` We would be negotiating a consent decree on a schedule we felt we could meet,'' she said of the <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON> bill. `` EPA, of course, would be pushing us to have the most expedited schedule possible.'' The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has stopped negotiating with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> over the city's compromise offer to stop dumping by 1998, said <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a regional <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> `` We're not negotiating any deadline yet because we're waiting to see what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is going to do,'' he said. Meanwhile, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last month passed a similar bill to stop the dumping of sewage sludge by January 1992. Under that bill, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> could end up paying up to $ 152 million in fines, according to <PERSON> Chesser </PERSON>. City officials arehoping a later deadline will be worked out when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bills move to conference for reconciliation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shultz-Bases     09-10 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz-Bases,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Disappointed, But Persistent in Talks Over Philippine Bases</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is disappointed that negotiations on military bases in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> have broken down, but Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials will be patient. He said the demands <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> had made on <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were `` out of bounds.'' `` We will be patient, and we will be persistent,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said Friday. `` But we'll also stick to our basic ideas.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will meet in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> next week with <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> and again in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> at the end of the month when they attend the special session of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said `` we seemed to have things on a pretty good track'' when he saw <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> on a trip to <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> last July. `` But, subsequently, it did n't work out that way,'' he said. `` I am a little disappointed right now,'' he told the board of directors of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>'s Clubs. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> spoke to the group about various foreign policy issues. He was asked about the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> when he opened the discussion to questions. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is paying the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> $ 180 million a year for use of the <ORGANIZATION> Subic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> <PERSON> Base </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials have not said what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has offered to extend the agreement past 1991 and what the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> demanded. <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON>, in a news conference Friday in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had offered $ 502 million for use of the bases and four smaller installations. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> sources told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had offered to double the yearly payment to $ 360 million as part of a $ 489 aid package. According to the sources, who spoke only on condition of anonymity, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> requested more than $ 1 billion a year in overall aid. Asked if he would insist on the same figure when he meets with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, <PERSON> Manglapus </PERSON> replied, `` Oh, yes. We shall be clarifying that our position is reasonable.'' `` We frankly think that what the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> seems to be asking is out of bounds, `` <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said, without referring to any specific figure. `` We are saying that to them and trying to convince them.'' He said the two bases were `` very useful to us'' and `` we believe they are very useful for the security of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0636EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Yugoslavia     09-10 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Serbia Leader's Defiance Sparks National Crisis</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By IVAN STEFANOVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Serbian <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief's public defiance of the national leadership has thrown this <LOCATION> Balkan </LOCATION> country of competing ethnic groups into its most explosive political crisis of the postwar era <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> on Tuesday rejected a call from the federal <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presidium </ORGANIZATION> to put an end to nationalist rallies in the southern province of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, where minority Slavs contend they are harrassed by ethnic Albanians who form 90 percent of the province's population. On Tuesday, more than 100,000 Serbs and Montenegrins, who are Slavs, staged protest rallies. Demonstrators shouted, `` Give us arms'' and `` Army to <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>,'' underscoring the Serbian leadership's demand to send the army to <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> to restore order. <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> is an autonomous region within the republic of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> and other Serbian leaders want to change the federal constitution so the republic can assert control over <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and the autonomous province of <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>. Under the 1974 constitution, <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> can not interfere in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s judiciary, police or other institutions Leaders of other republics oppose the idea. Newspaper editorials have said that the foundation of the Yugoslav state is threatened. Commenting on the showdown, the daily Vjesnik of <LOCATION> Zagreb </LOCATION>, capital of <LOCATION> Croatia </LOCATION>, warned that an increasing number of Yugoslavs were questioning the 1943 agreement that gave birth to communist <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. The nation is made up of six republics, each of which has its own constitution, assembly and president. `` We witness a sharpening of nationalism and chauvinism on the entire <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> territory,'' the editorial said. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s supporters planned weekend rallies in the city of <LOCATION> Jajce </LOCATION>, where the agreement was worked out, but local officials rejected the plan. The organizers then said they would hold a `` solidarity meeting'' there Sept. 17. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> has lashed out at the national leadership by saying the <LOCATION> Serbs </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Montenegrins </ORGANIZATION> have `` shown patience for the inefficiency of this country and the incompetence of its representatives.'' In Tuesday's speech, he asserted <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> leaders failed to bring peace to <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>. Referring to Slavs living there, he said, `` This summer their patience came to an end.'' <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> defended the fast-spreading Serbian discontent as justified expression of popular sentiment, while opponents say it will result in anarchy. Within hours, the <ORGANIZATION> Yugoslav </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> scheduled a session for late September to take action on <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, who enjoys popular support in <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> press. On Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Tanjug </ORGANIZATION> news agency said a police unit from another part of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION> would leave for <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> to reinforce local police. On Thursday, more than 10,000 Serbs and Montenegrins assembled at the <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Vucitrn </LOCATION> to protest what they called `` aggressive assaults of Albanian chauvinists and separatists,'' the <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> Politika </ORGANIZATION> reported. The rally followed an attack last week on the home of a Serbian woman. Two ethnic Albanians, convicted of damaging the house, were sentenced to 30 days in jail. The ethnic <PERSON> Albanian </PERSON> judge involved was dismissed and the terms were increased to 60 days. Demonstrators were heard singing a folk song that boldly compares <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON> to the late President <PERSON> Josip </PERSON> <PERSON> Broz </PERSON> <PERSON> Tito </PERSON>, the virtually uncontested leader of non-aligned <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> for three decades. Most Belgrade newspapers give a lopsided view of what is going on in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, scene of bloody rioting for greater autonomy in 1981. They keep reiterating that more than 30,000 Serbs and <PERSON> Montenegrins </PERSON> left the province in recent years because of arson and other attacks blamed on Albanians. Ethnic Albanians are rarely given a chance to respond in public to what appear to be grossly distorted accounts. In the regime-controlled press, the Slav exodus is entirely blamed on the Albanians, an estimated 500 of whom are in jail. The <ORGANIZATION> Tanjug </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported Friday that authorities in <LOCATION> Duesseldorf </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, warned Albanian families from towns in <LOCATION> Macedonia </LOCATION> they would be turned down as political refugees because `` their true motives ... are purely economic.'' Conversely, <LOCATION> Serbian </LOCATION> media have had practically no reports that Slavs have relocated for economic reasons from <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s most underdeveloped region
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Correspondent <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stefanovic </PERSON> has been covering <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for 33 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0637EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Drugs     09-10 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Drugs,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thirteen Tons of Marijuana Found on Honduran-Registered Ship</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 13-ton stash of marijuana was discovered aboard a Honduran-registered freighter stopped in British waters last week, a customs official said. `` There's tons of it coming out,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Biles </PERSON> of the Customs and <ORGANIZATION> Excise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday of the discovery on the ship, identified as the <LOCATION> Salton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. `` It's ... a big pro job.'' <PERSON> Biles </PERSON> said the ship's Dutch captain, three Dutch crewmen and four Colombian crewmen were charged with illegally importing cannabis into <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and were being held in police custody. The Honduran-registered ship was captured Sept. 3 after a chase across the English Channel from the northeast coast of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, where it had failed to stop for a routine check by <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> customs officers. The French fired two warning shots but the freighter churned off to British waters and finally surrendered to the British coast guard. It was escorted into <ORGANIZATION> Ramsgate </ORGANIZATION> on the southeast coast of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0638EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-10 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0445</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ARCOLA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's time for a clean sweep in this east-central <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> town _ and in most places, say promoters of the annual Broomcorn Festival in the self-proclaimed Broomcorn Capital of the World. <PERSON> Broomcorn </PERSON>? The stuff that brooms are made of _ actually a form of sorghum. And it does n't last forever. `` People always say, ` I've got to buy a new broom,' but they do n't,'' said <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Winger </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> _ one of seven broom makers around this town of 2,700 _ has been in business since 1900. `` You ca n't do much with an old broom except sweep rocks off the driveway,'' he said. So the highlight of this year's festival is a broom-burning _ come one, come all. Those who chuck a broom into a bonfire today receive a discount on a new one. The fiery event has a message: A new broom sweeps clean. `` Take a look at a new broom. The straws are split into little feathery ends. That's what picks up the dust and dirt,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Libman </PERSON>, whose family owns <ORGANIZATION> Libman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the biggest of the area producers. Brooms provide 250 jobs in the broomcorn capital, although much of the broomcorn _ which must be hand-harvested _ is imported from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Arcola </LOCATION> goes all out to celebrate its industry. In addition to the bonfire, the three-day festival ending Sunday features a parade, a miniature corn palace, broom-making demonstrations, folk crafts and country cooking. It has drawn as many as 50,000 visitors in past years, said spokesman <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hines </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATTLE CREEK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bull that wandered from its new owners' farm sauntered through a city neighborhood before stopping to munch apples from one of <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Schense </PERSON>'s trees. <PERSON> Schense </PERSON> was repairing a thermometer outside his home Thursday when he encountered the stray animal. `` I glanced up and then it dawned on me, ` Hey, that's not a common critter, there's a bull coming through the yard,''' he recalled. The bull knocked down part of a fence belonging to the animal's owners, the <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> family, and walked about a mile before stopping to partake of <PERSON> Schense </PERSON>'s apples, said animal control officer <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> and fellow officer <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON> roped the bull and tied it to the apple tree. The <ORGANIZATION> Wrights </ORGANIZATION> took it back to pasture in a trailer. `` Luckily, the critter was quite tame,'' <PERSON> Schense </PERSON> said. `` He was pretty peaceful through the whole thing. You could walk up to it. I even mooed at him a couple times, you know.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880910-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-10-88 0639EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RollsFlap     09-10 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rolls Flap,0372</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parking Dispute Causing Some Shakes, Rattles And Rolls</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL FLEEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
