<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Steinberg 1stLd-Writethru a0674 11-21 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Steinberg, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0674,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychiatrist Report on Nussbaum Details Lisa's Last Night</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New thruout with confidential psychiatric report on Nussbaum;
No pickup. Note contents.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The night before <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s adoptive 6-year-old daughter was removed unconscious from their apartment, his live-in companion said she heard noises in a bedroom `` like <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> throwing <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>,'' sources said Monday. <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> told a psychiatrist at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> on Nov. 20 that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, who is accused of beating <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> to death, then handed the child to her, saying, `` This is your child; what have you done; this has gone far enough,'' <ORGANIZATION> WCBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> said Monday, quoting from a copy of the unidentified psychiatrist's report. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> confirmed the contents of the report through sources close to the case. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> told the psychiatrist that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> was angry that night because <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> refused to drink water after he had given her and <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> hot pepper. She said he gave them the hot pepper to get them to drink more water. She later heard noises from the bedroom that sounded `` like <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> throwing <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>,'' the report said. Afterward, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> gave the child to <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, who placed her on the floor and noticed water and food coming out of her mouth. The report said that <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> thought <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> may have poured water down <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s mouth and that she was drowning. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> said she then began pumping the child's chest. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> told the psychiatrist that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> had left the apartment shortly afterward and returned about 10 p.m.. At about 6 a.m. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said, `` She's stopped breathing'' and told <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> to `` call 911. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, 46, a former editor of children's books, also was charged with <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s murder, but the charges against her later were dropped. She has spent the last year undergoing physical and psychiatric rehabilitation for injuries the prosecution says she suffered at <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s hands. At <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s trial on Monday a photographer testified that he used poses and lighting tricks to hide bruises he saw on the battered child when he took pictures of her in school two weeks before she was found dead. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON>, working that day for <ORGANIZATION> Scholastic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Books </ORGANIZATION>, said he initially was reluctant to photograph the first-grader when he visited her school on Oct. 22, 1987, because of her numerous bruises and her unkempt appearance. `` I observed some bruises underneath her left eye, by the cheeks, a bump on the forehead and underneath the chin here, a bruise, and some bruises on her arms,'' <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> said. `` The hair was very unkempt ... uneven,'' and her clothes were `` very rumpled, dirty,'' he said. <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> said he eventually took several black and white pictures of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>. He said he was drawn to her when she began directing two other children on posing the way he wanted them. `` She seemed older, more mature,'' he said. `` I put her on the right side and I flooded my light into her and I had her turn her head this way and down so you would n't see it. The last thing my client wants to see is bruises,'' <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> said. He said the rumpled and dirty quality of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>'s clothing also was eliminated `` in the way I photographed them.'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, 47, is charged with murder for allegedly beating <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> to death. The disbarred lawyer denies that he hit the child. He says she fell unconscious after choking on food she had vomited. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was taken unconscious from <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION> apartment early on Nov. 2, 1987, and died three days later at a hospital. Prosecutors are trying to show by Gross' photographs and testimony that <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was an abused child in the weeks before her death. They hope to eliminate any reasonable inference except that the abuse was inflicted by <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, who illegally adopted the girl.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea     11-21 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea,0506</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korea's Roh Indicates He May Pardon Chun, Who Prepares
Apology</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL SHIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON> was quoted as saying Monday that he wants to resolve politically the controversy raging over his predecessor, <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON>, an indication he may pardon <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> is preparing to apologize for corruption and other misdeeds before moving into rural exile. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> said his government hopes to resolve the controversy over <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> by the end of this year. The former president is being forced out of the capital, <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, by militant students who rioted and tried to break into his home, demanding that he be arrested and punished for alleged corruption and other abuses during seven years of authoritarian rule. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> was quoted as saying in an interview with the national daily <ORGANIZATION> Shinmun </ORGANIZATION>, a pro-government newspaper published in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>: `` In handling past wrongdoings, a clear distinction must be made between those -LRB- wrongdoings -RRB- to be dealt with judicially and those to be dealt with politically ... Any wrongdoings by <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> as chief executive of the country should be dealt with politically and there should not be political reprisal against the former chief executive ... `` I will take actions under the principle that any wrongdoings by a chief executive should be dealt with politically and that any political reprisal would only hurt democratic development.'' He made the remarks as the 56-year-old <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> reportedly was preparing to make a nationally televised apology Wednesday. Newspapers said <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> also is to turn over most of his wealth to the government and accept rural exile, a traditional way of repentance for a disgraced Korean. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> originally planned to leave <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Tuesday, but was delayed because of difficulty finding him a safe rural home, news reports said. The former president, who stepped down in February, denies personal wrongdoing. However, about a dozen of his relatives and associates were convicted or charged with corruption involving millions of dollars in public funds. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> needs a refuge from attack. Some reports said he would go to a mountainside Buddhist temple near an army unit in the north. Others said he might move to central <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. He reportedly is unwelcome in his southern hometown. National Assembly hearings Monday on abuses under the Chun government focused on attempts to stifle press freedom. More than 700 journalists were fired under government pressure and many newspapers and broadcast operations were merged and placed under state control by <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>'s administration. In recent weeks, <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> has been a virtual prisoner in his luxurious <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> home, guarded by hundreds of riot police to prevent attacks by dissidents. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s government has been accused of trying to protect <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> and is trying to defuse public anger without being implicated in the furor. <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>, a former army general, took power with military backing in 1980. He was succeeded by <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, another former general and close associate, after presidential elections last December.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Long-FlyingBalloon     11-21 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Long-Flying Balloon,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Balloon Flies 2,500 Miles</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten-year-old <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> does n't care that experts are having trouble explaining how his helium-filled balloon flew 2,500 miles from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. He just thinks it's neat, said his mother, <PERSON> Liz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>'s 11-inch, yellow balloon was one of 250 launched Oct. 23 to commemorate a local church's anniversary. Each balloon was tied with a string that carried a card asking the finder to return it to the church. The church received 10 to 15 responses, mostly from within 20 miles. <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>'s balloon wound up deflated in the swimming pool of a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> sheriff's deputy Oct. 30. `` I ca n't explain how it got there,'' Deputy <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>. `` At that distance, I ca n't believe it was the wind itself. It had to have some help somewhere along the line.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> ca n't explain the trip, either. `` That would be some trick,'' said the weather service's <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalembkiewicz </PERSON>. If the balloon were only windblown, it would be `` a once in a lifetime happening.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-21 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0452</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JELLICO, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Deciding that it's never too late to change, the mayor wants to give women here the right to vote. Actually, women in this east <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> town of 2,800 have been voting since 1920, when the 19th Amendment to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution was ratified. But the town's 1902 charter still forbids it, and Mayor <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> says it's time to have it changed. `` I'd like to see them try to stop the women in <LOCATION> Jellico </LOCATION> from voting,'' said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, wife of City Councilman <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>. `` They would have a riot on their hands.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There is such a thing as a free lunch _ just ask about 1,000 people who patronized a downtown restaurant. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrolias </PERSON>, owner of <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON>'s on the Square, gave away free chicken and cole slaw lunches Monday to promote his 2-week-old eatery. `` We're just thrilled with the people who came out,'' <PERSON> Petrolias </PERSON> said. The 25-year-old restaurateur, whose family has owned another downtown restaurant for 55 years, said the crowd consumed 1,500 pounds of chicken, 150 pounds of cabbage and 15 gallons of salad oil. He estimated the giveaway cost him about $ 1,500, but added, `` I really have n't figured it out myself. I'm afraid to.'' <PERSON> Petrolias </PERSON> said he was pleased with the crowd, which was orderly and friendly. `` We were just delighted,'' he said `` Our kitchen is n't gigantic, and it was tough to keep up, but we managed.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gettel </PERSON> has designed papier-mache heads of the famous for <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s Thanksgiving Day parade for 45 years, but to his surprise, parade organizers have had him immortalized. Organizers last week unveiled a 15-pound, baldheaded bust of <PERSON> Gettel </PERSON>. `` They kept it a secret from me for eight months,'' said <PERSON> Gettel </PERSON>, who has designed likenesses ranging from <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> to <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> as decorations for parade floats. `` It was packed in the same huge crate as -LRB- civil rights pioneer -RRB- <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Parks </PERSON>' head. `` When I pulled it out, I almost flipped. I was so flabbergasted I got all red in the face. Now I'm immortalized. Even when I die I'll be part of the parade.'' This year, nine new heads will make their parade debut, including likenesses of aviator <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON> and rock singer <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gettel </PERSON> said. The heads have become a major attraction at the Thanksgiving procession, where children and adults make a game out of guessing the identities of the lesser-known noggins. `` I just love it so much I can hardly call it a job,'' <PERSON> Gettel </PERSON> said. `` To me, Thanksgiving lasts all year.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Australia-Population     11-21 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Australia-Population,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biggest Annual Increase Since 1950 Recorded</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CANBERRA, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country's population grew by 268,600 in the past year to total 16.5 million, its biggest annual increase since 1950, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> said. The year that ended June 30 was also just the third since 1950 in which net migration exceeded natural increase _ the excess of births over deaths _ in total population growth, the bureau said Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> said net migration _ permanent arrivals minus departures _ totalled 143,200, also the largest increase since 1949-1950. It said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> were the largest source of migrants, followed by the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malayasia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. Aborigines, the country's indigenous inhabitants, number some 160,000, or about 1 percent of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Koreas-Trade     11-21 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Koreas-Trade,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Clams First Direct Trade Item Between Koreas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 North Korean clams have been imported to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, the first product to arrive since the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government approved a policy allowing direct trade with <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. A customs spokesman said today that 40 pounds of short-necked clams from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> had cleared customs at the port city of <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION>. Half the shipment was frozen and half were dried, the spokesman said. The clams were brought to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> by way of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a general trading company, as food samples in preparation for expansion of trading with the north. The <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government approved the resumption of direct trade of all but military goods in October as a gesture of goodwill in efforts to ease tension and improve relations between the two Koreas. Goods from the communist north had been banned since the division of the peninsula after World War II.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DisciplinaryBarracks     11-21 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Disciplinary Barracks,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strict Rules in Military's Biggest Prison</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MATT TRUELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT LEAVENWORTH, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They call it `` The Castle,'' a massive stone building with eight wings radiating from a central six-story rotunda. The wings hold eight tiers of cells, stacked one upon the other, and in each 8-by-10-foot cell an inmate is allowed a cot, a table and a chair. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disciplinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barracks </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION> is the biggest military prison in the nation. It is a grim home for about 1,450 inmates, sent here from bases all over the world, wherever American military men and women are stationed. Forty-two officers, including one lieutenant colonel, and 21 women are serving time here. Among them are drug dealers, armed robbers, rapists, murderers and spies. More than 80 are serving life terms. Three inmates are on death row. And there is strict military discipline. `` Our rules are so strict that if a guy turns left and he knows he's not supposed to turn left, he's in trouble,'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON>, prison chief of staff. `` You earn what you get here,'' added the prison commandant, Col. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Berrong </PERSON>, a former Army airborne Ranger and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran. `` There are n't any free lunches.'' Military officials say the goal of the prison is not just confinement, but correction. `` Unfortunately, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> today we do a lot of confining and not much correction,'' <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said. `` We attempt to give them tools so when they leave here, they can be productive citizens.'' When inmates leave these walls, they return to civilian life, not to the military. Next to discipline, training is the top priority at the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION> prison, which has more than 20 vocational programs including automotive repairs, printing, carpentry, upholstery, and hotel and restaurant management. Inmates, whom officials would not allow to be interviewed, even repair cars and furniture of military families living at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION>. Officials claim the Disciplinary Barracks has the oldest shoe repair business west of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, started in 1877 to make boots for cavalrymen. Now it repairs everything from prescription orthopedic shoes to cleated golf shoes, <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said. The prison also has one of the largest silk-screening businesses in the nation, providing all the decals for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> planes. Congress authorized the prison's construction in 1874. An old quartermaster depot that had supplied military posts in the Indian Territory housed the first prisoners. The Castle was completed in 1915 by inmate labor. Inmate labor is still used for maintenance, but the prisoners also work with their minds. Most have high school diplomas, and those who do n't go straight into the classroom when they arrive, <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said. They can earn associate and bachelor's degrees through correspondence, and a few are working on master's degrees, but <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said they do that at their own expense. The prison takes enlisted men from all branches of the service except the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. It takes all convicted officers, regardless of the length of the sentence. <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said the shortest sentence for an officer he recalls is seven days. `` I think they wanted him to see the inside of a prison,'' he said. One inmate is going into his 17th year, he added. Some famous inmates have seen the inside of its walls, from Lt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Calley </PERSON>, who was convicted of murdering Vietnamese civilians at My Lai, to <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> who was convicted of espionage while an embassy guard in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Three inmates are awaiting death sentence, although the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has not executed anyone since 1961 and no execution dates have been set. They are: _ <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, who was sentenced last April in connection with the death of two women. He was stationed at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 24, of <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, who was convicted last year of murdering his wife, his 6-year-old stepson, and his 2-year-old son, while stationed in <LOCATION> Nanau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, with the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON>, 22, a Marine from <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, who was convicted in August 1987 of murdering his platoon commander and platoon commander's wife at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lejeune </LOCATION>. Although most inmates are first-time offenders, the average sentence is about 10 years. About two-thirds are serving time for such crimes as assault, rape, murder or kidnapping; 17 percent are imprisoned for narcotics violations, and 11 percent were sentenced for theft. No inmate is serving time for just a military offense, such as being absent without leave. Some prisoners work outside the walls and in nearby <LOCATION> Leavenworth </LOCATION> on work-release programs. About 20 inmates work on the 2,600-acre prison farm, which raises hogs and cattle and grows row crops and vegetables. Outside The Castle walls, inmates who are `` installation parolees'' stay in an unsecure barracks. They have proved themeselves reliable while doing their time, and have earned a few extra privleges. `` The only thing that keeps them out there is moral restraint,'' <PERSON> Gasko </PERSON> said. `` But the rules are extremely tough, and we do n't tolerate any violations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Jackson     11-21 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Jackson,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michael Jackson to Release Full-Length Music Video</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Moonwalker,'' a 94-minute video celebration of the weird and wonderful world of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, is being released early next year. The video will be an amalgam of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s musical performances, his reflections on media pressures and a narrative film in which he transforms himself into a robot and then a spaceship to battle a drug pusher named Mr. Big, said CBS Music Video Enterprises. The release of the video on Jan. 10 comes at the end of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 15-month world tour, which was seen by 4 million fans in 15 countries Songs on the video include <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s `` Man in the Mirror,'' his redo of the Beatles' hit `` Come Together,'' and `` The Moon is Walking,'' a song written and performed by the South African vocal group <ORGANIZATION> Ladysmith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mombazo </ORGANIZATION>. The suggested price of the video is $ 24.98.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghan-KeyCity     11-21 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghan-Key City,0784</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moslem Guerrillas Lurk Outside Key Afghan City</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 One of the key factors of the post-Soviet era in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> will be who can hold the nation's cities. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent based in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> recently visited one of those cities and in this dispatch describes the situation now with the Soviets still there but committed to withdraw by February.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By KATHY GANNON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANDAHAR, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Evening campfires in the nomads' camelhide tents dance to a nightly staccato of gunfire from warring rebels and communist government soldiers on the desert plain outside this ancient provincial capital Turbaned men oblivious to the shots face southwest toward the Moslem holy city of <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION> to begin their evening prayer. Women in voluminous layers of colored cloth move about nearby. The primitive nomad tribes have for centuries encamped near <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>'s satellite village of <LOCATION> Argandab </LOCATION>. Now, Soviet jets scream overhead. <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s war goes on around them and sometimes engulfs them. Less than a mile from the nomads' camp, Moslem rebels, blast away at government military posts with recoilless rifles, rocket-propelled grenade launchers and light and heavy machine guns. The army's artillery is an even match, but government troops have an advantage in air power from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Newly introduced MiG-27 ground-attack fighters and Backfire bombers have blasted civilian and guerrilla targets since the beginning of November. The question is how long can the government hold <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, a key city, once the Soviets withdraw from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. They are committed to do so by February. In <LOCATION> Argandab </LOCATION>, where civilians far outnumber rebels, jets swept one recent day over the main bazaar, levelling a portion of it, killing nine people and wounding 80 others. A squat man with a gray beard said, `` When I wake up in the morning until I go to sleep, I'm not sure about my life, that I will be alive five minutes from now because of the war.'' The old man, wrapped in a blanket, said he lived in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, once the capital of all <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Through the fine dust that hangs over the city, the pale blue dome of the <LOCATION> Kalqi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sharif </LOCATION> mosque can be seen from a distance. The mosque, which embodies the Islamic tenets propelling the rebel mujahedeen in their fight sits opposite the governor's home, a stronghold of the Soviet-backed government. The western entrance to the city is deserted but for the army and militia, tanks and trucks. Civilians are not seen except at the bazaar at <PERSON> Shaheedan </PERSON> <PERSON> Chowk </PERSON>, a pillared monument honoring Afghans killed fighting the British more than a century ago. <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, known as the city of kings, is the birthplace of generations of Afghan royalty. The ornate tomb of <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Durrani </PERSON>, the grandfather of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s exiled King <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>, is a vernerated site of monarchists who are in the majority around <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, both among the mujahedeen and civilians. The rubble of blasted buildings chokes the streets, forcing motorized rickshaws and horse drawn `` tonga'' carriages to steer an obstacle course through the bazaar. <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> <PERSON> Lalai </PERSON>, a commander of the rebel <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION>, said the bulk of the damage near <LOCATION> Herat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION> on the western edge of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> occurred when fighter jets aiming at guerrilla positions in a nearby suburb missed their mark. Evidence that the guerrillas have operated extensively in the city for years is the heavy tank-fire damage to the mud homes and shops. About 50,000 people remain in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> compared to a prewar population of about 200,000, making it second only in size to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s capital. Old men, women and children crowd daily into the bazaar before it closes at 2 p.m. The free access of women and children is used by mujahedeen who employ youngsters to bring supplies to rebel bases from the city. One of the young recruits, <PERSON> Gul </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON>, said he lost his mother, two younger sisters and a brother when a tank round hit his home in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> two years ago. He was 9 years old at the time. Police once stopped him and a friend carrying turbans, sandals and `` important letters'' to rebels, he said. `` When they captured me they beat me up. Even they broke my head.'' <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> said he spent almost a year in <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION> prison. `` Everyday for questioning they brought us to a room full of water and made us lie down and they beat us,'' he said. `` I'm not afraid of anything,'' he boasted. But mujahedeen said his forays into the city were finished.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Indictments     11-21 0940</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Indictments,0961</SECOND>
<HEAD>17 Congressmen, One Delegate, Indicted In Past Decade While In
Office</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Garcia-Wedtech, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, indicted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on conspiracy charges in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> corruption scandal, is the 18th person in the last decade to be indicted on criminal charges while serving in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He is also the second Democratic congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to be indicted for allegedly using his influence on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a minority-owned <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> machine shop that won no-bid <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> contracts. It has since gone bankrupt. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, whose former congressional district in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Borough </LOCATION> abuts <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s, was convicted Aug. 5 of racketeering, mail fraud and accepting bribes from <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> in exchange for his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> influence <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, 71, resigned his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat Aug. 6 after serving nearly 10 terms. He was sentenced Friday to eight years in prison and a $ 242,000 fine. <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> also was convicted in November 1987 of accepting an illegal gratuity _ a paid vacation _ for helping an ailing shipyard in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Borough </LOCATION>. He was sentenced to 2 -LCB- years in prison and a $ 500,000 fine in that case. <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> is slated to report to prison authorities on Jan. 9. Last month, former two-term Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, R-Ga., was indicted on perjury charges <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, who narrowly lost his seat Nov. 8 as a result of the charges, allegedly lied to a grand jury investigating a proposed $ 850,000 home mortgage loan he discussed with an <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> businessman and an undercover agent posing as a financier. <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON> allegedly denied being told the source of the loan could be illicit drug money. <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>'s trial began last month but was postponed after a juror received a mailing from his campaign. Also last month, Fofo I.F. <PERSON> Sunia </PERSON>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>'s former delegate to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, was sentenced to five to 15 months in prison for participating in a payroll-padding scheme that reportedly earned him $ 39,000. <PERSON> Sunia </PERSON>, a Democrat who had served almost four terms, pleaded guilty to conspiring with his chief aide to defraud the government of $ 130,920 through false payroll claims. The 51-year-old <PERSON> Sunia </PERSON> resigned his congressional seat Sept. 6. As a delegate, he was allowed to vote in legislative committees but not on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. Other members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> indicted since 1978: _ Rep <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Tenn., charged in April 1987 with bank, mail and tax fraud No trial date has been set. _ Rep <PERSON> Bobbi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON>, R-Calif., indicted Jan. 23, 1986, along with an aide on charges she tried to buy off an opponent for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nomination in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> The charges subsequently were dismissed by a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON> lost the primary. _ Rep <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, indicted in April 1983 and convicted one year later on charges of violating the 1978 Ethics in Government Act by failing to report $ 333,978 in loans and other transactions on his financial disclosure forms. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> was freed in October 1987 after serving nearly one year of a five-to-15-month sentence. _ Sen <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, convicted in May 1981 on charges stemming from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s Abscam investigation, including conspiracy, bribery, conflict of interest, receiving an unlawful gratuity and interstate travel in aid of a racketeering enterprise. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in March 1982. He was paroled from a halfway house in January 1986 after serving nearly two years of a three-year sentence at the federal penitentiary at <LOCATION> Allenwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. Six House members also were indicted as a result of the undercover Abscam investigation, and all served prison terms They were: Rep. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>, D-Pa., convicted in January 1981 of conspiracy, bribery, receiving an unlawful gratuity and interstate travel to further racketeering; Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> `` Ozzie'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, D-Pa., convicted in August 1980 of conspiracy, bribery and interstate travel; Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenrette </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, convicted in October 1980 of sharing a $ 50,000 Also, Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, convicted in December 1980 of conspiracy, conflict of interest and receiving an unlawful gratuity; Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, convicted in December 1980 of bribery, conspiracy and aiding and abetting in the acceptance of a criminal gratuity; Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., convicted in January 1981 of taking a $ 25,000 bribe from an undercover <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent and of taking part in a $ 250,000 bribery conspiracy _ Rep <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., was indicted in July 1979 on charges of buying votes in the 1978 election and violating federal campaign finance laws He was acquitted of some vote-buying counts and the others were dropped, and a federal appeals court dismissed the charges of campaign finance law violations. _ Rep <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Eilberg </PERSON>, D-Pa., indicted in October 1978 on federal charges of illegally receiving compensation to help a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> hospital get a $ 14.5 million federal grant He pleaded guilty in February 1979 and was sentenced to five years' probation and fined $ 10,000. _ Rep <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Flood, D-Pa., indicted in the fall of 1978 on 13 counts of bribery, conspiracy and perjury His trial on 11 counts ended in a mistrial in February 1979, and he resiged from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in January 1980, citing health reasons, after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee accused him of 25 rules violations. In February 1980, he pleaded guilty to conspiracy in a plea-bargaining arrangement and was given a year's probation. _ Rep <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Mich., indicted in March 1978 and convicted in October 1978 on 29 felony counts of illegally diverting his congressional employees' salaries to his personal use Censured by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1979, <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> resigned from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1980 and served seven months of a three-year prison sentence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JFK-BroadcastersRemember     11-21 0922</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-JFK-Broadcasters Remember,0941</SECOND>
<HEAD>Broadcasters Remember Kennedy Assassination Coverage</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Note language in 13th graf.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Young <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> was standing just over a ridge from <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>' <LOCATION> Dealey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaza </LOCATION>, holding a yellow sack, waiting for a film drop from the cameraman in President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s motorcade `` I saw what I thought was the president's limousine, and it seemed to make a wrong turn,'' Rather recalled recently. `` It all went by in a blur. `` I knew something was wrong. You know when you know something, but you do n't know why you know it? I went back over that ridge and saw an incredible scene. Some people were on the ground, some people were trying to cover children. It was a scene of great confusion.'' Rather looked for a telephone but could n't immediately find one. He sprinted to <ORGANIZATION> KRLD </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> affiliate, a few blocks away. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> anchor <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, working in the newsroom. `` I happened to be standing at the printer when the UP bulletin came across that shots had rung out in <LOCATION> Dealey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaza </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` As soon as we got that first report, we ordered up lines and got into the announce booth ... and started interrupting with voiceover bulletins on the ongoing program. And then we got the camera up there I think in about 10 minutes.'' While <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> read wire reports on the air, Rather was at <ORGANIZATION> KRLD </ORGANIZATION> trying to confirm rumors that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was dead. The Parkland Memorial Hospital switchboard told him <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was dead. <ORGANIZATION> KRLD </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> had the head of the hospital saying he was dead Rather finally got a surgeon and a priest who were in the emergency room to confirm that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was dead. Rather told <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> went with it on the air. `` There was n't any doubt in my mind,'' said Rather, who had beaten the opposition on the biggest story of their lives. `` The official announcement was n't made for another 17 minutes. It was a very long 17 minutes.'' After those 17 minutes, <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> was handed a piece of wire copy. `` From <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the flash, apparently official,'' he said solemnly, removing his glasses. `` President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> died at 1 p.m. Central Standard Time. Two o'clock Eastern Standard Time. Some 38 minutes ago.'' <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> choked up for a moment, on camera. `` This one really struck home,'' he recalled. `` This was tearing the guts out. `` It was when you finally had to say the word, officially, that he was dead that it really impacted in the way it did.'' <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> walked off the air after six hours and just wanted to call his wife, <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON>. The phone lines had been tied up all afternoon. A line came free for a second, and he grabbed it, only to hear a woman ask to speak to `` someone in charge of the news department.'' `` She said, ` I'd like to complain about having that <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> on the air at this time crying his crocodile tears when everyone knows he hated <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.' I said, ` Madam, what is your name?' She gave me her name and address on Park Avenue. I said, ` You are speaking to <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON>, and you, madam, are a goddamn idiot.''' He hung up. On Sunday, the networks were covering the movement of accused assassin <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> from the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> to the county jail. Only <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> was on live when <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> stepped out of the crowd and shot <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> at point-blank range. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettit </PERSON> was the correspondent on the scene. `` I clearly saw the shooting which was about six feet from where I was,'' he says. `` I had a clear visual field to see somebody fire a revolver into <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>'s lower abdomen. I did not see <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> come through the crowd. I did not see anybody; I just saw the gunshot. `` What I was seeing was coming out of my mouth. It was the only time I've really experienced doing eyewitness reporting while you're live on the air. <PERSON> Pettit </PERSON> said he has never seen his own coverage of the <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> assassination and does n't want to. `` You know, it's a kind of a historic event in broadcasting, the first televised murder, but for me it was so horrendous a situation to be in and so emotional and so charged with fear, concern and a sense of pending doom that I would not like to relive it. `` I remember hearing our coverage when they had the casket at the rotunda of the Capitol. No narration, just symphonic music. Television really distinguished itself in that time, I think, really devoted itself to the notion that it was holding the country together. Whether it was in truth or not, who am I to say? But at the time, we certainly felt that responsibility.'' `` It was a major moment of course in our history and in our television history,'' <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> said. `` I think we responded as an industry well. We showed our capabilities technologically and substantively as well _ what we covered, how we covered it, the decorum with which we approached the story.'' `` I think these four days were the beginning of the television age, certainly the beginning for television journalism,'' Rather said. `` There was a second-class citizenry to being a television journalist. That day, not only did we take you there, television journalists did some real good reporting. ... That day, we began to feel, hey, we're as good as anybody.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vietnam-Monks     11-21 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Monks,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Commutes Death Penalty for Two Buddhist Monks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CANBERRA, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vietnamese authorities have bowed to international appeals and commuted the death sentences of two <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks convicted of subversive activities, an Australian government spokesman said today. Authorities in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> told <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s ambassador in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> on Friday that the sentences of philosopher and teacher <PERSON> Thich </PERSON> <PERSON> Tue </PERSON> <PERSON> Si </PERSON> and scholar <PERSON> Thich </PERSON> <PERSON> Tri </PERSON> <PERSON> Sieu </PERSON> were commuted to 20 years in prison, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> official said. The two monks were condemned to death in October by the <ORGANIZATION> Ho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on charges they participated in subversive activities, the spokesman said on condition of anonymity. The two monks were arrested in 1984 with 19 <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> scholars. The scholars received undisclosed terms of imprisonment. There were no details on what kind of subversive activities they were alleged to have undertaken. The status of a third person also facing capital punishment in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Luong </PERSON>, was not known, the spokesman said. He said <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and other countries began making pleas to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> after the death sentences were imposed. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> opposes capital punishment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiotAnniversary     11-21 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riot Anniversary,0631</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cubans Pour In And Out Of INS Detention A Year After Prison Riots</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A year after Cubans from the Mariel boatlift rioted at two prisons for a chance at freedom, thousands are out on parole, but more are dribbling back into what could be lifetime custody. Many of the thousands of Cubans held by the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> will be freed more quickly because of changes made in the review process as a result of the agreement that ended the riots, but others will have to await new laws or the whim of the Cuban government. Critics of the process acknowledge it has increased the number of Cubans freed but say it has other problems. `` We're not saying some of -LRB- the Cuban prisoners -RRB- in there are n't bad,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Leshaw </PERSON>, a Legal Aid lawyer who has represented the detainees `` We're saying we're not sure the system is designed to sort out the people who do not belong there.'' The detainees are a minority among the 125,000 Cubans who arrived during the five-month `` Freedom Flotilla'' from the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Mariel </LOCATION> in 1980. Many of those who arrived were criminals or mental patients freed from jails and hospitals. A few were arrested on arrival for crimes committed in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. Others were convicted of crimes here and turned over to the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> for deportation after finishing their sentences. But <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> would n't take them back, so they remained in detention. Since the detainees never were officially admitted to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, they have existed in legal limbo as `` excludable aliens.'' Courts ruled that the Cubans did not have to released and could be excluded without legal protections. Then rioting erupted at federal prisons in <LOCATION> Oakdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> after the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s Nov. 20, 1987, announcement that <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> had agreed to take back more than 2,500 of the 3,800 Mariel refugees locked up nationwide at the time. The rioters, wielding crudely fashioned weapons, took 145 hostages and burned several buildings. One inmate was killed in the 11-day uprising in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. The uprisings ended Dec. 4, 1987, after the government agreed to a moratorium on deportations and a one-time-only <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> review of each <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> decision. <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said the agreement also called for speedy reviews of inmates' cases, which have resulted in the parole of about 60 percent of the detainees. Since the uprisings, <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> increased the number of review panels from four to 20. `` The reviews conducted by these panels go beyond anything that's required by law or by court order,'' <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, a deputy associate attorney general, said Thursday `` They're designed to give the detainee and his representative every opportunity to tell the panels anything they feel appropriate in reaching their decisions.'' So far about 2,500 Cubans have been paroled. Parole has been denied to about 1,500 others who will continue to get annual INS reviews but could spend years, even their lives, in <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> custody even through they have finished prison sentences for their crimes. About 115 are at a federal facility in <LOCATION> Talladega </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, awaiting word on whether they will be sent back to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced plans Thursday to deport 13 detainees. <PERSON> Leshaw </PERSON> sued to block that, claiming the cases are entitled to additional review. An additional 3,000 Cubans are serving jail sentences and eventually will enter <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> detention, either to be paroled or held until <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> takes them back. Unless another agreement is reached with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, many will not face deportation, but they will stay in jail indefinitely until an INS panel decides they are fit for parole.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM--BRF--Poland-Cigarettes     11-21 0105</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM--BRF--Poland-Cigarettes,0107</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cigarette Price To Go Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government raised cigarette prices today, saying it wants to discourage heavy smoking and bring prices more in line with production costs. The official <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency on Sunday announced increases of 10.9 percent for all Polish-made cigarettes and 12.1 percent for imported brands. Health officials have increasingly expressed concern about heavy smoking among Poles. Cigarette consumption in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> rose by nearly a third between 1965 and 1985. Polish cigarettes cost an average of about 25 cents per pack. The average monthly salary in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> is about $ 100 at the official exchange rate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Withdrawal     11-21 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Withdrawal,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>European Navies Scaling Back, Could Put Pressure on Bush</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gambling that peace will prevail despite a deadlock in Iraq-Iran peace talks, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' European allies are stepping up the postwar dismantling of their military forces in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. In recent days the mine sweeper <PERSON> Crocus </PERSON>, the last of three Belgian warships deployed to the gulf a year ago, sailed for home. The last five Italian warships and one from the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> are preparing to leave by Dec. 31. Officials said those moves, like an earlier cutback in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s regional fleet from 11 to seven ships, came because the Iraq-Iran cease-fire, three months old Sunday, had brought stability to the gulf The European actions could add pressure on President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to step up an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> pullout, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats and military officials, speaking on condition of anonymity. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has withdrawn one ship and scaled back convoys and other operations. But its 25 warships represent about half the foreign vessels in the region. Diplomats said defense budget cutters are likely to focus on the operation, whose monthly cost the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> estimated at $ 15 million - $ 20 million at its peak <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, however, say the American commitment to peacekeeping has led to the best-ever relations with the <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> gulf </LOCATION> states, and the <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders remain nervous about a hasty pullout. `` They have made it clear they want us here and they are n't pushing for us to leave too quickly,'' said a senior diplomat <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military sources say Arab sensitivity to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pullout prompted <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials in September to fudge reports on the departure of the <LOCATION> USS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>, listing the cruiser as still on duty nearly a week after it left the area. The Pentagon says decisions on reducing the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> _ 15 ships in the gulf and a 10 in the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> _ depend on the Iran-Iraq cease-fire holding. The Pentagon has given no timetable for cutbacks but says the gulf-based force eventually would revert to five or six ships, the level before last year's buildup to protect shipping endangered by the gulf's `` tanker war.'' The U.N.-sponsored truce has held despite warnings from leaders in both <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> that fighting could resume if no peace agreement is achieved. `` The general feeling seems to be that the -LRB- war -RRB- momentum in the gulf is gone, and even if fighting started elsewhere it would n't spread,'' a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat said No incidents have been reported since the Aug. 20 cease-fire. Gulf Arab states have appealed to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to help in clearing mines that still pose a major threat to shipping. More than 500 commercial vessels were damaged and more than 300 sailors killed in attacks by both sides during the 8-year-old conflict. The war led the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and six other governments to send or reinforce naval units in the gulf, which provides nearly a fifth of the western world's petroleum. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> foes initially attacked <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision as risking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> involvement in the war. The criticism later faded, and some diplomats expressed amazement that the move scarcely was mentioned in the campaign between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` If anybody told me 18 months ago that we could have the biggest single concentration of warships since World War II in the gulf, with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> at war, and it would n't become an election issue, I'd have said they were all wet,'' said a senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat. Since the cease-fire, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has withdrawn one ship and canceled deployment of another, reduced air patrols and removed a fortified barge from the northern gulf. Instead of escorting commercial vessels in convoys, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships now are posted along the 600-mile gulf to lend assistance if needed. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military sources say there is no sign of cutbacks by the Soviets, who have kept seven to nine ships in and near the gulf since 1986. Just as President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s move to expand the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> force was prompted in part by that growing Soviet presence, diplomats say, any major change by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> could influence the American withdrawal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Scholarships     11-21 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scholarships,0563</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brokerage, Urban League, Offer Inner-City Scholarships To Prevent
Dropouts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> today promised 250 first graders in 10 cities full college scholarships or cash incentives if they stay in school through graduation. The <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, the charitable arm of the nation's largest brokerage firm, is underwriting the new `` ScholarshipBuilder'' program with an initial $ 500,000 contribution, or $ 2,000 per student, to cover college tuitions estimated to reach $ 17,500 by the year 2000, when this year's first-graders will enter Students preferring jobs or the military would still get a one-time $ 1,000 cash payment to cover clothing and travel expenses, provided they graduate from high school. `` You are the hope for our future,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schreyer </PERSON> in remarks prepared for delivery today at <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> @ <ORGANIZATION> Langston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION>, one of the 16 schools chosen. `` That is why we are investing now in your higher education. In return we want you to stay in school, to study well, to be free to dream important dreams, and to know that you can make them come true.'' In addition to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the schools are in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. A school in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> is to be named shortly, according to <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION>. Other corporations and philanthropists have offered similar incentives to persuade inner city children to stay in school. Philanthropist <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, for example, promised 61 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> sixth-graders full college scholarships if they stayed in school. A group of businessmen called the `` 100 Black Men of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'' is acting as mentors to a class of 28 ninth-graders and is guaranteeing their college expenses. But <PERSON> Schreyer </PERSON> said `` ScholarshipBuilder'' is different from other such `` adopt-a-class'' programs: `` Our program begins earlier in the child's educational career _ first grade _ and provides funds not only for college or other post-secondary education but also a stipend upon high school graduation for students who immediately become fully employed or who enter military service.'' The foundation's future annual contribution could go up or down to meet projected average college costs. But foundation president <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> estimated his fund would eventually contribute about $ 8 million, which could appreciate to $ 16 million through investments by the time students are old enough to draw upon it. The Urban League chose inner city schools that ranked high in orderliness, attendance rates, parental involvement and other `` effectiveness'' measures. Students were chosen at random but with an eye toward achieving ethnic and racial balance. The league will continue to administer the scholarship program, including keeping tabs on youngsters' progress. Asked whether <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> would give preference to those students who eventually wanted careers on <LOCATION> Wall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> said: `` I would say without committing us that we would, if they were qualified.'' The 15 other schools selected are: Capitol View Elementary, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Overton </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Goodale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>; 74th <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Earlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Floral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, Lorah Park Elementary, <ORGANIZATION> Olinda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Orchard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Villa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Hendley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SkinheadArrest 1stLd-Writethru a0757 11-21 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Skinhead Arrest, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0757,0463</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three `Skinheads' Arrested in Beating Death of Ethiopian Immigrant</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS spelling of Mieske sted Miske throughout; UPDATES
throughout with new information, background; no pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three men belonging to a `` skinhead'' gang were charged in connection with the beating death of an Ethiopian immigrant a week ago, police said Sunday. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Mieske </PERSON>, 23, <PERSON> Kyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Brewster </PERSON>, 19, and <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Strasser </PERSON>, 20, were charged in what police said was a racially motivated and unprovoked attack on <PERSON> Mulugeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Seraw </PERSON>, 27, who had just been dropped off by friends in front of his home. The friends, who tried to intervene, suffered minor injuries. <PERSON> Seraw </PERSON> died a short time after the beating, in which his attackers used a baseball bat. <PERSON> Mieske </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brewster </PERSON> were charged with murder and remained in custody, said Detective <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>. Bond for <PERSON> Strasser </PERSON>, charged with second-degree assault, was set at $ 100,000, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mieske </PERSON>, who also uses the alias `` <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Death </PERSON>,'' was arrested early Saturday, and <PERSON> Brewster </PERSON> and <PERSON> Strasser </PERSON> were arrested about noon Sunday, he said. The three were to appear in district court Monday afternoon. <PERSON> Mieske </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brewster </PERSON> face additional charges of assault and racial intimidation in a Sept. 10 incident at a grocery store, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. A black security guard and several store employees forcibly ejected a large number of `` skinheads'' about 11 p.m. that evening. In another charge that resulted from the homicide investigation but was unrelated to <PERSON> Seraw </PERSON>'s death, police and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> arrested <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON>, 20, and charged him with unlawful flight to avoid prosecution and escape, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. The charge relates to a <LOCATION> Redwood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, case involving vandalism to a place of worship, he said. The Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith said recently that reports of violent crimes have surfaced in every area where skinhead groups have organized. The civil rights group estimated in October there were about 2,000 young people actively involved in skinhead gangs in 21 states, but noted that many youngsters who adopt the skinhead look reject the racist element. The skinhead subculture emerged in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> as early as the 1960s. Segments of the movement took on <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> overtones in 1985 and since have been supported by and associated with the white supremacist <ORGANIZATION> Aryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> and White Aryan Resistance. <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> has a skinhead group of about 20 called East Side White Pride, with ties to the White Aryan Resistance, according to the league. It also has a group called Preservation of the White American Race, with about 10 members, half of whom are women, and a suburban group, Youth of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, the league said. Although police identified the suspects as part of a skinhead gang, officers did not identify any group by name.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MappaMundi     11-21 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mappa Mundi,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cathedral's Plan To Sell Medieval World Map Stirs Anger</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL WEST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The prelate of <ORGANIZATION> Hereford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION>, which is crumbling for lack of cash, has provoked a heated dispute among churchmen and art experts by putting one of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s greatest medieval treasures on sale. The 708-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Mappa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundi </ORGANIZATION>, Latin for map of the world, has been kept in the cathedral for centuries and is to be auctioned by <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in June. News reports put its value at more than $ 4.5 million. The sale announcement Wednesday prompted a leading member of the cathedral's fund-raising committee to resign in protest. Newspapers have published angry editorials against the sale, and <ORGANIZATION> Hereford </ORGANIZATION> town leaders have vowed to fight it. The map shows historical events, Bible stories, topography, animals, plants and 420 cities on a 6-by-4 sheet of vellum. <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> is at the center of the map while <ORGANIZATION> Hereford </ORGANIZATION>, 144 miles northwest of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, is drawn on one edge. The controversy illuminates the dilemma faced by custodians of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s national heritage. The 900-year-old cathedral in <LOCATION> Hereford </LOCATION> is one of many in need of cash, but sales of treasures such as the <ORGANIZATION> Mappa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundi </ORGANIZATION> threaten to put the nation's historical heritage into the hands of foreign buyers and remove them from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The Dean of <LOCATION> Hereford </LOCATION>, the Very Rev. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, said in announcing the sale of the map that cathedral authorities need to clear a $ 273,000 overdraft and spend millions more on repairs, more staff, the cathedral's choir and new premises for its library of medieval books. Announcing his resignation from the fund-raising committee, Sir <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Strong </PERSON>, a former director of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Portrait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallery </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Museum </PERSON>, said Thursday, `` I was very upset to see the Dean standing outside his cathedral and holding up the <ORGANIZATION> Mappa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundi </ORGANIZATION>, its finest treasure, for sale to the world. `` If that is the kind of church they are running, I no longer want to be associated with it.'' Replied <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Champion </PERSON>, chairman of the cathedral's appeal committee: `` I am sorry he feels the way that he does ... Put bluntly, it is a choice of what is more important, continuing the work of the cathedral ... or retaining a marvelous medieval treasure.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, deputy mayor of <LOCATION> Hereford </LOCATION>, a town of 48,000, said he wants <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, as secular head of the Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, to intervene. The map `` may legally be the cathedral's, but morally it belongs to the citizens of <LOCATION> Hereford </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s says that as a national treasure, the <PERSON> Mappa </PERSON> <PERSON> Mundi </PERSON> is equivalent to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s 11th century <ORGANIZATION> Bayeux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tapestry </ORGANIZATION> depicting the invasion of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> by <PERSON> William </PERSON> the Conqueror in 1066. <PERSON> Georgina </PERSON> <PERSON> Nayler </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, said: `` We are outraged that one of the most important documents in the world is about to be put into an auction room.'' Lord <PERSON> Gowrie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s chairman, strongly denies allegations that no effort was made to find a British buyer. `` I am sorry that national institutions have not felt able to buy this great map,'' said <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Gowrie </PERSON>, adding that he spent more than a year seeking a buyer among government-funded bodies such as the British Library. The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that chances of the map staying in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> appear slim. Critics accuse Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s Conservative administration of starving the arts of adequate government funding. The government favors sponsorship of the arts by private industry. Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gem </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Cathedrals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> for <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> was quoted by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> as saying many other cathedrals in financial trouble may have to sell off `` very important treasures.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-TheChases-V Bjt   11-21 0912</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-The Chases-V, Bjt,0938</SECOND>
<HEAD>Part V: Fall's Flooded Fields End 1988 With Sad Irony</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This is the final installment of an occasional series that has told the story of the Drought of'88 through the eyes of one farm family, the Chases of <LOCATION> Barry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By LISA PERLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HASTINGS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> prayed for rain all summer long. Now they pray for just a few days of sunshine. In June, when hot, dry winds blew the dusty dirt off seeds that would n't germinate _ when the worst dry spell since the Dust Bowl of the 1930s left crops withered and stunted _ the Chases never expected their fields would be too muddy at harvest time. `` We've never seen a year like this,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says, shaking his head. `` We've gone from the worst drought in 50 years to one of the wettest and coldest Octobers ever. One extreme to the other.'' From April 1 through mid-July, the Chases' 1,100-acre cash-crop and dairy farm in southwest <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Barry </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> received barely an inch of rain. Since Aug. 1, about 18 inches of rain and an inch of snow have pounded the weak stalks of corn and wilted soybeans _ more than twice the normal amount of precipitation. The Chases are n't alone. Many of the same <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> farmers who struggled through the summer's devastating drought were taunted by rains that came too late to do any good. The recent downpours, which have forced many farmers to delay harvesting their shriveled crops, bring the year to a sad, ironic close. This will be the first time in the Chases' 18 years of farming that they will have no crop to sell. Everything they harvest will be needed to feed their 300 head of beef and dairy cattle. With only about half a silo full of high-moisture corn _ enough to last about three months _ the Chases will have to buy from other farmers. `` A year like this makes you realize more than ever that the weather is the farmer's biggest friend or worst enemy,'' <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says, sinking into a recliner in the couple's living room. He and his wife, both 51, estimate they lost about half their corn and soybean crop, and all of the string beans they were growing for a canning company. Their wheat crop was harvested before the drought hit in May. But the Chases do n't complain. `` At the height of the drought, you wondered whether you'd have anything at all,'' <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says with a shrug. The loss of their cash crop represents a 30-percent cut in the Chases' income. To compound their financial plight, their expenses have been 20 percent higher than normal, mostly because of the money they spent on irrigation. But because irrigation only helps when there's some rainfall, `` we got zero out of that,'' <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says in disgust, recalling the summer nights he and his son, <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON>, spent in the fields baby-sitting the irrigation system so that no water was wasted. The Chases are thankful their dairy herd, which represents about 60 percent of the farm's income, is healthy and productive. The income they make on their cash crop usually covers their operating expenses and pays for the 700 acres of land they rent _ about $ 75,000 this year. `` It's really frightening,'' <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says. `` We do n't know where we'll get it, but it'll work out. ... We do n't dwell on it because it reminds us how horrible that loss really is.'' The Chases also are thankful they have an understanding lender. They're waiting to find out if they qualify for the federal government's $ 3.9 billion drought-relief aid program. But they ca n't help but think back to their early spring projections. On paper, this looked like it was going to be the family's most prosperous year ever. After managing to save their farm from foreclosure three years ago by deeding to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and leasing it back _ parcel by parcel _ the Chases expected this year would be the one to pay off a sizable chunk of the debt they had accumulated. Now, all they'd like to do is finish harvesting by Thanksgiving _ a goal they've met every year. It seems unlikely this time. The Chases, who are in a partnership with son <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> and daughter-in-law <PERSON> Dena </PERSON>, pray for clear skies in order to harvest the remaining acres of corn and soybeans. Every time it rains _ or snows _ several dry days must follow before it's safe to take equipment out in the fields. They've already had equipment stuck in the mud twice `` Now all we can do is pray for a freeze,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says. `` But if it snows first, that'll just insulate it and it'll stay wet.'' And if the fields are n't harvested in the fall, it means more work in the spring because the fields would have to be cleared before planting. Meanwhile, the corn still standing in the brown, muddy fields is growing moldy, rendering it useless as feed for the cattle. And with each pounding rain, more of the weak crop is ruined. Still, the Chases look ahead with hope. `` I guess the thought of giving up does n't enter my mind,'' <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> says. `` Even though it has been a very trying year and very frustrating, we have a lot to be thankful for and we survive because we know next year will be better.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Homeless Bjt   11-21 0897</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless, Bjt,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Examples Abound Outside Convention on the Homeless</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conventioneers trying to figure out what to do about the homeless did n't have to walk far from their luxury hotel in the nation's capital to meet the problem face-to-face. <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, who runs a shelter in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, told the 800 people at the home builders symposium that they were ringed by the homeless. It was not much of an exaggeration. Two blocks from the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION>, in an alley, a 64-year-old woman in a smudged, ankle-length wool coat complained about her life on the streets since her husband died in 1976 and she lost her apartment. `` It's a crying shame that people have to live this way,'' said the woman, who is among as many as 15,000 people who are sleeping these cold autumn nights in the doorways of the nation's capital or in crowded temporary shelters because they have no place to live. A couple of blocks further, at a subway entrance, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Curley </PERSON>, 32, held up a cardboard sign: `` Lost apartment to fire ... please help ... all gifts are welcome.'' <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> said he can get occasional work with demolition crews for $ 70 a day, but had not earned enough to afford to eat and to rent the cheapest rooms available in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, which he said require a $ 150 advance payment for two weeks. `` I try not to look like a street person,'' he said. `` But I'm lucky to get a shower Hopefully by next week I will have amassed enough of a fortune to spend Thanksgiving indoors.'' Estimates of the number of homeless Americans range from 250,000 to several million. Experts agree that they will be a major challenge for President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s administration. All surveys show that the numbers of the homeless are growing, that they include increasing numbers of families with children and that they are found in all parts of the country. Many are people who hold jobs but do n't earn enough money to pay rent or qualify for mortgages. The symposium, sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Builders </ORGANIZATION> and an odd mix of establishment organizations and homeless action groups, sometimes sounded more like a human rights conference or tent revival than a gathering of mostly conservative business people. Participants gave a standing ovation on Friday to <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION>, whose shelter takes in hundreds of people every night. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, who has slept for months on city grates, fasted and been jailed in his 18-year battle for the homeless, accused the government of turning its back on the nation's neediest citizens and challenged the builders to cut their profits to help solve the problem. `` No one has a right to more than they really need to live. Anything beyond that is theft,'' he said. `` I may not be dressed as you are, but I ai n't no different,'' <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> said, standing at the podium in an olive drab jacket and a knit shirt open at the collar. Most of his audience, about half of them builders, were in business attire. After his speech, <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> told a reporter the well-dressed crowd was made up of `` decent people who struggle to be decent people. That's all anyone can expect.'' But <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>'s suggestion that the builders forsake profits to make low-income housing more affordable did n't sit well with some of them. `` When you continue to talk about giving up some of your profits, that ai n't the way that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> works,'' shouted builder <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, Del. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said homelessness can not be treated simply as a moral issue. He said it requires a strong federal housing policy and subsidies of low-income housing comparable to the billions of dollars in tax deductions allowed on home mortgage interest. <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Colton </PERSON>, builders association executive vice president, said many builders have cut profits to build low-income housing, and the industry has more than its share of bankruptcies. `` Builders are willing to be part of the solution,'' <PERSON> Colton </PERSON> said in an interview, `` but leadership has to come from the federal government. The new administration has the opportunity to focus on the positive side of housing as a national priority.'' The symposium included two days of meetings focusing on how businessmen and others can help shelter the homeless, including sessions on creative financing, job training and construction methods. Some participants also toured homeless shelters in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area. A woman at a floor microphone during one session shouted an appeal: `` If we get together and pray together we can do something about this situation.'' A <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> priest, the Rev. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleba </PERSON>, challenged each of the nation's 400,000 church congregations to join local builders in constructing one house apiece for the homeless. <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, in a conference keynote speech, called the homeless `` our brothers and sisters.'' Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, said some Americans are `` almost too alone to live in a house.'' He said that simply building more houses, particularly for the mentally ill, wo n't solve all the problems. Conventioneers, who paid $ 95 apiece to attend the two-day conference, passed by huge photographs of sorrowful women and children and a naked man standing in a hall before a cluster of wheelchairs. They ate elaborately prepared desserts at the end of a gourmet luncheon and then were told that baskets of vegetables serving as centerpieces would be donated to a homeless shelter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     11-21 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,xxx</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDs. Bush announcement skedded for 9:30 a.m. EST; will be topped.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, faced with unease in the financial markets over the gaping budge deficits, today will name <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> to run <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> and tap <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON> as chief financial adviser, transition sources say. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> scheduled a morning news conference today to make what his office described only as an announcement about the transtion. But sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the president-elect has enlisted <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> as director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON> as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisers </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> was the right arm of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> throughout the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, both when <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> was White House chief of staff and later as <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> secretary. He played a behind-the-scenes role in negotiating the 1983 rescue plan for Social Security. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> was a whiz kid for <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> as secretary of health, education and welfare in the early 1970s. <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON> is a well-known conservative economist and expert on the Social Security system. He was a father of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s `` flexible freeze'' idea to drive down the deficit in four years. The stock market has sagged and the value of the dollar fallen since <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> captured the White House Nov. 8 from fears that his no-tax-hike pledge will impede efforts to bring down the deficit, now growing by $ 155 billion a year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he takes the deficit seriously and will work with Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to forge a solution. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spent a quiet weekend out of the limelight, attending church Sunday, jogging and conferring at home with Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, his chosen chief of staff. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was also meeting today with two former presidents, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, who have made some bipartisan recommendations for the incoming president. Also on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s schedule is a meeting with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Packard </PERSON>, the computer magnate who headed a commission that recommended an overhaul of <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> procurement procedures. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> revealed last Tuesday he is keeping his friend <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> as treasury secretary. He told reporters Friday he was concentrating on naming the rest of his economic team before turning his attention to defense and national security posts. In <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s second term, <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> was deputy to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> as treasury secretary. Both left the government when <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> resigned in August to run <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presidential campaign. <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON> argued in a recent book titled `` Too Many Promises'' that the program should be overhauled to separate its welfare and pension functions. <PERSON> Boskin </PERSON> proposed a two-tier system, with a flat monthly payment aimed at helping people stay out of poverty and the second or upper tier tied strictly to how much people paid into the system. Currently there is a sharp tilt to Social Security benefits, with lower-income workers getting a far heftier return on their payroll taxes than middle - and upper-income workers <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> named <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, his longtime associate from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, as his choice for secretary of state the morning after the election. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who served eight months as a caretaker senator from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> in 1982, was sworn in two months ago as <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s successor at <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>. He is a former chairman of the investment banking house of <ORGANIZATION> Dillon </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Read </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co.. Inc.. On Tuesday, the president-elect plans to fly to <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> to visit a conference of Republican governors and to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> for a get-acquainted meeting with Mexican president-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, who takes office Dec. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> was preceding <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> governors conference to deliver a luncheon speech there today. The governors will also hear from <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign manager and now his choice for chairman of the Republican party. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will return to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Tuesday night, then fly Wednesday to <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, for a long Thanksgiving holiday weekend that could include a fence-mending session with <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the vanquished Democratic presidential nominee. cvc
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881121-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-21-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugTesting Bjt   11-21 0942</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Testing, Bjt,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Drug Testing to Quadruple</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
