<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-RowanShooting     07-28 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rowan Shooting,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Columnist To Face Weapons Possession Charges, Newspaper Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANITA WOMACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syndicated columnist <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> will face weapons possession charges after shooting a teen-ager who had taken an unauthorized predawn dip in <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>'s backyard swimming pool, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday night. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said in its Friday editions that <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> was charged with possession of an unregistered handgun and unregistered ammunition in District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Layton </PERSON>, director of communications for the <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> government, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that officials refused to comment on the the case until Friday, when a statement will be issued. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, 62, was cleared of assault charges in the case on June 23 after an investigation by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> said at the time that he believed <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> should be prosecuted for possessing an unregistered handgun. But <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON> deferred that decision to the city, which normally decides whether to prosecute such cases. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, who has frequently written columns calling for strict restrictions on handgun use, was out of town and unavailable for comment. His wife, <PERSON> Vivian </PERSON>, said the couple had no knowledge of the charges against <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said it had been told by <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> office of corporation counsel, which under local law has the authority to prosecute cases involving unregistered firearms, that <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> was charged on Wednesday. The shooting renewed debate on handgun restrictions, as pro-gun groups accused <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> of hypocrisy for owning a gun after publicly opposing the practice. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> said he obtained the weapon after receiving death threats. If convicted on the charges, the columnist faces a maximum penalty of two years in jail and a $ 2,000 fine in connection with the June 14 incident at his northwest <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> home. The District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s 1976 handgun ordinance requires that all weapons be registered, but <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> told authorities that the gun had belonged to his son, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> claimed that his son was told he did not have to register the weapon after leaving the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> told authorities that he shot <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, after hearing noises in his back yard, calling police and discovering <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and three other youths by his pool. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> said he shot <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> after the teen-ager lunged at him. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> disputed that, saying he did not threaten the columnist and was shot while trying to flee. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who was wounded in the wrist, was treated and released the same day from <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. He and and a companion were each charged with one count of unlawful entry stemming from their foray onto <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>'s property, but prosecutors dropped the misdemeanor charges in exchange for 40 hours of community service work from both.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-St.Patrick'sShooting     07-28 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-St. Patrick's Shooting,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officer Kills Man Accused Of Robbery Outside St. Patrick's</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA ROSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man robbed a tourist at gunpoint on crowded Fifth Avenue outside <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Patrick </LOCATION>'s Cathedral, then was shot and killed Wednesday when he tried to escape in a car driven by an off-duty correction officer, police said. During a struggle inside the car, the correction officer fired his gun, striking the robbery suspect three times in the chest, said a police spokesman, Sgt. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. The suspect, <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Santiago </PERSON>, 22, of Queens died later in the afternoon at <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. The correction officer, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON>, 33, also shot himself in the foot during the struggle and was in stable condition at <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> fired no shots, but police recovered a revolver, believed to be <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>'s, that contained five live rounds, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON>'s 5-year-old son, also named <PERSON> John </PERSON>, was in the car at the time of the 5 p.m. shooting but was not injured, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. A second robbery suspect was still at large, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Muncie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said he was visiting midtown <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> with his family, standing on the sidewalk photographing the historic Roman Catholic cathedral, when two men pulled up in a car and one got out and demanded his video camera. `` He said if you do n't give me your camera and take it over and put it in that car right now I'm going to shoot you. At that point I did n't believe he had a gun,'' said <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON>. `` But then he pulled the gun and when he pulled the gun I gave him the camera,'' <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON> said. As the robbers tried to speed off, their car collided with a taxi and then slammed into the side of a bus. The pair then jumped out of their car and fled on foot before <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> got into <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON>'s car, police said. The gun used by <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> was his personal revolver, which he was authorized to carry, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON> recovered his video camera from the robbery suspects' car, where they had left it behind when they fled, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said `` We've been riding the subways every place we go and not had a fear in the world,'' said <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON>, who was with his wife, their 6-year-old daughter and 9-year-old son and Mrs. <PERSON> Ashcraft </PERSON>'s uncle. Now, he said, `` I'm a little afraid.'' But he said he would n't consider <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> `` a bad place. It's just one incident.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 4thLd-Writethru a0783 07-28 1195</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0783,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Asks Information From Kemp, Other VP Prospects</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS new graf 12 with with Dukakis signing money bill;
SUBS 13th graf pvs, Aides to, to CORRECT that Alexander is former
governor</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stepped up his search for a vice presidential running mate Wednesday, inviting former rival <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and other prominent Republicans o submit detailed background information. Democratic candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> burnished his law-and-order credentials. Several other Republicans who figure prominently in vice presidential speculation have not yet received questionnaires from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, according to their spokesmen. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has about three weeks left to pick a running mate for the fall campaign, also disclosed plans to testify before the Republican platform committee when it meets the week before the party's convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> early next month. Republican sources said a request for background information had gone out to Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> as well as to <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. And <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> said he had received a questionnaire from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign officials. An aide for <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said the congressman met with <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimmitt </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney who is helping the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign filter possible running mates. The aide, <PERSON> Marci </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, said the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> congressman would return the material to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign within a week. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, lambasted the Republican for opposing the Equal Rights Amendment and other women's concerns. `` The Reagan-Bush administration opposes the ERA ... they ripped it out of the -LRB- Republican -RRB- platform,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> and Professional Women meeting in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>, N.M. He said that despite <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s call last week for tax credits for day care, the administration fought ` ` every step of the way'' against a $ 50 million spending proposal with the same goal <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, boosted by his own party's convention, drew his biggest lead of the presidential campaign _ 18 points over <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ in the latest <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> poll. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spent his day in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, ostensibly tending to <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> statehouse duties but staging a bill-signing ceremony for legislation to add about 1,000 beds to state prisons and to restore child pornography legislation that was struck down by the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. He also announced distribution of $ 7.8 million in state and federal grants to assist the victims of crime, and said his state is a national leader in `` increasing sensitivity and awareness of what it is like to be a victim of crime.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also cited a 13 percent drop in crime in his state in the past four years. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' public events during the day seemed designed to counter the Republican charge that he is soft on crime, particularly in view of his one-time support for a prison furlough program that permitted some first-degree murderers to receive passes. One such prisoner raped a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> woman while on furlough. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also signed a $ 124 million spending plan to close the books on the fiscal year that ended June 30. The money was largely for underfunded entitlement programs such as Medicaid and Aid to Families with Dependent Children. Aides to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meanwhile, have said he is conducting polling in several key states to gauge the impact of several potential running mates. In addition to <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, the names mentioned most frequently in the speculation include <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>. Several women's names also crop up periodically, including Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>, a former secretary of Transportation. Aides to Sen. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>, former <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and Sens. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> all said they had not received questionnaires. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign officials declined to say how seriously candidates such as <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> were being taken, although there was speculation that at least some names were being made public to mask the true deliberations as well as to give the officials involved additional stature in their states. One man not mentioned in the speculation, Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, held a news conference in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to announce an effort designed to pressure <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> into picking a conservative running mate. <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> said the Coalition for a Winning Ticket would not be a `` stalking horse for any one candidate'' but a `` rallying point for conservatives who hope to persuade the vice president to choose someone from the conservative majority wing of the party.'' As for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, campaign spokeswoman <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> said the vice president would travel to the convention city of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> on Aug. 8 to address the platform committee and `` put his stamp of approval on the platform.'' The vice president is n't expected to return until Aug. 17, the day he is formally nominated as the party's candidate for president. In other developments, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> disclosed it is conducting a multi-million dollar advertising campaign leading up to the convention. The three, 30-second commercials do not mention <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> by name, but tout `` seven years of jobs, peace and economic growth brought to you by the Republicans.'' One commercial evokes images of the high inflation and long gas lines of <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s presidency as the announcer says, `` The Republicans have worked very hard to make sure you'll never have to see it again.'' In the latest poll _ a telephone survey of 1,770 registered voters conducted Saturday through Monday _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> received 50 percent support to 32 percent for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had led by 10 points, 46-36, in a pre-convention NBC-Journal poll. Other recent surveys have found a jump in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' support, common for presidential nominees following their party conventions. Two Gallup polls done after the convention had <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ahead by 17 points, and he led by 10 points in one poll and by 12 in another conducted during the convention. The latest poll found women providing a major component of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' support, a continuation of the `` gender gap'' suffered by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> led by 30 points among women, 54-24, compared to a six-point lead among men. The survey had a margin of error of three points. Among the Democrats, an aide to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said the runner-up to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the primary campaign is `` fired up'' and ready to begin active campaigning for the party's ticket. A spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would continue to receive security protection while a decision is made on whether to grant protection for the entire fall campaign. In <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> met briefly Wednesday with <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> to discuss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s role in the campaign, but neither side would give details. `` It's part of a series of meetings to ensure ongoing communication with all parts of the party and to make certain everyone gets involved,'' committee spokeswoman <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anbender </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Also Wednesday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told a group of young inventors `` this election is really about you,'' saying they and other young people hold the key to the 21st century. `` Education is the engine that drives our inventive spirit,'' the vice president said, reiterating his frequently sounded theme that he wants to be the `` education president.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-IrelandPilgrimage     07-28 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ireland Pilgrimage,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>O'Connor Disagrees With Koch On British In N. Ireland</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICK HAMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, breaking with fellow peace pilgrim Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, said Wednesday that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> should remove its `` occupying forces'' from <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> `` within a reasonable time.'' `` I can not imagine there will be lasting peace ... until all British troops have withdrawn,'' he told reporters as he left <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> after a six-day peace pilgrimage. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> had said at the start of the pilgrimage that he'd come to pray, not to talk politics. But the cardinal broke his silence after <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, his pilgrimage companion, reversed himself and endorsed the British presence in <LOCATION> Ulster </LOCATION>. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who returned Wednesday afternoon to <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, called on <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> officials to announce `` a phased withdrawal'' _ one the cardinal said was supported by most people in the province. Asked if it should begin immediately, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> replied, `` That's not for me to say. Before leaving <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> on Tuesday, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said a day in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> had convinced him the British do not deserve `` the castigation that many of us, myself included, have heaped upon them. The British army is not an ` occupation force,' -LRB- but rather -RRB- a guardian of peace.'' The British army has patrolled <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> since the early 1970s, when a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> civil rights movement came under attack by <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> police and paramilitary groups. But the Protestant violence also revitalized the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>; since then, the primary opponents have been the British and the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>, which wants to unite the island. In recent years many British troops have been withdrawn, and their duties assumed by members of Ulster's army reserve. About two-thirds of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s population is Protestant, and surveys indicate that a majority of the province's residents _ including many Catholics _ favor union with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said his own 24 hours in Ulster convinced him there is `` an environment of increasing understanding'' between Catholics and Protestants, and that `` an overwhelming number'' of both want the troops out. Although <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said he based his conclusion on talks with Protestants, he did not meet with militants in either community during his visit. The mayor's comments drew a heated response from Irish-American politicians, including <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Comptroller <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, who called the remarks `` senseless and ridiculous.'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> was more circumspect. He said he was not angry with <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, and felt that because <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> did not grow up as an Irish-American, he failed to realize the British have been calling themselves peacemakers in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> for centuries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0645EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--RobberClerk     07-28 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Robber Clerk,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Calls To Complain About Service From Robber-Turned-Clerk</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rude treatment by a clerk at a Radio Shack store prompted a customer to call the store and complain. But it turned out that the man who waited on her was a robber, police say. Three men walked into the suburban Colerain store Tuesday, pulled a revolver on a clerk, then took him to a back room and tied him up, police said. Before the three could take anything, the woman, whom police would not identify, walked in. One of the gunmen, who was wearing a white dress shirt, went behind a counter to wait on her. She purchased her merchandise and left, and the three then escaped. Police arrived after the clerk freed himself, and an officer answered the woman's call of complaint about `` the demeanor and conduct'' of the service, police said. Officers told her she had been waited on by a burglar and asked her to return to the store to help identify the robbers. No arrests were made.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BeggarBillboards     07-28 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beggar Billboards,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Billboards Against Beggars May Hurt El Paso Image, Critics Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four highway billboards that urge motorists not to give to street beggars have drawn some uncharitable comments from the city's <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, which worries the advertisements may hurt El Paso's image. `` I'm concerned -LRB- they -RRB- may not do good service to the fact that this city is a truly giving city,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dugan </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` It does n't portray us as the kind of city I know us to be.'' An anonymous group paid for four billboards along Interstate 10 that read: `` Please do n't give to beggars _ they cause traffic problems.'' The signs are the latest development in a controversy about street beggars who cross the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juarez </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, and panhandle on interstate access roads east of downtown. City Councilman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Candelaria </PERSON>, who participated in several council discussions about the scores of beggars congregating at access road intersections, said people who give encourage panhandlers to return. He said givers can contribute in other ways. `` We feel sorry for the people, but they endanger their lives by crossing near I-10,'' <PERSON> Candelaria </PERSON> said. `` Give your charitable dollars to Project Hungry before you give to these beggars.'' Some witnesses told the council earlier this month that panhandlers often are employed by Juarez-based professional begging rings, and that they often are not as needy as they seem. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Huff </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Bauman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the billboards, said the group that paid for the ads wishes to remain anonymous. The ads cost about $ 1,200 and will be visible for about two weeks, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0242EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--AIDS-Kissing     07-28 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--AIDS-Kissing,0140</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Say Kissing Can Transmit AIDS</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MUNICH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bavarian state officials are warning people leaving on vacation to avoid sex and French kissing with strangers as a precaution against AIDS. The recommendations, carried in a travelers' brochure issued Wednesday, unleashed an angry debate over how the deadly disease is transmitted. AIDS-Help, a West German group that gives AIDS advice, accused state officials of trying to `` legitimize pseudo-medicine.'' The group said the salivary gland can not transmit AIDS. However, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, an AIDS adviser to the Bavarian government, said tests indicate it might be possible for the deadly virus to be transmitted through mucous membranes. AIDS, which attacks the body's immune system, is spread mainly by sexual contact, the use of contaminated needles among drug abusers and transfusion of tainted blood.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Murder-Suicide     07-28 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Murder-Suicide,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>Child Actress And Parents Dead In Apparent Murder-Suicide</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA10, 11</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL FLEEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A child actress who starred in last summer's `` Jaws IV: The Revenge'' was killed with her mother Wednesday in an apparent murder-suicide initiated by her father, who also died, authorities said The coroner had not yet identified the couple and the child, but neighbors said the girl was <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON>, 11, who starred in the third sequel to the series about a man-eating shark. Miss <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON> also appeared in the partly fact-based television movie `` Fatal Vision,'' playing a daughter of Dr. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON>, who was convicted of killing his pregnant wife and both his daughters at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bragg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, in 1970. Miss <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON>'s father apparently shot the girl and the mother in their heads, set the inside of the house on fire, then turned the gun on himself, police said. The fire caused extensive damage to the interior of the home. A researcher at <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> confirmed Miss <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON> starred in `` Jaws IV: The Revenge'' as a character called `` Thea.'' She also performed in several commercials and had appeared in the television show `` Growing Pains,'' neighbors said. `` She was adorable ... quite precocious, blonde and blue-eyed,'' said former neighbor <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON> <PERSON> Conway </PERSON>. She said the mother and father had been having marital problems. Neighbors said they heard an explosion at 8:30 a.m., then saw flames shooting out of a front window of the tan, single-story house on a quiet street. One neighbor tried to douse the flames with water from a garden hose until firefighters arrived. Officers at the scene said the father, identified by neighbors as <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON>, apparently doused the interior of the couple's home with gasoline and set it ablaze before shooting himself in the head. The mother, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON>, estimated to be about 40, was found in the hallway and the body of Miss <PERSON> Barsi </PERSON> in a bedroom, officials said. Both had been burned, said Fire Battalion Chief <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Police Lt. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Knowles </PERSON> said the man was found still holding the gun. Neighbors said the girl had an extremely protective father. `` The child was not allowed to go anywhere, very few places alone,'' said neighbor <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. `` Even when she came to our home, it always had to be OK'd by <PERSON> Dad </PERSON> before she came up the street because apparently he was afraid she would run away.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DadeTeachers     07-28 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dade Teachers,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Board Approves Raising Teachers' Top Pay To $64,000</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teacher contract that significantly boosts salaries in the nation's fourth-largest school system and pays $ 64,000 to some veteran educators won unanimous approval Wednesday from the <ORGANIZATION> Dade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The three-year contract increases average teacher pay for the upcoming academic year 28 percent to $ 33,066, more than $ 5,000 above the national median. `` The excuse that teachers could not do their jobs because of low pay is no longer an excuse in this school system,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Krop </PERSON>, chairman of the seven-member school board. `` Many school systems have talked about programs like this, but we did something about it.'' <PERSON> Krop </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dade </PERSON> has already received more applicants because of publicity about the pay proposal. <ORGANIZATION> Dade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> Superintendent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> said he hoped the pay increase will raise the status of teaching in the minds of students making career choices. `` We want young people making their professional decisions to not look at teaching as a dead-end profession,'' <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> told the school board. <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s system, with about 255,000 students and more than 15,200 teachers, is the nation's fourth-largest behind <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Under the contract, a first-year teacher would receive $ 23,000 annually and $ 64,000 a year would be paid to an educator with 14 years experience, a doctorate and who teaches summer school. The average salaries would increase to $ 36,042 the second year and $ 39,646 the third year, said <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> schools spokesman <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gollan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GoetzAppeal     07-28 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Goetz Appeal,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Agrees To Hear Goetz Gun Charge Appeal</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s highest court, agreed Wednesday to hear <PERSON> Bernhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s appeal of his conviction on charges that he illegally possessed the gun he used to shoot four young men on a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> subway in 1985 Without comment, Judge <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellacosa </PERSON> granted the appeal and scheduled arguments for Oct. 17, said <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mordaunt </PERSON>. <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s original sentence on the gun possession charges had been ruled illegal by a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> appeals court and his resentencing is set for Oct. 22 in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>'s lawyers claim that state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, the trial judge, erred in his instructions to the jury and that the gun conviction should be overturned. <PERSON> Crane </PERSON> had originally sentenced <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> to six months in jail, a $ 5,000 fine, 280 hours of community service, five years probation and psychiatric counseling. The <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> appeals court allowed all but the jail term to stand. The appeals court ruled that <PERSON> Crane </PERSON> should give <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> an undeterminate sentence or, if sentencing was going to be under <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s gun control laws, a definite one-year term without probation. <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON>, 40, was convicted last summer of third-degree illegal possession of a gun in connection with the December 1984 shooting aboard a subway of four teen-agers he said were trying to rob him. The young men claimed they were panhandling for money. <PERSON> Goetz </PERSON> was acquitted of all but the gun charge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Volcano-Quakes     07-28 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Volcano-Quakes,0588</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rumbling Beneath Volcano Draws Attention</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scores of small quakes have rattled an Aleut fishing village during the past 17 days, and geologists say they are keeping a wary eye on the possible source: a volcano that's been dormant for centuries. King Cove village is only nine miles from <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dutton </ORGANIZATION>'s 4,834-foot peak About 1,000 people live in the village during the summer; 700 stay through winter. Aside from the earthquakes that have been jolting the community 625 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, there have been no other signs of an imminent eruption, said <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Yount </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey geologist here. `` There's no melting back of snow around the summit. No steam-type vents,'' sher said Wednesday. `` We're still assessing the seismic activity to determine whether it's related to volcanic activity or not.'' Geologists are unsure when <PERSON> Mount </PERSON> <PERSON> Dutton </PERSON> last erupted. `` There's no historical records of its erupting. That means in the past 200 or so years,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, state seismologist and coordinating scientist for the newly formed <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volcano </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION>. `` It may have erupted 500 years ago, but we have no date. Clearly, it's erupted in the last 10,000 years or so.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Taber </PERSON>, a geologist with <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lamont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doherty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Palisades </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said seismographs first picked up earthquake activity near <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dutton </LOCATION> on July 11. Some of the 18 instruments installed by the institute to monitor Aleutian Arc volcanic activity indicated the first temblors were centered 10 to 15 miles southeast of the peak, he said. `` In the last three or four days its been dying off,'' <PERSON> Taber </PERSON> said from the institute's Sand Point office. `` There's no cause for concern at this point at all. There was a sequence of -LRB- earthquakes -RRB- in 1984. They were smaller, but they went on for about four months. It's not even unusual to have them there.'' Scores of quakes ranging from 1.0 to 3.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale have struck in this round. The peak activity occurred Friday, when 127 were recorded, <PERSON> Taber </PERSON> said. On Monday, there were 25, he said. The epicenters moved slowly toward the <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dutton </LOCATION>, and in the last few days, the centers have been underneath the volcano's south flank, <PERSON> Taber </PERSON> said. The temblors have jolted the nearby village regularly. `` We've felt four or five in a day, that's probably the most But there's no other sign of activity at all,'' said <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuelson </PERSON>, city clerk the village on the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> `` People are concerned, but no one's leaving.'' <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> officials had been scheduled to travel to King Cove in September, but went this week because of the earthquakes, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sey </PERSON>, the agency's chief of operations and planning. `` The main purpose was just to answer questions, make people aware and bring them up to date on what's happening and explain different things they could do if there were an eruption,'' Sey said. A telephone line is being installed so that the <ORGANIZATION> Geophysical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alaska-Fairbanks </ORGANIZATION> can monitor <PERSON> Taber </PERSON>'s seismographs, plus one <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> recently installed on the mountain's <PERSON> Taber </PERSON> has been in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> servicing his observatory's seismographs and plans to leave this week, <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> said The link will allow scientists in Fairbanks to check the volcano's pulse virtually around the clock, he said. `` We're going to monitor it as closely as we can,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cambodia 1stLd-Writethru a0611 07-28 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0611,0797</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prime Minister Says Khmer Rouge Obstructing Talks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with Cambodia prime minister
quoted as saying Khmer Rouge trying to obstruct talks. Picks up 2nd
graf pvs, `The enduringly ...' Edits thereafter to conform and
trim. Changes byline.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOR, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s prime minister was quoted Thursday as saying <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla delegates tried to obstruct agreements at talks on ending <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s civil war. The <ORGANIZATION> Jakarta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted Prime Minister <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> of the Vietnamese-installed government as saying he would hold a third round of separate peace talks with resistance leader Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> in October. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>'s forces are allied with the communist <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Son </PERSON> <PERSON> Sann </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> in a coalition fighting Vietnamese troops that invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, the guerrilla groups, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and the six-member <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday began their fourth day of informal peace talks in <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Jakarta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Khieu </PERSON> <PERSON> Samphan </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> representative, `` was not forthcoming to the point of acting obstructive when it came to nailing down some specific points of agreement.'' On Wednesday, <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> urged all factions to agree on a plan for ending the `` miseries and humiliations'' that have afflicted <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> since the <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION> war ended in 1975. The enduringly popular leader, who ruled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> until 1970, made the remarks in <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION>, where he has tried to influence developments in a meeting of the four factions at <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION>, about 40 miles south of the capital. All factions agree that <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, 65, should have a central role in the future leadership. `` I ask you not to leave <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> without having signed together a joint communique which shall tell our people and the world that the four Cambodian factions are at least capable to understand each other on certain essential points ... leading us towards the end of a long and dark tunnel,'' <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> said. Evoking the glories of Cambodian history, he said: `` Allow me to recall that you all pretend to be the dignified descendants of the very glorious builders of the world famous monuments of Angkor. `` If, like dignified descendants of the builders of Angkor, our four factions wish to rapidly get rid of the last Vietnamese units from our soil, they will only succeed to do so by achieving national reconciliation and unity.'' Angkor, in northwestern <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, was the capital of the Khmer Empire from the 9th century to the 15th. Its most imposing monuments are Angkor Wat, a temple complex built in the 12th century by King Suryavariman II, and <PERSON> Angkor </PERSON> <PERSON> Thom </PERSON>, built about 1200 by <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayavarman </PERSON> VII. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> said, speaking in English, that it is handy to blame <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> for all <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s troubles, `` but it is not less true that some Khmer -LRB- <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> -RRB- factions are equally heavily responsible for these miseries and humilations.'' <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in December 1978 and ousted the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> regime of <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON>, which gained control at the end of the war and had killed hundreds of thousands of Cambodians. More than 100,000 Vietnamese soldiers remain in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, fighting the resistance coalition <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> formerly led. <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> has said it will withdraw all its troops by early 1990. The prince called for an interim government of the four factions under `` a collegial system perfectly equal,'' and proposed that fighting units be kept intact under a general staff representing all factions. Each government department would have four co-ministers. An international conference convened under the auspices of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> secretary-general would supervise withdrawal of foreign forces, guarantee the nation's neutrality and help organize free elections. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> resigned earlier this month as head of the resistance coalition and is in <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION> as a guest of President <PERSON> Suharto </PERSON>, which allows him to participate in the peace talks indirectly. <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> presented his own peace plan at <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION> on Monday, and <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> said his proposals include some of its points. `` I think my proposal is the most realistic,'' he said. `` The very solution is in my proposals, not those of the charming <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>. I have to reject all other proposals in favor of mine.'' He and <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON> negotiated in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last December and January without finding a formula for peace. Son <PERSON> Sann </PERSON> said he supported <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>'s plan but the other participants were not available for comment. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Co </PERSON> <PERSON> Thach </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> told a news conference Wednesday that working groups would be formed to prepare for further negotiations. No conclusive agreement had been expected from the <LOCATION> Bogor </LOCATION> conference, which was considered a success for merely taking place.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PipeBombs     07-28 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pipe Bombs,0379</SECOND>
<HEAD>24-Year-Old Arraigned in Suburban Pipe Bombings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEFAN FATSIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 24-year-old carpenter was charged in federal court Wednesday in connection with a series of pipe bombs planted last week on streets, in a mailbox and in a newspaper vending machine in two suburban towns. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tefft </PERSON>, who said he had homes in both <LOCATION> Framingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Belmont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, was charged in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> with unlawful possession of an unregistered destructive device, interstate transportation of 10 destructive devices and malicious damage to property by means of an explosion. Each charge carries a maximum penalty of up to 10 years in jail and a $ 250,000 fine. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON>, assistant agent in charge of the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> office of the federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>, said an investigation is continuing and there may be other arrests in the case. Three of the homemade pipe bombs exploded in <LOCATION> Needham </LOCATION> last week, one each outside the police and fire department and one in a newspaper vending machine about 15 seconds after a jogger ran by. All mailboxes in the town were sealed after a fourth bomb was found unexploded in a box outside the post office. Two undetonated devices were found later in neighboring Wellesely. Authorities said <PERSON> Tefft </PERSON> gave no reason for exploding the devices. They declined to say whether he was involved in all the incidents, but they said he traveled between <LOCATION> Needham </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> to make and plant some of the devices. <PERSON> Tefft </PERSON> was arrested late Tuesday by <ORGANIZATION> ATF </ORGANIZATION> agents assisted by state and local police as he drove into a friend's driveway in <LOCATION> Needham </LOCATION>, authorities said. The bombs were made of galvanized pipes about 6 inches long, filled with gunpowder, threaded and capped on both ends, with fuse holes in the middle, authorities said. Trooper <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherven </PERSON>, who is assigned to the state fire marshal's office, said `` any spark, heat source or static'' electricity could cause the bombs to explode. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sainato </PERSON>, senior explosives technician with the state police, said the bomb found in the mailbox was `` as powerful as a military grenade ... -LRB- and -RRB- could send 10 pieces of shrapnel flying off at 6,000 feet a second.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-The``L''Word Bjt   07-28 0578</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The ``L'' Word, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Liberalism Remains Issue Despite Presidential
Scoffing</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Back in 1936, Republican <PERSON> Alf </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> campaigned against <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and his New Deal by telling voters, `` I believe that a man can be a liberal without being a spendthrift.'' How times have changed. The Republicans would n't dare call themselves liberals in this presidential campaign, and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says the Democrats wo n't either. `` You'll never hear that ` L' word - liberal - from them,'' the president said in his radio address last weekend. Some liberals and academics agree with the president, although they say the issues underlying the question of liberalism will still be part of the campaign just as they have been since New Deal days. <PERSON> Landon </PERSON>'s claim to being a liberal did n't do him much good. <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> was re-elected in the biggest electoral landslide in the history of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presidential elections. After that the political landscape shifted, and by 1964, presidential nominee <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON> was telling fellow Republicans, `` Extremism in the defense of liberty is no vice and moderation in the pursuit of justice is no virtue.'' <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON> fared little better than <PERSON> Landon </PERSON>, as voters gave a green light to <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s `` Great Society.'' Not all of <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s programs turned out as their backers hoped, however. And, as resistance to the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war deepened, liberalism took on a new face _ one which drew the scorn of the then-governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, among others. `` The word ` liberal' came to be associated with costly government activities which did n't eradicate the problems for which they were intended,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>, professor of political science and public affairs at The <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Secondly, the word ` liberal' got a bad connotation because of the protests over the war in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. I think the word liberal started getting a real bad rap during the period from 1968 to 1972, culminating in the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> candidacy.'' <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON>, director of the liberal organization Americans for Democratic Action, conceded, `` There is a recognition on the part of many liberals, of many Democrats, that to admit to being a liberal somehow is a detriment, is a negative.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moe </PERSON>, a former aide to 1984 Democratic nominee <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, said he does n't think it makes much difference what the Republicans or the Democrats call each other. `` All of these labels take on different meanings in different contexts at different times,'' said <PERSON> Moe </PERSON>. `` There is an ebb and flow to American history. I do n't attach much significance to labels or what people say about labels. I think the election is going to be fought out on a different ground.'' Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> suggested one ground when he said in his acceptance speech that `` this election is not about ideology; it's about competence.'' `` If that becomes the case, it would be the first one in modern political history that was able to achieve that,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> ADA </ORGANIZATION>'s Pearl Instead, suggested <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON>, `` they are all going to be fighting for the center, as it were, because that's where the decisions are going to be made.'' <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> put it this way: `` I think the new Democratic position is to be conservative on economic issues, and liberal on social issues.'' Sounds a lot like <PERSON> Alf </PERSON> <PERSON> Landon </PERSON>, does n't it?
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-HefnerMarriage     07-28 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hefner Marriage,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>Playboy Talks Of Giving Up Bachelorhood</HEAD>
<HEAD>Kimberley is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA METZLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Playboy empire founder <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> said he chose to give up life as a pajama-clad swinging single and marry model <PERSON> Kimberley </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> because `` it will make the relationship better.'' <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> proposed to Ms. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Playboy </PERSON> magazine's Miss January 1988, on Saturday over the wishing well at the <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mansion </ORGANIZATION>, where many other women have shared his life but never completely captured his heart. `` I always had the feeling before that there was something else, some further personal adventure waiting over the hill,'' he said in a telephone interview Wednesday. But in this case, he said: `` It is inconceivable that there could be something else that could be comparable or better.'' <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, 62, described his fiancee as `` a homebody,'' who despite the age difference holds similar interests in things like animals and spending evenings talking and watching old movies. Ms. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, who turns 26 next week, said she thought about <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>'s proposal for a minute, then said `` ` Yes' because I ca n't imagine life without him. She plans to give up modeling. `` I'd rather be at home with <PERSON> Hef </PERSON>. He's my priority,'' she said. Ms. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>'s family apparently is supporting the marriage, planned for sometime next year at the mansion. `` I wish them all the luck in the world,'' her grandmother <PERSON> Lila </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said Wednesday from her home in <LOCATION> Moulton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, where her granddaughter was born. <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> said he has never proposed marriage to anyone `` nor ever really considered marriage'' since his 1958 divorce from his first wife. `` I am doing it as much for myself as for her,'' he said. `` It is going to make the relationship better, that security, that continuity, that reaffirmation.'' Ms. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, who met <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> last summer during a photo shooting, moved into the Playboy Mansion with two dogs and cat shortly after <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>'s longtime flame <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> moved out in January. Earlier this year, Ms. <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION>'s 1983 cover girl, attempted to bring a $ 35 million palimony action against <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON> after their affair soured, but it later was dropped. Ms. <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> said Wednesday through manager <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Battig </PERSON>: `` I hope that he's finally happy at 62 years of age.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Peru-Blackout     07-28 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peru-Blackout,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blackout Blamed On Leftist Guerrillas Hits Capital Before Garcia
Speech</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A blackout hit the capital and most of coastal <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> Wednesday night, hours before President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> was to give his state-of-the-union address. Leftist guerrillas may have sabotaged power lines and caused the blackout, said <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, spokesman for the state power company Electro-Peru. Shining Path guerrillas and a smaller rebel group, the pro-Cuban <ORGANIZATION> Tupac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amaru </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, have caused dozens of blackouts in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and used the cover of darkness to launch attacks. Radio Programas, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s leading news station, said people heard explosions in several parts of the capital. Police told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> they had no reports of guerrilla violence during the power outage. The blackout at 8:15 p.m. affected <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, cities along the 600 miles of the central Peruvian coastline and the highland city of <LOCATION> Huancayo </LOCATION>, 125 miles east of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> said. Power was restored to most areas within an hour, but areas south of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> were still without electrticity late Wednesday night, <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> planned to speak midday Thursday and is expected to address growing violence by leftist guerrillas. The government says more than 12,000 people have been killed in the violence connected to the 8-year-old insurgency of the <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION>, a Maoist guerrilla group.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrashTests     07-28 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash Tests,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>NHTSA: Nearly Half Auto Crash Tests Show Chance of Severe Head
Injury</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly half the 37 cars, vans and light trucks that have been crash tested by the government this year would likely cause severe head injuries or death to their drivers in a 35 mph collision. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traffic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday released its final report on 1988 crash tests with results showing drivers of vans and light trucks were at high risk of severe head injuries in a crash. Drivers of compact cars were least likely to have severe head injuries, the agency's figures showed. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> reported the likelihood of injury as an index called the head-injury criterion. The agency derived the index from monitoring dummies strapped into vehicles that were crashed into a fixed barrier at 35 mph. Seventeen of the 1988 vehicles tested produced a head-injury criterion above 1,000, levels that show a high chance of severe head injury or death. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> cautioned it tested only one vehicle of each model, and additional tests could produce varying results `` due to slight differences in the way vehicles are manufactured and equipped, or due to slight variations in test conditions.'' Small differences in the test results should not be considered significant, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> said. The Chevrolet G-20 van showed the greatest likelihood of head injury to the driver, with an index of 3,665. The Mazda 929 4-door car, a large and mid-size model, showed the least likelihood, with an index of 273. Tests of nine subcompact cars found five with an index of more than 1,000. The average for the nine vehicles was 966. Subcompact cars showing the greatest chance of head injury and the criteria reported by <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> were the Dodge Colt 4-door station wagon, 1,354; <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pulsar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NX </ORGANIZATION> 2-door hatchback, 1,134; <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> 2-door, 1,114; Ford Festiva 2-door, 1,014; and the Toyota Tercel 2-door hatchback, 1,005. Two of the nine compact cars tested produced head-injury criteria exceeding 1,000. The average head-injury criterion for that class of car was 887. Compact cars most likely to cause head injury were the Peugeot 505 GLS 4-door, 1,701, and the <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> Sentra 4-door wagon, 1,047. The tests found three out of nine large and mid-size cars with criteria above 1,000. The average head-injury criterion for larger and mid-size cars was 921. Large and mid-size cars with head-injury criteria exceeding 1,000 were the Renault Medallion 4-door, 1,656, Buick Park Avenue 4-door, 1,467; and the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yorker </ORGANIZATION>, 1,362. The agency tested 10 vans and small trucks and found seven with head-injury criteria exceeding 1,000. The average index for the vehicles was 1,491. Trucks and vans showing the greatest likelihood of head injury were the Chevrolet G-20 van, 3,665; <PERSON> Isuzu </PERSON> <PERSON> Spacecab </PERSON> pickup, 1,873; <PERSON> Chevrolet </PERSON> <PERSON> Astro </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON>, 1,603; <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> LEV </ORGANIZATION> pickup, 1,528; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Montero </ORGANIZATION> 4x4, 1,320; <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vanagon </ORGANIZATION>, 1,320; and the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> F-150 pickup, 1,074. <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION>'s 35 mph crash-test program is not used in the agency's regulation of the automakers but is intended solely as a guide to consumers, the agency said For regulatory purposes, each manufacturer crash tests its own vehicles at 30 mph before the model-year begins. The results are usually kept secret for competitive reasons. Vehicles that test with head-injury criteria exceeding 1,000 must be redesigned before being placed on the market. Also, <ORGANIZATION> NHTSA </ORGANIZATION> conducts random testing at 30 mph to check results certified by the automakers. A 35 mph crash is one-third more severe than a 30 mph crash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen     07-28 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Veep Contender Disputes GOP Description Of Three-Man
Ticket</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Speech scheduled for 12:50 p.m. EDT; lead prospects uncertain</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is fending off questions about differences with running mate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and working to point up his differences with <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> standard-bearer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` You're going to see diversity in both parties,'' he told reporters, pressing him to answer <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s charge that they had more in common than <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He also brushed aside <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> statements that the Democrats had effectively created a three-man ticket that includes <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` I do n't think there's anything to it,'' he said. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said he still might vote for new aid to the Nicaraguan Contras, despite <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' opposition. As for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposing <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s plan to impose an import oil fee, he joked, `` I have n't been able to convince <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> either.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s comments came following a speech in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> to a businesswomen's convention, in which he tied <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policies opposed by feminists. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> supports the Equal Rights Amendment and several other initiatives supported by the women's group. The campaign stop in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> was at the start of a four-day cross-country campaign swing, which continues with speeches today in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev </LOCATION>. The campaign will then travel to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Amarillo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; and a finale in either <LOCATION> Lousiana </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. Events will be designed to highlight some of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s differences with the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> and not with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, such as the senator's work on the trade and plant-closing notification bills, and of energy independence programs <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> came just three days after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> unveiled a $ 2.2 billion child care plan before the same group. `` It's interestng to me that it's taken eight years -LRB- for the Republicans -RRB- to discover day care,'' said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. Just last year, he said, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> fought `` every step of the way'' against just $ 50 million proposed for child care for poor women. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> himself has not endorsed a $ 2.5 billion Democratic day care proposal, which won the approval Wednesday of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told the group that the `` gender gap'' _ the pattern of women supporting Democrats in greater proportions than men _ was a direct result of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> record on issues including the equal rights amendment, equal pay and the law banning discrimination by institutions receiving federal money. `` The Reagan-Bush administration opposes the ERA ... they ripped it out of the -LRB- Republican -RRB- platform,'' he said. `` They oppose the study that will provide the legal foundation for women who are discriminated against to bring their case to court and win.'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto of the bill overriding the <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> ruling of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which weakened federal anti-bias rules, showed `` this administration tried to compromise equality. ... But we overrode that veto. And we scored a major victory for equality and opportunity in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` The gender gap ... was n't created by accident,'' he said. At the end of his speech, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> was presented with a red purse, the group's symbol of how women make less money for comparable work. `` By the end of the Dukakis-Bentsen administration,'' he promised, `` this purse will be black.'' He received a standing ovation from the 2,000 women in the convention hall, several of whom held up Dukakis-Bentsen campaign signs. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> supports pay equity legislation in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> but not the more ambitious comparable worth legislation. He told reporters after his speech he wanted to go one step at a time. He also said he had not yet endorsed maternal leave legislation and has not had time to study it. The businesswomen's group, founded in 1919, has 125,000 members nationwide, of which 51 percent list themselves as Republicans, 47 percent Democrats and the rest independent, according to executive director <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorian </PERSON>. `` There was a lot of enthusiasm for Sen. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and what he had to say,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Dorian </PERSON>. The group was conducting a straw poll and planned to release the results today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0555EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AlaskanForest     07-28 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Alaskan Forest,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Votes to Scrap Federal Subsidy on Alaskan Timbering</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Score one for the environmentalists in their protracted battle with tree-cutters in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest national forest. By a lopsided 361-47 vote, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday approved legislation to scrap the 1980 law that groups like the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> say is responsible for overharvesting and big <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> losses in the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> forest in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The bill moved over to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s two members could have more success in blocking it in the final weeks of the 1988 session than its lone representative, Republican <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, had in the House. The legislation would scrap a 1980 law that guarantees the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> at least $ 40 million a year to support commercial timber sales in the Tongass, the continent's last large temperate rain forest. Supporters of the bill say the guarantee _ unique for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> national forests _ has not only led to destruction of ancient trees but also produced red ink as Tongass timber sales posted a deficit of $ 254 million from 1982 through 1987. Young argued unsuccessfully that the the bill repudiates a deal made in 1980 with environmentalists when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> put huge portions of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s vast acreage off-limits to development. He said that in return for allowing 8.5 million of the forest's 17 million acres to be declared wilderness, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> lawmakers won the spending guarantee and another requiring the forest service to make an average of 450 million board feet of Tongass timber available for sale each year `` The leisure lobby now wants to go back on its word,'' said <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who argued that the guarantees are necessary to preserve some 6,000 timber-related jobs in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. `` It's a matter of jobs,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` There are people's livelihoods at stake. But backers of the legislation argued that the Tongass region should be looking to tourism and commercial fishing for economic growth. They said overharvesting the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> hurts both tourism and fisheries. Besides getting rid of the guarantees, the overhaul bill sponsored principally by Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N </LOCATION>. Y, would put another 1.7 million Tongass acres off-limits to timber cutting for five Much of the Tongass timber is sold to two large corporations, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Pacific-Ketchikan and the Japanese-owned <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lumber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pulp </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which turn it into pulp, chiefly for export to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The bill would require the forest service to renegotiate the 50-year contracts it entered into with these companies in the 1950s. Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., the bill's floor manager, said new contracts are needed to encourage competition in <LOCATION> Tongass </LOCATION> timbering, prevent excessive cutting of old-growth stands and ensure that the companies pay more for <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> trees <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said a mature <LOCATION> Sitka </LOCATION> spruce from <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> now sells for $ 1.48, compared to $ 2 for a map of the national forest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma 1stLd-Writethru a0665 07-28 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0665,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Hard-Line Former Army General New Burma Leader; Rioting Leaves One
Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with rioting and curfew in
northern city. Picks up 4th graf pvs, ``A one-day...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former army general <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> was elected president Wednesday, one day after being named party leader, and rioting broke out in a northern city in which one person was reported killed and five wounded. The official <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> said a curfew was imposed in <LOCATION> Myede </LOCATION>, 220 miles north of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, after hundreds of rioters on Tuesday destroyed buildings and attacked police, who fired their guns to disperse the crowd. Sources in the area said one person was killed and five wounded. It was not immediately known if the violence was related to this week's leadership changes, which included the naming Wednesday of active or retired military officers to all but two of the cabinet's 22 posts Western diplomats had said the rise of <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, a 64-year-old hardliner known for his ruthless supression of dissidents, could lead to more of the anti-government protests that have broken out three times since October. Travelers returning from <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> said leaflets have appeared in recent days urging continued anti-government agitation. A one-day, emergency session of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> elected <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> president. On Tuesday, he assumed the nation's most powerful position, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, at a special party congress. The Parliament elected the former deputy prime minister, <PERSON> Tun </PERSON> <PERSON> Tin </PERSON>, as prime minister. Vice President <PERSON> Aye </PERSON> <PERSON> Ko </PERSON> remained in his post. Defense Minister <PERSON> Kyaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Htin </PERSON> moved to the No. 3 government position as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, part of a realignment that saw changes in eight of the 22 major government positions. Only two civilians were included in the new lineup: Attorney General <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> and Education Minister <PERSON> Kyaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Sein </PERSON>. The rest are retired or active duty military officers. The selections appeared to represent a continuation of the hard-line, one-party system instituted 26 years ago by <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON>, who resigned Saturday as president and party chairman. However, a number of liberal economic reforms were endorsed, and some balance within the top echelons appears to have been reached by the promotions of <PERSON> Kyaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Htin </PERSON> and Tun Tin. Both are regarded as relatively liberal on issues of economic reform and dealing with dissent in the country. <PERSON> Kyaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Htin </PERSON> also moved up to a top party post. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, a close associate of Ne Win, commanded forces that brutally put down student riots in March in which dozens of people died. Several other officials were reprimanded or fired, including former Prime Minister <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Kha </PERSON>, for their handling of the March 18 unrest in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, but <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> escaped officially unscathed by the incident. The government has admitted that 43 people died, 41 of them suffocating in a crowded police van while being taken to prison. Unofficial reports said more than 100 people were killed. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, who formerly ranked No. 4 in the party hierarchy, also commanded the <ORGANIZATION> Fourth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifles </ORGANIZATION>, a unit that opened fire on about 2,000 anti-government demonstrators at <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> on July, 7, 1962. Unofficial casualties were put at more than 100, and the following day authorities blew up the university's student union building. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> was also involved in putting down demonstrations in 1974, when students and <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks, angry at a shoddy government funeral for former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General U Thant, snatched his coffin and brought it to <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Troops firing rifles later stormed the campus. Ne Win cited his age and the recent unrest when he resigned. In his resignation speech, he raised hopes that major changes were in store for <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. In an unprecedented move, he called for a referendum to decide whether the country wished to continue with one-party rule or opt for a multiparty system. The congress turned down the referendum proposal. Ne Win's resignation followed three periods of student-led rioting. There also is mounting discontent over deteriorating economic conditions that have made <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> one of the world's 10 poorest nations, despite its abundance of natural resources. The congress promised a package of liberal economic reforms, including allowing joint ventures between private foreign and local investors and loosening control on a number of sectors, including agriculture and forestry. There was initial skepticism among diplomats about how far these will go and whether the current leaders can implement them. Several diplomats said that the new lineup lacks the expertise in dealing with anything but a state-controlled system, which has led to plummeting industrial production, food shortages, a foreign debt of about $ 4 million and meager social services. `` That the country has gone from bad to worse -LRB- 26 -RRB- years after the seizure of power is evident to anyone not living in a fool's paradise,'' <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON>, a respected government critic, wrote to Ne Win on May 12 `` The country has plunged to the bottom politically, economically and socially. The moral decay is the most deplorable.'' <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON> resigned from Ne Win's government in 1963. His letter has been widely circulated underground in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. Ne Win is believed to hold his old comrade-in-arms in some respect but there has been speculation the government would move to silence him.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0557EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Farmer     07-28 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Farmer,0582</SECOND>
<HEAD>All His Crops Parched By The Drought, A Farmer Prays For Rain</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China-Drought</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAOHEKOU, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wenbao </PERSON> does n't consider himself religious, but each night he puts a stick of incense outside the door of his house and prays for rain. `` There's no other way. I have to rely on heaven,'' <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said this week in this village in northern <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> province. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON>, his wife, three children and mother live in the heart of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s drought country, stricken this year with its worst blight in 50 years. Beginning as early as February in some parts of central and eastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the drought has hit eight out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 30 provinces. Officials in <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> say about half of the province's rice crop and 70 percent of its peanut and sesame crops will be affected. In addition, they worry about starvation in some areas like <PERSON> Laohekou </PERSON>. The Chinese news media have cited similar figures for grain and vegetable production in other provinces. Officials said other provinces also faced the possibility of starvation. <PERSON> Laohekou </PERSON> has been hit particularly hard by the drought. The village's reservoir is bone dry for the first time since it opened in 1958. <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> for drinking water contain only mud. Trucks carrying potable water from the nearest town, <LOCATION> Xiangfan </LOCATION>, are few. Draft animals have been dying, some because of the heat, which has hovered around 104 degrees for weeks, others because of thirst. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON>, 33, said he's concerned for his family. This spring he planted about 2 -LCB- acres of land. In a good year, with the rich <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> soil, <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said he could clear $ 540 profit from his fields, well above the average farmer's annual income of $ 125. But this year, the fields are barren. `` My mungbeans are burned. My cotton should be up to my chest but it only hits my ankle so it will be worthless. My tobacco is dead,'' <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said, pausing to spit in the dust outside his brick house. `` We'll have no vegetables this year and no money.'' Under <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s recent agricultural reforms, peasants sign a contract with the government, promising to produce a certain amount of grain. That grain is then sold to the state at a fixed price, well below what it would get on the free market. Anything extra can be sold for market value. In addition, all vegetables and cash crops can be sold on the market. But without a harvest of vegetables or cash crops, <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> will have no money. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said he and his family will live on the winter wheat he harvested earlier this year. But after fulfilling his contract with the state, only 3,000 pounds remained. Chinese officials say one person needs at least 550 pounds of grain a year to survive, so <PERSON> Chen </PERSON>'s family of six has come up short. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> has pulled up some cotton and planted sweet potatoes to try and fill the gap. `` That's why I'm asking heaven for rain,'' he said. `` But if there's no rain, then things wo n't be good at all.'' <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said that if the rains do n't come he'll probably take a job in a nearby rock quarry with other villagers, making $ 1.60 a day. `` It will help to feed my family because no one here wants to beg,'' he said. `` But really I do n't want to leave the land.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugTests     07-28 0253</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Tests,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>False Drug Test Results Often Mean Loss of Jobs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People victimized by erroneous drug test results frequently face loss of their jobs and few are in a position to defend themselves adequately, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has been told. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waple </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, attorney who has handled more than 500 drug test cases in the past six years, said Wednesday that such a person `` loses the presumption of innocence and is instead burdened with a presumption of guilt.'' <PERSON> Waple </PERSON> said that in at least 75 percent of his cases, `` there was a significant legal or scientific irregularity which substantially affected the reliability of the ultimate conclusion that the individual had in fact used a controlled substance.'' He said his clients have faced threats of incarceration, loss of security clearances and hospital credentials as well as loss of employment, rank and position. <PERSON> Waple </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on oversight and investigations that the combination of the `` presumption of guilt'' and complex legal and scientific issues makes it very difficult for a person to defend against the positive test result. `` Very few individuals who test positive for controlled substances will have a proper background either through experience or education to know where to begin to defend themselves,'' he said. `` Drug testing laboratories guard their scientific data, their test results, their mathematical computations and their standard operating procedures very carefully.'' He called for `` complete and total disclosure of all of the data supporting a positive test result.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RuralHousing     07-28 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rural Housing,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mortgage Subsidies to Rural Poor Prove Cost-Effective, Study Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Low-income rural homeowners who receive federal mortgage subsidies have excellent repayment records and benefit from a more stable family life, a private study of 894 households has found. The study by the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> also said the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s low-income home ownership program is cost-effective and should be expanded. Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said the study released Wednesday proves the program has succeeded in `` the very toughest, hardscrabble places'' and that the poor are neither lazy nor irresponsible and hopeless. `` After all of the attacks on housing assistance programs, this study shows what really happens with subsidized homeownership programs. ... These programs work,'' said <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on housing. Subsidies to participants in the program declined over a five-year period as their incomes increased, and the number of children living below the poverty level decreased, the study said. The council tracked 894 sample families nationwide who obtained subsizied mortgages in 1981 and concluded the rural homeownership program `` represents a cost-effective strategy to provide decent shelter to low-income households and to assist them in overcoming the burden of poverty.'' The study, financed with a grant from the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, also found homeownership had indirect benefits, particularly on children, such as stabilizing family life. In 1986, when most borrowers had five years' experience with the program, the study found most were ahead in their payments. Only 7 percent were as much as three months behind, 5 percent had returned their homes to the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>, and only 1.3 percent had lost their homes to foreclosure. Poverty-level borrowers were less likely than others to be delinquent and more likely to be ahead in payments, the study showed. At the same time, subsidies to the families declined steadily. `` The decline in the subsidy was in part a reflection of upward economic mobility, and this was most evident among young families with children,'' the study said. The Washington-based council advises low-income and minority groups seeking federal assistance for improving rural housing and studies and makes recommendations for state and local housing policies. <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> said the program has been cut from $ 2.9 billion in 1979 to $ 1.1 billion last year. `` If anything, the need has grown,'' he said. He and Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said they are pressing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to expand the program.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0602EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ForeignInvestment     07-28 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foreign Investment,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Sees Dramatic Climb in Foreign Investment in U.S.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign investment in American companies, real estate and other assets has increased dramatically in recent years and is likely to keep climbing through the year 2000, according to a new study. The private study, released Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said direct foreign investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has jumped by more than 215 percent since 1980, while American investment abroad increased by only one-fifth that rate. And the study said the pace of foreign investment is expected to accelerate, with foreign buyouts in 1988 expected to make up as much as 20 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acquisitions, up from 5 percent in 1987. However, the report said that in absolute terms, foreign investments still account for only 5 percent to 6 percent of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assets. The study said seven nations account for nearly 85 percent of the foreign investment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. They are <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, with $ 75 billion in cumulative investments by 1987; the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, $ 47 billion; <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, $ 33 billion; <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, $ 22 billion; <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, $ 20 billion; <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, $ 14 billion; and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, $ 10 billion. Other findings include: _ Foreign investors now own 10 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturing base, with majority interest in the concrete and consumer electronics industries and significant portions of machine tools, chemicals and auto parts _ Most foreign outlays in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are to acquire existing businesses rather than to establish new ones _ Jobs of nearly 3 million Americans are dependent on foreign investment, up from just 1.1 million 10 years ago Foreign affiliates account for 7 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manufacturing jobs. _ More than 25 percent of all commercial and industrial loans in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are owed to foreign banks _ More than 12.5 million acres of farm land in 49 states are owned by foreigners, about 1 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> total The study was compiled with data from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other sources. The institute is a private organization founded in 1987 to act as a forum on economic policy for lawmakers and business, labor and educational leaders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880728-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-28-88 0604EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DartmouthReview     07-28 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dartmouth Review,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservative Paper At Dartmouth Sues School Over Disciplinary
Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
