<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PresidentialPolls 3rdLd-Writethru a0796 10-12 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Presidential Polls, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0796,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC-Post Poll: Big Bush Lead in Electoral Votes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: To UPDATE with information on margin of error, SUB graf 6,
The poll...; to revise explanation, DELETE 9th pvs, The network...,
and SUB 10th graf, Sampling error...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state-by-state poll of nearly 10,000 likely voters Wednesday rated <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as solidly ahead in the race for the presidency, saying he held a huge lead in the contest for electoral votes. Although polls of the nation as a whole indicate a close race between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> survey of the standings in each state _ where the election actually is decided _ put <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> firmly ahead. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led solidly in 21 states with a total of 220 electoral votes _ just 50 short of the total needed to win. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was firmly ahead in three states and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, for 30 electoral votes. With the election nearly a month off, voter sentiments can change. But the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Post </ORGANIZATION> poll, the only public survey of its size this year, was the first recent poll to indicate a significant advantage for either candidate. `` It's interesting and encouraging,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do n't know what the other fellow has But look, we've just got a game plan. Stay with it. And if polls are encouraging it makes me feel good, but I also remember when they were n't.'' The poll was conducted from Sept. 21 through Monday among 9,778 likely voters in the 50 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Its margins of error varied by state from five points to 10 points. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and the Post also conducted a standard national survey that put the race at 51 percent for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to 45 percent to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. A <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll Wednesday had nearly the same result: 50-45. Such national polls measure popular sentiment across the nation as a whole. But in the election each state gives its electoral votes to the winner in that state, so the state-by-state standings are more relevant to the outcome. Such polls are rarely done because conducting polls in each state requires a far larger sample than surveying the nation as a whole. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, from 100 to 500 voters were interviewed in each state. The Post noted that there are many potential sources of error in the poll, including the length of time it took to conduct the survey. The states that <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> put firmly in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s column included <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where recent state polls have given him a 10-point lead; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, where he led by eight points in a state poll last week; and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, where he led in a state poll a month ago by just four points. Also, the states that it said leaned toward <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> included <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where most other recent polls have shown a slight <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> lead; and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where most recent polls have found a tie. These are the states that <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said firmly favored <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. It said these were leaning for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> rated these states a tossup: <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. Firmly favoring <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> it said, were <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Leaning for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> were <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. The CBS-Times poll, meanwhile, found increasing doubt about the qualifications of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee, Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, to serve as president, and it indicated the concern was keeping the race a close one in terms of the popular contest nationally. By a 2-1 margin, probable voters in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS-Times </ORGANIZATION> poll doubted <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s qualifications for the presidency, his worst rating in that survey. He was seen as qualified by only 30 percent, while twice as many _ 63 percent _ said they would worry about him serving as president. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s presence appeared to help <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>: Asked if they could vote only for president, without considering the running mate, support for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dipped from 45 percent to 41 percent. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s support remained at 50 percent Another poll Wednesday, by <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, put the popular contest at 50-48. It also said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> may be helped a bit by concern over <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>; asked to chose between <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> only, without their running mates mentioned, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dipped from 48 to 46 percent support. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> remained at 50 percent. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> polled 1,355 likely voters Oct. 6 through Monday. Its poll had a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points. The smaller, national ABC-Post poll was done Oct. 5 through Tuesday among 1,187 likely voters nationwide; The CBS-Times poll was done Oct. 8 through Monday among 1,009 probable voters. Both had four-point margins of error.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HitlerParties 2ndLd-Writethru a0797 10-12 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hitler Parties, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0797 ,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede GRAND FORKS, N.D.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Casino Hotel Owner Plans To Donate Nazi Collection</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE that Engelstad plans to donate
Nazi material to Holocaust museum. Picks up 4th graf pvs, ``I have
...' ADDS byline.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TIM DAHLBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hotel owner criticized for throwing <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> birthday parties for his employees said Wednesday he plans to donate his collection of Nazi material to a planned Holocaust museum in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>, 58, who owns the Imperial Palace hotel and casino, said he began discussions Wednesday with officials of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Holocaust Memorial Council toward donating the Nazi items. `` We have offered it. They have expressed interest in having it,'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>, who earlier painted over a <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> wall mural and scrapped plans to display the Nazi items at his car museum, said he hoped the planned donation to the Holocaust museum would end the flap over his activities. `` As I said earlier, I now feel I have done what can be done,'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> said, reading from a statement. `` I have apologized for what can not be undone.'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> said he hoped to donate the various Nazi artifacts to a Holocaust museum that is being planned by the council in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But he said he would keep the various cars he has bought that are related to the Nazi regime. In a letter to the Jewish Federation of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> on Tuesday, <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> said he would sell the collection of Nazi-era cars, motorcycles, posters and other items and turn the room into a warehouse. `` I have not been successful to date in convincing you that my apology for my insensitivity to Jewish concerns was heartfelt and sincere,'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> wrote. `` In retrospect, I realize that what was missing in my apology was an acknowledgement of the specific hurt and pain felt by the Jewish community over this issue,'' he said. <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>, a former goaltender on the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION>'s hockey team, announced plans earlier this year to set up a $ 5 million endowment to benefit the university's hockey program. The school's Winter Sports Center was subsequently renamed <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>. Officials said the university does n't plan to reject <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>'s money and wo n't change the name of the hockey venue But school President <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> said school officials would watch the controversy for any new developments, and `` we're keeping our options open.'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Thief </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, has apologized for the two <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> parties, which he held in 1986 and earlier this year. `` In retrospect, they were not only stupid but insensitive, but at the time they were merely excuses for parties,'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> said, adding that he threw parties often for his employees. <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON>'s collection included a portrait of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, signed `` To <PERSON> Ralphie </PERSON> from Adolf 1938,'' and a bumper sticker inscribed `` Hitler Was Right.'' <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> has said the portrait was sent to him by a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> broker as a joke after he purchased a number of German vehicles. <PERSON> Engelstad </PERSON> did not authorize the bumper stickers and found them offensive, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Murray     10-12 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Murray,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vaudeville Actor Ken Murray Dies</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY65</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, whose 30-year career spanned the vaudeville stage and films including the 1962 motion picture `` The Man Who Shot Liberty Valance,'' died Wednesday. He was 85. The <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> resident died of natural causes at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION>, said his publicist <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Godsick </PERSON>. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> was born <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Court </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in 1903. His film career began from the 1930s and continued until the late 1960s. He is best remembered for his long-running Hollywood stage appearances in `` <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>'s Blackout,'' which ran from 1942 to 1949. He produced `` Bill & amp; Coo,'' a feature-length fantasy film about birds that received a special Academy Award in 1947 for `` novel and entertaining use'' of the film medium. He also starred, produced and directed television's `` The <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> Show.'' Other television credits include `` Hollywood Without Makeup,'' `` Hollywood, My Home Town,'' and `` El Coyote.'' His motion picture debut was in `` Half-Marriage'' in 1929. Other films included `` Leathernecking,'' `` You're A Sweetheart,'' 1937; `` A Night at <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s,'' 1940; `` Juke Box <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON>,'' 1942; `` Son of Flubber,'' 1963; `` The Power,'' 1968 and `` <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>'s Shooting Stars'' a homemade 16mm film <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> shot recording the day-to-day lives of his contemporaries The candid scenes have been internationally distributed as classic vignettes of the golden age of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> also wrote books including `` The Body Merchant,'' `` Life on a Pogo Stick,'' and `` The Golden Days of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simeon </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 4thLd-Writethru a0800 10-12 0971</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0800,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Dukakis Talk Baseball, Huddle With Advisers as Debate Nears</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 9th graf, The poll's..., to add margin of error and
other information.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Neither <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> came in contact with the voters on Wednesday, huddling instead with their handlers to go over lines for Thursday's second and final presidential debate of the campaign. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, buoyed by an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll giving him a huge lead in electoral votes nationwide, staged a brief made-for-television event before disappearing into his debate preparation meetings. He invited <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Police Chief <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> in for breakfast in a subtle continuation of his effort to make crime control a central theme of his candidacy. The vice president told reporters he intended to show the country `` what my heartbeat is'' during his face-to-face clash with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and said he would continue depicting his rival as a liberal. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also attended the National League playoff game between the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> after wrapping up his debate preparation for the day. He shared a box with his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, Dodger owner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Malley </PERSON>, and campaign chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. Democrat <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had baseball on his mind as well as he interrupted his debate homework to play catch with an aide while photographers recorded the scene. Referring to the first presidential debate and the one last week between running mates, he said, `` We're ahead 2-0; we're going to make it a clean sweep.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will need a clean sweep to overcome the kind of lead that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has in the newest poll, which surveyed 10,000 likely voters from Sept. 21 through Monday. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> led solidly in 21 states with a total of 220 electoral votes _ just 50 short of the total needed to win. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was firmly ahead in only three states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> with 30 electoral votes. With the election nearly a month off, voter sentiments can change. But the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Post </ORGANIZATION> poll, the only public survey of its size this year, was the first recent poll to indicate a significant advantage for either candidate. The poll's margins of error varied by state from five points to 10 points. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said from 100 to 500 voters were interviewed in each state. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> described his debate repertoire in baseball lingo, as well, saying he would use a `` fastball, curve, slider _ maybe a knuckler'' during his 90 minutes on stage. Workers in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> erected a debate-night set _ wooden lecterns, red carpet and telegenic blue background _ that was trucked in from <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, where it was used in last week's vice presidential debate. The debate begins at 9 p.m. EDT on the <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> campus in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> goes into the 90-minute encounter with a modest lead in the public opinion polls, although <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> appears to have cut into the Republican advantage since last week's vice presidential debate. Republican vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, the subject of anonymous criticism from senior <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advisers since that debate, said as he set out on his daily campaign rounds that if he finds out who was talking, `` I think there will be staff changes.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> uttered a seeming declaration of independence after saying his campaign appearances had been so tightly scripted by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advisers that he was told when he could wave as he got off his campaign plane. `` That's all been thrown away,'' he said. `` I am my own handler, and if you have any questions, ask me.'' He said he would take advice from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s aides `` under consideration.'' Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had a ready retort for that idea. `` That may be his pitch, but I'll bet it's thrown <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a real curve ball,'' he said of his vice presidential rival. The <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator campaigned through <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, where he said the Republicans `` refuse to stand up for the American economy.'' With election day still more than three weeks away, there was fresh evidence that presidential politics is eternal. One Democratic official already was speculating that the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, the lead-off contest in the last several campaigns, might be moved back in the election calendar if the Democrats lose the White House this year. `` I think that the cry would be very loud for a different look at the nominating system,'' said Democratic Vice Chair <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Cutler </PERSON>, a former Iowan now living in <LOCATION> Washingon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s breakfast with Republican supporter <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> came as the vice president worked hard to make crime a key issue. In speeches throughout the country, he has sharply criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' record on crime, citing a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prison program under which a murderer escaped while on furlough and attacked a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> couple. Some Democratic strategists say the issue is particularly effective against <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the nation's largest state. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he believes he is in a stronger position politically than before the first residential debate on Sept. 25 and added that his goal for Thursday night is to have the voters understand `` what my heartbeat is, what I really care about.'' As for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, the losing 1984 Democratic presidential candidate, said the 1988 nominee should loosen up in front of the television cameras. <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, that he knows <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a `` very warm nice person'' but that that side of his personality has n't come across on television. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had his No. 1 surrogate campaigner at work, with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> traveling in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. In a speech to high school students in <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Darby </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> touted the economic expansion since the recession early in his term of office and said, `` In the last eight years we've worked to return <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s values to all areas of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> government.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Newspage-NLPlayoff     10-12 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newspage-NL Playoff,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dodgers Defeat Mets, Will Meet Oakland in World Series</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> won the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> pennant Wednesday night by beating the favored <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> 6-0 in the seventh game of a playoff. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> will be host of Game 1 of the 85th major league baseball World Series on Saturday against <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>. It is a rematch of the 1974 Series won by the Athletics in five games. <PERSON> Orel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hershiser </PERSON>, who pitched a five-hitter for the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>, finished the season with a record 59 consecutive scoreless innings. We was credited for the win, after starting playoff Games 1 and 3 without getting a decision but getting a save for Game 4. The pennant is the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>' ninth championship since moving to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 1958 from <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, and their first since 1981, when they went on to beat the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> in the World Series. The <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> scored first in six of the seven games against the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> and made things easy for <PERSON> Hershiser </PERSON> by scoring a run in the first inning Wednesday off losing pitcher <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Darling </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> then chased him with five runs in the second as <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> made three sloppy fielding plays. <PERSON> Hershiser </PERSON> had five strikeouts, two walks and two hit batsmen in pitching the third shutout in a series-deciding game in playoff history. Catfish Hunter of <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> beat <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> 3-0 in the final game of the 1973 AL playoff and <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> shut out <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 6-0 last year in the NL playoff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BrownStrike     10-12 0329</FIRST>
<SECOND>Brown Strike,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last-Minute Agreement Staves Off Strike at Brown</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KAREN SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and its food service, plant operations and library workers reached a contract agreement on Wednesday just hours before a midnight strike dedline. After two days of negotiations, the <ORGANIZATION> Ivy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> school agreed to pay full health insurance premiums for members of Local 134 of the <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> union. `` We feel that we have a great victory here,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> McAninch </PERSON>, the union's business agent. `` The important thing is we got 100 percent Blue Cross coverage for the life of the agreement. A three-year contract for the 250 plant and food workers provided a 5.5 percent pay increase in the first year and a 5 percent increase in the remaining two years. The 90 library workers received a two-year contract that gave them a 5.5 percent increase in the first year and a 5 percent raise in the second. The contract was ratified by a show of hands by the plant and food workers and by a 50-21 vote from the library workers, <PERSON> McAninch </PERSON> said. The workers earlier this month authorized a strike for midnight Wednesday, when the contract covering plant and food workers expires. The contract for the library workers expired on Aug. 19. `` Both sides gave substantially in the interest of harmony to get the matter resolved,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichley </PERSON>, a university spokesman. `` In the long run it may not be the best solution for both sides, but at least it averted a strike.'' On Tuesday, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> officials offered a higher wage increase, but said they would pay only half the insurance premiums for the first year and 60 percent of following increases. <PERSON> McAninch </PERSON> said the principle of cost shifting was as important as the numbers. `` They knew that we were serious about striking and that we felt very strongly about the issues,'' she said. `` We had a lot of support from <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Zaire-AIDS     10-12 0854</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Zaire-AIDS,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>Zaire, Other African Countries Opening Up On AIDS</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>^By ROBERT WELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KINSHASA, Zaire (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This Central African nation kept a long official silence on AIDS, but now is attacking the epidemic openly and plans to test 10,000 people in its first survey of the deadly disease. `` We know that it is a difficult problem, but we are trying to do what we can do,'' said Dr. <PERSON> N'Galy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosenge </PERSON>, leader of <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>'s national AIDS committee Reporters visiting <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION> in the past had to seek information from Western health officials or private organizations involved in fighting AIDS. N'Galy, whose business card shows a skull in the middle of a heart beneath the French abbreviation for AIDS, now admits them to his office without demanding government authorization and even takes telephone queries from journalists in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome, for which no cure has been found, is caused by a virus that damages the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to infections and cancer. It is spread most often through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, infected blood or blood products and from pregnant women to their offspring. Although homosexuals have been the main victims in developed countries, the disease has spread among heterosexuals in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. This may be because of the unchecked spread of other sexually transmitted diseases, which speed the transmission of AIDS; because of contaminated syringes and blood supplies, and because there are comparatively few homosexuals on the continent. <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Netter </PERSON> said by telephone from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agency's <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> headquarters that <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> countries have quickened their AIDS programs in the past 18 months. `` It's an acknowledgment that this is a problem and ... it's no longer seen as some sort of a stigma,'' he said. `` I think people have gotten over that.'' African nations were reporting five to 10 cases 18 months ago but now the total is about 19,000, he said. <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> recently held an international AIDS conference, and <LOCATION> Gabon </LOCATION> did the same in June. <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> and several other countries have begun aggressive education campaigns that use comic books, popular music, television and theater. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s daily newspaper for blacks, The Sowetan, began a column on AIDS this week, which warns that promiscuity facilitates transmission of the disease. A WHO statement Friday said reported AIDS cases worldwide rose 7 percent to 119,818 in September, with updated figures from <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> accounting for most of the increase. <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION> listed 2,586 cases, more than four times the number in its last report Oct. 31, 1987; <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> reported 3,055 cases, nearly twice the total of Oct. 17, 1988, and <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> reported 2,732 cases, up one-third from a March 31, 1988, report that also showed a big increase. <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> has reported only 335 cases. <PERSON> N'Galy </PERSON> said his government knows the figure is many times that, but `` we just did n't do a very good job. ... We ca n't verify it yet.'' <PERSON> N'Galy </PERSON> said he was preparing a new total figure. The government has been sensitive because of press reports describing <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> as the birthplace of AIDS and because of the reaction to reports of a survey that found 6 percent to 8 percent of the staff of a <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION> hospital to be sero-positive. `` It was regarded as a national catastrophe,'' <PERSON> Ngaly </PERSON> said. Officials in <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION> say their openess about AIDS has resulted wrongly in that East African country being labeled an AIDS epicenter. Dr. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Okware </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Uganda </LOCATION>'s AIDS control program, said the number of cases doubles every six months. N'Galy said <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> is preparing its first general AIDS survey in cooperation with WHO, and about 10,000 people will be tested. He said it probably will find a sero-positive rate somewhere between the 6 percent to 8 percent at the hospital and the 3 percent to 4 percent found in tests at a <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION> factory. The survey's purpose is `` to evaluate the success of our AIDS education program,'' <PERSON> N'Galy </PERSON> said. `` The most important thing is to check the rate of AIDS infection. We are confident that people understand the need for change, but it is a long-term effort. Perhaps we will be able to save some lives.'' <PERSON> Netter </PERSON> said the survey `` probably will come up with a lot of cases,'' but added: `` The most significant thing is that there is a program in place to find out what the extent of the problem is and how to go about doing something about it.'' <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>, said condom sales have gone from virtually zero to 100,000 monthly in <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION> and surveys indicate most residents know as much about AIDS as people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Reports indicate the disease may not be spreading to rural areas, and `` in many villages the sero-positive rate remains zero,'' according to N'Galy. Tests in <LOCATION> Kinshasa </LOCATION> of pregnant women and blood donors also suggest the general incidence of AIDS infection is not rising, but the infection rate among prostitutes has grown from 27 percent to 40 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FraternitySuspended     10-12 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fraternity Suspended,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fraternity Suspended Amid Rape Charge; Sorority in Maine Also in
Hot Water</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OXFORD, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> suspended the <ORGANIZATION> Sigma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alpha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Epsilon </ORGANIZATION> fraternity Tuesday after an `` extended period of disruptive behavior'' that included a member being charged with raping a sorority pledge. And in <LOCATION> Orono </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> withdrew recognition of a sorority after a hazing inciden in which pledges allegedly were branded with a heated metal stamp. The earliest the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> fraternity will be eligible to return to campus is Jan. 1, said <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Beasley </PERSON>, university vice chancellor for student affairs. Last month, the university banned all on-campus fraternity-sorority parties when a freshman Chi Omega Sorority pledge said she was raped after attending a mixer held by the fraternity and the sorority. That party was held off-campus because the fraternity was already on social probation because of a rush infraction and was prohibited from having on-campus parties. <PERSON> Stover </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Metairie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, was freed late last month on $ 50,000 bond after being arrested on rape charges, said <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>. The woman told officers that she left the party and was driven to a field, then beaten and raped, <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. University officials said the rape charge was not the only reason for the suspension of the fraternity, but it was a contributing factor. The unversity began an investigation into the fraternity's activities after the incident. The suspension means removal of all fraternity members from the campus chapter and the placing of the chapter in the hands of an alumni committee, <PERSON> Beasley </PERSON> said. The identities of the victims in the Sept. 25 incident in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, said to have occurred in a <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION> cemetery, were not disclosed. Officials said a preliminary investigation found that two pledges had suffered burns. An associate dean, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>, said the burns had been characterized as minor. Hazing is prohibited by both state law and school policy, university officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Defense     10-12 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Defense,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mitterrand Says France Will Remain Its Own Master</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> has reaffirmed that <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> will remain its own master on defense issues, saying <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s `` mission was not to assure the protection of any other West European country.'' That task, he said Tuesday, belonged to the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said, however, that a French president could realize <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s vital interests were affected by events beyond its borders and, for example, come to the aid of its neighbor <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in an emergency. Other points <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> made in a major policy speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Higher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>: _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s new mobile short-range Hades nuclear missiles should not become theater or battlefield weapons, but serve as a final warning to an enemy that a nuclear confrontation was starting _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> would continue to modernize its mainly submarine-based nuclear deterrent, but would also update a missile complex in southern <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> retains the capability of building a neutron bomb at any moment _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> will not join any negotiations on reducing strategic nuclear weapons until deep cuts were made in the arsenals of both superpowers _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> opposes deployment of weapons in space as envisaged in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Administration's Strategic Defense Initiative _ <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> will keep its chemical weapons capability until an international ban on their manufacture and use is negotiated <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said the main objective of French defense policy was to `` maintain our identity, our independence,'' which is why `` we have our own strategy of nuclear deterrence.'' He said <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was committed to achieving nuclear disarmament and hailed the U.S.-Soviet accord to ban intermediate-range nuclear weapons as one of the major events since the end of World War II. He said <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> will remain a reliable member of the Western alliance without `` abandoning its autonomy of decision'' with regard to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s integrated military command structure. Gen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaullle </PERSON> took <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> out of this structure in 1966. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said in the event of war, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> `` will be present from the first minute with all its forces, including nuclear ones, provided that this was within the framework of the alliance.'' He remarked that <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s common defensive capabilities could be strengthened in 1993 after the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> established a single market. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> warned any attack against <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s land-based missiles would mean `` we were at war and the unleashing of our strategic weapons would be instantaneous.'' The president said with regard to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s short-range nuclear weapons, such as the Pluton or Hades missiles, that these weapons would be used only against military targets. The Hades, to be deployed in eastern <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> by 1992, has a range of about 280 miles, barely enough to reach targets in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> or other <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries. Newspaper reports last month, denied by <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> aides, said <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was considering delaying or canceling the Hades program.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0811 10-12 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0811,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Storm Joan Forms in Mid-Atlantic</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE with 10:30 p.m. location of storm</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A depression in the <LOCATION> mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> became Tropical Storm Joan Tuesday, packing top sustained winds of 40 mph on a course that forecasters said could threaten the Lesser Antilles in two or three days. At 10:30 p.m. EDT, <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> was centered near 12.0 north latitude and 49.5 west longitude, or about 700 miles east of <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION>, moving west-northwest at 15 mph, the National Hurricane Center said. Little change in strength was expected Tuesday night, and <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> was expected to maintain the same speed and direction for the next 24 hours, the center said. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> is the 10th tropical storm of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> season, which runs from June through November. Depressions are upgraded to tropical storms when sustained winds reach 39 mph and become hurricanes when winds hit 74 mph. Four hurricanes have formed this season, including Hurricane Gilbert, which killed more than 300 people and caused billions of dollars in damages as it ravaged <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Election Bjt   10-12 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Election, Bjt,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Labor Fights For Crucial Sephardi Vote In Likud Strongholds</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMLE, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cheering children greeted Moroccan-born <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>, the No. 2 man in the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc, during a campaign stop in this town where two-thirds of the residents are Jews of North African origin. When <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, head of the left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, campaigned in <LOCATION> Ramle </LOCATION>'s open-air market last week, he was jostled and booed. <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> supporters shouted `` traitor'' and `` <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> go home.'' The contrasting receptions underscore <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s continuing difficulties in winning the support of the Sephardim, Jews of Middle Eastern and North African origin. They make up 55 percent of the 2.1 million Israeli voters and will be crucial in determining the outcome of the Nov. 1 elections. In 1984, 70 percent of the Sephardim voted for the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, and this time, `` there is still a strong element of identification with the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>,'' said a pollster for the Labor-affiliated Decima polling company, speaking on condition of anonymity. However, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> pollsters said they expected a dip of about 5 percent in Sephardic support for <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, providing an opening for Labor to campaign aggressively among Sephardic voters. A key target group are young, financially successful Sephardim born in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> who make up about half of the 5 percent of the voters wavering between Labor and <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> Decima </LOCATION> pollster. They might determine the election because polls show Labor and <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> running neck-to-neck. Sephardic voting power first became evident in 1977 when Labor was ousted from the government after 29 years because Sephardim voted for the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> in massive numbers. The Sephardic identification with <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> has its roots in the 1950s and 1960s when Labor, at the time dominated by Western-born Ashkenazim, often was arrogant toward the North African newcomers. Today, most Sephardim still feel greater affinity toward Likud than Labor, but after 11 years of the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> government, some supporters are becoming more critical. `` I will vote for the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> again, but it's not what it used to be in the times of -LRB- former <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> Prime Minister Menahem -RRB- Begin,'' said <PERSON> Yehuda </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, 36, a taxi driver in <LOCATION> Ramle </LOCATION> where 70 percent of the votes traditionally go to <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. `` Labor was in the government for 30 years, and became corrupt. Now the same thing is happening to the Likud,'' he added. `` Likud can no longer say ` the Sephardim belong to us,''' said his colleague, <PERSON> Eli </PERSON> <PERSON> Zarfati </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> voter who is now leaning toward Labor. Political analyst <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Elazar </PERSON> warned that the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> might be overestimating its hold on Sephardic voters. `` The Likud is convinced they have the Sephardim in their back pocket. I do n't think they do,'' said <PERSON> Elazar </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION>, a think tank. `` If the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> had been better at governing and had not been associated with inflation and the war in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, their position with the Sephardim would have been unassailable,'' he added. Labor officials say they are making inroads, mainly because <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> candidates for the 120-member <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> includes 16 Sephardim. In addition, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, currently the foreign minister, is making many campaign appearances in predominantly Sephardic areas. But <PERSON> Levy </PERSON>, who as deputy prime minister is the highest-ranking Sephardi in the Cabinet, played down the importance of the ethnic vote. `` Forty years have passed. Time has come to do away with the labels of Sephardim and Ashkenazim and to relate to people as <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> citizens,'' <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. During a tour of <LOCATION> Ramle </LOCATION> on Tuesday, <PERSON> Levy </PERSON> was greeted by more than 100 school children, many of them chanting the party's slogan: `` Only Likud Can.'' <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Odelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Karmon </PERSON> denied Labor claims that Sephardic support for the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> was weakening, but said <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> leaders are not targeting thos voters in particular. `` Labor has to do that because of the past, but we have nothing to apologize for,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0817 10-12 0742</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0817,0764</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Wrather, Troast and Adams; AMs separates moved as a0720
on Flowers and as a0826 on Wrather.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY62</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Wayland Flowers</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wayland </PERSON> <PERSON> Flowers </PERSON>, a ventriloquist who brought life to a cackling, off-color puppet named Madame, died Tuesday of cancer. He was 48. Flowers created a cast of characters, but it was the craggy old hussy Madame, manipulated with rods rather than strings, that launched the popularity of the television and showroom act. <ORGANIZATION> Wayland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Madame's first big break came on `` The Andy Williams Show'' and led to guest appearances on the reincarnated `` Laugh-In,'' `` Hollywood Squares'' and a four-year stint on `` Solid Gold.'' Their own syndicated situation comedy `` Madame's Place'' was shown in 1982 Flowers also brought life to such characters as <PERSON> Crazy </PERSON> <PERSON> Marv </PERSON>, who had terribly accurate observations on humanity, Jiffy from <LOCATION> Harlem </LOCATION> with humor and song stylings, vaudevillian Mr. <PERSON> Mackelhoney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baby </PERSON> <PERSON> Smedley </PERSON>'s high chair view of the world.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>B. Frank Polk</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Polk </PERSON>, who helped pioneer AIDS research as a professor of epidemiology at The <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, died Tuesday in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> of a brain tumor at age 46. <PERSON> Polk </PERSON> was a member of a committee that started the Hopkins hospital AIDS inpatient unit in 1986. Three years earlier, he had started a program called SHARE, for Study to Help AIDS Research Efforts, which became one of four National Institutes of Health-supported studies of the natural history of the incurable disease. Polk had been conducting several studies, still in progress, on heterosexual transmission of acquired immune deficiency syndrome and on the risk of infection by the AIDS virus among recipients of screened blood, prison inmates, intravenous drug abusers, mothers and their unborn children. He worked with AIDS patients in the Hopkins hospital and directed the AIDS outpatient clinic, where more than 700 patients receive care.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Lois Wilson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AKRON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, the founder of <ORGANIZATION> Al-Anon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Programs </ORGANIZATION>, died Wednesday in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kisco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>. She was 97 Mrs. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> was the widow of Alcoholics Anonymous co-founder <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Al-Anon </PERSON>, established in 1951, provides support programs for friends and family members of recovering alcoholics. The program, based on the 12-point plan of Alcoholics Anonymous, has about 500,000 members. Alcoholics Anonymous was founded in <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> in 1935 by <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stock broker, and Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>. Their program to start and keep alcoholics on the road to sobriety has an estimated 1.5 million members.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Bonita Wrather</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bonita </PERSON> <PERSON> Granville </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON>, an actress, businesswoman, philanthropist and widow of oilman-entrepreneur <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON>, died Tuesday of cancer at age 65. Mrs. <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON> starred in her first film, `` Westward Passage'' at age 7. She earned an Academy Award nomination for her role as a lying school girl in the 1936 movie `` These Three,' and by the time she was 23 she had been in 50 films, including `` Cavalcade,'' `` Ah, Wilderness,'' `` Now Voyager'' `` The Plough and the Stars,'' and `` <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s Children.' In 1946, Mrs. <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON> starred in `` The Guilty,'' and fell in love with the movie's producer, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oilman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON>. They married the next year. She appeared on television in the 1950s in such shows as `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Steel Hour,'' `` Playhouse 90,'' `` Climax,'' and `` Studio One.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Wrather </PERSON> was active in several <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> philanthropic organizations. She was appointed by President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in 1972 to serve on the Board of Trustees of the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and was appointed for another term in 1982 by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Troast</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HEMET, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Troast </PERSON>, 78, a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> art director whose 40-year career included 14 years with the `` Lassie'' show, died Monday. Troasts' credits included the `` My Three Sons'' television show, the `` <PERSON> Sandburg </PERSON>'s Lincoln'' miniseries and the 1977 movie, `` The Magic of Lassie.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Joseph Adams</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Joey </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, an award-winning former <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> photographer, died Sunday. He was 59. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> started as an apprentice at the old <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bulletin </LOCATION>, working as the equivalent of a copy boy in the photo department. During the Korean War, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> sereved as an Army combat photographer and won the <ORGANIZATION> Bronz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>. He worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> from 1954 to 1973 and amassed some 25 major awards for his news and feature photos. He set a record in 1957 when he won four prizes in the PPPA contest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     10-12 0417</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0428</SECOND>
<HEAD>Duel of Liberace Movies Ends in a Draw</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 CBS' saga about <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> finished among last week's top 15 prime-time TV shows and nearly matched the rating of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s version broadcast the previous week. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Liberace'' had a rating of 16.8 and ranked seventh. It was the `` official'' version, sanctioned by the flamboyant entertainer's estate. Perhaps viewers tuned in for CBS' `` Liberace: Behind the Music,'' hoping for a more sensationalized account of his life. The CBS movie had a rating of 16.6 and ranked 14th, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won a week it had expected to lose because of major league baseball championship playoffs on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> A rainout of Friday's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> game 3 lowered <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s score in the Nielsens and gave <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> the unexpected victory For the week that ended Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had a 15.0 rating, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 13.4 and CBS 12.4. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> added two new shows to the top 10, its premiere of `` Empty Nest,'' nestled behind the hit `` Golden Girls'' on Saturday, and a preview of `` Dear John'' in the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Thursday hit lineup. The season premiere of `` The Cosby Show'' was No. 1, though it had a considerably lower rating and share than its premiere last season _ 24.2 and a 40 share, compared with 31.5 and 51 last year. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for research projects, attributed the `` Cosby'' number to competition from baseball, but said <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had expected the show's ratings to slide in this, its fifth season. The rest of last week's top 10 were: `` A Different World,'' `` Golden Girls,'' `` Empty Nest'' and `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' all <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON>,'' a CBS Tuesday movie; and tied at eighth: `` ALF,'' `` Tonight Show 26th Anniversary'' and `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family'' on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, plus CBS' `` 60 Minutes'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Monday Night Football.'' In news, the `` CBS Evening News'' won the week with a 10.2 rating and 20 share, though <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' managed a close second, 9.9 and 21, despite baseball pre-emptions. `` NBC Nightly News'' had a 9.6 and 20 share. A rating point equals 904,000 homes with televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Olympics coverage sputtered to a close with the `` Summer Olympics Review'' ranked 47th with an 8.7 rating and 14 share, just above the 10 lowest-rated shows of the week: `` Incredible Sunday,'' `` American League Championship Pre-game 3,'' `` National League Championship Pre-game 3,'' `` Full House,'' `` Bugs Bunny Specials,'' `` Cavanaughs,'' `` Perfect Strangers,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'' and `` Live! <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> Presents.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0425EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>a a PM-NielsensList     10-12 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0580</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Does not contain year-to-date rankings due to irregular
scheduling. FOX network ratings also were unavailable.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Oct. 3-9. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.2 rating, 21.9 million homes. 2. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.7, 20.5 million homes. 3. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.6, 19.5 million homes. 4. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.0 million homes. 5. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Preview </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.8, 17.9 million homes. 6. `` Jesse'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 19.4, 17.5 million homes. 7. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.3, 16.5 million homes. 8. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 8. `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Football: <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> vs. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 8. `` Tonight Show 26th Anniversary,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 8. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 12. `` The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Across </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 17.3, 15.6 million homes. 13. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9, 15.3 million homes. 14. `` Liberace: Behind the Music'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 16.6, 15.0 million homes. 15. `` NLCS Baseball Game 1: <ORGANIZATION> N.Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> L.A. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4, 14.8 million homes. 16. `` NLCS Baseball Game 4: <ORGANIZATION> L.A. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> N.Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.6 million homes. 17. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 14.1 million homes. 18. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 19. `` Unholy Matrimony'' _ `` CBS Monday Movie, `` 15.1, 13.7 million homes. 20. `` Going to the Chapel'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.0, 13.6 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` Unsolved Mysteries Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 21. `` ALCS Baseball Game 2: <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> vs. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 21. `` Super Bloopers and Practical Jokes Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9. 24. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 25. `` The Secret Life of <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>'' _ `` NBC Movie of the Week-Friday,'' 14.5. 26. `` High Risk,'' CBS, 13.5. 27. `` ALCS Baseball Game 3: <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> vs. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 28. `` NLCS Baseball Game 2: <ORGANIZATION> L.A. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> N.Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 28. `` Night Court Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 30. `` Leap of Faith'' _ `` CBS Thursday Movie,'' 12.0. 31. `` NLCS Pre-Game 1,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 32. `` Sonny Spoon Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 32. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 34. `` Seven Wonders-Circus World,'' CBS, 10.9. 35. `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 36. `` ALCS Pre-Game 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 36. `` Burning Questions,'' _ `` ABC News Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 38. `` NLCS Pre-Game 4,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 39. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 39. `` Street of Dreams'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 9.5. 39. `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 9.5. 42. `` NLCS Game 3-Rainout,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 43. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 9.0. 43. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 45. `` 48 Hours: Making Babies,'' CBS, 8.8. 46. `` Summer Olympics Review,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 47. `` ALCS Pre-Game 3,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 47. `` NLCS Pre-Game 3,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 47. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 47. `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 51. `` Bugs Bunny Special,'' CBS, 7.9. 51. `` The Cavanaughs,'' CBS, 7.9. 53. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 53. `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 7.4. 55. `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 56. `` Live! <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> Presents,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Jobless-Entrepreneurs 1stLd-Writethru a0403 10-12 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jobless-Entrepreneurs, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0403,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three States to Try Turning Jobless Into Entrepreneurs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS lede to delete extraneous words</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three states _ <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> _ will test giving some laid off workers their unemployment compensation benefits in lump sums for use in starting their own businesses. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the demonstration project authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year will divert about $ 8 million in the unemployment insurance fund to helping between 1,000 2,000 beneficiaries `` become successful entrepreneurs.'' The program would provide cash allowances equal to the amount laid off workers would normally receive in weekly unemployment insurance benefits, the department said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     10-12 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Alien Nation' Leads Box Office Sweepstakes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Alien Nation,'' starring <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Caan </PERSON> as a seasoned veteran cop paired with a crime-fighting humanoid from another planet, earned $ 8.4 million to become the box office leader in its first week of release. `` Punchline'' finished second with $ 5.2 million while `` Gorillas in the Mist'' was third with $ 4 million. <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON>'s `` Crossing Delancey'' was fourth and the dark comedy `` A Fish Called Wanda,'' in its 13th week, was fifth. The <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> action adventure `` Die Hard'' took sixth, the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> documentary `` Imagine'' was seventh, followed by `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>.'' The father-son conflict comedy `` Memories of Me'' was ninth and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON>'s `` Cocktail'' was 10th. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Alien Nation,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 8.42 million, 1,430 screens, $ 5,889 per screen, $ 8.42 million, one week. 2. `` Punchline,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.21 million, 753 screens, $ 6,914 per screen, $ 5.47 million, two weeks. 3. `` Gorillas in the Mist,'' Universal, $ 4.04 million, 1,081 screens, $ 3,740 per screen, $ 9.2 million, three weeks. 4. `` Crossing Delancey,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.66 million, 290 screens, $ 5,733 per screen, $ 7.35 million, six weeks. 5. `` A Fish Called <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON>,'' MGM @ <ORGANIZATION> UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.63 million, 959 screens, $ 1,706 per screen, $ 53.32 million, 13 weeks. 6. `` Die Hard,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 1.51 million, 1,050 screens, $ 1,441 per screen, $ 72.77 million, 13 weeks. 7. `` Imagine: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.41 million, 561 screens, $ 2,517 per screen, $ 1.41 million, one week. 8. `` Who Framed <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbit </PERSON>,'' Disney, $ 1.4 million, 1,147 screens, $ 1,224 per screen, $ 141.98 million, 16 weeks. 9. `` Memories of Me,'' MGM @ <ORGANIZATION> UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.39 million, 723 screens, $ 1,919 per screen, $ 1.49 million, two weeks. 10. `` Cocktail,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.28 million, 1,042 screens, $ 1,227 per screen, $ 69.22 million, 11 weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Panama-Cocaine     10-12 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Cocaine,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witness Testifies He Posed As Soldier To Deal In Cocaine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who told police he had 8.5 kilograms of cocaine in his car when they stopped him for a traffic violation testified Tuesday he made $ 139,000 dealing drugs while posing as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldier in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON>, dismissed from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in 1986, said he made six trips to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in his old uniform between April 1987 and last May. He testified he was paid $ 25,000 for each of five times he flew back with duffle bags containing cocaine, which he then took to apartments in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He said he also was paid $ 13,000 for a cardboard box of cocaine he mailed to a girlfriend and also got another $ 1,000 from a contact in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON>'s testimony came in the first day of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> trial of four people accused in a smuggling ring that included the alleged drug mailings. <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Doerun </LOCATION>, also was charged in the case but has pleaded guilty. The case broke when <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON>, 27, was stopped by police on May 28 for failing to have a driver's license. He told police he had 8.5 kilograms of cocaine in his car. On trial are <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Julia </PERSON> <PERSON> Thom </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Doerun </LOCATION>. They are accused of smuggling up to 600 pounds of cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> through various means. Defense lawyers have said that <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON> has concocted his story to win a lighter sentence for himself. But <PERSON> Bigelow </PERSON> testified that King made two of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> trips with him, and that <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was on the receiving end of most of his visits to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MyersonTrial     10-12 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Myerson Trial,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Myerson Defense Seeks to Defuse Clerk's Testimony</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prosecution witness at the divorce-fixing trial of former Miss America <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> conceded Tuesday that both sides in her boyfriend's divorce case did favors for the presiding judge's daughter. Miss <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON>, 64, the former city cultural affairs commissioner, is accused of giving a city job to the daughter of former state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Hortense </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON>, 75, in exchange for the judge's favorable rulings in the divorce of Miss <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON>'s lover, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> `` Andy'' <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>, 43. The defense succeeded in getting Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON>'s former law clerk, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON>, to admit during cross examination that a lawyer for <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s wife once helped secure an apartment for Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON>'s daughter, although he did not remember exactly when In earlier testimony, <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> made numerous phone calls to the judge's chambers while Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> was deciding whether to cut <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s alimony payments to his estranged wife. According to <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> apparently did not tell lawyers in the <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON> divorce trial about the <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> phone calls when she offered to excuse herself from the case after a newspaper article revealed that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> had hired the judge's daughter, <PERSON> Sukhreet </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> is accused of giving a $ 19,000-a-year city job to <PERSON> Sukhreet </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON>, who was then 34, shortly after <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> became cultural affairs commissioner in 1983 in order to get the judge to reduce <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s temporary support payments. Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> also did not tell the lawyers that Mrs. <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Felder </PERSON>, helped <PERSON> Sukhreet </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> obtain an apartment, <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON> testified under questioning by the judge's defense attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldberg </PERSON> <PERSON> Felder </PERSON> is not accused of any wrongdoing. In cross examining <PERSON> Leventhal </PERSON>, the defense sought to explain or defuse his apparently damaging testimony that Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> deviated from her usual routine in handling the <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON> case. On Sept. 14, 1983, Mrs. <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> cut <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s weekly temporary alimony and child support payments from $ 1,850 to $ 680 a week. Her ruling came just a few weeks after <PERSON> Sukhreet </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabel </PERSON> got a job as Miss <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON>'s assistant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Trees-Greenhouse     10-12 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trees-Greenhouse,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Power Company Seeks To Offset Pollution By Helping Grow Trees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a gesture cheered by environmentalists, the operator of a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> power plant has agreed to chip in on a tree-growing project it says will indirectly offset its boilers' addition to the `` greenhouse'' warming of the Earth The company, <ORGANIZATION> Applied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday it will give $ 2 million to an international effort to plant 52 million trees on 385 square miles in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. The trees should absorb enough carbon dioxide to offset the 1.4 million tons that the company's 180-megawatt coal-fired plant in <LOCATION> Uncasville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, will generate each year during its 40-year life, according to the company's calculations. The <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, Va.-based company said that as an environmental rule of thumb, two square miles of forest are needed for every megawatt of coal-fired plant capacity. Environmentalists hailed the company's move, saying it helped illustrate the international nature of the greenhouse effect, a warming of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> that scientists say appears to have begun due to increasing carbon dioxide and other chemicals released into the air. Carbon dioxide is formed by fossil fuel combust ion. The warming could mean an average temperature increase of 3 to 8 degrees Fahrenheit by the middle of the next century, an increase in sea levels of a foot or more and widespread weather changes that could mean more frequent droughts in the center of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, scientists say. Worldwide, some 20 billion tons of carbon dioxide every year are released into the atmosphere. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Speth </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> that helped organize the <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> project, called the Applied Energy action `` one of the most far-sighted and socially responsible decisions that any company has ever made.'' Requiring plant operators to offset their emissions in some similar manner `` might be proposed someday'' in legislation, he said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON>, atmospheric physicist with the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, said a colleague, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dudek </PERSON>, had recently proposed payments from utilities to plant trees on land taken out of agricultural production in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Other environmentalists were quick to praise the Applied Energy decision. `` I like it,'' said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which is planning a tree-planting campaign of its own. `` It recognizes we're in one world, when you've got a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> company going to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> to plant trees.'' <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Sant </PERSON>, chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Applied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>, said he hoped the project would prove `` a useful mitigation strategy'' for all new coal-fired electric generation capacity. `` We do n't yet know that this is going to work perfectly,'' but if it does `` we're looking to follow the same strategy at our other plants,'' <PERSON> Sant </PERSON> said. Applied Energy is one of the new independent producers selling power under contract to utilities, escaping tight state regulation for generally looser federal supervision. The company operates three plants totaling 360 megawatts and has contracts to build 1,600 megawatts of generating capacity. When the <LOCATION> Uncasville </LOCATION> plant is completed, it will sell power to <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. Applied Energy's cash for the <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> project will be matched by cash or services totaling $ 2 million from CARE, $ 1.2 million from the government of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, $ 3.6 million from the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> and $ 7.5 million from the <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. CARE, an international development organization based in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, will handle the company's contribution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Cambodia     10-12 0563</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Cambodia,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Calls for Measures To Block Khmer Rouge in Cambodia</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: time of meeting indefinite</NOTE>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is expressing strong support for the efforts of former <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> to achieve national reconciliation in his homeland and says `` effective safeguards'' must be imposed to prevent a return to power by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, who was meeting today with Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, said Tuesday after a visit with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> he agrees that leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> `` must go into exile, if possible,'' as part of a post-settlement coalition government. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> are believed to have killed between 1 million and 2 million Cambodians during their 3 -LCB- years in power during the late 1970s. They are one of three rebel groups fighting the Vietnamese-backed government now in power in <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is providing $ 5 million in non-lethal assistance to the two anti-communist rebel groups and is consulting with members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about the possibility of an increase. Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> that he `` supported -LRB- <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>'s -RRB- efforts to establish a reconciliation government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.'' `` He said our policy rests on two elements, a complete Vietnamese withdrawal and no return to power of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> deputy spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which has been a major backer of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, recognizes that `` discredited'' leaders of that group, such as <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON>, can not be permitted to play a role in a future Cambodian government. But she said the administration could not confirm a <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> report that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has offered political asylum to individual <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> leaders. There have been intensified diplomatic efforts to shape events in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> as <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has begun a drawdown of its troops in that country, setting a 1990 deadline for a complete withdrawal. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, who was ousted as head of state in 1970 and heads a rebel faction active in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, met with Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> after his visit to the White House. Aligning himself with the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> told reporters it is `` necessary to give the world some guarantee about the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> in the future.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said the discussion with <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> focused on ways to achieve a negotiated settlement that includes the complete withdrawal of Vietnamese troops and effective safeguards against a <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> return to power. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> is said to be the strongest of the three factions and a major international effort is under way to ensure that group does not play a dominant role in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s future political evolution. Particularly active in this effort have been the six members of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> ASEAN </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. One of the measures being discussed to limit the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> role is the establishment of an international peacekeeping force. Other measures under discussion include the disarming of all Cambodian factions and removing leading <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> figures from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> gave a strong endorsement of <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, calling him a `` leading symbol of Cambodian nationalism for the past 40 years.'' `` We believe that his role is central to a satisfactory settlement in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and we welcome the opportunity of his visit to express our strong support for him,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DiamondfromSewage     10-12 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Diamond from Sewage,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Naval Research Turns Sewer Gas Into Diamonds</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ancient alchemists, who strived to convert base metals into gold, have been outdone. A modern-day chemist is changing sewer gas into diamonds. Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> and his colleagues at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> wo n't likely be going into the fancy jewelry business, he admits. But they have found a way to produce some tiny industrial-type diamond crystals using one of the most widely available raw materials, the methane from sewer gas. In this case, gas from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Blue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION>, which is adjacent to the research laboratory. In addition, other chemists working at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> have grown diamond crystals using an oxygen-acetylene torch, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think we'll be able to grow gemstone size and quality diamonds in the near future,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> cautioned. But the tiny diamonds made in his process _ using chemical vapors to deposit crystals on a surface _ could have a variety of industrial applications from abrasives to protective coatings, computer insulators and a host of other uses, he said. What <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> and the other <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> scientists are doing is developing methods of getting carbon to form diamond crystals. Their process requires heating chemical vapors at normal air pressure or less and then getting carbon from the vapor to crystalize on a surface at temperatures of about 900 degrees Celsius -LRB- 1,440 degrees Fahrenheit -RRB-. Current industrial processes for making diamonds require much higher heat and pressure. Graphite _ the soft black material used in pencil leads _ is the normally stable form of carbon at room temperature, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> explained. But by heating carbon-containing gases like sewer gas or acetylene the harder form of carbon can be made to grow on a surface. And if enough crystals form they combine into a thin diamond film, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> added. Why use sewer gas? `` Sewer gas was just a case of having a convenient, inexpensive source of methane,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. Methane, a combination of carbon and hydrogen, is a primary constituent of sewer gas. It is generally burned as waste. Researchers in other countries have performed some similar experiments, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said, adding that such sources of carbon as vodka also have been used. It will be years before the diamond-making system could be developed on an industrial scale, he said, but when that happens plenty of raw material will be available. And if burning of the waste gas is halted that also would reduce pollution and release of carbon dioxide, a product of the burning which scientsts fear will add to the so-called greenhouse warming of the Earth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     10-12 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meetings This Week on US-Soviet Grain Pact</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Another meeting is scheduled for this week in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to see if a new long-term U.S.-Soviet grain agreement can be worked out. The meeting was announced Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as `` tentatively scheduled'' for Thursday and Friday, but no other details were provided in the brief statement by <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmer </PERSON>, deputy trade representative, who leads <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators. The previous 5-year agreement expired on Sept. 30, despite months of negotiations and informal talks by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet officials. One possibility has been a simple extension of the old pact for a year while negotiators work out details of a new arrangement. Negotiators have been pressured by some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm interests to insist on larger minimum levels of annual grain purchases by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Meanwhile, the Soviets have been buying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain in large quantities without a new agreement, including an additional 250,000 metric tons announced Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The sale brought total corn sold to the Soviets and delivered in the 1988-89 corn marketing year that began on Sept. 1 to more than 4.3 million tons. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn or 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. The 250,000 tons of corn would be about 9.85 million bushels. Corn prices have been averaging about $ 2.73 per bushel at the farm level, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates, meaning that the latest sale could have a farm value of around $ 27 million. According to the old agreement, the annual purchases were supposed to include a minimum of 4 million tons each of wheat and corn. The Soviets had the option of buying the remaining 1 million tons as wheat, corn or soybeans, with every ton of beans counting as two tons of grain _ up to a maximum of 1 million tons of grain equivalent. Prior to the round of sales announced since Sept. 1, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had purchased 9.05 million tons of wheat and 5.17 million tons of corn for delivery in the fifth year and final year of the agreement, plus 830,000 tons of soybeans and 1.3 million tons of soybean meal.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last weekend's meat loaf might still taste good tonight with the addition of a substance from the shells of crabs and lobsters, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scientists. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vercelloti </PERSON>, a chemist at the department's <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, said the substance, called chitin, inhibits a warmed-over flavor in uncured meat, poultry or fish that is cooked, stored and reheated. The additives have shown in laboratory tests to inhibit the off-taste for up to five days when mixed with hamburger, he said. <PERSON> Vercellotti </PERSON>, in a report issued Tuesday by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said TV dinners, microwave foods and leftovers are prime candidates for off-tastes Meats cured with nitrite, such as bacon, ham and lunch meats do n't have such problems, he said. The warmed-over flavor also is described by the food industry as `` cardboardy'' or `` painty.'' The off-taste is caused when fat in the uncured meat breaks down as it is reheated. <PERSON> Vercellotti </PERSON> and a fellow chemist, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Angelo </PERSON>, are seeking a patent on additives made from chitin, which he described as `` a surplus material from the shellfish industry.'' Chitin is most commonly found in the shells of lobsters, crabs and other shellfish. The warmed-over flavor occurs when oxygen in the atmosphere breaks down fats in the meat, the report said. Large amounts of iron present in meat speed up the oxidation. But the chitin additives bind the iron so it can not speed up the oxidation, thus slowing down the development of the warmed-over flavor. Chitin additives would have to be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> before being available to consumers. `` Basically they are a type of soluble dietary fiber that we think will be safe to use in foods,'' <PERSON> Vercellotti </PERSON> said. `` We've only tested chitin additives on beef, but we think they will work on other meats, poultry and fish as well. The laboratory studies show that the additives `` have no other effect on meat flavor,'' he said. `` We're only talking about adding a few parts per million to the meat.'' <PERSON> Vercellotti </PERSON> said the compounds can be mixed into the meat, rolled on to the meat surface or sprayed on as a liquid.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881012-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-12-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LaborCosts     10-12 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Labor Costs,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Labor Costs In Europe Now Higher Than In US</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
