<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-NY-Dem-Deleg-Sum     04-19 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-NY-Dem-Deleg-Sum,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>04-19-88 23:23</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Democratic presidential primary in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 91 percent of precincts reporting. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 152 <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> 17 <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 86 <ORGANIZATION> Uncommitted </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Gephardt </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> LaRouche </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> 0 Total 255
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-NY-GOP-Deleg-Sum     04-19 0121</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-NY-GOP-Deleg-Sum,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>04-19-88 23:23</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the delegates won by each candidate in the Republican presidential primary in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 92 percent of precincts reporting. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 91 <ORGANIZATION> Robertson </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Uncommitted </ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION> Dole </ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION> Kemp </ORGANIZATION> 4 Total 96
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ABC-Stoddard     04-19 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ABC-Stoddard,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC Developing New Prime-Time News Show</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 ABC News is developing a new prime-time news program that could show up on the network's schedule next fall, says <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON>. `` They're developing a couple of shows and I think there's a possibility ABC News would have another hour prime time come fall, I just do n't know what time period or when or what the show would be, but there is active development in that area,'' <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> told a news conference on Monday. The <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> programmer stirred controversy last year when he announced he was moving <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` 20-20'' newsmagazine out of its successful Thursday night time period. The news division feared the show's ratings would decline, but much of its audience apparently followed it to Friday and it finished the season in the mid-range of the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> rankings. If there is a new news show, it might be the only new show ready to start in the fall. <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said he was n't optimistic of an early end to the 6-week-old <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> strike. He suggested if it lasts into June, it could substantially delay the start of the 1988-89 television season, causing more defections by network viewers to alternatives like cable and videocassettes. According to <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> figures, the three networks lost 9 percent of their audience between last season and this season, though the networks blame part of the reduction on a change in <LOCATION> Nielsen </LOCATION>'s audience measurement system <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said a delay in the start of the new season would force networks the keep running repeats. `` In addition to that, when the strike is finished, and we start putting programs on the air, there's going to be tremendous pressure to get something up on that screen, and maybe it ai n't perfect when we do,'' he said `` I think there also could be some erosion caused by the lack of quality. This is a very serious problem.'' Of this season's new shows, <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said he was most disappointed in `` Dolly!'' and that the network was considering buying out star <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> and canning the show next year. <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> got a two-year guarantee last year. `` As you all know, we actually have the right not to do the show,'' <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said. `` There is a penalty payment we would pay if we did not go ahead on the second year.'' He would not say how much it is. <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> also listed `` Moonlighting'' as a disappointment. Formerly a top-10 show, `` Moonlighting'' dropped into the top 20 this season, due to frequent repeats and episodes without <PERSON> Cybill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> during her pregnancy. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said, the show most likely will be back next season. Other likely returnees are `` The Wonder Years'' and `` thirtysomething.'' <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said he was optimistic that `` Hooperman'' would be renewed and that executive producer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Bochco </PERSON> had even developed a spinoff. `` The ` Slap' Maxwell Story'' is going to be a tough call, <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said. While happy his network was second this season in the Nielsen ratings, with an average, prime-time rating of 13.7 to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 13.5, <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said the performance really was `` not that terrific.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had a 16.1. Without high-rated prime-time sports programming _ the World Series, the Super Bowl and the Winter Olympics _ <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> actually was third in the ratings. The rating is a percentage of the nation's 88.6 million homes with televisions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PrimaryAnalysis 1stLd-Writethru a0897 04-19 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Primary Analysis, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0897,550</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS news grafs 5-6, to update with comment from
California chairman</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> gave <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leaders what they wanted, a front-runner, but the history of their roller-coaster process made many reluctant to declare that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had the nominaton locked up. `` We no longer have the winner-a-week syndrome,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruvolo </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. But he quickly added, `` I do n't think you can say it's over.'' One of the few party leaders willing to describe <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as the nominee was <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Cutler </PERSON>, deputy chair of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think we have a nominee,'' said <PERSON> Cutler </PERSON>. But she warned that the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign must be `` very careful not to look as though it's a done deal.'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said many of the elected and party officials, designated as super delegates to the nominating convention, may be reluctant to jump too quickly onto the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> bandwagon. `` They're going to want to be real careful about angering <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his supporters,'' said <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>. `` I, for one, am very sensitive about offending that constituency.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' big victory in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> essentially knocked Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> out of the race, finally paring the Democratic field down to a two-man contest _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> versus <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor was assured of a big delegate harvest in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> next Tuesday after <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> filled only about 65 percent of the 178 delegate slots at stake. But caution stemmed in part from the fact that for months every time a candidate was on verge of claiming front-runner status, the voters knocked him down a peg. An even stronger factor was the formidable presence of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and the need now to seriously confront the often-asked question, `` What does <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> want?'' On the campaign trail, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> relishes ridiculing that question, responding with a recitation of the basic liberal <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> agenda _ a higher minimum wage, health care, housing, a shifting of priorities away from those of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Repeatedly, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has also said he wanted to `` enable our party to win'' and was determined to `` play a role in making that happen.'' When a questioner at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> breakfast asked <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> what he would do if he did n't get the nomination, the candidate replied that it was important to `` put the nation first and party second and your role third.'' Among the established leaders of the party there was concern about what <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s large constituency, so essential to Democratic victories in general elections, would do if he failed to get the nomination. <PERSON> Ruvolo </PERSON> said it was important for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to continue campaigning hard in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and other upcoming primary states, to avoid being embarrassed, but also because the contest `` has to be perceived as a fair fight'' by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s supporters. <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Cutler </PERSON>, `` I think we have to be very careful in these next weeks that Rev. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s candidacy continues to be treated with respect, well-earned credit for everything that he's done for the party.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDITOR'S NOTE: Donald M. Rothberg is the chief political writer</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-JusticePosts 1stLd-Writethru a0810 04-19 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Justice Posts, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0810,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Top Justice Aides Leaving, Word On Shepherd May Come
Wednesday</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Inserts 2 grafs after 6th graf bgng: A bookkeeper, to UPDATE
with report on Shepherd's ties to Wallach, possible timing of
Shapherd announcement. Picks up 7th graf pvs bgng: Two other ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three top <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> aides to Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> are quitting or transferring to new jobs, marking a new round of departures and creating additional problems for Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. All three deputies rejected overtures by aides to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to remain at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> after the abrupt March 29 resignations of <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and criminal division chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, department sources said Tuesday. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> said he expects to hear shortly from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> on whether the former <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> president plans to withdraw from consideration as <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' successor. `` Probably tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastland </PERSON> said Tuesday evening when asked whether there was any word on Shepherd's status. <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>, 62, told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> last Friday that he was giving serious consideration to withdrawing because of stress on his family stemming from his selection. A former bookkeeper from <ORGANIZATION> Shepherd </ORGANIZATION>'s law firm testified shortly before <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> recommended him for the post that she had an affair with <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>. The bookkeeper, who was convicted of embezzlement, claimed <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> had told her to write checks to herself. <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> denied that he had an affair with her or that he had authorized her to write checks. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Wednesday's editions, meanwhile, that <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> was recommended for a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> position in late 1984 or early 1985 by <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> associate now under indictment in connection with the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> scandal in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The Post, quoting <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources, said <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>'s ties to <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> came up in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s background checks of Shepherd and `` caused some concern.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> also reported that <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> agreed not to withdraw from consideration until Thursday, to give <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> time to find a replacement. Two other deputies to Burns, <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Boykin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, also handed in their resignations March 29. The latest exit of personnel would virtually empty the No. 2 office in the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> of top aides. It is customary for the deputy attorney general to pick his own assistants. But the sources said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s staff has sought to keep top deputies' posts filled following the resignations of <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and the vacancy in the department's No. 3 position due to the departure of Associate Attorney General <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Trott </PERSON>, who is now a federal judge. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> resigned with <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> out of concern that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continuing legal troubles stemming from a nearly year-long criminal investigation were damaging the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s operations, morale and image. The department sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the latest departures included: <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ludwiszewski </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Walden </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ludwiszewski </PERSON>, an associate deputy attorney general who came to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in 1985, has handed in his resignation and is negotiating with private <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> law firms for work, the sources said. <PERSON> Ludwiszewski </PERSON>, who was graduated magna cum laude from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 and was on the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>, specialized in legal issues pertaining to the lands and civil rights divisions and the solicitor general's office. <PERSON> Cassell </PERSON>, a Burns deputy who dealt with issues involving the department's criminal and antitrust divisions, is transferring to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where he will become an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney. <PERSON> Cassell </PERSON> was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. In a move that has been in the planning stages for some time, <PERSON> Walden </PERSON>, an associate deputy attorney general, is to become chief counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. He will leave the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in a few weeks. <PERSON> Walden </PERSON>, who has been with the department since 1983, has helped spearhead the government's various criminal investigations of former <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' last day at the department is Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WorldAIDS Bjt   04-19 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-World AIDS, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Cases Likely to Multiply Five Times in Next Three Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of full-blown AIDS cases in the world is likely to increase fivefold in the next three years, and hundreds of millions of people probably engage in activity that leaves them vulnerable, says the head of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>'s AIDS program. `` While it has become fashionable to reassure and state that AIDS will never threaten large populations, we believe that virology, immunology, sociology and epidemiology require us to take the long view, and a more somber view,'' Dr. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> AIDS commission Monday. `` Let us remember that we are still in the early phases of a global epidemic whose first decade gives us every rational reason for concern about the global future of AIDS,'' he said. `` HIV -LRB- the AIDS virus -RRB- does not need to spread rapidly in a population to have a tremendous and gradually expanding cumulative effect.'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said that while no precise figures are available, `` it is likely that several hundred million people around the world may have behaviors which make them potentially vulnerable to infection with HIV.'' While he did not spell out such behavior at that point in his testimony, it was clear he was referring primarily to unprotected sex with potentially infected partners and, secondarily, to drug users sharing needles with people who may be carrying the virus. `` Individual behavior is responsible for most HIV transmission,'' he said. `` This transmission requires the active participation of two persons. Therefore, the chain of transmission can be broken by the individual behavior of either the infected or the non-infected person. For this reason, the proper focus of prevention is behavior.'' He said education is essential to combating the epidemic. `` If intravenous drug users do not understand the words you use to describe needles, syringes and other drug equipment, they can not learn prevention. If adolescents are convinced that AIDS is being used to deprive them of sexual freedom, they may refuse to listen to prevention messages and even counterreact in ways that further endanger their lives,'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said. More than 81,000 AIDS cases were reported to the organization as of the end of February, but the actual number of AIDS cases is believed to be twice the reported total. WHO estimates that between 5 million and 10 million people are infected with the virus and that 150,000 new cases of fully developed AIDS will be reported during the coming year. `` If we adopt the conservative estimate then 5 million people are infected today with HIV -LRB- the AIDS virus -RRB-, a cumulative total of 1 million AIDS cases would be expected by 1991,'' he said. `` Thus, the period 1988-91 will likely witness over five times more AIDS cases than have thus far occurred.'' Dr. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pape </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> told the panel the epidemic in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> is shifting dramatically to one of heterosexual transmission. Whereas only 26 percent of the cases reported in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> 1983 were believed to have resulted from heterosexual sex, the number jumped to 64 percent last year. In <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION>, he said, only 12 percent of the cases reported in 1985 were attributed to likely heterosexual sex, compared to 58 percent last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0605EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--MaimingShooting     04-19 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Maiming Shooting,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Draws 12-Year Term for Shooting Off Tip of Ex-Girlfriend's
Nose</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A spurned lover was sentenced to 12 years in prison for shooting off the tip of his former girlfriend's nose after she ended their relationship early last year. <PERSON> Krikor </PERSON> <PERSON> Chouchanian </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, was taken into custody Monday immediately after <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaffe </PERSON> sentenced him and rejected a motion for bail pending appeal. <PERSON> Chouchanian </PERSON> was convicted last month of the attempted murder of <PERSON> Eiman </PERSON> `` Amy'' <PERSON> Rahal </PERSON>, a 28-year-old bellydancer. The jury also convicted him of the special allegations of use of a firearm and causing great bodily injury. The panel, however, rejected an allegation that the shooting was premeditated, which could have brought a life sentence. During the trial, Miss <PERSON> Rahal </PERSON> testified that <PERSON> Chouchanian </PERSON> tried to kill her three times after she broke off their relationship.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Patriots'Day     04-19 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Patriots' Day,0500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Modern-Day Revere Rides To Lexington Dodging Manholes, Battling
Laryngitis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Revere </PERSON>'s laryngitis made it hard for him to shout, `` The British are coming.'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawes </PERSON> got locked in a men's room during a rest stop. And the rain made slippery manholes treacherous for the patriots' horses. Otherwise, Patriots' Day on Monday was the occasion of a satisfactory re-staging of the 13-mile mission to <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> 213 years ago that alerted revolutionary colonists that British troops were heading their way. `` I'm ready to go back,'' <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON> said in a cracking voice at the end of the 2 -LCB- - hour horseback ride from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> It was the seventh portrayal of <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Revere </PERSON> for the 72-year-old entrepreneur from <LOCATION> Wellesley </LOCATION> who is a brigadier general in the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lancers </ORGANIZATION>. For decades, the ceremonial militia of 30 men has roughly recreated in daytime the horseback ride that <PERSON> Revere </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dawes </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON> made in the late hours of April 18, 1775. By alerting the insurrectionary colonists that British troops were on their way to <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, the 18th century trio set in motion the next day's confrontation that started the American Revolution. Monday, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>, a lieutenant in the lancers who portrayed <PERSON> Dawes </PERSON>, was freed from a men's room in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION> in time to meet up with Snow for their grand finale in <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> where they were met by a cheering crowd estimated at 500 people. This year's journey was considerably harder than the one taken the first time around. Just before Snow left <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> with a send-off from Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, he groused about the rain. His costume of three-cornered hat, wig, cloak and boots made for a hot ride compared to <PERSON> Revere </PERSON>'s, who had the advantage of a cool, clear night and his own clothes. Snow also had to watch out for slippery manholes. But Snow said he enjoyed himself and was grateful for the audience along the way that ignored the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marathon </LOCATION>. When Snow left <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Revere </PERSON> lived in a house that still stands, a throng of spectators stood under store awnings and a makeshift canopy of umbrellas. There were grinning toddlers, graying baby-boomers taking off for the state holiday and elderly Italian widows. `` This is how <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was founded,'' said <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Gant </PERSON>, an accountant from <PERSON> Everett </PERSON>, who recommended historical re-enactments as a way to understand this country. `` You've got to get the concept of where you come from to know where you go from here,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Gant </PERSON>, 50. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Federico </PERSON>, 35, a pharmacist who grew up in the old, narrow streets of the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>, said he's been coming to see <PERSON> Revere </PERSON> ride off his entire life. That's why he brought his 10-year-old son, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, he said. `` It's a family tradition,'' the elder <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> said with a nod toward his son. `` It's important to see what you read about in the classroom.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Dance     04-19 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ballet Theater Opens Season with Panache</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American Ballet Theater opened its two-month season at the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> with panache _ the kind of dancing, style and brio that expects, deserves and receives bravos. Monday's program began with <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>'s new production and staging of `` Raymonda -LRB- Grand Pas Classique -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Martine </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamel </PERSON>, a commanding stage presence as well as a glorious ballerina, was partnered superbly by <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Amanda </PERSON> <PERSON> McKerrow </PERSON>, who danced the fourth solo variation, which requires lightness, long extension and some difficult balances, has blossomed into the ballerina her early promise predicted. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> staged the ballet after <PERSON> Marius </PERSON> <PERSON> Petipa </PERSON>, incorporating the grand pas de dix from Act 3 and several variations from the full-length `` Raymonda.'' Music is by <PERSON> Glazounov </PERSON>. <PERSON> Antony </PERSON> <PERSON> Tudor </PERSON>, who died last year, choreographed `` The Leaves Are Fading'' for American Ballet Theater in 1975. The music is by <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>. Sometimes this seems merely an overlong, pretty ballet, in which the women's thin skirts ripple as the men lift them and they seem to float. On Monday, it was a beautiful ballet. The various moods were strongly defined. There is much more than a pastel sense of autumn and saying goodby. Exquisite dancing _ which was seen opening night _ is important. Dim lighting instead of very noticeable dappled lighting helps, too, allowing the dancers and the music to hold prominence. <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Browne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> were the nimble leading couple, their virtuosic dancing having a carefree air about it. The evening ended with the first <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> performance of the company's production of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>'s `` Ballet Imperial.'' The company looks comfortable with this <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON> piece, which is more classical than his usual _ he based it on the Petipa style. Also, in this 1941 ballet, there are intertwinings which are <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON> trademarks. `` Ballet Imperial'' is as visually regal as the `` Raymonda'' which began the evening and the dancing was as glittering as the women's small crowns. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Stretton </PERSON> were the impressive leading couple and Miss <PERSON> McKerrow </PERSON> distinguished herself again in solos. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Boriskin </PERSON> was the thundering soloist in <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s `` Second Piano Concerto'' for `` Ballet Imperial. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Everly </PERSON> conducted the entire evening.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChildLabor     04-19 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Labor,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Children Working Illegally In Areas Of High Employment, Department
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Employers in areas of low joblessness are increasingly turning to using teen-agers in violation of child labor laws as an alternative to paying higher wages to attract and retain adults, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say. Illegal employment of children increased by more than 50 percent in 1987, the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. It said the most dramatic increase in violations occurred in the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION>, where unemployment rates are lowest. `` Because of the high levels of employment, we're finding a lot of firms hiring minors illegally for positions formerly held by older workers,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, deputy administrator of the department's wage-hour division. `` It's a trend in that geographic region.'' The number of children nationwide that the department found to be illegally employed last year was slightly more than 19,000, up from 12,662 in 1986. The department said it assessed civil fines totaling $ 1.5 million last year against 811 companies illegally employing 10,160 minors. Under the labor protection laws, children ages 14 and 15 can hold limited, non-hazardous jobs, but the number of hours they can work is restricted. Children ages 16 and 17 can work full-time but not in dangerous occupations such as roofing, excavation work and mining or around hazardous machinery. The biggest violator, the department said, was a large chain of supermarkets in the Northeast which was working children too many hours a week and illegally employing them in hazardous occupations such as meat cutting. Ms. <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON> would not identify the supermarket chain, saying the case is still being litigated. The department said it found that nearly 488,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers were cheated out of $ 126 million last year through employer violations of minimum wage, overtime pay and other provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act. At least 155,000 workers were due $ 28.5 million in minimum wage violations and 329,000 employers were underpaid at total of $ 98 million in overtime due them, said Assistant Labor Secretary <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>. Of those amounts, the department recovered about $ 20.2 million in minimum wages for 136,000 of the workers who were underpaid and $ 79.5 million for 293,000 of those not paid overtime. The department also assessed $ 873,430 in civil penalties against farm labor contractors for violations of pay and health and safety standards under the Migrant Worker Protection Act.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Helmsley-Curse     04-19 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Helmsley-Curse,0850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helmsley Home Has Brought Bad Luck To Its Owners</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Tuesday AMs. First name Gregg in graf 9
cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LINDA STOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GREENWICH, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 28-room mansion built as a wedding gift has gained a reputation of bringing bad luck to those who live there: Three of its residents have faced criminal charges, two have lost their fortunes and one killed himself. The latest owners of <PERSON> Dunnellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> are real estate tycoons <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>, who were indicted last week on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state and federal tax charges. `` It was n't the happiest home,'' said <PERSON> Marjorie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Preferred </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Properties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, who handled two of the sales of the mansion. `` It seems as if some very wealthy people who lived there lost their fortunes. If the walls could talk ...'' The house sits on 26 acres in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, hometown to such notables as <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>. The average price of a home here is about $ 1 million, real estate agents say. It was built in 1918 at a cost of $ 1 million for <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Grey </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, as a wedding gift for his daughter, <PERSON> Rhea </PERSON>. She married <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Topping, son of <PERSON> John </PERSON> A. Topping, president of Republic Steel. The estate, referred to locally as the `` Topping House,'' was named <PERSON> Dunnellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> by <PERSON> Rhea </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> <PERSON> Topping </PERSON> for her mother, <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>. It was sold for the first time in 1950 to <PERSON> Loring </PERSON> <PERSON> Washburn </PERSON>, president of S.H. <ORGANIZATION> Pormeroy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a steel fabricating company. But he suffered financial troubles and lost the house in 1963. Others who have had trouble after they moved into the house were: _ <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Moran </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> policeman who was married to <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodge </PERSON>, a heiress to the <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> automobile fortune <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> shot and killed a busboy who apparently was trying to climb into the bedroom window of their <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> home in 1968. The slaying was ruled justifiable homicide. <PERSON> Moran </PERSON> killed himself in 1977, although a judge would not say whether the shooting was intentional or accidental. _ Investor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> He was indicted by a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> grand jury on 46 counts of grand larceny and forgery for allegedly stealing $ 840,000 through the use of false documents to obtain a loan. He pleaded innocent in 1971. The case was pending when he died suddenly in 1974 at the age of 46 while being driven to the estate by his chauffeur. _ <PERSON> Ravi </PERSON> <PERSON> Tikkoo </PERSON>, owner of the one of the world's largest oil supertankers He lost the bulk of his fortune during the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> oil embargo and petroleum shortages in the mid-1970s. The <ORGANIZATION> Helmsleys </ORGANIZATION>, one of the world's wealthiest couples at an estimated $ 1.4 billion and with a stake in the Empire State Building, bought the estate in 1983 for $ 11 million. The Helmsleys pleaded innocent last week to charges in a 188-count <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state tax evasion indictment. They are accused by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> officials of avoiding taxes by claiming about $ 4 million in renovations to <LOCATION> Dunnellen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION> as business expenses at their hotels. The couple also face a 47-count federal indictment on similar charges. <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Parizek </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday that two auditors had been assigned to examine the <ORGANIZATION> Helmsleys </ORGANIZATION>' finances. Last week, <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bannon </PERSON>, state commisioner of revenue services, said his investigators were taking a close look at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> charges to determine if any <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> taxes were owed on items at the estate. One of the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s attorneys, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>, said Monday that he thought the couple would not fall victim to the curse. `` I'm sure the <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>'s have broken the bad luck streak at <LOCATION> Dunnnellen </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Duff </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Duff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which handled the sale of the estate for <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, widow of <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, said the property had been compared to a famous gem with a bad reputation. `` She -LRB- <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> -RRB- said this place is like the Hope Diamond _ everyone who ever owned it and lived here had bad luck,'' <PERSON> Duff </PERSON> said Monday. `` I argued with <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> at the time, but I would n't argue with her today.'' According to the book `` Diamonds Eternal,'' by <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Argenzio </PERSON>, the gem was owned by <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON>, who went to guillotine with his wife. A Dutch cutter who changed the stone's appearance had the stone stolen from him by his own son who later killed himself. Turkish sultan <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamid </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, lost his throne and had to abdicate shortly after aquiring stone in 1908, the book said. Later, after <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> and <PERSON> Evalyn </PERSON> <PERSON> McLean </PERSON> acquired the stone, their first son was killed in an auto crash, and <PERSON> McLean </PERSON> was implicated in the Teapot Dome scandal and died in mental institution. After Mrs. <PERSON> McLean </PERSON>'s death in 1947, the diamond was purchased by <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON>, who gave it to the current owner, the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TimberingDispute     04-19 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Timbering Dispute,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservationists Cite Report on National Forest Timbering Losses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A congressional study is giving fresh ammunition to conservationists and lawmakers who want to end the big-bucks losses sustained by taxpayers from timber sales in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest national forest. Weighing in on the side of the sales program's critics, the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> says <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should scrap the 1980 law requiring the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to market a minimum amount of timber from <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative wing of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said in a study released Monday that the requirement cost the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> $ 22.1 million in 1986 and has not created the lumbering jobs it was supposed to in southeast <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The 1980 law directs the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to offer to sell at least 4.5 billion board feet of Tongass timber each decade and guarantees at least $ 40 million in spending a year to support the sales program. The law resulted from a compromise worked out by conservationists and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> lawmakers. In return for the guarantee program, conservationists would get 5.4 million of the forest's 16.8 million acres declared wilderness, putting them off-limits to commercial use The Tongass is the only national forest with a minimum sales goal set by law, although Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, has proposed a similar guarantee for the <ORGANIZATION> Panhandle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in his state. Last month, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved legislation to repeal the Tongass guarantee. A similar bill is pending in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The proposals are being pushed by environmental and conservation groups who say the guarantee leads to lost tax dollars, unnecessary roadbuilding by the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and needless harvesting of 400-year-old trees. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> study, requested by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said sales of Tongass timber should be subject to market supply-and-demand forces <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said that from 1981 through 1986, sales of Tongass timber averaged 245 million board feet a year, some 205 million below the yearly average needed to meet the 10-year goal. Focusing on 1986, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spent $ 47.9 million on the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> and realized only $ 3.3 million in revenues. The net loss was $ 22.1 million because some spending was for timber production in future years, according to the study. From 1981 through 1986, $ 131 million was spent to prepare for timber sales that were not needed to meet existing demand, the study said. `` The timber supply provision should be revised so that the amount supplied would be based on the anticipated demand for timber and on the data currently being formulated by the <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> ... rather than on a rigid per-decade requirement,'' the study said. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said Tongass-related timber jobs declined from 2,700 in 1980 to 1,420 in 1986 `` primarily because of the decreased harvest levels resulting from declining demand for timber and increased production by the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> native corporations that directly compete with the Tongass timber industry.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> chief, <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, said in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> that the proposal to scrap the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> guarantee `` has merit.'' <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> said in a prepared statement that <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> focused on a low-demand portion of an economic cycle and that timber has since rebounded. He said money must be spent on the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> even in slack periods in order to meet peak demand. He also said the study is flawed because it focused only on the guarantee, not on the other side of the 1980 compromise: prohibiting commercial activities in nearly one-third of the Tongass.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EuropeanTrade     04-19 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-European Trade,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Freer Trade in Europe Would Help US, Other Countries</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Knocking down barriers to trade among the 12 countries of the European Community by 1992 will also benefit outside countries such as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, a researcher says. The main advantage to outside trading partners from greater unification would be in having only a single set of rules to deal with, instead of a dozen, said <PERSON> Paolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON>, assigned by the Community to study the issue. `` A foreign company that sells to only one of the 12 will have jumped over the culture gap,'' he said Monday. <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Krucoff </PERSON>, press officer for the Community's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office, gave labeling requirements on European imports as an example. Now each of the 12 governments has its own rules. <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON> added that since there would be no official discrimination against subsidiaries of foreign firms within the Community, they too would benefit from any additional growth. <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON> said that over the `` medium term'' _ about five years _ new measures of unification also could create as many as 5 million new jobs in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where unemployment is higher than in this country.. He said about 200 people have contributed to his project called `` The Cost of Non-Europe'' _ the cost of not having unified the economy of the Community yet. In addition to <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON>'s own <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, members include <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. Together, these countries have as many people as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> has also asked to join, and Community officials say <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> are possibilities. The European Common Market program is conducted under the auspices of the Community. <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON> noted that in some matters the Community already has more unity than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. For example, a doctor licensed in one of the 12 countries is qualified to practice in all of them, unlike the rules here which differ from state to state. Next month <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON> will start publishing more than 6,000 pages of research. He said his study has found that European economic gains from greater unification could be worth more than $ 300 billion and prices paid by consumers could be 6 percent less than in a divided continent. `` Five million new jobs would cover half of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s unemployed, or all the young unemployed,'' he added. He also cited the example of Japanese auto exporters, whose sales to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> are limited under a quota imposed by the Italian government. The effort is now being made to `` Europeanize'' this quota, so that Japanese sales could go to any of the 12 countries on the same terms. Community officials emphasized there would have to be some hard bargaining with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> first. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Calingaert </PERSON> is a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official on leave to study the European effort for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Planning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a private group. He said the European plans are moving ahead fast. `` In 1957 industrialists were frightened of the possible results and opposed it,'' he said. `` Now they are in favor.'' He said the private sector is acting as if the effort will succeed, and that attitude could be self-fulfilling. The idea of a unified <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, which dates back centuries, got a boost after World War II when Americans held up the economic advantages of a `` common market'' like that of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. West European countries had to organize themselves to distribute the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid offered in the Marshall Plan, and began to eliminate import quotas in trade with one another. In 1957 six of the present 12 members signed the Treaty of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, pledging the removal of all barriers among them. Progress has been slow. `` Now things are accelerating,'' <PERSON> Cecchini </PERSON> said. `` Six months ago nobody was even talking about a central bank for the Community. Now the prospect is that the summit meeting in <LOCATION> Hanover </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB- in June will set up a study of something like the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Federal Reserve system.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Taiwan-Nuclear     04-19 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Taiwan-Nuclear,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mystery of the Missing Nuclear Scientist Captivates Taiwan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The disappearance of a leading nuclear scientist has Taiwanese fuming at the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and worrying about damage to their national security. Newspapers carried unconfirmed reports after Col. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsien-yi </PERSON> vanished in mid-January that he worked for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and might have turned over nuclear secrets to the Americans. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> was a deputy director of the official <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>. He disappeared while on leave from his post. `` We immediately looked at this map, maybe he fell off a cliff,'' said <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuang-chi </PERSON>, secretary general of the government <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, as he moved to an office wall map of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and traced a route along rugged interior roads. But several local newspapers provided a different scenario for <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>'s disappearance, reporting that he was a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> informant who left for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with details about a Taiwanese nuclear weapons program. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last month that the department had no comment on whether <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> was an informant for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taiwan </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests here, has told the government and local media the institute has no idea of what happened to <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> officials have repeatedly denied plans to build a nuclear bomb. Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has said the production of atomic weapons by <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> would be reason to invade the island, which <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> regards as a renegade province. Nevertheless, the uproar over <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> has increased anti-American sentiment that already was brewing here because of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s tough trade talk with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, which last year had a record $ 16 billion trade surplus with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> Although the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1979 broke diplomatic relations with <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and recognized the Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> government, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> remains the island's major trade partner and arms supplier. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> serves as an operative diplomatic and commercial link in the absence of an embassy. `` I get a lot of hot reaction from my students,'' said <PERSON> Su </PERSON> <PERSON> Chi </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> who also teaches at <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chengchi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Until this point there's always been a huge reservoir of good will toward the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ... but I think the reservoir has cracked.'' The <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> media, which has given intense coverage to <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>'s disappearance, also has criticized the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> A March 25 commentary in the mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said that no matter what the motive, `` the act of stealing our defense secrets has invaded our national sovereignty and respect to a certain degree. ... No one can interpret this as friendly behavior.'' <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> officials now believe <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. They have asked the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for information about him but the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration claims it does not know his whereabouts. Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> recently said <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> can not lodge a protest with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because `` we do n't have evidence showing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government or <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> involvement.'' But Jaw Shau-kong, a maverick lawmaker from the governing <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, is demanding retaliatory action. The government `` probably should expel some -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- diplomats from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, expel some <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>; it can not keep silent,'' said <PERSON> Jaw </PERSON>, who views the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as an imperialist nation. <PERSON> Jaw </PERSON> said he fears <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> took important military secrets, possibly classified information about <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s missile development program. Jaw added that he wonders if such material could fall into the hands of Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON>, the nuclear energy official, noted that many of <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>'s classmates worked on missile and airplane projects at the military-run <ORGANIZATION> Chungshan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> The government maintains, however, <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> did not take any sensitive information from <LOCATION> Chungshan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> believes the missing scientist did not have access to such secrets even though he knew of work done by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> staff for military-related Chungshan projects. Professor <PERSON> Su </PERSON> believes <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>'s disappearance is unlikely to cause a serious re-evaluation of Taiwanese-U.S. relations but could eventually lead to public debate of the country's nuclear policy. In early April, the mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> newspaper published a poll that indicated <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> was split over the development of nuclear weapons. According to the survey, 35 percent of the 767 people polled by telephone said <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> should make atomic bombs while 34 percent were against such a policy. The poll, with a margin of error of 3.5 percentage points, indicated most people believe <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> is capable of making the weapons. Nearly three-fourths of the respondents said that if <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> developed nuclear weapons they should not be used against mainland <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Gulf-Chronology     04-19 1355</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Gulf-Chronology,1300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of U.S.-Gulf Developments</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a chronology of developments in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> since last May, when the attack on the USS Stark and the reflagging of <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil tankers by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> brought increased attention to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> activity in that area. May 17 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> frigate Stark is attacked in the gulf by an Iraqi warplane; 37 crew members die. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials term the attack a mistake by the Iraqi pilot. May 19 _ President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says the Stark tragedy `` must never be repeated'' and says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in the gulf will have more leeway to protect themselves from military threats. May 21 _ <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> issues waivers of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> maritime law to allow speedy reflagging of Kuwaiti tankers under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> colors. May 29 _ <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials report a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military buildup in the gulf is planned to protect Kuwaiti tankers. June 16 _ Maritime executives say <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is mining the gulf. June 18 _ The <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> characterizes the threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel in the gulf as `` low to moderate.'' <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., says <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is underestimating threat from mines July 1 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> specialists aboard a four-boat Arab mine-sweeping flotilla remove 10 to 12 mines near <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> ports. July 3 _ Administration postpones plans to send <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine-sweeping helicopters to the gulf, deciding to rely on the Arab ships. July 9 _ Iranian gunboat attacks U.S.-flagged tanker Peconic with rocket-propelled grenades. Tanker is set afire but no one is injured. July 18-20 _ Reflagging of Kuwaiti tankers begins. July 19 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> teams complete month-long mine-sweeping operation in channel leading to <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil terminal. July 21 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> convoy operations begin. July 24 _ Reflagged supertanker <LOCATION> Bridgeton </LOCATION> hit by `` very large explosion'' after striking mine in narrow channel near <LOCATION> Farsi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military sources say <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine sweeping capability in gulf is `` virtually nil.'' July 26 _ <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine-sweeping capability in gulf will be improved. Over next 10 days, mine sweepers are dispatched along with the helicopter carrier <LOCATION> Guadalcanal </LOCATION>, carrying mine detecting choppers. July 31 _ <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> helicopter crashes in gulf, killing four crewmen. Aug. 7 _ Lawsuit filed by 114 members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> seeking to invoke the War Powers Act, under which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commitment in gulf would need congressional approval to extend for more than 60 days. Administration denies that gulf situation meets the act's `` imminent danger'' test Aug. 8 _ <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> F-14 Tomcat fighter fires two missiles at Iranian jet approaching an unarmed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> surveillance plane. Both missiles miss but Iranian jet retreats. Aug. 10 _ U.S.-operated supertanker <ORGANIZATION> Texaco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caribban </ORGANIZATION> strikes mine in <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION> anchorage previously assumed to be safe. Aug. 20 _ <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> admits sowing mines to `` defend our coastline.'' Sept. 4 _ Silkworm anti-ship missile of type used by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> explodes on Kuwaiti soil. Sept. 9 _ Two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sailors aboard cruiser in the gulf injured by premature detonation of cannon shell. Sept. 18 _ <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> jet with two aboard crashes in <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>; search called off three days later with crewmen presumed dead. Sept. 21 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopter attacks Iranian ship found to be laying mines. Iranian ship left `` dead in the water'' after fire on board is extinguished. Sept. 22 _ <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> vows revenge. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> denies <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> has entered shooting war, saying `` We did what was authorized by law ... in international waters.'' Oct. 1 _ Iraqi war planes fire a missile at a shrimp boat and kill its Australian captain. Oct. 2 _ <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> jets firing Exocet missiles set ablaze a Cypriot tanker, one of 16 chartered by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The number of vessels attacked or damaged by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> and Iranian forces stands at 375 since their war began seven years earlier. Oct. 3 _ Low-flying aircraft scare off Iranian speedboats from a joint Kuwaiti-Saudi Arabian oil port. Oct. 8 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopter gunships sink three Iranian patrol boats after an American observation helicopter is fired on. Two of six Iranian crewmen picked out of gulf waters later die. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, calls accelerate to invoke the War Powers Act. Oct. 9 _ Pentagon says <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> appears to have U.S.-made Stinger anti-aircraft missiles; <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> refuses to kill a move to invoke the War Powers Act. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says using the act would mean `` 535 secretaries of state.'' Oct. 11 _ <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> severely damages a Liberian-flagged supertanker; two crewmen are killed. Oct. 16 _ Iranian missile hits Kuwaiti ship flying the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flag, blinding its American captain and wounding 17 other crewmen in the first direct attack on the tanker fleet guarded by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Oct. 19 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships destroy two Iranian oil platforms in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> in retaliation. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> calls it a prudent response. Says Weinberger: `` We do not seek further confrontation with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> but will be prepared to meet any further military escalation by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> with stronger retaliation. We consider this matter is now closed.'' But Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says, `` Nobody thinks that this will end it.'' Oct. 20 _ The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> resumes convoy operations for reflagged tankers. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> vows it will make the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> `` regret'' the shelling of the oil platforms. Oct. 22 _ An Iranian Silkworm missile strikes <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s offshore supertanker oil terminal, starting a fire and wounding several people. Oct. 27 _ The arrival of five mine sweepers raises the number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval ships in and near the gulf to 40. Nov. 2 _ The frigate USS Carr, on escort duty, fires machines guns to chase off three small vessels, thought to be Iranian. At least one of the vessels later turns out to be a private fishing boat, and one Indian crew member was killed. Nov. 6 _ Iranian commandoes shoot up a U.S.-managed tanker from a speedboat, but no casualties were reported Nov. 16 _ Iranian speedboats attack a U.S.-owned supertanker and three other ships in the southern Gulf. Nov. 20 _ A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mine sweeper discovers two new mines in an area near <LOCATION> Farsi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Divers destroy the mines. Dec. 12 _ A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> warship and television helicopter rescue 40 people from a burning supertanker, which had been attacked by an Iranian gunboat. Feb. 1 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> divers raise an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> boat that had been sunk in October, and find Stinger anti-aircraft missiles aboard. Feb. 11 _ The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration waives the law that requires the U.S.-flagged Kuwaiti vessels being escorted in the gulf to carry American crews. Feb. 17 _ There are now 28 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in the gulf region; some have been withdrawn in what the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> calls a `` fine tuning'' of the American presence. Feb. 18 _ Mine-sweeping Stallion helicopters are withdrawn as the USS <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> leaves the gulf. March 6 _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopters draw heavy machine gun fire from an oil platform and small boats in the central gulf, but do not return fire. March 9 _ <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is examining options for helping non-U.S. flagged vessels in the area. March 10 _ Military sources say <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has begun building crude launch pads for missiles on an island in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. April 1 _ A <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman announces that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has found and destroyed 41 mines since sweeping operations began. April 14 _ The USS <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> strikes a mine, seriously damaging the frigate. Ten American sailors are injured. April 18 _ American forces strike two Iranian oil platforms to punish <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for the mine attack. In response, two Iranian navy frigates fire missiles at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft, and an Iranian guided missile patrol boat fires on the cruiser <PERSON> Wainwright </PERSON>. The frigates were attacked and heavily damaged by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces and the patrol boat was sunk, the Pentagon said. Officials say the Wainwrights was not damaged.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsTreaty     04-19 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Treaty,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Committee Sends Senate Report Urging That INF Treaty Be Passed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Critics of the U.S.-Soviet treaty banning medium-range missiles should be satisfied with Soviet assurances the pact covers both existing missiles and future weapons using exotic technologies, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told the committee on Monday that the Soviet position was spelled out last week in a conversation between Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. The dispute centers on the treaty signed Dec. 8 by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, eliminating nuclear missiles with a range of 300 to 3,400 miles. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration said the treaty banned both existing missiles and any `` futuristic'' weapons, such as those using lasers or beam rays, as long as the weapons had a range covered by the treaty. But critics, including members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, questioned whether the Soviets might have a different view of the treaty and suggested that the ambiguity should be cleared up. Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>'s `` unequivocal statement should allay concerns that have been raised about this subject.'' <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>'s committee sent the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> a report Monday that said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> should approve the treaty and protect its constitutional rights by blocking presidential attempts to change the way treaties are interpreted. The 515-page report sums up the panel's three months of hearings and its votes on the historic pact. The report was approved by the same 17-2 majority which recommended two weeks ago that the treaty should be ratified by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The opposition votes were cast by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, R-S. Ratification requires a vote of 67 of the 100 senators. Leaders of both parties estimate that 90 or more senators will support the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty when it finally comes to a vote. Publication of the committee report means the way is finally clear for formal consideration on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor. Republicans say the most contentious issue will likely be the Democratic-backed amendment that would bar the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from changing the interpretation of the INF treaty. The amendment, approved 12-7 by the committee, arises from a fight over the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile treaty. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has asserted that the White House can unilaterally change how the ABM pact is viewed, a move that would permit expanded `` Star Wars'' testing, but congressional Democrats dispute that claim. `` A presidential right to adopt a different interpretation of a treaty, irrespective of the understanding on which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> based its consent, would tend to nullify the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s share of the treaty power and thus undermine a basic provision of the Constitution,'' the report said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s only recourse, to prevent its share of the treaty power being nullified, would be to attach elaborate and numerous conditions to treaties in order to have the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s understanding become an integral and explicit part of the ratification documents,'' the report said. `` Such procedures could easily overburden the treaty process to the point of paralysis,'' it warned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CommunityColleges     04-19 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Community Colleges,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commission Says Community Colleges Get Short Shrift</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's community colleges meet ambivalence about their role and often `` receive the state's budget leftovers'' when they can be of great help both to their neighborhoods and the nation, an educational commission said today. `` The community college, at its best, can be a center for problem-solving in adult illiteracy or the education of the disabled,'' said a report by the <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on the Future of Community Colleges. `` It can also be the place where education and business leaders meet to talk about the problems of displaced workers. `` It can bring together agencies to strengthen services for minorities, working women, single parent heads of households and unwed teenage parents. ... The community college can take the lead in long-range planning for community development and it can serve as the focal point for improving the quality of life in the inner city.'' Community colleges enroll 43 percent of the nation's undergraduates and 51 percent of all first-time freshmen, but the schools `` encounter ambivalence in the larger community about their role and mission, and competing priorities within the college,'' the report said Such schools `` are threatened by excessive fragmentation and division'' and increasing cultural separations and racial tensions, the report said. `` We propose therefore, that the theme ` Building Communities' become the new rallying point for the community college in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> We define the term ` community' not only as a region to be served but also as a climate to be created.'' The commission was headed by <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commissioner of education and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Teaching. It conducted the study for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> and Junior Colleges. The panel said community colleges must help solve the dropout problem or minority students will continue to leave. It recommended that every college develop an aggressive outreach plan for disadvantaged students. Among other recommendations: _ An `` early warning system'' to spot and help students who are at risk of dropping out. _ Each community college should commit itself to recruiting and retaining a top-quality faculty and increase the percentage of members who are black, Hispanic and Asian. _ Careful assessment of reading, writing and mathematical ability of all first-time community college students and an intensive developmental education program for those who need it _ Completion of a core curriculum by all associate degree students
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ATVs     04-19 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ATVs,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Debates Whether Flawed Ban Is Better Than No Ban At All</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge says he must decide whether to approve a flawed consent decree regulating all-terrain vehicles or do nothing to regulate the vehicles blamed for 900 deaths in five years. `` Is it best to move in the direction of doing what one can do to reduce it as opposed to doing nothing about it?'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said after a hearing on a proposed out-of-court settlement between the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and five manufacturers. Opponents of the consent decree argued at Monday's hearing that the agreement between federal regulators and manufacturers is flawed because it does n't provide for refunds to people who purchased the vehicles, popularly known as ATVs. Lawyers for consumer groups and 32 states said the consent decree also fails to protect children from the hazards of the four-wheel machines, particularly smaller models marketed for children, which would still be sold. `` We do n't believe these child-sized ATVs should be sold at all,'' said <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, who called ATVs `` some of the most dangerous consumer products sold in this country.'' The decree would ban future sales of three-wheel ATVs unless the manufacturers devised performance standards that would be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION>. It would also require warning labels on four-wheel models and distributors would have to offer training about the safe use of the machines to owners of vehicles currently in use. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> appeared troubled by the decree's ban on further action by the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> against ATVs during the 10-year period the agreement is in effect. `` The mechanism provided by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is stymied by the consent decree,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> told a lawyer for the manufacturers. `` As I understand the decree, the agency represented here _ <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION> _ is not able to issue a rule under the statute which would be in many respects more severe'' than the sanctions imposed by the consent decree, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. `` You take the agency out of the game, you ca n't tell me with quite the same assurance the agency is going to continue to perform its function,'' the judge said. Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, who is sponsoring legislation to force manufacturers to give refunds, called that provision `` a wolf in sheep's clothing.'' The senator urged <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to modify the decree to give the agency the option of taking further action after a year or 18 months if the agreement has not led to safer use of ATVs. But <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said the agreement allows the government to avoid a lengthy court battle during which it would be difficult to prove the allegations that the ATVs are an `` imminent hazard'' as defined by the consumer protection statute. `` This is an outstanding resolution of the matter in light of the facts as they exist and the law as it exists,'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> told <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>. `` The government will get some of what it asked for, the other alternative is the government will get none of what it asked for.'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> also expressed concern about the mechanics for supervising the decree's enforcement, saying he was particularly dismayed that it empowered the <ORGANIZATION> CPSC </ORGANIZATION>'s general counsel to extend deadlines. Nevertheless, the judge said the unprecedented decree could be `` a technique that could be of great value to consumers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MarinePaint     04-19 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marine Paint,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bill Passes to Ban Common Barnacle Blocker</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has some bad news for boat owners who hate to scrape barnacles off the hull. The chamber gave voice-vote approval Monday to legislation to regulate the use of tributyltin, or <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION>, a hull paint additive that is effective against barnacles but poses dangers to other marine life. The bill would ban the use of paints containing <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION> on vessels under 82 feet in length and would impose limits on the amount of <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION> that can be released into the water from hull paint on larger vessels. The restrictions would last until the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> decides on an environmentally safe release rate for paints containing <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION>, which have been regulated by <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> because of damage to shellfish. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION> `` is without a doubt the most effective anti-fouling compound yet developed, and it can not be matched for preventing the attachment of barnacles, algae and other marine organisms that hasten the decay of wood and cause drag on boats. `` On the other hand, there is growing evidence that <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION> is extremely toxic and is affecting ` non-target' marine and freshwater organisms rather than just organisms that are trying to grow on boat hulls.'' He said <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION> produces toxic effects in some marine organisms at exposures of less than 100 parts per trillion _ `` the equivalent to one drop of water in 100,000 tanker trucks of liquid.'' <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> TBT </ORGANIZATION>'s effects on humans are not known, although high levels of the substance have been found in some chinook salmon by federal researchers. The regulatory legislation originated in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which now will be asked to consider an amendment approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FishingPorts     04-19 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fishing Ports,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scallops Make New Bedford Nation's Richest Fish Port</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, was the nation's richest fishing port last year thanks to a banner year for scallops, government and industry officials say. Other <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> fishing cities slumped because of a decrease in fin fish such as cod and haddock, and some ports around the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> suffered from problems in the shrimp industry, analysts said Monday. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> led in 1987 with catches valued at $ 143.7 million, up nearly 36 percent from $ 106 million in 1986, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The 1987 figure was a record, the agency said. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Weddig </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a trade association, attributed <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bedford </ORGANIZATION>'s big increase to strong scallop harvests and scallop price increases. <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> said scallops accounted for nearly half of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bedford </ORGANIZATION>'s total dollar value, but made up only 21 percent of the port's catch in weight Alaskan ports also enjoyed a profitable year. <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> was second to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> with catches valued at $ 132.1 million, up from $ 89.8 million, and <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harbor-Unalaska </ORGANIZATION> was up from $ 37.2 million to $ 62.7 million, <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Weddig </PERSON> said the healthy <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> industry was due to strong salmon and crab harvests and a sharp increase in exports due to the fall of the dollar overseas. Nationwide, foreign sales in 1987 were more than $ 2 billion, up from $ 1.6 billion the previous year, according to <PERSON> Weddig </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> ports suffered from falling shrimp production and prices, he said. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, led the nation for the 10th consecutive year in the amount of fish caught, <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> landings rose from 616.8 million pounds to 672.4 million pounds, bringing it nearly back to its 1985 level. The record was 848.2 million pounds landed in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> in 1960. <LOCATION> Pascagoula-Moss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, was second at 391.6 million pounds, up from 365.5 million pounds. More than two-thirds of the major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fishing ports were up in volume from last year, but nearly half had value decreases. While <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> enjoyed a robust year, most of the other major <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> fishing ports suffered declines in both volume and value, according to the <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> report. Down in both categories were <LOCATION> Gloucester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, Point <PERSON> Judith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Only <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, showed increases, largely because of the operation of the new <ORGANIZATION> Portland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Weddig </PERSON> said. He said decreases in cod, haddock and flounder, as well as the emergence of the <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> exchange, led to the decline in landings at the other <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> ports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Trade     04-19 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trade,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Lawmakers Deadlock Over Foreign Investment Plan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers are nearing final action on a sweeping, 1,000-page trade bill, still uncertain if it will contain a plan to force public disclosure by foreign investors of their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> holdings. `` If you're interested in passing a trade bill, which I am, then I think the best course of action is to drop the <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> amendment,'' Sen. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., said Monday after lawmakers failed to break a deadlock over the issue A House-Senate panel has been stalemated for more than a month over the amendment sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, which would require public disclosure of much foreign investment within the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> states. <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> said that dropping the plan would reduce the chance of a presidential veto, or if President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoes the bill anyway, increase the chance of an override. He noted there already are presidential veto threats over a separate provision that would require 60-day notice of plant closings and large-scale layoffs. The foreign ownership dispute is the last unresolved controversy in fashioning the trade bill, which <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said could come to the floor as early as Wednesday. Most of the compromise provisions were drawn up by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees before the congressional recess Easter week but they left farm items, the plant closings feature and the foreign disclosure plan until the last minute. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> told reporters he was pushing for inclusion of the <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> provision. But he added he would not seek to attach the measure to the trade bill if it would `` put its life in jeopardy.'' The speaker said that if conferees would not accept the plan `` I would be inclined to give <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> a run on its own merits'' by bringing it to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor later as a separate bill. Under the plan, foreign investors would be required to register with the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> if they owned 5 percent or more of any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> company or real estate in this country if such assets were worth at least $ 5 million. Some of this information already must be filed with the department but is not public record. That would change under <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>'s plan. Companies with a 25 percent share in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business or property with assets or annual sales of more than $ 20 million would have to disclose much of the detailed information required of corporations by the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on its 10-K form. The items range from a list of directors and officers to a financial balance sheet. Critics say the measure would reduce new capital from overseas that helps prime the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic pump; proponents say it would put a spotlight on foreign investment that could be harmful to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> interests. Most lawmakers believe the trade bill itself will clear both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> without much difficulty. The question is whether it will get the two-thirds support it would need for a veto override. Three major petroleum industry associations called on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to sign the bill because it would repeal the windfall profits tax on oil companies. `` We can not allow the stagnation of domestic oil exploration and production to continue,'' the groups said in a letter. The letter was sent by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Midcontinent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880419-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LFund     04-19 0609</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Fund,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Insurance Fund Deficit Poses No Threat To Depositors, Board Member
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
