<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HostagesFreed 6thLd-Writethru   05-04 0953</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostages Freed, 6th Ld-Writethru,a0957,0985</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three French Hostages Freed, Fly To Paris</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: LEADS with 3 grafs to UPDATE with plane stopping in Corsica.
Picks up 4th graf pvs, ``It's a ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three French hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> since 1985 were freed Wednesday and headed home, and one of them said his liberation was `` a rebirth.'' The plane carring journalist <PERSON> Jean-Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> and diplomats <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Carton </PERSON> stopped briefly in <LOCATION> Salonica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, and in <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION> on its way to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Corsica </LOCATION>, it was met by Interior Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasqua </PERSON> and a medical team. `` It's the most beautiful day of my life. There are no other words,'' <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> RTL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>, whose reporter <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Auque </PERSON> _ himself a former hostage _ was permitted to board the plane in <LOCATION> Salonica </LOCATION>. `` It's a rebirth, because for three years I wo n't say we lived, we survived,'' he said. `` It's the end of a nightmare, a nightmare that lasted three years and then some,'' Carton told <ORGANIZATION> RTL </ORGANIZATION>. `` At first we were together, then we were separated,'' he said. `` We saw other hostages, but we did not know exactly who they were.'' Wednesday's release leaves 18 foreigners, including nine Americans, missing and believed held captive in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by Moslem extremists. <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> Veyret </PERSON>, the second secretary at the <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that Carton, 62, <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, 45, and <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>, 44, were set free at 7:20 p.m. -LRB- 1:20 p.m. EDT -RRB- Wednesday near the Summerland Hotel in the seaside <LOCATION> Jnah </LOCATION> neighborhood of the Lebanese capital. There were reports in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> this week that <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> had agreed to pay <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> $ 670 million still owed to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on a billion-dollar loan made by the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON>. The French government froze payments after the 1979 Islamic revolution in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The kidnappers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> were believed to have loyalties to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON> both spoke of being blindfolded and chained. `` No longer to have a blindfold ... chains,'' <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> said. `` I would n't say we were in a tomb but, after all, it is a little like that.'' <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> said the hostages had heard little news. He did not know who was running in Sunday's second round of French presidential elections. `` I knew my wife fought for me, not only for me, but for us,'' he said. <PERSON> Joelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> made several trips to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and made frequent public appeals for the hostages' release. <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON> said, `` To have had a blindfold over your eyes, and chains on your hands and feet, that makes a change. It is the difference between night and day.'' In <LOCATION> Strasbourg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, conservative Premier <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>, who faces incumbent Socialist <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> the presidential election this Sunday, announced the men's release Wednesday at a campaign rally. `` I have been informed just now that the three French hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> were freed and have been turned over to a representative of the interior minister,'' he said. `` I am thinking of the horrible time they've been through, which they did n't deserve. ... I am thinking of the one who, alas, was the victim of these kidnappers and has not returned,'' <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> said. He was referring to <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Seurat </PERSON>, 39, who was kidnapped May 22, 1985. Islamic Jihad, a pro-Iranian Shiite Moslem group, claimed it killed him March 5, 1986. His body was not found, but his wife says <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> officials confirmed his death. A total of 10 French hostages now have been released since <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> took office in 1986. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, appearing later on national TV, expressed happiness about the release but sorrow for `` the one who did not return, <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Seurat </PERSON>, and for his family, as well as for the foreign hostages still held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.'' In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it was awaiting details of the release. `` We would be concerned by any sign that concessions were made,'' the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. `` We believe concessions encourage future kidnappings and could prolong the captivity of other hostages.'' The release followed weeks of reports that <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>'s government was working feverishly, through contacts with the Iranian government and elsewhere, to win the men's freedom. Hostage negotiations, shrouded in official secrecy, were the subject of continuing press speculation. Last December, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> expelled 17 Iranian exile opponents of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, but denied this had any connection with hostage talks. French negotiator <PERSON> Jean-Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Marchiani </PERSON>, personal representative of French Interior Minister <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasqua </PERSON>, met the freed captives at the headquarters of the Syrian army in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, embassy secretary <PERSON> Veyret </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marchiani </PERSON>, a former intelligence officer, made several trips to <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> in recent weeks. He had negotiated the freedom of two other French captives, <PERSON> Auque </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jean-Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Normandin </PERSON>, last November. In <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, Syrian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Farouk </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Sharaa </PERSON> said in a statement: `` As in the past, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> exerted efforts to ensure the release of hostages.'' <PERSON> Pasqua </PERSON> said the former hostages would be taken to a military hospital in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, the Moslem-controlled Voice of the Nation quoted a reporter at the Summerland hotel as saying the three Frenchmen were brought there in a black Mercedes that had no license plates. Carton, the embassy vice consul in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, an embassy protocol officer, had been missing since March 22, 1985. Islamic Jihad said its members kidnapped them. <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON>, a journalist working for the weekly magazine L'Envenement <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeudi </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Seurat </PERSON>, an academic researcher, were kidnapped May 22, 1985. The longest-held foreign hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 40, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was kidnapped March 16, 1985. The November release of <PERSON> Auque </PERSON> and <PERSON> Normandin </PERSON> reportedly involved <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> agreeing to let <PERSON> Wahid </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordji </PERSON>, an employee at the Iranian Embassy, leave <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gordji </PERSON> was wanted for questioning in connection with terrorist bombings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0820EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-AlohaPassengerList     05-04 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Aloha Passenger List,0505</SECOND>
<HEAD>Partial List Released of Passengers On Aloha Airlines Jet</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A partial list of the 95 people aboard <ORGANIZATION> Aloha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 243, which was blown apart last Thursday during a flight from <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, was released Tuesday by state Attorney General <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>. <PERSON> Aloha </PERSON> had repeatedly refused to release the names of the 89 passengers on board the ill-fated flight, saying it wanted to protect them from unsolicited legal advice and to protect their privacy. The names of pilot <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schornstheimer </PERSON>, co-pilot <PERSON> Mimi </PERSON> <PERSON> Tompkins </PERSON> and flight attendants <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Honda </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato-Tomita </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Clarabelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansing </PERSON>, who was killed, were released last Thursday. Price said he released the list because of media requests. It includes only the 63 people who were transported to or treated at <ORGANIZATION> Maui </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> after the plane, with 20 feet of its upper fuselage ripped off, made a safe emergency landing at <LOCATION> Kahului </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Maui </LOCATION>. The names of the 14 people from the states other than <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> are: <PERSON> Arlo </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clippinger </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Daryle </PERSON> <PERSON> Clippinger </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Monte </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreben </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calabasas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanigan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Davids </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Flanigan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Davids </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Godwin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Godwin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Citrus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> <PERSON> Cosme </PERSON> <PERSON> Mangibuyat </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wann </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Elouise </PERSON> <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Wann </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON>
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The rest from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> are: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Araki </PERSON>, <PERSON> Aiea </PERSON> <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Becklin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Branley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <PERSON> Waimanalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Carland </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pahoa </LOCATION> <PERSON> Donn </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlsmith </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Leihulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebisuzaki </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kaneohe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujimoto </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mililani </PERSON> <PERSON> Eyal </PERSON> <PERSON> Gershfeld </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Harlow </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Hilo </LOCATION> flight attendant <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Honda </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> off-duty flight attendant <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Waimanalo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mae </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kagihara </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Aiea </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaniaupio </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kaneohe </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Katayama </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kurtistown </PERSON> <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawamura </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mililani </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilgariff </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kitaoka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kaneohe </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kupihea </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Waipahu </PERSON> <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Muraoka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Helene </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagata </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Nekota </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kailua-Kona </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Ogawa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Renwick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Waipahu </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Richlie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridgway </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Damon </PERSON> <PERSON> Runyan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kailua </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Samson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> flight attendant <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato-Tomita </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kaneohe </PERSON> <PERSON> Emiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Sugino </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sugitaya </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sumida </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Tateishi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wailuku </PERSON> <PERSON> Shizuyo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tokihiro </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Toyooka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Honolulu </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wurcher </PERSON>, <PERSON> Keaau </PERSON> <PERSON> Fumiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoshina </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ewa </PERSON> <PERSON> Beach </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Syria     05-04 0867</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Syria,0894</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lebanon Action Shows Willingness To Use Military Might</HEAD>
<BYLINE>AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The army's thrust into south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> may signal a new phase in a simmering guerrilla war, one in which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> again is ready to use its military might even if it means raising tensions with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. The fact that helicopter-borne troops landed Tuesday in a village only four miles from Syrian lines in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> was likely to be viewed as a challenge by <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s initial reaction was to put its troops on alert. But there was no corresponding war of words, and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials stressed they sought to avoid a confrontation with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>. `` Our intentions are limited. We are not out there to go to war with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> but simply to control the security of our northern border settlements,'' said Col. <PERSON> Renaan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissin </PERSON>, deputy army spokesman. `` We made it very clear to the Syrians as well as the population in the area that we intend to complete this search mission and return our forces back,'' he said in an interview on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION>. The disclaimers were reinforced by the makeup of the mechanized brigade that entered <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Only a few tanks were involved, and the use of artillery was extremely limited. `` It was not a combat force,'' said one diplomat who spoke on condition of anonymity. On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers reported seeing six Israeli F-4 Phantom jets fire 30 missiles in the direction of Syrian lines in the <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> newspapers said a SAM-6 surface-to-air missile was launched, but there was no confirmation from either side. The last war of nerves with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> came in November 1985 after <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> warplanes patroling over <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> chased two <LOCATION> Syrian </LOCATION> jets into Syrian airspace and shot them down. Some observers said tensions with <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> would divert attention from the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, where the army has been fighting daily battles with rioters since Dec. 8. But Israeli officials rejected such suggestions and insisted the primary motive was to keep <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrillas from building up new bases in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> like the ones they had before <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion. `` This operation is aimed at searching for the terrorists, at trying to locate groups and weaponry, and to deliver a message to residents of the villages ... that we would not agree to an increase of hostile activity,'' said Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Peled </PERSON>, the head of the northern command. The new strike into <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> was an unusually well-publicized campaign accompanied by a stream of public statements. It seemed designed more to send a warning about <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s readiness to use the military option than it was to fulfill the declared mission of capturing guerrillas. The warning was directed at the Palestinian factions who carry out the raids, at the Syrians who provide the protective umbrella and at villagers who provide guides and shelter. There was also a hint of more to come if the infiltrations continued. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s new thrust into <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> was the army's first major ground offensive since February 1986, overcoming a reluctance to get involved in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that lingered from an unpopular three-year occupation ending in 1985. `` We will not wait to engage in defensive activity only ... and we want to initiate activity in the field which would make it harder for terrorist groups to operate,'' said <PERSON> Peled </PERSON>. The new campaign in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, like last month's assassination of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> military chief <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>, appeared designed to show off <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s military potency. Many believe such actions will help restore the army's image as a force to be reckoned with, an image that has suffered as a result of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> riots and guerrilla infiltrations. `` The message is we will get the terrorists whereever they are,'' said an army official who spoke on condition of anonymity. But to a nation suspicious of any longterm involvement in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio `` I think there is totally no danger of entanglement.'' The army was prodded to go into <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by a rebirth of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> guerrilla activity in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> had amassed a large military presence before <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion. A dozen infiltration attempts since last November have claimed 11 Israeli lives and alarmed residents living along <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s northern border They have in turn put pressure on the government to take action. There has also been a marked increase in attacks on a 2,000-man Israeli-allied Lebanese militia and the few hundred <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops permanently stationed in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. In March, there were 105 anti-Israeli operations mounted by Palestinians, Lebanese Communists and pro-Iranian Shiite Moslems, said a security official in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> who monitors the warfare. Two pro-Israeli militiamen were killed in the March fighting along with eight guerrillas. Three Israelis and 16 fighters in the Israeli-backed militia were wounded. The official said it was the highest monthly casualty count since October 1985, when there were 130 operations in which six pro-Israeli militiamen were killed and 8 others wounded.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tatro </PERSON>, bureau chief in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, has been based in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> since 1983 and served in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> since 1977.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-PanamaManeuver     05-04 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama Maneuver,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega May Have Outfoxed United States</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In its confrontation with Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> seems to have been maneuvered into an awkward position by the military strongman. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government had pledged to remove the commander of the Defense Forces, the de facto ruler of this country, from office and from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Now the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration appears to be offering <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> a deal he had hinted at more than a month ago: that he leave power, but not the country. He also wants his <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictments on drug trafficking charges invalidated. The apparent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy shift has managed to alienate opposition leaders. They now privately use the word `` incompetence'' when referring to the way the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has handled the general. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> denied on Saturday that he had reached any agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But Treasury Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said on Sunday that talks with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> continued during the weekend and that `` progress is being made.'' Initially, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> encouraged the opposition as it demanded both <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster and exile. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> imposed economic sanctions and froze Panamanian government assets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, causing a severe economic crisis in this country, where the dollar is the legal currency. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> recognized as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s legitimate president <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, a man <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> himself had picked as president and whose only merit, opposition leaders say, was that he later tried to fire the general. But <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, a military leader with the populist tactics of a Latin American politician, vowed he would not leave under pressure. He clung to power in spite of the crisis, whipping up Panamanian nationalism and the sympathy that <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nations feel for anyone who confronts the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` The gringos overestimated the opposition and underestimated <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>,'' said Maj. <PERSON> Edgardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a spokesman for the general. As late as April 16, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials were telling opposition members the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position had not changed, and that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had to leave soon. `` If they -LRB- <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> -RRB- are now offering a deal that would enable <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to stay in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, then it is a serious mistake,'' said <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` All Panamanians know that allowing <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to stay in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is not a solution,'' said <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the largest opposition party. Concerned about a possible U.S.-Noriega deal that might bypass them, the opposition parties met on Monday for the first time `` to discuss the serious crisis we are suffering.'' The opposition includes the National Civic Crusade, an umbrella organization of private, professional and labor groups that since June has mounted demonstrations against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s rule. Opposition leaders feel the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government created <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> by sustaining his 15,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and allowing him to impose and depose presidents during the past five years. `` The change in attitude on the part of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to support democratization in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> now is not the result of solidarity with our people,'' said <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>. `` It merely recognizes that its interests in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> are more compatible with the struggle for democracy than with the support of a dictatorial regime.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has insisted that the American decision to topple him was political because he refused to cooperate with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attempts to involve <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in incidents to embarrass the leftist Sandinista regime in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration supports the Nicaraguan rebels, known as Contras. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said on Saturday that he would not leave unless the `` popular forces,'' meaning the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and his political base, `` negotiate their security.'' `` He will leave on his terms now,'' said an opposition party leader, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Aides said the general also wants the economic sanctions lifted. `` <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is more concerned about lifting the economic sanctions than any discussion about his departure,'' <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. `` He is not going to resign under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure and he is not going into exile,'' he said. `` We have learned to be wary of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a country that historically had been our friend.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eloy </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>, as bureau chief for <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, has been covering the region since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-CandyBarWars Bjt   05-04 0791</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candy Bar Wars, Bjt,0815</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Bidders Target Top Two British Confectioners</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SpA is cq in 20th graf, ``The offer...''
^An AP Extra</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By COTTEN TIMBERLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s top two confectioners, <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schweppes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION> and Kit Kat-maker <ORGANIZATION> Rowntree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION>, have become tempting targets for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Swiss bidders in what the British have dubbed the candy bar wars. The bidding and stake-building reflect a trend among consumer companies to go global by acquiring existing, strong brands, which are almost prohibitively expensive to create from scratch, analysts say. The moves also reflect Swiss companies' concerns about the approach of 1992, when the Common Market is to become one barrier-free market of 320 million consumers. Because <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> is not a member, Swiss companies are eager to buy operations within the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Felicity </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, an analyst with the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> investment firm <ORGANIZATION> Hoare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Govett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd </ORGANIZATION>. The candy bar wars also underscore the key roles <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Rowntree </PERSON> play in the industry and the importance of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as a confectionery market. The two companies rank among the world's largest chocolate-makers, as do the Swiss suitors for <PERSON> Rowntree </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.A. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Jacobs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suchard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.A </ORGANIZATION>. The American company <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which said it wants to increase its stake in <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>, has interests in movie theaters and soft drink bottling. In <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> _ the third-largest chocolate consuming country in the world after <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION> has the largest share of the $ 3.9 billion chocolate market, or 30 percent, according to the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> brokerage firm <ORGANIZATION> Henderson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crosthwaite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rowntree </PERSON> comes in a second with 26 percent, and <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mars </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> is third with 24 percent, the firm said <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>'s brands also include <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> Dry soft drinks. Many Britons are not happy that two of their venerable institutions are being raided by foreigners. `` The fate of the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Rowntree </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- Yorkie bar has stirred the nation into a fit of patriotism,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said. `` The Little English lobby has been in a lather ...'' Rowntree has n't made a direct approach to the government about possible intervention, but it is discussing the matter with `` one or two people,'' a <ORGANIZATION> Rowntree </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said on Tuesday. In accordance with British practice, the spokesman was n't identified In <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>'s case, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION>, which is headquartered in <LOCATION> Chestnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, said last week that it would increase its 17.7 percent stake in the British company, possibly through a tender offer. London-based <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>, whose brands include <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s Mounds and Almond Joy candy bars, said any involvement or interference from General Cinema would be `` unwelcome, and strongly resisted.'' It was more than a year ago that <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION> first became a major shareholder in <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>, whose shares fell 15 cents to finish at $ 6.51 on <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Rowntree </PERSON>, which is based in <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, last week became the reluctant target of a hostile, $ 3.9 billion bid from <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest food company with interests in chocolate and coffee. <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION>, which has acquired almost 7 percent of <LOCATION> Rowntree </LOCATION>, offered $ 16.64 a share for the company, which rejected the bid. The offer from <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> _ whose brands include <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION>'s Crunch _ is said to be the largest by a non-British bidder for a British company. <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Vevey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, also recently reached an agreement to acquire the Buitoni SpA foods group, including its <ORGANIZATION> Perugina </ORGANIZATION> chocolates business, from <LOCATION> Italian </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedetti </PERSON>. Separately, competing suitor <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> <PERSON> Suchard </PERSON>, another Swiss company with chocolate and coffee interests, has amassed a 21 percent stake in <LOCATION> Rowntree </LOCATION>, which did n't welcome that move, either. Zurich-based <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> <PERSON> Suchard </PERSON>, which makes the triangular Toblerone chocolate bars, initially paid $ 11.78 a share for its Rowntree shares. <PERSON> Rowntree </PERSON>'s shares finished at $ 17.30, up nine cents, on Tuesday. <ORGANIZATION> Nestle </ORGANIZATION> currently has a 3 percent share and <PERSON> Suchard </PERSON>, 2 percent, of the British chocolate market. `` What it is all about is globalization of consumer products markets,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, a food analyst at <ORGANIZATION> Henderson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crosthwaite </ORGANIZATION>. `` You have the multinational companies at the moment trying to accumulate tremendous brand strength in a narrow product line, but internationally.'' <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> added: `` The scramble for shelf space is some of it and the big brands are the only ones that can get it.'' `` Satellite advertising and international travel are creating a greater homogenization,'' <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> said. `` The supermarket shelves of the world are starting to look like one another.'' Rowntree, which traces its origins back to a Quaker grocer's shop in <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, northeast <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, in the 18th century, had pre-tax profit of $ 210 million on sales of $ 2.67 billion in 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Cadbury </ORGANIZATION>, which began as a seller of tea and coffee in <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> in 1824, had pre-tax profit of $ 329 million on revenue of $ 3.8 billion last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CranbrookSchool     05-04 1229</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cranbrook School,1263</SECOND>
<HEAD>$12,000 for Prep School? Is It Worth It???
^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Convincing parents that top prep schools are `` worth'' tuitions exceeding $ 10,000 is n't always easy. But even harder are the challenges of ensuring classrooms are filled in future years with ethnically diverse students and faculty.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BLOOMFIELD HILLS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Perhaps the least of the challenges facing the private school that proclaims itself `` the pearl of the Midwest'' is explaining to parents why it's worth $ 12,000 annual tuition. The 300-acre campus of <ORGANIZATION> Cranbrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kingswood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> has the requisite prep-school luxuries: a hockey arena, bowling alleys, indoor and outdoor tennis courts where players' strokes are videotaped, and an old-time swimming hole called <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonah </PERSON>, so named because it's shaped like a whale For its 800 students, each day is an aesthetic feast _ from the tapestries and art deco light fixtures down to the very doorknobs and lunchroom chairs. These, and practically everything else, were designed or influenced by famed Finnish architect <PERSON> Eliel </PERSON> <PERSON> Saarinen </PERSON>, who lived and taught here from 1925 to his death in 1950. But just as the virtues of top private schools like this are n't just skin-deep, neither are the problems With the school-age population declining and prep school tuitions sometimes rivaling <ORGANIZATION> Ivy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> colleges, officials worry about future enrollments and are casting their recruiting nets from coast to coast. The nation's approximately 1,700 independent private schools, those not receiving tax or church funds, enroll some 600,000 students, up 9.7 percent over the last decade. But the number of students taking private school admissions tests dropped by 14 percent in the last two years, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION>. A few years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Cranbrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kingswood </ORGANIZATION> could almost fill its classes with students just from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and surrounding <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> states. Now the school recruits from as far away as southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. `` If we did n't do that kind of thing we would n't be in good shape in five years because of the demographics. The best schools are out there all the time,'' said admissions director <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Kridler </PERSON>, whose travel budget has risen from $ 500 to $ 15,000 in recent years, and who now makes routine visits to 35 cities in 17 states. Like other prep schools, <PERSON> Cranbrook </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingswood </PERSON> has constantly fought a perception of elitism. The formerly all-white, predominantly <PERSON> Episcopalian </PERSON> school is now 25 percent Jewish and 25 percent `` persons of color'' including Indians, Asian-Americans and blacks, a change due largely to aggressive minority student recruiting and a $ 15.8 million endowment that helps make sizable scholarships possible. <PERSON> Cranbrook </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingswood </PERSON> is the most expensive boarding school in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, and among the most expensive in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. But it is a bargain compared with the priciest Eastern schools. <ORGANIZATION> Leland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, is the nation's most expensive private college preparatory school, charging $ 18,500 for a year's tuition, fees, room and board. <ORGANIZATION> Cranbrook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kingswood </ORGANIZATION>, at $ 12,000, ranks 44th in the nation. Another stubborn problem is finding minority teachers. Of 90 upper-school faculty members, four are black, one is Hispanic, one is Asian-American. But such challenges seem remote at 8 a.m. as English teacher <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fayroian </PERSON> poured the coffee in his carpeted classroom for a dozen students, about half the size of most public school classes. He kicked off a discussion on the religious and moral implications of <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hesse </PERSON>'s classic `` Siddhartha'': `` Should we prepare to come to the presence of the holy on a motorcycle?'' he asked. `` What should be the relationship between technology and the holy?'' In <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Conner </PERSON>'s biology lab, nine juniors toil on a typically complex question: At what wavelengths does chlorophyll in plants absorb the most light? `` They use a college text,'' <PERSON> Conner </PERSON> said. `` And I do n't give them a whole lot of answers.'' `` Academically I've never seen anything like it,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubino </PERSON> from nearby <LOCATION> Sterling </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, whose daughter <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> is an 11th-grade day student. `` Public school kids might come home at 2:30 or 3 in the afternoon, but my daughter typically is n't home until 6 or 7 at night, and then she buries herself in the books.'' It's a school rule that the 270 boarding students must be in their rooms studying every evening Sunday through Thursday. Upon graduation, each student's name is hand-carved into the oak walls of Alumni Court. Those names include such luminaries as <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> Senator <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellsberg </PERSON>, who leaked the Pentagon Papers; poet <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Leithauser </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> editor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>. Nonetheless, schools that tout themselves as training grounds for future leaders in an increasingly diverse world simply ca n't ignore the issues of race and ethnicity any longer, said school president and acting director <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> Yet private schools remain overwhelmingly white, according to the <ORGANIZATION> NAIS </ORGANIZATION>'s own statistics. In 1986-87, independent school enrollments were 4.7 percent black, 1.8 percent Hispanic, 4.7 percent Asian-American and 0.1 percent Native American. `` I recruit in <LOCATION> Cabrini </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Kridler </PERSON>, referring to an all-black <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> housing project, `` and I go to Mexican-American neighborhoods. `` Inner city kids think we're not affordable. I talk a lot about financial aid opportunities,'' <PERSON> Kridler </PERSON> said. About 24 percent of students in the upper school, grades 9-12, get financial aid, covering two-thirds of need on average. Still, 22 students accepted last year did not enroll for money reasons. Low teacher salaries remain a source of frustration, especially for younger faculty, even though median salaries have risen $ 7,000 in five years. Nationally, beginning private school teachers make $ 12,000-19 ,000 and average salaries for all such teachers was $ 23,000, about $ 5,000 less than public school teachers Fayroian, a 25-year-old first-year teacher, earns $ 16,300. He says he is up at 4 a.m. and in bed at midnight, spending his day and evening grading papers, teaching classes and meeting with students. The salary `` can be disheartening for the amount of work we do,'' he said. Top scale at <LOCATION> Cranbrook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingswood </LOCATION> is $ 34,000, and the median is $ 25,600. There's no teacher union and no tenure. On the other hand, private school teachers generally have more freedom to choose textbooks and shape their lessons free of bureaucratic interference. At <LOCATION> Cranbrook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingswood </LOCATION>, the resulting curriculum is so rigorous many students find college easy by comparison. The school recently studied its recent graduates and found their freshman grades often improved compared with their grades at <LOCATION> Cranbrook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingswood </LOCATION>. Students who averaged 2.0 to 2.5 at the prep school averaged 2.86 as college freshmen, for example. What makes the grind worth it is the extraordinarily high probability of admission to one of the better <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> colleges. Of 190 graduates in 1987, 187 went to college, 14 as national merit finalists. Their Scholastic Aptitude Test scores averaged 1100 of a possible 1600, compared with a national average of 906. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Botvinick </PERSON>, a 17-year-old senior from <LOCATION> Bloomfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, whose public schools lead the state, nonetheless chose to come here and was recently granted early acceptance at his dream school, <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Brainard </PERSON>, a 12th grader from <LOCATION> Crosslands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, says there's no comparison between what she gets here and what she would have gotten at her hometown school `` Private schools are very stereotyped,'' she said. `` People think they're very snobby. But we're not; we come here for the education. I do n't know what my chances would have been at <ORGANIZATION> Nitro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Crosslands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0258EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Amnesty-Border     05-04 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amnesty-Border,0514</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fear, Uncertainty Remain As Amnesty Deadline Nears</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Amnesty Rush Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SHARON L. JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN YSIDRO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> has guided hundreds of illegal aliens to new jobs and new lives, escorting them through the hills and canyons dividing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. But fear has kept the 29-year-old alien smuggler from seeking a new way of life for himself as time runs out on the yearlong amnesty program. `` I do n't want to lose my money, my family, my house,'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Border </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> agent who accompanied two journalists Sunday. `` I want to know if I can make it -LRB- pass legalization requirements -RRB- or not.'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said he has documentation from three employers and has spent 15 years in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But, he said, he feared his dozens of arrests for alien smuggling would make him ineligible for amnesty and lead to his deportation. His wife and three children live in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, he said. At sunset Sunday, hundreds of illegal aliens, mainly Mexicans, gathered on the so-called Soccer Field on <LOCATION> Otay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> just north of the international border in <LOCATION> Tijuana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The site is about 12 miles south of downtown <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. Most were waiting for darkness before venturing north. Vendors hawked used clothing, coffee, beer, tostadas. Many people knew little about the immigration law. Several who believed they qualified for amnesty had n't realized the time to apply runs out midnight Wednesday. Many aliens were uncertain whether they would find work in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but they were convinced the odds were more favorable there than in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> or South or <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Some people took advantage of bilingual Agent <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Kutz </PERSON>'s unusual presence among them to press for information about the immigration law <PERSON> Kutz </PERSON>, a 12-year veteran of the border force, was amused by the attention. `` One asked me what time was the best to cross. I said, ` No hour, because I'm going to be there looking for you.' They all got a good laugh.'' `` If there is only three more days then you should give us a chance to cross tonight,'' <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, 23, a native of the Mexican state of <LOCATION> Michoacan </LOCATION>, suggested to <PERSON> Kutz </PERSON>. `` If we no find work, we'll come back -LRB- to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> -RRB- and leave you without work.'' To qualify for amnesty under the 1986 Immigration Reform and Control Act, illegal aliens must prove they have been living continuously in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> since Jan. 1, 1982. Under the law, employers face sanctions if they hire illegals without documentation. So far, the new law does n't appear to have lessened the Border Patrol's workload. Arrest figures, accepted as a measure of border traffic, dropped 30 percent last year but have steadily increased this year. In April, agents in the agency's <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> sector arrested 41,815 illegal aliens, 20 percent more than were apprehended the same month last year. In April 1986, 71,910 undocumented migrants were arrested.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Astrology     05-04 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Astrology,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>The `Pseudoscience' Remains Popular</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Reagan-Astrology</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Long before `` What's your sign?'' replaced `` Come here often?'' as a lounge lizard's opening line, people sought their fortune in the stars, planets and signs of the zodiac. Astrology assumes that the planets and stars, in some way, predict or rule the lives of humans. Soothsayers searched the skies for omens in Babylon of the 18th century B.C., but what is now known as astrology developed during the Hellenistic period from the 3rd century B.C. to the 3rd century A.D., according to the Encyclopedia Britannica. The World Book Encyclopedia says that astrological forecasts, or horoscopes, are based on four elements: the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, the planets, the zodiac _ the 12 signs that divide up the heavens and comprise an astrological year _ and 12 `` houses,'' or elements of personality associated with 12 imaginary divisions of the Earth's surface. Astrology assumes the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> is the center of the solar system. `` Newtonian physics eradicated a belief in astrology among the educated. The practice of the now pseudoscience continued among nonintellectuals in the West, gradually losing contact with its rich tradition and becoming more and more fraudulent,'' the encyclopedia says. But popular interest in astrology grew after newspapers began printing horoscopes in the 1930s. <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> is known to have consulted astrologers, as did his deputy, <PERSON> Rudolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, who was captured on a bizarre peace mission to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1941. Sir <PERSON> Ivone </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in 1941, said that <PERSON> Hess </PERSON> was `` a simple, stupid'' person whose astrologer had told him he would bring peace.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-DCPrimary 1stLd-Writethru a0875 05-04 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC Primary, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0875,350</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Updates with 70 percent in; new delegate figures, lists other
Jackson victories.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> scored a runaway victory over <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> primary Tuesday, duplicating his 1984 primary win. It was <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s first primary election victory since he won <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> in March. With about 70 percent of the vote counted, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> had 41,694 or 80.2 percent, while <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 9,215 or 17 percent. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> captured 13 of the district's 16 Democratic convention delegates with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> winning 3. The results maintained <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s strong nationwide showing among black voters; about two-thirds of the district population is black. On the Republican side, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had 3,111 or 88.5 percent; Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 279 or 6.5 percent and <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> 170 or 3.9 percent. Elections director <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> <PERSON> Fremaux </PERSON> said a light turnout resulted from a lack of campaigning and the fact that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have all but wrapped up the presidential nominations for their parties. In other balloting, Del. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-D.C. </LOCATION>, running unopposed in his party's primary. Seeking his 10th term to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> will face Republican <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> in November. <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> also ran unopposed. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spent the day in the district, doing radio interviews and speaking at a local high school. Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, an active <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backer, voted early and said it would be tough for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to win the Democratic nomination, but that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would stay in the race all the way to the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> delivered an anti-drug message to students at <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and in a WOL radio interview he supported patrols by Nation of Islam members designed to curb drug traffic at two apartment complexes. In 1984, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won all but three of the delegates on the primary ballot. The only other primary he won was <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. This year <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has won primary elections in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. He won caucuses in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage     05-04 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Committee Member Says Damaging Data Were Suppressed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> says the Democratic leadership has tried to quash a non-partisan report indicating that an increase in the minimum wage to $ 5.05 could cost up to 500,000 jobs. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Petri </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> member on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> standards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> that handled the minimum wage legislation, said Tuesday that the Democratic leadership is not interested in objective analysis `` They're just interested in ramming their bill through with brute force _ no matter who gets hurt,'' <PERSON> Petri </PERSON> said in a floor statement. The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> studied the Democratic-sponsored legislation, which would raise the minimum wage from $ 3.35 an hour to $ 5.05 an hour over the next four years. <PERSON> Petri </PERSON> said that although the <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> found the legislation could wipe out 500,000 jobs and boost inflation, `` the folks who run the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> did n't want that kind of information, and ordered it removed from the <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> report before the minority could see it.'' <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greigg </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said it followed its normal procedure of sending a copy of the report to both Rep. <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif., labor committee chairman, and Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Vt </LOCATION>., ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> `` We followed the same procedure we always do,'' said <PERSON> Greigg </PERSON>. `` A copy went to both of them simultaneously. We were baffled by the suggestion -LRB- of <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON> -RRB- that he made three requests for a copy of the report.'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is expected to take up the minimum wage bill sometime this month. The <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION>, the research arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, has disputed news reports that the agency has become politicized in issuing a report on the cost estimates of the legislation. In a letter to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> acting chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> said the budget office was `` fully responsive to the requests made of us by the committee staff and that nothing has transpired to change the non-partisan, professional conduct of our office.'' At the specific request of the staff, <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> said, the <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> provided the committee with an assessment of the possible impact of the measure on the economy. `` Our cost estimates normally provide information only on the possible budget impacts for federal, state and local governments,'' <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, committee staff director, sent a letter last Thursday to all panel members in which she said the staff requested <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> to provide a second submission `` because the first <ORGANIZATION> CBO </ORGANIZATION> cost estimate included an analysis not required by the Budget Act or House Rules for inclusion in the committee's report.'' `` This analysis has been available to any member requesting it, and the staff's action in requesting CBO to conform ... in no way constituted suppression of the analysis or improper pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0312EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S.Africa-Candidates     05-04 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S. Africa-Candidates,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nujoma Hopes To Meet With Candidates, Shultz</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-South Africa Sanctions Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 African guerrilla leader <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> is asking presidential hopefuls <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to pressure <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> into relinquishing control over <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the territory known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, said he had met with campaign managers who promised him a meeting with the two Democratic candidates within the coming week. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contender <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not responded to a similar request for a meeting, <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> said in an interview Tuesday. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>, 58, said that despite claims to the contrary, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is trying to strengthen its hold over the mineral-rich territory which it rules in defiance of a 1978 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolution calling for Namibian independence. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>, who lives in exile in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, accused South African troops of arson and bombing attacks against <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s 1.5 million residents, including the burning of 14 church-run schools last month. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has denied the charges, accusing <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> of the attacks. South African President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> paid a rare visit to the territory on April 8, and proposed increased powers for his chief representative there. The proposal would weaken the `` transitional'' government established by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in 1985 with a view to eventual independence for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has no intention whatsoever to leave <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON>. The South Africans will have to be `` forced out by the combined resistance of the Namibian people and international pressure.'' He called on the next <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration to pursue steps similar to the trade sanctions legislated by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> said he had requested a meeting with Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> but had not received any response. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official confirmed <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> had asked for a meeting, and said <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> had yet to reply. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has been criticized by conservative members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, such as Rep. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, R-Ga., for allowing <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> into the country in view of his organization's guerrilla activities and support from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> In a letter to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON> called <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> a `` terrorist and Soviet puppet.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> supports a South African pullout and an independent <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, but its contacts with <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> have been limited. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representatives are taking part in two days of talks in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> with representatives from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> on a plan for the pullout of South African forces from <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has an estimated 37,000 soldiers in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. Estimates for the South African military presence in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> range from 40,000 to 100,000. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> said he was sure <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> would protect his group's interests at the talks and press its demands for Namibian independence `` It will be a package, I am assured of this by the Angolan government,'' he said. If an agreement is worked out, <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> will stop its attacks against South African troops, he said. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> says it killed more than 90 South Africans this year, but its claims can not be verified. <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> conceded that <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> gets most of its arms and training from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and several other members of the Organization of African Unity. But he added that if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants to supply <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> with weapons, `` we will certainly accept it with great pleasure.'' <PERSON> Nujoma </PERSON> is on a three-week visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to attend several U.N.-sponsored seminars on <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and to highlight his organization's demands.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NearingTheEnd Bjt   05-04 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nearing The End, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates Mustering Forces For Final
End-Of-The-Season Push</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1988 campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> slows dramatically in coming weeks, with only a handful of primaries through the rest of May as the candidates gather strength for a final push into <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is coasting a bit after winning <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> on Tuesday, making his record 7-1 in recent primaries. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> won Tuesday's primary in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. The front-runner will campaign in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> _ the site of next week's contests _ for a day later this week before taking some time off in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Not only has <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> surged nearly 600 delegates ahead <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, his only remaining rival, but the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor is also favored to win the lion's share of the remaining eight primaries, including the biggest prize of all _ <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, with 314 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> delegates at stake. That single state, with more delegates than the other remaining states combined, will host most of the campaigning for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the next five weeks. Each candidate plans at least 10 days there. Republican nominee-to-be <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will be campaigning across the country in the coming weeks, even though he already has enough delegates to win the nomination at the GOP National Convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> in August. He will spend considerable time in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, and not to campaign against <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who technically remains in the race. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, like <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, is looking to the general election campaign when <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> will once again be the biggest electoral prize of all on Nov. 8. The next stops on the 1988 presidential trail for both parties come next Tuesday in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. The campaigns have spent little time in the states, since only 62 Democratic delegates are at stake and 37 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> ones on May 10. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> leads the polls in both. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> edge over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was 43-14 in a recent poll of likely Democratic voters. In <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, a poll taken last week put <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> at 54 percent and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> at 15 percent among registered voters. Then on May 17, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> weighs in with the first <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> primary. Once again <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is ahead in the polls, taking a 36-24 margin over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in one recent survey. Forty-five Democratic delegates will be awarded that day, as will 32 Republican slots. The next week brings <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, which holds a Democratic beauty contest primary with no delegates at stake. The delegates were allocated in a caucus system that began March 8. On the Republican side, 18 delegates are available. After a two-week pause comes the primary season finale for the Democrats. With <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> leading the way, 466 Democratic and 265 Republican delegates will be awarded that day in balloting that also includes <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Next to Super Tuesday on March 8 _ when most of the Southern and border states held primaries _ June 7 is the biggest delegate day of the 1988 primary season. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is the leader again in the polls. The latest <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Poll gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a 44-33 edge over <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> with 14 percent undecided. The final <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary day of 1988 is June 14, when <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> votes. There was to be a beauty contest on the Democratic side, but no one filed to win a place on the ballot. Sixteen delegates are at stake on the Republican side, but no major candidate filed to oppose <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. In addition to the primaries, at least eight other states and territories will be allocating <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> delegates in the next five weeks. On Friday, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> will hold its state convention to choose 20 delegates and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> will do the same on Saturday for six delegates. On May 14, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> hold either state conventions or congressional district meetings to pick Republican delegates. On May 21, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> make their <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> choices. And <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>'s June 4 state convention will pick 36 Republican delegates.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-RothCandidacy     05-04 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Roth Candidacy,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sen. Roth Announces For Re-election</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GEORGETOWN, Del. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three-term Republican Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> declared Tuesday he will seek re-election, creating an uphill battle for the winner of September's Democratic primary between Lt. Gov. S.B. Woo and civic activist <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON>. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said he already has raised about $ 800,000 toward the $ 1.2 million he estimates he'll need for the campaign, which kicked off in <LOCATION> Georgetown </LOCATION>, with similar announcements later in <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, 66, said his campaign will focus on issues important to <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> families, including the economy, job, affordable child care, a secure national defense and making sure Social Security is available for future generations. `` It's important that we continue to prepare for tomorrow. And tomorrow depends on our young people,'' <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said he has supported the war on drug abuse and stiffer penalties for drug dealers, in addition to fighting against child pornography. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> probably became best-known nationally as co-author, with Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Kemp-Roth </ORGANIZATION> multiyear tax-reduction legislation. The measure was eventually endorsed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and enacted in large part by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as a prime feature of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first-term economic program. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> was a two-term congressman when in 1970, he replaced retiring incumbent Republican Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> was re-elected in 1976 and 1982. <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> law graduate, was appointed a federal court judge in <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION> in 1985 by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The Roths have two children, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0858EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--CatDisease     05-04 0175</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cat Disease,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents of Massachusetts County Warned To Keep Cats Indoors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Veterinarians urged cat owners in <LOCATION> Berkshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> to keep their pets indoors after 25 cats became sickened, apparently by a deadly illness that may be linked to a wild bird disease. The <ORGANIZATION> Berkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in this western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> city has been treating cats for the past three weeks for an infection that evidently hit some animals after they ate wild songbirds, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON> of the hospital said Tuesday. At least three cats have died, he said. <PERSON> Kellogg </PERSON> said humans were not in danger of contracting the disease and that it did not appear to be communicated from cat to cat. Outbreaks of the disease have been reported in western <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> and parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, said Dr. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Feline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ithaca </LOCATION>, N.Y. He said the illness appeared to be related to a malady killing wild songbirds in the same areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Rainstorm     05-04 0094</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Rainstorm,0096</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rainstorm In Japan Kills Three</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A torrential rainstorm over the <LOCATION> Kyushu </LOCATION> region of southern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> caused flooding and landslides that left three people dead and three missing in <LOCATION> Kumamoto </LOCATION> state, police said today. They said <PERSON> Masue </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaitsu </PERSON>, 71, <PERSON> Satsuko </PERSON> <PERSON> Kumagai </PERSON>, 57, and <PERSON> Kaoru </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoshizumi </PERSON>, 79, all drowned during the rainstorm Tuesday night. Washed away by a flash flood and still missing were <PERSON> Yuji </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueda </PERSON>, 9; his brother <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON>, 3, and <PERSON> Haru </PERSON> <PERSON> Goto </PERSON>, 65, police reported. They said flooding from the overflowing <LOCATION> Ofuna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> also disrupted transportation in <LOCATION> Kumamoto </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArcticOil     05-04 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arctic Oil,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmentalists in House Fight To Stop Refuge Drilling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists are looking to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in their efforts to reverse a congressional tide that is running toward oil development in the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge. The focus of the biggest energy-vs. - environment battle of the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> shifted to that panel Tuesday after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved a bill to open the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> preserve to <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> drilling </ORGANIZATION> foes said he is optimistic about stopping the bill in the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, chaired by Rep. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., who opposes developing the nation's largest refuge `` It's been a friendlier committee to us traditionally,'' <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said. `` The committee is always split 50-50 on tough developmental issues. ... Our strategy is pretty simple. We believe in the just-say-no strategy.'' <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> and other anti-drilling lobbyists are trying to slow down the bill, which is similar to a measure approved narrowly earlier this year by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He said he thinks the chance of a drilling bill getting through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year are `` very low. There are a lot of people who prefer not to vote on controversial issues in an election year.'' Drilling opponents hope to stall final action until 1989 on the theory that a new administration will be less eager than the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to develop the 1.5 million acre coastal plain of the 19-million-acre refuge. <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Snodgrass </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Wilderness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> said that <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has pledged to make the coastal plain a no-development wilderness area. Drilling advocates, including <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodel </PERSON>, say the refuge's potentially rich oil deposits must be tapped as soon as possible in order to reduce the nation's growing dependence on imported petroleum. The <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved its drilling bill 28-13 after rejecting bipartisan pleas by some members that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> postpone a decision on the issue until a new president can study the matter and formulate a new national energy policy. `` This is the first positive energy step we've made since 1973,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, a principal proponent of tapping what the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the oil industry say may be a major supply of petroleum. Young was referring to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' approval of the pipeline that carries Alaskan oil from <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, the huge field about 70 miles west of the refuge boundary and the source of about 20 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> oil production. An opponent, Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, D-Mass., said the drilling legislation backed by <PERSON> Young </PERSON> and crafted by chairman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, was `` ill-conceived and ill-timed. `` The resources of the Arctic will wait, and we can await the arrival of a new president and a new energy secretary,'' said <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, predicting a bitter battle if drilling legislation reaches the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor. `` We will have a donneybrook of such dimensions that it will be recalled for some time,'' <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> predicted. The <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> bill would allow drilling to begin within 21 months of enactment. It would bar rigs from a caribou calving area and earmark federal revenue from refuge oil for national wildlife and conservation programs. The closest drilling opponents got to victory was a 23-18 vote against a plan to allow pre-leasing activities, which would take two or more years, to be carried out while the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> studied the nation's future energy needs and how they could be filled by conservation and renewable sources of energy. The foes also tried to add language to force the administration to reverse its decision to lower the auto fleet economy standard from 27.5 mpg to 26 mpg. Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, D-Wash., said that over the long term oil saved this way could equal what the refuge may contain
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0825EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-04 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0871</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tears streamed down Nazi hunter <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiesenthal </PERSON>'s face as he toured a concentration camp mock-up built for a movie about his years in death camps during World War II. Filming of `` Murderers Among Us: The <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wiesenthal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Story </ORGANIZATION>,'' which stars Academy Award-winner <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON> in the title role, began at the set outside <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> this week. The movie is based on a book of <PERSON> Wiesenthal </PERSON>'s recollections. <PERSON> Wiesenthal </PERSON>, 79, told reporters Tuesday he long resisted the idea of making a film about his life in the camps and as a tracker of Nazi war criminals after the war. `` I read every version of the script to make it accurate,'' he said. `` In four hours you can not bring everything that happened. But they are doing a fine job.'' The film is being shot entirely in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and is expected to take nine weeks to complete. The set includes barracks and a crematorium built into a limestone quarry ringed by barbed wire, guard towers and stone wall.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suspense author <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> says her new multimillion-dollar contract with <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster-Pocket Books shows mystery writers have a `` lot of readers out there.'' The contract announced Tuesday guarantees her $ 10.1 million for four novels and a book of short stories, said her literary agent, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Winick </PERSON>. By the time the fourth novel is published, the sum of $ 10.1 million will reach $ 11.6 million, depending on the earnings of the previously published books, <PERSON> Winick </PERSON> said. `` For the whole mystery field it is an acknowledgement that we do have a lot of readers out there,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, 60, who was the 1987 president of the Mystery Writers of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The first book, to be published next spring, will be `` While My Pretty One Sleeps,'' a novel of suspense set in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Schuster statement. Ms. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s most recent book, `` Weep No More My Lady,'' was on <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> best seller list for 17 weeks, the publisher said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ada </PERSON> <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Sipuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, who broke the color barrier at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> in 1948, was honored as a civil rights pioneer who led a `` peaceful desegregation'' of higher education. The <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> presented Mrs. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> with a plaque during a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> session Tuesday to mark the 40th anniversary of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s May 3, order making her the first black to attend the school. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>'s 3 -LCB- - year fight to enter the school was a `` notable example of courage and determination'' and `` a giant step toward the peaceful desegregation of higher education in the state of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. `` I am a native of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, and I have been a part of the history of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> for 40 years,'' the 64-year-old Mrs. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members. `` I'm proud of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>. I hope <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> can be proud of me.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Versions of the following items are moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WELLESLEY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Celtics </ORGANIZATION> Coach K.C. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> says he's decided to retire at the end of the season because he's not ambitious and wanted to spend more time with his family. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who led the <ORGANIZATION> Celtics </ORGANIZATION> to two <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> championships during his previous four seasons as coach, made the surprise announcement Tuesday, a day before <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> plays the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knicks </ORGANIZATION> in the third game of their best-of-five, first-round playoff series. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> leads 2-0 and can wrap it up with a victory tonight. `` It's something I wanted to do. I'd been giving it consideration since last summer,'' the 56-year-old <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said of his retirement. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said he will be succeeded by assistant coach <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>. The decision had to do with `` not being ambitious and wanting to ... win another nine titles,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said, adding that wants to spend more time with his family and play a little more golf and tennis. `` It's good for me, it's good for the family, it's good for <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who said he will become a <ORGANIZATION> Celtics </ORGANIZATION> vice president and director of player personnel.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FORT PIERCE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The mother of <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Bias </PERSON>, the basketball star who died of a cocaine overdose, told high school students it takes courage for young people to take a stand against drugs, but it's worth it. In moving appearances at three area high schools Monday, Lonise Bias told students they must learn not to cave in to peer pressure when it comes to drugs. `` Anyone can go along with the crowd. Who could stand to go alone?'' she said. `` It takes courage and character. ... You must stand up for what's right.'' Ms. Bias told students they needed to put their problems in proper perspective, and called suicide `` a permanent solution to a temporary problem.'' Her son, a <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> basketball star, died in 1986 shortly after being named the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Celtics </ORGANIZATION>' first-round draft pick.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-United-Engines     05-04 0628</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-United-Engines,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fuel Distribution May Have Been Behind Engine Failures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An inspection has found no mechanical problems with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jumbo jet that landed in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on one engine after three of its engines lost power during a flight over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, the airline says. United spokesmen refused to speculate on what caused the incident, although they say the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 has been found to be airworthy and was being flown today without passengers from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. That appeared to lend credence to a theory that the engine problems may have stemmed from a pilot error in shifting fuel among the jet's four fuel tanks. Industry and government sources, asking not to be identified by name, said Tuesday that the plane landed with three of its fuel tanks empty and not feeding three of the huge jet's engines, causing them to stop operating. During a flight, fuel routinely is transferred among the four tanks to maintain the aircraft's balance. According to these sources, more than 20,000 pounds of fuel was left in a fourth tank feeding the engine that continued to operate. The jetliner with 258 passengers and crewmembers aboard landed safely at the <LOCATION> Narita </LOCATION> airport in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> with only the one engine providing power. The pilot had reported losing the first engine at 39,000 feet about 1 hour and 15 minutes from the airport, a second engine 30 minutes later and a third engine just before landing. `` The airplane has been thoroughly inspected,'' said <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` We have not found a mechanical problem. ... The airplane is airworthy enough to ferry it back to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Franicsco </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Doughty </PERSON> refused to speculate what caused the engine problem, but said the plane had 23,500 pounds of fuel left when it landed in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> on Monday, 7,500 pounds more than the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> requires and 4,500 pounds more than the airline requires. But he said he did not know the distribution of the fuel among the jumbo jet's four tanks. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 has a maximum fuel capacity of 320,000 pounds. Other aviation and government sources said Tuesday that the fuel was in the tank that powered the engine that continued to operate, although it has yet to be determined whether the improper distribution of the fuel was caused by mechanical problem or flight crew error. `` Each of the four engines is independent and has its own fuel lines drawing from the tanks in the wing. ... You can interchange fuel from tank to tank,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jimenez </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. Such fuel transfers in the older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747-100 series aircraft are often performed manually, according to another <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> official, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Reese </PERSON>, although she said she did not know the procedure used on the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> aircraft involved in Monday's incident. Industry and government sources, speaking on the condition that they not be identified, said that a mechanical problem such as a fuel line or filter clog or malfunctioning valve might have kept the crew from transferring the fuel. Another possibility is that the flight crew shifted too much fuel into the fourth tank and was unable to transfer it back to the other tanks, said one aviation source. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> officials, the aircraft has a variety of gauges to tell the flight crew how much fuel has been burned, how much fuel remains and the fuel flow rates for each tank. The incident is being investigated by Japanese authorities, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air safety investigators also are interested in the case. <PERSON> Drucella </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, said staffers plan to talk to pilots of the plane when they return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880504-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-04-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpeedLimit Bjt   05-04 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speed Limit, Bjt,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>65 MPH Limit Has No Discernable Effect on Fatalities, DOT Chief
Says</HEAD>
