<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CigaretteSuit     04-25 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cigarette Suit,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tobacco Companies Seek Another Mistrial Following Key Ruling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL J. WAKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three tobacco companies in a cigarette liability suit will ask again for a mistrial following a judge's opinion that narrowed the claims against them, lawyers said Monday Lawyers for <ORGANIZATION> Philip </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Liggett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Lorillard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> will file papers this week for a mistrial in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarokin </PERSON>'s ruling last Thursday, said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parrish </PERSON>, a lawyer for <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Lorillard </ORGANIZATION>. The companies have sought at least four mistrials since court proceedings began Feb. 1 and twice have sought to have <PERSON> Sarokin </PERSON> removed from the case. All those efforts were unsuccessful. <PERSON> Sarokin </PERSON> last week dismissed charges brought by <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON> on behalf of his wife, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, who died of lung cancer at age 58 in 1984 after four decades of smoking the defendants' cigarettes. <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON> had charged that the companies caused his wife's death by failing to market a safer product or do enough research on smoking. Although the judge ruled there was not enough evidence to support the claims, he decided that the evidence could lead to a finding that the companies engaged in conspiracy to cover up the dangers of smoking. The companies say the jury could not decide fairly on the remaining contentions because so much evidence on the safer cigarette and research issues has been introduced. <PERSON> Sarokin </PERSON> also let stand allegations that <ORGANIZATION> Liggett </ORGANIZATION> failed to warn Mrs. <PERSON> Cipollone </PERSON> about the dangers of cigarettes, but threw out the charge against <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Lorillard </ORGANIZATION> because she did not smoke their cigarettes after 1966, when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> mandated warnings on cigarette packs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Strike     04-25 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Strike,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Construction Workers Begin Hunger Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>BY ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-seven union members began a fast Monday as part of the two-month-old strike by thousands of construction workers demanding that the government grant wage increases and better working conditions. About 4,500 construction workers belonging to four opposition labor groups have been on strike since Feb. 25. The 27 hunger strikers began their fast at the General Workers Confederation headquarters in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> and the Sandinista government's representative in talks with domestic opposition groups, called plans for the hunger strike `` a political publicity show.'' The construction workers went on strike after the leftist government decreed new wage scales and raised prices for basic staples on Feb. 14 as part of reforms intended to combat inflation, which reached 1,500 percent last year. Government officials have called the strike illegal, and Labor Minister <PERSON> Benedicto </PERSON> <PERSON> Meneses </PERSON> said only 600 workers have walked off their jobs. Monday night, the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said negotiations with the strikers had been suspended. A statement said the unions were seeking `` to return to former payment systems that were eliminated precisely because they ran against the logic of the economic reform measures.'' It called on the strikers to return to work `` with the guarantee they wo n't be the object of any reprisals.'' The strike was called by the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION>, the Autonomous Workers Central of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Confederation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> and Unity Central. They claim a membership of 100,000. There was no immediate response from the government to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s message to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Monday in which he threatened to expand the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embargo against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. But on Sunday, President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said that if the embargo continued, the Sandinistas would prohibit further shipments from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of equipment and other assistance to Nicaraguan organizations. The embargo had been set to expire April 30. It permits <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid and independent donations of supplies to `` democratic organizations,'' including newsprint and equipment for the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Jagger     04-25 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jagger,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Gets Song Copyright Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARLENE AIG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WHITE PLAINS, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lawyer for rock singer <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> said Monday that there was only the `` barest, scintilla of evidence'' that <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> ever heard a song he is accused of pirating in his 1985 hit `` Just Another Night.'' A federal court jury got the case Monday and deliberated 3 -LCB- hours before retiring for the evening. The jury listened to several tapes and reviewed <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>'s travel schedule for early 1983, when reggae musician <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s song was broadcast in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> area. Testimony showed <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> was in the area for five days in January and February of that year. Alley is suing <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>, maintaining that <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> infringed on his copyright of a song with the same name. Two alternate jurors, who were dismissed at start of deliberations, said it seemed to them that <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> had developed his song independently. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Parcher </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>'s lawyers, said the only similarity between <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON>'s song and <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s 1979 song were the title and the theme of a man spending one more night with a woman, which is `` certainly not original.'' <PERSON> Parcher </PERSON> said there was only the `` barest, barest, scintilla of evidence'' that <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> ever heard <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s song and added that his client had `` no motive to steal <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s song.'' <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Farley </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Alley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> had several mutual friends and acquaintances, and said the songs' similar choruses were `` the certain spark that made the songs memorable. If the jury decides <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> infringed upon <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s copyright, damages would be decided in a second trial unless a settlement were reached. <PERSON> Alley </PERSON>'s lawyers say <PERSON> Jagger </PERSON> netted as much as $ 6 million from the song.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-AlaskaQuake     04-25 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alaska Quake,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moderate Earthquake Shakes Gulf of Alaska</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A moderate earthquake occurred Monday in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION> reported. The tremor was centered about 350 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> and occurred at 5:48 p.m. local time -LRB- 9:48 p.m EDT. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION> earthquake monitors in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said they recorded the tremor at a preliminary magnitude of 5.6 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale. It was reported felt strongly in <LOCATION> Yakataga </LOCATION>. There was no immediate word of any damage or injuries. The Richter scale is an open-ended gauge of energy released by an earthquake as measured by ground motion recorded on a seismograph. Every increase of one number means that the ground motion is 10 times greater. A quake with a magnitude of 5 can cause considerable damage in a populated area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Elaine's 1stLd-Writethru a0654 04-25 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Elaine's, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0654,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>25 Years Of Wine, Pasta And Celebrities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf ``RSVPs had'' with 5 grafs to UPDATE with
party, picking up 4th graf ``This place...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto Staffing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL STIEG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s, whose clubby confines have provided refuge for a generation of creative minds and famous faces, celebrated its first quarter-century Monday with a celebrity bash. <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON>, the rotund proprietress who rewards loyalty and fame with choice tables, expected her `` nice, neighborhood restaurant'' to be filled with people whose names have filled gossip columns for years. For the party, the checked-cloth-covered tables were removed, the ceiling was filled with balloons, and rotating spotlights were set up outside. A crowd of onlookers watched as celebrities filed by: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Segal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumet </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawford </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Maas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eli </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, <PERSON> Iman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, <PERSON> Raquel </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiegs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Halston </PERSON>, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Southern </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosinski </PERSON>. `` The Eighth Avenue subway at rush hour is a picnic compared to this,'' said <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> in the jam-packed interior. `` These people are used to being treated like kings here. Tonight they are treated like cockroaches.'' And this was early by <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s standards: 10 p.m. `` This place is a living <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>,'' said bartender <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>. But a glitzy night of revelry is hardly what the regulars think of when they think of <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s. A comfortable tavern chockablock with posters, photos and book covers donated by its celebrated clientele, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s has evolved from a writer's and artists' hangout to a required stop in the city's see-and-be-seen circuit. Saturday night was typical: <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paloma </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>, among others. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> was there a couple of weeks ago. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> opened his cinematic valentine to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, `` <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>,'' with a scene set in <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s. He's a regular, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> said, because `` He loves to people-watch. It's comfortable, nobody bothers him, we make him what he wants.'' The food, critics love to point out, is undistinguished. It's the restaurant `` where you get the least for your money,'' according to the Zagat Restaurant Survey And its reputation, deserved or not, is that service can be rude and inattentive if you've never made the best-seller list. Even writer <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Plimpton </PERSON>, among the most loyal of regulars, said, `` I'm afraid you do n't get treated very well if you do n't have a pencil in your top pocket.'' Nevertheless, it usually fills up by 9 p.m. with stars, stargazers, yuppies and just neighborhood folks. Those at the bar can nurse $ 3.50 beers and watch the scene. In a city where formality sometimes chokes the fun out of a meal, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>'s is a relaxing, familiar retreat, its regulars say. `` It offers an ambience of camaraderie that is centered on <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> herself _ she's the den mother there,'' said author <PERSON> Gay </PERSON> <PERSON> Talese </PERSON>, adding: `` It's like a boarding house, you've got the round table, and you do n't need a reservation, if you're a friend of hers.'' If you're not, you'll sit farther back. Detractors and celebrity-watchers alike make too big a deal out of the place, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> said. `` I think a lot of people just come in to have dinner,'' she said. `` And you have a good time. A good bottle of wine, a nice plate of pasta _ I mean, that's life.'' When she plunked down $ 10,000 for the bar in 1963, she already knew some show folk, writers and artists from her days as a waitress and cafe manager in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>. `` Actually, what I did was just bring the Village uptown,'' she said. `` Then, it was barely going, a rather sleepy place up there,'' <PERSON> Plimpton </PERSON> recalled. `` Friends got their friends to go. It was just one room, very quiet, and we would play darts. `` <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> made sure it was a very informal, non-frantic atmosphere. Now it's a bit different, and more expensive.'' Overall, however, it's much the same as it was 25 years ago, said <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON>. Regulars can count on a good table, and count on her being there. `` I'm not changing it all the time,'' she said. `` I'm not going with the current trend.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Panama-Military 1stLd-Writethru a0717 04-25 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Military, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0717,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Military Move Against Noriega Planned, Envoy Says</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 11th graf pvs, bgng: ``The Reagan ...''
to UPDATE with report that U.S. sanctions to be eased.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of Panamanian dissidents is planning to undertake a military operation against strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> by the beginning of next week, an opposition leader said Monday. Ambassador <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, who has maintained his loyalty to ousted President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, told reporters the group is made up of very knowledgeable officers who have many friends in the Panamanian Defense Forces, or PDF. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> gave no details, but the group apparently is comprised of high-ranking defectors from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> who came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> shortly after <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s crisis erupted two months ago with <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s ouster. One is <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Villalaz </PERSON>, who has been living in exile in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for the past five weeks. He claimed that he and other <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> pilots flew more than 90,000 pounds of weapons from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> before he defected. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, who has refused to relinquish the embassy to a replacement envoy appointed by the new government in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, said the dissident group has set up a `` military command'' and has `` intimate knowledge'' of the Defense Forces. `` We are very confident that the military actions will have the help, the support of people within the PDF,'' <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said. `` This is an asset we never had before.'' A military coup attempt against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> last month was put down quickly. Asked why he was disclosing a planned military operation at a news conference, <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is aware that his opponents will not give up the struggle against him. He indicated that he did not believe that the disclosure would hurt the chances for the success of the plan. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said the plan is being worked out on the assumption that no assistance from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or other outside countries will be necessary. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have said for weeks that opposition to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> has been growing but that the dissident elements have been unable to agree on a plan for his ouster. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has imposed a series of economic and diplomatic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> over the past two months, and officials have become increasingly frustrated over <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ability to survive these pressures The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> quoted an unidentified <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration official as saying that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> would be relaxed `` within a week or so.'' The official said the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was considering a list of possible exemptions, including payment of utility bills and `` normal administrative fees and costs'' such as gasoline excise taxes, rental fees and airline landing fees, The Times reported in its Tuesday editions. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug smuggling charges. Some in the administration favor a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military move against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> but several proposals which have been passed on to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> have been given a hostile reception. <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON> said that among the seven new cabinet officers appointed on Sunday by <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s successor, President <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, were several with pro-Cuban leanings. At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, spokeswoman <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not view the <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> government as legitimate, and she therefore declined comment on the reshuffling. Asked about the shutoff Sunday of electricity to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy annex in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Oakley </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> does not believe embassy operations will be affected. The electricity to the annex and to the apartments of at least 45 embassy workers was cut off because of non-payment of bills. As part of an attempt to deprive Panamanian authorities of cash, the administration has ordered a ban on all payments to the government by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens and organizations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FicusOutbreak     04-25 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ficus Outbreak,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ficus Trees Growing Wild In South Florida</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ficus tree, long considered sterile, now has a way to reproduce on its own, and scientists in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> are bracing for an explosion of the lush, iron-rooted titan of the tropics. The ficus benjamina, or weeping fig, may be a finicky house plant, but it grows very large very fast in hospitable climates. Its dense crown snuff out plants below, and its notorious roots can muscle through pavement to strangle other large trees and choke pipes. Ficus had been held in check by their inability to reproduce _ until now. Tiny insects from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and tropical regions have found their way to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and are allowing the trees to pollinate the wild seeds, which are spread by birds and animals that eat the small berries. A single tree can produce millions of seeds a year. `` You get the idea it's just a rain of these things coming down all the time,'' said <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON> <PERSON> McKey </PERSON>, tropical biologist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION>, where ficus have been seen sprouting on stone walls and sidewalk cracks. Until such insects as the female fig wasp came to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, ficus could only be reproduced in plant nurseries from other cuttings. That meant the spread of ficus was limited to where property owners planted them. Most of the wild seedlings spotted so far are small, but the growth has been widespread. They have been seen dotting lawns and forests throughout <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and north to the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area. `` I think we're going to see our landscape change,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>'s subtropical research station in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION> It's too soon to tell whether they'll be mostly a suburban nuisance or begin to crowd out native vegetation in unspoiled areas, scientists say. `` They might become a pest in our nature preserves and hammocks,'' <PERSON> McKey </PERSON> said recently. `` Otherwise, the habitat is going to be in <LOCATION> suburbia </LOCATION> in our landscapes, where everything else is unnatural.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     04-25 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>Najib Urges Better Ties With United States, Confirms Rebel Victory</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> says his communist government wants better relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and would even consider accepting military aid from a nation now supporting thousands of Afghan rebels. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> also confirmed on Sunday that guerrillas fighting his Soviet-backed government had captured a garrison near the <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> border after a four-month siege. The guerrillas said the victory opened a new, direct supply route for weapons into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. In a speech to a visiting Soviet delegation and a group of private American citizens, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must stop providing military aid to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> if it wants the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to stop arming <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s demand appeared more rhetorical than practical. His army's vulnerability to attacks by Pakistani-based Afghan guerrillas would become even more pronounced if <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> lost <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s backing Expounding on a `` formula of symmetry,'' <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> suggested Soviet aid to his government continue at the same level as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. If `` there must be a cutoff of aid for the Afghan government, there must be a cutoff of all American aid to the Pakistani government,'' <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> told the two groups at the end of a week-long conference on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has agreed to start withdrawing its estimated 115,000 troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on May 15 under a U.N.-mediated agreement signed April 14 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and several other countries have been aiding the Afghan guerrillas via <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> arms the Afghan military forces. Each superpower has reseved the right to continue its assistance as long as the other one does. Throughout his address to the American and Soviet delegations, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> stressed his government's friendship with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which shares a 1,400-mile border with this central <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> nation. But he said repeatedly that his government sought friendlier ties _ and specifically private investment _ from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Talking later with reporters, he said: `` We would like good relations, politically, economically, culturally with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, even including military aid to our country to defend its sovereignty and its territorial integrity.'' Guerrilla leaders in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> said Saturday their fighters captured <PERSON> Barikot </PERSON>, base of the Afghan army's 55th brigade, on Friday. The garrison is in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s northeast <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION> province. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> confirmed that government troops evacuated the garrison but described the incident as `` a hange of position'' rather than a defeat. Later Sunday, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> attended a ceremony marking <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s April 27 communist revolution and reiterated his call for reconciliation with the rebels `` Now more than any other time, we are hopeful for peace and national reconciliation,'' he was quoted as saying by <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION>. For the guerrillas, the capture of <LOCATION> Barikot </LOCATION> would open a major weapons supply route from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s border town of <LOCATION> Arando </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s northeastern province of <LOCATION> Nuristan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION>. The guerrillas, who were not direct party to the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accord, have vowed to continue fighting until <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s government is overthrown. The Soviets intervened in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979. The Afghan president, whose robust, fleshy build gives him the appearance of a football player gone slightly to seed, flashed broad smiles and gestured expansively as he met the Soviet and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> groups for two hours at Arg Palace in the heart of <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Throughout his speech, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, who replaced another Soviet-backed Afghan leader in 1986, denounced the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for supplying the guerrillas with high-powered Stinger missiles. The Afghan government repeatedly has accused the rebels of using Stingers against civilian Afghan aircraft. The head of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> delegation, former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, defended the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` It was not the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that introduced high-tech weapons into <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> White </PERSON>, who is now president of the non-government <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` Stingers ... are terrible weapons, but their objectives are to destroy machines of war that have rained death and destruction on <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cuba-Church     04-25 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cuba-Church,0718</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cuba Accepting Church To Certain Extent</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TINA SUSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAVANA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The visit last week of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> marked the latest in a series of moves indicating greater government acceptance of religion in this communist nation. Thousands of worshipers filled cathedrals in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, for Masses celebrated by the Roman Catholic cardinal during his four-day visit. One woman, <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Padron </PERSON>, said her husband, <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON>, had been imprisoned 22 years simply for being a practicing <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>. But when asked if she was afraid to be at the <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, she said: `` Nervous? No, we are not nervous here. No, that was in the past. It's different now. The hands of the communists are easier _ not so harsh.'' <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> met with <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> on Wednesday night and, according to the cardinal, agreed to grant more visas for foreign nuns to come to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. Last month, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> authorized 19 foreign priests and an expatriate Cuban clergyman to work in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, along with the 210 priests already in the communist nation. Last year, the government allowed importation of 30,000 Bibles. And in 1986, the leadership called on citizens to respect the beliefs of churchgoers. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> now has an office of religious affairs, and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> has made no secret of the fact that he would welcome a visit by the pope. There apparently is more than one reason for this relaxation. The number of Roman Catholics has decreased to an acceptable level, by government standards. When <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> siezed power in 1959 about 85 percent of Cubans were Roman Catholics. Now Roman Catholics make up an estimated 41 percent of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s 10.2 million people. In addition, the government has realized that it's possible to be loyal both to the church and to the revolution. `` Theoretically it is possible, and in reality it also is,'' Education Minister <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> told reporters while touring <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>'s historical colonial section with <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>. Even <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> told reporters, `` All of us in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would be revolutionaries, I guess. We are the product of a revolution. I've never thought of myself as a bad Catholic for that reason.'' <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s treatment of religion began changing around 1985 after the publication of the book `` Fidel and Religion,'' by the Rev. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Christo </PERSON>, a Brazilian priest. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> told <PERSON> Christo </PERSON> he never opposed the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chuch </ORGANIZATION> as an institution _ only those `` militant Catholics ... from the rich class that supported the counterrevolution.'' He described as `` models for Communists'' the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> nuns who work in Cuban hospitals and mental asylums. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said he drummed the idea of the church's resourcefulness into <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> during their talk, and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> responded eagerly <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> welcomed the idea of having an American clergyman as a liaison between the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government and Cuban political prisoners in an attempt to get the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to accept the prisoners, the cardinal said. The two also discussed the possibility of church assistance in helping <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> obtain medical supplies unavailable on the island nation. Closer church-state relations and especially a papal visit would boost <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s image abroad. `` The church could be very very helpful in explaining to the world at large what is legitimate in the revolutionary government here in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. Government officials turned out in force to greet <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, and the cardinal indicated the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> would pay close attention to this in deciding whether <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> should be added to the <PERSON> pope </PERSON>'s future itinerary. The reaction in churches and on the street to <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s presence gave credence to the cardinal's comment that the faith in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is still solid, despite years of restrictions One elderly woman clutching rosary beads rushed up to pastor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>'s secretary, as he walked through the streets of <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> and told him what a wonderful thing the cardinal's visit was. `` No political system, no ideology, is going to be ultimately successful in driving -LRB- the faith -RRB- out,'' <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> said. `` Success could be achieved for a period of time, but the seed is there, and it keeps springing back into flower.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Italy-Fascism     04-25 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Italy-Fascism,0985</SECOND>
<HEAD>Italy Re-examining Fascist Past</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A recent series of books and articles and a sharp political debate have bared some of the darkest and most sensitive moments of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s fascist past. The treatment of Jews, the conduct of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the plight of Italian soldiers left to choose sides between the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> and the Allies all have come under scrutiny. Some of the issues are being used as fuel in current political maneuvering, particularly in the struggle between the Communists and the Socialists for dominance of the Italian left. Others have surfaced as <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s Jewish community prepares to mark the 50th anniversary of the racial laws enacted by <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>'s fascist dictatorship, which foreshadowed deportations to Nazi death camps. The controversy involving the alleged complicity in war crimes of President <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldheim </PERSON> in neighboring <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> brought a reminder that Italian as well as Nazi troops were occupying the <LOCATION> Balkans </LOCATION>. The probing has touched some raw nerves. When <PERSON> Renzo </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON>, a leading historian who wrote a highly respected biography of <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>, lectured at <ORGANIZATION> Rome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, he was heckled and harassed by leftist students. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON> recently suggested anti-fascism was mainly serving the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and should be abandoned. But other books praise Italians who fought fascism. `` We all looked at ourselves as anti-fascist and on the side of the Allies,'' says <PERSON> Furio </PERSON> <PERSON> Colombo </PERSON>, the president of <ORGANIZATION> Fiat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> lecturer who wrote the preface to the Italian edition of American historian <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuccotti </PERSON>'s book `` The Italians and the Holocaust.'' The book, published here in March by <ORGANIZATION> Mondadori </ORGANIZATION>, gives generally high marks to Italians, noting that <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> shares with <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> the merit of the highest percentage of Jews saved. But it also makes the point that Italians bear a share of guilt. More than 8,000 Jews were deported and only about 900 of them survived. `` It should n't be possible any longer to boast of the ` minimum number' of Italian Jews put to death,'' said <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> in his preface. `` Only one Italian Jew persecuted -LRB- and there were thousands -RRB- would already represent a crime serious enough to force a collective rethinking of the past.'' Any confusion about Italians coming to terms with the past can perhaps be attributed in part to the shifting loyalties that evolved as <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> became bogged down in World War II, leaving the country in a `` no man's land'' between winners and losers at the end. <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> came to power in 1922, launched an invasion of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> in 1936 and took <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> into World War II on the side of <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germany </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. He was ousted from power in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> in July 1943 after Allied forces landed in <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>. In September 1943, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> surrendered unconditionally to the Allies. In the meantime, the Germans helped <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> escape from prison and established him in a puppet regime in the north. Italian partisans captured <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> and his mistress, <PERSON> Clara </PERSON> <PERSON> Petacci </PERSON>, on April 27, 1945, shot them and hung their bodies upside down at a gasoline station near <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>. One of the bitterest quarrels to emerge has pitted Communist and <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials over whether <PERSON> Palmiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Togliatti </PERSON>, who led the Communists from 1927 until his death in 1964, had abandoned the party's founder, <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramsci </PERSON>, to fascist prison. The allegations center over whether <LOCATION> Togliatti </LOCATION>, from his exile in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, had not tried to press the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to negotiate the freedom of <PERSON> Gramsci </PERSON>, known more as a liberal thinker than the party boss. `` <LOCATION> Togliatti </LOCATION> was neither a saint nor a hero,'' said former Socialist Premier <PERSON> Bettino </PERSON> <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON>, drawing the rage of the Communist leadership. Historian <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON>'s point is that <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> is ill-served by a continued use of anti-fascism as a political reference point, as if anti-fascist meant democratic. `` I do n't say you have to forget fascism,'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` I say that today, that the use of the label anti-fascism has allowed the Communists to present themselves as the other parties. It has given them a common heritage.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON> also contends that the postwar laws forbidding re-establishment of the <ORGANIZATION> Fascist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> are anachronistic, since there is a neo-fascist party, the Italian <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, which has consistently gathered around 6 percent of the vote. The historian also told <ORGANIZATION> Milan </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Corriere </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> della </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sera </ORGANIZATION> that the `` myth'' of fascism is over, noting that <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>'s granddaughter, a budding actress, recently posed topless in an Italian men's magazine Others disagree that it's time to move on. <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, for example, said that while he may agree with <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Felice </PERSON> intellectually `` some signal still has to be given'' about the evils of fascism. The Jewish community of about 40,000 plans major commemorations this fall of the enactment of the racial laws that expelled Jews from government positions and the military and put restrictions on their work, schooling and possession of property. `` It's too soon to say let bygones be bygones,'' said <PERSON> Tullia </PERSON> <PERSON> Zevi </PERSON>, president of the Union of Italian Jewish Communities. Jewish leaders note that until 1938 the Jewish community was fully integrated in Italian society, holding important posts in the military and government and even the Fascist Party. Another a point of controversy is whether <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Pius </PERSON> <PERSON> XII </PERSON> did all he could to save the Jews. The <PERSON> Zuccotti </PERSON> book praises the efforts of individual priests to protect Italian Jews. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>, which has repeatedly defended the efforts of the pope, on April 13 ran excerpts in its daily newspaper from a new book by a German historian contesting allegations against <PERSON> Pius </PERSON> <PERSON> XII </PERSON>. The newspaper, <PERSON> L'Osservatore </PERSON> <PERSON> Romano </PERSON>, called it a `` vibrant and direct response to the denigrators of the pontiff.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Soviet-Golf     04-25 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Soviet-Golf,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ground Broken For First Soviet Golf Course</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first golf course is being built in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. As a group of Swedish diplomats and area residents looked on Saturday, a bulldozer began work on the course near the Swedish Embassy in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. The project is a joint venture of the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a group of Swedish companies and will be finished in the fall, the news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said. The course apparently will be off limits initially to most Soviets, to whom the sport is alien. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said embassy workers and foreign businessmen in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> will use the course and that a golf school will be built for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nightline     04-25 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nightline,0424</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC's `Nightline' Begins Week Of Shows From Jerusalem</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Nightline'' tonight begins a week of shows live from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, including a three-hour panel discussion in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> before an audience of 700 Israelis and Palestinians. `` Good Lord only knows'' how the live discussion will turn out, said `` Nightline'' anchor <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>, who has done shows in previous years from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. `` This just seemed like one of those subjects that is so rich and meaty it really ca n't be covered in an hour or two over here, so we're going to spend a week over there,'' said <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> before leaving for <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> from which most of the shows will be broadcast. Monday night's one-hour broadcast will feature an interview with <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, as well as other guests not yet lined up as of this weekend. Likewise, guests for the `` town hall meeting'' on Tuesday had not been determined. <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> said participants would include Israelis and Palestinians, though selection of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> representatives was difficult because Israeli government officials will not participate if there's anyone sympathetic to the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> involved. The trip was planned last year, <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> said, before the recent violence on the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> prompted new interest in the conflict between <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> and Israelis. `` What we're trying to do is make it clearer to an American audience what the different positions are and also make it clear what you're dealing with is not a homogenous Israeli point of view or for that matter a homogenous Palestinian point of view. There are shadings,'' said <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON>. `` Part of what we're going to try to do out there, and I'd say probably the most important thing we going to try to do is provide a context that critics of television, I think quite correctly, have suggested we have not been providing over the past couple of years.'' The rest of the week's schedule was not set, though <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> said he hoped to interview King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>. That show would originate from <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. As far going to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> itself, <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> said, `` I'm sure I'll be taking a few field trips.'' <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> said officials in the region had been cooperative so far, but he added: `` I've spent too much time in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to take anything for granted. I'll find out when I get on the air.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Shultz 1stLd-Writethru   04-25 0428</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shultz, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0717,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shultz Leaves Soviet Union</HEAD>
<HEAD>PRECEDE, Moscow</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with Shultz in Tblisi, Kiev; picks up 4th
pvs: Shultz and ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TBLISI, USSR (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> attended religious services in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Sunday, extolling the `` spread and acceptance of faith'' in a subtle jab at this nation's institutionalized atheism <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> flew out of <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION>, the capital of the southern Soviet republic of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Caucasus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, after a day of sightseeing. He headed for <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, to brief members of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> on his talks in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Thursday and Friday with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. Before he left, in <LOCATION> Tblisi </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION>, he delivered an overt message on religious freedom, attending the Georgian Orthodox Cathedral here Sunday and <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sophia </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION> on Saturday. Even at a lavish lunch here with dozens of writers, singers and artists, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> went out of his way in a toast to say: `` I could feel, in a sense, I was in the presence of the Creator.'' In <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> also visited <PERSON> Babi </PERSON> <PERSON> Yar </PERSON>, the Nazi killing ground in World War II, where tens of thousands of Jews and other Ukrainians were slaughtered. `` We have to say to ourselves always, never again,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> vowed. In <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sophia </LOCATION>'s, a cathedral that <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> authorities have converted into a museum, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said the majestic building `` just shows you the commitment of and power of religion.'' In an evolving human rights policy, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has kept up <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure on the Soviets to expand Jewish emigration while pressing for more freedom of religious practices for all citizens. <LOCATION> Tblisi </LOCATION>, a relatively relaxed city far from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, has functioning churches and even two jewish synagogues. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, addressing the patriarch, <PERSON> Iliya </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, and the congregants who jammed the small cathedral, said he understood their desire for `` progress in belief, in religion.'' `` ` You must be meaning progress in the spread and acceptance of faith because it has an immense continuity,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said, `` It could n't be more evident them being here in this church.'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> reported little progress in the talks, which focused on a treaty that would halve <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet arsenals of strategic nuclear weapons. The goal had been to complete the treaty by May 29 when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> journeys to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for a summit meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. But officials have expressed doubt the pact will be ready by then because too many disagreements remain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-25 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0579</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KEWANEE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> does n't know what the 12,000-pound acorn-shaped piece of iron is, but he likes it. Workers from <ORGANIZATION> Ratliff </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> were clearing a site for a restaurant in <LOCATION> Abingdon </LOCATION> when they dug up the massive object buried about a foot underground. His workers hauled it back to <LOCATION> Kewanee </LOCATION>, thinking the iron might be worth several hundred dollars. But <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> says the mystery object has brought him so much attention he wo n't scrap it. Now, <LOCATION> Kewanee </LOCATION> is abuzz as folks in this town of 14,500 try to figure out what it is. `` At first we were worried it was a bomb,'' said <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON>, 68, who has unearthed many strange things in his 46 years in the construction business. <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> bomb specialists examined the find Tuesday and determined it was n't a bomb. But that was all they could say. `` Everyone in town is plotting and scheming to explain what this thing is,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Bialowbreski </PERSON>, a truck dispatcher at <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON>'s. `` There is no way it's a wrecking ball because it's too heavy and there's no way to hook on to it.'' <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> ran his hand along the rusted exterior of the object as it sat Friday in the rear of his company's yard. `` Whatever it is, it sure was made nice,'' he said. Some <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> workers think the 3-by-5-foot hunk of iron is an old bank safe. Retiree <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Cinnamon </PERSON> speculated that the thing was a weight used to anchor something huge _ a blimp or a crane; farmer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Betts </PERSON> theorized it's the base for a flagpole. <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> and some of his friends have tried, with no success, to drill into the object. With the mystery unsolved, <PERSON> Ratliff </PERSON> is considering sandblasting the knob, painting it and using it to mark the entrance to his business. `` Maybe it would become a tourist attraction,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was a clash of wits in the tradition of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, the Founding Fathers and the <ORGANIZATION> Ivy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. In the end, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> emerged as winners. Teams from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> took sides in the final round of the National Debate Championships on whether to abolish the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> senior <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, taking his role of prime minister for a make-believe Her Majesty's Government quite seriously, denounced the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as `` fundamentally undemocratic.'' He called it a rich man's club that slows the legislative process and unfairly shifts power to small states. His partner, <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, pressed the attack, questioning the purpose of creating a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with two houses _ the 200-year-old compromise between large states like <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and small ones like <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. `` Why should an artificial boundary like a state have a voice, Mr. <PERSON> Speaker </PERSON>? People should have a voice,'' insisted <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Grumet </PERSON>, speaking for Her Majesty's Loyal Opposition, countered that `` all political boundaries are artificial. Except for rivers, there's nothing separating us from <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. I do n't want to share things with <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>.'' Swayed by this nationalism, traditionalism, federalism _ or the <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> team's more humorous heckles _ the audience declared the Opposition team the winners Saturday by a 2-1 margin. About 50 two-student teams competed at the two-day tournament at <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliamentary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Debate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-25 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1002</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>'s condition is improving and the actor has been moved out of intensive care following last week's quintuple heart bypass surgery, hospital officials said `` He is really doing quite well,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Correia </PERSON> said Sunday. <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>, who won an Emmy for `` The Rockford Files'' television series, underwent five hours of surgery Thursday. Doctors had planned to perform surgery for an aneurysm on his aorta, the main artery carrying blood from the heart, but tests determined he needed the bypass. Surgery for the aneurysm will be scheduled later, hospital officials said. <PERSON> Garner </PERSON>, 60, blamed his heart problems on cigarettes. `` He said he regretted having smoked for 45 years,'' said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Gless </PERSON>, whose cop character on TV's `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>'' sunk into alcoholism last season, checked into a drug and alcohol rehabilitation center two weeks ago, according to People magazine. <PERSON> Gless </PERSON>' publicist would not confirm the report that the two-time Emmy winner entered the <ORGANIZATION> Hazelden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Center </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, the magazine said in its current edition. The publicist, whom People did not identify, confined comment to a statement from <PERSON> Gless </PERSON>: `` Everything from my personal life to my metaphysical beliefs have been speculated on and made cheap. I continue to maintain the position I've held for some time _ I'll not comment on my personal life for the press,'' said the statement. A spokesman for the series refused to comment, People said. CBS has yet to renew the show.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the second time in six months, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> displayed its Scandinavian colors for monarchs from the old country, treating <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvia </PERSON> to a day of pomp and praise. `` We celebrate the fabric of friendship between the two countries. Nowhere is the fabric tighter than in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mari </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, a member of the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> organizing committee, said Sunday. The couple's 18-day American tour, to conclude Wednesday at <LOCATION> Disneyland </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, highlights `` New Sweden'88,'' a year of events marking the 350th anniversary of the first Swedish colony in the New World. <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, with its many residents of Scandinavian descent, was host to <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s King Olav last November.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sleep gave way to shopping when Soviet prima ballerina <PERSON> Maya </PERSON> <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> had time to kill between performances here with the Bolshoi Ballet. `` After all, sleep is kind of boring, is n't it?'' the 62-year-old Ms. <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> asked with the help of an interpreter Saturday. `` We've been everywhere. I've bought a lot of presents for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.'' She spent a day buying shoes, accumulating nine pairs by day's end, according to one of her hosts Ms. <PERSON> Plisetskaya </PERSON> was one of 16 dancers of the famed ballet to visit <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> at the invitation of the Pacific Ballet Theater. They played to sold-out houses in a series of performances last week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SHANGHAI, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Evangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> says religion could aid <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s communist government in its modernization drive. `` Even secular leaders are asking the question, ` Where are we to find the moral renewal we need to be successful in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s modernization program? Could they turn to us?'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> asked about 100 <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> pastors and church leaders Sunday. The 69-year-old Southern Baptist minister preached through an interpreter to nearly 5,000 Christians who packed three churches in this sprawling port city. The sermons are part of <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>'s first-ever <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> tour
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Politician-turned-playwright <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> says he paid $ 2.26 million for a 60-percent share in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s newest theater, the Playhouse. `` I could have invested in an office block but I shall get much more pleasure out of this,'' the former deputy chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> said he hopes to buy the remaining 40 percent of the 800-seat theater, which reopened in October after a $ 3.79 million facelift. <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, 47, wrote the play `` Beyond Reasonable Doubt'' last July while waiting for the courts to hear a libel case he brought against <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> newspaper for stories alleging he had a sexual liaison with a prostitute. He won a record $ 800,000 in damages, which he later donated to more than 70 charities, universities, institutions and individuals.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON> says he has a method for reading should-read books _ those books considered important or written by an acquaintance _ as opposed to those he really wants to read. <PERSON> Vonnegut </PERSON>, author of `` Slaughterhouse-Five,'' `` Cat's Cradle'' and `` Bluebeard,'' said he dips into a few pages or chapters of such a book, puts it down, reads another book and eventually returns to the first one, which he refers to as a `` conscience book.'' For those books he really wants to read, his pattern is to consume them from beginning to end. If he discovers such a book does n't really interest him after all, he quits, feeling no obligation to finish it, he said. `` I assume people do the same to my books,'' he said in an interview in the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> Sunday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Television's <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> received a lifetime achievement award for his work with young viewers. <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, creator of public television's `` Mister <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' Neighborhood'' children's show, was among a group of 19 winners of awards by the <ORGANIZATION> Dolores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kohl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> Others included teachers from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> who will receive $ 1,000 each. The awards presented Sunday are designed to focus international attention on outstanding teachers for `` their innovative teaching methods, commitment, sensitivity and courage,'' the suburban Wilmette-based foundation said in a statement. The organization, founded in 1972, has teaching centers in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0204EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Spain-Cocaine     04-25 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Spain-Cocaine,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spanish Police Seize 1,235 Pounds Of Cocaine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BARCELONA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police confiscated 1,235 pounds of cocaine and arrested two people, including a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen, an official said. The cocaine was found in 19 bags on a beach near <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION>, and police suspect it was dropped there on Saturday by a ship sighted off the coast earlier in the day, said <ORGANIZATION> Barcelona </ORGANIZATION> civil governor <PERSON> Ferrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reginaldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaco </PERSON>, a Cuban-born <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen, and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Arrarate </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> were arrested in connection with the confiscation, <PERSON> Cardenal </PERSON> said on Sunday. No charges were immediately filed against them, and authorities did not release an address in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for <LOCATION> Blaco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Cardenal </PERSON> said the cocaine _ found in <LOCATION> Vilanova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Y </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Geltru </LOCATION>, 30 miles south of <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION> _ represented one of the largest amounts of the drug ever seized in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He did not estimate the cocaine's street value
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Veep-Shopping Bjt   04-25 0928</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veep-Shopping, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Talk Turns To Running Mates, And Boosters Come
Forward</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s spokesman suggests that there is `` something really unseemly'' about efforts to promote this or that person as the ideal vice presidential candidate. Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is even more blunt. `` The nominee makes that decision,'' he says. But the people who are promoting various running mates as the only real hope for the Republican or Democratic ticket in the fall are not easily discouraged. To begin with, they tend to be people who thought neither <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had a chance of surviving the primary season. Depending on their place on the political spectrum, they spent much of the past year dreaming that <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> or <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON> would bring some excitement to the presidential race. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was saddled with the `` wimp factor,'' with Iran-Contra and his unwillingness to talk about where he differed with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. He was giving new definition to the phrase `` loyal to a fault.'' And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>? Was the country ready to turn from <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to the governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, the state that is a national symbol of liberalism? And talk about dull _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> often seemed to put himself asleep. Despite the skeptics, here they are _ as close to a sure thing as you get in American politics. The <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary on Tuesday should give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the 1,139 delegates he needs to claim a majority at the Republican National Convention next August in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. That same primary should give <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> a fourth straight primary victory and convince most of the remaining doubters that the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor will be the candidate chosen in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in July to recapture the White House for the Democrats. But the skeptics still doubt either man can win in November without considerable help from a carefully chosen running mate. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has a perceived problem of geography. Not since 1976, when Georgian <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was at the top of the ticket, has a Democratic presidential candidate carried the South. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> carried 10 of 11 Southern states in 1976, but four years later lost 10 of 11 states in the region to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. This year, conventional wisdom is the Democrats need to carry the South. Southern legislators came up with the dubious idea of a Southern regional primary as the way to ensure that the party would pick somebody acceptable to the South. But the big winners on Super Tuesday were <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, the favorite of the white Southern establishment, also did well but never could win a major state outside the region. To bolster his Southern strength, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is being urged to choose from a small group of <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> senators _ <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> or <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> is viewed as the party's most impressive spokesman on national security issues, an area where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is seen as potentially vulnerable. But on domestic policy <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> is a Reagan Democrat. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> have more basic credentials _ each comes from a state that is high on the Democrats' short list of those their nominee must carry in November. Neither <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor his party has to worry as much about geography. After all, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is from practically everywhere _ claiming ties with <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, where he was born; <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, where he grew up; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where he now has a home; and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> where he has a home and a burial plot. In obvious contrast to the Democrats, the Republicans have been looking unbeatable in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in recent presidential elections. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> makes a lot of Republicans nervous. Some think he's a weak candidate; others find him ideologically suspect. The party's conservative wing wants a signal from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that he is a loyal conservative who wo n't ditch the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> agenda if he becomes president. What they now view as the clearest signal would be the choice of one of their own as his running mate. Few people set conservative hearts aflutter like <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, the hardline former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador. So now comes <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinkscales </PERSON>, a conservative activist, who has formed an unauthorized committee to draft Mrs. <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> ticket _ an effort the former ambassador disavowed through a spokesman. `` She believes the decision on the vice president should be solely that of Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Salter </PERSON>. Nor was it encouraged by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeley </PERSON>, spokesman for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` These efforts are sometimes embarrassing to the people that they're allegedly designed to help,'' he said. `` There's just something really unseemly about trying to force somebody onto a ticket ... to throw them forward in an effort they have n't sanctioned themselves. About the only politician who regularly campaigns for the vice presidential nomination is <PERSON> Endicott </PERSON> <PERSON> Peabody </PERSON>, the former governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> who now resides in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. However, Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, who was a conservative favorite in the early stages of this year's presidential campaign, now is coming as closed to <LOCATION> Peabody </LOCATION> as he can get. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> denies he's running for the vice presidency, but makes no secret that he'd love to have the job. `` Anybody in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would have to look upon the vice presidency with interest,'' he said. `` But _ and it was a very large but _ I said I do n't expect it.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothberg </PERSON> is the chief political writer for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietEconomy Bjt   04-25 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Economy, Bjt,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Has Work Cut Out Improving Soviet Economy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is facing serious obstacles in his effort to overhaul the troubled, inefficient Soviet economy and things are n't likely to improve anytime soon, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence agencies. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s ambitious program to create a modern, more dynamic Soviet economy ran into trouble in 1987,'' says a joint study by the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. `` The short-term outlook for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic program is not good,'' concluded the study, which was released Sunday by the congressional <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` The real loser in 1987 appeared to be the consumer, who _ now three years into <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic program _ has seen almost no increase in his standard of living,'' the study said. The main problems last year were poor weather and resistance to change in the huge, slow-moving Soviet bureaucracy, said the report. As a result, the Soviet gross national product grew only 0.5 percent last year, compared with a 3.9 percent increase in 1986, which was the first full year of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s term. The gross national product is the total value of all goods and services produced and is a key measure of an economy. By contrast, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> GNP grew by 2.9 percent in both 1986 and 1987, but the American economy is much larger and exact comparisons are difficult to make. Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the study shows `` the Soviet economy did not pause last year, it stumbled This does not mean that the reform program is necessarily doomed or that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will be ousted.'' `` It is still too soon to pass judgment on the reforms or on <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s leadership,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said. The study predicted that unless <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> can turn things around, he faces trouble. `` Tension within society and the leadership will increase,'' it said. `` Bureaucrats will become increasingly frustrated by loss of privileges and status and by demands that they show greater initiative. Military leaders are likely to become more and more uneasy if benefits from the industrial modernization fail to materialize. `` Soviet citizens will need to see some improvement in living standards if the regime is to achieve necessary gains in worker productivity and avoid widespread discontent,'' the study said. `` Failure to head off these tensions would, at a minimum, make it more difficult to pursue his economic program vigorously and could ultimately call into question his strong political position at home,'' the study said. The study was presented April 13. The <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> released a declassified version. When <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took over in March 1985, the study noted, he inherited an aging, backward, extremely inefficient economy. He made reform a top priority. Last year's problems were caused by a combination of factors, the study said. `` Familiar problems with poor weather and transportation bottlenecks were compounded by the disruptions caused by the introduction of economic reforms,'' it said. Agricultural output fell because of bad weather. Industrial quality control measures also `` proved to be particularly disruptive, especially early in the year.'' Thus, industry only grew 1.5 percent and the civilian machine-building sector did n't grow at all
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ArchMoore Bjt   04-25 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arch Moore, Bjt,0777</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biggest Opponent Of West Virginia's Governor Is His Self-Created
Image</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CN2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By A.V. GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Arch </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> is finding that perhaps his toughest opponent in his re-election bid is the image he helped create for himself. The almost mythical <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> benefited from an influx of federal funds and a healthy economy as he opened highways, constructed buildings and created jobs during his first two terms from 1969 to 1977. But he has been criticized during his third term as skippering a rudderless ship awash in financial problems that the captain can not or will not control. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 65, faces his first serious political challenge in May 10's <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary in which he is seeking an unprecedented fourth term. His opponent, <LOCATION> Morgantown </LOCATION> businessman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Raese </PERSON>, is an aggressive campaigner who has capitalized on the state's woes. `` Everybody changes as they mature,'' former state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Strange </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` I think the real changes are the circumstances and conditions in which he's operating. `` Number one, he does n't have the money that was available either through federal funding or the state's economy. And secondly, he does n't have the team of department heads and advisers he had in the first eight years.'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s administrative abilities have drawn the most fire. Even administration officials concede that when <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> was returned to office in 1984, people expected a miracle turnaround that <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has been unable to produce. The governor can point to a record of hard work, a gradual reduction in the unemployment rate and increased industrial development, but the days of major announcements have ended. A spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, for instance, says the state has lost 36 major plants between 1979 and 1986, idling 4,450 workers, and said 28,000 manufacturing jobs were lost in the plants that remain open. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s first two terms were marked by a burgeoning economy. Federal money poured into the state, and <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> took the credit. He seemed to be everywhere at once, opening 225 miles of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s 515 miles of interstate highway, overseeing construction of the state Science and Cultural Center on the Capitol grounds, and luring new businesses. The myth of the all-knowing, all-seeing leader is one that he helped cultivate in a state where registered Democrats outnumber Republicans 2-1. Even a 1976 federal extortion indictment did not slow him. On the day he was indicted, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> called a news conference to announce he would seek a third consecutive term, although the state constitution appeared to prohibit it. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> was acquitted, but the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> barred his re-election bid. He left what he said was a $ 234 million budget surplus, a booming interstate highway building program and reasonably strong coal, steel and glass industries. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> opened a law practice and ran unsuccessfully for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1978 and governor in 1980. When <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> again entered the governor's office for an unprecedented third term in 1985, he found the state in much different shape. The unemployment rate hit 18 percent the year before as the state's economy hit rock-bottom. The state faced a $ 250 million debt in the unemployment compensation fund that had been run up by Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>. The Legislature had enacted huge tax increases. And federal funding for highway construction and other projects dwindled. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> asked the Legislature for a myriad of economic tools to attract business, and later claimed success. He says he has attracted more than $ 1 billion in development money during each of the past two years, and that the unemployment rate dropped below 11 percent in 1987. Critics, however, scoffed at his economic announcements, saying thousands have fled seeking jobs elsewhere. A <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> study found the state lost 52,600 of its 1.9 million residents since 1980. Raese, a newspaper publisher and coal and limestone company owner, calls himself a conservative, pro-business candidate. He says <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has failed to adjust spending to the state's dwindling tax income. `` Arch <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> is just a credit card governor,'' <PERSON> Raese </PERSON> said during a recent interview. `` He's marching to an old liberal tune of the late 1950s and early 1960s.'' According to a poll released today, <PERSON> Raese </PERSON> holds a substantial lead over <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> among Republicans and independents, 54 percent to 30 percent. Sixty-nine percent of the Republicans surveyed rated <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s performance as governor as poor or fair. The poll, conducted by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Charleston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mail </ORGANIZATION> and WSAZ-TV, had a margin of error of 4.4 percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Drugs     04-25 0092</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Drugs,0094</SECOND>
<HEAD>All Government Workers To Undergo Drug Tests In Malaysia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's 870,000 government workers will be forced to undergo urine tests for drug abuse, an official said today. <PERSON> Yusof </PERSON> <PERSON> Noor </PERSON>, a government minister, told reporters that people applying for 185,000 vacant government positions also will be tested. There are an estimated 500,000 drug addicts in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> out of a population of 16.5 million. Officials said they did not believe drug addiction is common among government workers and that the testing was merely a precaution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AcidRain     04-25 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Acid Rain,0403</SECOND>
<HEAD>Acid Rain Threatens Northeast Coastal Waters</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists have concluded that acid rain is one of the main pollutants threatening marine life in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coastal waters, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Monday. Up to now, most experts have assumed that agricultural runoff and sewage were the major culprits responsible for the increasing number of mass killings of marine life along the <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> coast </LOCATION>, the newspaper said. But a new report prepared by scientists of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, a nonprofit environmental group, shows for the first time that acid rain is also contributing to the problem, according to the newspaper. Acid rain comes from nitrogen oxides in emissions from automobiles, power plants and other industries. The oxides are converted into nitric acids and nitrates in the atmosphere. Nitrate salts and other nutrients encourage the growth of algae, which in turn use up oxygen needed by other plants and animals living in the coastal waters, according to the report. `` It is choking off the ocean's nurseries,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON>, an atmospheric physicist for the environmental group and a co-author of the report. `` It is shutting down the playground for millions of Americans.' `` It is a regionwide problem, and it is only going to get worse because of the projected growth of nitrogen emissions,'' he added. The study focuses on <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and its tributaries and found that atmospheric sources account for 25 percent of the nitrogen pouring into the bay each year. Fertilizers account for 34 percent, sewage and other industrial discharges 23 percent, and animal wastes, including runoff from land and evaporated ammonium from manure that travels through the atmosphere, 18 percent. If current trends continue, atmospheric nitrates will constitute 42 percent of annual nitrogen deposits into the bay by the year 2030, according to the report. The conclusion of the report was endorsed by other scientists who have read drafts of it, including <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, an ecologist with the <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Stony </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, according to the Times. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hidy </PERSON>, director of the environment division of the <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> _ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> a </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> utility </ORGANIZATION> companies that emit large amounts of sulfur and nitrogen from their plants _ called the report's findings `` an interesting and surprising hypothesis that needs to be verified.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VietnamMovies     04-25 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam Movies,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Vet Collects 8mm Home Movies Of The War</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NA1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDEL HUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON> has seen the Vietnam War twice: first-hand as a gunner on a helicopter, and through fleeting images captured by soldiers on 8mm home movie film. <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON>, 38, estimates he has collected 1,000 hours of amateur footage during the last decade. Some of it is entertaining and some is boring but little is gory. All of it helps neutralize the nightmare of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON> says. He has pieced together some of his best footage in a 90-minute videocassette being test marketed in the <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> area. The tape, `` Helicopter Gunship Assault,'' is the first of what <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON> hopes will be a series of at least six tapes. `` In 90 percent of the film, it's unknown to me who took it or where it was taken,'' he said. `` But still, everybody wanted to watch it because what a soldier would take a picture of over there just to show mom was not what they were showing on the news.'' To <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON>, who spent seven months behind a machine gun aboard an Army helicopter, the film `` is the best therapy I ever had. It's like reliving a nightmare If you relive it long enough, it's not a nightmare anymore. I've watched this 300 times, and I'm never bored. `` ` Nam was such a hard story for everybody to tell people back home about,'' he said. `` This makes the memories bubble out of you.'' Some footage shows soldiers escaping the war on a muggy day by landing their helicopters on a riverbank and taking a swim. Another scene shows helicopters dropping down to rescue patrols under attack. There are scenes of helicopter gunships firing at ground targets and receiving return fire. Most of the footage is remarkably intact after 20 years; little of the color has faded. One pilot shows the hut he made from scrap wood and discarded rocket boxes after his tent rotted through. Another narrates as a dog yaps in the background. `` If you watch over to the left, you'll see the tracers coming up at us,'' he says. `` There they are.'' <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON> says he has come across few gory scenes. `` I have some helicopter accidents,'' he says. `` I got aftermath of an ambush. But actual combat footage, I do n't have much,'' he said. `` Soldiers were paid to keep their heads down.'' <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> was the first war in which soldiers could carry a lightweight camera with automatic shutter control and focusing capability. Still, <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON> says very little 8mm footage was shot in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. His first three reels were purchased for $ 1 each at a flea market. `` They were very boring,'' he said. `` I wanted at one time to collect photographs _ I lost my own collection,'' he said. `` And everyone has photos. But the 8mm stuff is real rare.'' So he started placing ads in local papers and national publications asking veterans to send him their film. He then transferred the film to VHS tape, returning one tape and the original film to the owner, and keeping a copy for himself. When possible, he got the soldiers to send an audio cassette narrative. <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON>, who formed a company called `` <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>,'' has the owner sign an agreement giving him rights to the film. `` I promise to give them a royalty on each cassette,'' he said. He hopes to place his videos in libraries. `` I'm no <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Wiese </PERSON>. `` My intention is a real simple one: to collect this film and save it. I think some of it is worth being preserved. `` And it's great to get a bunch of guys together and sit down and watch this. You just ca n't believe the lies these guy will tell from their war stories.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ColorsShooting     04-25 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colors Shooting,0252</SECOND>
<HEAD>1 Dead, 1 Injured Aftter Shooting At Gang Movie Showing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKTON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young man was shot to death Sunday in a gang-related scuffle as he stood in line for the movie `` Colors,'' police said. A 17-year-old was suffered minor injuries outside the Regency Cinema when the bullet passed through the 19-year-old's head and hit her, said Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wim </PERSON>. `` Colors,'' which stars <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Penn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvall </PERSON> and opened nationwide April 15, portrays the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crips </LOCATION> and Bloods gangs. It opened amid fears it would inspire more bloodshed, but until Sunday little violence materialized. The assailant, a man in his 20s, wore a red handkerchief denoting membership in the Bloods; the victim wore the blue handkerchief of the Crips, <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> the gunman had gotten out of a car and approached the 19-year-old, asking, `` Are you a ricket?'' Swim said the word is a derogatory term for the <LOCATION> Crips </LOCATION>. The victim's girlfriend stepped between the two, a scuffle broke out involving two of the gunman's companions and the victim's brother-in-law, and the victim was shot in the head as he started to run, police said Police and sheriff's deputies have kept up a presence at theaters in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and other places with gang problems during the screening of the movie, and some theaters across the nation have declined to show the film. Minor scuffles at an opening in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> led to 13 arrests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880425-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-88 0238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-25 0965</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dropping Water Table Means Long-term Changes in Plains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
