<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDS-Blood     12-01 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS-Blood,0505</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blood Bank Held Responsible for Transfusion-Related AIDS Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER McNULTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury found a blood bank negligent Thursday for improperly screening its blood in the case of a 5 -LCB- - year-old boy who contracted AIDS through a transfusion, a verdict believed to be the first of its kind, lawyers said `` We just feel this is a great moral victory. I think the blood industry, particularly in high-risk areas like <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, has got to shape up,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborn </PERSON>, whose son, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, was the plaintiff in the case. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, who has a brain tumor and lymphoma, was diagnosed with acquired immune deficiency syndrome in September 1987. He has only a few months to live, said the Osborns' lawyer, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Moriarty </PERSON>. `` At least <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> will be around in some way in the future. At least his name will not be forgotten,'' added Mrs. <PERSON> Osborn </PERSON>. The jury found <ORGANIZATION> Irwin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION>, which supplies blood to about 40 hospitals, to be negligent in failing to screen the blood adequately, although some AIDS screening was done at the facility at the time. In addition, the jury ruled that the blood bank erred in not allowing family members to target their blood donations for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>. <PERSON> Moriarty </PERSON> said the blood bank had rejected requests by the boy's family and friends to donate blood for the transfusion, saying they had no policy to accommodate such requests when in fact they did The blood bank's attorney, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>, denied that the blood bank acted negligently and said the decision will be appealed. The jury awarded the <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> family $ 550,000 in compensatory damages. The child, suffering from a congenital heart defect, received the transfusion Feb. 24, 1983, when he was three weeks old. The boy's parents were awarded $ 200,000 to pay for past and future medical bills but were denied any damages for pain and suffering. The jury voted unanimously to award the damages and split 9-3 on the question of liability, said <PERSON> Moriarty </PERSON>. Defending <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON>'s decisions in the case, <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> said in 1983 the blood bank had a policy of allowing so-called directed donors only for medical reasons, such as blood donations from organ donors. <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Asher </PERSON>, founder and chairman of <ORGANIZATION> HemaCare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a private blood bank in <LOCATION> Sherman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oaks </LOCATION>, said the case was the first time a blood bank was found responsible for a transfusion-related AIDS case. A <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> jury in June cleared a blood bank of liability in the case of a woman who contracted AIDS through a transfusion. A similar case in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in 1986 ended in a settlement before the trial ended. AIDS is caused by a virus that damages the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to infections and cancer. It is spread most often through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, infected blood or blood products, and from pregnant women to their offspring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua-Gorbachev     12-01 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Gorbachev,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Paper Says Ortega Wants To Meet With Gorbachev</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> wants to meet with <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> during the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> leader's visit to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the opposition daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> asked the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy for more than 20 visas for his entourage, <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> said in its afternoon edition. Nicaraguan government sources told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> they were unable to confirm the visa request because <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> has been in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> since Sunday. He is in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to attend the inauguration of President-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> on Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> said that <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> plans to leave for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> next weekend, shortly after returning from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` It is not known if <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s tight schedule in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> includes a visit with <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> plans to meet with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Dec. 5. `` Political observers and diplomats'' said <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s trip indicated `` Sandinista concern about possible negotiation between the two powers regarding Soviet presence in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> said. In a separate editorial, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> said that `` for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to develop his perestroika ... he must seek better relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' `` Here is where <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> enters the picture,'' the paper said. `` The Sandinistas with their politics of alignment toward the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have put <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> into the field of the East-West fight, making a place for itself in the agenda for any dialogue between the superpowers ... <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s potential trip to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> confirms that.'' The paper also said, `` <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> runs to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, undoubtedly to seek concessions from the Soviet delegation.'' Perestroika, Russian for restructuring, refers to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program for reforming Soviet economy and society for efficiency
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EarliestFire     12-01 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Earliest Fire,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Human Ancestors Used Fire Up to 1.5 Million Years Ago, Study
Suggests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists said today they have found the earliest direct evidence for use of fire by ape-men or early humans, bone fragments that were burned as long as 1.5 million years ago. Fires were apparently a regular event in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> cave where the fragments were found, although it is unclear whether they were for cooking, warmth or scaring predators, scientists said. `` We're not absolutely certain those bones were there -LRB- in fire -RRB- because they were food remains,'' said researcher <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON>. `` They could have been thrown into the fire as kind of a refuse heap.'' <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and C.K. Brain of the <LOCATION> Transvaal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, describe their analysis in today's issue of the British journal Nature. The fires may have been set by ancestors of humans called <PERSON> Homo </PERSON> erectus, or by ape-men called Australopithecus robustus, which are not direct human ancestors, they wrote. In an interview, <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON> said the bone fragments could be 1 million to 1.5 million years old, but most likely they are 1.2 million years old. Previous research suggests fire was being used in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> a bit more recently than 1.4 million years ago, a date many experts accept but with some hesitancy, said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Delson </PERSON>, professor of anthropology at <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>. That research is supported by indirect evidence, magnetic irregularities in the ground thought caused by ancient fire on the surface, he said in a telephone interview. The evidence from the new study is `` certainly the strongest to date in favor of early human-controlled fire,'' <PERSON> Delson </PERSON> said. Other research suggests fire was used slightly less than 500,000 years ago in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and certainly less than 150,000 years ago in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, he said. In the new work, researchers used bones recovered from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s Swartkrans cave, well-known for providing remains of <PERSON> Homo </PERSON> erectus and the ape-man robustus. To make sure they could identify signs of ancient burning, researchers took a fresh leg bone from a South African antelope called a hartebeest, and heated bone slices to different temperatures. Then they used the chemical and microscopic characteristics found in the heated slices to analyze the fossils. They concluded that 270 fossil fragments had been burnt, with most identifiable ones from antelope. Fragments from zebra, warthog, baboon and a finger bone of robustus were also identified. The robustus bone does not necessarily mean an ape-man was eaten, since the purpose of the fires is unknown, <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON> said. The fragments' color and structure showed they had been heated to a range of temperatures similar to that recorded in experimental campfires set by Brain. The experimental fires used what was probably the most common wood in the vicinity in ancient days, <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON> said. In the interview, <PERSON> Sillen </PERSON> said no burnt bones were found in older sections of the cave even though the conditions for deposition of fossils were identical. That suggests the burnt fragments mark the beginning of the use of fire, he said. <PERSON> Delson </PERSON> said the idea that the fragments burned in natural fires rather than deliberate blazes can not be ruled out. But <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Susman </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Stony </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> who has studied the ancient inhabitants of the Swartkrans cave, said he believes the fires were deliberate. `` It's highly unlikely that these bones would have been burned in a naturally occuring situation,'' he said. Range fires would not have reached the campfire-like temperatures identified for the bone fragments, he said. In addition, <PERSON> Homo </PERSON> erectus was known to use fire elsewhere, he said. <PERSON> Homo </PERSON> erectus appeared about 1.6 million years ago and evolved into a more advanced form by about 250,000 years ago. <PERSON> Robustus </PERSON> appeared about 2.5 million years ago and survived until at least 1 million years ago before extinction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Murphy     12-01 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Murphy,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eddie Murphy Buys Cher's Canyon Estate</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainer <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> has bought <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s four-acre Moroccan-style canyon estate for about $ 6 million The <LOCATION> Benedict </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> home has six bedrooms, 7 -LCB- bathrooms, two maids quarters, 10 fireplaces, a granite kitchen, pool, spa, gym and atrium with electronic skylight, according to the listing with the <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Hyland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Young real estate firm. `` He has purchased it,'' confirmed <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> publicist <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who said Wednesday she could n't provide any details on the sale. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasteler </PERSON>, also said the house was sold to <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, but would n't elaborate. Ms. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> wanted homes on both coasts. The actor-comedian has a home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, and usually stays at the L'Ermitage Hotel in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> when in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area, she said. The two-story <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> home, 20 miles northwest of downtown, was listed for $ 6.5 million and reportedly sold for about $ 6 million. A few miles away in <LOCATION> Holmby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, the home owned by actor <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> was re-listed with <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Hyland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> and wife <PERSON> Loni </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> have moved to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and he's `` anxious to sell,'' she said The $ 6 million asking price includes a 15,000-square-foot, three-bedroom Mediterranean-style main house with four bars, a tennis court and two spacious guest houses, said Ms. <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> bought the home from <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, who bought it from <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, said Ms. <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. She described the walled estate as `` the perfect bachelor or couple house in the country's most exclusive neighborhood.'' Neighbors include <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>'s Playboy Mansion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Schirra     12-01 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Schirra,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mercury Astronaut Says U.S. Lags in Space Technology</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wally </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON>, one of the first seven Mercury astronauts, says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> no longer leads the world in space technology and should renew its commitment to space exploration. In an address at the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Naval Academy Tuesday night, the former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> captain called on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to make building a space station the top priority of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s space program. Such a station could serve as a port for manned and unmanned exploratory missions to other planets and their moons, said <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON>, 65. <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON>, a 1946 academy graduate who is now a business executive, wore a `` Beat Army'' pin _ the same message he carried on a placard during a 1965 Gemini mission. The annual <ORGANIZATION> Army-Navy </ORGANIZATION> football game is this weekend. <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON> said the Skylab project marked the beginning of the decline of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space program. Budget cuts forced the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to allow Skylab to break up in orbit and no serious financial commitment has been made since, he said. The former astronaut, speaking on the eve of the launching of the secret military shuttle <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION>, said space shuttle missions have had `` no place to go. ... They were just supposed to go into outer space and come home. We did that 25 years ago.'' <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON> praised the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s space program for its long-range goals. The Soviets have done extensive research on how weightlessness affects humans and have worked to develop ships that can stay in orbit for years, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has attempted neither, he said. <PERSON> Schirra </PERSON> was selected as a Mercury astronaut in April 1959. In 1962, he became the fifth astronaut to fly in space.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Tehran-Scene     12-01 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tehran-Scene,0801</SECOND>
<HEAD>Visit to Tehran Gives Glimpses of a City of Contrasts</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Missing Iranians</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> is a city full of contrasts, showing the effects of war, tradition and modern lifestyles. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent accompanied West German Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> on a recent visit, and here is his report:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DETLEF RUDEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEHRAN, Iran (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the bustle of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s main bazaar, young women wearing blue jeans under their traditional Islamic chador robes stroll past crippled war veterans hobbling on rickety wooden crutches between merchant stalls. A few blocks away, curious children and young people flock to gaze at the magnificent former residence of the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Some people on the streets of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> openly indicated their displeasure with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s revolutionary government, which toppled the shah in 1979. A book vendor asked for an up-to-date city guidebook told a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> reporter, `` There has been nothing like that since the revolution.'' The merchant then held up a tattered guidebook dating back before the Islamic revolution. She pointed to a photograph in the book of the shah's family. The picture had been crossed out with thick black censorship marks. `` It really is a shame,'' the book vendor said angrily. Journalists accompanying West German Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> were not allowed to tour the city freely or take pictures during the three-day state visit that ended Tuesday. But the glimpses they were allowed showed <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> is a city full of contrasts. The Westerners witnessed clear evidence of Moslem fundamentalism, but also signs of modernism. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has been making efforts to increase its contacts with some Western nations, such as <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, as it tries to recover from its crippling eight-year war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> after a cease-fire. But West German businessmen who accompanied <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> said it is still not certain whether <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s commitment to conservative Moslem principles will hinder efforts to build up the country. `` Whoever plans to invest here must carefully weigh each step,'' said <PERSON> Rochus-Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> Freiherr </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Luettwitz </PERSON>, a West German involved in business discussions with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. There are signs everywhere that a fundamentalist Islamic philosophy that has governed life in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> since the <PERSON> shah </PERSON>'s ouster still holds sway. Iranian Revolutionary Guards carrying automatic rifles were plainly visible on <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s streets, watching the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> journalists to make sure they did not violate any of the restrictions under which their presence was permitted. The Iranian government's disdain for the late shah, who was friendly with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, becomes bitterly clear with a visit to the grand palace where he and his family had lived. Pictures of the shah have been turned upside-down inside the rooms of the palace, now a museum. Photographs showing poverty and squalor during the <PERSON> shah </PERSON>'s rule have been placed near tables exhibiting valuables once owned by the former ruler. Plaques tell visitors the purpose of rooms in the palace during the <PERSON> shah </PERSON>'s reign, but in a belittling fashion. `` Former Working Room of the Shah Who Fled,'' reads one plaque. But along with such clear evidence of Moslem fundamentalism, there are also signs <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s people do not totally reject Western ways. Many of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s young women wear blue jeans or short skirts under their traditional black chador robes, the fabric pushed back just enough on their foreheads to reveal a lock or two of hair. Several young women were also wearing high-heeled shoes. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> residents on the streets did not stare at the Western visitors but actually seemed to welcome them. There were also signs of the devastating war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Crippled young men hobbled along the streets and the Westerners saw empty lots where they were told bombed-out homes once stood. There are also signs of stymied progress within <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. Just behind the Hotel Esteghlal, called the Royal Tehran Hilton before the 1979 revolution, chickens raced among building materials at the site of an uncompleted structure. Rusty steel girders were scattered on the ground, giving the impression the structure had not been worked on for some time. Inside the hotel itself, the climate-control system was able to churn out only humid blasts of air. <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> and his entourage were greeted with open arms by Iranian officials. But Western journalists were told through the West German Embassy that while in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> they would be permitted to write only about <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>'s meetings and that their visas were valid only for the duration of the official visit. In addition, it was made clear to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> photographers that the Iranians would not allow pictures to be taken of life on <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s streets
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PhilippinesReactor 1stLd-Writethru a0788 12-01 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines Reactor, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0788,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawsuit Expected As Smokescreen, Westinghouse Says</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE with formal announcement of
lawsuit set; picks up 4th graf: ``What we're ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EARL BOHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday it will not be a scapegoat for what it calls politically motivated opposition in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> to a nuclear power plant it built under former President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> says the $ 2.3 billion plant 60 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Bataan </LOCATION> province is unsafe in part because of its design and its location on an earthquake fault near a volcano. Her government has said it plans to sue <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> for damages and breach of contract regarding the plant, which never went into operation because of alleged safety defects. Her legal adviser, <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcuna </PERSON>, said in late October that a lawsuit was ready and likely would be filed within a month in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. An agreement barring either the government or the company from taking legal action was due to expire Thursday. Formal announcement of the lawsuit was scheduled Thursday in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> for 2:30 p.m. -LRB- 1:30 a.m. EST -RRB- at the presidential palace. `` What we're finding here are the results of a political policy that came to life when they were running for office,'' said <PERSON> Nathaniel </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON>, general manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> nuclear fuels unit. `` They now feel they have a political albatross around their neck and they're trying to blame us.'' The reactor's opponents also allege that bribes were paid over the awarding of the prime contract. `` We won fairly and squarly,'' <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON> said in an interview. <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON> and Deputy General Counsel <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Briskman </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> officials have acknowledged during private talks that no matter how safe the plant is, they do n't intend to allow nuclear power production in the country. `` Safety has nothing to do with it,'' <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON> said. With all but $ 20 million to $ 30 million still due from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> for the power plant, <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> could walk away from the 10-year-old controversy, said <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON>. The bigger risk perhaps is damage to the company's international standing as a designer and builder of nuclear power plants. `` All over the world we have built plants, and we have n't had this problem. If they do n't want to operate this plant, that's they're decision, but do n't make <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> a scapegoat,'' he said `` <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> will not be a scapegoat.'' The company cited investigations by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> that produced no evidence warranting charges. Further, a safety study commissioned by the Aquino government concluded that the plant is safe, <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> said. A trade journal published a draft of that report. The government says the final report concludes otherwise, but officials have refused to release the document. The 620-megawatt plant, powered by a Westinghouse-pressurized water reactor, was completed three years ago. In its early stages, the project was shaken by allegations of kickbacks to officials of the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> regime and by safety concerns. Communist rebels have bombed transmission towers leading from the plant, and people have cut and sold the copper lines as scrap. The plant's corps of operators has largely disbanded, and <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> has only a handful of employees still in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Woodson </PERSON> said. Yet the cost of the plant continues rising, <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> said. Interest on the loans the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> took to build cost an estimated $ 300,000 per day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-01 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 21; 24; 28; 32; 34.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 03; 05; 18; 37; 40; 48. Supplementary 42.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 4-1-8; 0-5-2-2; 8-7-8-8-1; 6-4-4-0-6-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DeficitCommission 1stLd-Writethru a0683 12-01 0925</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deficit Commission, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0683,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright Urges Bush To Move Quickly Against Budget Deficit</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: ADDS 3 final grafs with Bowen letter to OMB on health spending
cut proposals</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> on Wednesday called for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to quickly present <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with an `` honest and responsible'' budget, saying the president-elect has a duty to spell out in detail his plan for attacking the country's deficit problems. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> joined a chorus of witnesses before the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> who urged quick and decisive action on the part of the new administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to break the seven-year deadlock over huge budget deficits. Former <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, who also testified, said that failure to act could trigger a loss of confidence by foreigners in the value of the dollar, sparking higher interest rates and possibly a severe recession in this country. `` We are, entirely unnecessarily in my view, undercutting the economic foundation of <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> world leadership,'' <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should submit his own spending blueprint no later than mid-February and this should be followed by the recommendations of the economic commission by March 1. `` We do not have the luxury of a leisurely schedule,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. `` The problems wo n't wait indefinitely while people try to read our lips or read our minds.'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and other Democrats want to force <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to be specific on how he would cut the deficit without raising taxes while still keeping his other campaign promises to boost spending in such areas as education, day care and environmental cleanup. They fear that unless the president-elect is forced to spell out how his spending cuts would work, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will try later to blame <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for boosting taxes while ignoring his `` flexible freeze'' approach. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said last week he intends to appoint people to begin deficit negotiations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on his first day in office, but he has not said whether he will submit his own spending plan or simply use President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s final budget as the starting point for discussions. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not want to submit a separate budget then <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> should consider allowing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to incorporate his own recommendations into the administration's 1990 budget, which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will submit on Jan. 9. `` This would be an act of smooth transition and the kind of resolute leadership which could inspire greater confidence both from the public and from financial markets at home and abroad,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, in his testimony, sounded many of the same warnings as his successor at the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>. In testimomy before the commission two weeks ago, <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said the deficit had begun to `` eat away at the foundations of our economic strength, and the need to deal with it is becoming ever more urgent.'' <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON> said since the current economic recovery began in late 1982 the country has been on a consumption binge, fueled by the huge budget deficits and large flows of foreign capital into the country. To keep foreigners from losing confidence in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy, <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON> said the government needed to launch a credible deficit reduction program that would bring the deficit down by between $ 30 billion to $ 40 billion each year until the budget reaches surplus. The deficit in the last fiscal year was $ 155.1 billion. <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON> said he would favor using a gasoline tax to raise extra revenues, saying each 1-cent-per-gallon boost in the tax raises $ 1 billion annually in new revenues. This tax would promote conservation, <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON> said, thus reducing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dependence on foreign oil and helping to trim <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s huge trade deficits. The Council on Competitiveness, composed of 157 chief executives from business, organized labor and higher education, presented the commission with a list of proposals to trim the deficit by $ 120 billion by 1993 with a combination of spending cuts and $ 48 billion in higher taxes. Among the taxes the council suggested were a boost in excise taxes on cigarettes and alcohol, which would raise $ 8 billion annually; a 20-cent-per-gallon increase in the gasoline tax, which would raise $ 20 billion annually; and higher income tax rates for families earning more than $ 220,350 a year, which could bring in $ 7 billion in additional revenues, the council said. Former Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Giaimo </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., and co-chairman of the Committee for a <ORGANIZATION> Responsible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, said a nationwide series of town meetings had shown him that Americans support balancing the budget, even it means tax increases and a freeze in cost-of-living hikes for Social Security <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, presented the commission with a <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> transition report which came to the conclusion that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s flexible freeze would not be enough to eliminate the deficit and consideration would have to be given to increasing taxes. `` When the long-term health of our nation's economy is at stake, everything must be negotiable, including defense spending, entitlements and taxes,'' <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> has registered his objections to proposals by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> to cut Medicaid payments to states next year and to reduce the growth in spending on AIDS. In a letter <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> wrote to <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, reported in Thursday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the secretary called the <ORGANIZATION> Medicaid </ORGANIZATION> proposal `` unrealistic.'' <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> wants to slash federal Medicaid payments to states by $ 1.1 billion, and to allow AIDS spending to grow from $ 1.3 billion to $ 1.6 billion. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> wants the government to spend $ 1.9 billion on AIDS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soldier'sRampage     12-01 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soldier's Rampage,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heartbroken Soldier Runs Amok, Kills Seven, Military Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A soldier went berserk after a quarrel with his girlfriend, firing a rifle at neighbors and villagers and killing seven people, the military said today. The killer surrendered after the rampage, in which nine people were injured, the military said. The report said <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Negro </PERSON>, a constable at the <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, went on the killing spree after he left his girlfriend's home Wednesday in <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION>, a village in <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION> province 360 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The military said the violence was triggered by a `` love problem'' between Negro and the woman, who was not identified. After <PERSON> Negro </PERSON> left his girlfriend's home, he began firing his semiautomatic rifle at neighbors in the coastal village. Five people were killed and five others injured, the report said. <PERSON> Negro </PERSON> then hitched a ride in a jeep to nearby <LOCATION> Talisay </LOCATION> town. While en route, he opened fire on a group of men in <LOCATION> Lawaan </LOCATION> village, killing two and wounding four, the report added. He surrendered later and was undergoing interrogation, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-PLO Bjt   12-01 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-PLO, Bjt,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>General Assembly Deplores U.S. For Denying Arafat A Visa</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> voted 151-2 to condemn the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for not letting <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> enter the country and gave it until today to reverse the decision. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said they would not budge. If <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman, is not granted a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visa, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> nations will offer a resolution to reconvene the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> so <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> can address it. Diplomats said passage was assured. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> opposed Wednesday's condemnation. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> abstained because it said the criticism was too harsh, but all other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies supported the denunciation. The vote was conducted in a rare and dramatic roll call, requested by <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>. In a departure from the standard electronic voting, delegates voted in the official <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> languages: Arabic, English, Chinese, French, Russian and Spanish. They called out `` Na'm,'' `` Yes,'' `` <PERSON> Zan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>,'' `` 0ui,'' `` Da,'' `` Si,'' and in the case of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, `` No.'' Absent from the roll call were <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kitts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevis </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The resolution asked <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> to inform the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> by tonight of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> response. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would not change its mind. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> denied <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> a visa on security grounds, saying he condones and encourages terrorism perpetrated by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had said he wanted to explain to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> the position taken by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in its recent meeting in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. The council _ the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s parliament in exile _ implicitly recognized <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist, accepting key <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> calling for negotiations with states in the region. Iraqi Ambassador <PERSON> Ismat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kittani </PERSON> said if <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> does not receive a visa, `` it will constitute a grievous blow to the process of peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' `` I feel very pained to see that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the odd couple with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Clovis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, ambassador of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, which sponsored the resolution. `` We are hopeful the international outcry against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position will jolt the subsequent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration into a reassessment of its policies of bias toward <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' he said. Arab diplomats said they would quickly introduce a resolution to shift the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in mid-December. The second resolution would likely be voted on by early next week, and the diplomats said they had the votes to pass it. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says it does not oppose a move to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> and would participate in debate there. Undersecretary-General <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Verner </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said plans were already under way to move the assembly to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, the European headquarters of the world body. It would be the first time the assembly has moved as an act of protest. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has had a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> mission in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since 1975 and holds non-voting observer status. It is considered the sole, legitimate representative of the Palestinian people and is invited to speak on all debates concerning Palestinians and the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Under the 1947 U.S.-U.N. Headquarters Agreement, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is required to grant visas to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> diplomats and invitees on <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> business. In debate Wednesday, <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Okun </PERSON> reiterated the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s assertion that the Headquarters Agreement allows the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to protect its security interests. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> debate on the Palestinian issue originally was scheduled today, Friday and Dec. 6 but has been postponed. Diplomatic sources said the week of Dec. 12-16 would be the most likely time for the session in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. The resolution on moving must first be heard by a 16-member budgetary advisory committee because it has financial implications. It then would go to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>'s finance committee, formally called the <ORGANIZATION> Fifth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which would vote on it and send it to the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> for action. The cost of the move to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> was not known, but <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> sources have said it would be relatively modest, perhaps $ 150,000, covering the travel of a small number of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> personnel. Most nations would send their <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> ambassadors to the session.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RJR-Nabisco 3rdLd-Writethru a0405 12-01 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-RJR-Nabisco, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0405,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Management Group Raises Ante to More than $24.3 Billion</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE with previous takeover record,
comment from RJR, Kohlberg; picks up 11th graf: `Johnson, known .. .</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICK GLADSTONE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Buyout specialist <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kravis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roberts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> won the free-for-all takeover war for <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nabisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> late Wednesday with a record $ 24.53 billion offer for the cigarette-and-food giant. The $ 109-a-share offer shattered a rival effort by an <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> management group and came in a day of frantic maneuvering that at times left the unprecedented auction for the company in utter confusion. <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION>'s offer of $ 81 in cash, $ 18 in stock and additional securities worth $ 10 beat out a last-minute offer valued at $ 112, or $ 25.2 billion, by the management group that instigated the takeover struggle last month at a price that was $ 8.3 billion cheaper. The value of <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION>'s offer was nearly double that of the previous record, a $ 13.4 billion takeover of <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in March 1984. Although the management offer looked higher in face value, <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement that its board of directors concluded the <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION> offer was worth substantially the same. `` The Board of Directors of <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nabisco </ORGANIZATION>, by unanimous vote of all directors present, adopted the <ORGANIZATION> KKR </ORGANIZATION> offer as being in the best interest of the company and its shareholders,'' <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Kohlberg </LOCATION>, the undisputed leader in the business of buying companies with borrowed money in deals known as leveraged buyouts, issued a statement that it was pleased with the decision that capped the biggest takeover in history. `` We are also pleased that this process has come to an end so that the employees of <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION>, its consumers and suppliers and the communities it serves, can be assured that business will now return to normal and stability will be restored,'' <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION>'s two principals, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravis </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, said in the statement. <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION>'s victory caps a struggle that broke all previous takeover records and raised major questions about the frenzy of leveraged buyouts and other debt-financed restructurings transforming much of corporate <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The end of the <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> battle also signaled a spectacular defeat by its chief executive <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who began the takeover struggle last month with a $ 75 a share offer that he later raised four times. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, known as a scrappy adversary unafraid of taking risks, had no immediate comment on <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION>'s victory. It was n't immediately clear whether he would take another tack in what has been an unpredictable battle Earlier in the day, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s group made an 11th-hour effort to raise its bid from $ 101 a share to $ 108 a share after a company-decreed deadline for all offers had expired. The move temporarily upended a $ 106-a-share, $ 23.8 billion offer from <ORGANIZATION> Kohlberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kravis </ORGANIZATION> that was about to be approved, sources said. That development made the already unwieldy auction even more chaotic and raised questions about whether all bidders were receiving equal treatment. It also sent <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION>'s stock roaring higher, partly in anticipation that the unprecedented auction might be prolonged yet again. Sources familiar with the bidding also said the offer of a third contender, <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> was rejected as too tentative, although the bidder valued it as high as $ 115 a share or $ 25.87 billion. A crucial element of each proposal was the portion of cash each bidder intended to pay, because the value of the securities segment is difficult to determine. These securities often are worth less than their face amount. <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION> stock surged on the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> briefly halted trading when buy orders overwhelmed sell orders on Wednesday. The stock resumed trading by midafternoon and closed up $ 2.25 to $ 93 on volume exceeding 6.7 million shares. RJR stock was trading at less than $ 56 a share when the battle began in late October. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s group incited the battle when he proposed to take the nation's 19th-largest industrial company private via a leveraged buyout. <ORGANIZATION> RJR </ORGANIZATION>'s board of directors then put the company up for sale to attract rival bids and conducted the first round of an auction Nov. 18-20. They decided to prolong it because the offers received were too vague and inadequate. RJR is one of the largest consumer products companies, with more than 120,000 employees. It makes well-known brands that range from Camel cigarettes to Shredded Wheat cereal to Life Savers candy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-PLO-Text     12-01 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-PLO-Text,0345</SECOND>
<HEAD>UN Resolution Deplores U.S. Visa Denial To Arafat, Urges Reversal</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-UN-PLO, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The following is the official English-language text of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Arab-sponsored resolution deploring the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> denial of a visa for <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> and urging the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to reverse its decision. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, Recalling Article 105 of the Charter of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the Agreement between the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> regarding the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, dated 26 June 1947, Recalling also its resolution 3237 -LRB- XXIX -RRB- of 22 November 1974, in which it, inter alia -LRB- among other things -RRB-, invited the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to participate in the sessions and the work of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in the capacity of observer, Affirming the right of member states and observers freely to designate the members of their delegation to participate in the sessions and the work of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, Having been apprised that the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, in conformity with the usual practice, had requested through the Secretary-General an entry visa for Mr. <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, Chairman of the Executive Committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, in order to participate in the forty-third session of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, Having been informed of the decision of the host country to deny the requested visa in violation of its international legal obligations under the Agreement, Endorsing the opinion of the Legal Counsel of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> rendered on 28 November 1988, Considers that the decision by the Government of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the host country, constitutes a violation of the international legal obligations of the host country under the Agreement between the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> regarding the Headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>; Urges the host country to abide scrupulously by the provisions of the Headquarters Agreement and to reconsider and reverse its decision; Requests the Secretary-General to submit a report on the developments in this matter no later than December 1, 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Pentagon-Computer     12-01 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pentagon-Computer,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Severs Military Computer Network From Academic Network</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, citing technical difficulties, has cut links for several days between an unclassified military computer network and a nationwide academic and corporate computer network, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. Several computer security experts said Wednesday that they had been told by <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials that the network connection was severed after an unknown intruder illegally gained entry recently to several computers operated by the military and defense contractors, according to the Times. The computer specialists said they thought the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> broke the connection, which permits military and academic researchers to exchange information, while it tried to eliminate a security flaw in the computers in the military network, the newspaper reported. An unidentified spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communication </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> told the Times in a statement that the links between the two networks were cut at 10 p.m. Monday and were expected to be restored Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> apparently acted after a computer at the <ORGANIZATION> Mitre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, company with several military contracts, was illegally entered several times during the past month, according to the Times. Officials at several universities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> said their computers had been used by the intruder to reach the Mitre computer. <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Mitre, told the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday that one of the company's computers had been entered. But she said no classified or sensitive information had been handled by the computers involved and the problem was fixed within hours of being detected. The military computer network, known as Milnet, is linked through seven gateways to another larger computer network, Arpanet, which was jammed last month by a rogue program introduced by a <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> graduate student. The decision to disconnect the military computers upset a number of computer users around the country. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rochlis </PERSON>, assistant network manager at the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, said that a computer user complained Tuesday night that `` he could not send mail.'' `` Initially we were given the run around, but eventually they unofficially confirmed to us that the shutoff was security related,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NerveGas     12-01 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nerve Gas,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Investigating Alleged Scheme To Ship Nerve Gas To Iran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal authorities are investigating an alleged scheme to illegally ship a chemical used to make nerve gas to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> reported. Documents filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> say a company in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> attempted to ship thiodiglycol, a chemical precursor of mustard gas, to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> via <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Post-Dispatch </PERSON> said in its Thursday editions. The documents were filed in an application for a search warrant which sought telexes, computer printouts and records of messages between <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, maker of the chemical, and two companies in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>. In the 8-year war between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, both sides _ but particularly <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> _ were accused of using chemical weapons. Both sides denied using the weapons, which are outlawed under the Geneva Convention. Thiodiglycol has permissible applications in the textile industry, but its export is restricted under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export laws `` to prevent diversion to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> for use in chemical warfare,'' the affidavit says. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> outlined the scheme in a 14-page affidavit file in their application for the search warrant. The affidavit says <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION> began shipping thiodiglycol in February 1987 for <ORGANIZATION> Colimex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GmbH </ORGANIZATION>, a West German company now called <ORGANIZATION> Chemco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GmbH </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co.. KG <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION>'s shipping documents referred to the cargo by its trade name, <PERSON> Kromfax </PERSON>, rather by its chemical name. The documents had been manipulated to make it possible to divert the cargo to <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, in violation of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Export Administration Regulations, the affidavit says. The cargo began its journey by barge from <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, where customs agents intercepted it and switched the Kromfax drums with drums of water. Customs agents then monitored the cargo's route to <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and its transshipment to <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>. In late June, agents with the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> learned from customs officials in <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION> that the shipment had been transferred to an Iranian flagship named `` SS <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> Ekram.'' The cargo then made its way to the Iranian port at <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>. It was set to be delivered ultimately to a company in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The affidavit says an undated telex from <LOCATION> Walaschek </LOCATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION> indicates `` that he intended to cause the shipment of thiodiglycol to be transshipped from <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, and ultimately <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, and that <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION> knew that <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> was not the ultimate destination for the shipment.'' <ORGANIZATION> Alcolac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> was incorporated in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> in 1955. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, vice president and general manager of the performance chemicals division, said the company manufactured `` specialty chemicals'' like those in shampoos. Thiodiglycol is a solvent, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-01 0859</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chicken, Fresh Veggies Will be Best Food Buys in 1989</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chicken, rather than beef and pork, and fresh vegetables rather than canned or frozen ones are likely to be the best bargains for consumers in 1989, according to a top <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> food economist. Prices for eggs are likely to shoot upward as much as 20 percent, and substantial price increases for fresh fruits, cereals and bakery products also can be expected, department economist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> says in a 1989 outlook report issued Wednesday. Overall, consumer food prices should rise about 3 to 5 percent next year, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said, roughly equaling this year's 4 percent increase. This year's rise means food prices have about kept pace with price increases in the rest of the economy, although consumers may notice their food bills more because of more frequent trips to the grocery store, he said. A variety of factors influence food costs, including the amount farmers make for the raw commodities, the costs of packaging materials, and charges for processing and distribution. In 1988, packaging cost increases were the main contributor to a 5 percent increase in processing and distribution expense, while farmers averaged 3.5 percent more for their raw products. For 1989, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said increases in egg prices will be the sharpest in the marketbasket, 15 to 20 percent, in part because of a squeeze produced by increased use of eggs in processing and a decline in production because of higher feed costs and poor returns to producers. Other steep increases are likely in fresh fruits, which may go up 6 to 9 percent because of strong consumer demand both domestically and in the export market. Orange prices are likely to remain strong because of growing purchases by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, and a smaller apple crop will lead to higher prices there. Continued effects of the 1988 drought will be felt in the area of cereals and bakery products, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said. Prices are expected to rise 4 to 7 percent next year due to a combination of grain price increases and strengthened demand from health-conscious consumers who see cereals as a good and easy-to-prepare nutrition source. The biggest bargain for shoppers, compared to current prices, will be in poultry, <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said. Growing supplies will bring prices down by at least 4 percent and possibly as much as 7 percent, he said. Beef production next year is likely to drop by 6 to 8 percent, leading to a moderate 1 to 3 percent price increase, similar to that expected for pork. Prices for fresh vegetables, which climbed this year because of the drought, will show little change next year because of expanding production, the economist forecast. <PERSON> Parlett </PERSON> said he expects an increase in the range of 0 to 3 percent, compared to a 4 to 7 percent increase for processed vegetables.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prices farmers received for raw products in November declined slightly from a month earlier but remained nearly 8 percent above their level of a year ago, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said in its preliminary report Wednesday that lower prices for hogs, corn, grapefruit and soybeans were partly offset by higher prices for tomatoes, potatoes, milk and sweet corn, resulting in an overall drop of nearly 1 percent for the month. In part driven by the summer's drought, prices received by farmers had been rising throughout most of 1988 until September, when the increase leveled off. November's decline was the first drop in the price index since February. Despite the decline of the overall price index, some commodities continued higher in November. Wheat, for example, rose an additional 6 cents per bushel to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm price average of $ 3.90 per bushel, the most since it was $ 3.95 in May 1981. Prices of livestock and livestock products as a group were off just less than 1 percent from October. Hog prices, at $ 36 per hundredweight, were the lowest since June 1980, while beef cattle prices were unchanged at $ 67.10. Dairy products and eggs were higher, while broiler prices declined. Compared with November 1987, the index was up 5.6 percent. The department's all-crops price index for November, although unchanged from October, was up 11 percent from a year earlier. Prices of feed grain and hay as a group declined 3.7 percent from last month and averaged 49 percent above the year-earlier level. Prices of commercial vegetables were up 22 percent from October but off 30 percent from November 1987. Tomatoes led the price increases, while carrot prices decreased slightly. Although the projections are subject to change, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists say that net cash income of farmers may be in the range of $ 55 billion to $ 60 billion this year, compared with the record level of $ 57.1 billion in 1987. That is the difference between cash receipts and cash expenses during the calendar year. Preliminary figures show that food prices for 1988 will average a 4 percent increase, about the same as last year's increase. For 1989, department economists are projecting food cost hikes in the same range, about 3 to 5 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-QuayleInterview Bjt   12-01 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle Interview, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle May Preside More In Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> may spend more time than his predecessors presiding over the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, a move that could spell conflict between the Democratic-controlled chamber and the administration. In an interview, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> on Wednesday also made his strongest public rejection of the notion that he will act as the link between the administration and the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s far right. He also said his verbal gaffes during the campaign gave him some hard lessons about his own tendency to talk too much. Being besieged with questions and jokes about his qualifications was painful but educational, he said. `` I know myself better now. I'm a stronger person,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said his focus now is on the task ahead _ picking his vice presidential staff during the transition period and working with President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Since the election, conservatives have beaten a path to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s transition office seeking his ear <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> himself is an ardent conservative who has largely supported <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration positions during his eight years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` I've worked with a number of conservatives in the past; a lot of good friends are conservatives, but I'm not the point man for the conservatives in this administration. ... You wo n't see me being the so-called spear carrier for all the so-called conservative issues,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also hinted that he may take a more active role in his official capacity as president of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, presiding over the Democratic-controlled chamber more frequently. `` It's certainly an option. ... There have been suggestions to me by many that I consider spending more time in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> than my predecessors have. I have not made a decision on that,'' he said. The presiding officer has substantial discretion as to which senator to recognize for the purpose of offering amendments, bills and motions. Normally the chair is occupied by a member of the majority party. A Republican in charge could touch off partisan parliamentary warfare. The vice president may take the presiding chair at any time, and the presiding officer's decision to recognize a senator is not subject to a point of order or appeal under <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he wants to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said if he did decide to preside more often, it would not be done `` in a contentious manner.'' `` I would be fair and objective and do what the president of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> should do to protect senators' rights, all senators' rights,'' he said During the interview, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was relaxed and friendly, but clearly weighing his words. He has not generally spoken to the press in depth since the election. He confessed to being `` far more careful of what I say today than six months ago.'' `` I also try to discipline myself when I get into a situation ... instead of being verbose, which is a tendency that I have, to be concise. Because verbosity leads to unclear, inarticulate things.'' Also on Wednesday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> met with retiring <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, a Republican who will appoint <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s replacement in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will resign effective Jan. 2 so his replacement can have seniority over other incoming senators. <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> has not said whom he will appoint, and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he made no recommendation. But he did not reject a reporter's suggestion that he favors Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s district representative in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, while <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> from 1976 to 1980. Coats now represents <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s old congressional district. `` Obviously I think a lot of <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON>. He worked for me for four years. He's been a very good congressman from my old congressional district. He took my seat. We've had a long and strong personal and professional relationship,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. On another subject, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the vice presidential mansion in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> may need alterations before his family can move in after the inauguration. He said the house is not configured for a family with three children. It does have six bedrooms, but some of them now serve as offices and servants' quarters and some do not have closets. The Quayles will live at their home in <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, until they can move into the official residence. Their three children _ <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, 14, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>, 12, and <PERSON> Corinne </PERSON>, 10 _ will continue attending public schools in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> for the time being.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ABA-CriminalJustice Bjt   12-01 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ABA-Criminal Justice, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug War a Failure but Courts Overwhelmed, ABA Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The war on drugs is overwhelming a criminal justice system whose greatest problem is lack of resources, not legal protections afforded criminal suspects, a two-year <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> study concludes. `` The entire system is starved: police, prosecution, criminal defense, courts and corrections,'' says the report by an <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> committee. `` As currently funded, the criminal justice system can not provide the quality of justice that the public legitimately expects and that the people working within the system wish to deliver.'' Less than 3 percent of all government spending in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> went to support civil and criminal justice activities in fiscal 1985, a previously released federal study has shown. Those already thin resources are being overwhelmed by a massive _ but largely unsuccessful _ battle against illegal drugs, the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> panel concluded. It said that while courts are increasingly clogged, the drug problem `` is growing worse, and ... law enforcement has been unable to control'' it. The <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> study noted political disputes about the Miranda decision but found relatively few problems in the field related to it. That decision, issued in 1966 by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, said police must warn suspects of their right to remain silent and to consult with a lawyer before any questioning takes place. While the Miranda decision `` has sparked heated controversy on a political level, the restrictions itsaid. Eighty-seven percent of prosecutors surveyed for the study said no more than 5 percent of their cases were dismissed because of problems involving the Miranda requirements. The exclusionary rule _ under which evidence obtained illegally by police may not be used in court _ also has caused few major problems, the study concluded. Some police officials, in fact, told the panel that the demands of the exclusionary rule have promoted professionalism in the nation's police departments. Most prosecutors put the number of cases dismissed because of the exclusionary rule at 5 percent or less, while three-quarters of the judges and defense lawyers polled said suppression motions succeed just 10 percent or less of the time. The study was based on testimony from the legal community and a national telephone survey of police, prosecutors, defense attorneys and judges. It was compiled by a panel chaired by <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Dash </PERSON>, former chief counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watergate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law professor. The study said efforts to bring the nation's drug problem under control are swamping the criminal justice system. `` Police, prosecutors and judges told the committee that they have been unsuccessful in making a significant impact on the importation, sale and use of illegal drugs, despite devoting much of their resources to the arrest, prosecution and trial of drug offenders,'' the panel reported. `` These extraordinary efforts have instead distorted and overwhelmed the criminal justice system, crowding dockets and jails, and diluting law enforcement and judicial efforts to deal with other major criminal cases.'' The panel recommended that the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> set up a special commission to study and re-evaluate national, state and local strategies in dealing with the drug problem and to educate the public and lawmakers as well as government policymakers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0304EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperColliderFunds     12-01 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Super Collider Funds,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen, Pickle Say Funding Atom Smasher Will Be Tough</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Texans in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will have a tough time persuading their colleagues to spend the billions of dollars needed to build the super collider, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> says. `` I'll be working very hard to get it funded,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` It's going to be exceedingly difficult to get.'' Even when seven states were candidates for the potentially lucrative physics project, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was adamant about financing the super collider. It voted earlier this year to give the project $ 100 million _ less than one-third of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s request for $ 363 million _ and decreed none of the money could be spent on construction. `` It's going to be uphill and tough, and particularly now because it's just one state,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, chairman of the influential <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told a group of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> reporters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Wednesday. `` We had seven states working on it before.'' Now that a site in <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has been chosen by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for the super collider, at least one member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from a state that lost its bid to host the project is questioning the feasibility of finding enough construction money. The super collider is expected to cost $ 4.4 billion, and to create thousands of construction and scientific jobs. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., said last week that the superconducting super collider was in trouble and would likely be doomed by budget constraints and opposition from others in the scientific community `` And quite honestly, the way the program has been set up, the consequences are that there's really very limited support outside of one particular state,'' said <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I have n't said it's going to go down the drain, but it's in serious difficulty.'' He said it stood a chance of one or two in 10 of ever being built.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0304EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSDay-US     12-01 0370</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Day-US,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Letters From Victims Mark AIDS Day Observance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 20-year-old <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> resident wrote a top federal health official that the public reaction to disclosing he tested positive for the AIDS virus would end his life `` sooner than AIDS will probably take it.'' The letter from `` D'' _ his identity is known to <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials _ was among eight from people with AIDS being read today during a World AIDS Day ceremony at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. `` I live in the Bible Belt of our country,'' began the letter to Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>, the No. 2 physician in the federal health department. `` I have lived most of my life in a small town in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. I attend a large university in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> and will soon be finishing my junior year. `` I ca n't tell you my name because my short life of only 20 years would be over very quickly. It would be over sooner than AIDS will probably take it. I'm HIV positive and have been so diagnosed since spring of 1987. `` I sit in classrooms and hear people discuss AIDS and what they think they know is right. Why ca n't I speak up and tell them they ca n't get it from just being in the same room? Why ca n't I tell them the truth? `` I'm so afraid of what will happen if I openly admit to being HIV positive. Would I get kicked out of school? I was so afraid of what people would think, I did n't even talk to my parents about it for six months. I was hurting so bad. I was lonely. `` Now, my father has never even said the word AIDS and my mother only makes sure I'm in good health and eating right and taking vitamins.'' <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>, the assistant secretary for health, arranged the program, including an opening minute of silence for the people who have died of AIDS. As of Nov. 7, 1988, AIDS had been diagnosed in 77,994 Americans, of whom more than half, or 43,888, have died since June 1, 1981, according to the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>. No one is known to have recovered from AIDS.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSafety     12-01 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Safety,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRC Chief Cites Improved Safety And Efficiency At Plants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARTON REPPERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's nuclear power plants have become safer and more efficient over the last four years, according to the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The remarks by Chairman <PERSON> Lando </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> came at ceremonies Wednesday to dedicate an 18-story headquarters building for the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION>, Md. `` I am pleased to report that we are seeing evidence that overall performance is improving,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> told the gathering. Spokesmen for anti-nuclear groups challenged <PERSON> Zech </PERSON>'s upbeat assessment, with one contending that the situation with power reactors amounted to a `` mixed bag'' of improvements and problem areas. `` From 1984 until now, there has been a clear and definite improvement,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said, noting that the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> began an analysis in that year of safety indicators. <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said there had been reductions in `` significant operating events'' at power reactors, unplanned automatic shutdowns, safety system activations, `` precursor events'' signaling the possibility of a major accident as well as exposure of workers to radiation. `` Along with this improvement in critical safety performance indicators, we have seen improvements in plant reliability and availability,'' <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> said. `` Recent data shows an increase in the average capacity factors for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> reactors from about 59 percent in 1986 to almost 67 percent in 1988.'' The capacity factor is the actual output of a plant compared with what it would generate if it operated at full power all the time. <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopeck </PERSON> later provided the following specific figures for the performance indicators cited by <PERSON> Zech </PERSON>: _ `` Significant operating events,'' or major problems: 2.4 per operating reactor in 1985; 1.6 in 1986; and 0.8 in 1987. _ Unplanned automatic shutdowns: 5.24 per reactor in 1984; 5.04 in 1985; 3.96 in 1986; and 3.24 in 1987 _ Safety system activations: 2.76 per reactor in 1984; 2.6 in 1985; 2.04 in 1986; and 1.68 in 1987 _ Precursor events: a nationwide total of 17 in 1984; 10 in 1985; and 6 in 1986 _ Radiation exposure: 714 man-rem in 1984; 574 man-rem in 1985; 431 in 1986; and 425 in 1987 Man-rem is a measure of radiation exposure for large numbers of people. For example, when 100 people receive an average exposure of 0.01 rem, that would result in a figure of 1 man-rem. Spokesmen for anti-nuclear groups said they had questions about <PERSON> Zech </PERSON>'s assessment of overall plant performance. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Bossong </PERSON> of Public Citizen, a Washington-based public interest group founded by consumer advocate <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON>, said: `` It's a mixed bag. There are some positives and there are some negatives. It's not fair or accurate for <PERSON> Zech </PERSON> to say everything is looking better because it's not.'' For example, <PERSON> Bossong </PERSON> said: `` On the radiation issue, what he said is true as far as it went, but it's not complete. The average dose per worker at nuclear power plants has decreased since 1984, but the number of workers exposed, on the other hand, has increased.'' He said the number of workers exposed has increased from 93,000 in 1985 to slightly more than 100,000 in 1986 and 104,000 workers in 1987. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariotte </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resource </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, another Washington-based public interest group, said: `` There may be a slightly improving track record. However, there's no reason to be smug about it. ... It seems like every time they think something has been solved, they find a new problem.'' The new 286,000-square-foot <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> headquarters building, purchased by the government for $ 47.5 million, provides space for about 1,400 <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> employees. It marks an effort to consolidate operations of the agency, which previously were dispersed among 10 separate buildings. A second structure is to be built at the same <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION> site by 1991 to accommodate the rest of the agency's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area employees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Poland Bjt   12-01 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland, Bjt,0759</SECOND>
<HEAD>Solidarity Supporters Cheer Walesa After Debate</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity backers declared <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> the winner of an unprecedented TV debate in which he dueled with his official counterpart and urged the government to legalize the banned labor movement. `` This is a fantastic day, beautiful, which will be noted in the history of our country as a great victory for Solidarity,'' said film director <PERSON> Andrzej </PERSON> <PERSON> Wajda </PERSON> after Wednesday night's showdown between the Solidarity chairman and <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON>, head of the government's official trade unions. `` He was perfect, just perfect,'' a grinning <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON>, a senior Solidarity adviser, said of <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. It was the first time in five years that <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> had a chance to defend his federation on state-controlled television and his longest appearance ever on Polish TV. The exchange was broadcast live and uncensored. A clock was even placed in the background of the set to demonstrate that no deletions were made. In the 43-minute debate, an animated <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> spoke rapidly, challenging authorities to legalize Solidarity. He urged the official unions to join Solidarity in `` creating freedom.'' He also said <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON>, as a member of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> and as leader of the <ORGANIZATION> All-Poland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION>, should press for the legalization of the outlawed labor movement. `` If you can make a man's decision that there is a place for Solidarity, we will immediately roll up our sleeves and we will begin working hard for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, because time is running out,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> told the 59-year-old former steelworker. Solidarity, the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc's first independent union federation, was crushed under martial law in 1981 and banned in 1982. <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON>'s group, known by its Polish initials OPZZ, was created by the government in 1982 to replace it. The official unions say they have 7 million members, including 4.5 million former Solidarity members. Solidarity was founded during a turbulent series of strikes in 1980. In its heyday, it said it had 10 million members. In the debate, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said proposed talks between the opposition and government could begin when officials acknowledge Solidarity's right to exist After the broadcast, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> told reporters he suffered from a severe case of flu that hampered his performance and made him `` too impulsive.'' <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON>, interviewed as he left the debate set, said only: `` I have fulfilled my task. I am pleased that Mr. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> accepted my invitation.'' The state-run <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency said that although the two debaters disagreed, `` the very fact of the meeting is a good prognosis for overcoming barriers in reaching ... dialogue and national agreement.'' The debate brought thousands of rapt Poles to television sets. In <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s Central Station, <PERSON> Grzegorz </PERSON> <PERSON> Streszynski </PERSON> missed his train to western <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> to watch. `` <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> made great remarks. I waited seven years to hear them,'' he said afterward. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said during the debate that all socialist countries were in difficult straits and blamed their problems on a lack of `` pluralism,'' independent groups and ideas in public life. In a reference to changes under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, he said conditions had never been better for reform but that <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> nevertheless was merely `` toddling in place.'' <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON> said said each enterprise should have only one trade union to avoid dividing the workforce. He said some Solidarity backers have shouted anti-state slogans like `` Down with the Commune,'' which he called `` terrifying.'' `` Our society must have peace, at least social peace, at least security for society,'' he said. He urged Solidarity supporters to enlist in his trade unions. But <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, a 1983 Nobel Peace Prize winner, said: `` You want me to come on my knees to your union. I do n't want to. I want to be myself.'' Dressed in a gray suit and wearing a Solidarity badge and an image of the madonna on his lapel, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, 45, looked relaxed as sat next to his debate opponent, both in leather lounge chairs. As the debate progressed, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> took the offensive, gesturing broadly with his hands. The Solidarity leader did most of the talking overall. <PERSON> Miodowicz </PERSON> proposed the debate Nov. 14 during an interview with the official <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Trybuna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ludu </ORGANIZATION>. The last time <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> defended Solidarity on Polish television was in 1983, when he responded to a speech given by then-Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>, who now serves as prime minister.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881201-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-01-88 0314EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PatronageDeliberations     12-01 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Patronage Deliberations,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: A Friendly Takeover in Presidential Personnel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
