<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Brazil-Hijacking 4thLd-Writethru a0897 09-29 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brazil-Hijacking, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0897,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hijacking Ends With One Dead, Four Wounded</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 9 grafs to UPDATE with official saying hijacker
wanted to crash airliner into government building; hijacker in
critical condition; no Americans aboard. Pickup 7th graf pvs `A
small...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto RIO1</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police shot and captured an armed hijacker who wanted to crash a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 with more than 100 people aboard into a government building in the Brazilian capital Thursday, officials said. The airliner hijacking left one person dead and four wounded in the central <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION>, 850 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> and 150 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, the capital. The gunman was shot as he left the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 and tried to board a small getaway plane with a hostage after the rest of the passengers and crew of <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION> Flight 375 were released unharmed, officials said. Authorities said the hijacker shot and killed the airliner's co-pilot and wounded three other crew members They described the hijacker as mentally disturbed. Federal Police Chief <PERSON> Romeu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuma </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> that the hijacker received several bullet wounds throughout his body and was in critical condition. <PERSON> Tuma </PERSON> identified the hijacker as <PERSON> Raimundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Conceicao </PERSON>, 28. Airport officials said no Americans were aboard. The police chief said <PERSON> Conceicao </PERSON> told the control tower at <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Genoveva </LOCATION> airport that he wanted to `` slam the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737 into a ministry building in <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>'' but later agreed to take a smaller plane. Holding a .38 - caliber revolver and taking the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>'s pilot with him, the hijacker descended from the jet parked on the runway at the A small Brazilian-made Bandeirantes plane was to take him and the pilot to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, said air force spokesman Col. <PERSON> Eden </PERSON> <PERSON> Avolinsque </PERSON>. The hijacker had demanded to talk to President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> about the country's economic policies, which he thought were wrong, said <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON>. `` Police shot at him as he left the plane and he turned around and shot the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> pilot, whom he had taken as his only hostage,'' Avolinsque told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>. `` He ran off into the bushes, and police following close behind shot ... him.'' Pilot <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Murillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> was shot in the leg, <PERSON> Avolinsque </PERSON> said. `` We had orders from the president not to negotiate with the hijacker and not to refuel the plane,'' Avolinsque said. Hundreds of heavily armed federal and state police and uniformed army troops had surrounded the jet, isolated at the end of a runway. <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION>, a domestic carrier, is a <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> acronym for <ORGANIZATION> Viacao </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sao </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paulo </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Mona </PERSON> <PERSON> Cury </PERSON> said Flight 375 was on its daily run from the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle city of <LOCATION> Porto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Velho </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> on the southeast <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast when it was hijacked. The hijacker ordered the airliner be flown to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> but the government refused to let it land, said <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON>. After nearly running out of fuel, the jet landed in <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION>, `` He told the control tower he was against the economic policies of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> and insisted on going to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>. He did n't make any other demands,'' <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> said by telephone from <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION>. Earlier, <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION> and the Rio airport authority had reported a passenger also was killed, but later denied the information. <PERSON> Tuma </PERSON> flew from <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> to direct negotiations with the hijacker. He said the man `` showed signs of mental disturbance.'' <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrini </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION> employee at the <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> airport, said soldiers were taken to an identical plane to study it for a possible invasion. Live TV reports from <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> showed soldiers with rifles creeping up to the plane and then running away. <PERSON> Avolinsque </PERSON> said the hijacker boarded the plane during a refueling stop in <PERSON> Belo </PERSON> <PERSON> Horizonte </PERSON>, 290 miles north of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>. `` About 20 minutes after takeoff, he got up and walked toward the cockpit. A steward said, ` That's not the toilet,' and the man turned and shot him, injuring him in the head,'' Avolinsque said at a news conference in the air force ministry. <PERSON> Avolinsque </PERSON> said the hijacker entered the cockpit, shot co-pilot <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Evangelista </PERSON> in the head and a flight engineer in the leg and ordered the pilot to fly to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> VASP </ORGANIZATION> said the plane carried 98 passengers and seven crew members. When the plane landed in <LOCATION> Goiania </LOCATION> in the early afternoon, the hijacker permitted the injured crew members and another steward to be taken from the plane. <PERSON> Evangelista </PERSON> later died, <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> and air control officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Bradley-Trucks     09-29 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bradley-Trucks,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bradley Unveils Plan to Cut Truck Traffic</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> on Wednesday proposed a plan intended to cut the number of trucks traveling on highways leading into the nation's second-largest city during peak traffic hours. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s plan, which will be submitted to the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> for approval, is intended to keep 70 percent of heavy-duty truck fleets that normally operate during peak trafic hours off the road. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was joined by rerpesentatives of the area's trucking industry as he announced the plan. He said he did not blame truckers for <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' traffic woes. But he said it was their turn to help alleviate the traffic congestion that afflicts the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area. `` No one doubts that truck shipments are vital to our economy,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. `` The old saying ` If you got it, a truck brought it,' still largely applies. But there is no reason so many truck deliveries must be made during these peak rush-hour travel times,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. The mayor's plan would allow only 30 percent of large truck fleets to operate on city roadways from 6 a.m. to 9 a.m. and from 4 p.m. to 7 p.m. The 30 percent of the trucks that fleet owners decide to operate during peak hours would have to display a city certificate that could cost up to $ 60. Stiff fines would be levied if a trucker operated without the certificate. Trucks weighing 29,000 pounds or more would be subject to certification under the <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> plan. The $ 60 certificate fee would help fund a multi-agency `` rapid deployment force'' that <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said would quickly clear snarled surface streets and freeways of broken-down trucks and cars. The plan includes partial exemption for owner-operators of single trucks. They are allowed to use city roads either in the morning or the evening rush hour. The plan will also allow for a case-by-case exemption. City sanitation turcks and certain hazardous materials collection trucks also will be exempted under the <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> plan. Although the plan will only allow 30 percent of the large-fleet trucks that currently travel during rush-hour, analysts with the mayor's office estimate the partial exemption for owner-operators and the case-by-case examption will result in a cut of about 50 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-29 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VANCOUVER, British Columbia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> gave an art contest, but nobody won. Jurors decided the entries just were n't good enough `` It was a difficult situation but it was n't a difficult decision,'' said <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON>, director of the Vancouver Art Gallery. <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> was among the jurors who decided that none of the 380 entries deserved any of the $ 10,000 in prize money. But the show will go on. Even though prize money has not been awarded, the 20-odd finalists will be displayed at an exhibition opening Oct. 11. The contest was organized by the Federation of Canadian Artists and sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd </ORGANIZATION>. The theme of the competition, for which only British <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> artists were eligible, was `` water and its usefulness to industry.'' About 380 entries by 300 artists were submitted. `` We did n't see any work which we felt we could support for the prizes,'' <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` I had reservations about taking part in this event and those reservations have been confirmed.'' He said the jurors first looked at color slides of all the entries and could n't reach a decision. They then looked at the originals of about 20 potential winners without success. <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said his company was disappointed with the jury decision but has told the artist federation to keep the prize money and use it as it sees fit.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MOORESTOWN, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of people from around the country want to buy the antiquated penny parking meters that lined the streets of this <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> suburb for more than 30 years. But officials say the proposed sale has turned out to be a big headache. Initially, the township planned to trade in the 167 meters for new ones, but decided to sell them after being flooded with purchase requests, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON>, the township's finance director. `` If I had any idea -LRB- about the problems -RRB- I probably would have thought twice,'' <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON> said Wednesday. The township council scrapped a plan last week to sell the meters for $ 100 each through a lottery-by-mail after a resident charged the proposal was unfair because it gave preferential treatment to current and former residents, taxpayers and business owners. The resident, <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonberg </PERSON>, said the plan did not comply with a state statute on the disposal of municipal property. The township either must open up bidding for the meters, hold a public auction or trade them in, he said. Because of the controversy, <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON> said, the township is considering holding some form of bidding or auction. More than 600 prospective buyers have indicated they want a meter, <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON> said. In August, the community of 16,000 residents replaced the old-fashioned meters with nickel meters. The old meters, which dated from the 1950s, took a penny for 12 minutes of parking. But replacement parts became hard to find. <PERSON> Leonberg </PERSON> said he is even considering buying a meter, although he said `` they have no value at all.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-35Cats     09-29 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-35 Cats,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman, 35 Cats Wear Out Welcome</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORTH BRADDOCK, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For most people, house-hunting is no easy task. For <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> and her 35 felines, it's become a catastrophe. <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> thought she had found an ideal home a year ago when she moved into a seven-room house with a big yard in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Braddock </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> suburb with no law restricting pets. <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> said she told neighbors about the cats before she bought the house and was told they would not be a problem. `` Maybe they really did n't believe me when I said I had 35 cats,'' she said. In July, District Justice <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> found <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> guilty of harassment after neighbors claimed the cats damaged their lawn furniture and left paw prints on their cars. <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> has appealed to Common Pleas Court. <PERSON> Asher </PERSON> concedes the cats wandered outside her yard despite a new $ 3,800 fence that surrounds the home and is topped with an overhang that slants inward. Neighbors have pressed for passage of a local pet ordinance, and Council President <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Holt </PERSON> said the town's solicitor is drawing up a measure. Frustrated over continuing problems, <PERSON> Asher </PERSON>, 47, an employment training and placement specialist for the state, has put her house up for sale. `` I've made a lot of sacrifices to keep my little family together,'' said <PERSON> Asher </PERSON>, who also was evicted from an apartment in <LOCATION> Braddock </LOCATION> because of the cats.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-MissNicaragua     09-29 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Miss Nicaragua,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miss Nicaragua Misses Visa</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She may be a hit in her homeland, but Miss <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is strictly a miss in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a victim of chilly relations between nations. `` Yankee Administration Behaves Worse Than A Fool. They Deny Visa to the <PERSON> Belle </PERSON>,'' screamed a headline Wednesday in the pro-government newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuevo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diario </ORGANIZATION>. The newspaper said the reigning Miss <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, 19-year-old <PERSON> Gabriela </PERSON> <PERSON> Robleto </PERSON> <PERSON> Barquero </PERSON>, was denied a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visa this week to enter <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> for an international beauty contest. But a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy official in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION> said not even beauty queens can thaw the icy relations between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which has since 1981 backed the rebels known as Contras who are seeking to overthrow this country's leftist Sandinista government. `` She is just one of thousands of Nicaraguans to whom we've been unable to provide visa services because of the actions of the Nicaraguan government,'' said the diplomat, speaking in a telephone interview on condition of anonymity. `` The Nicaraguan refusal to issue visas to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic personnel prevents us from replacing our diplomats,'' he said. `` The embassy can not function in a normal manner when Nicaraguan actions are keeping us severely understaffed.'' The embassy stopped issuing visas to Nicaraguans in July, shortly after <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> expelled <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven diplomats, accusing them of trying to undermine the government. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> responded by expelling <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s ambassador and other diplomats The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official said Wednesday that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had in July requested official visas to replace the eight ousted American diplomats. He said those requests were not processed. American tourists do not need visas to enter <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Miss <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is not the most prominent victim of the visa war, however. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last week failed to process half of the requested visas requested by President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> for a visit to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> claimed the requests were made too late. <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> responded by canceling his trip.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0406EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-CrewSketches     09-29 1032</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Crew Sketches,1069</SECOND>
<HEAD>Capsule Sketches of Discovery's Five Astronauts</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are brief sketches of the astronauts who will fly aboard the space shuttle Discovery. <ORGANIZATION> NAVY </ORGANIZATION> CAPT. <PERSON> FREDERICK </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> HAUCK </PERSON>, who has flown on two previous shuttles since becoming an astronaut 10 years ago, will be commanding the first shuttle to fly since the Challenger blew up little more than a minute after it left the launchpad Jan. 28, 1986. <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>, 47, said he has had plenty of time to dwell on Challenger and wo n't be concentrating on that when he lifts off. `` There's no doubt I'll be looking at the screen, that when it says 73 seconds and it's counting upwards, I'll know we've passed that particular milestone. But it's not like I'm worried about it,'' he said in a recent interview. The former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> test pilot, who flew 114 combat and combat support missions in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, piloted the Challenger in June 1983 and commanded Discovery in November 1984 when the crew made the first space salvage mission in history, retrieving two disabled satellites. <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> grew up in <LOCATION> Winchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. He received a bachelor's degree from <ORGANIZATION> Tufts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a master's in nuclear engineering from the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> His wife, <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON>, and 25-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, planned to be at the launch, he said, but his 23-year-old son, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officer, is stationed on a ship that was sent to the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 AIR FORCE COL. <PERSON> RICHARD </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. <LOCATION> COVEY </LOCATION>, an astronaut for nearly 10 years, will pilot the shuttle on which he logged more than 170 hours in space on a previous flight. The 42-year-old former <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter and test pilot guided Discovery on an August 1985 mission and will be thinking about the Challenger astronauts when he lifts off on his new mission. `` I'll also be knowing that they would be pleased that we have gotten back to the point where we are going to fly again.'' His wife, <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON>, and daughters <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, 14, and <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>, 12 will attend the launch. <PERSON> Covey </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, and grew up in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Walton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. His late father was an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel He earned a bachelor's degree from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in 1968 and a master's in aeronautics and astronautics from <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> a year later. As an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> pilot, <PERSON> Covey </PERSON> flew 339 combat missions during two tours in southeast <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. He has flown more than 4,000 hours in more than 25 different types of aircraft.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 MARINE LT. COL. <PERSON> DAVID </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> HILMERS </PERSON>, an astronaut since 1980 and veteran of one previous shuttle flight, will be a mission specialist aboard Discovery. <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON>' first space flight was in October 1985 _ the maiden voyage of the orbiter Atlantis, on which he was a mission specialist. On Discovery, he will help deploy a $ 100 million communications satellite. <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON> grew up in <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and graduated with a bachelor's degree in mathematics, summa cum laude, from <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1972 He earned a master's degree in electrical engineering in 1977 and the degree of electrical engineer from the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Postgraduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1978. <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON> said that like the other astronauts, he will be thinking of their Challenger crew members. But, he added, `` I think that when it gets right down to the last couple of minutes, that we're going to be looking up at the sky and not behind us.'' <PERSON> Hilmers </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, have two sons, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, 13, and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON>, 9.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 GEORGE `` PINKY'' <PERSON> NELSON </PERSON> is the only one of Discovery's five-man crew who has walked in space. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 38, logged nine hours of space-walking on his first flight, aboard Challenger in April 1984. His second mission, on <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, began 16 days before the Challenger tragedy. On this launch, there are no plans for <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> to walk in space, unless something goes wrong in deploying a $ 100 million communications satellite. He is again a mission specialist and this time has the duty of blowing off an escape hatch and deploying a new escape pole for the five men if an emergency occurs. `` On the one point, you have to be doubly focused on what's happening On the other hand you just have to be soaking in this amazing experience,'' he said in a recent interview. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, an astronomer, is the only one on the five-man crew without a military background. He is the son of a high school science teacher, grew up in <LOCATION> Willmar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, and earned a bachelor's degree in physics from <ORGANIZATION> Harvey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mudd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1972 and a master's and doctorate in astronomy from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> in 1974 and His wife, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON>, and daughters, <PERSON> Aimee </PERSON> <PERSON> Tess </PERSON>, 16, and <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, 13, will be present for the liftoff.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> JOHN </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>'' LOUNGE, who first flew into space on Discovery in August 1985, will again be a mission specialist on <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s first flight in 2 -LCB- years. This time aboard Discovery, <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON>, 38, a former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> aviator, is the lead astronaut in charge of deploying the $ 100 million communications satellite. His other flight, which launched Aug. 27, 1985, is described by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> as its most successful shuttle mission so far, with astronauts deploying three satellites and repairing an ailing satellite. Lounge, of <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said the Challenger tragedy will add to the anxiety astronauts always feel during the first few moments after launch, <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> said. But, he said, once the spacecraft gets into space `` and it gets real quiet, my heartbeat will probably go down quite a bit.'' Lounge, a <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> native, received a B.S. degree in physics and mathematics from the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in 1969 and a master's in astrogeophysics from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION>. He completed a nine-month cruise in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> aboard the USS Enterprise and participated in 99 combat missions. He currently is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and flies with his unit at least once a week. He was selected as an astronaut in 1980. His family, including, his children <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, 17, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON>, 7, and <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>, 4, plan to be there for the liftoff.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0408EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czechoslovakia-Activist     09-29 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia-Activist,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Frees Opposition Activist</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An appeals court in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> has freed an activist who spent four months in prison for distributing leaflets critical of the government, an emigre source said. <PERSON> Jaroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Popelka </PERSON> began a hunger strike on Sept. 2, the day he was convicted of disturbing the public peace, and was ill when the appellate court in <LOCATION> Brno </LOCATION> ordered him freed on Tuesday, the source said. <PERSON> Popelka </PERSON>, 32, had been sentenced to eight months in jail and already had spent 21 weeks behind bars since his arrest, said the source, speaking on condition of anonymity. The appeals court on Tuesday also reduced the charge against him to infringing on public order. <PERSON> Popelka </PERSON> was arrested for passing out leaflets calling for `` genuine perestroika.'' Perestroika, or restructuring, is Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s term for his economic and political reforms. Two human rights activists were arrested for unfurling a banner that said `` Freedom for the political prisoner <PERSON> Jaroslav </PERSON> <PERSON> Popelka </PERSON>'' prior to the appeals court proceedings, the emigre said. They were later released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0408EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-SovietSpace     09-29 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Soviet Space,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet-French Mission Scheduled for November</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 30-day Soviet-French space mission in November will include a space walk by cosmonauts from both countries and an experiment designed to help choose building materials for a future French spacecraft, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported. The official Soviet news agency said Wednesday that the space flight, scheduled to begin Nov. 21, will have a more demanding program than a previous Soviet-French orbital mission in 1982 that only lasted eight days. Two French cosmonauts are vying for a position aboard the November flight _ Jean-Loup <PERSON> Chretien </PERSON> and <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tognini </PERSON>. The Soviet spaceman has not yet been named. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said the participants in the November mission are scheduled to dock with the orbiting space station Mir and unfold a metal contraption outside that could serve as the basic building block for future space platforms. The cosmonauts will also leave a panel of materials outside the Mir to test their performance in space. French scientists plan to use the materials in building a French spacecraft, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0410EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-MannedFlight     09-29 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Manned Flight,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Summary Of U.S. Manned Spaceflight Programs</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Space Shuttle, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a summary of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> manned space flights. Mercury -LRB- One-man capsules -RRB- _ Six flights, six astronauts, from May 5, 1961, to May 15-16, 1963. The shortest flight was the first, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, 15 minutes, 22 seconds; the longest was the last, <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, 22 orbits in 34 hours, 19 minutes. Gemini -LRB- Two-man capsules -RRB- _ Ten flights, 20 astronauts, from March 23, 1965, to Nov. 11-15, 1966. The longest flight was by <ORGANIZATION> Gemini </ORGANIZATION> 7, 14 days. Apollo -LRB- Three-man capsules -RRB- _ Eleven flights, 33 astronauts; from Oct. 11-22, 1968, to Dec. 7-19, 1972. Six landed on the moon, three circled; the longest was Apollo 17, 301 hours, 51 minutes. Skylab -LRB- Apollo capsule used to ferry three men each to a space station -RRB-; Three flights, 9 astronauts; from May 25-June 22, 1973, to Nov. 16, 1973-Feb. 8, 1974 Longest stay was 84 days, 1 hour, 15 minutes. Apollo-Soyuz -LRB- Joint U.S.-Soviet mission -RRB- One flight, three astronauts, two cosmonauts, July 15-24, 1975. Space Shuttle -LRB- Reusable winged spacecraft -RRB- _ 24 successful flights, with 91 astronauts, the first on April 12-14, 1981. Flight 25, the Challenger, exploded 73 seconds after liftoff, Jan. 28, 1986, with seven crew members, four of whom had flown before. Total Number <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> flights, including Challenger: 56. Number of crew members: 203.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0419EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpeedingJustice     09-29 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Speeding Justice,0631</SECOND>
<HEAD>`A Real Impact' _ Judge Sends Young Speeders To Meet Crash Victims</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CARL MANNING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MACON, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tired of teen-agers driving dangerously fast, Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> came up with an `` educational punishment'' that officials say may save lives by making the youths think twice. Youngsters convicted of going 80 mph or more in <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> are ordered to spend a day with high-speed accident victims, many unable to move more than their eyeballs in the hospital beds where they live out their lives. `` I've been on too many phone calls from the highway patrol saying that some youngster was killed in a car wreck. I'm sick of that,'' said <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, a county prosecutor for 23 years before becoming an associate circuit judge 1 -LCB- years ago. He is 53. `` I'm trying to reach youthful drivers who have 50 years ahead of them. You expect kids to make mistakes, but if you let them do nothing about it but mail in a fine, then what have you done to modify their behavior?'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> has sent about 30 speeders aged 16-21 to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missouri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> for a day of talking to doctors, nurses and other staff members along with some of the patients. The youngsters then have to write an essay about what they learned. If they fail to go to the hospital and write the essay, they risk losing their licenses. The hospital trip does not keep them from having to pay fines of $ 150 - $ 200 `` I really chew on these kids so they'll know what they did,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. Nobody making the trip to <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> has reappeared before him for speeding, the judge said, although one youth was later ticketed in another county. In one essay, a 17-year-old boy who had been caught going 94 mph summed up the effect of touring the intensive care unit, where tubes and wires keep patients alive: `` This scene was more disgusting than watching all of the Friday the 13th movies consecutively.'' He added, `` Although everyone makes mistakes, not everyone gets by as easily as I did. Some people will pay for their high-speed driving for the rest of their lives.'' Another speeder wrote that he gave up his motorcycle: `` I have lost my nerve and do n't want to have my luck run out. I want to live a long life.'' At the hospital, the teen-agers get a picture of what happens from the time a patient is admitted, through treatment and rehabilitation, said <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Cain </PERSON>, who runs the program and is coordinator of the hospital's head and spinal injury prevention project. `` They expect to see blood and guts and be frightened,'' she said. `` The real reality for them is seeing somebody trying to learn to eat or learn to speak. They see people doing things as basic as learning how to comb their hair.'' For the most part the patients are the same age as the speeders, which Ms. <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> said has a profound impact on them. `` The day slowly grows on them. They do n't come in and immediately see something that'll knock their socks off,'' she said. `` As the day goes on, they get quieter.'' One turning point in their feelings, she said, is having lunch with a 21-year-old quadriplegic. `` It makes a real impact on them. He's pretty blunt with telling them what his life is like.'' Ms. <PERSON> Cain </PERSON> and <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said it is too early to assess the program's impact on the speeders but both believe it is paying benefits `` At least we can see where we get their attention and they learn something,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0421EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChineseMedicine     09-29 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chinese Medicine,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hong Kong Researchers Try To Unlock Secrets Of Chinese Medicine</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A university research center here has started to unlock the secrets of the centuries-old Chinese tradition of using herbs, deer antlers, dried seahorses and other exotica as medicines. Some scientists believe the medicines could help improve modern health care. Chinese medicine also has long been popular in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and sales have boomed in recent years. `` Sales of herbs have gone up because they have preventative functions and do not have side effects,'' said <PERSON> Lau </PERSON> <PERSON> Pun </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheung </PERSON>, president of the 600-member <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchants </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicinal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Material </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> was set up 12 years ago to investigate the traditional prescriptions and disseminate its findings. The program involves compiling an exhaustive English-language database on Chinese medicine and conducting experiments with traditional prescriptions to determine their efficacy. `` We wish to open up this treasure house of information to worldwide research,'' director <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Hson-mou </PERSON> explained of the center's computer system that stores botanical, chemical, pharmacological and clinical reports of common Chinese herbs. The data is constantly updated with information from about 180 journals from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, he said. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> acknowledged that some Communist Chinese authorities originally resisted the program, claiming that giving foreign researchers access to information about traditional medicine was similar to giving away state secrets. They later backed down, <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said, and the center now stores more than 700 items used in Chinese medicine, including herbs, ginseng -LRB- the white root of a carrot-like plant -RRB-, shells, insects, frog secretion, deer tails and minerals such as sulphur and gypsum. Scientists at the center are analyzing selected prescriptions made of such material in search of active ingredients that could provide clues to developing new drugs. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said researchers recently analyzed a series of popular formulas known as `` anshen zhenjing,'' or tranquilizers, and discovered an active ingredient with effects similar to the popular Western drug Valium. `` Although these herbs have been used for generations, the active component ... had not been uncovered,'' he said. The center's scientists have learned how to synthesize the compound, which has attracted the interest of five pharmaceutical companies. The center also is using modern detectors to examine herbs used by Chinese hospitals for treatment of serious heart conditions such as acute myocardial infarction _ the blocking of the heart vessel. `` This is not a placebo,'' <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said of the prescription. `` The result seems to be quite good.'' Another project involves basic research into the use of Chinese medicine to reinforce the body's immune system. `` This is a hot topic because of AIDS,'' <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said, but he cautioned that the center is not trying to develop a wonder drug to cure that fatal disease. `` The Chinese immunology approach is to go slow, to recover your natural balance,'' he said. The experiments are designed to separate the useless from useful in Chinese medicine, <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said. He expressed skepticisim, for example, that any of the hundreds of traditional Chinese prescriptions for hepatitis can be effective. `` We have analyzed only a few, but I am doubtful,'' he said. <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> said well over half the respondents to a 1983 university survey said they used traditional medicine or acupuncture to supplement Western medicine. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, general manager of Bristol-Myers -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> HK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> -RRB- </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, said the U.S.-based international pharmaceutical company is keeping an eye on the center's research. `` It could develop new leads,'' he said. `` It's new ground, a new field.'' Other programs in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> also are bringing traditional Chinese medicine into the computer age. For example, the research institute of the local <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Practitioners </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has developed a system in which a patient's symptoms are entered into a computer program that then determined what traditional prescription would be best. The program is used primarily by junior practitioners to help them learn the art of diagnosis, said <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ying-chee </PERSON>, president of the institute.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0441EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OlympicSecurity     09-29 0617</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Olympic Security,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Several Factors In Korean Clampdown As Games Near Their End</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES J. HANLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The South Koreans, world-class friskers and scanners, are drawing their tight security net even tighter around the Olympics as the sports spectacular heads toward its final days. <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s tough-talking student radicals are threatening to disrupt Sunday's marathon. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security specialist says his biggest worry is the anti-Americanism surfacing among ordinary <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION>. One Korean official finds the real security threat coming from the athletes themselves _ one might defect and put the Olympic hosts in an awkward position. After 12 days of Games, the security concerns at <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> are often in the eye of the beholder. But by Wednesday everyone could see the new Olympics-wide clampdown. For the first time, for example, police bomb-sniffing dogs were deployed at the Olympic weightlifting hall. At the Olympic press center, the security men blocked driveways with more steel barriers, checked car trunks and undercarriages for bombs, and closely searched visitors and journalists. `` We increased the vigil,'' one Olympic security official said. The tightening up coincided with Tuesday's announcement that an anti-government student leader jailed since last week had been formally charged under the tough <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION>, which covers sedition and similar acts. Oh Young-sik's followers have threatened to disrupt Olympic events, including Sunday's men's marathon, a 26-mile run through the heart of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, unless he is freed. The marathon, vulnerable because of its length and route, is expected to be well-guarded by police strung out along the boulevards and by commandos trailing along in armored vehicles. But some questioned whether <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s militant students were the main target of the stepped-up security, since the students favor symbolic street clashes with police, rather than car bombs or other terror blows against innocent civilians. Had authorities detected a sudden threat from international terrorists, such as the shadowy, ultra-leftist <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>? `` Categorically, no,'' said an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> official who works closely with the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> security authorities. This informant, who like most security officials here spoke on condition of anonymity, suggested that the Koreans reinforced their security apparatus simply because it had grown more lax since opening day, Sept. 17. `` They had let their socks down a little bit,'' he said. Of the Korean protective net, involving more than 100,000 security personnel, the American said: `` It's working. And not only have there been no big plots, there have not even been attempted plots. ... `` We're more concerned now about the mood swings of the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> people, the anti-Americanism.'' <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> newspapers have been flooded with letters and calls from ordinary Koreans angry over the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> athletes' unruly, `` arrogant'' behavior during the opening ceremony, Americans' boisterous cheering at sports events, the `` biased'' reporting by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> news media of an Olympic boxing incident in which Korean officials attacked a referee, and the theft of an expensive bar ornament by two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swimmers. On Tuesday night, another American got in trouble. Runner <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> was arrested after he kicked a taxi door in a dispute with the driver. He was later released. Meanwhile, down at the Olympic Village, where the athletes reside, village Director-General <PERSON> Ryu </PERSON> <PERSON> Keun-ha </PERSON> has other things on his mind. He told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> that his security people would thoroughly check names of departing athletes against official lists to ensure that none tries to defect. `` We will pay our utmost attention to prevent any undesirable incidents,'' he was quoted as saying. In an unusual move, the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> government, eager to establish relations with <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc countries, has announced it will not grant political asylum to any athletes who seek to defect.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-JudgeCensured     09-29 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Judge Censured,0491</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Supreme Court Censures Judge For Remarks To Woman Later
Slain</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state's highest court censured a district court judge Wednesday for `` discourtesy, rudeness and sarcasm'' to a woman involved in a domestic dispute case who later was slain by her husband. The state Supreme Judicial court recommended private censure for <ORGANIZATION> Somerville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> for his courtroom treatment of <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Nigro </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, who was murdered by her husband, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, in August 1986. Private censure involves no fine, penalty or loss of judicial power. The case stemmed from charges by <PERSON> Mrs. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>'s family that <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> humiliated and belittled her in court hearings. The high court dismissed allegations of a pattern of such conduct by <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON>, noting that he granted Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>'s request for court protection from her husband. It said no connection existed between <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON>'s courtroom demeanor and her murder. <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON>, 55, of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, did not return phone calls seeking comment. His attorney, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said the judge accepts the <ORGANIZATION> SJC </ORGANIZATION> ruling. <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Nigro </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>'s mother, called the ruling too lenient. `` I'm not saying he was the cause of her murder, but just the way he handles women in court is wrong.'' A central incident in the case stemmed from a March 14, 1986, hearing before <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> in which Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, who had been beaten by her husband, sought permission to return to retrieve her clothes from her husband's house. At that hearing, <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> interrupted Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> and said, `` I do n't think it's the role of this court to decide down to each and every piece of underwear who owns what. As a matter of fact, I find it a little ridiculous to be involved in it.'' At a March 26, 1986, hearing with both husband and wife present, <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> told <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, `` Let's get this matter resolved. O.K.? You want to gnaw on her or she on you, fine, but let's not do it at the taxpayers' expense.'' Five months after that hearing, <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> murdered his wife and disposed of her body at a town dump. He has been convicted of first-degree murder. <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> `` was rude and sarcastic during portions of the <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> proceeding. A single listening to the tape recording of those hearings establishes those facts,'' the justices said in their 11-page ruling. The decision noted that <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON>'s `` loud, deep voice -LRB- and -RRB- physically imposing manner,'' contributed to the intimidation of Mrs. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>. The court said it was `` troubling for the future,'' that <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> refused in testimony before the state <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judicial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conduct </ORGANIZATION> to admit his demeanor was intimidating. <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON>'s attorney, said <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> had voluntarily withdrawn from domestic dispute cases and had no mmediate plans to resume hearing them. And he said <PERSON> Heffernan </PERSON> has tried to tone down the resonance of his voice in court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MetzenbaumAideIndicted     09-29 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Metzenbaum Aide Indicted,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Metzenbaum Aide Indicted For Illegal Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DWIGHT WOODWARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former aide to Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> was indicted Wednesday on charges of accepting illegal payments from <LOCATION> Polish </LOCATION> immigrants trying to become <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens and enter <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> was indicted by a federal grand jury for allegedly agreeing to accept $ 2,000 from <PERSON> Waclaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Pietrzykowsky </PERSON> for helping get a friend of <PERSON> Pietrzykowsky </PERSON>'s admitted to the veterinary school, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Special Agent <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. The indictment also alleges <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> accepted $ 300 for assisting <PERSON> Irena </PERSON> <PERSON> Boc </PERSON> in gaining <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. He said no other <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> aide was involved in the allegations. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said Wednesday he had notified the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> 22 months ago of the allegations a constituent raised against <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> informed me that they completed their investigation of Mr. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> in November of 1987,'' the senator said. `` Why has it taken the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> almost a year to seek the indictment is a question that remains to be answered.'' On July 19, 1987, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported the evidence was credible enough to go to a grand jury and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> was fired, <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> said. A spokesman for the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, office of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was unavailable for comment Wednesday night. <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> attorney, said Wednesday he had not received a copy of the indictment. `` I have to assume my client is innocent,'' <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> lives in a <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> suburb but <PERSON> Giuliani </PERSON> declined to give his address and the <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> telephone directory has no listing for a <PERSON> Ladd </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicalFees Bjt   09-29 0866</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medical Fees, Bjt,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Recommends Massive Changes in Medicaid Payments to Doctors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Family physicians are grossly underpaid relative to surgeons and other high-priced specialists, says a long-awaited report laying the groundwork for potentially massive changes in the way medicine is practiced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Ordered up by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> three years ago, the 2,000-page survey released Wednesday is certain to spark sharp debate in the medical profession and beyond. If the study recommendations were applied immediately, heart surgeons would suffer a 45 percent reduction in their <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> fees and general practitioners would receive a 65 percent raise. But because of the complex and emotionally loaded issues surrounding any discussion of health care _ not to mention the competition for dollars and cents _ no one is predicting an early and literal application. That is not to say the preliminary skirmishing will not begin immediately and be intense. Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roper </PERSON>, head of the federal agency that pays the medical bills for more than 31 million elderly and disabled Americans on Medicare, held out the prospect Wednesday that there are some things a budget-conscious <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> `` might want to do in 1989 before the mega-debate'' is completed. For example, he said, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> might use the study as a rationale for trimming some Medicare-approved payments from the top end of the scale without adding much or anything at the bottom end. `` Nobody is going to get 65 percent more from Medicare next year, for example,'' he said. Even the father of the $ 2.3 million study told reporters it would not be practical to implement its recommendations at once. <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> medical economist <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON> said a five-year phase in period might be needed. <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON>'s study pointedly does not say any category of physician is overpaid or underpaid in actual dollars and cents _ but rather that the way they divide the financial pie is unfair and potentially detrimental to sound medical treatment. Officially, it is entitled `` A National Study of Resource-based <ORGANIZATION> Relative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Value </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scales </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> For </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Physicians </ORGANIZATION>' Services.'' In simplest terms, what <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON>'s work suggests is that if a physician faces the option of performing surgery or using an equally promising but less financially rewarding treatment, the present fee system encourages surgery. His proposal would attempt to change that. `` You can predict that under the new system, doctors will be willing to spend a lot more time with patients to examine and counsel them,'' <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON> said. `` Right now, physicians are being penalized financially for spending time with patients.'' Moreover, he said, the changes could encourage more young doctors to go into primary patient care and lower the overall cost of medical treatment. <PERSON> Roper </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, hailed <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON>'s work although he expressed reservations about whether it should serve as the basis for a wholesale revision of Medicare pay scales. <PERSON> Roper </PERSON>'s agency contracted for the $ 2.3 million study. He said it provides a scientific basis for `` what medical observers have known for some time.'' He cautioned that the new system advocated in the report would not necessarily constrain overall medical costs _ which are rising far faster than any other segment of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy _ and `` could worsen the ... problem if the resulting income redistributions encourage those physicians who face fee reductions to increase the volume or intensity of services.'' Even though the impact of the report is likely to take years to percolate throughout the health care system, the attention it is generating within the profession is intense. The Journal of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> is devoting its entire next issue to the subject, and the <ORGANIZATION> AMA </ORGANIZATION>'s house of delegates will vote in December on whether to endorse <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON>'s plan. While the study originated with a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> struggling to get a handle on skyrocketing <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> costs, it also could affect the way private insurers determine how much they will pay for particular services. And although doctors technically are not limited in how much they charge by how much public or private insurance will pay, their insured patients _ their customers _ become acutely aware of the cost of medical care when they have to pay part of the bill out of their own pockets. The first summaries of <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON>'s work, along with an editorial commentary by <PERSON> Roper </PERSON>, appeared in The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> of Journal of Medicine at the same time the study was formally delivered to <ORGANIZATION> HCFA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hsiao </PERSON> tried to determine how much work is involved in 2,000 duties performed by doctors in 14 specialties. He and colleagues took into consideration malpractice insurance premiums and other costs, specialty training, time, mental effort, technical skill, physical effort and psychological stress. For each task, he came up with a non-monetary value. For instance, a comprehensive visit by a new patient to a family practitioner is 248, while a well-baby visit is 64. An appendectomy is 621, a pacemaker insertion is 620, and a triple coronary bypass is 2,871. To figure out how much doctors will get, these values would be multiplied by a monetary conversion figure. If the figure were $ 1, for example, a well-baby visit would be worth $ 64 and an appendectomy $ 621.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0531EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-Opera     09-29 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>Met Presents First Ring Cycle Opera</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This season the Metropolitan Opera will stage all four operas in <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s Ring Cycle and on Wednesday, the third night of the season, it presented the first one, `` Das Rheingold.'' Casting was carefully done. As the Met chose singers who knew the Handel style for its second-night `` <PERSON> Guilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesare </PERSON>,'' the singers in `` Das Rheingold'' knew the <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> style. Two were making very fine debuts. <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, sang <LOCATION> Fricka </LOCATION>, wife of <PERSON> Wotan </PERSON>, leader of the gods. The mezzo-soprano, who has sung at <LOCATION> Bayreuth </LOCATION> since 1975, has the needed volume and has her vibrato under control. Through much of the opera she is concerned about her sister <PERSON> Freia </PERSON> and her voice always sounded sympathetic, with a sweet overtone. <PERSON> Wotan </PERSON>, sung by <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Sotin </PERSON>, has a dark voice that sounds full of compassion, even when he's laying down the law. Seldom does one hear this couple sound so understanding and kind. Mezzo-soprano <PERSON> Birgitta </PERSON> <PERSON> Svenden </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vuollerim </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, made her debut as <PERSON> Erda </PERSON>, who comes out of a hole in the ground near the end of the opera to tell <PERSON> Wotan </PERSON> to surrender the ring. Her voice was very clear and pleasing. Miss <PERSON> Svenden </PERSON> has sung at <LOCATION> Bayreuth </LOCATION> for four seasons. She will sing <PERSON> Erda </PERSON> with the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> in 1989 and for her debut at Covent Garden in 1990. She has recorded <PERSON> Erda </PERSON> in `` Rheingold'' and `` Siegfried'' with <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> and the Met Orchestra. Clarity ruled the evening. <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> conducted so that singers could be heard. The <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Schenk </PERSON> production, with sets and projections by <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider-Siemssen </PERSON>, new last October, is lighted by <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wechsler </PERSON> so that singers can be seen. Almost everybody sang clearly. <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazura </PERSON> was outstanding as <PERSON> Alberich </PERSON>, who steals the gold from the <LOCATION> Rhine </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and later puts a curse on anybody who wears the ring he made from it. <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerusalem </PERSON> as Loge had a much-textured voice, rich but with a con man's inflections. <PERSON> Horst </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiestermann </PERSON>'s Mime was effective, though less squeaky than the usual interpretation. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Macurdy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Matti </PERSON> <PERSON> Salminen </PERSON> were expansive vocally, as the giants. <PERSON> Kaaren </PERSON> <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kesling </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON> blended well as the <ORGANIZATION> Rhinemaidens </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0449EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-SovietSpace     09-29 0103</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Soviet Space,0104</SECOND>
<HEAD>While America Recovered from Challenger, Soviets Were Busy In
Space</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 During the 32 months <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s shuttle fleet has been grounded, the Soviets have launched 16 men into space aboard six spacecraft All of them visited the Mir space station, and one of them, <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Romanenko </PERSON>, logged a record 326 days there in 1987. Two of the three cosmonauts currently aboard the station have been there since last Dec. 21 and space officials said the three would stay there a full year. The Soviets say the long-duration flights are preparing humans for trips to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushPlan Bjt   09-29 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Plan, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush Savings Plan Fails to Impress Many Analysts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s proposed tax break for saving does n't amount to much of a benefit, according to most analysts, although one <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> economist says it could be an incentive for new parents to set aside money for a child's college education. Under the right conditions, says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Makin </PERSON> of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, after 20 years a savings account at withdrawal using the vice president's proposal would have earned 22.5 percent more than under current law. But that assumes an account could earn 10 percent a year _ which it generally would not now _ and that the family was in the 28 percent tax bracket, which would cut out a large number of families that the proposal is designed to help. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Minarik </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> used a different calculation and reached a decidedly less upbeat conclusion. `` I do n't think it is a good idea. The benefit to the saver is quite small,'' he said. In addition, <PERSON> Minarik </PERSON> said, `` any benefit to the saver comes dollar for dollar from the federal treasury.'' And because the government is spending more than it takes in, enactment of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal would mean `` the government is borrowing so the individual can save. Some might suggest that's not necessarily a wise thing for the government to do.'' <PERSON> Makin </PERSON> acknowledges that `` it's going to look a lot less attractive if you are talking five years -LRB- of contributions rather than 20 -RRB- and a 15 percent tax bracket'' rather than 28 percent. `` It's better than nothing, but it's not going to change the world dramatically,'' he says. According to <PERSON> Makin </PERSON>'s calculation, a couple in the 28 percent bracket fortunate enough to deposit $ 1,000 a year for 20 years and earn 10 percent could withdraw $ 57,275 and, after subtracting the $ 20,000 principal and paying tax, be left with $ 26,838. Without the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> incentive, the money would have earned $ 4,936 less, or $ 21,902. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> offered the broad outlines of his proposal while campaigning Tuesday in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. He billed the plan as an incentive for low - and middle-income Americans to save more and, thus, foster economic growth Under the proposal, a taxpayer could set aside up to $ 1,000 a year in an account, leave it intact for at least five years, and earnings on the money would be tax-free until withdrawn. The full $ 1,000 a year would be available only to people with adjusted gross incomes of $ 50,000 or less. The benefit would decline as income rises above that figure and disappear when income tops $ 60,000. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal should not be confused with Individual Retirement Accounts. Since the 1986 tax overhaul any worker not covered by a company pension may contribute up to $ 2,000 a year to an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> and pay no tax on the contribution or its interest until withdrawn. Workers who have a company pension and make less than $ 50,000 may qualify for some deduction. But the big difference between IRAs and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan is the deduction. Most workers may fully deduct their <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> contribution; no one could deduct the annual contribution under the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal. The only tax benefit would be deferral of taxes on interest earned by the annual contributions. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> has not analyzed the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal but said that generally conservative organization supports encouraging increased saving through tax incentives rather than by raising taxes. Some in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> are suggesting a federal sales tax to encourage saving; they reason that since the tax would apply only to money that is spent, most people with a choice would choose to save. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McIntyre </PERSON>, director of Citizens for <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal research organization, views the vice president's proposal as a way to undo the tax overhaul enacted in 1986. `` This is just another move to turn it around,'' he said. <PERSON> McIntyre </PERSON> calculated that the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan would be worth an extra $ 471 to a couple in the 28 percent bracket whose $ 1,000 contribution earned 10 percent a year for 10 years. `` What's the point?'' he asked. He said the far more valuable IRAs are used by only 8 percent of people at the $ 30,000 income level. `` Nobody uses them because they do n't have the money, and they would n't have the money for the less attractive'' accounts that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposed, <PERSON> McIntyre </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0445EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-29 0890</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agriculture Department Signs Deal To Import Chinese Hogs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If animal scientists have their way, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> consumers some day may be eating bacon that has its roots in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says a `` historic agreement to import Chinese breeding swine'' has been reached and that the pact may help upgrade the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pork industry. Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> said Wednesday the contract involves <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s ministry of agriculture, and the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Breeding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Import </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Export </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The imports will include 144 pigs of the <LOCATION> Meishan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ming </PERSON> and Fengjing breeds, he said. The animals will be used in research studies under a cooperative agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s meat animal research laboratory at Clay Center, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. No other details of the agreement were announced, but a department spokesman, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, said the financing arrangements were handled by the two universities. <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, a hog farmer from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has about 100 breeds of swine that represent a `` unique reservoir of unexplored germplasm'' that could offer potential benefits for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> industry. Germplasm is semen and other genetic material. `` This unexploited source ... could prove to be very valuable to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research programs on resistance to diseases, parasites and improvement of some production traits,'' he said. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has a long history in the domestication of pigs that can be traced back for at least 6,000 years.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> reports, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> also is the world's largest hog producer. At the end of 1983, for example, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> had an inventory of 298.5 million hogs, compared with 55.8 million for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at that time. A goal of the import program is to cross the Chinese breeds with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> breeds to increase litter size, and at the same time maintain the quality and lean yield of pork. The breeds being imported have three to four more pigs per litter than the average <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> breed. The animals will be imported in late March 1989 after spending 60 days in quarantine in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and meeting other health requirements. They will be quarantined again for 120 days at <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s animal import center in <LOCATION> Fleming </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, before being released for research <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerrits </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said scientists hope to conduct at least five years of research to evaluate the animals and determine if they should be released for use by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swine industry. <PERSON> Gerrits </PERSON> said that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swine geneticists recognized the potential value of Chinese swine more than 10 years ago, but `` satisfactory health and quarantine requirements were not completed'' until last year. `` The three breeds selected for the research studies are highly prolific,'' he said. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> geneticists estimate it would take at least 30 generations of conventional selection to increase the litter size of the average <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> swine breed to the level routinely produced by these Chinese breeds.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it has resumed research into the growing and use of kenaf, a fibrous plant that can be used to make paper, after a decade of being on the back burner. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waterworth </PERSON>, coordinator of kenaf research for <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday that $ 300,000 is being spent this year in kenaf studies through agency laboratories in <LOCATION> Lane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Weslaco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Another $ 300,000 is scheduled for 1989. `` Industry trials, including test runs by several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> newspapers, indicate that pulp from kenaf makes newsprint paper that is as sturdy as woodpulp paper but generally is brighter, consumes less ink and has less ink ruboff,'' <PERSON> Waterworth </PERSON> said. Kenaf can be grown in southern <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> states such as <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, he said. The plants grow 15 to 18 feet in height in less than five months and can reach about 22 feet. An acre yields 7 to 10 tons of dry fiber. The <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> -LRB- Ill. -RRB- <PERSON> Journal-Star </PERSON> in 1977 was the first newspaper to make a press run on kenaf newsprint. At least eight other newspapers have had similar tests, including the most recent in July 1987 at the <LOCATION> Bakerfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Californian </LOCATION>. Agency research on kenaf was suspended in 1978 when supplies of paper pulp were plentiful and prices were down, <PERSON> Waterworth </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has spent about $ 900,000 to support commercial development of kenaf through private industry since 1986, and the new funds for research are expected `` to give additional support'' to that enterprise, he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has bought an additional 250,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn for delivery during the coming year, says the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The sale, announced Wednesday, raised total corn sold to the Soviets in the last four weeks to more than 3.75 million tons. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn. The 250,000 tons of corn would be about 9.85 million bushels. Corn prices have been averaging about $ 2.61 per bushel at the farm level, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates, meaning that the latest sale could have a farm value of around $ 26 million. A five-year long-term grain agreement with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will expire Sept. 30 and negotiators are trying to work out a new one, or at least an extension of the current agreement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0451EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicalWaste     09-29 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medical Waste,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Moving On Law To Tighten Controls On Medical Waste</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is preparing to force the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to combat a mounting wave of infectious medical waste washing up on the nation's shores. The latest step in the process came Wednesday when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> gave voice-vote approval to legislation that would require creation-to-disposal controls on things such as used syringes. The action all but guaranteed that before adjourning next month <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will respond to the tides of used syringes and AIDS-contaminated materials that appeared this summer in <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> and at beaches in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. The bill, which backers say will be passed next week by the full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, is similar to legislation approved in August by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Staffers on both sides of the Capitol say they expect no problems resolving differences between the two plans. `` The illegal disposal of medical waste is spreading like an epidemic,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, principal sponsor of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill. `` Much of this waste is infectious. It can literally kill people. All of it is repulsive and frightening.'' <PERSON> Luken </PERSON> said that in <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a physician put used syringes in a trash bin. `` Kids found the needles and played ` doctor' with them, giving each other injections that could have proved fatal.'' The legislation would require <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to set up a system to track infectious medical waste generated in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and the eight states bordering the Great Lakes. However, the regional demonstration program could become national in scope because any state would be allowed to opt for coverage under rules that would require a paper trail from waste generation to disposal. `` Tracking helps stop midnight dumping,'' <PERSON> Luken </PERSON> said. `` Hospitals and clinics will now know where their medical waste is going, and so will <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>.'' The bill proposes stiff penalties: a civil fine of up to $ 25,000 for each day of violation and a maximum criminal penalty of 15 years in prison and a daily violation fine of up to $ 50,000. Committee members said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is being forced to act because <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> had failed to issue regulations _ first proposed 10 years ago but then quickly dropped _ ensuring proper disposal of waste created in hospitals, laboratories and clinics. `` This is not just a question of a bloody syringe washing up on a beach on the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore. `` The medical waste system in this country is broken and inefficient and is regurgitating what it ca n't keep down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0453EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InsiderTrading-Defense     09-29 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Insider Trading-Defense,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consultant Said To Have Met With Navy Official</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> consultant charged with insider trading involving a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contract discussed the project with a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> assistant secretary who has been named as a target in the government's defense procurement probe, according to the consultant's attorney. Charles A. Mills of <LOCATION> Beachwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, who had served as a consultant to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in a project to develop a new generation of blimps, agreed Wednesday to pay $ 9,315 to settle a civil complaint filed by the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> said it was continuing its investigation, and its complaint cited a meeting between <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> and `` a certain then assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>,'' whom it did not identify further. However, sources speaking on condition of anonymity indicated it was <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, who was assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for research, engineering and systems, and has since been named as a target of a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> probe into <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> purchasing practices. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s attorney, said his client has not been subpoenaed or otherwise notified by the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> that he is the subject of an investigation. Moreover, he said the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> complaint does not imply that the unidentified assistant secretary did anything improper. According to the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> complaint, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, in his role as a consultant from February to May 1987, had access to confidential information about competing bids for a contract worth $ 168.9 million to develop a prototype of a radar-surveillance blimp to help protect <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> fleets. Through meetings with Naval officials, including one on March 13, 1987 attended by the unidentified assistant secretary, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> learned the officials favored a bid from a joint venture of <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Airship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Cardington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> alleged. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schupper </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>' attorney, said his client told him Wednesday that he met once with <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> and other officials for five or 10 minutes, but was not certain of the date. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> announced the contract award June 5. A day earlier, according to the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> purchased receipts on the over-the-counter market in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the purchase of <ORGANIZATION> Airship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> stock, which is traded in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> sold the receipts June 8 and 9, earning a profit of $ 4,658, the agency said. Without admitting or denying the charges, <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> agreed to return the profits and pay an equal amount as a penalty. The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> also said `` certain assistant secretaries of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'' were briefed on the bid award June 3 and 4. By that time, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, who was appointed assistant secretary in 1981, was out of government, according to <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON>. The blimp contract had a potential value of $ 3 billion if the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> had decided to build a fleet of airships. However, the program was scrapped following agreement between the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in late 1987 on a plan to reduce the federal budget deficit. <PERSON> Schupper </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> had not believed he did anything wrong and cooperated fully with the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>. `` In light of his health and his financial resources, he believes that the settlement represents a fair resolution of conflicting conclusions drawn from basically the same facts,'' <PERSON> Schupper </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is investigating whether private consultants, many of them former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees, paid bribes to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials for inside information about contracts, chiefly within the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. The probe became public in June after subpoenas were issued in the case. No one has been charged yet. Investigators have searched <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s home looking for evidence that he took payments from defense contractors while he was at the Pentagon. Investigators also have alleged in court papers that while <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> was a consultant to <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, he improperly provided the company with secret <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> documents about its competitors. Through his attorney, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> has said the government has provided no evidence to support such allegations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0454EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget     09-29 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress May Complete Its Spending Bills On Time _ For a Change</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the White House may be about to accomplish something they've not done since <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> was president _ enact all federal spending bills before the start of the fiscal year. Although it's not likely to spark a giddy citizenry into launching fireworks, approval by Saturday of all 13 spending bills would be a political coup for both parties. It's already inspired people on both ends of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> to begin publicly patting themselves on the back. `` We're showing that we can govern,'' Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., the No 3 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leader, said Wednesday. `` The warning has been taken to heart,'' said President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. He was referring to a promise he made in January that if the spending measures were wrapped into a single piece of legislation, he would veto it. As the start of the new fiscal year approaches, lawmakers and the administration are working out disputes that in ordinary years could take weeks or months to resolve. Thus, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who signed his first appropriations bill for the new year on July 19, signed the sixth into law Wednesday, a measure appropriating $ 8.8 billion for military construction. In addition, a $ 15 billion spending measure for the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> and State departments and a $ 10.8 billion transportation bill were on his desk. Legislative action on the five remaining appropriations measures was scheduled for today and Friday. This is no ordinary year. It's an election year, and Republicans and Democrats want to avoid any blame for a replay of last year's budget embarrassment `` In an election year, neither side wanted to face responsibility for a massive CR,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, using the initials for `` continuing resolution'' _ legislative lingo for a giant spending bill. `` This helps incumbents, period,'' said <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>. `` The more you make the process work, the more you help incumbents.'' Last December, after a year of inconclusive squabbling between <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed a 1,400-page, $ 600 billion behemoth that contained all the money federal agencies needed to function this year. Within hours of receiving it, the president signed it. The alternative was shutting down the government. In January, an angry <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used his nationally televised State of the Union address to promise to veto any similar bill this year. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> leaders called on the president to work with them to smooth out any disputes that might arise, and pledged to avoid a catchall measure for 1989. The most serious stumbling block this year had been defense spending. But on Wednesday, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> resolved a long-running dispute over <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> and arms control restrictions with both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approving a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> authorization bill. That made congressional action possible by Friday on a separate $ 300 billion Pentagon spending measure. The quicker-than-usual action this year is due in part to last fall's budget summit agreement between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and congressional leaders. In that pact, both sides agreed to broad spending totals for 1989, leaving only less-sweeping issues to be worked out. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> and other Democrats are crediting their own leadership for the rapid movement of the spending bills. `` We announced at the beginning of the year that we'd do it,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. Even if all 13 bills are not enacted by 12:01 a.m. Saturday, there would be little immediate impact. Federal workers deemed essential _ including the military _ would be permitted to work over the weekend. Government agencies would not have to shut down unless spending legislation was not in place by Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0502EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Hotel     09-29 0567</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Hotel,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reporters' Notebook: With Reagan at the Waldorf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, his trip to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> meant a dramatic farewell appearance. For fellow guests at his hotel, it meant something of a nuisance. For reporters and photographers, it meant scrambling up and down stairwells, waiting in line in a hotel kitchen and getting stuck in an elevator. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spoke at the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, making his seventh appearance there and his last before he leaves office in January. After his speech, he went to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mission </LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> for lunch. It's just across the street, so most people would walk. Presidential security, however, required that he make the crossing by motorcade.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Then it was off to the <LOCATION> Waldorf-Astoria </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, a few blocks away. The Waldorf had warned its guests of what was coming. `` It is my great pleasure to tell you that President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be staying in the <ORGANIZATION> Waldorf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Towers </ORGANIZATION> during your stay in the hotel,'' manager <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cotter </PERSON> said in a letter handed out at the registration desk. `` Unfortunately, however, it may mean some inconvenience for you,'' <PERSON> Cotter </PERSON> added. `` To ensure the president's safety, the Park Avenue entrance will be closed from 5:30 to 7:30 p.m. on Monday evening. Please be so kind as to enter and exit the hotel from the <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> area.'' One woman entering the hotel from <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> still found herself inconvenienced when she was asked by a White House aide to step aside while the traveling pool of journalists made their way through the door. `` But we're staying here,'' she protested.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Once inside, the pool was taken by elevator to a holding room on the 33rd floor to wait until it was time to walk up three floors to where the president was holding the first in a series of meetings with foreign leaders. After a brief picture-taking and question-asking opportunity, the scribes scrambled back down to the holding room to file stories by telephone and wait for the next meeting. In a few minutes, however, a harried assistant manager of the hotel showed up to announce that the room set aside as the holding room turned out to be part of a suite rented to a permanent hotel guest. So it was out in the hall for the reporters and their telephones.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The next event after the series of meetings was an evening reception in a room decked with magnificent crystal chandeliers. To get to it, reporters were ushered through the kitchen, past tray after tray of dirty dishes, before standing in line to have security officers check their equipment. Next morning, reporters were assembled in their third-floor press room and taken to three elevators for the ride back up to the 33rd floor to wait for more meetings. At the ninth floor, one of the elevators got stuck for 10 minutes. Word of the mishap apparently even got to the president. When the media people arrived on the 36th floor for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s meeting with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sahabzada </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaqub </PERSON> <PERSON> Khan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the president told them, `` You seem like you've been breathing hard I'm trying to pick out the ones who had to walk up the stairs.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880929-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-88 0503EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganTrade     09-29 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Trade,540</SECOND>
