<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MethodistMeeting Bjt 1stLd-Writethru 05-03 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Methodist Meeting, Bjt, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0763,0690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Singing Church Adopts New Hymnal</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 6th graf ``It was'' with two grafs to UPDATE with
approval of doctrinal paper. Picks up 7th graf pvs ``But the...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE W. CORNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Religion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodists </ORGANIZATION> voted Tuesday to write mankind out of their hymns in favor of people and include portrayals of God as a feminine figure, but the denomination did n't tamper with psalms The nation's second-largest Protestant body overwhelmingly adopted a new hymnal that generally shifts to inclusive language for humans, such as using `` All'' for `` men'' and `` people'' for `` mankind.'' But members decided to retain masculine pronouns for God in the book's psalms, denying the request of several delegates to use gender-neutral nouns such as `` God's'' rather than `` His.'' Delegates of the 9.6 million-member denomination _ whose founder, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON>, exhorted followers to `` Sing lustily and with full courage'' _ approved the new hymnal by 893 to 69. `` An exciting and historical moment,'' proclaimed the Rev. <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> <PERSON> Bevins </PERSON> of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, after applause quieted in the <ORGANIZATION> Cervantes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, packed with about 3,000 visitors and observers. It was the eighth day of the church's 11-day quadrennial governing conference. Delegates also approved a major, revamped summary of doctrine, reflecting a conservative shift in church attitudes. It gives Scripture a firmer primacy and eliminates an explicit acceptance of `` pluralism'' in concepts, a key shift away from a recognition of divergent theologies, including some embraced by feminists and leftist liberation movements. But the new hymnbook, replacing the old edition of 1966, provided the zestful note of the day, with several interludes of rousing song from the book and deliberations about it. The hefty, 960-page volume combines ritual, psalms and 625 songs, compared with 552 in the old book. The hymnal has 330 songs new to Methodists, including gospel songs, spirituals, ethnic hymns and new compositions. Some hymns such as `` Faith of Our Fathers'' and `` Dear Lord and Father of <LOCATION> Mankind </LOCATION>'' were not changed at all because they are imprinted deeply in people's memories. But the most popular Easter hymn, `` Christ the Lord is Risen Today,'' was given a revised first verse changing `` sons of men and angels say'' to `` earth and heaven in chorus say.'' The book also includes `` Good Christian Friends Rejoice'' instead of the old `` Good Christian Men Rejoice,'' and substitutes `` God of the Ages'' for `` God of Our Fathers.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, editor of the new hymnbook, said the revision offered a chance to `` address God in alternative terms,'' other than masculine, but `` we backed off because of controversy.'' As a result, he said, only three hymns offer feminine images of God. Several others were rejected. Those three include `` Wonder of Wonders'' and `` How Can We Name a Love,'' by British poet <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Wren </PERSON>, which portay God both as mother and father. The third song, `` The Care the Eagle Gives Her Young,'' compares God to a mother eagle. The hymnal also retains many popular mainstays, including many of <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON>'s. At one point in the book's genesis, a massive reaction by members overturned a committee decision to delete `` Onward Christian Soldiers'' and `` The Battle Hymn of the Republic'' because of their militaristic metaphors. It also keeps familiar revival hymns, such as `` In the Garden'' and `` Jesus Calls Us,'' often frowned on by musicologists. Tuesday's only substantial debate concerned the use of masculine pronouns for God in the book's psalms. They had been substituted with gender-neutral nouns initially, but a legislative committee recommended that masculine pronouns be restored, and the conference agreed despite the opposition of some delegates. Bishop <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Job </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, who chaired the 25-member committee that worked four years in compiling the volume, said the `` voice of the whole church'' was involved in the process. Job told a news conference the new book `` will serve to draw this denomination toward its center, toward Christ. It also will serve to open us to people and cultures to which we have n't been sensitive.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama-Church 3rdLd-Writethru   05-03 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Church, 3rd Ld - Writethru,a0904,0742</SECOND>
<HEAD>Banks Announce They Will Reopen</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, ``We are...'' to CORRECT spelling of Lasso;
picks up 5th graf: ``We will...''
^By ELOY O. AGUILAR</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Banks will reopen for nearly normal operations next Monday after being closed for two months because of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economic and political crisis, the president of the Bankers' Association announced. Earlier Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> said it will not mediate the crisis until the civilian government that does Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s bidding has `` a change of attitude.'' <PERSON> Edgardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasso </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> president, said in a television interview Tuesday that to avoid a run on the banks, the amount of cash depositors can withdraw will be restricted. `` We are trying to reactivate the economy of the country,'' <PERSON> Lasso </PERSON> said. `` We will take care of the public in all banking activities'' within the restrictions set by the government's <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> late in March, he said. Conditions for reopening the banks limit withdrawals to 25 percent of checking account balances as of March 3, the day the government ordered banks closed. It sets a maximum of $ 10,000, with the rest frozen for 90 days. Withdrawals of up to $ 50 may be made from savings accounts one month after banks reopen. Payment of interest is restricted and subject to cash availability in each bank. The commission has promoted a gradual reopening of the banks. On April 18, it let them begin accepting deposits. Because of limits on withdrawals, however, about 75 percent of the checks deposited bounced, analysts and business people said. A week later, about a dozen additional services were resumed, including handling letters of credit; collecting outstanding loans; transferring funds within <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, and making foreign exchange transfers. But business people said the operations were largely on paper and did little to help resolve their problems of liquidity and credit. The association represents 93 of the 117 banks operating here, most of them foreign. Both the March 3 closing and the reopening applied to the 67 banks holding licenses to conduct both local and international banking business. Others also closed their doors because of the impact of the crisis. Some closed as early as late February, after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> ousted President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> following the president's attempt tried to fire the military strongman. The political instability, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions and the lack of banking facilities brought <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economy to a near-standstill. The <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> had urged the banks to reopen with some restrictions intended to `` maintain the cash position of the banks and protect depositors.'' The church agreed at the end of March to mediate talks between the government and <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s opponents. It suspended the effort a week later. In a statement issued Tuesday, the church accused the government and official news media of `` personal and institutional attacks'' on it and Archbishop <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>. `` Since the attacks have proliferated in government news media, we assume the government rejects the mediation of the church,'' it said. Monsignor <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>, signed the statement. The bishops had offered to seek an `` honorable way out for Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as commander of the Defense Forces.'' The opposition demands <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> leave as a condition for further talks, but the government said it would not accept conditions for negotiating. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochez </PERSON>, a spokesman for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s opposition <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is considering stepping down on Aug. 12, which <PERSON> Cochez </PERSON> said is <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s fifth anniversary as defense chief <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under federal indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges, which he denies. In its attempt to remove him, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration imposed sanctions that include blocking Panamanian assets in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and prohibiting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> payments to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The church has held the government responsible for the crisis, but also blamed the `` economic domination of foreign powers and.. the corruption in the public and private sectors.'' Leaders of the opposition said Tuesday they had held their first meeting aimed at establishing common objectives. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, said the objectives include `` democratization of the country and the search for a solution to the economic and political crisis.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> still recognizes <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s chief executive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All     05-03 0098</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-PP-GOP-Pres-All,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>05-03-88 23:44</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest, unofficial results in the Republican presidential primaries on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 3,692 of 4,895 precincts reporting - 75 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 275,647 - 84 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 21,425 - 6 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 32,926 - 10 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 12,087 of 13,600 precincts reporting - 89 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 578,032 - 80 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 51,350 - 7 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 90,124 - 13 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WASH. D.C.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 98 of 140 precincts reporting - 70 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 3,811 - 89 percent <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, 170 - 4 percent <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, 279 - 7 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Pensions     05-03 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Pensions,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>States Denied Chance To Tax Income From Federal Securities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Less than two weeks after creating a potential new source of federal tax money, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is denying a similar opportunity for state treasuries. The justices on Monday refused to let states tax pension fund income from investments in federal government securities. On April 20, the court had ruled that the federal government may tax the interest earned on state and municipal bonds. Although congressional leaders say there is no plan to impose such taxes, the court's ruling last month cleared away a constitutional hurdle in the event <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> some day changes federal tax law. Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, writing for the court on April 20, said giving the federal government power to tax state and municipal bonds does not suggest that states should have reciprocal power. `` States can never tax the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> directly,'' he said. `` The federal tax immunity has always been greater than the states' immunity. That opinion was reinforced indirectly Monday as the court rejected an appeal by <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> officials seeking to tax income from such federal obligations as treasury bills and short-term borrowing. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> officials said they should be allowed to tax the income after it is distributed to retirees. The <ORGANIZATION> Vermont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last December upheld a ruling by a state judge who said the pension fund money is tax-exempt. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> ruled that interest on federal obligations is immune from state taxation even when the income is passed on by a pension fund to a retired investor. `` In practical operation, the tax in question was in fact a state tax on interest derived from federal obligations,'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said. The fact that pension money was passed on to someone other than the fund itself does not eliminate the exemption enjoyed by investments in federal securities, he said. The judge rejected arguments by state officials that interest on a government security is exempt `` only in the hands of the original recipient unless there is a specific federal statute to pass through the tax-exempt character of such income.'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> ruled in favor of <PERSON> Loren </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keys </PERSON>, who when he retired in 1981 received a lump-sum distribution of $ 141,000 from a savings plan in which he had invested. The money included $ 35,000 in interest on federal securities. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> officials said Keys owed an additional tax of $ 1,246 on the income from the government obligations. The court rulings in Keys' favor meant he received a tax refund of $ 203 plus interest. <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> officials said a lot more was at stake. They said the state court rulings could force them to examine the source of payments from pension and mutual funds, corporate dividends and even bank deposit interest and then eliminate from the state's tax base any income traced to investments in federal obligations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MissouriBullfrogs     05-03 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Missouri Bullfrogs,680</SECOND>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON WIRE: Could Missouri Bullfrogs Eat Britain?
^By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It happened in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, and the plot reminded the congressman from Missouri of the title of an imaginary horror film _ `` The Bullfrogs That Ate <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>.'' According to Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Mo </LOCATION>., British gardeners who raise goldfish in ornamental pools were looking for a way to scare off marauding cats that scooped the goldfish out of the pools and had them for lunch The solution: A British pet store imported <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> tadpoles which are said to grow into foot-long <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> bullfrogs, large enough to give a British cat the fight of his or her life. But, said <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, alarmed environmentalists saw in all of this an unintended consequence. `` Ecologists protested that the carnivorous amphibians would eat native frogs and newts and wreck the area's ecological balance,'' he said. So the pet store recalled 400 <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> bullfrogs as a threat to the native-born inhabitants of British gardens, <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON> said and added this: `` After hearing this, I hopped over to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor to deliver this sad news to my colleagues. `` Lest the tiny creatures of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> croak, it is far better that our <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> bullfrogs be recalled. Sounds like a horror film _ `` The Bullfrogs That Ate <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>.' `` And so my colleagues I stand before you warts and all. `` As a responsible Missourian, I believe that although we should not leap to conclusions, we must ensure our frogs do not cause any undue harm in the land of <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. `` So we welcome our British brethren to send back both our tadpoles and foot-long bullfrogs back home. `` Imagine _ a foot-long frog! `` Who would believe it? `` It's no wonder they call <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> the ` Show Me State.'''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Lady <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> last week to receive <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> tributes on the 20th anniversary of the launching of her campaign to beautify the capital and the nation's highways. The celebration took place at a season appropriate to the occasion. The flowers of spring _ most of them planted as a result of her labors _ were bursting like an explosion in a paint factory. But the occasion, perhaps inevitably, also brought forth memories of President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s legendary style and towering ego. Some went to the point of how <LOCATION> Lady </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bird </LOCATION> coped with it all. Rep. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who said he had been proud to call himself `` <ORGANIZATION> LBJ </ORGANIZATION>'s congressman,'' told the House of the time Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> had prepared dinner for guests at the <ORGANIZATION> LBJ </ORGANIZATION> ranch only to find her husband was driving some of the guests around the ranch `` to show them the deer and the antelope and where the buffalo do not roam.'' Three times, he said, Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> radioed the car using the Secret Service code names for the presidential couple. `` Volcano, this is Volunteer,'' she said. `` When can we serve dinner?'' `` Finally, <PERSON> Pickle </PERSON> said, `` after hours of waiting, <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Bird </PERSON>'s voice came over the radio _ ` Volcano, this is Volunteer Our guests and I are sitting down at the table. Goodbye.' `` Whereupon, without a word, the president wheeled his car around and returned to the ranch house so quickly he not only got there in time for dinner, he got there in time to say the blessing.'' Another Texan remembered a hunt at the <ORGANIZATION> LBJ </ORGANIZATION> ranch for which <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> had made some unusual preparations. He had hired an artist to record the results. After it was over the artist produced five identical paintings showing <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in the foreground bringing down a bird. When <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> saw the results, this Texan said, he sent it back for retouching. The new version showed the president bringing down two birds, not just one. Another tale teller told of a Johnson friend using his car phone to call <ORGANIZATION> LBJ </ORGANIZATION> who was riding in his car. `` The purpose was to show he had his own car phone and he started bragging about it to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>,'' he said. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> produced an immediate display of one-upmanship. `` <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said, ` Let me put you on hold for a moment, someone's calling on my other line.'
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietSpace     05-03 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Space,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Scientist Says USSR Not Under ``Illusion'' It's Ahead In
Space</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet scientist says that despite the delay in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space exploration caused by the Challenger disaster, his country is not ahead in space. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Galeev </PERSON>, co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said Monday that the Soviets have taken advantage of the two years that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not been able to launch satellites easily, but he said both countries could learn from the other. `` We never have had the illusion that we were ahead,'' said <PERSON> Galeev </PERSON> at a news conference at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` Temporarily, you've lost launch capability, but if you take into account the satellites waiting to be launched, the understanding is that you'll easily catch up,'' he said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has not had regular space launches since Challenger exploded and killed its seven crewmembers on Jan. 28, 1986. Since then, the space shuttle fleet, which was the main <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> launch system, has been grounded. Flights are scheduled to resume in August. `` We took advantage of this delay,'' said <PERSON> Galeev </PERSON>. `` We are still leading in a few fields.'' He noted, however, that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has to launch more satellites because its equipment is not as durable as American models. `` We launch a lot of satellites but their lifetime is shorter,'' he said. `` That means we do n't get as much data.'' A Soviet astronomer, <PERSON> Rashid </PERSON> <PERSON> Sunyaev </PERSON>, also a co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, said scientists everywhere keenly felt the Challenger accident. `` Challenger was a tragedy for astronomers,'' he said, `` because the space telescope is still on the ground.'' <PERSON> Sunyaev </PERSON> said astronomers are anxious for the American-made telescope to be placed into orbit and to start bringing back new visions of the universe. The telescope is to be the most powerful astronomy instrument ever placed into space. In answer to a question, <PERSON> Sunyaev </PERSON> admitted that some of the scientific information gathered by the Soviet space program has been used for military purposes. But he said this can be said of many things learned by scientists. `` Even some of the work of <PERSON> Issac </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> has been used for military purposes,'' he said. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> formulated basic principles of gravity and motion. <PERSON> Galeev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sunyaev </PERSON> answered questions at a news conference that marked the end of a week of meetings with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> colleagues who are members of the U.S.-Soviet joint working groups on astronomy and astrophysics. Representatives of the two spacefaring nations met to work out ways to exchange data from their space science programs. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials said the working groups arrived at an agreement, but the plan will have to be approved by leaders of the two governments before it is released publicly.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Traficant     05-03 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Traficant,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ohio Has A Home-State Presidential Ballot In Some Districts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YOUNGSTOWN, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> congressman waging an on-again, off-again campaign for president, is hoping to pick up a few delegates today in his home state but admits his chances of winning even his own congressional district are slim. <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, a Democrat from suburban <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION> who also is seeking his third term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, announced last summer that he would run for president to attract attention to the problems of his congressional district, which has been hard hit by the decline of the steel industry. <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> said he would run a national campaign for the Democratic presidential nomination, but it never materialized. He blamed a lack of money. `` If I had the same amount of money these other candidates had in the state of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and could have come on TV the past two weeks, there would have been a fight,'' he said. <PERSON> Leesa </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> secretary of state's office said <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> met the qualifications to get onto the ballot in 12 of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s 21 congressional districts. A former sheriff, <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> is best known for successfully defending himself against charges that he accepted $ 163,000 from mobsters in 1980. But he had little name recognition outside his own district. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Binning </PERSON>, chairman of the political science department at <ORGANIZATION> Youngstown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>'s presidential candidacy was actually given some credence early on because so many of the Democratic candidates were not well known nationally. But ultimately, <PERSON> Binning </PERSON> said, `` I think <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> would have to win a major statewide office in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> in order to be considered a viable candidate for president.'' A survey conducted by <ORGANIZATION> Youngstown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> suggested residents of his district favor <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> as a congressman, but not as a presidential candidate. The poll, commissioned by The <ORGANIZATION> Youngstown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vindicator </ORGANIZATION>, indicated 38 percent of the 697 people surveyed favor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic front-runner, with <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON> supported by 14 percent and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> backed by 11 percent. Nearly a quarter of the participants were undecided. However, more than 70 percent of the same respondents supported <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>'s bid to a third term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The poll was conducted between April 11 and April 20 and had a margin of error of 5-6 percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-INDIANAAt-A-Glance     05-03 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-INDIANA At-A-Glance,200</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, May 3 Presidential filing deadline: Friday, March 4, 1988 Pledged delegates: 79 Super delegates: 6 TOTAL: 85 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, May 3 Selection of delegates: Sunday, June 5 and Monday, June 6 The results of the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> primary on May 3 will govern the proportional allocation of all of the state's 79 pledged <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> delegates among the presidential candidates.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICANS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, May 3 Presidential filing deadline: Friday, March 4, 1988 Delegates: 51 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, May 3 and Thursday, June 9 Selection of delegates: Wednesday, June 8 and Thursday, June 9 <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Republicans allocate their national convention delegates at the primary election on May 3 and at the state convention on June 9. Three delegates from each of the state's 10 congressional districts will be awarded to presidential candidates on a winner-take-all basis in each district. The remaining 21 national convention delegates will be chosen at large by the state convention. Their allocation will not be governed by results of the primary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-DISTOFCOLUMBIAAt-A-Glance     05-03 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-DIST OF COLUMBIA At-A-Glance,210</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEMOCRATS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, May 3 Presidential filing deadline: Friday, March 4, 1988 Pledged delegates: 16 Super delegates: 7 TOTAL: 23 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, May 3 Selection of delegates: Tuesday, May 3 and Thursday, June 9 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> picks its delegates to the Democratic National Convention through a two-step caucus and primary system. Delegate candidates are slated according to presidential preferences at caucuses held on Feb. 6 in two districts in the city. Allocation of the 11 district-level and three at-large national convention delegates will depend on the results of the primary May 3. The two party and elected officials delegates will be picked by the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on June 9 and will be allocated in proportion to the results of the primary.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>REPUBLICANS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Method: Primary Date: Tuesday, May 3 Presidential filing deadline: Friday, March 4, 1988 Delegates: 14 Delegates allocated: Tuesday, May 3 Selection of delegates: Tuesday, May 3 District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republicans </ORGANIZATION> will award all 14 of their national convention delegates to the winner of the presidential primary on May 3. The delegates are elected directly from the primary ballot and all run at large.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese-Graffiti     05-03 0304</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese-Graffiti,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese Critics Include Graffiti Artists</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX22 of May 2</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is the apparent target of anonymous graffiti artists who have left inscriptions such as `` sleazy'' and `` resign'' on the walls of the main <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> building. The graffiti began appearing at about the time two top aides to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> resigned March 29 due to concern about problems associated with the criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. The word `` sleazy'' last week was scrawled in black, 4-inch-high letters on a second-floor staircase in the middle of the building. The stairwell is far from <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s fifth-floor office but is heavily traveled. Employees first noticed the graffiti there Friday, said a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyer who spoke on condition of anonymity. The basement and first-floor levels of the staircase are heavily traveled because they lead to the cafeteria. In another instance, the word `` resign'' was scribbled on a wall near <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s office but it was cleaned off quickly, said department sources, speaking on condition of anonymity. Such graffiti started appearing around the same time that Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and criminal division chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> submitted their protest resignations March 29, the course said. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> quit out of concern that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continued tenure as attorney general was hurting the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s operation, morale and public image, sources said. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Monday for a meeting of police executives. Independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> last May 11 launched an investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s activities including his involvement with the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline. The probe also has examined his holdings of regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> telephone stock and his wife's $ 40,000-a-year job. The money for <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s job comes from a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> family whose real estate company leases office space to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CleanAir Bjt   05-03 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Clean Air, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release noon EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Ozone Violations Up, Monoxide Violations Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More areas violated federal clean air standards last year for ozone, a principal part of smog, while fewer violated the carbon monoxide standard, the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said today. Sixty-eight urban and rural areas failed to meet the limit for ozone, up from 62 last year. Fifty-nine urban areas failed to meet the carbon monoxide standard, down from 65 last year. There is substantial overlap between the two lists, and all the nation's 24 largest metropolitan areas are on one or both. The largest urban area not on either list is <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` We had a hot, dry summer in the East, which tends to push up ozone levels,'' said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>. `` It was much like the summer of 1983, except confined to the East.'' The decline in carbon monoxide was expected as more and more cars made before 1981 are junked. Cars made before then had to meet less stringent standards for exhaust pollution. In addition, the same weather that elevates ozone tends to depress carbon monoxide, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> noted. The carbon monoxide list is based on data for two years. Looking only at 1987 readings, 37 cities would have failed to comply, while 50 would have flunked in 1986. Motor vehicle exhaust is the primary source of carbon monoxide, which can interfere with the oxygen-carrying capacity of the blood. In most areas, motor vehicles also are the major source of a key raw material for making smog, unburned gasoline from both exhaust pipes and natural evaporation from the fuel system. Those gasoline vapors react in sunlight with oxides of nitrogen, also present in exhausts as well as in power plant emissions, to produce ozone. The brighter and sunnier the day, the more ozone that is produced. Ozone is the part of smog that interferes with breathing and makes the chest feel tight. Winds can blow the raw materials for ozone away from the source, but they may still react in sunlight, which accounts for violations in several rural counties in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says. The chemicals that made their ozone were emitted in the <LOCATION> Boston-Washington </LOCATION> corridor. Because weather has such an influence on ozone, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> judges compliance in three-year blocks. This year's compliance is based on ozone readings for 1985-1987. But weather can still push areas into and out of compliance. For example, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, Grand Rapids, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, are listed as violators this year, but were not last year. All four were on the 1986 list using 1983-1985 data. The relevant ozone readings for those four cities for 1985-1987 are similar to those for 1983-1985, possibly because the summers of 1983 and 1987 were similar, <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> is far and away the national leader in ozone pollution, with an average of 143.5 days out of compliance per year over the three-year period. Elsewhere, only <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> showed 10 or more estimated days per year in which the ozone standard would be exceeded. On last year's list, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, much of urban <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> showed such days. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s lists were produced three months early this year to help <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> decide what to do about areas that fail to meet the standards. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has prohibited <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> from taking any action against non-complying areas until Aug. 31 while it debates the issue. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> had planned penalties for some areas for failure to comply with planning requirements. The turnover of the motor vehicle fleet will eventually bring all but a handful of areas into compliance with the carbon monoxide standard, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> believes. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said agency analysts now estimate that just four to six cities would not comply eventually. For ozone, however, 25 or more cities will not comply without more stringent control measures, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0610EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF-ReligiousDeath     05-03 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF-Religious Death,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christian Science Couple Plead Innocent in Son's Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Christian Science couple pleaded innocent to manslaughter in the death of their 2 -LCB- - year-old son who died after they refused to seek medical help for him because of their beliefs <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Twitchell </PERSON> entered the plea at their arraignment Monday in <ORGANIZATION> Suffolk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on charges stemming from the April 8, 1986, death of their son <PERSON> Robyn </PERSON>. Magistrate <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> set a pretrial conference for June 1, and ordered the Twitchells, who have two other sons, released on their recognizance. The Twitchells are the second Christian Science parents to be prosecuted in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and the first since 1971, when the state amended the child abuse and neglect law to recognize spiritual healing as an alternative to modern medicine. Followers of Christian Science refuse medicine or other health care on the belief that true understanding of God acts as a cure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LifeAbroad-Kenya     05-03 0792</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Life Abroad-Kenya,0818</SECOND>
<HEAD>LIFE ABROAD: Kenya _ Where Women Can Marry Women</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report. Spelling of Ochieng' with
apostrophe correct 23rd graf and thereafter.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 This is one of a series of periodic reports by <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondents on the way of life in other countries.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE FAUL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ancient custom permits one woman in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> to take another as a `` wife,'' but a divorce case involving two such women has thrown up a challenge to <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s Western-style legal system. The case involves <PERSON> Wanjiru </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>, a barren widow, who 10 years ago took <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Njeri </PERSON> <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> as a `` wife'' to bear her the children she desperately wanted. The relationship went sour and the women have asked a Western-style divorce court to sort out their broken marriage, including the question of alimony, child support and property settlement. `` We do n't have a precedent for this case,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Mberi </PERSON>, Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON>'s lawyer. `` The problem we have is that our legal system as practiced in the courts is changing to the Western legal system. But at the same time, in the village we are living with people whose arrangements are based on customary law concepts.'' Marriage between women is not uncommon in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> and neither is divorce. But this case is unique because the couple has turned to Western laws, instead of adhering to custom and letting tribal elders decide the issue. Barren women, such as Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>, often take one or more fertile women as `` wives'' to bear children, which the female `` husband'' then claims as her own. Even married women make such arrangements, with the husband of the barren woman fathering children by his spouse's wife. Barren women often are ostracized in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, where wealth and prestige still are measured by the number of children a couple has. Since both Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON> were single, Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> was entitled to choose the man to father the children. For the surrogate mother, such an arrangement offers the security of a home and income. Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON>, in her late 20s, was a single mother of two children, aged 12 and 10, when she married Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON> and took her surname. She brought them to Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>'s home and had two more children, now 7 and 5. After a fierce quarrel in January 1986, Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON> chased her `` wife'' from their matrimonial home in the western Kenyan town of <LOCATION> Nakuru </LOCATION>, according to court records. Before turning to the Western-style courts, Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> twice went to a court of tribal elders, asking for alimony and child support or a share of Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>'s property, including a small grocery store. Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>, about 60, complained that Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> beat her, threatened her life and stole from the business. Both times the elders ruled that Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> could keep the children but should receive nothing else. `` This was not a hardship in the past, as the woman would go back to her father and his community, which jointly owned and shared land and resources,'' explained <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamau </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuria </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION> lawyer who specializes in family law. Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> did return to her father, a peasant farmer near <LOCATION> Nakuru </LOCATION>. But when she felt that she and the children were a burden, she sued her former `` husband'' for divorce in the district magistrate's court, again demanding alimony and child support or a share of Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>'s property. She filed suit in August 1986, but the case has been delayed by a backlog and is expected to be heard soon. Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON> had told the tribal courts Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> had no money or property when they married, and that the relationsip gave her status and a comfortable lifestyle. <PERSON> Odhiambo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochieng </PERSON>', Ms. <PERSON> Gutu </PERSON>'s lawyer, argues in an affidavit that because the marriage is recognized only by customary law, only a traditional solution is possible: for Ms. <PERSON> Macharia </PERSON> to return to her father's family with nothing. <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s very diversity is at the root of the now-budding legal problems. The East African nation's 22 million people are divided among dozens of ethnic groups who abide by Islamic, <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> and various tribal customary laws in addition to the statutory Western laws inherited from British colonizers at independence 25 years ago. A case last year pitted the widow of a prominent lawyer, S.M. <PERSON> Otieno </PERSON>, against his <PERSON> Luo </PERSON> clansmen in a tussle over whether the widow or the tribe should bury him. The High Court ruled that in the absence of written law, customary law prevails. <PERSON> Otieno </PERSON>'s widow lost. `` These problems are going to have to be tackled and will not go away until <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> is lived in by an overall younger and more modern generation,'' <PERSON> Ochieng </PERSON>' said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Budget Bjt   05-03 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Budget, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Backers May Make Dukakis' Budget-Balancing Struggle A
Campaign Issue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUNCAN MANSFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has made his efficiency as a manager one of the key selling points in his presidential campaign, is struggling to balance his state budgets for this year and next year. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' budget-balancing efforts are turning into something of a balancing act, because his status as the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner puts him under intense scrutiny. Supporters of Republican rival <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> are hoping the situation will provide them with ammunition they can use against the governor. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> boasts that he has given <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> nine balanced budgets as governor, including the current one for fiscal 1988, and that he will do the same for the coming fiscal year. But he'll have to find some way to make up a $ 77 million revenue shortfall this year, and already has proposed $ 233 million in additional cuts to offset supplementary spending. `` We will make the necessary adjustments which will make it possible for us to live within our income,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said last week. He said there are `` a number of ways to do that,'' but has n't said exactly which way he favors <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> backers were rubbing their hands in anticipation. `` I think it raises a credibility issue for the governor,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s state campaign chairman. `` He has talked about balancing a federal budget, yet it appears he is going to have difficulty with a fiscal 1989 state budget.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he will work matters out with the legislature. But some lawmakers are grumbling that that has n't happened yet. `` You are telling us you are going to work with us, and you have n't worked with us,'' Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodgkins </PERSON>, a Democrat on the budget-writing <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' budget chief, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON>, during an appearance before the committee last week No one doubts that the budgets ultimately will be balanced, because they must be under the state constitution. But how <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> does it could become a campaign issue. `` He is either going to have to raise taxes or cut human services spending, neither of which he wants to do. So it's something we -LRB- Republicans -RRB- are obviously going to watch very carefully,'' said <PERSON> Cellucci </PERSON> Advocacy groups fighting to keep funding for their programs are mindful of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' status as a presidential candidate. `` I think the governor running for president has created a situation where the advocates feel that they can leverage his cooperation more _ that they can make him look bad if they do n't get what they want,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Salisbury </PERSON>, the state budget director <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his aides have consistently said he will not cut existing services to balance this year's budget, but will instead clamp down on program expansions, primarily in human services. But even that tactic is bringing complaints. `` People were promised ... they were going to get this service and they still have n't gotten it yet,'' said <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>. `` That is suffering and you ca n't take that away.'' The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration had projected 6.6 percent revenue growth, but this week reduced its estimate to 5.7 percent. Even so, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Voke </PERSON> says the administration's revenue estimates are too optimistic. A large part of the shortfall is blamed on smaller-than-expected corporate tax collections due to a state law allowing state companies to use losses on out-of-state subsidiaries to reduce their <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> tax bill. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has proposed changing this measure. Meanwhile, the state has an appeal pending with the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The governor has proposed a $ 700 million package of savings and revenue increases to balance his fiscal 1989 budget. Some of the controversial features include: _ Recouping $ 70 million in unclaimed bottle deposits from beverage wholesalers That issue is also before the courts. _ Spending $ 22 million for more tax collectors _ some of the nearly 1,600 new jobs contained in the budget _ to raise $ 190 million in new revenue _ Raising $ 55 million by requiring applicants for Medicaid nursing home coverage to agree to a state lien on their homes for reimbursement after they die The administration has modified the proposal to say Medicaid eligibility will be delayed after applicants transfer assets to others, depending on the size of the transfers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     05-03 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Hits Dukakis Anew On Foreign Policy</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Bush leaves for West Virginia at 11 a.m. EDT; top prospects
uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is displaying his lack of experience on foreign affairs with `` macho'' talk about how to oust <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s dictator. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was headed to <LOCATION> Morgantown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, today to visit research facilities at <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> before returning home for a belated victory party this evening to celebrate his clinching the number of delegates needed to win the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s primary is a week from today. On a primary-eve campaign swing to <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> on Monday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ridiculed both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for what the vice president said was naivete about how <PERSON> Panaman </PERSON>'s strongman, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, should be dealt with. `` You'd think it's a cinch listening to these guys: ` Throw out <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>! Do this! Do that!''' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug indictment. In pressuring him to step down, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must avoid moves that hurt the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people or seem like some `` great bullying, gringos-of-the-North kind of overstatement of power.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told high school students in <LOCATION> Vandalia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, that `` we're still living down'' past military intervention in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> `` Ninety percent are now living under democracy in this hemisphere. We do n't want to set that back by some kind of macho statement out of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was a lecturer at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION>. Even with the nomination all but in hand, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was continuing to campaign in primary states. On Wednesday, he heads to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which votes June 7. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s celebration tonight comes a week after he actually obtained his mathematical lock on the nomination. He secured the last few delegates he needed in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary on April 26. Aides had thought it would take today's round of contests _ in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> _ to put him over the top. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told 1,200 supporters at the <ORGANIZATION> Canton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> Monday evening, `` They say, ` What in God's name are you doing in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, when you got this Republican nomination wrapped up?' I will not project in overconfidence. I will not project in arrogance.'' `` I will work right down to the Republican convention and, with your help, in the fall will be the next president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' he said. He predicted `` a classical confrontation'' in the general election with a liberal Democrat nominee. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman, said President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is not expected at tonight's `` Over The Top'' celebration at a posh <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel. There had been speculation that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who has stayed neutral during the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primaries, would use the occasion to formally endorse <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Mishawaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, on Monday, `` I had the feeling the president did endorse me at lunch the other day.'' That was a reference to a private <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meeting with the president, at which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> congratulated him for his <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> win and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> indicated a formal endorsement would come soon. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seemed exasperated when the question was raised again by local reporters in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>. `` Do you think there's any doubt in any credible person's mind about who he's for? So what's the big deal?'' he said. `` You'll see an endorsement soon, so stay tuned.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Election     05-03 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Election,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>View From The Provinces: It Doesn't Really Matter Who Wins</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FOIX, France (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The political joustings, coded language and sophistictated election arguments of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> fade long before they reach this French provincial capital. To the residents of <LOCATION> Foix </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> and challenger <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> are just about the same. `` Do you know what ` bof' means?'' asks 80-year-old <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Boy </PERSON>, a retired draftsman, as he sipped his morning coffee on the main square of this lovely town nestled in the foothills of the Pyrenees. <PERSON> Bof </PERSON> is a French expression that amounts to a verbal shrug. And that's exactly how Boy and many other inhabitants of <LOCATION> Foix </LOCATION> view Sunday's election runoff between the Socialist president and the conservative premier. `` Whether its one or the other, things will continue just the same,'' said Boy. `` It's ` le bof' in general. <LOCATION> Foix </LOCATION>, a town of about 10,000 residents 500 miles from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, is the capital of the <ORGANIZATION> Ariege </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, one of the least populated districts of the country. It is dominated by the 11th century chateau of the Counts of <LOCATION> Foix </LOCATION> perched on a massive rock overlooking the town. The area has a long Socialist tradition, and because of this <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> is favored, but with more resignation than enthusiasm. On April 24, in the first round of voting, the Ariege gave <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> 41 percent of its vote, seven points above the president's national score, and 18 percent to <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>, two points under his overall showing. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> no doubt will win again here Sunday, but it will be a gut vote more than a carefully reasoned choice. <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Doumenc </PERSON>, who for the past 25 years has been the local correspondent for the <LOCATION> Toulouse </LOCATION> newspaper 50 miles away, put it best when he said the things people here really care about are television reception and a proposed tunnel to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. `` Mitterrand does n't have a program for after May 8,'' said <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Firon </PERSON>, a local homebuilder. `` Really, there is no fundamental difference between the two. And they both need the <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> vote.'' <PERSON> Jean-Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON>, leader of the extreme right <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, won 14.4 percent in the first round, stunning many political observers. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> campaigned hard on a platform of ridding <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> of its immigrants and cracking down on law and order. In the Ariege, despite its leftist tradition, <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON> won 10.3 percent. It's hard to find somebody who will own up to voting for the extreme right and many Fuxiens, as local residents are called, were looking suspiciously at their neighbors last week. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rouch </PERSON> lounged on a bench in <LOCATION> Foix </LOCATION>'s packed criminal court, wearing the traditional black bailiff's robe. A crowd waited for the jury to return its verdict in a sensational local murder case. `` The Ariege is a place where we live well,'' he said. `` There is no pollution, no racism. There is unemployment, yes ... but we live well. I do n't know about <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Pen </PERSON>. It's a rejection phenomenon.'' Despite the lack of enthusiasm for <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, polls after the first round show him winning the runoff by scores ranging from 53-47 percent to 57-43 percent. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> `` still represents a popular image that no other political group can match,'' said defense attorney <PERSON> Yves </PERSON> <PERSON> Saez </PERSON>, just before the jury convicted his client and sentenced her to 12 years in prison for bludgeoning her husband to death. In the Cafe de la Mairie on the night of the great debate between <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON>, most of the clientele sat in the back room drinking and socializing. Up front, where the debate was on the television, only a few folks paid attention. Lined up on a bench were four working-class men in their 30s and 40s, stonefaced, arms crossed. After the two-hour debate, they got up as a unit and left. One of them, in another typical French mannerism, expressed his opinion by filling his cheeks with air and letting it out with a soft puff. `` They're all the same.'' The next morning at the farmers' market, a peasant selling her cheese declared herself for <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, but was hard put to explain why. `` We live on agricultural subsidies,'' she said. `` For peasants it's an absolute necessity.'' Has <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> threatened to cut subsidies? `` Well, you have the feeling that you are listened to under the left. Under the right, decisions are made without consultation, and that's it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AtomicVeterans     05-03 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Atomic Veterans,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Aides Recommend Veto of Benefits for `Atomic Veterans'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s advisers are recommending that he veto a bill which would grant some new benefits to `` atomic veterans,'' the American servicemen exposed to radiation in the 1945 occupation of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> or during post-World War II tests of nuclear weapons. The bill was sent to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved it Monday on a 326-2 vote, which would be far above the two-thirds majority needed to override any veto. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> margin last week was just 48-30, indicating that a veto could be sustained there. The Veterans Administration opposes the bill and says there is no direct evidence proving that the veterans' exposure is causing current health problems. The bill was part of a larger measure authorizing benefits for some 2.7 million veterans. But it was stripped out after administration officials said they would recommend a veto of the overall bill because of the `` atomic veterans'' provision. The measure would cover an estimated 250,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel who were in <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION> after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> atomic bombs were dropped on those Japanese cities in August 1945, or who took part in open-air tests of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear weapons in the southern <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> or in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> after the war. Many have health problems which they say are related to their radiation exposure. But the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says they ca n't get disability benefits unless they can show a direct link to their service duty The bill establishes a presumptive link and sets out 13 types of cancers for which the veterans could receive disability payments. According to Rep. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, D-Ga., the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has only allowed 44 of the 6,000 claims filed by atomic veterans The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Rep. G.V. <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, D-Miss., said the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s standard ca n't be met because `` the level of exposure can not be verified. He said that during the tests, some personnel did n't wear radiation-monitoring badges, other servicemen lost their badges and some badges were found to be ineffective. Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McEwen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, called the bill `` a reasonable and modest approach'' to the problem. `` If we err in our approach, and I think we do not, then we err on the side of compassion,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearCooperation     05-03 0342</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Cooperation,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S., Soviet Delegations Discuss Building New Nuclear Power Plants</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of a Soviet delegation says prospects are good for collaboration with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> company to develop new nuclear power reactors. The company, <ORGANIZATION> GA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, built the only working commercial gas-cooled reactor in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vrain </LOCATION> plant of <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. A joint U.S.-Soviet committee on peaceful uses of atomic energy last week visited GA Technologies for talks on development of so-called modular high-temperature gas-cooled reactors. In a ceremony at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Monday in which the heads of both delegations signed a document recommending renewal of the cooperation agreement, the Soviet chairman, <PERSON> Alexandor </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Protsenko </PERSON>, said, `` We think the prospects are very good for collaboration with -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> GA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- in this area, as well as with other companies.'' The agreement was begun by President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON> in 1973. It was renewed in 1983 and 1985. Asked just what form cooperation with <ORGANIZATION> GA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> might take, <PERSON> Protsenko </PERSON>, who is chairman of the state committee for the utilization of atomic energy, said through an interpreter the Soviet and <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> delegations were discussing `` a possible collaborative program with -LRB- the company -RRB- in the context of the general agreement.'' But, he added, `` We do n't exclude the possibility that our cooperation will lead to a time where we might have a separate agreement'' with GA Technologies. Gas-cooled reactors have been widely used in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, but neither the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> nor the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has favored them for civilian power. They do offer certain safety advantages, such as slow reaction to disturbances. Modular designs, which could be built efficiently in small sizes so utilities could add generating capacity only as needed, have attracted increasing attention both in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and the Soviets plan to complete construction of two in 1995. The modular high-temperature gas-cooled reactor is `` a good example of a safe, economically feasible new generation of reactor,'' <PERSON> Protsenko </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     05-03 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Cautions Against Overconfidence But Focuses On Contest
With Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is looking ahead to the November election with calls for Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to provide more information about his role in the Iran-Contra affair and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's dealings with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The Democratic front-runner also turned aside criticism from <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, but continued to avoid any sharp attacks on his Democratic rival. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was back home in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> today, after a day of primary-eve campaigning in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> where he held a substantial lead in the polls. The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> is holding a primary today too, with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> seen as sure to win there. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, trying to prevent overconfidence in his camp, urged supporters to disregard the polls in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. `` This is not over,'' he said. `` It's very, very important that we get a big turnout.'' At the same time, though, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner was warming up for a fall campaign against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been criticizing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for foreign policy inexperience, and did so again Monday. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in turn questioned the administration's dealings with Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on drug charges, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s role in other foreign policy matters including the Iran-Contra affair. `` This administration for the past 7 -LCB- years has broken the law. ... I think the vice president has to address the issue,'' he said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` I want to know why we were doing business with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, why they were paying off <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, why they were doing business with a drug-running Panamanian dictator,'' he told reporters in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. `` That's the first thing we need, a full explanation, and I think the people of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> are entitled to it.'' Earlier, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was promising to be `` the education president'' without saying whether he opposed administration cutbacks in college financial aid programs. `` I do n't know where the vice president stands on education,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if he has a program.'' In addition to criticism from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has come under increasing fire from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in recent days. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> refused to respond directly. `` I hope we can keep it positive,'' he said upon arriving in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` While we have some differences, we respect each other.'' In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, responding to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s suggestion that he lacks leadership, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ticked off his administration's accomplishments, including his state's 2.9 percent unemployment rate and legislation providing health care for all workers `` That's a lot of fire and a lot of productivity,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` I'm not just a talker. I'm a doer. There's no question about my record.'' In an interview with Japanese television, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he would try to negotiate a trade agreement with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> that accommodated both nations. He also called on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to increase its aid to developing nations. `` I would also hope that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> could do a great deal in Third World countries with its surpluses,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HospitalCruise     05-03 0508</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hospital Cruise,0526</SECOND>
<HEAD>Medical Team Helps Chronically Ill Enjoy Cruise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHANIE NANO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Deetz </PERSON> thought her traveling days were over when she was diagnosed as having emphysema. But this week she's packing for her third <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> cruise, accompanied by a hospital medical team. For the third year, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> is sending a doctor, nurses and therapists on a week-long cruise with a group of people with chronic lung diseases. The trip begins Sunday from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> with ports of call including <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION>. `` You might say we're all in the same boat,'' said the 73-year-old Ms. <PERSON> Deetz </PERSON>. `` We all have something in common. We understand each other's problems.'' Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON>, medical director of the hospital's <ORGANIZATION> Pulmonary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said many people with breathing problems are afraid to travel because of their unstable health `` They live for years with the anxiety of something happening suddenly,'' said <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON>, who went on the first two trips. `` Cruise lines are not equipped to handle complex medical illnesses and you ca n't expect them to be.'' He said the hospital-sponsored cruise developed after a patient brought up the problem of traveling. Besides the patient's fear, there's the problem of carrying oxygen supplies and other medical equipment along, he said. Some airlines and cruise lines wo n't allow the equipment, a situation that <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON> wants changed. `` Somehow we've got to set up a system to accommodate these people so they can live as near as normal lives as possible,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> plans the cruise with a supplier of home medical equipment that publicizes the trip among its customers. The first cruise drew about 25 people, including 17 patients. Last year, the group swelled to 80 people, about half patients, from more than a dozen states. The cost of the cruise ranges from $ 1,600 to $ 2,000. <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON> said this year's trip was almost canceled because of <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> restrictions on portable oxygen tanks on cruise ships. But <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON> said an exemption was obtained to allow about three dozen to make the trip. Some past participants had n't traveled for years because of their health problems, said <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON>. `` For many of the patients, this is a goal,'' he said. The trip has many side effects as well, he added. `` It's humbling to see how this experience improves on the patient's sense of well being, achievement and independence,'' <PERSON> Nochomovitz </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Deetz </PERSON> said the first hospital-sponsored cruise gave her the confidence to continue traveling. She was found to have emphysema about four years ago, after returning from a trip to <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>. The cruise was her next trip. `` I thought -LRB- my travels -RRB- were over and that's why I jumped at the first cruise,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Deetz </PERSON>, of suburban <LOCATION> Berea </LOCATION>. Next week's cruise will be her fifth in three years, and she's planning a trip to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this summer with one of her three sons She takes along a breathing machine for daily treatment. `` I enjoy the cruises. They're really wonderful for people like me,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0610EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BayonetStabbing     05-03 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bayonet Stabbing,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Accused of Stabbing Man with Bayonet Over Beer Can in Yard</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Oakre is cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>PEORIA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman accused of stabbing a man in the head with a 12-inch-long bayonet after he dropped a beer can in her yard has been charged with aggravated battery, authorities said. <PERSON> Oakre </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was charged in <ORGANIZATION> Peoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, said county Sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Basfield </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> was set at $ 15,000, and a preliminary hearing was scheduled May 27. The 51-year-old <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> woman is accused of attacking <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 37, in a parking lot Saturday after he refused to pick up the empty beer can, <PERSON> Basfield </PERSON> said. When officers arrived, Ms. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was sitting on her porch with the bayonet, according to a police report. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was treated for cuts on the back of his head, forehead and chin. <PERSON> Basfield </PERSON> said he did not believe <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> were related.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-03 0904</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0951</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON>, who romanced a mermaid in the movie `` Splash,'' has taken the plunge in real life. <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Rita </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> were married Saturday night at an undisclosed <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> church, his publicist, <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, said Monday. The couple left for a honeymoon at an undisclosed location, Miss <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said. No details were released because the couple does n't want any publicity, she said. <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> met while making the film `` Volunteers,'' Miss <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said. She said they will live in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hanks </PERSON>' other screen credits include `` Nothing in Common'' and `` Dragnet.'' He stars in the comedy `` Big,'' scheduled for June release, and appears with <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Field </PERSON> in the film `` Punchline,'' due out this year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> is getting nearly $ 20 million for his latest skirmish on the silver screen as <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rambo </PERSON>, making him the world's highest paid performer, a trade newspaper says. <ORGANIZATION> Carolco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION>' `` Rambo III,'' due in theaters May 25, cost $ 63 million to make and ranks among the most expensive movies ever produced, <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. <ORGANIZATION> Carolco </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> said Monday the figures were inaccurate. He declined to give any amounts but did say both figures reported were substantially higher than the actual cost.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State senators honored actress <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as a `` Jersey jewel'' for her Academy Award-winning portayal of an aging Italian matron in the movie `` Moonstruck.'' Miss <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> came to the capital Monday to be recognized for acting achievements by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and to campaign for her cousin, Democratic presidential contender <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` Acting is her trade and she continually works at this trade,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Orechio </PERSON>. `` Olympia is an actress' actress. She is a Jersey jewel.'' Senate President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Russo </PERSON> presented her with a `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and You _ Perfect Together'' T-shirt. `` I'm very moved and deeply gratified,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. She thanked the Legislature and Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> for annual funding of the performing arts. Ms. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> resident for the past 18 years, helped found the Whole Theater in <LOCATION> Montclair </LOCATION>, which has been nominated for a Tony Award as an outstanding regional theater. She won two Obie Awards for off-Broadway performances, and has appeared in numerous television, film and stage productions.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> Rickie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, whose song `` <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON>'s In Love'' became a hit, has given birth to a girl, her record company says. The 7-pound, 9-ounce girl, named <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamanti </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabet </PERSON>, was born April 9 at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in this coastal city, <ORGANIZATION> Geffen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> publicist <PERSON> Bryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridenthal </PERSON> said Monday. Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> is married to composer <PERSON> Pascal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nabet-Meyer </PERSON>, 30. At the 1980 Grammy Awards show, Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was voted best new artist. Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 34, has been recording a new album for <ORGANIZATION> Geffen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EAST RUTHERFORD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Turtles, Rare Earth and other 1960s rock groups will appear at a Memorial Day benefit concert to raise money for a state <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans memorial, officials announced. The May 30 `` Salute to Vietnam Veterans'' at <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> is intended to `` heal old wounds,'' singer <PERSON> Richie </PERSON> <PERSON> Havens </PERSON>, who is lining up acts for the concert, said at a news conference Monday. Others scheduled to appear include The Association and The Mamas and the Papas, Havens said. The concert is a joint effort by the state and <ORGANIZATION> AMNI-Winston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, which markets and sells advertising space on billboards and transit systems. Organizers hope to raise $ 50,000 to $ 100,000 toward the estimated $ 675,000 cost of the memorial, said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Herd </PERSON>, president and chief executive of <ORGANIZATION> AMNI </ORGANIZATION>. The memorial is to be built at the <ORGANIZATION> Garden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Holmdel </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW HAVEN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> has been honored with a $ 1 million grant to the <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repertory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drama </ORGANIZATION> aimed at keeping generations of students and their audiences laughing. The <ORGANIZATION> All-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collegiate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>'s donation will be used to establish a `` Bob Hope Comedy Fund'' and help cover comedy production costs, theater officials said Monday. `` The rare and precious art of comedy will continue to be taught and learned every year in a production uniting our best students, writers, directors and actors,'' said <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>, artistic director of the theater and dean of the drama school. The grant was a surprise to the 84-year-old Hope, a theater statement said. Hope is an avid golfer. The All-American <ORGANIZATION> Collegiate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Golf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> provides academic scholarships.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GREENEVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress Park Overall's small role as a personable prostitute in the movie `` Biloxi Blues'' got her a key to her hometown and a day of her own. Mayor <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Love </PERSON> proclaimed Sunday `` Park Overall Day.'' About 100 people gathered at a theater to meet Miss Overall or renew old acquaintances. Miss Overall, 31, lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. She played the part of <PERSON> Rowena </PERSON> on Broadway as well as the big screen. Miss Overall, known in this eastern <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> city as `` Parky,'' chatted with the crowd and signed autographs before a special showing of the movie. `` I never really wanted to leave Greeneville,'' she said. <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Broderick </PERSON> stars in the film as a young <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> recruit who is introduced to the pleasures of the flesh by <PERSON> Rowena </PERSON>. Her scene is only about five minutes but has earned her positive reviews.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WaterRationing Bjt   05-03 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Rationing, Bjt,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Water Rationing Plan Stills Fountains, Boosts Bar Tabs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One day after a water rationing plan took effect, decorative fountains fell idle, bar tabs grew and plumbing supply stores reported brisk sales of water-saving devices. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> residents have been told to cut consumption by 25 percent in response to the area's most severe water shortage since the 1976-77 drought. But many of the cutbacks will be highly visible to the hundreds of thousands of tourists who crowd the City-By-The-Bay each summer. Only fountains that use recycled water _ like the one in front of City Hall _ continued to flow Monday. Others were still filled with water, but no longer sprayed it into the air or let it tumble from sculpted waterfalls. Restaurants no longer serve water to diners automatically. Many, like <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>'s Plum at <LOCATION> Ghirardelli </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, have posted signs advising diners of the regulation. `` I would say right now, about one-quarter of the customers have asked for water,'' said dining director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> as he observed the popular restaurant's luncheon crowd. If one person at a table asks for water, only he gets water, said <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. Business at the bar was up, <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said. `` At lunch, most people have a beverage. They have a drink, they have a little wine,'' he said. `` The only people who might complain are usually from the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. You know, they do n't generally drink -LRB- alcohol -RRB- as much.'' Homeowners were snatching up plumbing supplies such as sink washers and flow-restricting shower heads. At the supermarket-like <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>'s Lumber store, plumbing manager <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> said he was especially busy Sunday afternoon as customers sought ways to cut water use in their homes. He said people were especially interested in water-saving shower heads, which <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>'s stocks at prices ranging from $ 5 to $ 40. `` The expensive ones have more adjustments for the spray,'' <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> said. `` We carry a flow restrictor kit -LRB- for about $ 3 -RRB-, but it seems like they're more interested in putting on a new head,'' he said. `` We're also selling a lot of washers. `` We're getting a lot of questions on what to do to save water,'' he said. `` They're bugging us pretty good on that.'' Meanwhile, city officials confirmed that 12 million gallons of water per year _ enough to supply 30,000 households _ are wasted cooling City Hall computers without any recycling system. The water is pumped continuously through four huge air conditioners that keep the temperature cool for the basement computers, city engineers said. The city <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will ask the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION> this week for an emergency fund to buy a water tower that would recycle the waste, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, public works director. The water has been dumped down the drain after one pass for 22 years, he said, explaining why no tower was built into the design. `` With technology what it is, a water cooling tower 10 years ago might have been the size of City Hall,'' said <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. Residents wo n't know exactly how much water they need to save until mid-May. City officials will send a notice to each household telling them how many gallons they used during an average month during the past year and, hence, how much they need to save 25 percent. City officials actually expect people to cut their personal use by 10 percent and reduce outdoor uses _ like car washing and lawn watering _ by 60 percent. Residents who do n't save enough will pay premium prices for the extra water they use. Anyone who does n't think their allotment is fair can appeal. Although there was a chance of rain in the forecast for today, water officials said it's highly unlikely <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> will get enough rain this season to make up for its extremely dry winter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880503-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-88 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WritingCure     05-03 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Writing Cure,0565</SECOND>
<HEAD>Through Writing, Ex-Mental Patient Finds A Cure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN GEORGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHATTANOOGA, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
