<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0642EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Montand     05-12 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Montand,0828</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tenderness Cannot Become Old</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The actors <PERSON> Yves </PERSON> <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> likes are the kind of actor he is himself. `` I admire <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> very much,'' he said. `` I like <LOCATION> Columbo </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Falk </PERSON>. I like this kind of actors who become older but they do n't lose their youth, really. They go on with some charm and are human beings. They do n't destroy themselves with face lifts, which are terrible.'' <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> was recently in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to receive this year's tribute from the <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the 17th person to be honored and the first Frenchman. His two most recent films are `` Jean de Florette,'' which won the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION>'s prize for best picture, and `` Manon of the Spring.'' In both, he portrays a farming village patriarch, <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Soubeyran </PERSON>. `` The reason I did n't want to make the movies was not because I look 20 years older,'' said the 66-year-old <PERSON> Montand </PERSON>. `` I said, ` Let the years do their job.' It was because I wanted to go on tour.'' <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> started as a singer, was discovered by the legendary <PERSON> Edith </PERSON> <PERSON> Piaf </PERSON>, made his first movie with her in 1945 and sang on stage and made movies until 1968 when he decided to concentrate on film acting. In 1982, he made a world singing tour which was a smash success, and planned to repeat in 1984 but made the two movies instead. `` I think it is a very good story, based on a wonderful book -LRB- <PERSON> Marcel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagnol </PERSON>'s ` L'Eau des Colines' -RRB-. But it was courageous to make this kind of part, contrary to what people wait for from you. He is a nasty man. He could be very cruel in some ways,'' he said. <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Simone </PERSON> <PERSON> Signoret </PERSON>, who were married from 1950 until her death in 1985, used to read each other's movie scripts. `` Sometimes she would say, ` You're going to shoot this thing? It is awful.' I would say, ` You're right but I promised this young director.' Of course the movie is a flop,'' he recalled. `` Sometimes you fall in love with a story you're reading. If a director has good taste, he puts you in his pocket.'' <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> has advice about getting older: `` Humor, tenderness and lucidity can not change and are important in life as you become older. You need to laugh, have a sense of humor, first of all against yourself. Everybody needs tenderness. Tenderness can not become old. Never. And if you are clear _ this is right, this is not right _ you stay a young man or woman. `` I'm going to look a little pompous now but I say, never, never stop working with your memory. You remember a girl. What is her name? You say it is n't important, forget it. No, no. Make the effort to discover again the name of this girl, even if it is not important. This is exercise, like for the muscles.'' For physical exercise, <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> walks four or five miles every day when he can. `` Sometimes I make a seven or 10-minute dance in the morning. Then I take a shower and that's it.'' At the tribute, French filmmaker <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Malle </PERSON> called <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> `` one of the most romantic figures the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> cinema has ever known.'' <PERSON> Montand </PERSON>, however, still has n't figured out romance. `` I remembered this morning, lying in bed, the first time a girl kissed me or I kissed her. I did n't like it. Two months later, someone else comes, you collapse. Both are very nice looking. It's very peculiar. `` When you are an adult, it is a mystery. You love me. I love you. It's the only thing you can say. You are mad. It's unbelievable It's a volcano inside. What does it mean? We can understand nothing. Death, love, we do n't know anything about. Maybe it's better, I do n't know. It's a wonderful mystery anyway, thank God.'' During the interview in <PERSON> Montand </PERSON>'s suite in Hotel Maxim's, the telephone rang several times and a <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> representative spoke to women who wished to stop by. `` I'm sure it is only for autographs,'' the actor said with a charming smile. Since `` <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Florette </PERSON>'' and `` Manon of the Spring,'' <PERSON> Montand </PERSON> has done a few TV appearances. He plans a TV version about <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfus </PERSON>, the French army officer who was convicted for treason but later found to be the victim of anti-Semitism. He also plans to do a movie about terrorists. <PERSON> Montand </PERSON>'s next movie, though, will be a musical, `` Three Seats for the 26th,'' directed by <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Demy </PERSON> with music by <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Legrand </PERSON>, who collaborated on `` The Umbrellas of <LOCATION> Cherbourg </LOCATION>.'' `` I do n't want to tell you the story; I want it to be a surprise,'' he said. `` It will not be a beautiful masterpiece as made by <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> or <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0643EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Fiji-Anniversary     05-12 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fiji-Anniversary,0824</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fiji Still Feeling Effects of Coup a Year Ago</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report. Note May 14 anniversary date.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PETER O'LOUGHLIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SUVA, Fiji (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A year after a military coup ended democratic government in <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> nation is still reeling in the aftermath of a conflict that arose over Fijian fears of domination by the Indian population. The economy is shaky, and skilled professionals and civil servants, mostly Indians, are leaving for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> at a rate of 500 a month, double the precoup figure. Sugar production, the country's major cash crop is down 20.3 percent; tourism has dropped 26.9 percent, the currency has been devalued 33 percent, inflation has tripled to 6 percent, unemployment has reached 7.5 percent and the gross domestic product is down 11 percent. The coup of May 14, 1987, was led by Lt. Col. <PERSON> Sitiveni </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON> who claimed that a newly elected coalition government dominated by the decendants of immigrants from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> threatened the future of ethnic Fijians. The Indians outnumbered Fijians 348,704 to 329,305 at the time and controlled trade and commerce. The election of an Indian-controlled government led to the army coup. Prime Minister <PERSON> Timoci </PERSON> <PERSON> Bavadra </PERSON>, a Fijian, and his Cabinet were arrested. The Constitution was suspended and rule by decree was put in force. Since then ethnic Fijian fears of Indian political supremacy have eased. But the coup virtually ended organized political activities, but the country is now seeing factional and clan rivalries among Fijian chiefs in a feud over a Fijian king. It was to solve just such rivalries that King <PERSON> Seru </PERSON> <PERSON> Cakobau </PERSON> handed over the islands, then known as the <ORGANIZATION> Cannibal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Isles </ORGANIZATION>, to <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1874, after first having tried to interest the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Ratu Sir <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Cakobau </PERSON>, grndson of the king and a former prime minister, now claims the royal title, which had been vacant since the British took control. But other chiefs and clans are disputing <PERSON> Cakobau </PERSON>'s claim to the title. <PERSON> Bavadra </PERSON>, the ousted prime minister, said he feared squabbling among the chiefs could provoke a violent reaction from Fijians feeling the effects of the economic downturn since the coup. Watching the tribal feuds with interest is the 39-year-old <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON>, who is a commoner. He has become a cult figure to many ethnic Fijians who regard him as the savior of their culture. He is the minister for home affairs in the interim government he appointed to run the country until a new constitution is drafted and elections held. A new book, `` Rabuka _ No Other Way,'' giving <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON>'s account of the coup, became an instant best seller. Also in demand is an autographed color poster of <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON> in an army T-shirt and bearing the slogan, `` <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>. In God's Hands.'' A documentary film titled `` Operation Surprise,'' the code name for the coup, has been showing to packed houses. <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> has has no television. One of the first acts by <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON>, a Methodist lay preacher, former rugby star and veteran of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nations </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace force was to make the religious observance of Sundays compulsory. No shops are allowed to open, no sports can be played, public transport halts and the populace is expected, but not yet compelled, to go to church. But the Sunday observance law has become so unpopular that even the <ORGANIZATION> Fiji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION> has called for its repeal. In the best-selling book, written by a Fijian and an Australian, <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON> says the majority of <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>'s Indians are heathens and should be converted to Christianity. Most of the Indians are Hindus. `` I do n't think they will resent it,'' <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON> is quoted as saying, `` because all we are trying to do is the same thing that missionaries did here in <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION> when we were cannibals and heathens.'' In the year since the coup, Indian leaders have fled or taken a low profile. But one Indian who remains prominent is <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Narayan </PERSON>, 56, <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON>'s minister for Indian affairs. She said in an interview the Indian community is now without a political leader, but added she saw little likelihood of communal violence between Fijians and Indians,. She expressed the view that while some Indians have left, the majority will remain and probably accept their loss of political rights. `` If Fijians want dominance and they are happy with it, perhaps that's not high a price for Indians to pay,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Narayan </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> Fiji </LOCATION>'s relations with traditonal friends and neighbors are taking time to mend. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> condemned <PERSON> Rabuka </PERSON>'s coup. They called their ambassadors home and suspended aid, but the envoys of all three have since returned. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> have resumed non-military aid, but relations remain chilly.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0644EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NaziScience     05-12 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nazi Science,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>Researcher Plans To Republish Nazi Data</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TOM KRATTENMAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A scientist is planning to use Nazi studies of concentration camp prisoners deliberately frozen to death to further his research about hypothermia. But some scientists and <PERSON> Jewish </PERSON> leaders have sharply criticized his intention to use data obtained during the Holocaust. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON>, director of the hypothermia research laboratory at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, says he plans to analyze and republish `` The Treatment of Shock from Prolonged Exposure to Cold,'' a study by doctors at <LOCATION> Dachau </LOCATION>. It includes observation and physiological measurements of people placed in vats of freezing liquid, often to the point of death, according to those familiar with the study. `` We should under no circumstances use the information. It was gained in an immoral way,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Hastings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, a medical ethics think tank in <LOCATION> Briarcliff </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Manor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` I think it goes to legitimizing the evil done. I think the findings are tainted by the horror and misery,'' said <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foxman </PERSON>, national director of the <ORGANIZATION> Anti-Defamation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>. Because mammals differ widely in their physiological response to cold, hypothermia research is uniquely dependent on human test subjects, says <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON>, a specialist in the field for 12 years. `` It could advance my work in that it takes human subjects farther than we're willing,'' he said. Several medical ethicists contend study of the Nazi research could save lives and, if published with a condemnation of the methods, call attention to the plight of the Jews, Poles and Gypsies killed in the experiments. Because the Egyptians used slave labor, `` does that mean we should never gaze at the pyramids?'' asked Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Biomedical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> at </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Case </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. `` It sends a chill down every normal human being's spine to think of the horrible things the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> did there, but I'm separating the results and the circumstances,'' said <PERSON> Ephraim </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuroff </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> representative to the <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wiesenthal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> `` Actually, if the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> doctor dedicated his study to the memory of those victims of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, it would serve as a nice way of reminding people about the horrible experiments.'' Use of Nazi science by post-World War II researchers is rare but not unprecedented. After facing a similar quandary this year, the federal <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> deleted references to Nazi research in its own draft report on a toxic gas. <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON>, 45, says he decided to use the Nazi hypothermia data after seeing a resurgence of public and scientific curiosity about it. He says copies of a 1945 English translation of the <LOCATION> Dachau </LOCATION> study have been available in about a dozen libraries around the country. Motivated in part by the loss of pilots in the frigid <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, the Germans used 100 to 300 prisoners to test the body's response to extreme cold, <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON> said; how many died is unclear. Besides testing the phenomenon of freezing, the doctors experimented with warming techniques ranging from body-to-body contact to alcohol ingestion, <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON> said. Word of Pozos' plans for the old Nazi experiments spread after he contacted <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> medical ethicist <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> for advice. <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> wrote a newspaper column about the issue. <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON> said he has had a generally positive response, including calls from about a half-dozen Holocaust survivors. `` They said I should get something out of this so these people would not have died in vain,'' said <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON>. Within two months, <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON> said, he hopes to republish the German study in a scientific journal with his own analysis of its quality and application to modern hypothermia research. While calling the study `` a record of unimaginable horror and cruelty,'' <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> said he believes <PERSON> Pozos </PERSON> should be allowed to republish it under strict guidelines. Among other stipulations, <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> urges omission of the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> doctors' names to ensure no credit is conferred. `` If the data can prevent a single death, then it is worth tolerating the stench of past deaths that will cling to each page,'' <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> wrote. <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> has organized an international symposium on <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> science, tentatively scheduled for May 1989 at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChryslerContract 1stLd-Writethru a0898 05-12 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chrysler Contract, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0898,0504</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chrysler Workers Narrowly Approve Two-Year Settlement</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with contract approved. No pickup. Version
also moving on financial wires.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JANET BRAUNSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Auto Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday ratified a contract giving 66,000 <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> employees in 15 states greater job protection, the union said. The two-year contract was approved by about 54 percent of those voting, according to union officials who spoke on condition they not be identified. Two former <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> locals in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> also voted Wednesday, approving separate pacts reached during the national contract talks at <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>'s Highland Park headquarters. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> bought AMC in August. The <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> and the No. 3 automaker reached the agreement May 4 after 2 -LCB- weeks of early negotiations aimed at mending a series of conflicts. Talks normally would have begun in July or August. The contract, which replaces a three-year agreement that would have have expired Sept. 14, mirrors that signed last fall at <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The Big Three contract prevents layoffs except when production is cut because of slow sales, forbids plant closings not announced before talks began and makes it harder for companies to transfer work to outside companies or foreign countries. The Chrysler contract also provides 3 percent lump-sum bonuses in 1989 and 1990, a $ 1,000 signing bonus and, for the first time, profit-sharing according to the formula that has generated thousands of dollars for <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> workers. But the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> pact also prevents the company from paying cash or stock bonuses to executives in years when a profit-sharing formula included in the contract generates no payout for workers. The <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> was angered in the past two years when <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> workers received no profit-sharing while executives were awarded generous bonuses. Union leaders, including Vice President <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Stepp </PERSON>, have said they expected the pact, approved last week by local union leaders on the <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION>'s 140-member <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> bargaining council, to be ratified by a comfortable margin. However, the contract was rejected at several large locals, including <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s Jefferson Avenue assembly plant and Mound Road engine plant and a stamping plant in <LOCATION> Sterling </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>, union officials said. <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>'s 3,500-worker Warren Truck plant approved the contract with 65 percent in favor, said Local 140 President <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wojcik </PERSON>. `` I'm surprised. I'm flabbergasted. I thought it would pass by a wider margin,'' said <PERSON> Wojcik </PERSON>, chairman of the elected 10-member bargaining committee. Unlike the <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> pacts, the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> contract also protects 2,200 workers at four closing <ORGANIZATION> Acustar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> parts plants from layoff. When any of the plants are closed, workers will be paid their regular wages and placed in a job bank. If any of the four plants _ one in <LOCATION> Van </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wert </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and three in the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> area _ are sold instead, workers can choose whether to go into the job bank and wait for a <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> opening or go with the new employer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Berlin 1stLd-Writethru a0847 05-12 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Berlin, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0847,0754</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fans Put on the Ritz for Berlin's 100th Birthday</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with Carnegie Hall concert,
picking up 3rd graf `At midday ...' Changes byline.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY201</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> to <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, show business put on the <ORGANIZATION> Ritz </ORGANIZATION> for <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and raised a classy, schmaltzy salute to the songwriter Wednesday on his 100th birthday. The creator of thousands of tunes was not in Carnegie Hall for the three-hour concert, but family members filled a row. The event started big and ended bigger, with the Army Chorus and soldiers from Ft.. Dix, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, filling the stage in front of a 30-piece orchestra, Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts standing in the aisles and <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Horne </PERSON>'s mezzo-soprano voice soaring above them in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s `` God Bless America. Then the evening's performers filed in the audience stood, and everybody sang a lusty `` There's No Business Like Show Business,'' still another <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> classic. The artists included <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> on piano. It was <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Carnegie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> singing debut with <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s `` Russian Lullaby. Director-choreographer <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tune </PERSON> tapdanced to `` Puttin' on the Ritz,'' and <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, in formal black with a black cowboy hat, brought his band for `` Blue Skies.'' `` We would n't think of doing a show without including it,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> sang `` Always'' and `` When I Lost You,'' <PERSON> Nell </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> did `` <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>'s Ragtime Band,'' <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Orbach </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> `` Easter Parade,'' and <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Clooney </PERSON> `` Count Your Blessings Instead of Sheep'' and `` White Christmas.'' <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> narrated a film of highlights of <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s life. The evening, a benefit for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Composers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, was taped by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> for broadcast May 27. `` <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON> took common American talk and made it into poetry. He gave it back to us as beautiful treasures of how we feel, not fancy, not too highbrow, simple and graceful,'' said <PERSON> Garrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON>, formerly of the musical radio program `` A Prairie Home Companion.'' At midday, 14 cast members of the Broadway show, `` A Chorus Line,'' warmed up the festivities with an enthusiastic songfest at the Central Park Arsenal, a 140-year-old landmark. `` There's no business like show business!'' proclaimed the youthful Broadway talents. Their sprightly medley ranged from love songs such as `` They Say That Falling in Love is Wonderful,'' to the torch song `` What'll I Do,'' to the humorous `` You Ca n't Get a Man With a Gun.'' In the latter, from the 1946 musical `` Annie Get Your Gun,'' the hungry-for-love sharpshooter laments, `` You ca n't shoot a man in the tail like a quail.'' After rallying around a grand piano played by `` Chorus Line'' conductor <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, the cast members moved outside to offer an a cappella chorus of `` God Bless America'' and `` Happy Birthday,'' then cut loose green helium balloons. People from all walks of life got into the act around the city _ and the nation. On <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, 15 handicapped Boy Scouts sang `` Happy Birthday'' and `` God Bless America'' during the dedication of a new log cabin named for <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. He had donated the residuals from the patriotic tune to the Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts. Patients in 100 Veterans Administration hospitals and nursing homes around the nation geared up to sing `` God Bless America'' simultaneously, at 5 p.m. Eastern time. The composer, meanwhile, was spending the day `` quietly at home'' and did not plan to be at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>, said <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s secretary, <PERSON> Hilda </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> `` He's never made a big thing about his birthdays,'' she said. `` Let's face it, he's not 22 years old.'' That did n't discourage the 75 New Yorkers who gathered outside <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> home to usher in his special day with a midnight serenade. `` Even if he did n't write a thing, to reach 100 is to be part of American history,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiessman </PERSON>, 21, a junior at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` But this guy wrote a lot. I love ` God Bless America.' Every American has got to love it.'' The reclusive <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, who lives on exclusive Beekman Place with his second wife, <PERSON> Ellin </PERSON>, did not appear at his window when <PERSON> Wiessman </PERSON> and the others crooned `` We'll be loving you, always.'' But he knew they were there. `` When they were there singing, of course he heard them. He was very thrilled by that,'' said his secretary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0650EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-HanfordWhistleblowers     05-12 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hanford Whistleblowers,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>DOE Official Concedes Whistleblowers May Have Been Harassed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LES BLUMENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> official conceded Wednesday that two whistleblowers from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state may have been harassed by their superiors after testifying last year before a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee about safety problems at the <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> nuclear reservation. Under Secretary of Energy <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON>, who has responsibility for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>'s safety programs at facilities such as the <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> reservation, said that both he and the department had `` failed'' to protect <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Simkin </PERSON> from any retaliation by their employer. `` It was negligent on my part,'' <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> told the oversight and investigations subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> said the handling of <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simpkin </PERSON> `` called into question'' the department's efforts to improve its safety programs and that the two should have been praised rather than harassed. `` We failed to acknowledge what they had done,'' said <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON>. `` It was the wrong thing to do.'' <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> also said that <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> had `` sent the wrong message'' to employees who are concerned about safety at federal nuclear facilities. During an October hearing before the same subcommittee, <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simkin </PERSON> had outlined a series of safety problems at the central <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> nuclear facility and <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> had pledged they they would not suffer because of their testimony. <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simpkin </PERSON> said Wednesday they had been `` harassed and intimidated'' since their last appearance before the subcommittee and that other workers at the <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> reservation are afraid to report safety problems for fear of reprisals. <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON>, laid off in February by the <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, said he was told by his superiors there was an `` unwritten understanding'' that he would never be promoted. In addition, <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> said one supervisor, <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who now heads one of <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION>'s employee concerns committee, told him if his testimony before the subcommittee prevented him from getting anotherjob `` that's just too bad.'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobi </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanford </ORGANIZATION>, admitted that <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> heads the employee concerns committee, but said he was not aware of <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON>'s allegation prior to Wednesday and promised to investigate <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON>'s claims. There are `` many other people -LRB- at <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> -RRB- who are afraid to come forward with serious problems because they fear reprisals,'' <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> testified. <PERSON> Simpkin </PERSON> still works at the Hanford reservation, but said he has been transferred to a department where he can not `` contribute ... to correcting the safety problems at Hanford.'' Less than a month after last fall's hearing, <PERSON> Simpkin </PERSON> said he received a letter of reprimand from his supervisor. The letter was withdrawn after an <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation found it was `` unfair and unjustified.'' Some Republican members of the committee suggested that perhaps <PERSON> Simpkin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruud </PERSON> were not qualified for the transfers they had sought. Others suggested the two had n't been singled out but had been caught up in the massive layoffs and employee reshuffling resulting from the closing of the reactor and the decision not to locate the nation's first high-level nuclear waste dump at <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION>. `` No congressional committee can function if witnesses have apprehensions about what will happen if they tell the truth,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingel </PERSON>, D-Mich., subcomittee chairman `` The matter will not end with this meeting today.'' But `` the function of this hearing was not to demean you or your department,'' <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> told <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MilitaryAIDS 2ndLd-Writethru a0983 05-12 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Military AIDS, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0983,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Man In AIDS Court-Martial `Guinea Pig,' Says Lawyer; Jury
Gets Case</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with penalty for having
visitor in his room after hours. PICKS UP 7th graf pvs, `The case
...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto FX4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CATALINA ORTIZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> technician accused of having sex with his fiancee without telling her he was infected with the AIDS virus was acquitted of assault Wednesday by a military jury. Petty Officer 2nd Class <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, 27, of <LOCATION> Magnolia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, stood at attention in the packed courtroom as the seven-member jury delivered the verdict after 4 -LCB- hours of deliberation. The sailor was convicted of a minor charge of having a visitor in his room after hours and was given 15 days in the brig and reduced in rank one grade. He could have received up to two years in the brig for the offense. `` It was what I felt was right,'' <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, accompanied by his present fiancee, <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Skavdahl </PERSON>, said of the verdict. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> could have been stripped of his rank, dishonorably discharged and sentenced to a decade behind bars had he been convicted of assault. The jury also acquitted him of adultery and of exposing his former fiancee, <PERSON> Jeannie </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON>, to the AIDS virus. <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> is a civilian. The case was unprecedented in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, although there have been similar cases in other branches of the military. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> was accused of having unprotected sex with <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> in 1987 without warning her he had tested positive for the AIDS virus. He was charged with adultery because <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> was separated, but not divorced, from her third husband. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, an avionics technician, testified he told <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> about his test results and wore a condom when the couple made love in his barracks room. But <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> said that she did n't learn <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> had been exposed to the virus until the next day, when her housemate _ who also had been <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>'s lover _ told her about the sailor's test. <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> has tested negative for the AIDS virus. Five of the seven members of the jury had to agree to reach verdicts. `` The government is attempting to explore how far the Uniform Code of Military Justice can be applied against an individual ... with the AIDS virus,'' defense attorney Lt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Richman </PERSON> charged as the case went to the jury. `` The government seeks to hold out Petty Officer <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> as a guinea pig to see how far it can go on the AIDS issue.'' Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilliland </PERSON>, prosecutor in the case, said in her closing statement that <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, depicted as caring and concerned by the defense, simply did n't care enough about <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> to tell her about the tests. `` She had no idea that the act of sex which she engaged in with Petty Officer <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> was potentially fatal to her,'' <PERSON> Gilliland </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> has said <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> was bitter that he had broken off their brief engagement and filed charges for revenge. Meanwhile, in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, the AIDS-related court-martial of <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> resumed for the hearing of motions after a nine-month delay. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a 28-year-old Army private from <LOCATION> Caseyville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, is accused of having threatened the health of three soldiers by not using condoms during sex and failing to warn them he had tested positive for the AIDS virus. Judge <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> set a July trial date after denying motions for dismissal of charges. Cole will hear the case without a jury at <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' request. He is charged with aggravated assault, conduct prejudicial to the good order and discipline of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and sodomy. The proceedings were adjourned Aug. 5 by Cole to allow the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> to appeal his ruling barring the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> from introducing <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>' AIDS blood test as evidence. Cole's ruling was later reversed. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> estimates that 20 percent to 30 percent of those who show antibodies to the AIDS virus will develop the fatal disease within five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0718EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DraytonHall     05-12 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drayton Hall,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Descendants of Colonial Planter To Gather At Homesite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 100 descendants of colonial planter <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> are expected at his plantation this weekend to celebrate the 250th anniversary of the family homestead. <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, a two-story brick Georgian structure northwest of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, has passed through seven generations of the <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> family. Now it is one of 13 sites maintained by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> that is open to the public. It attracts more than 52,000 visitors a year. The <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> family settled in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> in 1679 _ nine years after the founding of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. The youngest son, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, began construction of <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> in 1738. It was completed four years later. His father lived at nearby <LOCATION> Magnolia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plantation </LOCATION>, which also is a popular tourist attraction. There are an estimated 4,000 descendants of <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> scattered around the world, and at least 100 are expected for the celebration, which will include dancing under the stars and workshops on archaeology, said <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavin </PERSON>, curator at <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> is the only <LOCATION> Ashley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> plantation to survive the Civil War intact. Two small flanking buildings _ one used as a kitchen and one as a utility building _ were destroyed in the 1886 <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> earthquake and a hurricane seven years later. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, assistant director of <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, said that according to family legend, the house emerged from the Civil War unscathed because of the quick thinking of its occupant, Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON>. As Union troops marched through toward the end of the war, <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON> had the house posted with flags signifying it was being used to treat smallpox patients. However, it's not known whether it actually was used as a hospital. `` The story comes down both through the owners and slave descendants. Whether it was a ruse or not is unclear,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Lavin </PERSON>. The builder of the house was a successful planter who owned up to 125 slaves and acquired 30 other properties including townhouses in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. The cost of building the manor, located on a 125-acre tract, is not known, said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>. However, in the later part of the 18th Century the house was referred to as `` Mr. <PERSON> Drayton </PERSON>'s Palace.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WomenAtLarge     05-12 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Women At Large,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hefty Exercise Gurus Make Video</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YAKIMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They do n't look much like <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, but hefty <PERSON> Sharlyne </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON> are making a splash in the exercise video market with a tape for large women. The former housewives, who founded the Yakima-based Women At Large exercise studios, star in a slick new video designed for people whose bodies have more curves than angles. `` It's been on the market almost a month and we've sold 11,000 copies,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said Tuesday. The $ 160,000 production was financed by the women and television host <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> <PERSON> Weller </PERSON>, of `` Entertainment Tonight'' and the `` Home'' show. They are splitting the profits 50-50. <PERSON> Weller </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, who runs <ORGANIZATION> Weller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION>, met Mrs. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON> when they appeared on the pilot for <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Home'' show several months ago. `` They were terrific people and they wanted to do some other projects with us,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. The video, which sells for $ 29.95, is just the latest success for Women At Large, a chain of exercise studios founded by two, self-described bored housewives in 1983. The clubs cater to the 30 million women in the nation who wear clothes size 16 or above. Instructors average 175 pounds, and the goal is to build fitness and self-esteem, not lose pounds. In their determination that pounds do not matter, both women refuse to disclose their ample weight. Women At Large has sold 24 franchises around the country since 1986 and is negotiating with franchises in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` I'm ready to really bust out with it now,'' she said. `` I have all the systems in place.'' The two have become media darlings in the last year. They filmed a segment of the `` Today'' show on Wednesday morning, then were scheduled to depart for <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Monday for national and local television and newspaper interviews. Shortly after, they depart for a cross-country tour to promote the exercise tape. `` I'm flying around so much I have little time to exercise any more,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` I've got to make a concerted effort to get back on the regimen.'' The tape features the women's program of low-impact aerobics that does not include the running, jumping and jogging they feel can damage a heavier body.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0224EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StockMarket-Regan     05-12 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stock Market-Regan,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Donald Regan Calls For Steps to Quell Market Problems</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> took time off from discussing his book on the inner workings of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to tell <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that financial markets and the government must act quickly to reassure the nation's investors. The former <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> secretary said Wednesday that `` there should have been more prompt action'' after last October's stock market crash. `` This thing happened over seven months ago,'' he said. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that a form of computerized trading called index arbitrage should be prohibited, and that all transactions involving stock index futures should be temporarily halted. Both practices, he said, make the markets excessively volatile and have scared worried individual investors off. `` A stock market whose main participants are speculators and their programs can not be a healthy market, and an unhealthy Wall Street will sooner or later drag down the real economy,'' said <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, the former chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co. The banking panel has been holding hearings on the dramatic price swings that have dominated the markets since Oct. 19, when the Dow Jones Industrial Average fell a record 508 points. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, who was White House chief of staff for two years after being treasury secretary, has spent most of his time recently talking about his new book, `` For the Record: From Wall Street to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' In it, he says first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> often consults astrologers when planning the president's schedule and making other decisions. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> declined to discuss his book Wednesday with reporters. But he did blame computer-driven trading, especially index arbitrage, for the market's problems. Traders conducting index arbitrage use computers to profit from price discrepancies between the stock and futures markets by simultaneously buying in one market and selling in the other. `` In my mind, we should start by banning index option arbitrage, and then proceed with other reforms which will restore public confidence in the financial markets,'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> said. He said problems also have been caused by stock futures, which are traded in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. In a stock index futures transaction, an amount of cash equal to the value of a collection of stocks changes hands, with an agreement that the portfolio will be bought back at whatever those stocks' values are at a specific future date. Opponents of the practice say the massive amounts of money involved add unpredictability to the stock market when traders buy or sell equities to protect their futures transactions. `` I think there should be a pause'' in index futures trading, <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> told reporters after his testimony. `` It wo n't hurt very much for a three-month or six-month pause here while we take a look at the instrument itself and how it's used to see whether or not it should be permitted to continue.'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> told the senators the nation's financial markets, or the federal agencies that regulate them, should initiate the steps he recommended. If not, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should act, he said. At the same hearing, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>, chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Prudential-Bache </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said the abolition of stock index futures should be considered. `` Most knowledgeable professionals agree that if it were not for index futures, stock market moves would be far less wild, sudden or irrationally large,'' he said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>, who owns the discount brokerage firm that bears his name, also told the lawmakers that program trading should be abolished if other steps to restore market confidence do n't work. `` In surveys we have conducted, we hear over and over again the theme that individual investors fear they can not compete in markets that are so dominated by the volatility introduced by program trading and index arbitrage,'' he said. Earlier, <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Melamed </PERSON>, chairman of the executive committee of the board of governors of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercantile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters that index arbitrage helps stabilize the markets by ensuring that stock and futures prices closely track each other. `` I'm not going to defend perception,'' he said. `` The reality is it is not a factor'' in the volatility.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0715EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-PlantClosing Bjt   05-12 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Plant Closing, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan Uses Shopworn Argument Against
Plant-Closing</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's a creaky plank in the platform President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stands on when he sounds off against legislation aimed at protecting workers against sudden plant closings. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, speaking against the provision recently, said that `` as an old labor union president, I suggest that's a matter that belongs in the management-labor contracts between the unions and the people.'' But that suggests organized labor plays a larger-than-life role in today's economy. Many government statisticians, unionists and even business executives know better. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> headed the Screen Actors Guild in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> in the late 1940s, when unions were far more powerful than they are today, representing roughly a third of all workers. Because unions now represent only about 15 percent of all workers, and about 20 percent in manufacturing, it does n't necessarily follow that plant notification protections can be left for employers and unions to settle Doing that would leave open the question of who takes care of the interests of the other 80 percent of blue-collar workers. What's happened is that the administration has essentially accepted the boardroom argument that executives must be free to make their own decisions, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s shopworn argument notwithstanding. And Labor Secretary <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> conceded to a manfacturer's audience Tuesday that this may prove politically costly, especially if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s expected veto of the bill is sustained `` The polls have indicated that, from the people I've talked to, 62 percent of the people think that plant notification is the right way to go,'' she said. `` This issue is going to drive us kicking and screaming for the next five months.'' The plant-closing provision in the 1,000-page trade bill was the product of heavy lobbying by the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, and many Democrats were unwilling to see it pulled from the bill. `` The workers who do not have the benefit of a union are treated like dogs,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, assistant to <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` The fact is that, although a lot of companies talk a good game and a lot of them do a good game, the overwhelming fact is that many workers do not get sufficient notice,'' <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> said. He cited a <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study which found that workers hit by plant closings but not represented by unions had an average of only two days warning. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON>, special counsel for domestic policy at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is correct in opposing any move by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to legislate worker notification protections. `` Eighty-eight percent of the employers do give some notice and more and more employers are giving more, whether they have unions or not,'' he said. `` But it's not always possible for businesses in financial turmoil.'' Plant closing legislation, he said, `` would handcuff employers at a time which is particularly troubled and turbulent.'' <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, a labor economist at the <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, a business research organization in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, challenged arguments used by government, business and labor on this issue. Referring to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s statement about leaving plant-closing protection to companies and unions, she said, `` I think that's a cynical response that you're getting from the White House.'' `` The strength of unions tends to be more and more in government and government-affected employment,'' rather than in manufacturing, she said. `` The whole plant-closing thing is kind of artificial,'' she said. `` I have the impression that they're -LRB- the opponents and proponents -RRB- just acting in front of a painted scenery.'' Ms. <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said she thinks business overstates its concern about governmental interference and that organized labor merely is trying to get back a greater say in the decision-making process.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Korea-Politics     05-12 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Politics,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kim Young-Sam Elected President Of Opposition Party</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Young-sam </PERSON> regained control of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Reunification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday when he was elected its president at a special party convention in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>'s re-emergence at the helm of the party comes only three months after he resigned from the top party post in an attempt to forge a merger with the breakaway opposition <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, led by rival <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dae-jung </PERSON>. In his acceptance speech, <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Young-sam </PERSON> said he would reform the party and lead it to victory in the general elections four years from now. His party fell from first to second place in the opposition lineup after the Party for Peace and Democracy gained more seats in last month's parliamentary elections. The two Kims came under public pressure to retire from politics in the wake of the Dec. 16 presidential elections. The two opposition leaders both ran on separate tickets, despite widespread calls for a single opposition candidacy, and lost out to governing party candidate <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dae-jung </PERSON> resigned from his party's leadership post in March, following the party's poor showing in the presidential election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WaterProjects     05-12 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Water Projects,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pork Barrel Sounds Hollow For Water Projects</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Sheyenne in 15th graf is cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers who like to boast about how they brought their district a new dam, deeper harbor or irrigation system will find no cause to brag in a spending bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The committee on Wednesday approved its first fiscal 1989 spending bill _ a $ 17.8 billion proposal for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>. And for the first time in the memory of panel members and veteran staffers, there's no money for the corps or the bureau to begin construction of any new water projects in fiscal 1989, which begins Oct. 1. `` You ca n't have just one new construction start,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, D-Ala., chairman of the Appropriations energy and water development subcommittee `` If we do one, we have to do all the requests.'' <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said the unusual austerity was necessitated by last year's budget summit at which the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and congressional leaders agreed on a two-year blueprint designed to cut mounting federal deficits. `` This has been the most difficult appropriations bill we've ever put together,'' <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said as the full committee approved the spending bill, the first of 13 it will handle this year Rep. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif., said the no-new-starts decree could spell an end to an old <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> juggling act: satisfy as many member project requests as possible by putting up enough money to get the shovel in the ground, with the big bucks coming in later years `` Those days are over,'' <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON> said. `` Maybe the `` T'' word _ taxes _ needs to be mentioned. We've run out of room.'' <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said that Sen. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> counterpart in the appropriations process, has informally agreed to try to keep money for new starts for the corps and the bureau out of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> spending bill Another major casualty in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill is the administration's request for $ 363 million in fiscal 1989 to start construction of the Super Collider, the mega-bucks physics project that would explore exotic theories of matter The committee voted $ 100 million to keep the planning process alive but said the next president should decide whether to proceed and how to pay for the huge experiment, which has construction cost estimates ranging from $ 4.4 billion to $ 9 billion. <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said the committee's hands were tied by the budget summit's targets for his spending area and an agreement that there would be no reductions for defense-related nuclear activities by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>. He said that because these total about $ 8.1 billion, there was little discretionary money for new projects after financing other activities like continued work on some 400 water projects already under construction and paying for operation and maintenance of hundreds more. `` There just is n't a dollar left,'' added Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, the ranking Republican on <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>'s subcommittee. `` This is by far the toughest year we've had.'' Missing from the bill that goes to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor next Tuesday are six new corps flood control projects requested by the administration. They are <LOCATION> Nonconnah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cache </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Sheyenne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Ramapo </LOCATION> and Mahway rivers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>; and Lock Haven in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. Had past practice prevailed, the administration's wish list would have risen to 20 or more new construction starts as influential lawmakers got their pet projects added as the spending legislation progressed through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The no-new-starts posture would have less of an impact on the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agency that operates west of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. For the second straight year, the administration sought no new construction for the bureau, which has announced it is phasing down its building activities in favor of water conservation and environmental restoration. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> added no bureau starts last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VietVetsHealth Bjt   05-12 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Viet Vets Health, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Study Shows Viet Vets Have More Depression, Alcohol Abuse</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American soldiers who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> suffer from more depression, anxiety and alcohol abuse than do other GIs, but medical examinations reveal no physical indications of exposure to Agent Orange, a herbicide used widely during the Vietnam War. Those are among the findings of the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Experience Study, a federal report prepared for release today at a hearing before a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee. The study, conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> and released for publication in the Journal of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, also showed that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans have a greater hearing loss and a measurably lower sperm count. <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> based its findings on telephone interviews with 7,924 GIs who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and 7,364 veterans who served elsewhere. Those interviewed were selected randomly from enlisted men who entered the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> from 1965 to 1971. A subsample of 2,490 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans and 1,972 other soldiers also underwent extensive physical examinations as part of the study. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans were almost twice as likely -LRB- 19.6 percent to 11.1 percent -RRB- to report that they had health problems. Yet, when physicians who did not know the military history of the two groups examined the former soldiers, they could detect few medical differences between the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans and the others. The study said the difference between what the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans reported and what was found in examination may be the result of increased stress. `` <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans may have reported more symptoms and past medical conditions because they experienced more stress than did non-Vietnam veterans,'' said the study. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans also showed more anxiety and depression in a battery of psychological tests. `` Stress can produce anxiety, depression and a variety of somatic -LRB- physical -RRB- symptoms,'' the study said. The <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans are more likely to experience psychological problems, the study said. About 14 percent of the Viet vets are abusing alcohol, compared to 9 percent of the other group. For anxiety, the difference is 5 percent to 3 percent, and for depression, the difference is 5 percent to 2 percent. Drug use was about the same between the groups, but the study said data suggest that more <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans suffered drug-related deaths. Fifteen percent of the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans also suffered some symptoms of combat-related post traumatic stress disorder, and 2 percent reported such symptoms the month of the interviews. The study also said that the `` perceived exposure to herbicides -LRB- a perception that in itself may lead to additional stress -RRB- is associated both with psychological problems and with self-reported adverse health conditions, but is not associated with objective measures of exposure.'' Many in the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Veterans </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> organization have blamed health problems on exposure during the war in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> to Agent Orange, a herbicide used to thin vegetation in dense jungle combat areas. Use of Agent Orange was discontinued after it was determined that it contained dioxin, a potent cancer-causing chemical. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> study, however, said it found no difference in the rate of cancers between the two groups of soldiers. Soldiers who served in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, particularly those in combat, suffered more hearing loss than those who served elsewhere, the study said. `` <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans were 40 percent more likely to have high-frequency hearing loss'' than GIs not in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the study said. It added that this `` is consistent with results of several studies of army troops that show that exposure to military noise results in irreversible hearing impairment.'' A study of semen samples taken from 571 members of the two groups showed that the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran is twice as likely to have a low sperm concentration and 1.5 times as likely to have low levels of normal sperm cells. And, yet, the study said, the two groups fathered about the same number of children _ 1.4 each for the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> vets, and 1.5 for the non-Vietnam soldiers _ and reported about the same rate of birth defects in their children. `` We were not able to determine the reasons for the differences in sperm characteristics between <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and non-Vietnam veterans,'' the report said. The Vietnam Experience Study was ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as part of a veterans benefit bills passed in 1979 and 1981.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JedsReunion     05-12 0622</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jeds Reunion,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Old Soldiers Recall Adventure Helping European Resistance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They're all old men now, but the soldiers of the multinational `` Jedburgh'' unit today are remembering the days in World War II when they parachuted behind enemy lines with a radio and a small fortune. `` We're getting a bit thinner every year,'' said <PERSON> Ivor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Haverhill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, after some of the old soldiers chanted a raunchy put-down of superior officers in the <LOCATION> Dulles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> waiting area on Wednesday. The American and British veterans welcomed their French comrades, along with widows and family members of some who have died. In what is billed as probably their last full reunion, the 51 American, 26 French and 18 British `` Jeds'' _ some have not seen each other for 44 years _ were beginning activities today that would include wreath-laying ceremonies at <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION>, honors at the British and French embassies and a visit with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Friday. Some are bragging a little. Others speak softly of lost comrades in one of the most heroic and secretive exploits of the war. The `` top secret'' classification for hundreds of boxes of government documents on the unit was only lifted in 1985. In teams of three, 279 Jeds were dropped across <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, to help lead the resistance against German occupation. Their name comes from a town in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> where `` Jedburgh justice'' for sheep rustlers meant `` hang them first and question them afterwards.'' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bazata </PERSON>, who said he is still involved in government work and accepts the description `` red-headed soldier of fortune'' even though his hair is now pure white, asked another <PERSON> Jed </PERSON> at the airport if he'd ever lost any of the money they were given to aid the resistance around the time of the June 6, 1944, <LOCATION> Normandy </LOCATION> landings. <PERSON> Bazata </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, said he parachuted in with $ 300,000 in cash. `` I loved it. You were totally your own boss, responsible for everything. When you sent messages back to headquarters, they listened. And you had unlimited money,'' said <PERSON> Bazata </PERSON>. The Jeds sabotaged German troops, blew up bridges and helped organize and arm resistance forces. Most spoke French and blended into cities and villages taken over by the Germans. Some of the Americans went on to similar missions in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, organizing popular resistance against Japanese forces. Because they could pick their targets, few were killed during the mission, said retired Col. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who is writing a book about Allied efforts behind enemy lines. <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> worked in the Jedburgh operation and supervised some of the forces in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> but was not a <PERSON> Jed </PERSON> himself. `` They were guerrillas. They had to design operations that would keep them alive,'' he said. <PERSON> Daphne </PERSON> <PERSON> Friele </PERSON>, who has helped organize the reunion, was so taken by the American <PERSON> Jeds </PERSON> when she was an 18-year-old secretary to their <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> commander that she later married two of them. Her first husband, Col. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mundinger </PERSON>, died in the Korean War. Two years ago, she married <PERSON> Berent </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friele </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Redding </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, after they met again at a Jed reunion in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. `` It took some of them this long to find each other, and they wo n't let go,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Friele </PERSON>, 62, who is still trying to find out what happened to the only two Americans in the unit she has n't accounted for: <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Gruen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> American members include former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Colby </PERSON>; retired Army Maj. Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singlaub </PERSON>, who has organized a controversial worldwide effort to support resistance groups against communism, and internationally known yachtsman <PERSON> Hod </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, a retired Marine general. The late columnist <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Alsop </PERSON> also was a Jed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0720EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Piracy     05-12 0115</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Piracy,0118</SECOND>
<HEAD>10 Pirates Plunder Remote Malaysian Village</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten men armed with automatic rifles raided a remote village on <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>'s island state of <PERSON> Sabah </PERSON>, looted several homes and injured one woman, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Bernama </PERSON> said most of the 200 residents of Kuala Gum Gum village fled into the jungle when the men arrived by speedboat on Wednesday and began shooting. One woman who stayed behind was injured by the intruders, but the extent and exact cause of her injury was not known. The men made off with about $ 1,000 in cash and property from the village, located more than 1,000 miles east of <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OSHA-RepetitiveWork Bjt   05-12 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OSHA-Repetitive Work, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>$3.1 Million Fine for Requiring Employees to Do Dangerous,
Repetitive Work</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says serious health problems among workers required to do repetitive physical labor on assembly lines prompted the agency's second-largest fine ever against a single company. <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> says <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> is trying to impose `` Alice in Wonderland theories'' on industry, but the union representing workers at <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, meatpacking plant hailed Wednesday's decision to get tough with the company <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> said it was imposing a $ 3.1 million fine against <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> for willfully ignoring the hazards of repetitive motion. The agency maintains that <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> could have taken numerous steps to reduce the risk of injury, but did not. The affected employees work on production lines, doing such work as cutting, trimming, hide removal and lifting meat with hooks, said <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON>. All the work is done while the meat moves at high speed through work stations in a cold, damp environment. <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> said safety inspectors from the agency first `` noticed a pattern of repetitive motion injuries'' during a preliminary review of safety records in November 1987. Such injuries can be crippling and are caused by repeated hand, wrist and arm motion. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> Deputy Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said repetitive motion injuries are `` a major health hazard in one of the most dangerous occupations in the country, and we want the meatpacking industry, in general, and <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION>, in particular, to eliminate the problem.'' <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> says <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> refused to slow its production lines, change equipment designs or educate workers about the need to change positions periodically. `` IBP has known about the high toll that these disorders have had on its work force but has chosen not to deal with it,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. `` We're most pleased about the recommendations the <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> made in their lengthy complaint against <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> _ recommendations for some very simple ways of preventing injuries,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Zack </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION>, a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, has 15 working days to contest the fine. The company already is contesting a $ 2.6 million fine levied by <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> last July for safety and record violations at the <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> plant. In a statement issued late Wednesday, <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> officials indicated they will fight the case in court. The citation, the company statement said, `` represents a misguided attempt by <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> to force the meatpacking industry to blindly accept untested theories about the prevention of repetitive motion disorders.'' `` <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION>'s goal,'' the statement continued, `` is to intimidate companies by threatening enormous penalties unless they accept <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> in Wonderland theories.'' The company said it has urged <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> to develop a special program for the meatpacking industry, but that <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> has not done that. <PERSON> Zack </PERSON> said the union is disappointed that <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> continues to `` deny there is a problem. It would be far preferable if <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION> would start working on solutions.'' After the preliminary study revelaed a pattern of injuries, <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> hired an expert in ergonomics, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nebraska </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION>, to do more extensive studies, <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> said. The studies found that 620 workers at 45 work stations at the <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> plant were `` at grave risk'' of developing repetitive motion illnesses, he said. Of those, 377 workers actually had developed injuries, <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> said. Some required surgery, some are on restricted work schedules and some are on permanent disability leave, he said. The $ 3.1 million fine represents a $ 5,000 penalty for each of the 620 workers. <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> estimated that a total of 3,000 people work at the <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> plant, one of 15 IBP plants. Workers at the <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> plant went on strike in the winter of 1987, following a bitter lockout by <ORGANIZATION> IBP </ORGANIZATION>. The strike ended last July. The fine is the second largest <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> has ever imposed against an individual company. The largest was $ 4.2 million against Bath Iron Works in Bath, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, in November 1987 for health and safety violations. The largest fine against multiple companies came in March of this year _ $ 5.11 million against five contractors that worked on a <LOCATION> Brideport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, apartment building that collapsed in April 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Austria-Politics     05-12 0072</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Austria-Politics,0075</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vranitzky Elected Socialist Party Chief In Austria</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chancellor <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON> was elected <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chairman at a special party conference. <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON>, 50, the only candidate nominated in Wednesday's election, received 93.6 percent of the vote Before the election, <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinowatz </PERSON>, 59, a former chancellor, announced his intention to resign in March. <PERSON> Vranitzky </PERSON>, a former banker, was finance minister from 1984 to 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0245EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Zoo     05-12 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Zoo,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Reforms Planned For London Zoo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION> will receive an $ 18.8 million government grant to modernize and attract more visitors, a zoo spokeswoman said. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Zoo in central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Regent's Park, and Whipsnade Wild Animal Park in suburban <LOCATION> Bedfordshire </LOCATION>, have regularly lost money despite government subsidies and attempts to boost attendance in the past, said <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Copsey </PERSON>. The two zoos, with the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoology </ORGANIZATION>, form the <ORGANIZATION> Zoological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> which has been losing up to $ 3.76 million annually, Ms. <PERSON> Copsey </PERSON> said. She said on Wednesday that the losses were due to a large drop in annual attendance, which fell from an average of 3 million in the 1950s to less than 1 million in 1982. She said there had been a slight increase in recent years. The grant will help the zoo draw more visitors by funding new amusement-park type attractions and new animal housing and displays, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DeltaSummit     05-12 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Delta Summit,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Southern Governors Seek Aid For Depressed Delta</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES SAGGUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROSEDALE, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The governors of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> will join forces aboard a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> barge Friday for a fight against the Delta region's depressed economy. Govs. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> will sign an agreement to address chronic problems of unemployment, illiteracy and poverty in the fertile farmlands along the river. `` We decided to use a barge for the signing so we could get to the point where the three states come together,'' <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> said. `` We thought the coming together was symbolic.'' <PERSON> Mabus </PERSON> said he hoped the ceremony would mark `` the start of a regional economic development effort, one that will signal a new focus on our region of the country and attract international investments and national attention to the three-state region.'' The governors will sign two agreements. One will seek support for a congressional bill requesting federal assistance for the region. `` We are going to try to present a united front to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. He said the states could share administration of some programs to help the area and he cited as an example the possibility of schools in which children and their parents could be taught. `` I can see a mother bringing her child to a first-grade class to read and write and go down to a hallway where she would learn to read and write,'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said. The other agreement involves coordination of international trade efforts and attempts to attract foreign investment, with the first target country being <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> said the region has been devastated by national farm problems that had dried up markets for Delta-grown soybeans, rice, milo and cotton. Industries that once offered jobs to displaced farmhands have moved overseas in quest of cheaper labor. Statistics show the <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> counties and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> parishes in the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> region _ the flatlands on both sides of the river from <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION> _ are among the nation's poorest, many with poverty levels of above 50 percent Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., a sponsor of legislation to authorize federal aid, said the Delta should be the target of an anti-poverty crusade similar to President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s effort to improve conditions in <LOCATION> Appalachia </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, D-Ark., said he hoped a federal study would produce a report `` that will almost shame <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> into taking action. Reps. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Espy </PERSON>, D-Miss., have filed similar legislation in the House
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Germany-SAfrica     05-12 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Germany-SAfrica,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>German Department Stores Stop Buying South African Groceries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s largest department store chains have stopped buying South African produce for their supermarkets. The Hertie and <ORGANIZATION> Kaufhof </ORGANIZATION> chains said on Wednesday the policy was implemented recently and that little South African produce remained in their supermarkets. For more than 10 years, anti-apartheid, religious and other groups in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> have called on the nation's businesses to boycott South African goods. But <PERSON> Elmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Kratz </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Hertie </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the decision was based on business considerations. `` When we find our customers are not buying a certain line or type -LRB- of goods -RRB- then we stop purchasing them,'' he told reporters. He said sales of South African produce dropped drastically in recent years. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, one of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s largest trading partners, has refused to consider economic sanctions against the white-led <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0250EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NationalService     05-12 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-National Service,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Group to Push for National Service Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teams of elected officials from a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> group plan to campaign in coming months for a voluntary program that would link federal education, housing and job training aid to participation in civilian or military service. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., said the plan proposed by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> would say essentially `` that if you're going to get assistance from society for your education, then you're going to serve society. The group released its 66-page proposal on Wednesday. It calls for creation of a `` Citizens Corps'' made up of young volunteers who would work one or two years at subsistence wages in civilian or military service. For each year of service in the corps a volunteers would earn a $ 10,000 voucher that could be used for college, vocational training or a home down payment. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said the vouchers would eventually replace existing federal grant and loan programs as the primary source of federal aid to students. The proposal also calls for enlistment of volunteers over the age of 65, who would earn modest wages instead of vouchers and would perform primarily administrative and supervisory tasks within the corps. Former <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, past chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION>, said the proposal is `` an attempt to move away from the politics of pure entitlement to some sort of system that involves mutual civic obligation.'' The <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION> is composed primarily of moderate and conservative Democrats, many from the South, and was a prime mover behind the creation of this year's `` Super Tuesday'' multi-state primary day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DrugEffects     05-12 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Effects,0619</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Doctors Failing to Recognize Side Effects of Psychiatric Drugs,
Study Says
^By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors often fail to recognize serious side effects of psychiatric drugs, leaving patients with unnecessary anxiety and lethargy and at risk of giving up the medication, according to a study. `` The side effects are being missed in epidemic proportions,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON>, assistant professor of psychiatry at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. While the study dealt with hospitalized patients, the side effects are so unpleasant that they could make patients stop taking the medications once they are discharged, he said. Doctors must be better trained to spot and treat side effects, while patients and their families must be taught to recognize the problems and point them out to doctors, <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> presented his study Wednesday at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Similar findings have emerged from studies at several psychiatric hospitals, he said. `` It's cause for concern. It's a good reason for education'' of doctors, patients, families and health systems, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Talbott </PERSON>, chairman of the psychiatry department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and a former president of the association. The study dealt with side effects of drugs called neuroleptics, which are used to treat hospitalized patients for schizophrenia, manic-depression and severe depression. The same drugs are used in lower doses for outpatients with schizophrenia and related conditions, and some other illnesses. Serious side effects are fairly common. One recent study found them in about 62 percent of patients on the drugs. If recognized, the side effects can be treated with other medications or by reducing dosages of the neuroleptic. <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> and colleagues looked for side effects in 48 patients admitted to a private psychiatric hospital. They then compared their assessments with those of the doctors treating the patients. They found that the doctors overlooked side effects in: _ 20 of 27 patients with akathisia, a physical or mental restlessness that can include pacing, leg motion, agitation and the urge to move or flee. _ 12 of 29 patients with parkinsonism, which includes tremor, rigidity and slowing of movements. _ two of three patients with acute dystonia, an often frightening attack of muscle contraction that can last several seconds. _ nine of 23 patients with akinesia, a decrease in spontaneous movements and gestures or a zombie-like feeling. Some unrecognized cases of akinesia were so severe that `` the patients could hardly move,'' <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> said. In rare cases, side effects can be fatal, he said in an interview. Doctors overlook side effects for several reasons, <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> said. They are not extensively trained in spotting side effects, some of which mimic symptoms of a patient's illness. Working in a psychiatric hospital ward, they also tend to get used to seeing the side effects, he said, and `` you kind of forget how distressing it is.'' In addition, the acutely psychotic patients often can not communicate about the problem effectively, he said. To improve diagnosis of the side effects, doctors in psychiatric wards should ask specifically about the symptoms, carefully record the patient's physical and pharmacological history, and do physical exminations apart from therapy sessions, <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON> said. Nurses and doctors should get early training in spotting the problem, he said. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Long </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jewish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Glen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oaks </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said part of the discrepancy <PERSON> Weiden </PERSON>'s study found might result from different opinions on when symptoms are serious enough for a diagnosis. But he agreed that many physicians are not adequately trained on spotting side effects.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880512-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-12-88 0257EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-12 0941</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0983</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
