<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HospitalStrike 1stLd-Writethru a0835 08-26 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hospital Strike, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0835,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nurses Offer Tentative Agreement to Hospitals</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 3-4, `There was...' to UPDATE with nurses to
return by Wednesday if contract approved, DELETE reference to some
public hospitals; picks up 5th graf, `If approved...' SUBS last
graf to CORRECT terms of pay raises.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELISABETH DUNHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Representatives of 2,200 striking registered nurses reached a tentative agreement with six private hospitals Friday for pay raises of 21 percent, the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said. The tentative pact was reached after the hospitals' negotiating board accepted a proposal from the <ORGANIZATION> CNA </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>, spokesman for Affiliated Hospitals, which is handling negotiations for the medical centers. The nurses will return to work by Wednesday if the contract is approved, <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Maloney </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Mayor <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnos </PERSON> said. They went on strike Aug. 2. If approved, the pact would end a citywide labor conflict that at one point involved 4,000 nurses and hospital employees at eight medical facilities. The labor dispute involved two unions and three separate strikes. Nurses at the private hospitals last week turned down an offer of a 20 percent increase over three years by a 2-1 margin. The nurses were seeking 21 percent over two years. Under the tentative pact, nurses would receive an 8 percent pay raise the first year of the contract, compared with the 7.5 percent first-year raise in the previous offer, said nurses' spokeswoman <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardoni </PERSON>. `` The 8 percent the first year is very important in bringing Affiliated up to the standards of other area hospitals,'' <PERSON> Bardoni </PERSON> said. The increase would be over a 34-month period. The tentative agreement also carries improved language on staffing levels and higher weekend differential pay. A ratification vote was set for Sunday. Union officials are endorsing the proposal and predicted approval, <PERSON> Bardoni </PERSON> said. They also had recommended approval of the earlier offer. Some 1,700-members of Local 250 of the <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> began returning to work this week after reaching agreement with seven hospitals on a two-year pact that will restore fringe benefits and short-term sick leave. Under the pact, some workers will get raises of up to 6 percent over the life of the pact and others will get bonuses of up to $ 300 at the end of two years. The union had gone on strike July 26.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Stocks     08-26 0028</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Stocks,0027</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Close Up in Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 27,678.91 points, up 113.50 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PenthouseSuit     08-26 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Penthouse Suit,0226</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Overturns Judge's Decision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court Friday overturned a judge's ruling that a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> savings and loan pay <ORGANIZATION> Penthouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boardwalk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Properties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> nearly $ 130 million for allegedly sabotaging a loan. The decision, released Friday, also overturned an order that <ORGANIZATION> Dominion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> pay $ 7.65 million in damages to <ORGANIZATION> Queens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> and Loan, the lead lender in a $ 97 million loan package for an <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> casino-hotel project. Penthouse President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> spent more than $ 60 million on the casino project, but sought extra financing in 1983. Dominion Federal promised to provide $ 35 million in funding although it was barred by law from making a single loan of more than $ 18.5 million. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> accused Dominion Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Walde </PERSON> in a July 31, 1987, decision of launching a cover-up after a third lender pulled out of the deal. The appeals court, however, said in its 67-page opinion: `` There was no evidence establishing that Dominion intended not to proceed and there is an abundance of evidence to indicate just the opposite.'' Dominion Federal announced the 2nd U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> decision. Reporters could not obtain copies late Friday. The <PERSON> McLean </PERSON>, Va.-based lending institution had posted a $ 50 million bond while awaiting the appeal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Marcos     08-26 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aquino OKs Measures to Block Marcos' Return</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> approved legal measures Friday to block the return of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who has asked a court to grant him permission to come home and face an accuser. At a meeting with key legal advisers, she authorized Solicitor-General <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> to file a motion with the anti-corruption court to reject <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' petition to come home when a former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> minister gives a deposition against him in November. <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> said that if the lower tribunal upholds <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' request, the government will appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to keep the former president from coming home from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where he fled after a February 1986 uprising that toppled his administration and propelled Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power. In a petition filed Wednesday with the anti-corruption court, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> asked permission to return so he could defend himself when <PERSON> Baltazar </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, the former public works minister, gives a deposition on alleged kickbacks by Japanese firms during the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> administration. The former minister is not related to the president. The anti-graft court said last week that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> had the right to be present and cross-examine <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> if the testimony was to be used in criminal proceedings. The anti-corruption court stopped short of ordering <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return, however, and <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> indicated the government will use all legal means to prevent <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> from coming to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> spokesman Gemmo <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> withheld comment on the government's plans because `` we are confused by all the reports'' on the proceedings. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> presidential spokesman <PERSON> Teodoro </PERSON> <PERSON> Benigno </PERSON> said the government was trying to reconcile `` the demands of the judiciary and the demands of national security.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> cited national security as the main reason for preventing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> from coming back from his exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. But she has also pledged to abide by the decision of the courts, even if they order <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> home. Pro-Marcos groups within the armed forces have been responsible for at least two of the half dozen major coup attempts against the Aquino government. Key leaders of those coup attempts remain at large. Philippine law bans trials in absentia, and the government has delayed filing charges against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> for fear he would demand the right to return. The government claims <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> embezzled up to $ 10 billion during his administration. Efforts to recover the money have foundered, in large part because of the reluctance to file criminal charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FBI-Capitol     08-26 0412</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FBI-Capitol,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>FBI Searches State Capitol Offices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHLEEN GRUBB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal agents searched half a dozen state Capitol offices belonging to lawmakers or their aides as part of an apparent corruption probe, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and a state senator said Thursday. Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, the Democratic chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Assemblyman </PERSON> <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON>, the Republican floor leader of that chamber, confirmed that their offices were among those searched by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. But both denied involvement in any improper activities. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> refused to reveal the names of the lawmakers or even the subject of the investigation, but a <ORGANIZATION> Capitol </ORGANIZATION> source, who spoke on the condition that he not be identified, said all of the parties named in the search warrants were involved in the passage of a bill involving investment banking regulations. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> aide who received one of the search warrants, chief sergeant at arms <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON>, said the warrants specified documents related to a vetoed bill involving investment banking law. At least one office was searched for more than three hours, sources said. `` What I can tell you is that anything I have received in the way of contributions or honoraria is always done as prescribed by law,'' said <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, who confirmed that federal agents searched his office. <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON> also confirmed that agents were seeking information on the investment banking law bill. `` I guess they wanted to check things out,'' he said, adding that agents were seeking information about two measures that passed through his committee. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> executed warrants Wednesday on the offices of six legislators and legislative assistants,'' said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Knowles </PERSON>, special agent in charge of the Sacramento <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> office. `` The searches were in connection with an ongoing investigation,'' and were conducted late Wednesday, he added. A Capitol employee said a team of about 30 federal investigators from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office served search warrants on the lawmakers' offices. `` All I know is some agents came in last night and served some warrants. There were no arrests, no obvious scene. I ca n't tell you who -LRB- was served -RRB-,'' the source said. `` My office and the offices of several members from both parties were searched last night by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. It is not clear to me yet what the object of the investigation is, but I am confident that when the investigation is completed, my office will be completely cleared,'' <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> said in a written statement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SocialClub     08-26 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Social Club,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Social Club Owner Arrested in Fatal Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owner of a <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> social club where a fire killed six patrons was arrested Thursday and charged with manslaughter and assault for maintaining the basement club in a reckless manner, police said. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON>, 37, of the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, was arrested at a pay phone in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> after police traced a 45-minute call he made from a phone booth to a precinct house, said police spokesman Sgt. <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. He was charged with six counts of second-degree manslaughter and some 40 counts of assault for every person that was in the club last Sunday at the time of the fire, he said. `` The section of the penal law that he's charged with, it covers death caused in a reckless manner,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. `` He maintained the club in such a way it was reckless and that's where his responsibility to the deaths comes in,'' he said. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said police had been searching for <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> since the fire at the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> club, known as The Hole. `` He had an impending sense that they were looking for him,'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> said in explaining why <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> may have called police. When <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> saw the unmarked cars pull up to the phone booth and detectives getting out, `` he ran and there was a brief foot chase'' before he was captured, said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>. Dozens of club patrons were injured in the fire, many severely burned. Eighteen firefighters also were hurt, none seriously. Officials said the club was operated illegally because it served liquor without a license and did n't have enough exits to comply with building codes. Although arson was initially suspected, the fire was later ruled to have been accidental.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-BlackVoice     08-26 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Black Voice,0821</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radical Black Leader is Strong Voice in Britain's Parliament</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BEN DOBBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> was branded a public enemy three years ago for defending black youths involved in a north <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> riot in which a policeman was hacked to death. Today, far from being hounded out of public life, 44-year-old <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> is a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and perhaps the most influential black politician in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. When <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Boateng </PERSON> won seats for the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the June 1987 election to become the first blacks ever to enter the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, many hailed it as a breakthrough for <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 2.4 million blacks. Those who feared that <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s flamboyant radicalism would prove disruptive have been confounded. With his greying beard, gap-toothed smile and melodious <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> accent, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> has emerged as a charming conversationalist and a dedicated parliamentarian. `` I suppose some people must have expected me to act in a certain way and they were probably surprised,'' he said in an interview. `` But I have n't adjusted my approach to politics in any way.'' That approach holds that the 4-percent black minority `` are at the bottom of the pile'' and becoming `` a powder keg'' in the inner cities. `` I would n't be surprised if there were another disturbance tomorrow,'' he said. `` It's there and it's going to happen because the government is n't paying any attention to it. `` We've got our backs to the wall, and we're fighting against a very racist government that discriminates against black people. `` The problem I think black people are facing now is n't the overt racism that to a large extent happened in the 60s ... but it's the unconscious racism, the racism of the people that make policy that will affect a large amount of black people adversely.'' <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> emigrated from his native <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION>, a former British colony on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s northeast coast, to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1963. Here he became the first black ever to head a municipal council, leading the north <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> borough of <LOCATION> Haringey </LOCATION> for three years. He burst into national prominence in 1985 when an impoverished housing project in the <LOCATION> Tottenham </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> Haringey </LOCATION> erupted in riots and the policeman was hacked to death _ the first ever to die in British race-related unrest. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> accused the predominantly white police force of sparking the violence and, in his most controversial utterance, said the blacks felt they had given the police `` a bloody good hiding -LRB- thrashing -RRB-.'' He insisted he was not seeking to justify the killing but simply explaining how other blacks felt about it. The effect was incendiary. The right-wing tabloid press called him `` Barmy <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON>,'' Home Secretary <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> branded him `` a high priest of race conflict,'' and nearly 1,000 <LOCATION> Haringey </LOCATION> borough workers staged a one-day strike demanding his resignation. His white girlfriend, councilor <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, received death threats. `` I've never denied it,'' he says now, `` I've never regretted it, I've never withdrawn what I said. My position at the time was to put forward the views of the young people. `` It defused the situation. A lot of the newspapers turned on me. ... I was quite clear in what I was doing.'' In the 1987 election, he carried <ORGANIZATION> Tottenham </ORGANIZATION>, where 37 percent of the electorate are black or Asian, with a sharply reduced Labor majority. In his maiden speech to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said that unless young blacks were offered better prospects, `` they will find other means of expressing their frustration.'' He claims police still harass black youths, using unnecessary force and planting evidence. When he first arrived in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said, he underwent an initiation ceremony in which seven or eight legislators from the governing <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> gathered around him in the Smoking Room and `` sort of baited me'' with racial innuendo. `` They were deliberately trying to create an incident, but it did n't work,'' he said. `` I was quite cool.'' When a doorman tried to eject him from the public gallery `` even though he knew who I was,'' <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> threatened to withdraw from the daily business of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> until the Speaker examined his complaint. The doorman apologized. <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> has confronted Parliament with issues ranging from alleged harassment of blacks in the armed forces to Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s `` hands-off'' policy toward <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. But he said he has problems with the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> too. He charges that its hierarchical system keeps black politicians out of the limelight and ignores his expertise in local government and race relations. Nonetheless, <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said: `` I'm quite happy, despite all the faults of the place -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, to be there. It's relatively easy compared to the pressure I was under when I was leader of Haringey Council. To some extent, the spotlight has been dimmed.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PiningSwine     08-26 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pining Swine,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boar Owner Making Whole Hog Effort to Sell Swine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORTH FALMOUTH, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 800-pound, lovesick boar named <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> who's been hogging too much of his owner's attention lately has been put up for sale, but so far there have been few offers for the pining swine. `` A guy wanted to know if I would deliver him to <LOCATION> Nova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION>,'' said owner <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON>, who is asking about $ 300 for <PERSON> Walter </PERSON>. `` There really have n't been any serious offers.'' The trouble with <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> is that he's doubled in size since a friend gave him to <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> about 6 months ago and is `` desperately in need of female companionship,'' according to the classified advertisement <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> ran this week in the <ORGANIZATION> Cape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cod </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` He's just rooting up the fences and is constantly looking around and you can just tell by the noises he's making that he's desperately looking for females,'' <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> eats like, well, a pig, putting away close to five gallons of garbage a day, <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> said. `` I feed him mostly garbage and of course the green stuff from the garden that's left over and he loves it all,'' he said. Neighbors bring their children to watch <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> at the trough. `` It's a huge, awful sight to see him eat,'' <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> said. A cabinetmaker and construction worker who used to raise pigs, <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> says he wo n't have enough time this winter to look after <PERSON> Walter </PERSON>, whose currently living at a nearby farm along with four sheep and two horses. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON>, a blend of <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, is about 5 feet long and has chewed through the planks of his pen with his 4-inch tusks. <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> said selling his porcine pet for meat is n't likely to bring home the bacon because mature boar meat generally is n't good for anything more than catfood. However, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> is n't naturally boorish, even though he has made mistaken advances to the back of a pickup truck and was turned down for the local fair because there was n't a pen strong enough to hold him, <PERSON> Dewees </PERSON> said. `` He's really a very gentle fellow. He never has been aggressive as far as meanness is concerned. He really needs companionship.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle-Father     08-26 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Father,0116</SECOND>
<HEAD>Father Says ``Booze And Broads'' Quote Misconstrued</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The father of Republican vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> says a statement about his son's school interests was misconstrued in a published report. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was quoted in a story Wednesday in the Daily News of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> as saying his son's main interests in school were `` broads and booze.'' The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator's father said Thursday he had intended the statement as a reflection on himself. `` ` I said, ` If he's anything like his old man, it was probably broads and booze,''' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in its report Thursday. `` He -LRB- Dan -RRB- is n't that kind of guy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mayors'Cooking     08-26 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mayors' Cooking,0696</SECOND>
<HEAD>Koch Looking For Second Chef; Most Mayors Never Get One</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RONALD POWERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Maybe in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> they let the mayor cook for himself and feast on his own sausage-and-sauerkraut. Maybe in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> they think that because the mayor is also a Jewish grandmother she can subsist on her own chicken soup. Not in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where a food trend is big news and Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s appetite _ and battle of the waistline _ are well-known. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the mayor gets a chef. And the chef can cause his own scandal. Because of an indiscretion in an administration that has seen some major corruption, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> is looking for a new cook to share <LOCATION> Gracie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mansion </LOCATION>, the sprawling river-view estate the city provides him on the ritzy <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION>. In what could be known as the Cheesecake Caper or Garlicgate, chef <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> London </PERSON> resigned when investigators determined he had improperly used city workers and facilities in his private catering and baking business. While authorities decided not to prosecute, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> ordered the cook _ known for his salmon with garlic, his chocolate chip cookies and his cheesecakes _ to quit or drop his outside work. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> elected to leave the mayor's employ, giving <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s staff a task few other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mayors ever have to deal with _ finding a new live-in chef. Few other cities even provide their mayors with a home, never mind a cook to live in it. That leaves most of them with a coffeemaker in the office and maybe a takeout menu in a desk drawer. `` We do things a little differently here in the West,'' said <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartak </PERSON>, spokeswoman for Mayor <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goddard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, who is a bachelor like <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> but cooks for himself and lives in a bungalow he owns. `` Even our governor -LRB- Rose Mofford -RRB- is probably home fixing herself a bologna sandwich like the rest of us,'' Ms. <PERSON> Bartak </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> furnishes Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> with a place to live, but on the rare occasion he dines there, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and his wife must fend for themselves, said Deputy Mayor <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Gage </PERSON>. Nevertheless, he did n't want to help <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> find a chef for <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> has some wonderful chefs, but we're not inclined to export them. We enjoy them here,'' <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> said. Up the coast, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s Mayor <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnos </PERSON> has to provide his own house _ and is struggling to make the payments _ said spokesman <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Shafer </PERSON>. Does he get a chef, at least? `` His wife wishes he did,'' said <PERSON> Shafer </PERSON>. Does n't cook for himself, eh? `` I've never seen him near a stove.'' It gets worse in small towns, apparently. Mayor <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON> in the small coastal <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION> said he gets the following: `` No chef, no house, no car.'' He does, however, get a gasoline expense account in addition to his $ 125-a-week salary. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s salary is exactly 20 times higher at $ 130,000 a year. Some mayors seem to manage quite well without a chef, practicing the culinary arts themselves. <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> is `` a connoisseur of chili,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON>. `` He's also got a sausage and sauerkraut dish that he puts together.'' And in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, Mayor <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON>, a Jewish grandmother, is known to make a good pot of chicken soup and a great batch of cookies. But in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the tradition of hiring someone to cook for the mayor seems well entrenched. Officials at <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> and the city archives could n't say which mayor was the first to have a city-provided chef, but all agreed that several men who served before <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> assumed office in 1978 enjoyed the perquisite. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said the chef's position, which pays $ 51,000 a year, saves the city money because of the banquets <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> holds and the entertaining he does as chief executive of the nation's largest city. Besides, they say the cheesecake is really tasty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     08-26 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 71,171. Cases, year to date: 20,771. Total deaths: 40,090, or 56 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 43,908, or 62 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 13,433, or 19 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 5,116, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 2,939, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 1,919, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 737, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 879, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,240, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,127, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 41,477, or 58 percent. Cases among blacks: 18,671, or 26 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 10,366, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 417, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 72, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Aug. 22 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AfricaTwins     08-26 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Africa Twins,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hutu &amp; Tutsi Warfare Cloaked In Obscurity</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION> bureau, traveled to <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> to cover the latest episode in the decades-long feud between the Hutu and <PERSON> Tutsi </PERSON> tribes.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JERRY GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KIGALI, Rwanda (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> are like twins in the womb of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The tiny nations, landlocked in the center of the continent, are a mirror image of each other, with common histories and languages and ethnic likenesses. Cloaked by clouds that crown hills and mountain peaks and the smoke from thousands of cooking fires, <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> are two of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most beautiful _ and poorest _ countries. They also are among the most obscure. During the past quarter century, they have shared one of the world's worst ethnic disputes: the unrest between the majority <PERSON> Hutu </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Tutsi </PERSON> minority that has claimed hundreds of thousands of lives. The bloodletting that runs through the histories of both countries, like the meandering <LOCATION> Akanyaru </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> that marks their common border, began anew Aug. 14. Hutu tribesmen in two northern <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> communes set upon their Tutsi neighbors, hacking them to death with machetes and burning them alive in huts, refugees and <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> officials say. The Tutsi-dominated army was sent north as peacemaker, but the soldiers turned executioners after discovering the carnage inflicted on their tribesmen. How the most recent bloodbath began is unclear. But historically, it has taken little to set either side off on a murderous rampage. Gravediggers have confirmed at least 5,000 people killed. But hundreds of Burundians, mostly <PERSON> Hutu </PERSON>, who fled into <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> to escape the army's onslaught, insist that more people were left behind dead than the 40,000 who crossed the <LOCATION> Akanyaru </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to refuge in <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION>. `` In the beginning, there were many bodies floating along the river,'' said <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Munyakayanza </PERSON>, one of the officials in charge of three camps of refugees who have settled on the hillside overlooking the marshy plain that leads to their former homes. The refugees in both camps and six similar camps are mostly Hutus and they say their former homesteads are now killing grounds. The <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> government denies army-led massacres, but refugees are arriving in <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> with knife slashes, burns and bullet and shrapnel wounds. Tribal problems exist in virtually every African country. But modern weapons, the centuries-old feud and a pressure on land unlike anywhere else in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, have led to frequent genocidal orgies in <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION> ruled <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> as one territory known as Rwanda-Urundi under a League of Nations and later <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> trusteeship from 1917 until 1962, when both countries were given their independence. From 1899 until the end of World War I in 1917, the area was part of <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Major ethnic problems in the region date from the 15th century when the Tutsi _ tall and elegant <ORGANIZATION> Nilotic </ORGANIZATION> people _ migrated from <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> and imposed feudal rule on the short, stocky <LOCATION> Bantu </LOCATION> people they found living in communes on the blue-green mountains and hillsides. Today, the Tutsi govern <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>, while the Hutu control <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION>. The Hutu are the majority in both countries, making up 84 percent of the population, and the Tutsi the minority, at 15 percent. Nowadays, competition for space on the rolling landscape is at the root of much of the ethnic animosity. Most of the people in both countries are farmers. <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most densely populated state, with 6.1 million people crammed into an area about the size of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> is roughly the same size as its northern neighbor and has 5 million people. When independence came to <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION>, the Hutu assumed political power through the sheer weight of numbers. Their coming to power was aided by a 1959 Hutu uprising in which 20,000 to 100,000 of the then-ruling <PERSON> Tutsi </PERSON> were slaughtered and 200,000 more fled into <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION>. The Tutsi held on to power in <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> even after independence and have kept the Hutu subservient with guns and intimidation. In 1972, <PERSON> Hutu </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> tried to overthrow the government beginning with a massacre of hundreds of <PERSON> Tutsi </PERSON>. The rebellion was crushed and the government, in reprisals, killed between 100,000 and 300,000 Hutu, including most of the tribe's intelligentsia, according to human rights groups. `` The Tutsi live in mortal fear knowing they are in the minority,'' said an American missionary who lived and worked in <LOCATION> Burundi </LOCATION> from 1960 to 1970 and spoke on condition of anonymity. `` They fear that some <PERSON> Hutu </PERSON> leader is going to rally the people around him and they know that will be the Tutsis' death knell.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Witness     08-26 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Witness,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Correspondent Describes Imprisonment</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Burma</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Correspondent Sein Win, 66, has reported for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> since 1968. As a reporter and newspaper editor he was imprisoned in 1960 by <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> governments and on July 29 was picked up again and released Thursday after being held for 28 days. Here is his first person account:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 I was arrested on the night of July 29 with <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> in the grip of authoritarian rule. When I left prison Thursday, I entered a new country. As I emerged from jail I witnessed an incredible thing: For the first time in a quarter century, people _ thousands and thousands of them _ were chanting, crying for democracy, and there were no secret police, no soldiers with bayonets fixed and with fingers on the triggers to stop the demonstrators. I was picked up along with nine others, including dissident <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON> who had earlier this year sent a series of letters to strongman Ne Win pointing to political, economic and human rights problems in the country and urging reform. We had been accused of something akin to treason although no evidence was ever produced against me. During imprisonment in a special solitary cell measuring 16 feet by 14 feet I was never told of the tumultuous events sweeping <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>: the ouster of President <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> after 17 days in power, killings of unarmed demonstrators, mass uprisings demanding the return of democracy, which had once briefly flickered. After the authorities barged into my house at 10 p.m. and hauled me off, my family sent a telex to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> bureau in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. `` Daddy has been taken away.'' it said. `` He wo n't be able to answer your queries.'' When Ne Win retired and was replaced as head of the ruling party by <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> last month, one of the first acts of the new leadership was to order our arrest. Challenged openly by the <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON> letters, which were reprinted and sold like hot cakes, the government had apparently decided to crack down quickly. We were taken to Insein Prison, eight miles north of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, interrogated separately, and charged under a new law of `` attacking the state,'' comparable to high treason. The cells were furnished with a table, chair, bed, mattress, blanket and mosquito net. A bath with running water was attached. Food was good. There was a cup of milk and an egg in the morning, another cup of milk in the afternoon. The two main meals included meat and soup. Except for loneliness, the thirst for news from the outside and uncertainty over my future, life was not so bad. I had more than enough time for <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> meditation. I found out later that my house was searched for four hours but nothing incriminating had been found. My answers to the interrogators were simple: My frequent visits to <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON> were to gather news. He also was an old, friend. Jail was not new to me. As editor of the English-language `` The Guardian'' newspaper, I tried to do my part in fostering a free press in the country and was jailed for nearly a month in 1960 under the Official Secrets and Emergency Provision Acts. I was let out on bail and the government withdrew the charges after a year's trial. After Ne Win seized power in a 1962 coup, thousands of real or imagined opponents were arrested, I was among them, spending three years under `` protective custody'' without interrogation or trial. The lastest incarceration was far shorter than I expected. That perhaps can be accounted for by the rapidly changing events in the country. After 26 years of seemingly passive acceptance of authoritarian rule, hundreds of thousands in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION>, Prome, <LOCATION> Pegu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Moulmein </LOCATION> and elsewhere announced boldly that they had had enough. I saw them when they opened the prison doors Thursday. I got caught in crowd of demonstrators, delaying my return home. I could hardly belive my eyes. Returning home, reunited with my wife and children who for the 28 days had received no word of my whereabouts or condition, I did what I have been doing for most of my adult life. I sat down at the telex and filed a story.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Irish-Analysis     08-26 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Irish-Analysis,0857</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRA Rides High But British Government Vows To Hit Back</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wreath by the Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridge </PERSON> into central <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> is a reminder of how quickly the balance can shift in the treacherous ebb and flow of the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> conflict. The wreath commemorates Lt. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON>, a naval recruiting officer who was blown up by a bomb while driving into <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> Monday, the 26th British military man to die in an Irish <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> attack this year. Beyond the bridge, workers clear the wreckage left by an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> car bomb that exploded in the commercial heart of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> on Tuesday. The army deaths are a sharp increase from 1987, when the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> managed to kill only three soldiers, while the bombing is a sobering reminder to <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> not to take for granted the peace and prosperity that has blossomed in its business and entertainment center over six relatively bomb-free years. <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> successes usually go in short, bloody bursts, and no one knows how long this one will last. But it represents at least a temporary change of fortunes for the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> in its campaign to rid <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> of British rule and unite the province with the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Ever since November, when a bomb massacred 12 Protestant civilians at a war memorial ceremony in <LOCATION> Enniskillen </LOCATION>, little had gone right for the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. Blunder after blunder left a trail of 18 innocent dead, <ORGANIZATION> Protestants </ORGANIZATION> as well as the blue-collar Roman Catholics whose interests the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> claims to represent. Thus the shift to attacks on soldiers, with little risk to civilians, is a morale booster for <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> supporters, who were feeling increasingly embarrassed at seeing the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> repeatedly having to excuse its mistakes. Things got so bad that <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, president of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s legal political wing, <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, had to warn the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> publicly to `` get its house in order.'' The attacks on the army have taken place in mainland <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and continental <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, but the deadliest have been in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, where six off-duty soldiers were blown up in their van in June, and eight died in a bus bombed last Saturday. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s bolstered spirits were reflected in its boast that it smuggled Tuesday's bomb in central <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> through a massive security net, and that in future, a sophisticated system of non-defusible explosives would be used to set off more bombs, combined with remote-control smoke grenades to warn off bystanders. `` The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> are on a ` high' at the moment, flush with weapons and explosives, but it can not be sustained, because against a resolute government there is no way they can convert their violence into the political concessions they demand,'' commented The <ORGANIZATION> Belfast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s most influential newspaper. The government, responding to anguished Protestant appeals for tougher anti-IRA measures, says it has taken decisions which it says are being kept secret but will `` soon become apparent.'' Newspapers speculate that these include sending in more troops, extending legal powers to hold suspects, and tightening cooperation with the Irish police to close the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s refuges south of the border. But as the Telegraph itself noted, most of the ideas have already been tried, `` and for every argument in favor of radical change, there is another to say that it might make things worse.'' Some analysts imagine the fighting reaching a stalemate in which the British agree to talk about troop withdrawal, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> accepts a truce, and all parties acknowledge the futility of violence and sit down for peace talks. But <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION>, believes Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> is too deeply committed to fighting terrorism to agree to anything that smacks of a deal with the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> believes the only way the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> will be defeated is if enough Catholics are revolted by the bloodshed to expunge the gunmen from their midst. That's why killing soldiers makes the most sense for the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>. Civilian deaths only provoke revulsion, while killing local policemen and militiamen gets marginal publicity in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, compared with the death of a soldier who has been sent in from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The struggle at present is shaped mainly by propaganda needs. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> aims to turn the British public off <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and into a mood to bring the boys back home. `` The <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> people need to ask if there is not another way,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. `` They should actively press for their government to withdraw.'' The British government counters with the charge that the weapons and explosives fueling the summer blitz have come from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. These supplies, says <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, the government's <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> Secretary, `` may have given some people the idea that somehow violence can actually win.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliason </PERSON>, news editor in the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> affairs for four years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BatHouse     08-26 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bat House,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bat Colony Chase Owners From House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW LONDON, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A colony of more than 2,000 bats has chased a couple from their home of 15 years, and one of them says `` it's too scary'' to move back until they're sure the winged invaders are gone. After dark each day, <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Disburger </PERSON> watch brown bats flutter in and out of the yellow wood-frame house. They said they have n't been able to find anyone to help them solve their problem, largely because they have trouble getting people to believe them. `` I'll never forget the night we left,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Disburger </PERSON> said recently. `` I could n't sleep. I was too scared. You could hear them. It was one of those hot nights and it was like the house was breathing. `` We had the lights on bright,'' she said. `` The bats were right in the next room. Then one lit on <PERSON> Steve </PERSON>'s leg. That did it. We went outside and slept the rest of the night in our camper. The next morning I begged my mother-in-law to take us in.'' That was July 15, and they have n't been back to their central <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> home since except to do laundry and grab a few possessions. Disburger used heavy plastic to seal off the unfinished second-floor room that seems to be the colony's nursery. But his wife does n't want to go near the house if she can help it. `` It's too scary,'' she said. She said she's been frustrated in trying to get help from pest control experts, local and state health officials and legislators. The Disburgers have tried ultra-sound, mothball crystals and smoke bombs to get rid of the bats. The only weapon that worked was a tennis racquet, but smashing a bat creates possible exposure to rabies and disease carried by the flying mammals. On Thursday, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON>, a zoologist with the state <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Wadsworth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> who specializes in rodent and bat diseases, visited the Disburger home. `` Judging from what I've heard, it's certainly a problem,'' <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> said before the visit. `` The large number of bats reported is unusual, but not rare. This year, there seems to be more people with serious problems.'' The couple said they noticed more and more bats starting to appear at the house about five years ago. They'd disappear in the winter but would come back in spring, she said. The Disburgers tried their best to plug up their old house. They'd sit in the camper at night and watch the entrances and exits used by the bats. <PERSON> Disburger </PERSON> had ladders ready all around the exterior; he'd run and get some insulation and plug a hole. The couple said they expect to spend up to $ 4,000 to rid their house of the winged varmints. That includes scattering the colony, plugging all the holes and putting on a new roof. <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> said he was thinking of sealing up most of the holes in the house, then installing one-way exits in the remaining ones. When the bats leave at night to feed, he said, they wo n't be able to get return.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC--BirthDefects     08-26 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Birth Defects,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Birth Defects Still Major Cause Of Premature Death In U.S.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Birth defects such as lung abnormalities, cardiovascular problems and chromosome disorders continue to rank as the nation's fifth leading causes of premature loss of life, federal health researchers say. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>, which tabulates `` years of potential life lost'' nationwide to determine the role of various conditions in premature mortality, reported Thursday that in 1986, birth defects robbed their victims of 651,523 years of life they would have lived before age 65. That ranked fifth among all causes of premature life-years lost, the Atlanta-based agency said. Ranking first was unintentional injury, resulting in about 2.4 million lost life-years, followed by cancers, heart disease and suicide and homicide. Birth defects have ranked fifth in all previous studies of premature mortality published as far back as 1984, said researcher <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Erickson </PERSON>. `` As infant mortality due to other causes has been reduced -LRB- with advances in prenatal care and medical treatment -RRB-, congenital anomalies -LRB- birth defects -RRB- have become the leading cause of infant mortality,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said in its weekly report. In detailed statistics from 1985, the latest year for which such data are available, the leading category of premature mortality from birth defects was lung abnormality _ either impartial development or abnormal growth of the lungs. Those conditions accounted for more than 9 percent of the life-years lost to birth defects, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> said. Ranking behind lung abnormalities as a cause of premature loss of life were conditions where infants were born with incomplete brains, or with arrested development of the left side of the heart. Further, six of the 15 leading birth defects in the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s premature mortality analysis were defects of the cardiovascular system Three chromosome defects, including Down's syndrome, were also included in the top 15. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> uses age 65 as a statistical benchmark in its premature mortality studies; most average American life expectancies are somewhat higher.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Spies-At-A-Glance     08-26 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spies-At-A-Glance,0723</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Spy Ring, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a brief chronology of recent espionage cases: Aug. 24, 1988 _ West German officials arrested former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldier <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> and charged him with selling secret documents to Soviet bloc intelligence. The disclosure cames after <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported that Swedish and West German authorities had arrested eight people involved in a spy ring that supplied the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with secret military documents for at least 10 years. June 13, 1988 _ A Canadian, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratkai </PERSON>, was charged with gathering secrets about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> submarine-monitoring operations at a naval base in <LOCATION> Newfoundland </LOCATION> during three periods in 1987 and 1988. June 3, 1988 _ A military jury sentenced Army Sgt. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> to 10 years in prison for passing unclassified documents to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent who was posing as a Russian spy. June 2, 1988 _ A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> district court judge in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> ruled that former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence analyst <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Loring </PERSON> <PERSON> Morison </PERSON> would be allowed to stay out of prison at least temporarily while he appeals his October 1985 conviction for giving secret satellite photographs of a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear aircraft carrier to a British magazine. May 20, 1988 _ The 30-year prison sentence imposed on former Marine Sgt. <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON> was reduced by five years, and a $ 5,000 fine was lifted. <PERSON> Lonetree </PERSON> was convicted in an August 1987 court martial on 13 counts, including allegations that he turned over <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> identities and floor plans of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassies in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Dec. 21, 1987 _ <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelton </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> employee, lost an appeal of his June 1986 espionage conviction for selling electronic surveillance secrets to Soviet agents. He was sentenced to three life terms plus 10 years. Dec. 18, 1987 _ <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson-Pollard </PERSON>, the wife of convicted spy <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, lost her bid for a reduction of her five-year sentence for being an accessory after the fact to possession of secret government documents and to a charge of receiving embezzled government property. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, a former civilian intelligence analyst for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, is serving a life term for his guilty plea to selling hundreds of pages of classified military documents to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Dec. 17, 1987 _ <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Katkov </PERSON>, a mid-level official at the Soviet mission to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, was arrested in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for trying to obtain military-usable technology and was ordered deported. Jan. 23, 1986 _ <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffries </PERSON>, an employee of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> stenographic firm that does <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government work, pleaded guilty to giving classified national security documents to the Soviets. <PERSON> Jeffries </PERSON> was arrested Dec. 20, 1986. Nov. 25, 1985 _ The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> agreed to a spy swap with <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION> involving <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Soussoudis </PERSON>, first cousin of Ghanaian leader Flight Lt. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rawlings </PERSON>, arrested for receiving from his lover, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Scrange </PERSON>, a low-level <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> clerk in <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION>, the names of eight people allegedly employed by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> there. He pleaded no contest to espionage charges and was sentenced to 20 years, suspended on the release of the eight accused agents from Ghanaian jails. Nov. 6, 1985 _ <PERSON> Vitaly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yurchenko </PERSON>, a colonel in the Soviet <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>, returned to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> after `` re-defecting.'' On Aug. 1 he had sought political asylum at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yurchenko </PERSON> subsequently traveled to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where he briefed American intelligence agents on Soviet operations, fingering former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> employee <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pelton </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> spies. Oct. 28, 1985 _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> communications specialist, pleaded guilty to espionage charges for dropping off secret documents for his Soviet contact near <LOCATION> Washingtion </LOCATION>. He is serving a life sentence. He was arrested May 20. Oct. 28, 1985 _ <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> seaman, pleaded guilty to passing secrets to the Soviets through his father. Now serving a 25-year prison term, the younger <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> was arrested May 21. Aug. 7, 1985 _ <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s brother, was convicted of selling secrets to the Soviets. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, 51, said his younger brother enlisted him to pass confidential documents from the <ORGANIZATION> VSE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a defense contractor for whom he worked as an engineer. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> was sentenced to life imprisonment and fined $ 250,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SpyRing-Glance     08-26 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spy Ring-Glance,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>West Germany Has Long History Of Spy Scandals</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Spy Ring, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist spies have been operating in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since its founding in 1949. Here are some of the more recent spy cases, as well as some of the more notorious ones:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 March 28, 1988 _ West German federal law authorities announce the arrest of 10 people who are accused of working for the Soviet <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>. Chief Federal Prosecutor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Rebmann </PERSON> said the roundup marked `` an important penetration of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> spy network.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Aug. 31, 1987 _ <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoeke </PERSON>, a secretary for five West German presidents, is sentenced to eight years in prison after admitting she gave state secrets to a <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agent because she was lonely and loved him. The information she handed over included sensitive correspondence between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 1985 _ <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiedge </PERSON>, head of a West German counterintelligence unit responsible for catching East German spies, defects to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 1976 _ <PERSON> Lothar-Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lutze </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Renate </PERSON> are among 16 people arrested in an espionage crackdown. The Lutzes had passed <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> documents to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since the 1960s. Then-Defense Minister <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Leber </PERSON> resigns over the scandal. The Lutzes are later released to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in a spy swap.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 1974 _ <PERSON> Guenter </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON>, a top aide to then-Chancellor <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON>, is exposed as an East German agent. The resulting scandal forces <PERSON> Brandt </PERSON> to resign. <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> gets a 13-year prison sentence but is released to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in an East-West spy exchange six years later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0615EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a BC-Theater     08-26 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Theater,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Negro Ensemble Presents `Mississippi Delta'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three fine actresses take all the parts in `` From the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delta </LOCATION>,'' a strong, evocative evening of theater by <PERSON> Endesha </PERSON> <PERSON> Ida </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> at off-Broadway's Theater Four. The presentation by the <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ensemble </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> has nine sections, stronger than vignettes, which weave individual lives through a <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> small-town tapestry from the early 1950s into the 1980s. Humor and personal tragedy are well-balanced in the play which begins with a prologue of reminiscenses. In the first `` chapter,'' `` Calm, Balmy Days,'' <PERSON> Latanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> plays a white grandmother who takes an 11-year-old black girl, played by <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Denmark </PERSON>, home to babysit her granddaughter, played by <PERSON> Gwen </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts-Frost </PERSON>. The grandmother then calls the babysitter into the bedroom so her husband can rape her. This is followed by the evening's strongest section, `` Second Doctor Lady.'' Miss <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON> plays Ai n't Baby, a name she received when she no longer was the baby in her family. Now middle-aged, she is a wonderful midwife. With the other two actresses narrating dramatically and playing children peeking through a back window, Ai n't Baby delivers a breech-birth baby. `` The Water Meter'' is the funniest section of the evening. A white meter reader tells a gullible old black woman that if anybody steps on her ground-level meter her water bill will skyrocket. The old woman has a pile of bricks and a notoriously bad aim so children and drunks enjoy the challenge. Then northern Civil Rights workers arrive and a black girl cooperates with them. Whites burn down her mother's shack with the mother inside. It ends with a preacher praying the mother into heaven and the girl going north to college. The playwright, a native of <LOCATION> Greenwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, has a Ph.D. from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>. She is associate professor of American studies at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workshop </ORGANIZATION>, directed. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> designed the set, the back of which is the spare frame of a house. The first <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> production of the play was at the Henry Street Settlement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Bishop-Democrats     08-26 0251</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bishop-Democrats,0258</SECOND>
<HEAD>Archbishop Quits Democratic Party Over Abortion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>'s top Roman Catholic cleric has ended his longtime affiliation with the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and reregistered as a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> because of the Democrats' stances on birth control and abortion rights. Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whealon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> announced his decision to quit the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in his weekly column in `` The Catholic Transcript,'' the archdiocesan weekly newspaper appearing Friday. <PERSON> Whealon </PERSON> did n't say in his column that he had registered as a Republican, but he made the switch last week, according to officials in the office of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> registrar of voters. <PERSON> Whealon </PERSON> complained the Democratic platform drafted during the recent national convention `` is in favor of contraception and abortion, financed by the government.'' He said the Republican Party platform expressed support for the family and opposed abortion. `` In 1860, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was on the wrong side on the moral question of slavery. It is on the wrong side of the more serious moral question of abortion. Therefore, reluctantly, I am unable in conscience to remain a registered Democrat. Feeling abandoned, I hope that the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> regains its moral principles and soul,'' the archbishop wrote. <PERSON> Whealon </PERSON> had been registered as a Democrat in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> since 1969. `` I had no idea what his political affiliation was, and I do n't know that anyone else did either,'' <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Droney </PERSON> said Thursday `` We're glad to have him aboard,'' said <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kezer </PERSON>, vice chairman of the state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-RushHour Bjt   08-26 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Rush Hour, Bjt,0795</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers Weary and Frustrated By Daily Battles</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NABLUS, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The soldiers call it the `` rush hour.'' Each day at about 4 p.m., groups of Palestinian youths barricade streets with burning tires and hurl stones at <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers. Each time, the soldiers give chase through the narrow winding streets of the city's outdoor market. `` It's some sort of a game, but it gets serious from time to time,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON>, a reservist who was identified only by his first name in keeping with army regulations. As he spoke, a column of black smoke rose from a burning tire, signaling the start of the daily ritual of disturbances in this <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of 120,000. The soldiers in <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON>'s company say they are weary and frustrated with the lethal game that by army count has left 15 Nablus Arabs dead and nearly 150 injured in the past two months. `` It's like chasing our tail. If we go up the hill, they go down. If we go down, they go up,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON>. As he and the other soldiers spoke to a reporter on a hillside road, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> youths sneaked up and pelted stones at the soldiers. The soldiers dashed down the hill, but the youths had vanished. Lt. <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON>, a student in his 20s, and Pvt. <PERSON> Shalom </PERSON>, a farmer in his 30s, pulled up in a jeep with a makeshift top of spare tires and wire mesh serving as a protection against cement blocks dropped from rooftops. `` I do n't want rocks dropped on my head, and I do n't want to shoot them. But if I do n't have a choice ...'' said <PERSON> Shalom </PERSON>, his sentence ending in a shrug. Soldiers have orders to refrain from firing unless their lives are in danger or they are the targets of firebombs. For all other threats, they are supposed to use tear gas, rubber bullets or plastic bullets. `` Frankly speaking, almost anything can be life-threatening,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON>, fatigue showing in the dark smudges under his eyes. He said soldiers faced three to four dangerous situations every day and it was often a struggle to maintain restraint. The threats ranged from ball bearings fired from slingshots to stones hurled at drivers. `` It's difficult to tell soldiers they have to stay cool. After three weeks of this, everyone gets mad,'' said <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON>, a textile merchant and veteran of the 1982-85 <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> war. `` I explain every day to the men that to shoot three or four Arabs is not going to solve the problem or move us forward one bit.'' During a daylong tour with soldiers in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, 37 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, a reporter heard the crackle of gunfire about 20 times, although most were apparently warning shots. By army count, one <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> was wounded in the leg by live ammunition, two by experimental plastic bullets and two by rubber bullets. At one point, the radio on Maj. <PERSON> Elkana </PERSON>'s jeep crackled and a soldier manning a lookout post asked permission to shoot. He proposed using a .22 - caliber rifle to shoot at the legs of about 20 protesters erecting barricades on a main thoroughfare `` Absolutely not,'' snapped <LOCATION> Elkana </LOCATION>. `` You are not to shoot without my authorization.'' <LOCATION> Elkana </LOCATION>, 32, from a kibbutz near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>, said soldiers had to show a presence throughout the city because `` we are the law here.'' But he said he did not normally send his men into the maze-like network of narrow alleyways that made up the old city as long as Palestinians did not try to block main roads. `` See that fire?'' he said, pointing to a burning tire about 100 yards from the main road. `` I'm going to let it go. If we try to put it out, they will throw stones and then we have to run after them. I prefer to choose the time and place.'' One hour later, squads of 10 to 20 Palestinians tried to choke off a main street by simultaneously setting up burning barricades at both ends. Soldiers called in a bulldozer, which charged through one makeshift barricade, ripping open a water pipe that sprayed the smoldering debris. Other soldiers wearing helmets with face shields entered the marketplace. Members of the patrol could be seen frequently looking up at rooftops from where Palestinians have dropped bricks, large blocks and even refrigerators. `` The orders are to keep the situation under control. There is no way we can just let them do what they want. If we did, it would be total anarchy, just like <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SettingPriorities Bjt   08-26 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Setting Priorities, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Plenty To Do In Time Remaining</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> comes back from vacation after Labor Day, one of the first things he will have to do is set priorities from an immense list of foreign policy problems. There simply is not enough time left for <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and others in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to take on all the woes of the world before ringing the curtain down in January. But the long list is tempting because so many problems suddenly seem ripe for solution, and a nudge from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could make a difference. In <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is front and center, using its influence to seek solutions to the twin problems of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. It could be argued that only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mediation could have moved the Cubans and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> to where they are now __ holding talks in <LOCATION> Brazzaville </LOCATION> that might pay off in independence for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and the withdrawal of Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. The continuing unrest of the Israeli-held <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> beckons for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intercession. In <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s absence, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> gave the Palestinian Arabs a lift by hinting they may be entitled to a separate seat in peace talks and by admonishing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> for ordering 25 more deportations from the troubled territory. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is likely to give the <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> one more college try by scheduling a fifth visit to the region this year. There is little evidence, though, that prospects for success have improved. <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> has made official what seemed obvious to many for so long: He will not assume the responsibility for negotiating a solution to the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> dispute. Nor, with national elections looming in November, is <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> by any stretch of the imagination prepared to guarantee in advance of peace talks that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would withdraw from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON>, a rising star in <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> party and son of former Prime Minister <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON>, reminded reporters during a think-tank session this week on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> that Sept. 30 will mark the 50th anniversary of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. The Sudeten in 1938 was a strategic buffer between <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. But it was absorbed by <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, setting the stage for the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> to attack <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, with the argument that the rights of 3 million Sudeten Germans were being violated. Begin drew a parallel to the 1.5 million Palestinian Arabs whose demands also have attracted important international support. The fact that an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> politician finds <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> relevant to today's <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> illustrates the determination of a sizable segment of the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> population not to give up the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> That resistance, of course, stands smack in the way of <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s plan for a settlement in which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would relinquish at least part of the territory So, when he is back in his comfortable office on the seventh floor of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, tanned and rested after a golfing vacation, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> must decide how much energy to expend on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and, if he decides on a lot, what other world problems should be sidetracked. Tugging at his sleeve, too, is the U.S.-Soviet relationship, and whether the improvement that resulted from four summit meetings between President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> summit meetings could carry over into the negotiations to reduce strategic nuclear weapons. There are a number of problems in verifying some of the more elusive variety of these destructive missiles, bombers and submarines that may defy solution. And yet many elements of a possible treaty are already in place. A big push by <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, who put the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty over the top through regular meetings with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>, might just carry the day.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> covers foreign affairs for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PledgeDebate Bjt   08-26 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pledge Debate, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pledge an Official Part of School Day In Massachusetts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DUNCAN MANSFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teachers throughout <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> continue to lead children in the Pledge of Allegiance each day, on the voluntary basis supported by Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` Every elementary school child has an opportunity to say the Pledge of Allegiance to the flag every day,'' Education Commissioner <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Raynolds </PERSON> said in an interview Thursday. Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has attempted to make <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' 1977 veto of a state law requiring teachers to conduct the pledge into a campaign issue in their presidential contest. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, in vetoing the bill, cited advisory legal opinions and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> precedents that making the pledge mandatory would be unconstitutional. He says he supports saying the pledge itself. <PERSON> Raynolds </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> schools observe that policy of encouraging the pledge on a voluntary basis. `` The law is clear -LRB- that -RRB- those teachers who do not wish to conduct it, or those students who do not wish to say it, are not compelled to do so,'' he said. But he added that such exceptions are `` very, very, very few, one or two perhaps in a school, in most cases.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has claimed that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was simply `` looking for a reason'' to refuse to sign the bill. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> responded this week that he recites the Pledge of Allegiance himself and would urge children to do so. His 1977 veto was based largely on an advisory opinion from the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The court said the bill before <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> that year, to amend a 1935 law requiring teachers to lead the pledge once a week, violated the First Amendment rights of freedom of speech and religion. It also said the original law was unconstitutional. The amendment said: `` Each teacher at the commencement of the first class of each day in all grades in all public schools shall lead the class in a group recitation of the ` Pledge of Allegiance to the Flag.''' Failure of a teacher over a period of two consecutive weeks `` to salute the flag and recite said pledge ..., or to cause the pupils under his charge so to do, shall be punished for every such period by a fine of not more than $ 5.'' At <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' request, the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> studied the amendment and by a 5-2 vote issued an advisory opinion saying the entire law regarding the pledge violated teachers' First Amendment rights. The court cited a 1943 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision, <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> vs. <PERSON> Barnette </PERSON>, which held that requiring a student, under the threat of expulsion, to recite the pledge and salute the flag violated the student's First Amendment rights. The student, a member of the <PERSON> Jehovah </PERSON>'s Witnesses, had objected on religious grounds. `` In our view, the rationale of the <PERSON> Barnette </PERSON> opinion applies as well to teachers as it does to students,'' the state court said. `` However commendable the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>'s interest may be in imbuing young people with patriotic feelings, that interest can only be implemented through a precise and narrowly drawn provision which achieves the basic purpose without compromising First Amendment rights,'' the justices said. Acting on the court's opinion, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wrote to the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> in 1977, `` My oath of office, as does yours, requires me to uphold the Constitution of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. I can not sign any bill that violates the Constitution, as this bill has been declared to do.'' The Legislature overrode <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' veto, by votes of 201-27 in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and 24-7 in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The bill became law and remains on the books today. But then-state Attorney General <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellotti </PERSON> issued an opinion in 1977 saying that because of the constitutional question, the law `` may not be enforced.'' `` So it has never been enforced, could n't be enforced,'' current Attorney General <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in political speeches over the past week, has said he does n't believe the framers of the Constitution would have considered it a violation of anyone's constitutional rights to be required to recite the Pledge of Allegiance. `` I would have signed that bill'' and let the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> resolve the issue, he says on the campaign trail. But <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said, `` The question really was, OK, do you for political purposes make people go through the expense and the trouble of having to strike down a clearly unconstitutional law, or do you go with the highest court's decision? He -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- did the right thing.'' <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Tribe </PERSON>, a constitutional law professor at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said courts in other states have ruled similarly to the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> court. `` The confusion that I think is created about it ... is that many assume that if teachers have a right to kind of opt out of leading the class in the pledge, that therefore the Pledge of Allegiance will not be somehow an official part of the school day,'' <PERSON> Tribe </PERSON> said. `` But of course that's not what was at stake. It remains an official part of the school day. It is just a question of whether teachers, like students, have a right for reasons of religious conscience to be excused from taking part in it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle-GuardWrapup     08-26 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle-Guard Wrapup,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guard Controversy Poses Nagging Questions, But Hard Evidence
Scarce</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE H. DREYFOUS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The controversy over whether <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> used family influence to secure a spot with the Vietnam-era National Guard dogged the Republican presidential ticket for a full week before finally fading in recent days. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said Thursday he had answered questions `` for seven days now,'' and that the public was `` getting a little bit sick'' of the issue. He said it was time to focus on the differences between the two tickets. The guard questions arose immediately after the 41-year-old <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator was named to the Republican ticket by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. In his inaugural news conference, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked about his decision in May 1969 to seek a guard position instead of accepting a draft or volunteering for military service in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Later, in the midst of a round of network television interviews, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked whether his prominent family pulled strings to get him into the guard. He joined just six days before he became eligible for the draft at the height of the Vietnam War. His answers were not always consistent, but last Friday his spokesman acknowledged that phone calls may have been made on <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s behalf, and a former family employee acknowledged he had made one such call Thus began a controversy that occupied most of the vice presidential candidate's first week of candidacy. Millions of young American men sought alternatives to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> service in the late 1960s, but <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s effort raised eyebrows because of his pro-war stance then and his outspoken advocacy of a strong national defense now. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s decision to join the guard in preference to service in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> did n't sit well with everyone, even among the higher ranks of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>. `` I must tell you, in my generation you knew who was in the Guard and who was in uniform fighting for their country,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> GOP Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in a Sunday television interview. `` So they're very sensitive about it _ they did n't have anybody they could call, they could n't influence anyone, say, ` I asked my parents.' Well, my father wore overalls, who's he going to influence?'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has run into scattered hecklers chanting `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s a chicken'' and bearing signs reading `` <PERSON> Sissy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Boy </PERSON>,'' `` Dump Quayle'' and `` War Wimp.'' National Guard officials have repeatedly denied <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> received preferential treatment, insisting places were available in certain units, including <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s. `` We have found nothing anywhere in our files that would indicate any problem,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Cathi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiger </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. A retired major general in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> did acknowledge Tuesday he told subordinates to hold open a space for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> after retired Guard commander _ and <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON> employee _ called to recommend <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. Retired Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahner </PERSON>, who in 1969 was military support plans officer for the state of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> and later headed the state Guard, said he was contacted by retired Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillippi </PERSON>, then managing editor of <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. `` <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillippi </PERSON> had called and said he had a good man, and said he thought he'd make a good Guardsman,'' <PERSON> Ahner </PERSON> said. `` That's when I went over to personnel `` They said they had a couple of spaces. I said hold one of them, there's a good guy coming over.'' <PERSON> Kiger </PERSON> on Wednesday cited General Order 25, which authorized officials to fill the headquarters detachment's 138 allotted places as of April 1, 1969. Guard records show no more than 134 men were enlisted during April, May _ the month <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> joined _ and June. `` We're not waving the flag here, but a lot of people are saying ` what's the big deal?''' <PERSON> Kiger </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ahner </PERSON> notwithstanding, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> dismissed the issue Monday when he spoke at a Veterans of Foreign Wars meeting in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, saying he did n't need his family's help to join the Guard. `` My <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> unit had openings before I applied, they had openings when I applied and they had openings after I applied. So there was absolutely no influence used,'' said the maternal grandson of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON>, who published newspapers in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> at the time <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> enlisted. Retired Col. <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafferty </PERSON>, who was director of personnel in 1969, said the then-22-year-old <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was a solid Guard candidate, but conceded the recommendations of high-ranking officers carried some weight. `` If ... any of the generals called me and said they knew a man who would make a good Guardsman, I'd prick my ears,'' he said, `` because they only sent the highest quality young man. That's the way the system worked.'' But <PERSON> Rafferty </PERSON> maintained that, despite a certain amount of networking among officers, the service was fundamentally egalitarian. `` We recruited on the basis of the needs of the service _ not the individual,'' he said. The experience of a college dropout sworn in within three days of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> seemed to confirm <PERSON> Rafferty </PERSON>'s claims. Retired Sgt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morell </PERSON> was able to complete processing in three days while there was a 22-day span between <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s initial testing and his enlistment <PERSON> Morell </PERSON>, now an unemployed truck driver, said he dropped out of college and walked into a local recruitment office. He enlisted as a clerk-typist and served side-by-side with <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880826-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BudgetDeficit     08-26 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget Deficit,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Says 1989 Budget So Far Avoids Automatic Cuts</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
