<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-FederalDrugTests     04-08 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Federal Drug Tests,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government to Publish Guidelines For Drug Testimng Of Federal
Employees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government will publish stringent technical guidelines Monday for the random drug testing of federal employees in sensitive jobs, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Saturday's editions that the guidelines will guard against employee cheating by requiring that toilet water be dyed blue to prevent dilution of urine. Temperature readings will be taken from the samples to detect substitution. Quoting an unidentified government source, the newspaper said next week's printing in the Federal Register will be followed by a certification by <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> that all federal agencies have a drug-testing program that meets the guidelines. Although all agencies have submitted plans outlining who will be tested and for what drugs, the final certification date was unclear. Agencies will be required to test for cocaine and marijuana, but may test for PCP, opiates and amphetamines. Finally, the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> must estimate the cost of implementation to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> before the regulations become effective. The working estimate is thought to be `` about $ 7 million,'' the paper said. The new guidelines draw heavily on the experience of the testing which has been conducted in the military for the last seven years. Currently, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> is the only non-military agency testing employees in sensitive jobs. The American Federation of Government Employees, which has filed suit in federal district court in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> against earlier informal standards, contends the random drug testing violates workers' constitutional rights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 2ndLd-Writethru a0818 04-08 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0818,0894</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church Mediation Collapses; Opposition Splits</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 7th graf pvs, ``In another ... to UPDATE
with police breaking up demonstration.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>LaserPhoto PAN2
^By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday it was suspending its effort to mediate <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political crisis as the first major split appeared in the opposition to Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> archbishop of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, said in a statement he was withdrawing his mediation offer for three reasons: _ Opposition groups refused to talk to the government until it showed it was willing to discuss the departure of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> _ The archbishop had not received <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s `` explicit and personal backing of the initiative'' in writing _ There were no assurances that the four international leaders who proposed the talks could be present The breakdown came a day after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> ordered the arrests of several leading opponents. The general has defied <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to force his resignation. In another development, banking and diplomatic sources said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s banks would not reopen Friday, and possibly not next week. The government said last week it hoped to have banks functioning again Friday. Police detained 15 people Thursday night after using tear gas and rubber hoses to break up a march of between 500 and 1,000 anti-government demonstrators in the western city of <PERSON> David </PERSON>. Civilian sources contacted by telephone said National Civic Crusade members were beaten, but there were no immediate reports of serious injuries. A major rift appeared Thursday in the anti-Noriega opposition, as two parties split from the opposition alliance to form their own anti-government movement. Their leaders argued that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic sanctions are hurting <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s people more than they are damaging <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and the civilian government he controls. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Arosemena </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, announced formation of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> in a break with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crusade </ORGANIZATION>, an alliance of about 200 organizations that has led the 10-month-old effort to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. They told a news conference their movement also is backed by the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panamanian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the largest opposition political party. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has supported the Civic Crusade in its effort to remove <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as chief of the 15,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, which include the military and police. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is under indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges, which he denies. <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON> said the new movement rejects any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> influence. `` For us, no recipe that comes from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> has been favorable to the Panamanians,'' he said. `` The people of the world know that the recipes formulated in the imperial capitals, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, never are favorable to the interests of the people.'' He added: `` It is absolutely necessary for Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to abandon his post. For us, this is fundamental.'' Leaders of the two parties have joined demonstrations, strikes and other protests of the Civic Crusade, while differing with some of its policies and generally favoring a harder line. Popular Action, for example, refused to join the Crusade, Authentic Panamanians and three other parties in agreeing to the proposal for dialogue with the government mediated by the Catholic church. The dialogue was proposed by Presidents <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, Prime Minister <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and ex-presidents <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Oduber </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. Political parties linked most closely with the Civic Crusade are the Democratic Christians and the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, known as <PERSON> Molirena </PERSON>. Those two parties, the Crusade and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> all recognize deposed President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as the constitutional head of state. Popular Action and the Authentic Panamanian Party do not. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> orchestrated the ouster of <LOCATION> Delvalle </LOCATION> on Feb. 26, the day after <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> tried to fire the general. <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, brother of a former Popular Action presidential candidate, said the movement `` will center its fight on the original principles of the Civic Crusade.'' `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not continue economic and military action against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Arosemena </PERSON> said. `` The Panamanian people are capable of solving their own problems.'' Banking and diplomatic sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said bank would not open Friday even on a limited basis. They said bankers feared the government would use their deposits if they reopened. The government, whose deposits in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks have been frozen, has not met public payrolls since the crisis began. The last of 1,300 additional <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers arrived Thursday at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, completing a buildup meant to provide greater security for the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, American installations and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens. Late Wednesday, the government said it had issued arrest warrants for three leading opponents, including <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, who has been in hiding in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. It also asked <ORGANIZATION> Interpol </ORGANIZATION>, the international police organization, to arrest <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Galindo </PERSON>, a former ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s envoy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and remains there. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` would regard any efforts by the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> regime to attempt arrests or prosecutions of President <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> and the others for their activities in urging and supporting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sanctions as the unlawful acts of an illegitimate regime.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0705EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CarCorpse     04-08 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Car Corpse,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Four Months, Las Vegas Police Find Body In Missing Man's
Trunk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEFAN FATSIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman whose son disappeared in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> says police found his car abandoned on a highway four months ago but never checked inside the trunk, where a body was discovered by a towing company this week. The coroner in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> said he was completing an autopsy Thursday to determine whether the decomposed body found in the trunk of the <ORGANIZATION> red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buick </ORGANIZATION> is that of 25-year-old <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dumaine </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> police Detective <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Geary </PERSON> said the body has been tentatively identified as <PERSON> Dumaine </PERSON> and the case is being investigated as a homicide. <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, the man's mother, said <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> police repeatedly assured her that no foul play was involved in the disappearance of <PERSON> Dumaine </PERSON>, who apparently won $ 5,200 in a casino en route home for Christmas but was never heard from again. Mrs. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said she last spoke with her son on Nov. 27, when he called from <LOCATION> Bullhead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, a small town on the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> border about 100 miles from <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, to say he was stopping in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> on his way East. <PERSON> Dumaine </PERSON>'s car was found in December, police said, and sat on the lot of Quality Towing in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> about four months before workers noticed a strong odor and checked the trunk. `` They opened the trunk and found my son,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 45, said. `` I could n't believe it. I wanted them to open that trunk for so long and four months later they decided to open it.'' <PERSON> Dumaine </PERSON>, who grew up in <LOCATION> Westfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, had traveled around the western <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, was training to become a chef and had worked on boats, his mother said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0706EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0802 04-08 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0802,0852</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Conrad and Weatherby; AMs separates moved as a0613 on
Hamilton, a0615 on Firouz, a0616 on Polak and a0741 on Bray. A
separate on Hamilton also moved on the business wire.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Denis Hamilton</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, 69, a leading figure in the British newspaper industry for more than four decades and a former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> news agency, died Thursday. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> began his career as a cub reporter on the <ORGANIZATION> Middlesbrough </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> in northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1936. At age 28, he became personal assistant to newspaper proprietor <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemsley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> became editor of the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Sunday Times, weekly companion of the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>, when Canadian Lord <PERSON> Thomson </PERSON> bought the newspapers in 1959, as well as editorial director of the group. He was also editor-in-chief of <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> served as chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> from 1979 to 1985 during the British-based agency's expansion of its financial news services He was also the first president from 1978 until 1983 of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an organization of more than 200 editors and publishers. <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> introduced the color magazine supplement, now a feature of all the big national weekly newpapers, into British journalism.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Mozaffar Firouz</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mozaffar </PERSON> <PERSON> Firouz </PERSON>, a former Iranian vice premier who was known as the `` Red Prince'' for his close ties with the Tudeh Communist party, died at age 83. Members of his family did not say when he died. <PERSON> Firouz </PERSON> took part in negotations in 1946 on the withdrawal of Soviet troops from the Iranian part of <LOCATION> Azerbaijan </LOCATION> in the aftermath of World War II. He also held the labor ministry portfolio and helped draw up <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s first labor code. <PERSON> Firouz </PERSON> eventually was named ambassador to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> but resigned the post in 1947 to protest what he called undemocratic policies of <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON>. He moved to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and published articles and books attacking the shah.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Andre Polak</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BRUSSELS, Belgium (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Polak </PERSON>, a architect who helped design the <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> Atomium momument for the 1958 World Fair, died Saturday of a heart attack. He was 74. <PERSON> Polak </PERSON> created the structure along with his brother, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON>. The structure resembles an iron molecule to symbolize the power of science, the atomic age and Belgian industrial acumen of the 1950s. The nine huge spheres of the 335-foot-tall Atomium still dominate the cityscape of suburban <PERSON> Laken </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Jeanne Bray</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bray </PERSON>, a five-time national women's police revolver champion and a 28-year veteran of the <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> police force, died Wednesday at the age of 56 Ms. <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> won the National Women's Police Combat Pistol Championship, sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, in 1962, 1963, 1964, 1965 and 1967. In 1984, Ms. <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> was a nominee for the Outstanding American Handgunner Award. Considered an authority on personal protection, she traveled widely to lecture on the subject. Ms. <PERSON> Bray </PERSON> filmed a self-defense program for Dutch television and developed a slide show for baby sitters.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Allen Kingman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHAPEL HILL, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingman </PERSON>, a brigadier general who served in both World Wars and was awarded military honors from a half-dozen foreign countries, died Monday at age 94. <PERSON> Kingman </PERSON> was commissioned as a second lieutenant of infantry and served on the Mexican border during the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' 1916-1917 effort to capture <PERSON> Pancho </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON>. In World War I, he went to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> with the 16th Infantry of the First Division, the first company to land in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. In World War II, <PERSON> Kingman </PERSON> served with the Second Armored Division. He retired in 1953. During his 36 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kingman </LOCATION> received the Legion of Merit, the <ORGANIZATION> Bronze </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>, the Commendation Medal and the Purple Heart. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> honored him with the <PERSON> Croix </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerre </PERSON> with Palm for bravery in combat, and he received the Brazilian War Medal.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Francis Conrad</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, a high-level <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> official, was stabbed to death Thursday at the age of 51. <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> had private practices in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Stony </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION> before joining the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> in 1973 as a staff psychiatrist. He was a former associate professor of clinical psychiatry and associate dean of veterans affairs at <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Stony </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>. In 1985, <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> became director of the office of quality assurance, responsible for all quality-assurance programs in <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> health systems, which include 172 hospitals and 229 clinics nationwide.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Roy Weatherby</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weatherby </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, creator of the famed <PERSON> Weatherby </PERSON> rifle favored by big game hunters and a leading authority on firearms and ballistics, died Tuesday after heart surgery. He was 77. It was <PERSON> Weatherby </PERSON>'s perfection of his theory on high velocity and the resulting <ORGANIZATION> Weatherby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magnum </ORGANIZATION> cartiridges that led to the development of the <PERSON> Weatherby </PERSON> rifle. The Weatherby Big Game Trophy, created in 1956, is prized in the hunting world. <PERSON> Weatherby </PERSON> retired from active participation in the company's affairs in December 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Oscars-SupportingActor     04-08 0934</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Oscars-Supporting Actor,0952</SECOND>
<HEAD>OSCAR COUNTDOWN: Supporting Actor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Supporting Actor Nominees Are Diverse and None Has Won Before</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The race for best supporting actor of 1987 provides <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> voters a choice among a perspiring TV reporter, a steely <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> cop, a philandering <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> husband, a wily <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> pimp and a South African martyr. The nominees are a diverse lot, ranging from the first <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> to a stand-up comedian. None has ever won an Oscar. <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> is generally considered the quintessential 007, a role that seemed impossible for him to escape. But after 30 years in films, he has finally been recognized for his performance as another enforcer, the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> beat cop <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> in `` The Untouchables.'' `` I thought it was a very clever concept to take the old cop and use him as a kind of old dog who teaches a new dog tricks,'' says <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> of his role as mentor to the young federal agent, <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>. Yet Connery is maintaining a classic Bond cool over the possibility of winning his first Oscar. `` To be honest, I've never really spent much time thinking about it before,'' he said in a recent interview. `` I just go on with my work.'' Neither is he bitter that it has taken the Academy some 40 films to even nominate him. `` It's all a matter of timing and how your films and image are presented,'' <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> told the Hollywood Reporter. `` There are a lot of my films which I'm very proud of, which I think were artistic successes, but were n't huge box office successes like the Bond pictures.'' There's no chance, though, that <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> will snub the Academy if he wins. `` It'd be important to me, and I'd definitely turn up to collect it. I'm not one of those actors who'd send along the cleaning lady instead.'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> accomplished the near-impossible: winning a nomination in a film released early in the year to scant notice. His role as vicious `` Fast Black'' in `` Street Smart'' was dynamic enough to remain in Academy voters' minds. Born in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and raised in <LOCATION> Greenwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, before moving to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> built up an impressive number of stage credits before appearing in such films as `` Brubaker,'' `` Teachers'' and `` <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>.'' His performance in `` Street Smart'' prompted this outburst from the New Yorker's <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kael </PERSON>: `` Is <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> the greatest actor in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> today?'' <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> admits to a rough life while growing up in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION>: `` I stole, I conned, I passed the tests But I was scared. I'm not the violent type.'' This contrasts the brutal role he plays in `` Street Smart.'' Instead of sliding into delinquency, the young <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> found himself attracted to acting, and sold bottles so he would have money to go to the movies. <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardenia </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s excitable father in `` Moonstruck,'' has been in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> theater since 1954 and films since 1958. He also was a member of the `` All in the Family'' cast on television. <PERSON> Gardenia </PERSON> was ideal casting as the Italian plumber; his family emigrated from <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION>, and he began acting in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Italian theater. He was delighted with the `` Moonstruck'' script: `` It was the first about an Italian family in a long time that you do n't see shooting, killings, bombings. It's about love, about family.'' <PERSON> Denzel </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> was cast in `` Cry Freedom'' after a worldwide search for an actor to play the vital role of <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Biko </PERSON>, the black leader who was beaten to death by South African police while in their custody. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> admits that his nomination was `` both a letdown and a great honor.'' The letdown came because <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> had been promoting him for best actor, and he had been nominated for a Golden Globe in that category. He adds that his reaction was n't the result of an actor's ego. `` It has more to do with my own feelings about <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Biko </PERSON>,'' he says. `` I would like to see him in -LRB- a starring -RRB- light, and I think most people do. He was not a supporting player.'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> faced an imposing challenge: portraying a much-admired, even revered figure while making him a believable human being. `` I do n't know how to play a saint,'' he says. `` I could n't get any advice from anyone on how to play a saint. So that was no problem.'' Under <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Attenborough </PERSON>'s direction, he created a portrait of the martyr that was both human and convincing. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said the effect of `` Cry Freedom'' on the apartheid issue will be on a personal level. `` Most of the comments I've gotten from people were that they did n't know what goes on in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` That's where it will have its most important effect. I do n't think it's going to make a change in the government's attitude or the attitude of the black people there. It's just a movie, commenting on something from the outside.'' <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, the astute reporter and failed anchorman of `` Broadcast News,'' is noted for directing himself in films: `` Real Life,'' `` Modern Romance,'' `` Lost in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, a stand-up comedian before making films, says that the role of <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Altman </PERSON> was different from his own life: `` I do n't work in the news business I do n't have a 9 to 5 or even a 9 to 9 job. I do n't wear suits. I do n't have friends. ... Over a period of four months I hung out with a dozen reporters. I think what happens is you sort of compile little things from everybody.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Training     04-08 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Training,0779</SECOND>
<HEAD>Civilians Form `Dignity Battalions' To Repel Yankee Invasion</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In dusty fields and stadiums across <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, civilians turn out by the hundreds for military training to repel what the government says is an imminent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> invasion. `` We get political speeches, and sometimes we see patriotic films,'' said <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, a government housing ministry employee. `` We do physical training and we have some weapons instruction.'' The volunteer units, called `` Dignity Battalions,'' formed, and have grown, since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> started announcing increases in troop strength in the former <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Canal Zone in mid-March. There is close-order drill, replete with slogans vowing death on behalf of the homeland and questioning the ancestry of all <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>. About 300 volunteers showed up on one field near the capital Wednesday night, and some said it is one of the smallest battalions in the country. The battalion in the western city of <LOCATION> Davis </LOCATION> is said to have more than 1,000 participants. There is no reliable estimate on participation nationwide. In one corner of the field an instructor explained the basics of an M-16 rifle and passed several among his charges. Some, but not all, handled it uncomfortably. `` The Americans have them with a grenade launcher attatched. Do we have those too?'' asked one youth. `` Yes, we do,'' the instructor answered patiently. `` Hey, do n't point that thing at another comrade. The government press is predicting loudly that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will resort to invasion troops to oust Panamanian strongman Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. As head of the 15,000-member Panamanian Defense forces, <PERSON> Noreiga </PERSON> is the power behind the civilian government. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> normally keeps 10,000 troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to guard the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. In mid-March 500 military police were added, and 1,300 more troops arrived this week. The stated purpose of their open-ended assignment is to provide security for the troops, American installations and American citizens. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said 800 Marines will start arriving Friday for three weeks of routine jungle training. Evening papers Wednesday ballyhooed the planned arrival but neglected to mention the short planned stay. `` In Ships of Terror and Death, Contingents of War Veterans of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> Arrive in Open Plan of Aggression and Intimidation,'' read a headline in the government-owned Matutino newspaper. `` Gringo Invaders Begin to Arrive,'' read a headline in Wednesday's <PERSON> Critica </PERSON>, also government-owned. A cartoon shows Uncle <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> fleeing from gunfire from the `` popular forces,'' as the battalions also are known. The government closed all opposition media more than a month ago. All that Panamanians watch, read or hear comes from newspapers and broadcast stations owned at least partially by the government. Foreign newspapers brought in by travelers are confiscated at the airport. The volunteer battalions are instructed by <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> troops, who appear patient and have their work cut out for them. Most participants appear in their late teens or early to mid-20s. A few are easily 50. Many are women and all say they are not paid or required to attend the two-hour evening sessions held seven days a week. There is no roll call and no apparent other check of who shows up. `` We fight for our homeland and our dignity. The <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> only fight for money,'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said. The instruction and the rhetoric were more reminiscent of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> in recent years than a country where Americans have been well-tolerated, if not always cherished, for most of this century. The feeling is growing, it appears, but is far from universal. In a shabbier sector of downtown <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> a woman held up two shotgun shells fired by police during a minor demonstration. `` This is what they shoot at the people, like they are beasts,'' she said as the tear gas lifted. `` We've had it up to here. `` Panamanians are tired of this. We want the gringos to attack _ not tomorrow, today.'' `` Tonight,'' suggested a young man in a crowd that was gathering near two journalists. But those on the drill field felt otherwise. `` We believe an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> invasion is close, very close,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, an office holder in the nearby municipality of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miguelito </LOCATION>, speaks sincerely of American bodies going back to their home towns and said he is not worried about weapons availability. `` In revolutions in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> they did n't worry about weapons,'' he said. `` They took them from their dead enemies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0309EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Radio     04-08 0897</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Radio,0926</SECOND>
<HEAD>Staying Tuned To Radio Free Europe On Polish State Radio</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A curious new program is going out over <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s state radio every Monday morning. It's called `` The West Speaks,'' and it is composed entirely of excerpts of Polish-language broadcasts by <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Europe </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and other Western radio stations. The segments are broadcast without comment or counterpoint, but since the program went on the air the Polish media and officials have criticized the Western broadcasts with greater frequency. The Western stations always have been characterized here as hostile propaganda tools, but the Communist government says `` The West Speaks'' is one way to counter the influence of the broadcasts that deliver a mixture of uncensored news, features and commentary. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> stopped the electronic jamming of Western broadcasts Jan. 1 and Poles now can freely tune in to them. But government authorities have been raising the question of their fairness with Western officials, including the director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Z. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wick </PERSON>, who was here on a visit in March. The authorities say that in the struggle for the hearts and minds of the Polish people, they can not afford to overlook the influence of the Western stations. `` It does n't matter how many people listen to it when it is something very dangerous,'' government spokesman <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON> said in an interview. `` Even if it's only 100 people, that is enough, because the report will spread.'' At one time, particularly during the Cold War years in the 1950s, it was a crime to listen to the Western stations. Today, however, the strains of `` Yankee Doodle Dandy,'' the sign-on tune of the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, can be heard coming from apartments in housing blocks. Urban said Polish authorities believed that countering the broadcasts with `` polemics and arguments'' was better than continuing the jamming. A public opinion poll quoted by the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> said 80 percent of respondents approved the decision to end the jamming, but it said the number of listeners has not risen significantly. How many people actually listen remains a matter of dispute. According to a survey quoted by Urban, the percentage of Poles who listen to Radio Free Europe either regularly or occasionally is 16 percent, up 2 percentage points since jamming ended. Only 3 percent, or 1.2 million out of the population of 37.5 million, listen as often as once a week, he said. But the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>, the body that oversees <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Europe </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, says 59 percent of Poles listen to its broadcasts occasionally and nearly 14 percent at least once a week. An informal survey of half a dozen <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> residents indicated that most preferred the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> or the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> to Radio Free <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> RFE </ORGANIZATION>, on grounds that their information was more reliable. Recent <ORGANIZATION> RFE </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts were heavy with reports of demonstrations and protests in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, speeches and statements by leaders of the outlawed Solidarity trade union and accounts of opposition activities in other countries of the Soviet bloc. `` The West Speaks'' was conceived `` to show what sort of argumentation is used by these stations,'' said <PERSON> Witold </PERSON> <PERSON> Stankowski </PERSON>, an executive of Polish Radio One. He said the show, which premiered in October, was given a time slot when `` we have a pretty good audience,'' but said he could not judge its popularity or say how long it would be continued. In recent months a drumbeat of commentaries have shown up on the <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> service and in state-run newspapers disputing specific news items on the Western stations. Urban has made denunciations of the broadcasts almost a fixture at his weekly news conferences. In the interview, Urban noted that listenership tends to rise in times of public anxiety, such as during the 1986 <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear accident in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He claimed <ORGANIZATION> RFE </ORGANIZATION>'s `` disgraceful methods'' frightened people in its reports on <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> and in its coverage of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s announcement in late January of price increases totaling 42 percent in 1988 `` Radio Free <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> presents the opinion that prices in fact will go up twice as much,'' he said. `` They want to cause, and really do cause, an increase in wage demands.'' <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> defends the broadcasts. `` The great bulk of what goes out seems to me to be a repetition of what already has been published in the West,'' he said. `` It is broadcast in, sometimes with comment, and comment is fair game.'' <PERSON> Wick </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION> director who arrived in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> on March 23 for a series of talks with Polish officials, said the Polish side raised objections about Radio Free Europe and the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the complaints were discussed `` very forthrightly.'' <PERSON> Wick </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, which is part of <ORGANIZATION> USIA </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Europe </ORGANIZATION>, which is privately opeated but largely funded by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, have charters that mandate that they be `` objective and accurate.'' `` I invited the authorities to give me specific instances when they were not,'' he said. He added that editorials on Radio Free Europe and the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> are not intended to be objective, but to `` reflect the editorial viewpoint of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government.'' As such, he said, they might not be pleasing to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0709EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StungForGifts Bjt   04-08 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stung For Gifts, Bjt,0714</SECOND>
<HEAD>Women Always Stung For Presents Throw Bash _ For Themselves</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto PG2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCIA DUNN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The ladies of the club _ <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Always </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stung </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> _ are throwing a bash today, and as usual the guests of honor are themselves. The dozen or so retired school secretaries plan to treat themselves to a fancy lunch, toast their single status and present themselves with an extra special gift. That's for the years and years of giving presents to their married friends, but never getting anything back. `` This is really to treat ourselves because no one else really has,'' explained <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Kieffer </PERSON>, 63, who's serving as the queen, or organizer, of today's gathering of the society, otherwise known as WASPS. `` Oh, Lordy, every time you turn around you're giving gifts. Wedding gifts and baby gifts and shower gifts. You could n't begin to count them. You're giving all the time, but you're not getting anything in return,'' said <PERSON> Alma </PERSON> <PERSON> Eck </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON>, 81, a founding member of the 38-year-old society. Miss <PERSON> Kieffer </PERSON> is giving herself a new white coat. Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON>, a widow who married late in life, is celebrating with a watch on a necklace. Gifts can be whatever the women need or want. Over the years, presents have included diamond rings, new cars, houses, European vacations, even a custom-made girdle. `` She was quite a heavy girl and she could never get a girdle to fit her. So she had one made,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> said Thursday. Each woman writes a poem, to herself naturally, and gives herself a card that reads, `` I love me.'' They also sing this peppy tune: `` That's where our money's spent, on all the gals who went. We bought them everything to keep them supplied. We think the time is due to get a gift or two. So WASPS let's see what you brought you.'' The conversation covers just about everything except for children, grandchildren and, of course, men. `` That's why it's so nice. I do n't have to listen to stories about everybody's wonderful grandchildren,'' Miss <PERSON> Kieffer </PERSON> said, laughing. The members, ranging in age from their mid-50s to late 80s, have been gathering every April since 1950, when Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> and 23 other never-wed secretaries for the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> decided enough was enough. They formed the society after learning about a similar group in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. To be eligible, women had to be single and employed as a secretary for the <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> for at least 10 years. `` If you were married, somebody would have had some plush party for you. So that was it. We'd be the contributors,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> said. `` But you could be married after that because once a WASP, always a WASP.'' <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, says the society likely has its roots in the days when female teachers in some parts of the country were barred from saying `` I do.'' `` They just extended themselves through their kids'' in school, he said. The Women Always Stung for Presents Society grew to more than 60 members around 1970, but has since dwindled to 14, seven of them founding members. Two women are now married. Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> is the only widow. `` A lot of them -LRB- members -RRB- have died,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> said. Secretaries nowadays simply are n't interested. `` They do n't want to have that brand,'' <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Viehman </PERSON>, 69, said. `` To say they've been working for 10 years and they are n't married, I guess it's terrible. It does n't bother me, but it does some people.'' The society meets once a year on April Fools' Day. The date was pushed back this year since Good Friday fell on April 1. The restaurant get-togethers are mandatory and planned months in advance. Members who can drive pick up those who ca n't. Just about everybody comes freshly coiffed and sporting a new outfit. `` We enjoy seeing each other because who knows who will be there next year,'' Miss <PERSON> Kieffer </PERSON> said. `` Our girls are all getting older,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mullen </PERSON> agreed. `` But we always say if there's one left, that one will go. We'll keep it up.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SteigerVerdict     04-08 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Steiger Verdict,0406</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Convicts Former Mecham Aide Of Extortion</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BURT GOODMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury on Thursday convicted former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> of theft by extortion for threatening a parole board member to get his vote on a personnel matter while serving in the <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> administration. `` Any time you go to court you can expect a guilty verdict, but it's difficult to believe,'' <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> said in the courtroom moments after the jury returned its verdict. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, who was a top aide to the now-ousted <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> governor, was accused of threatening <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a member of the state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pardons </ORGANIZATION> and Paroles. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> allegedly threatened to withhold permission for <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> to work as a part-time <LOCATION> Tempe </LOCATION> justice of the peace and to remove him from the board unless he voted to retain as executive director <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Mecham </LOCATION> appointee. Judge <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinstein </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Maricopa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> scheduled a May 6 sentencing for the 59-year-old <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, who faces up to five years in prison. Asked whether the verdict would be appealed, defense attorney <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Karas </PERSON> said, `` We'll take it one step at a time.'' <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> said, `` That's up to counsel.'' Jury foreman <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a fire captain in suburban <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>, said the deciding factor behind the verdict was `` the tapes of the phone call between <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> called <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> at home from the office of the state attorney general, who taped the call. During testimony Monday, <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> denied that he threatened <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> or told him how he should vote. But the state alleged that <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> followed up on the alleged threat in a letter and a telephone conversation after <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> voted with the board majority to seek Ms. <PERSON> Costello </PERSON>'s resignation. The board voted 4-3 that Ms. <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> should step down because of low staff morale. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, a former five-term congressman, testified that he did suggest that <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> should back Ms. <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> but denied that he tried to `` steal'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s vote by threatening his job. <PERSON> Karas </PERSON> had asked <PERSON> Reinstein </PERSON> to declare a mistrial, contending the conviction of <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> at his state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> impeachment trial Monday might prejudice jurors against <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>. However, <PERSON> Reinstein </PERSON> ruled that great care had been taken to select unbiased jurors. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> gave up his 3rd Congressional District seat in 1976 to run unsuccessfully for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as a Republican.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0715EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     04-08 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra Defendants Argue Both Directions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> is being attacked in opposite directions by the Iran-Contra defendants, with one claiming he improperly ignored congressional testimony and the other three saying he illegally used it. Attorneys representing former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and arms dealer <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> moved Thursday to dismiss the indictment against them, claiming <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> illegally relied on testimony the three gave last year to the Iran-Contra congressional committees after being granted limited immunity. Because of the immunity grants, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> was required to collect all of his evidence independently. North, <PERSON> Piondexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> claim that, given the massive publicity surrounding the hearings, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s case was inevitably tainted by exposure to their immunized _ regardless of efforts to insulate investigators and grand jurors from that evidence. But lawyers for retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, the fourth defendant, claim that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> unfairly ignored the congressional testimony of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>. They say that testimony would have led the grand jury to decline to name their client in the 23-count indictment. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, who brokered the arms sales with <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, was the lead witness at last year's televised hearings of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Iran-Contra committees and testified without any immunity. All four defendants are accused of conspiring to divert profits illegally from the U.S.-Iran arms sales to the Nicaraguan rebels. The so-called `` use immunity'' grants conferred by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> prohibit <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> from using evidence obtained directly or indirectly from their congressional testimony. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> imposed special precautions to prevent his staff and the grand jury from being exposed to the extensive publicity surrounding the hearings. Prosecutors and grand jurors alike were told to ignore news reports or conversations with friends about the hearings. Evidence was filed under seal in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to prove that it was obtained independently of the immunized testimony. But in pleadings filed with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, lawyers for <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> said those precautions were not enough. `` Never in the history of this nation has the immunized testimony of putative defendants been broadcast live, on all major networks, to tens of millions of viewers and listeners,'' the defense said. `` Given the widespread dissemination of immunized testimony throughout our society, the broad use of immunized testimony has been inevitable, undeniable, and so pervasive that the indictment must be dismissed as a matter of law,'' the defense argued. As an alternative to dismissing the charges, the defense asked <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to conduct a hearing to determine if immunized congressional testimony influenced <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s investigation. The defense says it wants to question grand jurors to determine if they learned about the congressional hearings from friends, relatives or news broadcasts or from grand jury witnesses. <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s lawyers are taking a different course. They contend that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> unfairly refused to consider the congressional testimony of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, which they contend would vindicate their client of any wrongdoing. The grand jury should have had an opportunity to consider this testimony before returning an indictment against <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, his lawyers said. `` The independent counsel's decision to exalt prosecutorial convenience above General <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s Fifth Amendment right to a fair and informed grand jury taints the proceedings against him and requires, as a matter of fundamental fairness, that the indictment be dismissed,'' <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s lawyers said. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> has scheduled a hearing next Tuesday to discuss the immunity issue, which could take months to resolve.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-NoyesObit     04-08 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Noyes Obit,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Longtime Washington Star Editor Dead At 67</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Crosby </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON>, a longtime reporter and editor for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>, died Thursday after a heart attack. He was 67. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON>, who began his career as a reporter for the Star in 1947 and went on to become chief European correspondent and then foreign editor, died at <LOCATION> Sibley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. When <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> joined the newspaper's staff, his family had been associated with it for almost 100 years. He specialized in foreign affairs from the start, making various reporting trips to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and opening the paper's <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> bureau in 1954. He was in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from 1956-1958, then returned to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and reported from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> until 1964, when he became foreign editor. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> was `` especially good at putting complicated foreign issues in understandable terms,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Seib </PERSON>, a former managing editor of the Star. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> won the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Headliner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> award in 1958 for foreign reporting for a series on the rise of Gen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON> to president of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> retired in 1974, when the <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kauffmann </PERSON> families, which had controlled the newspaper since 1867, sold it to <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Albritton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Albritton </PERSON> later sold the paper to <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which closed it in 1981. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON>, who lived in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was born in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He served in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> during World War II, and after becoming a flier was assigned to instruct Free French pilots in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He later flew combat in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and was awarded the Distinguished Flying Cross and the Air Medal. <PERSON> Noyes </PERSON> is survived by his wife, the former <PERSON> Letitia </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughson </PERSON>, and four children, two brothers and a half-sister.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ShyKids     04-08 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shy Kids,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biology May Explain Why Some Children Are Bashful, Say Researchers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Extremely shy children and those who are very outgoing may be responding to a biological rhythm set at birth and continued throughout life, researchers say in a study published today. A scientist from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> and two from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> said in a study published in the journal Science that extremely inhibited children experience a more rapid heart beat, a dilation of the pupils and increased muscular tension when they encounter novel experiences or social stresses. `` It appears that a small percentage of children are born with a biological disposition that would tend to make them shy, and this is independent of what the parent has or has not done,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Reznick </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> psychologist. Although the study postulated a `` biological constitution'' for shyness, <PERSON> Reznick </PERSON> emphasized that this finding `` in no way indicates that -LRB- the shy -RRB- child will not be successful.'' `` They learn to compensate,'' <PERSON> Reznick </PERSON> said. `` They may learn strategies that would make them appear not to be shy.'' <PERSON> Reznick </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> researchers <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Kagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON> drew these conclusions from a series of tests that followed a group of children from the age 20 months to 7 -LCB- years. Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON> said in an interview that the scientists determined which children were extremely shy and which were outgoing by observing their response to novel situations in a playroom. `` Does the child immediately go to the center of the room and start playing, or does the child stay close to the mother? If a stranger walks in, does the child retreat to his mother, or go over and approach the stranger?'' said Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON>. The researchers also observed how the children reacted to new toys, to youngsters unknown to them, and how often the children spoke. `` If you took a random sample of children, you would find about 10 percent at either end of the scale,'' Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON> said. `` The rest of the children will do a little of both _ that's most children.'' After identifying the shy and the outgoing children, the researchers tested them for physiological reactions. They found that the shy youngsters tended to have faster heart rates that accelerated more rapidly in the presence of novel situations. Heart rates for the uninhibited children were among the lowest. Shy children also experienced marked dilation of the pupils, a rise in a body chemical that is produced during stress, and a change in the voice quality caused by muscle tenseness. This fundamental pattern remained consistent through all the years of the study, said Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON>, although `` as these children grow older, you see the behavior responses in different ways.'' When the children were 7 -LCB-, the scientists conducted a party for three shy youngsters, another three who were uninhibited and four who were in between. `` We find that the children whom we classified as inhibited at 20 months were the children in this party situation who tended to stay a little distant from the other children and not talk as much in the free play situation,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON>. Although it has yet to be demonstrated by study, <PERSON> Reznick </PERSON> said `` it would seem reasonable to believe that the biological differences would continue through life.'' But such a person, said Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON>, `` can learn to cope very well.'' `` Some children who are very inhibited have parents who are very understanding and deal with it very well,'' she said. `` Those children look less inhibited as they get older.'' The shy child may be very successful in school, said Ms. <PERSON> Snidman </PERSON>. `` They are quiet and attentive. Teachers love them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-RockAuction     04-08 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Rock Auction,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beatles, Who Memorabilia Yield More Than $350,000 at Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mock newspaper scribbled in a notebook by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> at the age of 18 sold for nearly $ 22,500 at an auction of rock and pop music memorabilia, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s auctioneers said. A flame-shaped bass guitar used by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Entwistle </PERSON> of `` The Who'' surprised bidders by selling for 15,000 pounds -LRB- $ 28,005 -RRB- at Thursday's sale, which yielded a total of 188,694 pounds -LRB- $ 352,291 -RRB-. Three manuscripts for songs by <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, who was shot to death in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in 1980 at the age of 40, also drew high prices. In the four-page mock newspaper written in a school notebook, <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON> wrote nonsense and comic text and poetry and drew cartoons in crayon. It was called the Daily Howl and priced at 1 penny or `` a halfpenny to the vicar.'' <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s called it an important stylistic landmark to be compared with <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s later written works. The <PERSON> Entwistle </PERSON> guitar _ one of 140 in his collection and five up for auction _ was sold to an unidentified buyer. The guitarist, who attended the auction, said he decided to put the instruments up for sale because they were taking up too much space in his house. <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s manuscript lyrics for the 1964 song `` If I Fell'' were purchased by a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> client for 7,800 pounds, and his manuscript for the 1964 tune `` Any Time at All'' was purchased by an anonymous person for 6,000 pounds. A Japanese Beatles Fan Club linked to the auction by satellite purchased 19 of the 250 items on sale for 8,000 pounds. Japanese coordinator <PERSON> Mariko </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujiwara </PERSON> said `` the Beatles are very popular in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' partly because <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, is Japanese.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Britain-Anti-Yuppies Bjt   04-08 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Anti-Yuppies, Bjt,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anarchist Group Promises `National Anti-Yuppie Day'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By COTTEN TIMBERLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As if <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s yuppies did n't have enough to worry about in the fallout from the stock market crash, they're now faced with anarchists plotting a `` National Anti-Yuppie Day.'' Adding to the misery of yuppie job losses, pay cuts and dwindling stock portfolios is Class War, an anarchists' group, which announced a 22-city rock concert tour in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for August dubbed `` Rock against the Rich.'' It said in a statement made available Thursday to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that it hopes the tour will culminate in an anti-yuppie extravaganza on Sept. 10. Just who Class War is has never been clear. `` It's not a club you join,'' said a sympathizer, who gave his name only as <PERSON> Sean </PERSON>. Nor has the size of its membership been divulged. Group members sometimes surface in anti-capitalist stunts like a 1984 campaign in which bank windows were smashed, a smoke bomb exploded near the Bank of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and about 470 people were arrested. But why pick on yuppies? Class War explained: `` All over <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, a plague of yuppies are descending on working-class communities like locusts. The time to resist is now _ let's Rock Against the Rich.'' In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> said it was `` because people have been pushed out from areas where they have always lived because of greed on the part of speculators, because it is n't possible to afford to buy somewhere to live in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> unless you have a hell of a lot of money.'' The story of the anti-yuppie campaign was broken, appropriately enough, in the Independent newspaper, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s newest daily and a favorite among yuppies. Its good-natured report Thursday on Class War's manifesto said: `` With this defiant, if ungrammatical, declaration, a new musical movement has been launched.'' But the newspaper wrote: `` Rock Against the Rich seems very unlikely to raise anything like the level of support given by musicians and audiences to the anti-fascist Rock Against Racism in the 1970s or pro-Labor -LRB- Party -RRB- Red Wedge rock tours before the last general election.'' The concerts are to be held in cities, like <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Exeter </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, whose run-down inner areas are being `` gentrified'' by wealthy young newcomers, <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> said. An exception is <LOCATION> Guildford </LOCATION>, the heart of the stockbroker belt south of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where the concert has been dubbed, `` Rock Against Stockbrokers.'' The planned anti-yuppie day's main attraction is an outdoor rock concert in the Docklands, in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>, where gentrifiers have been clashing with the local residents, the group said. Docklands developers say they have rescued the area from irreversible decline and provided affordable housing for local residents. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Strummer </PERSON>, previously guitarist with The Clash, a 1970s rock group, has agreed to join the tour, as well as other, less well-known musicians, Class War said. The group is targeting yuppies because `` they come off flaunting wealth when there's none there to start with,'' <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s yuppie class grew visibly during Big Bang, the huge deregulation of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s financial markets in 1986. Expanding investment firms paid top money to attract brokers and bankers, and many yuppie-haters reacted with glee to the stock market crash last October. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> still suffers from class antagonisms and the tug-of-war between capitalism and socialism continues unabated. Some see Class War as just another manifestation of British eccentricity. Others see a more sinister side in the group's reported support for `` taxing'' yuppies by mugging and burglarizing them Class War is `` tapping real feeling in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> End </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, who wrote about the group for the Independent, said in a telephone interview. But `` it's hard to know what their real influence is. Opinions vary on the left about whether they are publicity-seeking idiots or whether they are doing anything, even on the far left.'' `` Their rhetoric is quite nasty,'' <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> added. `` Nobody else -LRB- political groups -RRB- will have anything to do with them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CrashProbe     04-08 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crash Probe,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>FAA Gets Spotlight In Crash Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hearing on a commuter airline crash that killed 18 people focused Thursday on why the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> reduced a staff member's recommendation of a $ 250,000 fine to $ 16,500. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> official had recommended the fine against <ORGANIZATION> Ryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for more about 250 safety and records violations. The airline has been cited or fined several times for paperwork and safety violations in recent years. A tail-heavy, overloaded Ryan Air Beech 1900 crashed Nov. 23 at the Homer Airport in the country's worst commuter airline crash in 19 years. Eighteen people died and only three survived. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transporation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> members and their aides spent Thursday questioning <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> employees about the crash, the 10th <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> accident in eight years. Four involved fatalities. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON>, now seeking protection from creditors under Chapter 11 of federal bankruptcy laws, was grounded in January as part of a consent agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>. Before the agreement, <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> was <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s largest commuter airline, serving more than 80 cities and communities. The investigators tried to piece together why three of the company's pilots who volunteered to provide records concerning overloaded flights in exchange for immunity were rebuffed by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>. One of the pilots, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Deliman </PERSON>, was killed in the Homer crash. <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gossen </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> operations inspector, said he conducted a week-long inspection in February 1987 and found scores of discrepancies in record keeping, pilot competency checks and training records. He recommended a $ 250,000 civil penalty _ $ 1,000 per violation. `` That's the largest civil penalty I've ever recommended,'' he testified. `` I felt like a high civil penalty would have more or as much impact as a -LRB- flight certificate -RRB- suspension.'' His former boss, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, testified he supported the recommendation. The suggested fine was passed up the line, but was bounced back with instructions to gather more evidence. <PERSON> Gossen </PERSON> said he again submitted the recommendation. It was rejected by former <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> regional counsel <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Boberick </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gossen </PERSON> said he tried again, reducing the suggested penalty to $ 25,000. Boberick reduced the fine to $ 16,500. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Westall </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s director of flight standards in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> told the board the proposed fine was reduced because of `` purely legal defects.'' Courts in the past have not supported the notion of a $ 1,000 fine per violation, he said. <PERSON> Westall </PERSON> said he first supported the proposed $ 250,000 fine, but then changed his mind after talking with <PERSON> Boberick </PERSON>. `` In this case, he convinced me,'' <PERSON> Westall </PERSON> said. The $ 16,500 fine will not be assessed unless the airline again gets airborne, <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Steucke </PERSON> said. Despite his airline's history of problems, <PERSON> Wilfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who was forced from his position as president of <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> by the January consent order, testified Wednesday his company had been the target of <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> harassment. `` <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> was our largest carrier, so they got a larger part of our inspections,'' <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> said Thursday. `` I do n't think <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Air </PERSON> was over inspected because of the size and complexity of their operation.'' After the November crash, the airline was cited by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> for flying Beech 1900s that were tail-heavy at least four times in the month before the fatal accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CentralAmerica-Drugs     04-08 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Central America-Drugs,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hearings Raise Questions About Honesty of `War on Drugs'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration must answer tough questions about whether its support for the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels led it to wink at multimillion-dollar drug deals, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> says. The Foreign Relations subcommittee headed by <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., has heard a week of testimony about the daring night-time flights and huge profits made by cocaine and marijuana traffickers, along with allegations that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials knew about some of the trafficking but did nothing to halt it Two convicted drug smugglers testified Thursday that weapons were illegally flown to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> for the Contras and hundreds of pounds of cocaine were brought back on the return flights. The Contras have denied that they were involved in illegal drug trafficking. `` I think it is important to look at the link between the Contras and drugs,'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> said Thursday, `` but this is not meant to be focused on the Contra effort. The issue is whether a specific foreign policy goal -LRB- aiding the Contras -RRB- assumed a larger-than-life importance so that some things were permitted that should not have been.'' <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> chairs the Foreign Relations subcommittee on narcotics and terrorism, which is investigating the relationship between Latin American governments and the drug trade. `` I think what we've shown is that there is an enormous amount more that needs to be done to improve enforcement of the drug laws,'' said <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>. `` You ca n't ever stop it, but you can slow it down with more effective enforcement.'' <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON>, who is serving a 27-year prison sentence for drug trafficking, testified Thursday that he had twice flown planeloads of weapons from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> in July 1984. The weapons were replaced with hundreds of pounds of cocaine, he said. As <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> described his career flying illegal drugs from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, he described a series of high-risk trips in which he flew at wave-top level to avoid radar. He said that on one occasion, he entered <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> by flying between high-rise condominium buildings along the city's coastline. On another occasion, he said, mechanical and navigational troubles forced him to fly over <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, where he was chased by MiG-19 jets until he dived down to tree-top level. The profits were huge, according to <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON>, who said he was paid to $ 200,000 per planeload for delivering drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON>'s story was echoed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, a Colombian native who says he began dealing drugs in 1979. Within several years, he had made enough money to build an empire that included a fleet of 10 to 15 planes, helicopters, and speedy boats. <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> is serving a 27-year prison term for cocaine trafficking, while <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> is doing a 16-year term for his conviction on the same charge. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> said he gave the Contras `` several million dollars'' from his drug profits. On one occasion, he estimated the amount at between $ 3 million and $ 4 million, but he later said the figure was $ 5 million to $ 6 million. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> also said he arranged six times between 1984 and 1986 to ship weapons from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to the Contras because he said <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> officials who claimed to be <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> operatives promised to try to get drug charges dropped against him. Both <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> and <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> said the weapons were delivered to an airstrip near a northern Costa Rican ranch owned by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hull </PERSON>, an American who has been linked to both the Contras and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hull </PERSON> met the plane each time and watched as the small arms, including M-16 rifles, mines and C-4 explosives, were unloaded, <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> said. The plane was then loaded with cocaine, <PERSON> Betzner </PERSON> said, and he flew back to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. He estimated that he carried about 500 kilograms -LRB- 1,100 pounds -RRB- of cocaine on each return flight. ABC News on Thursday described a network that it said shipped Eastern European arms to the Contras and Latin American drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Citing unidentified <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, Panamanian and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> sources, the network said that from 1983 to 1986 Israeli agents, with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> financial support, purchased arms in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, shipped them from <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> and on to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. From there, the network said, the arms were flown to Contra supply drops in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said the same planes and pilots then flew illegal drugs from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The network said the operation was launched with $ 20 million in Israeli government money, which was later reimbursed from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> covert funds. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Harreri </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> liaison who also served as an aide to <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, was the middleman. It said former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was the American connection. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said the Israeli government denied Thursday that it supplied arms to the Contras and <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> has denied he was involved in such a supply network.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Kirk-Platform     04-08 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kirk-Platform,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kirk Seeks To Minimize Clashes Over Platform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 National Democratic Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> says he wants to minimize the clash of interest groups so his party can draft a 1988 platform that Democrats `` can run with and not shy away from.'' But <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, chairman of the platform committee, says at least one interest group will be courted this year: the business community. `` They think socially they have to be Republicans, for whatever reason. But the majority are really independent people,'' <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said. `` I would like to see special efforts with the business community.'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said Thursday there will be state and regional platform hearings around the country over the next two months. Some interest groups said they welcomed this news, since <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> earlier suggested there might be only two _ in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. But they scoffed at what they called an effort to keep controversial planks out of the platform. `` We are concerned about statements that they did not wish to cater to special interests, they want to open up the process and to bring in new groups,'' said <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>. `` It seems to us that business is also a special interest, and we do n't understand quite how women, who are over half the population, can be categorized as a special interest.'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> pledged to draft a lean document and avoid the kind of divisive battles that have marked previous efforts at writing party platforms. `` I'd like to think that someone will read it other than opponents,'' <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said. `` The platform is more than just what <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> thinks. It has to be one all Democrats are comfortable with.'' Even so, <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would have `` significant representation'' on the platform committee, regardless of who becomes the party nominee. He called <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign `` an important constructive force within the Democratic party.'' At the same time, <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> seemed to soften suggestions he made last December that platform writers would avoid emotionally charged issues on which there was not common agreement. He vowed Thursday the party would not `` sound a retreat'' from issues it had championed in the past, including the <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amendment </ORGANIZATION> and abortion rights. Asked specifically about abortion, <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said: `` I think our party has always embraced the rights of privacy, the rights of individual choice.'' However, he tempered his comments by saying that such issues `` can be addressed in a way without being divisive or controversial.'' `` I think we can put together a platform that a national audience can respond to and that all elected Democratic officials can run with and not shy away from,'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said. `` I would have been much happier if he said, ` we will of course keep equal rights and abortion planks,'' said <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Smeal </PERSON>, president of the Fund for the Feminist Majority. Turning to the Democratic campaign, <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> joined <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> in urging Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> to tone down his negative campaigning. He called <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s admonition to the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator to stop criticizing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` helpful and on course.'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> also reiterated his view that <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> would not become a presidential candidate, even in a brokered convention. `` There is a game going on on the field,'' he said. `` That's where the nominee's going to be be chosen from.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HostageFallout     04-08 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hostage Fallout,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Say Guns Were Fake, Girl Wasn't Hostage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YORK, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mentally ill man killed by police was merely pretending to hold his teen-age girlfriend captive and used toy guns during a three-hour standoff, authorities said Thursday. The guns 19-year-old Israel <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> held to the girl's head and brandished at police from the window of his second-floor apartment were plastic water pistols and the `` hostage situation was a charade,'' York County District Attorney <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Rebert </PERSON> said at a news conference. The 15-year-old girl, a <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> runaway whose name was not released, was a willing participant, he said. Officials did not discuss the motive behind the charade. A police marksman shot <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> once in the abdomen and he died several hours later at <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. Police originally said the marksman fired when <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> threatened to kill the girl. But film taken by <ORGANIZATION> WGAL-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION> showed <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> was shot seconds after yelling, `` I'm coming out'' and placing both hands on a window frame. No gun was in sight. <PERSON> Rebert </PERSON> and other officials refused to identify the officer who fired the fatal shot. They said he was on administrative leave without pay, pending the outcome of an investigation that is expected to last up to four weeks. The officials refused to say if any charges would be filed against the teen-ager.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CourtingDelegates Bjt   04-08 0749</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Courting Delegates, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Spring is in the air and so is courting _ especially among the Democratic presidential hopefuls as they woo the party's unpledged delegates to the national convention. Faced with the possibility that the primary process will not produce a clear-cut delegate leader, the candidates are focusing on the 645 `` super delegates'' who could tip the balance in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> July 18-21. Campaign brochures, news clippings and position papers fill the mailboxes of the super delegates _ 25 governors, 362 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members, 253 members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and five elder statesmen _ who could push a candidate closer to the 2,082 total needed to nominate. Some campaigns rely on phone calls, such as those made to <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, a Democratic national committeewoman from <LOCATION> Keene </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, who remains uncommitted. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> phoned twice and his wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, called too. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>'s staff called as well. Mrs. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> says she has heard from all the candidates except <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Since last fall, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign has been laying the foundation with the super delegates through phone calls, mailings and personal contact, said delegate counter <PERSON> Tad </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>. In recent weeks, aides have stepped up the pressure. `` It's much more focused, an intense effort,'' <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> said. `` When it looks like he's pulling away ... at that time we'll seek a more formal pledge of support.'' The <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> campaign has relied on congressional communication on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> as well as phone calls and mailings to the delegates, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutcheson </PERSON>, delegate counter for the senator. `` There's great potential among the super delegates,'' said <PERSON> Hutcheson </PERSON>, who describes the field as `` fertile territory'' for his candidate. `` The super delegates are most interested in a ticket that can win.'' The Jackson forces, however, are just getting started in their campaign for super delegates. `` I looked into what kind of a strategy he had to deal with them and who he had doing it,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who is advising <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` It turns out they apparently had very little. There's some mail being passed back and forth.'' `` It's something they have to do and they're probably very late in doing it,'' he said. Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, a member of the congressional <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>, said last week he will lead the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> effort to court the super delegates. `` The front line is the congressional Black Caucus ... to talk to our colleagues in our states, to lobby people who are super delegates,'' <PERSON> Leland </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> contends that if he leads in pledged delegates after the last primaries on June 7, he deserves the support of the super delegates and should get the nomination. `` We know that the super votes give rise to super delegates,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said last week after meeting with a select group of Democratic leaders. `` The delegates must respect and respond to the will of the people. `` If we do not believe that, why have a primary? Have a super-delegate convention and let the super delegates choose someone of their own,'' he said. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> speaker and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s national campaign chairman, said the campaign would use primary results to convince the super delegates. `` We will take the popular vote in their state or their district and say this is a factor you should consider,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. The constant communication _ by telephone and by mail _ is all too familiar to some super delegates. `` They do n't call on a per day basis,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON>, an uncommitted super delegate from <LOCATION> Norristown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> `` They called before and after <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, before and after <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. They tell us how well the candidates are doing.'' <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, said the campaigns phone to find out `` if there's anything I want to know about the candidate, if I'm getting the mailings. They're very diplomatic.'' <PERSON> Dora </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivo </PERSON>, an uncommitted super delegate from <LOCATION> Rosenberg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, has received `` a lot of calls from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' and expects it to get `` hot and heavy'' as the convention nears. Other delegates say the courting has n't even begun in earnest. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Gifford </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, a former supporter of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, said he had n't heard from any campaign since his candidate dropped out of the race two weeks ago. And <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON>, a former congresswoman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said she's heard from all the campaigns, but `` I do n't think they're vigorously working on it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880408-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-08-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-NPPAAwards     04-08 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-NPPA Awards,0411</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seattle's KOMO Named Station of Year by NPPA</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FARGO, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Delozier </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> KUSA </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> was named television photographer of the year, and <ORGANIZATION> KOMO </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> won the television station of the year for 1987 in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Photographers TV news competition. Individual awards also were named in six categories. The winners will be honored July 8 at the <ORGANIZATION> NPPA </ORGANIZATION> business and education seminar in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. Contestants from more than 100 stations, all three major networks, along with some freelancers submitted entries for the contest which was judged recently at WDAY in <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION>. Here are the other results:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SPOT NEWS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 1, <ORGANIZATION> Escondido </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Swat </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> KFMB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION>. 2, Four Die in <LOCATION> Blaze </LOCATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sauls </PERSON>, WRTV <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. 3, <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hiawatha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, KMSP <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. Honorable mention _ Van <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Weller </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> KOMO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Kuro </PERSON> <PERSON> Battle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairman </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GENERAL NEWS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
