<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TreasureTrove     09-06 0485</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Treasure Trove,0499</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Revokes Bail For Couple Accused of Hiding Untaxed Plunder</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARGARET STAFFORD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> was revoked Tuesday for a couple facing sentencing for income tax evasion after an <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> agent testified they stashed $ 1 million in valuables in hiding places such as trucks and a chicken coop. <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> and <PERSON> Trula </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> are accused of plundering <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> 66, once a nationwide trucking firm run by <PERSON> Trula </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s father. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, the company's former secretary-treasurer, pleaded guilty Aug. 2 to concealing income by submitting false income tax returns from 1981-85. He also pleaded guilty to filing false income reports to the <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> 66. Mrs. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> was found guilty in August of tax evasion and conspiring to defraud the federal government. The Walkers were jailed Friday after authorities discovered caches of jewelry, furniture and cash at several sites in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. `` By the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> recovering part of this treasure trove, the risk that the Walkers might flee is enhanced, not lessened,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON> said in ordering them held without bond. `` It is obvious that they intended to keep these assets hidden until they paid whatever fines might be assessed, and then still have a mother lode to start over with.'' <PERSON> Whipple </PERSON> said he hoped to sentence the couple this week. <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> testified Tuesday that two confidential sources led agents to the stashed assets, some of which had been buried in a chicken coop and a machine shed. Agents also found semi-truck loads of furniture, including a 5-foot-tall chandelier and several pieces of antique furniture. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said as many as four truckloads may have been filled with the Walkers' assets in the past two years. Other assets uncovered included about $ 315,000 in cash, nearly 600 precious stones and 30 pounds of gold flatware. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> testified that agents were still trying to determine the whereabouts of furs and `` almost priceless'' jeweled Faberge Easter eggs. Once, about $ 150,000 of the buried money became wet and one of the confidential sources dried it in a clothes dryer, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. `` The confidential source said that at one point, with both Walkers present, he put jewelry in a pipe,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. `` The jewelry was found in a machine shop near the source's home, buried under a floor.'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> also said agents found jewelry and cash encased in cement in a tool shed and about $ 150,000 to $ 160,000 in a chicken coop. Another $ 180,000 was found buried in two glass jars. He said a preliminary assessment showed that the items found were valued at a little over $ 1 million. The Walkers owe the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> at least that much, he said. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Kabonic </PERSON>, a probation officer in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, testified that the Walkers submitted 1988 financial statements to him in August saying they had $ 6,250 cash on hand and total personal property of about $ 5,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 2324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths Advisory   09-06 0014</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, Advisory,0014</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Eds: There is no AM-Deaths column this cycle.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The AP</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Australia-Protest     09-06 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Australia-Protest,0196</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activists Say U.S. Navy Turned Water Hoses On Anti-Nuke Protesters</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three anti-nuclear protesters were arrested for trying to cling to the hull of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> frigate, and activists charged Tuesday that crew members turned high-powered water hoses on the demonstrators. The protesters, who were in rubber dinghies,, were charged with disorderly conduct after the incident Monday. They tried to hang onto the hull of the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewton </ORGANIZATION>, which was moored near <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> off the southern coast of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Cmdr. <PERSON> Kraig </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Brewton </PERSON>'s commander, said hoses were turned on the protesters because they planned to deface the vessel with spray paint. Earlier, the three attached a banner to the ship. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said the action may have been `` heavy-handed'' but that every precaution was taken to prevent injury. <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Vallentine </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and an activist in the Party for Nuclear Disarmament, demanded an apology, saying one protester was treated at a hospital for an eye injury and facial bruises. ` I believe it is the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> that should be charged with disorderly conduct,'' she told reporters after a meeting with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TeacherStrikes Rdp 2ndLd-Writethru 09-06 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Teacher Strikes, Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0767,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teacher Walkouts Affect Schools In Five States</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf, `Nationally, walkouts ... and 21st graf,
`Louisiana: A ..., to UPDATE with Louisiana strike settled.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Teachers carried picket signs in more than 20 public school districts in four states Tuesday. Many held out for raises, and the biggest pay demand, 42 percent over three years, drew the ire of a mayor as `` irresponsible.'' `` The teachers decided it's time to take a stand and that stand actually is a walk and that's what we'll be doing tomorrow morning: walking a picket line,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Grady </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, after a unanimous strike vote there Tuesday. The first day of school was canceled Wednesday for the city's 13,100 pupils. Nationally, walkouts affected more than 100,000 pupils in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. A strike in its third week in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> was settled Tuesday night. More than 1,400 professors and academic staff members at <ORGANIZATION> Wayne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> also went on strike Tuesday over union work rules and salary. University president <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamany </PERSON> predicted classes for the roughly 30,000 students would continue with other full-time and part-time instructors, but professors said they expected few classes to be held. An additional 950 clerical workers and secretaries represented by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> have been on strike at <ORGANIZATION> Wayne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> since Aug. 25. In <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, bargainers representing 991 teachers met with school officials through the weekend with no success. Major issues were class size and salary, with teachers asking for a 10 percent raise and being offered 2 percent, <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Colleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudgens </PERSON> said. Superintendent <PERSON> LaBarbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Gragg </PERSON> said Monday night that talks would be scheduled later in the week. Meanwhile, classes that opened Sept. 1 were canceled Tuesday for <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION>'s 17,284 students as teachers picketed, Deputy Superintendent <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Love </PERSON> said. In State College, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, 415 teachers staged the first strike in the district's history, said union spokesman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Apaliski </PERSON>. About 5,900 students missed the scheduled opening day of school Tuesday. `` We are not at all close,'' district spokeswoman <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Best </PERSON> said. `` It's very discouraging.'' The school board offered a 33 percent raise over three years, Ms. <PERSON> Best </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has not made public its pay demand. In <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, teachers in nearly 40 school districts are going to work this week without a contract. The only strike votes taken, however, were in <LOCATION> Lowell </LOCATION> and Peabody. Teacher strikes are illegal in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. Officials canceled the first day of school for 13,100 pupils Wednesday in <LOCATION> Lowell </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, after the district's 970 teachers voted unanimously to strike for more pay and to preserve longevity bonuses. In Peabody, the city's 408 teachers rejected a 17 percent wage increase over three years and held out for 42 percent over the same time span. `` To sit at the table locked in at 42 percent is totally irresponsible,'' said Peabody Mayor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Torigian </PERSON>. School Superintendent <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said administrators were trying to bring in enough substitutes to keep classes going. <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latessa </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> defended the union's position. The 42 percent wage request, <PERSON> Latessa </PERSON> said, is smaller than it appears because the teachers maintain that they have been performing extra duties such as elementary preparation and handling oversized classes without extra pay. Here was the picture by state-by-state: <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>: Strikes in 10 districts idled nearly 45,000 students and more than 2,000 teachers, the <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>: Strikes by about 2,200 teachers in nine districts affected about 36,000 students, according to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Badner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>: Strike votes by union representing 1,378 teachers affected two districts. <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>: Strikes in two districts affected 501 teachers and 9,145 pupils in <LOCATION> Granite </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Farmer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Bellflower </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>: About 600 teachers, joined by bus drivers, ended a strike Tuesday night after school officials agreed to collective bargaining in Vermilion Parish, where a 6 percent pay cut was imposed in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CryingForTiffany     09-06 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crying For Tiffany,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shooting Of 11-Year-Old Galvanizes Boston Neighborhood</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALAN COOPERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death of an 11-year-old girl caught in a cross fire between rival drug-dealing street gangs has galvanized a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> community `` like nothing else in years,'' one city official says. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who had been sent away by her mother to live with relatives in the South because of the violence in her <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> neighborhood, was home for a visit when she was shot twice in the head Aug. 19 while sitting on a corner mailbox talking with friends. More than 400 people attended the funeral. In the weeks since the shooting, neighborhood leaders have met with the mayor and police commissioner to demand a war on crime. Some even suggested that the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> be called up. At meetings in the adjacent <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dorchester </LOCATION> sections, people have developed proposals that include circulating the names and pictures of known drug dealers. Some activists have gathered hundreds of signatures on petitions calling for evening court sessions to handle drug-related cases. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolling </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION>'s representative in the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said the shooting had `` galvanized this community ... like nothing else in years.'' In 29 years of law enforcement, said Deputy Police Superintendent <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Celester </PERSON>, `` I have never seen the cooperation I have seen in the past three weeks ... People are telling me to take the gloves off and take back the streets.'' <PERSON> Bolling </PERSON> suggested why the death of the girl had touched people so deeply. `` A little girl, totally innocent _ people can relate to that, because they think of their own families, and suddenly they recognize how vulnerable they are and how pervasive this problem has become,'' he said. Violence in <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> had captured the community's attention by the time of <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s killing. In July, two undercover state police troopers were wounded when they attempted to make a drug `` buy.'' Within hours of the two shootings, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> police office also was wounded, and police wounded a suspect in an unrelated shooting. A week after <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s death, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, 14, was fatally stabbed in front of his sister and other children. Police said the stabbing stemmed from an earlier fight and may have been connected to young gang activity. The pressure on police was intense to make quick arrests in the two killings. At one point, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> police Commissioner <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Roache </PERSON> publicly rejected the calls by activists to call in the National Guard. <PERSON> Roache </PERSON> said the city's 1,900-member police force could handle the situation. Thirty detectives were assigned full-time to hunt for <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION>'s killers; within two weeks, they had arrested two suspects Four suspects were arrested in the 14-year-old boy's stabbing. Police also have assigned two police officers to walk the street in the <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> neighborhood where <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> was killed. Two years ago, the violence in <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> had so alarmed <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s mother that she sent <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> and an older sister to live with relatives in <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> for a two-week visit with her mother; on Aug. 21, two days after the shooting, she was supposed to return to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, her mother, was upstairs in her apartment that hot night, lying on her bed and talking with a friend, when `` A little girl ran up and said <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> get shot and I ran down. `` I did n't take time to put on my shoes or lock my door or nothing, but when I got there, she was already dead. I was rubbing her skin and it was tightening up. I called her name and I called her name and she did n't say nothing.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, sitting in her living room under a tapestry of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> and a portrait of Marthur Luther King Jr., said people cared about her daughter's death not just because she was so innocent but because she was special. <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s ambition, she said, was to become a doctor or teacher. She played the organ and trombone. She like to talk with her friends as they took turns braiding each other's hair. Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said she's talked with all the politicians, reporters and television crews who visit her apartment because `` It makes me feel like people care.'' Holding a diary <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON> kept and looking at family snapshots, Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said: `` I was trying for them to be somebody, not just hanging on the street.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CrookedCops     09-06 0612</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crooked Cops,0629</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Corruption In The Philippines: A Growing `Perversion'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CLARO CORTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Burglars recently broke into the home of an elderly couple, ransacked the house and stabbed the wife. A few weeks later, a city councilman was found dead after exposing members of a car theft ring. On the surface, such incidents appear regrettably routine in a city with one of the world's highest crime rates. But in both cases officials admit the crimes were carried out by police. Hardly a day passes without newspapers reporting crimes of violence in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and elsewhere that were carried out by the very people charged with protecting society. During the first seven months of 1988, 67 policemen were fired for involvement in crimes nationwide. Most were assigned in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> area. Of the 67 policemen, 18 were charged with murder, according to official figures. <PERSON> Cicero </PERSON> <PERSON> Campos </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said his agency receives an average of 1,500 complaints each year of criminal activity among the country's 52,000 policemen. But he admits the figure represents `` the tip of the iceberg'' because the majority of crimes committed by police and soldiers are never reported. Much of the crime involves petty `` shakedowns.'' For example, traffic policemen extorting motorists for unauthorized, on-the-spot `` fines'' are a common sight on <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s busy thoroughfares. Last month, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Montano </PERSON>, commander of the Philippine Constabulary, told a congressional committee that investigators recently cracked a massive car-theft ring made up mostly of soldiers and police. <PERSON> Montano </PERSON> said the arrests of the corrupt officers contributed to a significant reduction in the number of car thefts in the country. Poorly paid policemen often moonlight as bouncers for bars and prostitution fronts. Others join crime syndicates involved in gambling, narcotics and prostitution, either by guaranteeing them virtual immunity from arrest or, in some cases, serving as bodyguards for mob leaders. Policemen are widely assumed to have been involved in the unsolved slaying of leftist leaders. Five policemen have been charged with the attempted murder in June of leftist <PERSON> Nemesio </PERSON> <PERSON> Prudente </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philippines </ORGANIZATION>. The officers, who were on duty when they allegedly attacked <ORGANIZATION> Prudente </ORGANIZATION>, are scheduled for arraignment this month. Crimes committed by police rose to unprecedented levels during the 20-year rule of President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who was ousted on Feb. 25, 1986, after a civilian-military uprising that propelled <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to the presidency. Many soldiers and police joined the uprising against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Once in office, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> pledged to restore honest government and end abuses by police and soldiers. But the police department's image, as well as the government's own prestige, is now threatened by a resurgence of corruption <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Yap </PERSON> <PERSON> Daza </PERSON>, a prominent newspaper and broadcast commentator, wrote in the <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Standard that corruption has reached unacceptable levels. `` Police corruption is not unique to us, all right,'' she wrote. `` But this is corruption with a different face, the face of perversion ... It is a dark time for the good cops, if there are any left.'' <PERSON> Campos </PERSON>, a retired Constabulary brigadier general, blames the problem on low salaries. A patrolman receives a monthly starting salary of $ 50, well below the government's poverty line of $ 120 a month for a family of five. `` We do not have a coterie of angels or saints in the police force,'' he said in an interview. `` But certainly these people are all humans, and they are up for temptation. Perhaps what we can do is insulate them from temptation.'' He said the commission has recommended that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> increase police salaries as a step toward curbing corruption.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PrimariesRdp     09-06 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Primaries Rdp,0623</SECOND>
<HEAD>Warmup for Hecht-Bryan Battle in Nevada; Florida Voters Narrow
Senate Field</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> voters were expected to set the stage today for Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>'s drive to oust Republican Sen. Chic <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, while six <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Democrats and two Republicans fought over the seat of retiring Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> faced only token opposition in today's primaries, and for months they have been attacking each other <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, who is seeking his second term, has criticized the governor as too pro-labor. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>, in the middle of his second term, has charged <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> with lacking credibility and being ineffective. A poll taken in August for the gaming industry showed <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> with a 14-point lead over <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, who six years ago narrowly defeated Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON> after the incumbent was implicated in a <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> union scandal. <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> has stopped releasing his own poll results but said he is closing the gap and considers the race a toss-up. <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, whose voting record is extremely conservative, has become known for his occasional verbal miscues, once referring to a `` nuclear suppository'' when he meant `` repository.'' A recent survey of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> administrative assistants ranked him as the least effective senator in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>'s only primary opponent is <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheffler </PERSON>, 38-year-old owner of a graphics business in <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> who said he would press for reprocessing nuclear waste brought to <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> so that only low-level, less radioactive waste would remain. <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>'s opponents in the Democratic primary are <LOCATION> Manford </LOCATION> `` Cave Rock Manny'' <PERSON> Beals </PERSON>, <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kepler </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, a two-man Republican primary matched Rep. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, grandson of the legendary <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> A's baseball manager, against former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON>, who successfully prosecuted Colombian cocaine kingpin <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivas </PERSON>. <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> entered the race late, in June, and <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> was heavily favored in pre-election polls after outspending his rival by about $ 2.2 million to $ 100,000. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and former Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> made appearances for <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, who has one of the most conservative records in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> was frustrated by <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>'s refusal to debate, and emphasized that point by carrying around a life-size replica of <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> he called `` Cardboard Connie.'' `` If he debates me, he knows the jig's up,'' said <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON>. `` He'd be forced to discuss issues ... People would see the lights are on but nobody's home.'' <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> said <PERSON> Merkle </PERSON> was n't `` a viable candidate,'' and that there was no reason `` to have been drawn into his campaign. My feeling was that we should continue with delivery of the message we started with in October, talking about the importance of freedom, free markets, less taxes, freedom as an objective of foreign policy.'' For the Democrats, state Insurance Commissioner <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON> appeared to hold a wide lead, but not wide enough to win a majority and avoid an Oct. 4 runoff with the second-place finisher. Others in the race were Reps. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mica </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> `` Buddy'' McKay, state Sen. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, former Republican Gov. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> postal clerk <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Rader </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON>, who lost to <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> in the 1980 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race, raised $ 1 million within six weeks of announcing, and opponents noted he took at least $ 160,000 from the insurance industry he regulates. <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> campaign manager <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Farmer </PERSON> called <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON>'s department `` a saga of sleaze. The early Democratic frontrunner, former Gov. <PERSON> Reubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Askew </PERSON>, quit the race in May, saying running for office had become too expensive. Democrats acknowledge that their crowded field and likely runoff may hurt their prospects in November. `` I do n't think it'll be an easy race, but I think it's winnable,'' said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-06 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0918</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mamas, do n't let your babies grow up to be restless, says <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, who blames his wanderlust nature for ruining three marriages. The country music singer says in his autobiography, `` <PERSON> Willie </PERSON>,'' due out next month from <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Schuster </PERSON>, that he prefers the road to matrimony. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> met his third wife, <PERSON> Connie </PERSON>, in 1969. They married, had two children and lived in <LOCATION> Westlake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> on the shores of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. But they spent much of their time arguing. `` For me the choice came down to staying ... with Connie all the time when I came off the road _ which meant giving up all my pals who I hung around with on the golf course or in my recording studio _ or never going back to the ... house again,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said in his book. He chose to leave and the couple divorced. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, whose hits include `` Mama, Do n't Let Your Babies Grow Up to Be Cowboys,'' and `` Blue Eyes Crying in the Rain,'' admits life as Mrs. <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> would be difficult. `` It's not easy to be married to somebody like me and be a wife and stay home and take care of the family when I'm out here acting like a big star,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. `` I mean, it rubs.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop balladeer <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON> says he does n't hunger for applause like many of his fellow entertainers. `` But do n't get me wrong. This is a great job that I've got. I enjoy it and I know there's a part of me that needs that love-me-love-me-love-me stuff,'' he said in a recent interview. <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON> concedes that his own time in the spotlight has been sporadic, by choice. `` I've done it this way throughout my career,'' the <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>, Emmy and Grammy winner said. <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON>, known for the hits `` Mandy'' and `` I Made It Through the Rain,'' is getting favorable reviews with the `` Big Fun'' tour, a lavishly produced stage show playing around the world until New Year's Eve 1990.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following is moving on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Time has run out on a congressional bid to grant tennis star <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> immediate citizenship so he could play on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic team, lawmakers said. <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> has lived in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, since 1981 and wanted to represent his adopted homeland in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> this month. Enlisting the help of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> lawmakers, <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> won <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approval in April of a special immigration bill. Rep. <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., blocked the measure on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor, saying he would drop his opposition only if the Czech government provided a waiver for <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> to be a member of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team Olympic rules required a waiver because <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON> had represented <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> in international competition at the Davis Cup. The Czechoslovak Association of Physical Culture rejected the waiver. `` We pressed the issue,'' Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., said last week `` Maybe we could have -LRB- succeeded -RRB- with more time, but ... time has basically run out.'' <PERSON> Lendl </PERSON>, 28, received his permanent residence status last year. He will be eligible for citizenship through traditional procedures in 1992. His attorney and spokeswoman did not return telephone calls for comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talk show host <PERSON> Regis </PERSON> <PERSON> Philbin </PERSON> took seven years to make a coast-to-coast round trip from here to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and back to introduce a new, nationally syndicated show. <PERSON> Philbin </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and his <ORGANIZATION> KABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> `` A.M. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>'' morning magazine show in 1981 for a similar job in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, only to return for the Labor Day debut of a new celebrity talk show with <PERSON> Kathie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Gifford </PERSON>. The format has n't changed much from the early days in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, with the obligatory how-to segments, cooking demonstrations and cozy celebrity chats. This week `` Live <ORGANIZATION> With </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Kathie'' will feature an interview with <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> real estate tycoon <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> aboard his luxury yacht and a talk with ageless funnyman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> at his <LOCATION> Burbank </LOCATION> mansion.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Prince and Princess of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> canceled an appearance at the premiere of a film about a daring British train robber because its star, singer <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, advised them not to go. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, who plays train robber <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> `` Buster'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> in the film `` Buster,'' said Monday he wrote <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> that they should shun the Sept. 15 premiere. `` ` <PERSON> Buster </PERSON>' does not in any way glorify crime'' as critics have claimed, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said. But, he said, in light of the controversy, he wrote the royal couple `` suggesting that it would probably be best if they did not attend.'' A Buckingham Palace spokesman said the prince and princess were `` aware of the contents of the letter that <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> has written them and in the light of this they have decided not to go.'' The Great Train Robbery of Aug. 8, 1963, was one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s most daring heists More than 120 mailbags containing $ 7 million in used banknotes were taken off a mail train from <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> of which less than $ 980,000 were recovered. Thirteen people, including <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, stood trial in 1964 for the crime. No one was killed during the robbery, but one man was seriously injured.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-06 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0442</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, a blue-eyed blonde singer, has the best chances of winning the 1989 Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> title, says a retired statistics professor. <PERSON> Patti </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorn </PERSON>, 23, has a 7-1 chance over the 50 other contestants vying for the crown Saturday, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. For the past 10 years _ to the displeasure of pageant officials _ <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> has entered facts and figures about the contestants into his home computer and calculated their odds based on past winners and finalists <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s statistics gained credibility in 1980 when he correctly predicted <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Prewitt </PERSON> would take the title. But he has not been successful every year. Most recently, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> picked <PERSON> Kellye </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> as Miss America 1987, but did not even have last year's winner, <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> <PERSON> Lani </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafko </PERSON>, in his top 10. `` She was a dancer who was a nurse and those are both zero categories on my list,'' he said Monday. To make his predictions, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who retired from <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, uses such factors as height, weight, hair and eye color, academic major and talent. His computer analysis further breaks down talent. `` If one is doing an acrobatic dance, that would be better than an interpretive dance,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A day at the office for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON> is spent carefully watching over his `` pets'' _ a barrel of cockroaches, containers of cenipedes and jars of maggots. <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON>, 29, is an entomologist responsible for making sure science classes at <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> do n't run short of things that crawl and creep. `` We're kicking into high gear now that the students are coming back,'' he said. `` One professor wanted 1,000 female German cockroaches for one class last year. That's tedious work.'' Most of <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON>'s bugs are destined for dissection. Some will be sprayed with chemicals in toxicology tests. Others will simply be watched so students can study their behavior. Flies and cockroaches are high on the science professors' most-wanted list <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON> raises cockroaches by the barrelful. A few, like an unusual Central American ant that inflicts a powerful sting, are being studied for possible use in fighting illnesses. <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON> has two African millipedes. They look like foot-long hot dogs standing on a thousand toothpick legs. Actually, they do not have a thousand legs. <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON> counted them. They have 370. Centipedes have 54 legs. `` We're not doing any research with them right now,'' <PERSON> Keeney </PERSON> said, picking up a handful of the insects. `` They're more or less pets.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Olympics     09-06 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Olympics,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Olympic Medalists Will Collect Cash in Seoul</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviets athletes who win gold medals at the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Olympics will be awarded the equivalent of $ 19,000 for their efforts, the head of the Soviet Olympic Committee says. <PERSON> Marat </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramov </PERSON> announced the new policy at a news conference Monday and denied such payments conflict with the purely amateur status Soviet athletes purportedly possess. He said those on the 550-member Soviet team in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> who win gold medals will be paid 12,000 rubles -LRB- $ 19,047 -RRB-. Silver medalists will receive 5,000 rubles, and bronze medalists will collect 3,000 rubles. Those are handsome sums in a country where the average monthly wage for a factory worker is around 200 rubles. According to <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Dmitrieyev </PERSON>, deputy foreign editor of the daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Sovietsky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sport </ORGANIZATION>, the sums earmarked for <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> medalists will be the largest ever paid to Soviet victors in a Summer Games. `` If they received $ 100 in the past, it was considered a large sum,'' <PERSON> Dmitrieyev </PERSON> said in a telephone interview, referring to payments made to Soviet participants in the 1976 <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> and 1980 <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> games. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> did not take part in the 1984 Olympics, held in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. According to <PERSON> Dmitrieyev </PERSON>, Soviet winners at the 1988 <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION> Winter Olympics also received large sums to reward them for good performance. <PERSON> Gramov </PERSON> noted that 15 percent of the prize money paid to Soviet medalists will be in foreign currency. That is important because the Soviet ruble, which is not convertible into foreign currency, is useless abroad and can not buy the sort of Western consumer goods that many Soviets covet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LastTemptation Bjt   09-06 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Last Temptation, Bjt,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christian Leaders And Universal Cash In On `Last Temptation'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` The Last Temptation of Christ'' has proven to be a blessing for conservative Christians. Denounced by its critics as blasphemous and profane, the movie about a Jesus with human frailties not only has energized the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> right; it has revived stagnant fund-raising, <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> leaders say. The movie `` has helped our ministry more than anything else before,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Beehler </PERSON>, director of communications for Campus Crusade for Christ: `` This gives us a wonderful opportunity to talk about the real <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>. ... We're taking lemons and making lemonade.'' At the same time, filmgoers are not avoiding the movie, as Christian leaders had hoped. In fact, the controversy seems to have prompted more people to see it. That price, though, might be a small one for <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> activists. Beset by negative publicity from the <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Swaggart </PERSON> scandals, conservative Christians have used `` Last Temptation'' as a lightning rod around which to organize and raise money. In addition to bringing together fundamentalists, Pentecostals, Prostestants and Catholics, the controversy makes for a natural fund-raiser: It pits the conservative Christian organizations, which often depict themselves as small and struggling, against a <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goliath </ORGANIZATION>. The Concerned Women for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, in a fund-raising letter, said, `` Your gift of $ 100, $ 75, $ 50, $ 20 _ or whatever amount _ is sorely needed. We need your financial help to fight these rich <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> moguls.'' Similarly, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has said that those `` giving $ 15 or more to help AFA oppose the movie will receive a one year subscription to the <ORGANIZATION> AFA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> has been preaching about the movie for the last three weeks,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hymers </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> minister who has been one of the movie's most outspoken critics. `` <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON>'s doing a tremendous fund-rasing job through the film. The American Society for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tradition </ORGANIZATION>, Family and Property used a four-page, full-color attack on the movie to solicit small contributions. `` People have put their money where their values are,'' said <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, president of the organization. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said that a phone campaign brought in $ 39,000, enough for a full-page advertisement in The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Times against the movie. It also may be true that some Christian-themed organizations are trying to exploit the controversy for less-than-noble purposes. `` I've seen the fund-raising letters. -LRB- The movie -RRB- has become another hype button to raise funds,'' said <PERSON> Cal </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a syndicated columnist and former comunications director for the Moral Majority. <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, appears to have benefited from the controversy. By telling people not to see the movie, <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> leaders may have encouraged the opposite response. `` Universal is raking in the dough,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. Studio officials refused comment. Although `` Last Temptation'' is by no means a blockbuster, it has done respectable business for an art film, grossing more than $ 2 million since its limited release Aug. 12. `` It would n't have done anywhere near what's it's done without the controversy,'' said <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Block </PERSON>, editor of the industry newsletter Sow Biz News. `` Although some Christians might have stayed away, many other -LRB- filmgoers -RRB- went because of the controversy. People say, ` If they tell me I ca n't go, I'll go.''' At the same time, production plans for at least one movie with a Christian theme are not being stalled by the flap: `` Christ the Man,'' to be directed by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Verhoeven </PERSON>, is in the planning stages at <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>' production company. Described by company spokeswoman <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Auerbach </PERSON> as a serious interpretation of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' life, the movie will be `` absolutely unaffected'' by criticisms of `` Last Temptation.'' It is too early to tell if the attacks on <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> will lead to any long-term losses, though <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> leaders are hopeful. `` What we're sensing is a lot of people _ in the tens of millions _ who are now angry at Universal,'' said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Penland </PERSON>, who served as a consultant to film producer <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> before becoming a leading critic of the movie. <PERSON> Wildmon </PERSON> and other activists will soon launch a boycott against Universal's videocassette of `` E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial,'' due out Oct. 27. After that, there are no announced plans aimed at Universal. But, said <PERSON> Beehler </PERSON>, `` Universal will always be remembered as the studio that made a film defaming <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Wildfires 2ndLd-Writethru a0682 09-06 1057</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wildfires, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0682,1084</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Area Fires Threaten Towns, High Wind Expected</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 1st to UPDATE with quote. Subs 17th
graf pvs `Also inside' to UPDATE acreage. Subs 21st graf pvs `About
30' to UPDATE with new Idaho fire. Subs 23rd graf `The weather' to
UPDATE Dry Fork acreage. Inserts one graf after 26th graf `Oregon's
largest' to UPDATE with Washington governor activating Guard.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XYS1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COOKE CITY, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire trucks from as far away as <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> took position in two smoke-filled <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> towns Monday and residents here waited to see if a backfire would burn fast enough to protect them from a wind-driven forest fire. `` First it starts snowing ash. Then it starts raining fire,'' said fire information officer <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaunert </PERSON> as he stood in a 65-foot-wide fire break bulldozed through the forest. Top federal officials said that blaze and 12 other fires in and around <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> had burned 900,000 acres as of Monday. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cargill </PERSON>, chief federal forester for the <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, warned that an additional 300,000 acres may be consumed this week, despite the efforts of 9,000 firefighters. And <ORGANIZATION> Cargill </ORGANIZATION> warned that 20 to 30 mph southwesterly wind is expected to arrive in the region Tuesday with a weather front. Protection of life and property are the top priorities, he said at a news conference in <LOCATION> Bozeman </LOCATION>. `` Containment of further acreage is just not in the cards.'' He said many of the nation's best firefighters `` are being whipped day after day'' by the Yellowstone fires. Evacuation orders for <ORGANIZATION> Cooke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> and a town three miles west, <LOCATION> Silver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gate </LOCATION>, were issued Sunday morning. By Monday night, about 30 of the approximately 150 residents in the two towns remained, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Fry </PERSON>, an emergency services official. `` Some of them are staying around because they want to see what the fire does,'' Fry said. `` They're mostly packed up, though, and we're trying to push them out.'' A backfire had been set by firefighters as a shield against the approaching <ORGANIZATION> Storm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek </ORGANIZATION> fire Sunday just a half-mile from Silver Gate. Firefighters wanted to establish a two-mile buffer of charred forest between Silver Gate and the 61,300-acre Storm Creek fire. But by Monday, the backfire had burned only a half-mile swath, said fire information officer <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON>. `` With an 18 to 20 mph wind behind the fire, that line would n't stop it You'd just stand there in the line and watch it go over your head,'' he said. And if the backfire had n't gone far enough, the wind would blow embers from the backfire itself into residential areas, endangering the town it was meant to protect. To prepare for that possibility, fire trucks rolled into positions around the two towns. About 75 trucks were called in from as far as <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> to protect buildings, <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON> said. `` We're here till they tell us to get out of <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Ty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>, manning a fire truck from the eastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Glendive </LOCATION>, 400 miles away. <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON> said firefighters also were worried that the Storm Creek fire and three other major fires in and around <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> have created their own wind circulation, `` almost like a whirlpool of wind,'' around the <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>. That circular wind pattern may encourage the fires to reach out toward each other, which could create a huge ring of flame that would eat its way inward through unburned forests, <PERSON> Comstock </PERSON> said. Also inside <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>, firefighters worried that the expected wind would blow the 141,900-acre North Fork fire back toward the complex of visitor facilities around Old Faithful Geyser. But <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Iobst </PERSON>, a fire information officer, said a lack of vegetation in the Old Faithful area would make it easy to protect the development. On the western side of the park, which is largely in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, fire officials were confident they could protect <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, a community of 750 people, from an advancing lobe of the North Fork fire just 2 -LCB- miles away Monday. `` Everything is based on what these winds do to us in a couple of days,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Avery </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> fire oficial, referring to the anticipated southwesterly wind. About 30 miles to the west in the <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, about 55 firefighters battled a new 25-acre blaze believed caused by humans. The fire burned to within 50 yards of half dozen summer homes near <ORGANIZATION> Macks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inn </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, but the winds pushed the flames in the opposite direction, fire commander <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bushnell </PERSON> said. In the northern Rockies, officials warned that an approaching weather front could drive existing blazes past fire lines and cause fires already brought under control to flare up again. The weather predictions prompted <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials to begin work on an evacuation plan for permanent and summer residences south of <LOCATION> Fortine </LOCATION>, in northwestern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. The Dry Fork fire there has scorched 12,300 acres. `` Right now, we've got our fingers crossed that this wind is n't going to be that harsh,'' said fire information officer <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Guth </PERSON> That fire is considered about 60 percent contained. Elsewhere, calmer wind and slightly lower temperatures Monday helped firefighters grapple with blazes that charred nearly 21,000 acres of southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> brush. Oregon's largest fire of the season was nearly contained at just under 57,000 acres in the rugged Hell's <ORGANIZATION> Canyon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> activated the National Guard to help provide support and transportation for hundreds of firefighters. Containment of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s largest fire, the 12,500-acre White Mountain Complex in Ferry County, was at least five days away, officials said Monday, but it had stopped moving toward the town of <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, air tankers and fire crews scrambled Monday to stop a runaway brush fire moving toward the northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> community of Paradise, authorities said. `` Right now they've got a problem,'' said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. `` They've got a 250-acre fire heading for the town. It just broke out a little while ago.'' The fire was the latest in a series of fires raging on <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s tinder-dry landscape Monday Air tankers that had been used for a 5,400-acre brush fire near <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> were diverted to the fire near <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION>, a community of about 500 residents between <LOCATION> Ogden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Wasatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. Forests also burned in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0738EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SchoolComputers Bjt   09-06 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-School Computers, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 2 p.m. EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Report: US Schools Lack Adequate Computers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American schools have only one computer for every 30 students and even those pupils with access to computers get to use them an average of just one hour a week, a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said today. The report by the <ORGANIZATION> congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION> said `` today's classrooms typically resemble their ancestors of 50 years ago more closely than operating rooms or business offices resemble their 1938 versions.'' The agency estimated that schools have spent $ 2 billion on computer hardware over the past decade. There are now 1.2 million to 1.7 million computers in public schools, and fewer than 5 percent have no computers. But the agency said it would cost $ 4 billion to buy enough equipment to reduce the student-computer ratio from 30-1 to 3-1. The 246-page report, based on two years' research, said that between 1981 and 1987 the percentage of schools equipped with computers for instructional use grew from 18 percent to 95 percent. But `` the vast majority of schools still do not have enough of them to make the computer a central element of instruction,'' it said. Computers are not the only new machines in American classrooms. `` The 1980s witnessed a tremendous expansion in school use of advanced technology of all types,'' the report said. `` In 1980 very few schools had videocassette recorders. Today roughly 90 percent do,'' it said, adding that the availability of cable and satellite transmission has made the television a more potent teaching tool _ especially for schools in remote areas. `` In practice there is wide disparity _ one computer in a classroom, clusters of computers in the library or classrooms, full computer laboratories and classrooms with no computers,'' it said. `` Not all students use computers and ... those who do spend on average a little more than one hour per week on the computer.'' The report said that `` although new interactive technologies can not alone solve the problems of American education, they have already contributed to important improvements in learning. These tools can plan an even greater role ... both by helping children acquire basic skills and by endowing them with more sophisticated skills so they can acquire and apply knowledge over their lifetimes.'' To tap the potential of technology, the report said, `` a greater investment will be necessary,'' including a more active federal role in spurring research and helping spread the new teaching tools. The report warned that `` the vast majority of those now teaching or planning to teach have had little or no computer education or training.'' Most of what they have been taught is to how to use computers themselves, not how to teach with computers. `` Despite a nationwide call to improve teaching, there is almost no federal money for the training of new teachers,'' it said. It said there are more than 10,000 educational software products on the market, but the quality `` could be much better.'' The Office of Technology Assessment is a nonpartisan analytical agency for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>, which commissioned the study, said increasing federal support for high-tech school aids `` would be good public policy and a wise investment for the future. The report cited several examples of schools putting computers and other gear to good use, including: _ <ORGANIZATION> Poteet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mesquite </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where interactive videodiscs are used throughout the physical science curriculum, allowing ninth graders to bring a volcanic eruption or solar flare to life at the touch of a computer keyboard _ Sacred <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Model </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, where fifth graders recently assembled a computer database of their pets -LRB- including 25 dogs, 4 hermit crabs and 1 guinea pig -RRB- and are currently testing the acidity of the city's tap water for a comparison with data from 199 other schools around the world
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-06 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hay Prices Highest Ever</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The drought-toasted 1988 hay crop is expected to be the smallest in 12 years and prices are likely to be the highest since the Agriculture Department began keeping annual figures in 1909. Preliminary figures show that hay prices at the farm in August averaged $ 83.10 per ton. Although that was unchanged from July, it was an increase of 35 percent from $ 61.60 per ton in August 1987. No dramatic declines in hay prices are in sight, say department economists. The supply is tight and demand is strong, meaning that prices probably will remain high until spring. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records, the record for hay prices over an entire season was $ 75.80 per ton set in 1983, another drought year. That was an increase of less than 10 percent from the 1982 average of $ 69.30 per ton. Historically, however, there have been larger year-to-year percentage jumps in hay prices. In 1934, for example, hay rose 52 percent to $ 11.70 per ton from $ 7.70 in 1933. But a year later, in 1935, prices plummeted just as fast to $ 7.60 per ton. The latest <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> production estimate on Aug. 11 put this year's hay harvest at 130.5 million tons on 66.2 million acres, down 12.5 percent from 1987 production of 149.1 million tons on 60.7 million acres It also is the smallest since the 1976 crop of 120.1 million tons, says the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in a new outlook report on the feed situation. `` Acreage harvested as reported in the August crop production report is almost 2.8 million acres more than the area indicated for harvest in the July report,'' the agency said. `` This increase likely reflects in part the emergency haying rules -LRB- for conservation land -RRB- under <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s drought assistance measures.'' At the beginning of the hay marketing year on May 1, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inventory was estimated at 27.3 million tons. Counting this year's production, that makes a total hay supply of 157.8 million tons for 1988-89, down 13 percent from last season Meanwhile, the number of cattle and other `` roughage consuming animal units'' will be about the same as last year, meaning there will be less to go around. If each animal eats as much hay as it did last year, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hay stockpile will be chewed down to only 3.8 million tons by May 1, 1989, a record low. Thus, the report said, it seems more reasonable that producers will reduce hay portions to ration available supplies. `` Hay use will depend on a number of additional factors,'' the report said. `` Silage yields will be sharply reduced by the drought. However, the area of silage harvested likely will be increased, because of abandonment of areas intended for harvest as grain.'' The report added: `` More straw likely will be baled this year to stretch out forage supplies. Fall pasture growth, or lack thereof, and spring pasture conditions also will be important to hay use. Good fall rains and pasture, and good early spring pasture would do a lot to ease the pressure on hay supplies.'' On the other hand, `` converse conditions would intensify supply pressures'' and push up hay prices even further, it said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm-raised catfish production continues to rise above year-earlier levels, according to <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reports. In July, production was an estimated 23.7 million pounds of live weight delivered to processors, the department reports. The July average price paid to growers was 80 cents per pound, up 19 cents from the same month in 1987. So far this year, production was about 169.7 million pounds, up from 160.4 million pounds through July 1987. In a related report, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said catfish farmers in 18 states had sales worth $ 247 million last year. It was the first such survey since 1981, when sales were $ 72 million, officials said. Of the 1987 sales total, hatchery operations accounted for $ 20.1 million, while sales from production were reported at $ 226.8 million. Last year's catfish sales, all sizes, were led by <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> at $ 178.5 million, compared with $ 44.7 million in 1981.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mushroom production rose to another record of almost 637 million pounds in the marketing year that ended June 30, up 4 percent from 1986-87, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. An annual report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> also showed that the value of crop, at $ 566 million, was up 7 percent. Growers received an average of 89 cents per pound, up 2.5 cents from 1986-87. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, the traditional leader, reported a production value of $ 205.1 million, up from 194.5 million the previous season.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IndigentPrograms     09-06 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indigent Programs,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Average Cost of Lawyer for Poor Defendant Now $223</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says it now costs an average of $ 223 to provide legal representation for a poor criminal defendant, and the number requiring such services has risen sharply since 1982. The <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> said Monday the $ 223 cost, the average in 1986, is up from $ 196 per case in 1982. The caseload rose to nearly 4.5 million, up about 40 percent from the 3.2 million cases four years earlier, the bureau said in a report. The 50 states and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, spent a combined $ 991 million for indigent defendants in 1986, compared to $ 625 million in 1982 _ an increase of 60 percent. The programs are financed by state, county and local governments in each state. The rights of poor criminal defendants to legal representation were spelled out in a number of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings beginning in 1932. One case was the landmark <PERSON> Gideon </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wainright </PERSON> in 1963, when the court extended the right to counsel in state courts to all indigent defendants charged with a felony. Some states have expanded the program to include representation for proceedings involving parole, probation, parental rights, civil commitment and post-conviction matters. The department said <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> spent the least for indigent defendants _ an average of 69 cents per state resident. The District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> spent the most, $ 29 per capita. The average per capita expenditure nationwide was $ 4.11 in 1986, up from $ 2.76 in 1982. When average costs per indigent case were computed, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> again was last, spending $ 63 per case in 1986. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> was first, spending an average of $ 540. There are three basic programs used to provide the legal services. Assigned counsel programs feature case-by-case appointments of lawyers; in contract programs, the government contracts with individual lawyers, law firms or local bar associations to provide services for a given period; and in public defender programs, a salaried staff is hired to provide legal services. The report was an update to a 1982 study on indigent defendants. Since the initial study, the report said, there was a movement from county to state financing; an increase in rates of compensation paid to private lawyers, and expanded use of contracts for providing representation to the poor. Here are the total state-by-state expenditures -LRB- including <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- in 1986, in millions; the per capita expenditure in actual dollars; and the state's ranking in per capita spending: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, $ 6.1 million, $ 1.52, 44; <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, $ 6.8 million, $ 12.91, 2; <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> $ 16.2 million, $ 4.89, 10; <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, $ 1.6 million, 69 cents, 51; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, $ 251.5 million, $ 9.32, 3; <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, $ 12.1 million, $ 3.71, 21; <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, $ 9.2 million, $ 2.90, 25; <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, $ 2.7 million, $ 4.34, 14; <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 18 million, $ 28.90, 1; <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, $ 82.1 million, $ 7.03, 5. <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, $ 8.3 million, $ 1.36, 47; <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, $ 4.3 million, $ 4.13, 18; <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, $ 2.6 million, $ 2.62, 28; <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, $ 33.1 million, $ 2.87, 26; <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, $ 10.9 million, $ 1.99, 37; <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, $ 11.5 million, $ 4.05, 20; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, $ 4.2 million, $ 1.73, 41; <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>, $ 7.6 million, $ 2.06, 36; <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, $ 10.8 million, $ 2.41, 34; <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, $ 1.9 million, $ 1.67, 42. <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, $ 20 million, $ 4.49, 13; <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, $ 20.7 million, $ 3.56, 22; <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, $ 43.6 million, $ 4.77, 11; <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, $ 14.1 million, $ 3.36, 24; <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, $ 2.9 million, $ 1.11, 50; <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, $ 6.7 million, $ 1.33, 49; <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, $ 4.2 million, $ 5.15, 8; <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, $ 4.3 million, $ 2.71, 27; <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, $ 6.3 million, $ 6.63, 6. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, $ 4.3 million, $ 4.22, 16; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, $ 31 million, $ 4.07, 19; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, $ 6.2 million, $ 4.25, 15; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, $ 111.6 million, $ 6.28, 7; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, $ 16.4 million, $ 2.60, 29; <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, $ 1.2 million, $ 1.81, 39; <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, $ 26.5 million, $ 2.47, 32; <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, $ 4.4 million, $ 1.36, 48. Oregon, $ 22.4 million, $ 8.31, 4; <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, $ 28.6 million, $ 2.41, 33; <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, $ 2 million, $ 2.14, 35; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, $ 4.6 million, $ 1.39, 46; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, $ 1.7 million, $ 2.52, 31; <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, $ 7.7 million, $ 1.62, 43; <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, $ 32.8 million, $ 1.97, 38; <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, $ 2.3 million, $ 1.40, 45; <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, $ 2.7 million, $ 5.13, 9; <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, $ 10.1 million, $ 1.75, 40; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, $ 21.1 million, $ 4.75, 12; <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, $ 4.8 million, $ 2.53, 30; <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, $ 20 million, $ 4.19, 17; <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, $ 1.7 million, $ 3.45, 23.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Whistle-Blower     09-06 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Whistle-Blower,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Whistle-Blower's Victory May Not Bode Well For
Others</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A victory that could give $ 800,000 to a fired government whistle-blower sets precedents that he and his lawyers fear will make it riskier for other federal employees to expose waste and hazards. <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, fired in 1983 after he accused the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> of becoming `` the nation's slumlord,'' said he will take early retirement in a settlement with the agency. He had been <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s top regional director, overseeing all major government buildings in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, area. Despite the settlement ordered by the <ORGANIZATION> Merit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said laws are needed to prevent the government from punishing other employees who disclose overspending and dangerous conditions and that the federal system to protect such whistle-blowers actually worked against him. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, who says he is the highest ranking civil servant ever fired for whistle-blowing, said federal employees should not think they can duplicate what he did unless they have several hundred thousand dollars to spend on attorneys. He was defended by a public interest group that can afford to back only a fraction of those who go against government employers, he said. `` If a government employee has that kind of money, they're usually not working for the government,'' said <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> Those who think they can get help from the special government counsel set up to protect whistle-blowers may find `` they're going to the executioner when they think they're going to the doctor,'' he said. The special counsel for the merit board refused to take his case and ended up testifying in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> against him, saying there were other grounds for firing him besides his criticism of waste, fire danger and health hazards in federal buildings, <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> had claimed that <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, who earned $ 64,000 a year overseeing 7,000 employees, engaged in `` irresponsible sensationalism'' in describing <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>'s problems. <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Koster </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> administrator who fired <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> would not comment on the settlement signed Aug. 18. <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> now heads the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Asset </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> officials also had no comment on the agreement. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>, legal director for the Government Accountability Project which represents <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> and other government and private industry whistle-blowers, said rulings by the merit board during its consideration of <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>'s case further inhibit whistle-blowing. `` Under the <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> standards, agencies have everything to gain and nothing to lose by opening up a witch hunt on a whistle-blower,'' he said. <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> said that under the precedent, government agencies are allowed to look after-the-fact for reasons to justify a dismissal. The <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> settlement agreement with <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> precludes further appeal by either side and says the settlement does not assume any `` unlawful personnel practice, discrimination, reprisal or any other unlawful or illegal acts'' by the agency or its officials. <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> said neither the merit board nor the courts have done anything to discourage government reprisals against whistle-blowing employees. The merit board's office of special counsel, which was set up to represent whistle-blowers, `` actually has been a <LOCATION> Troan </LOCATION> horse for civil servants who commit the truth,'' he said. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said in a telephone interview over the weekend that problems with government buildings have gotten `` worse rather than better'' since he was fired, with many buildings in serious disrepair while money is wasted. In a May 1983 memo, he had said 25 percent of <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> buildings were unsafe and `` for all practical purposes, we're becoming the nation's slumlord.'' <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said he agreed not to go back to the agency so he could continue his successful woodworking business in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and continue to fight for whistle-blower legislation. <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Costello </PERSON> said Friday that a check for $ 530,000 would shortly be made out to <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> and his lawyers. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>, 55, said that after legal fees he will get about $ 350,000, along with up to $ 430,000 in additional retirement pay based on his normal life expectancy. Lawyers said <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> also will have to pay $ 24,000 into <PERSON> Berube </PERSON>'s retirement account and reimburse the $ 6,000 paid him in unemployment compensation. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said he would retire with a $ 32,500 annual pension, based on 26 years of government service, including the five years since he was fired. <PERSON> Berube </PERSON> said that without the settlement he would have received annual retirement pay of $ 18,000 when he turns 65. A whistle-blower protection bill has passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. House leaders are discussing whether to consider similar legislation passed by a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee or a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration bill opposed by whistle-blowers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugBill     09-06 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Bill,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brady's Wife Says Reagan Reaffirms Support for Gun Wait Period</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, whose husband was shot along with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, says <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> recently reaffirmed to her that he supports a mandatory waiting period for the purchase of handguns. The wife of presidential press secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said she reminded <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in a telephone conversation that <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> shot him and <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> in March 1981 with a gun purchased in a state _ <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ without a waiting period. Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> endorsed the concept of a federal waiting period, but not the specific language in a comprehensive anti-drug bill that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will consider this week _ and likely pass. `` He recognized the need for federal legislation,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said, after she told him that states `` are not doing the job'' in stopping drug dealers from obtaining handguns. Debate on the overall drug bill begins Wednesday, and a final vote could take place Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will then follow with its own drug bill and the two versions would eventually be merged into final legislation. The House bill as introduced would carry a $ 1.5 billion to $ 2 billion annual price tag, money that would be added to the $ 3.9 billion a year the federal government is now spending to fight drug use. The legislation includes something for everyone involved in fighting illegal drugs: more money for education, treatment and rehabilitation; more resources for state and local law enforcement efforts to seize drugs on land, in the air and on the seas. Strict controls would be placed for the first time on the chemicals used as raw materials in the manufacture of heroin and cocaine. There will be controversies over Republican-inspired amendments for a federal death penalty against those who kill during a drug crime; a `` good faith'' exception that would allow use of illegally seized drug evidence in court, and denial of many federal benefits for convicted drug users. The gun language would require a seven-day wait in the purchase of a handgun from a licensed dealer. The dealer must send law enforcement authorities a sworn statement that includes a description of the gun, the serial number, the name, address and birth date of the buyer. Police may, but are not required, to conduct a background check. Purchasers who would be denied the pistol would be those already ineligible under existing federal law: convicted felons, fugitives from justice, illegal aliens, drug addicts, those adjudicated mentally ill or committed to a mental institution, those dishonorably discharged from the military and people under indictment for a felony. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., said he will offer an amendment to substitute a requirement that the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> establish a computerized system to identify felons trying to purchase handguns Access would be provided to local police and firearms dealers. `` I do n't think you should have a waiting period when it abridges the right to buy a gun'' for a law-abiding citizen, <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> first weighed in on the subject of waiting periods on June 21. The former <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> governor spoke favorably of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s 15-day waiting period with a mandatory background check, and added, `` Now, I would like to see that generally. I think that all states ought to take a look at that system.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who became a gun-control activist after her husband's shooting, said she wrote <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> thanking him for the remarks, and he called her a week later. She brought up the federal waiting period during the conversation. `` He wished it could be handled by the states,'' she said, but added that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was willing to have a federal law `` because of the overwhelming problem'' of drug dealers and other criminals obtaining guns. `` I told him we were trying to get that attached to the drug bill,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> said. `` I told him there is overwhelming evidence through the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION> that guns used in crimes are traced back to states where there is no waiting period. I indicated <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON>'s gun came from a state, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, where there is no waiting period.'' Other key provisions of the drug bill would: _ Require states to automatically `` pass through'' anti-drug money to local governments _ Revise banking laws to allow the government to closely watch institutions where drug money might be laundered _ Require recipients of federal grants or contracts to maintain a drug-free workplace _ Provide money for drug education, treatment and rehabilitation for AIDS victims and groups with a high risk of getting the disease _ Authorize $ 10 million for a Latin American regional anti-drug force if one is approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Environment     09-06 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Environment,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Time Running Out on Environmental Bills</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has left itself about a month to solve major environmental problems that have eluded solution in the 1980s _ redoubling the battle against urban air pollution and launching an attack on acid rain. Lawmakers return to town Wednesday, shooting for an early October adjournment. As the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> enter the home stretch, clean air legislation is barely out of the starting gate. Neither chamber has even scheduled debate on the Clean Air Act revisions that are being watched closely by some 100 cities and metropolitan areas that failed to meet last December's deadline for bringing ozone and carbon monoxide levels within national health standards. A comprehensive package to control urban smog, acid rain and airborne toxic chemicals was ready for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> debate last November, but it has been stalled by a variety of opponents, most notably Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. The package's principal sponsor, Sen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, has been trying to negotiate floor time with <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> has said that if necessary, he will offer his air bill as an amendment to must-pass legislation. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, serious closed-door negotiations among leaders of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> did n't begin until this summer, leaving little time to get a complicated proposal ready for the floor. Any package produced by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would most likely give cities more time to clean up their air but also require tougher actions to combat pollution, from local driving restrictions to stricter emissions standards for vehicles. Debate, a good bit of it in scientific terms, centers on how much more time will be granted and just what corrective steps will be required. A complicating factor is that the nation has already employed the measures that can bring large and quick reductions in pollution. Acid rain control is simpler scientifically but far more complicated economically and geographically. Acid rain, a byproduct of coal-burning factories and power plants, is a major concern of the East, which is downwind from the industrial <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. Just who pays to clean up Midwestern emissions is a major question, with many Western lawmakers cool to a national subsidy for Midwestern cleanup costs. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> not only has power plants in his state that would have to reduce their emissions, his state has huge deposits of high sulfur coal that could lose its market to cleaner burning coal from other states under an acid rain control bill. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has a fallback option if it fails to produce clean air legislation. It can, as it did last December, pass another stopgap bill that would prevent the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> from taking action against areas not meeting the standards. The environment surfaced as an issue last week in the presidential race between Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claimed to be highly committed to a cleaner environment, although the record of the Reagan-Bush administration has been given dismal marks by environmental groups. The clean air fight is at the top of the environment-conservation agenda for the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but other issues are vying for attention in the closing weeks of the election-year session. One that might not take much time is the early 1987 request by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the oil industry to allow petroleum exploration in the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s north coast The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and Fisheries committees have endorsed drilling bills, but the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, where the environmental lobby has more clout, is sitting on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill. Likely to emerge from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> after a four-year struggle is a renewal of the Endangered Species Act authorizing a 50 percent increase in program spending in the early 1990s. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is also ready to pass a $ 9.8 billion fiscal 1989 spending bill for the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other land and resource agencies. It is drawing veto threats because it would delay spending for clean-coal technology research and bar oil leasing off portions of the coasts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. House and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators are putting the finishing touches on legislation that would encourage the use of less-polluting methanol, ethanol and natural gas as alternatives to imported petroleum for powering vehicles. Awaiting Senate action are House-passed bills that would reorganize the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to make its director independent of political appointees in the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>; cut back on commercial timbering in the <ORGANIZATION> Tongass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>; and prevent a shopping center from being built adjacent to the <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Battlefield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle     09-06 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Has Patriotic Campaign Season Opener</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a week of refining his message and selling it to friendly audiences, <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is home preparing for the fall campaign following a patriotic season opener at the Statue of Liberty. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is spending time with his family today and holds staff meetings Wednesday before taking a quick swing to <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> at week's end. The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator delivered a Labor Day tribute Monday to the Pledge of Allegiance, which the Republicans have attempted to turn into a political weapon against <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> blasted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for vetoing a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> bill that would have penalized teachers who did not lead their students in the pledge. The values embodied in the pledge `` deserve to be transmitted to our children,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` To us, they are not hokey or cornball or passe,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also toured <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, where millions of immigrants entered the country and which is now undergoing restoration. The Quayles are of Scottish descent and their relatives did not come through <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. But the couple and their three children posed for photographs anyway with a group of people dressed in costumes of their native countries. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s speech at the base of <LOCATION> Lady </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION>, with the <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> skyline in the background and <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nearby, was planned as a moving kickoff to the countdown to Election Day. But it was disrupted briefly by about 30 demonstrators, members of a coalition that believes the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> have not done enough in the fight against AIDS. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s aides said later that the senator had an `` exemplary record'' on AIDS issues and had recently voted to provide $ 1.2 billion in funding for AIDS research, education and prevention. The demonstrators, however, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> voted against legislation to give the experimental drug AZT to AIDS victims. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s speech outlined what will be his themes this fall: the economy is doing well, inflation and interest rates are under control, and earnings and job growth are up. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s task will be to sell the voters on the idea that they will enjoy a bright future if they stick with the Republicans, according to campaign strategists. That was the message <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had for the Liberty Island crowd. `` We will win this election because we are the party of the future. We believe in our families. We believe in the future and we believe in preserving freedom in this country. We will never let it go,'' he said. It was the same message <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> worked on last week during his Southern campaign swing, speaking before largely sympathetic audiences on conservative college campuses and elsewhere in the deep South. But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is also beginning to get some less receptive crowds as he ventures outside conservative territory. On Monday, he got a mixed reception when he dropped into <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> to address Polish-Americans after a parade. The audience booed and heckled him as he spoke, although he did get a cheer when he declared, `` We will never give up until there's freedom again in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880906-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-06-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LRescue     09-06 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Rescue,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>California S&amp;L Bailout to be Most Costly Ever</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
