<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     07-09 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 17; 19; 22; 33; 35; 40.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     07-09 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0089</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 17; 19; 22; 33; 35; 40.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 3-7-5-9.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 06; 11; 13; 18; 34.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 04; 13; 18; 25; 28; 34. Bonus: 64064.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 06; 11; 17; 19; 24; 48. Supplementary 25.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 8-4-8-4.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 5-5-7; 9-6-5-1; 1-0-5-2-5; 2-9-6-6-8-8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Schedules     07-09 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning July 10. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, July 10: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Franicisco </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Monday, July 11: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Tuesday, July 12: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> Wednesday, July 13: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Thursday, July 14: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Friday, July 15: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Saturday, July 16: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Chatanooga </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open Sunday, July 17: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Republican: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0634EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--AgentOrange     07-09 0101</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Agent Orange,0103</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Toll-Free Number For Veterans</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The toll-free numbers for information about the distribution of the Agent Orange settlement fund for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans have been changed, officials said. The new number is 1-800-225-4712, officials said Friday. The previous phone numbers, one for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state and one for the rest of the country, were disconnected in order to consolidate them into one number at the <ORGANIZATION> Aetna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which will be the claims administrator for the program. The $ 240 million settlement fund resulted from a suit against manufacturers of the herbicide Agent Orange.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--GrannyGrenade     07-09 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Granny Grenade,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Cleans Out Attic, Dumps Grenade</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LA SPEZIA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An elderly woman tossed a hand grenade into a garbage dump and announced, `` Enough already, I ca n't keep this in the attic any more,'' authorities said. Police blocked off the area after learning of the incident and eventually fished out the American-made grenade, whose pin had not been removed. No one was injured in the incident Friday in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spezia </LOCATION>, 200 miles north of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. After the woman disposed of the grenade, she told bystanders, `` I have thrown it away and now it's up to you,'' the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said. The woman left the area and was not found, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Election 3rdLd-Writethru a0821 07-09 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Election, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0821,0907</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ruling Party Candidate Winning, But Lowest Margin in 60 Years</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 7th graf, `At a...' with six grafs to UPDATE with PRI
chairman proclaiming victory in 27 states, Salinas comments on
credibility of vote count. Pick up 8th pvs, ``I believe...' Edits
to trim thereafter</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ISAAC A. LEVI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Preliminary figures from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s presidential election show the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> candidate winning, but with the lowest margin in its six decades in office <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> figures obtained from a reliable source show <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> with 47.4 percent of the 4.5 million votes counted so far. <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> was second with 26.7 percent and <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> third with 20.7 percent. The 4.5 million votes counted are out of 11.7 million ballots reported so far to the commission. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has 38 million registered voters but no figures are available how many voted in Wednesday's election In addition to the presidency, 64 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats and 500 in the newly expanded Chamber of Deputies are at stake. A final vote count is not expected until Sunday. The early leak appeared designed to counter growing speculation that the ruling party, known as the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> for its initials in Spanish, had suffered a devastating loss. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> <PERSON> Dominguez </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, proclaimed a party victory in at least 27 of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s 31 states and said opposition accusations of fraud were meant to confuse the electorate. `` The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> is going to defend its legal and unobjectionable electoral triumph with all the means of the law. It is going to mobilize the force of all its organizations to combat the provocation and irresponsibility'' of the opposition, he said. A relaxed and smiling <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, meeting Friday night with foreign reporters, insisted that he was more concerned that the vote count be credible than with his margin of victory. `` Those results reflect real votes,'' he said. `` The results so far ratify this circumstance of plurality ... and a new political reality in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' He said opposition parties will be most visible in the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, where presumably would have a role in approving or blocking constitutional changes that require a two-thirds majority. At a news conference earlier Friday, <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> accused the government of delaying an announcement in order to falsify results. `` They are waiting to see how to disguise the figures,'' he said. `` I believe we won, but I do n't want to boast prematurely as my adversary has,'' he said of the victory claim by <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>. `` <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> has changed. Totally changed. ... We will never have only one party again.'' <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> met earlier in the day and agreed to share their information on voting results in order to challenge government figures. He said they also agreed not to release figures publicly for the time being, because when the government finds out what information the opposition has, then officials will know which results they can `` dress up.'' No PRI presidential candidate since the party's founding in 1929 has won less than 70 percent of the vote. The slow count also is making evident splits within the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> between the 40-year-old <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> and the old-style politicians. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which controls the vote count, is headed by <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, who was among <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>'s chief rivals for the presidential nomination. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> has insisted throughout the campaign that he will introduce a new era in which opposition voices will be heard. <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> governor in the central state of <LOCATION> Michoacan </LOCATION> until his break with the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> last year, waged an unusually strong campaign that capitalized on widespread discontent with the hardships caused by six years of economic crisis. The leftist candidate is the son of the revered late President <PERSON> Lazaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>. In renouncing his own presidential hopes and endorsing <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> last spring, <PERSON> Heberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> of the rival <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> described the <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> movement as a `` phenomenon.'' <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> appeared ready to concede losses to <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Michoacan </LOCATION>, the central state of <LOCATION> Morelos </LOCATION> and in the Federal District, the core of the sprawling <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> metropolitan area. A fourth <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> victory could come in the populous state of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, which abuts the Federal District on three sides. The vote count made available to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> also showed <PERSON> Gumersino </PERSON> <PERSON> Magana </PERSON> <PERSON> Negrete </PERSON> of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Mexican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with 0.95 percent of the vote and <PERSON> Rosario </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibarra </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Piedra </PERSON> of the radical <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with 0.4 percent. Most districts recorded so far are urban, where <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clouthier </PERSON> are strongest. The Salinas de Gortari percentage could be expected to rise slightly with reports from rural district where the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> is traditionally strong. <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> said soon after the election that technical difficulties with a new computer system delayed the returns. He later blamed bad weather. The government says the elections were peaceful and clean. <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> officials have said charges by opposition parties that the balloting was fraudulent were a publicity move. The Assembly for Effective Suffrage, a civic watchdog group, recorded 1,100 cases of voting irregularities ranging from ballot-stuffing to tampering with voter registration rolls.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--SmokingBan     07-09 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Smoking Ban,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Punishment For Smokers Violating Norway's Anti-Smoking Law</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Smokers will not be punished for violating <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>'s tough new anti-smoking law, a government official said. But operators of restaurants, hotels or other public areas risk fines if people are found smoking where they should n't, <PERSON> Trine </PERSON> <PERSON> Lind </PERSON>, information secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The law went into effect July 1, but its provisions were only set at a cabinet meeting on Friday. Maximum fines were not immediately published. The law bans smoking outside special smoking sections in public transportion, theater lobbies, banks, post offices and work places. The government has said it wants to make <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> tobacco-free by the year 2000. Four out of 10 adult Norwegians now smoke.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Koch     07-09 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Koch,0309</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pirates-Mets Rivalry Has Mayors Crossing Swords</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN SHANAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> they'll walk the plank in their next series with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION>, in another inning _ er, round _ of good-natured goading between <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. When the <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> ran a series of ads two weeks ago calling the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> another good reason to hate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, `` Where is it?'' <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON> <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON> sent <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> a map and reminded him of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>'s considerable charms. And <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, through a television reporter, invited her to lunch in the Big Apple. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> sent a letter Wednesday to <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON> saying he was `` delighted to learn that <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> has been designated one of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s ` most-livable cities.''' But the designation obviously was made, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said, by someone `` with a sense of humor.'' `` I ca n't promise your Buccaneers -LRB- the <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- will be walking on a red carpet when they arrive in the Big Apple for their next series with the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION>, but we will be looking for an appropriate plank,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said. The Pirates will be at <LOCATION> Shea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION> for a four-game series starting July 29. The Mets visit Three Rivers Stadium Aug. 5 for a four-game meeting. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s office released his letter Friday, as well as a letter sent June 30 by <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON> to <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Masloff </PERSON> wrote, `` While I felt your comment on <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>'s location was tongue in cheek _ <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> having been designated <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most-livable city and being the third-largest corporate headquarters in the nation _ just to be on the safe side, I am sending you a map of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> `` It would be nice if you could make use of it when the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> tangle here again,'' she added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlinerRdp Bjt   07-09 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airliner Rdp, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aegis System Got Poor Marks In GAO Report</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Aegis air defense system, used by the cruiser <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> last week to track and shoot down an Iranian passenger jet, may not have been adequately tested before it was deployed, according to a classified review by a congressional watchdog agency. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> study concluded that the $ 1 billion system has not proven its ability to discriminate among targets, said congressional sources who have seen the document. They spoke Friday on condition they not be named. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> review started last year and did not mention last week's destruction of <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> flight 655 that killed all 290 people aboard The <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> fired at the airliner after mistaking it for an Iranian F-14. Pentagon officials have said the Aegis system was not malfunctioning. A `` minor degradation'' of the Aegis radar was repaired before the ship entered the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> last month, they said. Aegis, named for the shield of Zeus in Greek mythology, is a complex mix of radars and computers. It was developed as the main component of protection for <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> surface ships against enemy ships and planes. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is building a fleet of Aegis cruisers, of which the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> is the third. The service is also using some components of the Aegis system aboard other surface ships. The system was first deployed in 1983. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> review looked at the Aegis testing program before the system went into service, said the sources. The study criticized a series of 1984 tests in which the Aegis system tracked 11 targets and guided the firing of weapons which hit 10, the sources said. At one point, two targets were fired upon at the same time. The 1984 test program was set up specifically to answer complaints from <PERSON> Aegis </PERSON> critics who argued that the system needed more realistic tests. But the tests were set up so carefully they did not approximate a `` real-life'' combat environment, the sources quoted the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report as saying. In other developments Friday: _ President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the issue of whether to pay compensation for the families of those killed is `` under consideration. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said there were `` still some open questions'' on the issue. _ Sen <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should adopt a new stance in the Iran-Iraq war `` equidistant'' from the two warring countries `` I do believe that we'd be much better served in trying to end the war if we were really in a position of condemning both attacks by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and also condemning the chemical warfare being conducted against innocent people by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>,'' he said. _ Pentagon officials said they are awaiting results of an investigation to learn why the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> missed air traffic communications and other clues indicating that the jet was a civilian plane and not an F-14 fighter, as officers aboard the ship believed Iranian officials have said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> systems should have been able to monitor 21 minutes of conversation in English between the jetliner and the airport control tower in <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>. But Pentagon spokesmen said they were not sure <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces were monitoring, or were able to monitor, air traffic control communications at the time of the incident. `` We are looking forward to an analysis of the tapes to help clarify the issue,' said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Baumann </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra Bjt   07-09 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Order Could Hinder Prosecution On Main Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge's order giving <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> broader access to secret government documents for his defense strongly raises the possibility he wo n't be tried on the main charges of the Iran-Contra indictment. But the order issued Friday by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> clears the way for the fired <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide to go to trial at least on charges he lied to cover up his activities and personally gained from his involvement in the Iran-Contra affair. The judge's order scheduling the trial for Sept. 20 set the stage for the proceeding to take place in the middle of the fall presidential campaign. In addition to fixing the trial date, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> ruled that <PERSON> North </PERSON> is entitled to use highly classified documents that might show the covert activities that are the basis of the Iran-Contra conspiracy charge were authorized by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. The judge noted that some highly sensitive portions of documents in the prosecution's case that government security experts want deleted `` tended to exonerate North of guilt on certain charges.'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> ruled <PERSON> North </PERSON> was entitled to cite these passages in a public trial. If the government continues to object, those charges could be dismissed under the Classified Information Procedures Act, known as <ORGANIZATION> CIPA </ORGANIZATION>. The judge further ordered that independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> and the government must provide <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> with such highly secret documents as references in President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s daily intelligence briefings to covert aid to the Contras. The fired <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide is charged along with former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> with conspiring to defraud the government by illegally diverting U.S.-Iran arms-sale profits to the Nicaraguan rebels. All four defendants, ordered by <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to be tried separately, are also charged with theft of government property and wire fraud. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> contends that the defendants corrupted the legitimate, fully authorized presidential initiative of trading <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms for American hostages by funneling weapons-sale proceeds to the Contras. According to court pleadings by <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, some of the documents sought are so sensitive that only the president and a handful of top officials have access to them. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he was not endorsing <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense or even the admissibility of the documents as evidence. But he said the material should be made available to the retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant colonel `` to assure that the truth, whatever it ultimately proves to be, ` will out.''' The judge gave North until Aug. 1 to notify the government of his intention to use classified portions of the documents he already has as evidence. He set an Aug. 15 deadline for North to file a similar list of material turned over as a result of Friday's order `` A jury trial on those counts remaining after the <ORGANIZATION> CIPA </ORGANIZATION> process takes it course is set for Sept. 20,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. `` It presently appears that, at a minimum, substantive charges of cover-up, falsification and <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s alleged receipt of personal benefit derived from his conduct as a government employee can proceed to trial,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. In a brief statement, <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said: `` We are ready to proceed as directed by the court.'' Even if the three major counts are dismissed, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> is charged with 12 other felony counts, including allegations that he: _ lied to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 about covert administration aid to the Contras _ shredded documents during Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>'s November 1986 investigation of the Iran-Contra affair _ created phony documents to obstruct an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation into the construction of a $ 15,000 security fence around his home _ accepted the fence as an illegal gratuity from <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>. _ pocketed $ 4,300 worth of traveler's checks from $ 90,000 given to him by a Contra leader to defray expenses for helping the rebel cause.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LegalServices Bjt   07-09 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Legal Services, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Probe Charges Improper Use Of Legal Services Funds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is defending its chairman against congressional allegations that he improperly used government funds for presidential politics, personal business and to help destroy the agency. The corporation, in a prepared statement issued late Friday, said it has uncovered no evidence `` that would lend credence to insinuations of misappropriation'' by <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., outlined the allegations and called for the resignation of <PERSON> Durant </PERSON>, who has served as chairman of the agency's board since December 1984 and was an adviser to Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s failed presidential campaign `` He's been undermining the <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> by personal and political activities ... at the expense of the taxpayers,'' <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> charged. Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on courts, civil liberties and the administration of justice, agreed that the evidence appears to show `` significant improprieties in the financial management of the corporation. `` It's very unlikely that -LRB- <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> -RRB- could explain these matters satisfactorily,'' he said. <PERSON> Durant </PERSON>, reached by telephone at his <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> law office, denied the allegations and countered that the congressional attack was motivated by political and policy disagreements over the direction of the agency, which funds legal assistance programs for the poor. The corporation said that it discovered during its examination of the records that `` Mr. <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> is entitled to approximately $ 8,800 in attendance fees, which he has not claimed.'' The agency said it was continuing to review records at the subcommittee's request The agency said the congressional investigation `` is being used by some in an attempt to derail needed reforms in the delivery of government-funded legal services to the poor and to discredit the efforts of Chairman <PERSON> Durant </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said a preliminary congressional investigation of corporation records covering an 18-month period revealed that <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> used <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> telephone credit cards to call <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> headquarters nine times and may have charged campaign-tied trips to the agency. <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said there were 23 trips to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> charged to the agency that have no documentation tying them to Legal Services work. <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> also charged to the agency long-distance phone calls to high-ranking federal transportation officials, an apparent link to his private sector post as a railroad trustee, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> alleged. And the congressman said <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> is `` the man behind'' the agency's controversial move to hire lobbyists who were instructed to urge lawmakers to cut the Legal Services budget. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said last month that federal law prohibits such lobbying. <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> added that documents provided by <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> at the subcommittee's request showed dozens of calls to private, conservative organizations that have advocated the abolition of Legal Services, including the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. Dismantling Legal Services was an early goal of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who appointed <PERSON> Durant </PERSON>, and the chairman has been a leading critic of his own agency. <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, who headed a Legal Services program in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, before his election to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1982, estimated the cost of `` questionable'' telephone calls at more than $ 5,000 plus thousands more in air travel. <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> scoffed at the allegations. `` This is purely rooted in policy and political differences,'' he said. `` I do n't have anything to hide ...,'' he said. `` If there are any calls that are not strictly related to Legal Services, I have no objection and think the corporation should be reimbursed.'' But he said those would not come close to the dollar estimates provided by <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>. <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> said he knew of $ 2.35 in telephone calls that were mistakenly charged to the agency, and he said he knew of no travel expenses. The decision to hire the lobbyists was made by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayly </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, then president of <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> said. But the congressmen said <PERSON> Durant </PERSON> was behind the move to hire the lobbyists and then orchestrated a move to force <PERSON> Bayly </PERSON> out of his job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-EpiscopalConvention     07-09 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Episcopal Convention,0381</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Visitor' Amendment Passed by House of Bishops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>'s policy making bodies Friday approved a resolution to let the presiding bishop name a man to perform some sacramental acts for members who object to having a female bishop. Approval of the measure was in doubt briefly Friday after a minor amendment was tacked onto it by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION>, one of two bodies meeting at the church's 69th General Convention here through Monday. But the House of Bishops, the church's other legislative body, concurred later Friday. While some at the meeting saw the resolution as watering down a 1976 decision approving the ordination of women, it sets a six-year time limit on the authority to name a `` visitor,'' as the man would be called. The resolution was approved 122-94 in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION> and 140-28 in the House of Bishops. There are no women yet serving as bishops in the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, but about 900 female priests have been ordained. `` I'm sorry that the statement was accepted. I'm glad there is a time limit, I can live with it,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Meadows </PERSON>, a female priest from southern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> House </PERSON>, a lay member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> said the time limit `` undermines the Episcopate in the long run. I feel that a woman bishop would hasten the day of understanding.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> of the east <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> diocese backed the proposal and its limit. `` I think the death of a belief is as painful as the death of a relationship,'' he said. `` There is a belief system dying. We need to be concerned during grieving process and reach out as often as we can.'' Also on Friday: _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION> approved a resolution in response to a call by Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> to boycott American companies doing business in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> The resolution goes to the House of Delegates. _ The House of Bishops unanimously approved an economic development package that passed the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday and calls for $ 250,000 from the church over the next three years to create community land trust, cooperative housing, employee-owned businesses, and community credit unions
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-09 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0809</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> says his sensitivity to alcohol abuse tempered his portrayal of the lovable lush `` Arthur'' in the sequel `` Arthur 2 On The Rocks.'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who won an Oscar nomination for his performance as the drunken millionaire <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Bach </PERSON>, said his approach to the character this time was different because of a heightened awareness of alcoholism. `` There was no official pressure from the studio or from any organized groups,'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said recently. `` But I personally have an educated awareness of the problem.'' The producers also avoided any scenes in `` Arthur 2 On The Rocks'' of <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> drinking and driving, unlike the original, in which <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> is seen cruising in his Rolls Royce swigging from a bottle. `` There's a scene in which <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> -RRB- says she never lets him drink and drive,'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said. `` And you can tell that <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> knows exactly what he should or should not do. He still gets very drunk, but that's because he feels panicked and isolated sometimes and unable to cope with the world.'' But <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> is quick to point out that the film does n't preach. The sequel opened Friday at theaters nationwide.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, who is eight months pregnant, escaped injury when her chauffeured car collided with an oncoming vehicle, police and Buckingham Palace said. The accident occurred Friday on a section of the M40, a busy highway about 20 miles outside of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Part of the road was closed for repairs, police said. A police bodyguard was driving the duchess' <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>. She continued the journey in an accompanying police car, Buckingham Palace said. The 28-year-old duchess, the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, is married to <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, the second son of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. She is expecting their first child.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Veteran actor <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Riquelme </PERSON>, who stars in <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>'s `` The Milagro Beanfield War,'' was reported in serious condition at a local hospital's coronary care unit. But the 77-year-old actor `` has been improving in the past hours,'' said <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ocampo </PERSON>, a doctor the <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santelena </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Riquelme </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> told the newspaper El Universal the stress of filming of the movie in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> last year may have contributed to his illness. `` The pace ... was exhausting. He was working nearly 14 hours a day,'' <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Riquelme </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Ramones </ORGANIZATION>, the band that gave the world `` Cretin Hop,'' `` Teen-age Lobotomy'' and other short, loud, fast and somewhat silly punk tunes, is celebrating its 15th anniversary. The <ORGANIZATION> Ramones </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Joey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dee </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Marky </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramone </PERSON>, who are not related but took the surname for the stage _ marked the milestone recently by releasing `` Ramonesmania,'' a two-record anthology of their best-known material. Except for an occasional guitar solo by <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramone </PERSON> _ a lapse some fans equate with selling out _ the anthology shows the punk pioneers have stuck to the formula of two-minute, three-cord head-bangers. `` We're a band that our fans can count on,'' <PERSON> Joey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramone </PERSON> said recently.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> is recuperating from a short hospital stay for hernia surgery, a spokeswoman said. `` It was a procedure called the Canadian repair, a very commonly performed surgical procedure and it was performed under local anesthesia,'' said <PERSON> Myrna </PERSON> <PERSON> Manners </PERSON>, spokeswoman at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital-Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, 75, was admitted Wednesday and was operated on Thursday morning by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Wantz </PERSON>, a hernia expert. He was discharged Friday. He is to recuperate at his home in <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, Manners said. `` It was really very routine, very minor surgery. And he went home in good condition,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRAND RAPIDS, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two members of the singing <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON> family have been indicted on charges they conspired to sell more than 2 pounds of cocaine. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> `` Chico'' <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON>, 22, of Grand Rapids appeared Thursday before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scoville </PERSON> and was ordered held in the <LOCATION> Kent </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> pending a detention hearing. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON>, 32, was held without bail Friday in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Both men were indicted on charges they conspired with five others to transport cocaine from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. The brothers also are charged with two counts of using interstate travel to distribute cocaine and one count of distribution of cocaine. If convicted of the conspiracy charges, they face up to life in prison. <PERSON> Chico </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON> are members of the large Grand Rapids family known for its singing talents. Two years ago, <PERSON> Chico </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON> recorded a solo album, `` <PERSON> Chico </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBarge </PERSON>,'' which reached No. 33 on the Billboard charts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OfficerKilled     07-09 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Officer Killed,0478</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officer Killed In Shootout; Backup Officer Wounds Three</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BIRK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> police officer was killed and three heavily armed <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> prison escapees were wounded in a gun battle that erupted Friday when the officer stopped to check a suspicious vehicle, a spokesman said. The slain officer was <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON>, 40, said police spokesman <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiracofe </PERSON>. A former reserve officer and probation official, <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> became a full-time member of the department in December 1986. He died Friday morning from two gunshots to the chest, said <ORGANIZATION> Tallahassee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brafford </PERSON>. Four injured people, all occupants of the car <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> had investigated, were arrested after the shooting behind a laundry several miles southwest of downtown. Police said <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 33, had gone to the trunk to retrieve identification but instead pulled a pistol from the vehicle and opened fire. The three escapees were wounded by gunfire returned by backup Officer <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, a member of the department for less than a year. A fourth occupant of the car, a <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> woman, also was wounded, apparently by gunfire from one of the other suspects, said <PERSON> Kiracofe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> `` did very well. He emptied his weapon at least once and had to reload under an awful lot of pressure. He fired a lot of rounds'' with a .357 - caliber Magnum service revolver, said The escapees were identified late Friday as <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who was serving 25 years for robbery with a deadly weapon and attempted robbery; <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goins </PERSON>, 26, who was serving 12 years for rape, kidnapping and robbery with a deadly weapon; and <PERSON> Irvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, 28, who was serving 45 years for assault with intent to murder. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was treated for a gunshot to the face and then released for police questioning, said <PERSON> Kiracofe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Goins </PERSON> was in critical condition with a gunshot wound to the head, said <PERSON> Brafford </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kiracofe </PERSON> said he might survive but would have brain damage. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> was listed in stable condition with a gunshot to the thigh at <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> Memorial. <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, 39, a longtime acquaintance of <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, was in stable condition at <ORGANIZATION> Tallahassee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudderman </PERSON>, assistant hospital administrator. She was expected to be released to police for questioning. All four face possible first-degree murder charges and if convicted under <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s felony-murder law they could be sentenced to die in the state's electric chair. The location of the fourth <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> escapee, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgerton </PERSON>, 21, who was serving a 20-year sentence for second-degree murder, was unknown. The four escaped June 25 by overpowering a guard in a recreation yard at <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correction </ORGANIZATION>. Their escape was the largest from the 1,600-inmate medium-security institution since 1979 when 30 men got away.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-OilRig-Jumpers Bjt   07-09 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oil Rig-Jumpers, Bjt,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survivors Describe Oil Rig Ordeal</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oil Rig, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ABERDEEN, Scotland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sixty-four men survived the <LOCATION> Piper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alpha </LOCATION> oil rig fire by leaping into the burning sea in the dark, but they had to leave behind more than 100 colleagues trapped and screaming for air in the inferno. `` I am one of the lucky ones,'' <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> said in an interview Friday. `` I am pretty sore, I am badly bruised and my hands are burned. But at least I'm alive. I have lost a lot of friends.'' Seventeen bodies have been found and 166 men are presumed dead in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> oil field where the rig exploded Wednesday night. At least 100 men died screaming for help, trapped in their sleeping quarters after surviving the first explosion, said <PERSON> Calder </PERSON>, a 35-year-old helicopter landing officer. The workers were in the smoke-filled galley of the platform, which was plunged into darkness when the emergency lighting failed, he said in an interview Friday. `` Windows and the emergency door were cracking under the intense heat. There must have been at least 100 men in there,'' <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> said. `` Men were shouting into their radios: ` We need breathing apparatus. What's happening? Is there anybody getting out? We are all going to die.' `` It was sheer panic. A lot of guys were lying on the floor, just trying to breathe. We had towels and we were just dipping them in anything to help us breathe,'' he said. <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> and a co-worker got out through a rear door just in time, he said, `` but I do n't think the others made it. I would have perished with them if I had n't got out when I did.'' He said he was asleep when the first explosion ripped through the rig, but he and his colleague had climbed on to the roof of the helicopter deck by the time the second blast hit. They made their way to the pipe deck and lay under a steel table for protection. `` We were hardly getting any breath. It was really bad,'' he said. `` Then, all of a sudden, the floor collapsed and we found ourselves lying at an angle. We saw a clear view looking through the smoke. We said rather than burn, we can get through that and jump. `` We crawled along pipes which were scalding hot. I burned my hands,'' he said. `` We got to the edge of the platform and just jumped. It was well over 100 feet to the sea. I missed the flames in the water. `` I did n't have a life jacket,'' <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> said. `` I hit the water and came up and I was OK. I started swimming and kept swimming.'' The two men got clear and <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> said he held onto his co-worker's life jacket. `` Then a life jacket appeared on the water in front of me and I put it on. It was a stroke of luck. `` There was debris everywhere and a lot of guys were sitting on pieces of debris. The waves were coming over my head. `` Then I saw a supply boat. It was easily a mile away. I kept swimming and swimming and waving and shouting. I was n't sure whether I had been seen. `` I was sure the skipper had given me a flash with his lights, but the boat seemed to be going away,'' <PERSON> Calder </PERSON> said. `` I thought that was going to be it _ that I was going to die. `` Then the boat went into reverse and turned round. It came to me and threw me a lifeline. They pulled me aboard. My friend was picked up by another vessel. I was told later that he was OK.'' Another survivor, 50-year-old <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, said that when he and some others tried to leave the crew's quarters, `` the flames were shooting into the doors ... For about three-quarters of an hour we were sitting inside. Nobody seemed to know what to do.'' Fire spread rapidly, turning metal girders red-hot and bringing decks crashing down in half-molten heaps. The men faced a hard choice: stay aboard and hope aid got to them before the flames, or jump into a sea that was cold enough below the burning oil to kill them. Even on a clear summer night, the water temperature was 57 degrees. Burning oil was spreading across the few bare patches of water remaining and the decision had to be made quickly. `` I decided to get myself out,'' <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> said. `` I was n't going to sit down and get burned to death. ... You either stayed where you were and burned to death or you tried to get out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-Election     07-09 0338</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Election,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pinochet Announces Presidential Vote Within 90 Days</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALCAHUANO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President and military leader <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> said a plebiscite to choose the president for 1989-97 will take place within the next 90 days. He is expected to be the only candidate. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> also said Friday he already has a platform for his next presidential term, but he refused to disclose it because the opposition `` would copy it.'' `` The plebiscite is near. There are less than 90 days left,'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> told an audience of 16,000 supporters in this southern port city 330 miles from <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>. The 72-year-old army commander has ruled this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nation since a 1973 coup. His remark was the most precise indication so far of a date for the ballot. According to the 1980 military-drafted Constitution, the nation's next presiddnt will be picked in a plebiscite in which Chileans will only be able to vote yes or no on a single candidate nominated by the heads of the three armed services and the national police. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> himself will participate in the nomination as commander-in-chief of the army and is considered the most likely nominee. He is allowed by the Constitution to seek re-election and has clearly indicated he intends to do so. If voters approve the nominee, he will serve for eight years starting in March 1989. If rejected, <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> will remain in power until 1990, and an open election would take place. <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> blasted opposition leaders seeking support from the international community as `` traitors.'' He said some critics who recently were given limited access to television are going too far in their broadscast remarks. `` When those bad Chileans make insults on television, because they know we are in a democracy and we wo n't do anything to them, let's tell them that our patience has limits and that they could soon discover those limits,'' <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> warned. He predicted an overwhelming victory in the upcoming plebiscite and said of his opponents, `` We will wipe them out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Politics-Quotes     07-09 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Politics-Quotes,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quotes From the Presidential Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some comments Friday from the presidential campaign trail: <PERSON> GEORGE </PERSON> <PERSON> BUSH </PERSON>, saying the timing his appearance at a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> fundraiser in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> is n't aimed at the Democrats: `` We are not going to rain on their parade. That is not to say we're not praying for rain.'' <PERSON> PAUL </PERSON> <PERSON> KIRK </PERSON>, Democratic party chairman, suggesting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may have violated the law by using tax money for campaign trips: `` The only thing that matches the hypocrisy of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of the 1980s claiming to be the party of fiscal conservatism is the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of the 1980s preaching about law and order.'' <PERSON> MICHAEL </PERSON> <PERSON> DUKAKIS </PERSON>, appearing in <LOCATION> Texarkana </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, asked whether <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> might be more valuable remaining in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> than joining him on the Democratic ticket: `` I'm pondering He could make a great contribution in this county in many, many ways. He already has.'' <PERSON> JESSE </PERSON> <PERSON> JACKSON </PERSON>, on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s recent pledge to appoint a Hispanic to his Cabinet if elected president: `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> came through here the other day talking about his conversion to a new religion _ respecting Hispanics is a new religion of his.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GreatLakes-Drought     07-09 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Great Lakes-Drought,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Urge Reagan to Divert Water from Great Lakes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Falling water levels on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> that have stranded barges are threatening to trigger a regional water fight on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, pitting southern senators and others against Great Lakes lawmakers. On Friday, Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Tenn </LOCATION>., asked President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for an emergency diversion of water from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> and 12 other senators urged <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in a letter to direct the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> to increase the flow of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> water to the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Waterway </LOCATION> and the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> from 3,000 to 10,000 cubic feet per second for 100 days. The action triggered immediate opposition from several <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> lawmakers led by Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, who said it would be illegal unless approved by all the Great Lakes governors. And in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, Justice Minister <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Hnatyshyn </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s ambassador in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gotlieb </PERSON>, would deliver a formal notice to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> saying that <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> is unalterably opposed to any diversion. <PERSON> Hnatyshyn </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> can veto any diversion proposal as a result of several treaties. `` We control our resources,'' he said. `` We will continue to control our resources.'' <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> said the drought has pushed water levels on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> three feet lower than they have been since 1872, when officials first began keeping records. As many as 3,000 barges are stranded, with the loss to the barge and towing industry possibly exceeding $ 60 million, he said. `` Communities along the river face the prospects of drinking water shortages and drinking water pollution because of the drought,'' said <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>. He said the diversion would raise the level of the river by one foot in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and six inches in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and only lower the level of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huron </LOCATION> by one inch. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said the Great Lakes states are hurting as well. He said Great Lakes water levels have fallen two feet in the past 18 months and are likely to continue to fall. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> also said any action to divert the water would be illegal because the 1986 Water Resources Development Act bars diversion unless it is approved by all of the Great Lakes governors. Also, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has set a limit on how much water can be diverted without its permission. <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> said he believes the president has the authority to take the action as commander in chief in a national emergency. Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., said corps officials he has talked to do not believe they have the legal authority to take the action or that it would do much good He said they believe that reducing the loads of barges would be more effective. Lake levels have dropped by 30 inches in the past two years, said Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich. Added Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., `` Diversion of water from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> into the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> may damage navigation, hydroelectric generation and the environment Signing the letter to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> urging the diversion were <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON> and Sens. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, D-Ark., <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., <PERSON> Mitch </PERSON> <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stennis </PERSON>, D-Miss., <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, D-La., <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky., <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., <PERSON> John </PERSON> Others joining <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> in speaking against the action were Sens. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FiresRdp 3rdLd_Writethru a0940 07-09 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fires Rdp, 3rd Ld _ Writethru, a0940,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aided by Weather, Firefighters Hope to Gain Ground on Black Hills
Blaze</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 11 grafs to UPDATE with rain, new acreage total,
new containment estimate in South Dakota. Picks up 12th graf `In
Alaska.'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHET BROKAW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CUSTER, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters battling a 5-day-old, 16,500-acre blaze near <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rushmore </LOCATION> National Memorial finally had the weather on their side Friday as they worked to reinforce existing fire lines before digging new ones. Brief late-afternoon thundershowers pelted parts of the fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, including the southwestern side considered the most serious problem area. `` This southern portion of the fire got dumped on pretty good,'' said fire information officer <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON>. `` We do n't think the whole fire got rained on.'' Rainfall amounts were not known, but firefighters getting ready to go on the night shift were smiling during a 30-minute thundershower and hail storm. Earlier, <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Neill </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the showers helped lower the temperature and raise the humidity, but also could bring stronger winds and the possibility of lightning. Lightning is believed to have started the fire Monday night in <LOCATION> Custer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. It spread Wednesday into the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, site of the memorial to four presidents. Friday afternoon, flames jumped a highway and 30 families were ordered to evacuate. The blaze could be contained by Sunday night if the weather holds, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Homann </PERSON>, a spokesman for the state Division of Forestry. In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, meanwhile, 32 fires burned, four of which had consumed more than 290,000 acres. Fires also burned on in drought-parched timber and grassland in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> fire threatened <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rushmore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> and the town of <ORGANIZATION> Keystone </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday night, but it stopped short of the tourist stops, both of which had been evacuated. <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rushmore </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Keystone </ORGANIZATION> were reopened Thursday, but Custer State Park remained off-limits. The fire had burned an estimated 16,500 acres by late Friday. Seventeen miles of fire line had been built and 64 percent of the perimeter had been contained, <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON> said. The cost to fight the fire so far is $ 361,000, and it could cost $ 1 million when all the expenses are tallied, <PERSON> Homann </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, a blaze that had come within 10 miles of the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pipeline </LOCATION> was held in check for a second day. <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s major fires are a 126,000-acre blaze 15 miles north of <LOCATION> Livengood </LOCATION>; a 40,000-acre fire near <LOCATION> Ambler </LOCATION>; a 53,000-acre fire northeast of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yukon </LOCATION>; and a 51,000-acre fire north of Central Elsewhere: _ In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, three fires in the <ORGANIZATION> Bridger-Teton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> totaling nearly 1,500 acres were spreading firefighters thin in the rough terrain Although one of the fires was only three acres, officials warned that it had to potential to rapidly become a major blaze. The fire near <LOCATION> Pinedale </LOCATION>, at 1,300 acres by far the largest of the three, was declared controlled Friday morning. Firefighters working on a 1,650-acre fire in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Shoshone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> continued mop-up work, and state Forestry Division crews contained fires covering almost 2,000 acres in <LOCATION> Converse </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Weston </LOCATION> counties. _ A wind-whipped fire in Echo Canyon in northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> doubled in size overnight to about 650 acres, but fire bosses were optimistic it would be contained late Friday, said <ORGANIZATION> Interagency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> Firefighters controlled both the 900-acre blaze in Zion National Park and a 3,500-acre fire near the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> border. _ A 1,000-acre timberland fire near <LOCATION> Nixonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, that jumped plowed fire lines in five places Thursday was declared contained Friday Two water bucket-equipped helicopters helped contain the blaze, which began Wednesday on land owned by <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CaribbeanLeaders     07-09 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Caribbean Leaders,0512</SECOND>
<HEAD>Caribbean Leaders Say US Drug Fight Should Not Interfere In Region</HEAD>
<HEAD>By HELEN J. SIMON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ST. JOHN'S, Antigua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The leaders of 13 Caribbean nations have accused the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> of interfering in their region's affairs as it cracks down on drugs and urged President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to halt the meddling. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Caricom </ORGANIZATION> _ the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Community </LOCATION> and Common Market _ ended five days of talks Friday without agreeing on <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s coup but they agreed to work toward eliminating obstacles to regional trade by Oct. 1. The leaders drafted a letter to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> saying that the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was overstepping its jurisdiction by investigating alleged drug traffickers in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. The contents of the letter were not revealed, but <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION> Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> said it would be signed by the <ORGANIZATION> Caricom </ORGANIZATION> secretary general to represent all the leaders. Bird announced it would protest what the leaders considered a `` derogation'' of their local laws and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> violations of their sovereignty as the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration seeks to win favor in an election year. Some of the leaders criticized <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> for making the announcement prematurely. Prime Minister <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Grenadines </ORGANIZATION> said it was `` bad manners.'' Others stressed their traditionally close ties with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and said it had not intervened directly in their affairs. Bird, reading from a communique drafted by the leaders, said they also `` reaffirmed their total commitment to the fight against ... all illegal trafficking in drugs.'' `` They expressed their willingness to ccoperate with other countries for the establishment of internationally acceptable mechanisms to bring offenders to justice,'' he said. The <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> has long been a source and an important conduit for drugs coming into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Cocaine from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> traditionaly passes through <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> ports before entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Much marijuana is also grown in the area. From the start of the meeting Monday, it was apparent the leaders were unlikely to reach unanimous agreement, as required by <ORGANIZATION> Caricom </ORGANIZATION> rules, on what position to take on the <LOCATION> Haitian </LOCATION> military government that ousted President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> in a coup June 19. They debated options ranging from revoking <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s status as an observer on four <ORGANIZATION> Caricom </ORGANIZATION> standing committees to simply issuing a strong statement denouncing the coup. The leaders were more successful when talking about intra-regional trade. The leaders agreed to remove all trade obstacles, such as stamp duties and import licenses, by Oct. 1 and to study a request by the smaller countries to protect 23 items they consider too fragile to compete with imports. Trade and industry ministers will meet before the Oct. 1 deadline to decide which items should be excluded and for how long. <ORGANIZATION> Caricom </ORGANIZATION>, established in 1973 to promote regional trade and set common positions on international events, includes <LOCATION> Antigua-Barbuda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barbados </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montserrat </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kitts-Nevis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lucia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Grenadines </ORGANIZATION> and Trinidad-Tobago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--DrunkenPilot     07-09 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Drunken Pilot,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helicopter Pilot Was Drunk Before Deadly Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of two pilots of a West German army helicopter that crashed in the Alps and killed all nine people aboard was drunk at the time, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said. Five civilians, the three-man crew and another West German soldier were killed when the Bell UH-1-D helicopter smashed into a cliff in the Bavarian Alps on Sunday. The ministry said Friday that one of the two dead pilots was found to have had a blood alcohol content of .25 percent. It did not say which pilot was operating the aircraft at the time of the crash. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a blood alcohol content of around .1 percent is considered drunk. A blood alcohol content of .25 is considered very drunk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DramaticRescue     07-09 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dramatic Rescue,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cruise Ship Officer Rescues Woman From Drowning</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Sylvie Mullaly and Lars Kragelund are cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NAN HERLIHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cruise ship officer stripped to his shorts and leapt more than 50-feet into choppy night seas to rescue a drowning woman, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The woman either fell or jumped off the Scandinavian Sky cruise ship 11 miles east of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> Thursday night, said Petty Officer <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sylvie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullaly </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Cocoa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, and her rescuer, Staff Capt. <PERSON> Lars </PERSON> <PERSON> Kragelund </PERSON>, were treated and released from <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> following the ships return, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Mullaly </PERSON>, who works at a topless nightclub in <LOCATION> Cocoa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, is under investigation for possible intoxication, <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said. An investigation of the entire incident, including the ship's safety procedures, is underway, he said. Ms. <PERSON> Mullaly </PERSON> was spotted bobbing in the water as the ship returned from a daylong cruise, <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kragelund </PERSON> raced from the ship's wheelhouse, peeling off his uniform as he ran and dived from a ship's rail, he said. As he swam to the woman, the ship's crew assumed `` man overboard'' alert stations and the vessel swung in a wide circle around the couple, <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said. `` Apparently they were retrieved from the water via ladder. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> headed to the scene but turned back when we found out they had her'' out of the water, he said. The Scandinavian Sky is owned by Miami-based <ORGANIZATION> Sea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Escape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION> and registered in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> reports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe Bjt   07-09 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe, Bjt,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Looking Into Whether Paisley Took Bribes In Navy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Court papers have revealed for the first time that federal agents are looking at whether one of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s former top officials accepted bribes while he helped direct President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s defense buildup. A search warrant used by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> in the June 14 search of defense consultant <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s home in nearby <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said agents sought details about `` payment from <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Paisley </LOCATION> in the form of checks, gifts or other forms of remuneration, or to his wife, <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON>'' at the time he was an assistant <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary. Another entry states agents wanted information about `` payments or gratuities from <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> employees to Paisley'' before he left the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in March 1987. <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> is a division of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. As an assistant <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> secretary between 1981 and 1987, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, 63, played a key role in guiding the enhancement of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> under then-Navy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. A former executive at the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> left government to become a <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> has surfaced as a key figure in the investigation into allegations that defense contractors and consultants, many of them former military men, bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials for contracting details that could be vital in winning contracts worth billions of dollars. To date, no one has been charged in the case. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported today that the unnamed informer referred to in an early government affidavit who helped investigators launch the probe is a retired <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> major who is now serving a prison sentence for child molestation. The Post, quoting unnamed sources, said consultant <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlowe </PERSON> offered inside information on Marine contracts to a defense firm and later agreed to cooperate with government investigators and secretly tape his conversations with other consultants. <PERSON> Marlowe </PERSON>, 45, is serving a six-year sentence at a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> state prison for his 1985 conviction on charges of indecent exposure and aggravated sexual battery in cases involving two girls aged nine and 10, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s house was one of as many as 40 premises across the nation searched on June 14, the day the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> revealed the existence of the investigation of alleged massive corruption in the $ 150 billion-a-year <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> purchasing system. The search warrant, which was released by a magistrate's clerk in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> also sought evidence that <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> gave <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>, a deputy assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, a Western painting titled `` Lonesome Whistle.'' They also sought evidence that <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> or fellow consultant <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> provided gratuities to <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>, including `` money to <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON>' companies, entertainment tickets, and tires.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> documents showed the government is investigating <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s work as a consultant to 10 defense contractors and disclosed the names of several <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees, or former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> employees, whose contacts with <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> are being investigated. The warrant sought any document `` establishing an employee or contractual relationship'' between <LOCATION> Paisley </LOCATION> and these 10 companies: <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> BDM </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> EMS </ORGANIZATION>, Pocal, <ORGANIZATION> Ball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Norden </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>. Agents are looking at <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s efforts to obtain government contracts for them from 1981 through 1988. Among the people mentioned specifically in the warrant was a person identified as <PERSON> Rumpf </PERSON>. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumpf </PERSON>, the principal deputy assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for research, engineering and systems, was <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s deputy in the Pentagon His wife, <PERSON> Lenore </PERSON>, works for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rumpf </PERSON> did not return a telephone call to his office Friday. Also mentioned was <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, a former deputy assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> who now works for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> said she would have no comment. <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> has not commented on the probe, but his attorney, <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON>, has criticized leaks of information about the probe and has dismissed the allegations as `` garbage.'' Of interest to investigators is <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s involvement _ both in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and as a consultant _ in the <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION>, one of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s biggest procurement programs. <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> are partners in the $ 4 billion program awarded last year to build the new aircraft. In another instance, the government searched for evidence that <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> supported <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> for the `` JVX project and V-22 engine,'' and `` payments or gratuities from <LOCATION> Pratt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> employees to <LOCATION> Paisley </LOCATION> during his tenure as assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s involvement with foreign concerns also was targeted in the search warrant. Investigators sought information about <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s involvement with the <ORGANIZATION> Mazlat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> company. In 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> awarded a $ 26 million contract to consortium comprised of <LOCATION> Mazlat </LOCATION> and the American <ORGANIZATION> AAI </ORGANIZATION> corporation to build three remotely piloted vehicles, known as drones. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> sought several items dealing with <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION>, the St. Louis-based defense contractor. The company supplies American forces with helicopters and fighter planes, and is involved in efforts to sell advanced fighter aircraft to several nations. An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> list of items seized by agents at the <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s home included tax returns, bank account numbers, <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>'s security badge from <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> and a `` confidential 12 pg memo re visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had no reaction to the revelations. `` We have it in hand and are studying it,'' he said. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Spivak </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION>, said the company `` knows of no payment of bribes by this company or any of its people'' to <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> or his wife while <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> was in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> or in private life. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Linse </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON>, said he could not comment because he had not seen the warrant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Edwards     07-09 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Edwards,0221</SECOND>
<HEAD>Popular British Comedian And Actor Jimmy Edwards Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, the mustachioed radio and television actor who kept Britons laughing in the dark days of food rationing after World War II, has died, his brother <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. He was 68. The comedian died Thursday of bronchial pneumonia in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Cromwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> He had been ill for several weeks after returning from a show business tour in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, his brother said. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> was famed for his huge 11-inch-long mustache, burly frame and gravelly voice. After the war, <PERSON> Edward </PERSON>'s starring role in the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s radio series `` Take It From Here'' ran for 11 years. He appeared in several plays in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s West End theaterland and gave a memorable performance in the 1956 movie version of <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON>'s classic comic novel `` Three Men in a Boat'' about a trip up the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION> in a rowboat in the 1880s. During the war, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> flew with the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and won the Distinguished Flying Cross, one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s highest awards for flying bravery. In 1962, he tried to become a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> legislator for the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> but was narrowly defeated. In 1959, he married actress <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> but they were divorced 11 years later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0319EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Airliner-Vincennes     07-09 0763</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airliner-Vincennes,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Cruiser Had Radar Malfunction In June</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Airliner Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> missile cruiser that shot down an Iranian passenger jet it mistook for a fighter plane was out of action last month because its radar malfunctioned, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. But a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the breakdown on the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincennes </ORGANIZATION> in June was only a `` minor degradation'' and had no bearing on Sunday's disaster that left 290 dead in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say the billion-dollar warship's high-tech radar system received signals from the <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airbus </ORGANIZATION> A300 identifying it as an Iranian F-14 fighter coming in for an attack. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said all 290 people aboard were killed. The breakdown was reported on June 13 by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, although gulf-based <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials refused then to confirm that the problem lay in the computerized system, called Aegis. The Aegis system of computer-linked radar and weapons is designed primarily for defending a naval fleet in the open ocean from air and missile attack. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> says it can detect, identify and head off a threat developing hundreds of miles away. The 9,600-ton <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> arrived in the gulf May 27, the first of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Aegis cruisers to be assigned to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval force in the waterway. It was assigned to patrol in the southern gulf, but by about June 10 it was anchored off <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sources said it was undergoing repair work on the radar system that lies at the core of its capabilities. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in the gulf, asked about the reported breakdown at that time, said only that the ship was in port for `` maintenance upkeep,'' the result of an unspecified problem. Officials here refused comment Friday, but a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, Lt. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Cullin </PERSON>, confirmed the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> had been down with a `` minor degradation'' of its radar system. He said there was no connection between that and the shooting down of the Iranian jetliner. `` The problem had absolutely no bearing on the whole incident,'' he said in a telephone interview. `` It -LRB- the cruiser -RRB- was never less than 100 percent up on any mission capability, including anti-aircraft warfare.'' He said he could not confirm that the ship was out of action for 16 days, as reported by the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cullin </PERSON> said the problem had actually been detected during the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>' 32-day voyage from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, where it arrived May 22. A necessary replacement part was flown to the ship and installed by the ship's own crew, he said, `` and the ship was back up on line by June 6.'' He said he did not know why the ship was then off the line again, spending at least three days around June 10-13 at anchor outside <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, before it returned to its duty station in the southern gulf. Some of the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>' crew said they were puzzled why the ship had been ordered to make a rush departure from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> after only 90 hours of port preparation, and on arrival spent five days in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, `` sailing in circles'' as one officer described it, before entering the Strait of <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>. Many <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships, especially those with sophisticated electronics and other equipment, have civlian experts, known as `` tech reps,'' aboard to maintain and repair the gear. Most are employees of the manufacturers. There were no such representatives aboard the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>. Its officers told journalists who rode the ship into the gulf that the crew was fully capable of maintaining and repairing the ship's complicated systems The <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> was riding at anchor off <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> for a third day Friday, but two other warships that contributed data to the investigation of the jetliner incident, the frigate <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> and the missile frigate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sides </PERSON>, returned to duty in the gulf. Both had been nearby when the aircraft was shot down. The disaster followed a clash involving the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Elmer </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> and some Iranian speedboats, two of which were sunk, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said. Computer tapes from the warships are being sent back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for analysis at the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Surface warfare Center in <LOCATION> Dahlgren </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources said they could offer no indication of when a team of six military investigators sent here to investigate the incident would complete their task and return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> The team, headed by Rear Adm. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogarty </PERSON>, arrived here on Tuesday with orders to deliver a report in 15 days if possible.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880709-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-09-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Haiti Bjt   07-09 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Haiti, Bjt,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Namphy Voids Haitian Constitution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
