<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Cuomo-Endorsement 1stLd-Writethru a0754 04-06 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuomo-Endorsement, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0754,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Interest Builds In Possible Cuomo Endorsement</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 3 grafs after 4th graf pvs, bgng: ``He gets, with
Cuomo comment in Washington Post interview</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARC HUMBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> is being courted by candidates and pursued by the press as curiosity mounts over whether he will endorse anyone before his state's important April 19 presidential primary. <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s closest advisers insisted Wednesday that they did n't know when or even whether the inscrutable governor would give his blessing to one of the Democrats competing for the party's `` They've made it clear both publicly and privately they want his endorsement,'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> press secretary <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> said of the candidates. `` But at this point nothing has changed, despite the 4,000 phone calls we got.'' `` He gets a constant stream of calls from the various candidates,'' said <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> political adviser <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON> <PERSON> Frucher </PERSON>. `` Obviously, the front-runners have always wanted him to endorse and the others try to keep him from endorsing.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said in an interview published in Thursday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that he has not ruled out endorsing someone, but added, `` The closer you get to primary day, the less reason'' there is to do so. The newspaper quoted the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> governor as saying he preferred to remain neutral until after the final primaries and then back the leader. `` That's the time for leadership in this process,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, fresh from twin victories this week in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, is seeking to solidify his front-runner status _ and clear his path to the nomination _ with another win over <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, for his part, is making a major effort in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to succeed outside his native South. He has not won a contest in a month and is no longer eligible for federal matching funds. There are two reasons candidates are eager for <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s endorsement First, the governor supported <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> in the 1984 election and, with the <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> team running his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> campaign, <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> scored a major victory. Second, and perhaps even more important to this year's candidates, a <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> endorsement would reduce speculation that the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> governor is angling for the nomination himself from a deadlocked national convention and that he might be an available alternative for Democrats <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> set off a new round of speculation Tuesday when, asked about a possible <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> endorsement, he chuckled and told reporters in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> that he planned to `` talk to you tomorrow.'' But on Wednesday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he had nothing new to report. `` I'd like to have it -LRB- <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s endorsement -RRB-. He knows that. But it's his decision to make,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` This is getting to be kind of fun,'' <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> said of the interest over what <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> will do. `` Yesterday, we were inundated with a wave of early morning ` he's going to go with the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION>' calls, all out of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Then, a little bit later in the day, there was a wave of ` he's going with <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>' calls out of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> aides and advisers said the candidates were treating <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> carefully, perhaps even warily, in seeking his backing. `` They're not pressuring the governor in any sense of the word,'' insisted <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, the governor's son and chief political adviser. `` This is one guy that is not susceptible to pressure,'' <PERSON> Fryer </PERSON> added. `` If anything, pressure with <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> is counterproductive.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> and the candidates are all expected to appear separately Thursday at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> meeting of about 300 members of the state <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The candidates will be making individual pitches to the Democratic officials, and <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> could use the opportunity to make a dramatic endorsement. While the governor's political advisers said they doubted that would happen, they said they did expect him to again stress that he does not intend to become a candidate and that there should not be a convention draft. Thus far, <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has refused to completely rule out accepting a convention draft, although he's said it wo n't happen and should n't happen He has maintained that should be enough of a disclaimer to satisfy everyone. `` He'll reinforce that people should not wait for him to endorse,'' said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> of his father's expected advice to fellow <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Democrats. `` He'll say again what he's said before: ` I'm not interested in running myself.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Oscars-BestActress     04-06 0826</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Oscars-Best Actress,0841</SECOND>
<HEAD>OSCAR COUNTDOWN: Best Actress</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>60th Academy Awards: The Year Of The Actress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>' 60th awards might well be termed the Year of the Actress, so impressive are the candidates for best performance by an actress in 1987. After being overshadowed for a few decades by macho stars, film actresses are now having powerful roles fashioned for them. This year's nominees afford proof: <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, the perplexed widow of `` Moonstruck''; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON>, the vengeful spurned lover in `` Fatal Attraction''; <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, the dynamic news producer of `` Broadcast News''; <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, the faded Czech actress, `` Anna''; and Meryl Streep, the down-and-out ex-singer in `` Ironweed.'' Adding to their impressive number are performances that many felt warranted Academy consideration: <PERSON> Lillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Gish </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, `` The Whales of August''; <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Miles </PERSON>, `` Hope and Glory''; <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, `` The Lonely Passion of <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearn </PERSON>''; <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Lahti </PERSON>, `` Housekeeping''; <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunaway </PERSON>, `` Barfly''; Barbra Streisand, `` Nuts''; <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON>, `` The Glass Menagerie.'' <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> has been drawing the most attention among the nominees, attracting a media broadside of amazing proportions. The one-time member of the <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> singing team is justifiably proud of her performance in `` Moonstruck'' and has been willing to talk about it. `` ` Moonstruck' is the first movie of mine that I ever watched without wanting to throw up,'' she says. `` I was in love with the story; it's my best work since ` Mask.' `` Usually everyone's first choice is Meryl -LRB- Streep -RRB- and then so-and-so and then so-and-so. It's something to start being someone's first choice. ... <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> has clout, you know. Barbra Streisand has clout. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> has clout. I think relative to them, I'm a newcomer. ... I'm not working my way toward power. I'm working my way toward the best roles I can get.'' Equally voluble is <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, who won the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> as best dramatic actress for `` <PERSON> Anna </PERSON>.'' She has been enjoying her success after years of trying: `` I have tested for the leading role in 25 movies, and each time the choice has narrowed to another actress and myself. Each time the other actress won.'' The actress campaigned for the role in the low-budget film, studying the Czech accent and absorbing the atmosphere of the emigre community in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. She even added 15 pounds and taped her face to create wrinkles. Does she want the Oscar? `` I can not tell a lie; my fantasy ever since I was 5 years old has been to hold that -LRB- statue -RRB- and say, ` Thank-you, thank-you, thank-you.''' <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, hailed as a bright new star because of `` Broadcast News,'' has been as silent as <LOCATION> Kirkland </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> have been vocal. She declined most interviews, arguing that she was too involved with the <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> play, `` A Lie of the Mind,'' at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' Mark Taper Theater Director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> predicts the Georgia-born actress `` will be around for decades.'' Of his script she commented: `` I loved it; I thought it was remarkably three-dimensional.'' She also talked about the differences between herself and the news producer she portrays: `` <PERSON> Holly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> is certainly less driven than <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>. I think that my priorities are quite a bit different, in that I'm probably retty obsessed myself, but not to such a manic degree.'' After three supporting-actress nominations in six film roles, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Close </PERSON> broke through in the starring category with `` Fatal Attraction.'' She terms the demonic <PERSON> Alix </PERSON> the first woman she's played `` who is out of control, who emotionally runs the gamut _ the first real, full-blooded role I've had. Her comment on the huge reaction to `` Fatal Attraction'': `` The whole male-female thing in this country is very volatile right now. I think many women are feeling used by men. They invest a lot in a relationship, in nurturing a man emotionally and in his career, but they have their own careers and emotions, and they do n't get that nurturing in return.'' After playing a number of glamorous roles, two-time Oscar winner <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> found her role as the derelict in `` Ironweed'' had its advantages: `` In this world of purgatory of the soul, there are very few markers to go by. I liked that about her. I liked not having to worry about how I looked and being able to strip away, strip away everying, except what counts.'' Streep has created a series of indelible performances, including Oscar winners in `` <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>'' and `` <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON>'s Choice,'' as well as `` The Deer Hunter'' and `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' She remains ambitious: `` There's so much I'd like to do. When the public is used to you in heavy drama, it's hard to make them take you seriously. But I want to play comedy. `` I ca n't stand it that stage fright inhibits me. At some point I'm going to face up and do a play. But for now I just go day to day.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-RatPack     04-06 0412</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Rat Pack,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sinatra, Sammy Davis Swing Radio City</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> called himself and <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` the <LOCATION> Springsteen </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> of the Geritol set'' Wednesday night as they launched into a `` Guys and Dolls'' medley, the encore in their Rat Pack show. Radio City Music Hall was n't exactly rocking, but it was swinging. The 6,000-seat hall was sold out, with a top ticket price of $ 75. `` Let's not overdo it,'' <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> cautioned as <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, making use of a new hip replacement, did a few dance steps during the encore, `` because I'm tired of working alone.'' <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had embarked with his old <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> buddies on the so-called Rat Pack tour earlier this year but has been sidelined in recent weeks by kidney problems. `` We check with him every day,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> assured the crowd. `` He is cooking; he'll be back to work soon.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, as thin as <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> used to be, did the first 40 minutes of the two-hour show. He really sang jazz, and sometimes seemed to be trying to pull the 37-piece band's ponderous arrangements up to his swinging tempo. He had listeners' fingers snapping to `` Satin Doll,'' inserted little jokes into the lyrics of `` The Lady Is a Tramp,'' put powerful emotion into `` What Kind of Fool Am I?'' and `` Birth of the Blues'' and made `` Mr. <PERSON> Bojangles </PERSON>'' into a one-act play. He was never slick. <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>'s voice sometimes has a frayed edge but his masterful phrasing and timing of pithy asides are intact. More important, his vocal timbre _ the thing that makes one know it's <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and not <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Damone </PERSON> or somebody else _ is still there. He sang the `` Soliloquy'' from `` Carousel'' and the audience exploded in applause. In it, he did some of his best singing of the evening. The audience also seemed to appreciate his ambition in choosing this high-quality, lengthy musical passage. Even better moments were <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>'s hard-swinging `` Mack the Knife'' and `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'' and the all-time saloon song, `` One More for the Road,'' which he has sung many times but this time also acted. When <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> harmonized beautifully on the final lines of `` The Oldest Established Permanent Floating Crap Game in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' you knew you'd been thoroughly entertained. On their final night in town, Sunday, the Geritol boys will be joined by <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> in a benefit for cancer research.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RIsforRitalinIII-Clinic     04-06 0992</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-R Is for Ritalin III-Clinic,1013</SECOND>
<HEAD>`R' Is for Ritalin</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part III: Inside a Ritalin Clinic _ One Girl's Journey</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Ritalin III-School</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Daily doses of the drug Ritalin are increasingly the treatment of choice for children diagnosed with attention deficit disorder. Not surprisingly, more and more clinics are specializing in such diagnosis and treatment. And schools are often enthusiastic about Ritalin's success. Two stories offer inside looks at one such clinic, where an 11-year-old girl learned she would begin what might be years of Ritalin therapy, and at a school where teachers credit Ritalin with helping children conquer their emotional and academic despair. A third story looks at <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, the state with the youngest population, a reputation for moral conservatism _ and the highest per capita use of Ritalin in the nation.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Her school principal had urged her mother to make the four-hour drive from rural northern <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. Now 11-year-old <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> sat in a tiny, windowless office where a psychologist peppered her with questions. The morning would end with doctors at the Attention Deficit Disorder Clinic of Children's Hospital telling <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> her baffling problems at home and in school would mean treatment with the stimulant Ritalin, quite likely for years. But first doctors tested Chrissie: spelling tests, math tests, reading tests, questions about her family life. They probed her moods, whether she ever felt like committing suicide -LRB- `` once or twice,'' she said. -RRB- They examined her school grades, read reports from teachers. They even had <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>, a sliver-thin, pretty girl with straight blond hair, draw a picture of herself. The 2-inch-high sketch spoke volumes to the psychologist about the youngster's poor self-image. Finally the psychologist asked <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> for three wishes. `` A horse ranch,'' the girl said after several moments. `` A happy life. And people who care who can help me through this tough time. `` I have n't really been happy since I was 2 or so. I yell at my parents. Later I wish I had n't done it. They're very good to me. So I have n't had a very happy life.'' <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>, which is not the girl's real name, indeed had many problems, the doctors concluded. But she hardly fit the popular, often mistaken, stereotype of children who take Ritalin. First, boys are eight times more likely than girls to be diagnosed as having ADD. Second, <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> was n't `` bouncing off the walls.'' In fact, many youngsters recommended for Ritalin treatment are not discipline problems and appear calm in most situations. <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>, said psychologist <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Robin </PERSON>, is `` a classic case of a kid whose ADD was not caught as a young kid.'' Pre-adolescents and teen-agers who unexplainedly struggle with school for years often arrive at ADD clinics deeply depressed as a result of their attention problems. The key was her inability to complete tasks and concentrate. Tests suggested she was weak in math, easily frustrated, dangerously depressed, and had a poor self-image. <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> knows she has troubles. `` I have quite a problem paying attention in school. I've had it since kindergarten,'' she told a visitor in a brief break from testing. `` I sometimes just have to get out of my seat. I go to the drinking fountain, and I'm not even thirsty. It's weird. `` If I have a problem, I'd really like to know about it.'' Fewer than 100 such ADD clinics operate around the country, according to <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>, a psychologist who heads one at <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Nearly all start with the assumption that ADD is essentially a physiological disease that in most cases can be treated chemically Some clinics simply juggle prescriptions, using placebos and Ritalin or other stimulant drugs alternately to find the most effective treatment. They leave the followup and monitoring to others, often the family pediatrician. Others, like the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> clinic, employ pediatricians, psychologists and social workers to look at the child in totality. That means that counseling and changes in lessons or surroundings are often part of the treatment. But at the heart of these clinics is the conviction that Ritalin therapy helps most patients. Since it opened in September 1986, the ADD Clinic here has examined some 600 patients and has a three-month waiting list, said Dr. <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenner </PERSON>, a pediatrician and co-director of the clinic. At least three-quarters were diagnosed as having ADD, and about 85 percent of those were placed on medication, usually Ritalin. Once treatment begins, doctors rely on teacher questionnaires, report cards and parents to monitor whether Ritalin is helping the child in school and whether it is having side effects. <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>'s teacher wrote this description of her on a Conners Questionnaire, the standardized form used to evaluate children suspected of having attention deficit disorder: `` <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> is not a behavior problem,'' her teacher wrote. `` I just do not have her attention 90 percent of the time. ... On the day we had our first bit of snow last fall, I was trying to help her understand something. She looked at me and smiled, saying ` I wonder what my kitten thinks of snow? She never saw it before.' Sometimes it seems her mind is way off somewhere else.'' <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> and her mother sat expressionless as the doctors later told them that Ritalin and psychological counseling `` should make a difference.'' Her mother expressed mild surprise over the prescription. `` Ritalin has a bad name,'' she said after the doctors had left the room. `` I was somewhat surprised because I associated Ritalin with hyperactivity.'' How is <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON> doing? After six weeks of Ritalin and counseling, <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>'s teachers told doctors she had shown mild improvement in attention span and a marked improvement in her ability to sit still and stick to school work. Even with an increase in dosage, to 30 milligrams a day, she has exhibited no side effects. Progress, but no quick miracles, then, for <PERSON> Chrissie </PERSON>. The Ritalin therapy continues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RIsforRitalinIII-School     04-06 0863</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-R Is for Ritalin III-School,0881</SECOND>
<HEAD>`R' Is for Ritalin</HEAD>
<HEAD>Part III: At One Elementary School, They `Work Magic' With Ritalin</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report; Recommended for side-by-side
use with PM-R Is for Ritalin III-Clinic</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WEST BIRMINGHAM, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Easton </PERSON>'s pupils takes the drug Ritalin to calm his hyperactivity and help him pay attention. She challenged a visitor to guess who. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> was the obvious choice. Seated with three other boys at a semicircular desk in a special education class at <ORGANIZATION> Scotch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, the third-grader fidgeted in his chair, got up several times to sharpen his pencil, drummed his fingers, asked questions repeatedly and never seemed to hear the answers. The guess was wrong. Instead, the child on Ritalin was a slender boy with flaming red hair who calmly sailed through a reading comprehension quiz and listened attentively to a lesson on homonyms. <PERSON> Easton </PERSON> says he's doing so well he probably will leave handicapped classes forever in the fall. At Scotch Elementary, they believe in <LOCATION> Ritalin </LOCATION> _ and teachers point to cases like these to vindicate their faith in the controversial drug. Far from thinking Ritalin creates passive `` zombies,'' as some critics have charged, teachers and parents alike in this affluent northwest <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> suburb seem convinced of Ritalin's track record for turning emotional and academic despair into success. Grades and attention span often improve, and some youngsters who might have spent entire school careers isolated in classes for the disabled have managed to rejoin their regular peers with the help of the drug. Most of all, teachers like <ORGANIZATION> Easton </ORGANIZATION> resent the assertion by some that Ritalin is merely a cynical way for schools to silence problem children while claiming they are trying to help them. `` I read that this is the way we treat kids we ca n't handle. It's not true. It's just not true,'' said <PERSON> Easton </PERSON>, whose daughter has taken the drug for four years. While an estimated 1-2 percent of the nation's 40 million schoolchildren take Ritalin, Dr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wender </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> psychiatrist and author of several books on attention deficit disorder, or ADD, believes 3-to-10 percent of all children have hyperactivity problems. At Scotch Elementary, approximately 5 percent of the 550 pupils drop by principal <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Childress </PERSON>'s office each day to take a pill. Several elements help explain why Ritalin is commonplace at Scotch Elementary; teachers and school administrators have attended seminars and taken other training to recognize symptoms of ADD. Area doctors are not only willing to prescribe Ritalin but also to work with teachers and schools to monitor its success. And parents generally seem to accept the professionalism, good faith and judgment of the teachers and doctors. `` When you first start talking to parents about this, they're devastated,'' said principal <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Childress </PERSON> `` Then 90 percent react that it is a medical problem.'' <PERSON> Childress </PERSON> tells of a youngster named <PERSON> George </PERSON> who has taken Ritalin for two years. He had been assigned to a `` resource room,'' where handicapped children get individual instruction for part of each day. `` He had an incident every day of losing his temper, punching someone or screaming in vile terms,'' said <PERSON> Childress </PERSON>. `` Now he's out of special education He's a winner.'' <PERSON> Childress </PERSON>, like other educators, insists `` we never recommend medication.'' But that's only partly true. If the school's psychologist, social worker or reading specialist believes a child has ADD, they know which doctors will nearly always prescribe Ritalin At the top of the list is Dr. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Robin </PERSON>, a pediatrician who operates the <ORGANIZATION> Attention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deficit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Southfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>. Schools from all over <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> recommend her, and prospective patients often wait 6-8 weeks for an appointment She now treats 1,500 youngsters for ADD, some as young as 3. Almost invariably, she prescribes Ritalin or similar medication. `` I work magic with the medicine,'' she said in an interview in her office. `` I'm willing to try things. `` We're talking about large numbers of kids who are getting a bum steer in life, from kindergarten on. Some look like couch potatoes. They do n't all look alike,'' she said. But even Ritalin's advocates admit it is n't always well-monitored. Teachers are supposed to provide crucial information enabling doctors to set the right dosage, or to determine if drugs are necessary at all to academic success. Such monitoring is frequent when medication first begins. After that, `` there really is n't that much to do unless there's a problem,'' the doctor said. <PERSON> Childress </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> and other ADD specialists typically send teachers questionnaires to fill out for the first 2-4 weeks of medication, then gradually less frequently until `` we feel we're on a steady course. At a certain point we step out of the picture unless the teacher notices a problem.'' Still, Ritalin remains a `` last resort,'' said <PERSON> Childress </PERSON>. Teachers might, for example, put distractible children in study carrels _ desks with three sides blocked off so the child ca n't see in front or to either side. But when `` we've exhausted all those things ... logged the classroom observations,'' <PERSON> Childress </PERSON> said, `` we would just as soon get a recommendation to try something else.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Ritalin-Utah     04-06 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ritalin-Utah,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crowded Classrooms, Large Families in No. 1 Ritalin State</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-R Is for Ritalin III</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRED BAYLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>and</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>SCOTT McCARTNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> is a state of large, close-knit families whose religion frowns on the use of liquor and caffeine. It is also a state with the nation's largest appetite for the stimulant drug Ritalin. The <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said that in 1986 pharmacies along the state's <ORGANIZATION> Wasatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> received 25,000 grams of the drug used for hyperactive children, or 1,558 grams for every 100,000 population. That figure compares to 1,218 grams per 100,000 residents of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, the next highest Ritalin state. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the figure was 347 grams per 100,000. The reasons for <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s high use of Ritalin are many. They may point the way for the future in other parts of the country. `` What we are doing here is, in some ways, ahead of many parts of the country,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wender </PERSON>, a psychiatrist and researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> has the youngest population of any state, with nearly a quarter of its residents aged 5 to 17. It also leads the nation in the size of individual families, about 4.3 children per household. Consequently it has the nation's most crowded classrooms with 24.6 students per teacher. Although <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> ranks near the top of the list in the amount of state money, 47 percent, going to education, it is last in per capita spending on education, at $ 2,372 per student. So when the fragile balance in these overcrowded classrooms is threatened by disruptive children, `` the pressures on parents and teachers are going to lead people to look for solutions ... and one of the solutions is medication,'' said <PERSON> Stevan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kukic </PERSON>, state director of special education. In the <ORGANIZATION> Salt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>, an estimated 2 percent of the 60,000 students receive Ritalin or one of its cousins for attention deficit disorder, a syndrome that includes hyperactive as well as inattentive pupils. `` It is becoming more acceptable in the parents' minds and the teachers' minds,'' said <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a special education teacher whose son takes Ritalin. `` When the teachers see the dramatic effect it can have on problem students, they want them medicated so they can learn.'' <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, a psychologist who saw 100 ADD children at his clinic last year, estimates a quarter of his patients are referred by the schools. Another 25 percent come at the suggestion of other parents whose children take Ritalin. Half his patients were sent by pediatricans. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s medical community also contributes to Ritalin use. Reseachers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> are considered leaders in ADD study. Their philosophies are passed on to their students, many of whom later set up practice nearby. As a result, <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> has three clinics that specialize in the diagnosis and treatment of ADD children _ many larger cities across the country have none. Psychologists, psychiatrists and pediatricians share information and refer patients for treatment. `` In a community this size it is easier to make an impact with an idea, especially an idea that appeals to people,'' said <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>. Parents of ADD children describe their successes with Ritalin as more than appealing. <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Miner </PERSON> cries when she talks about the effect Ritalin has had on her 11-year-old son, <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON>. `` There has been such a remarkable change in this child,'' she said. `` From the time he was 7 he talked about suicide. Now he's on the student council and is so thrilled with life.'' Mrs. Miner has joined others in a local support group for ADD parents. The gatherings can be emotional: laughter about the bruises and stitches their children have collected while rocketing around the house, tears as they talk about the difference treatment has brought. `` I wanted to share the knowledge with other families,'' said the group's founder, <PERSON> Terri </PERSON> <PERSON> Steineckert </PERSON>, whose son, <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON>, 11, has taken Ritalin for more than a year. `` It is very traumatic to put a child on drugs, but if you have a good experience, you're converted,'' she said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MayoralMystery     04-06 0605</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mayoral Mystery,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small-Town Mystery: Mayor Resigns But Doesn't Explain</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS G. KATSARELAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAMBERTVILLE, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three months ago, Mayor <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> stopped attending council meetings, changed her phone number and refused to explain why she had forsaken her duties. For the last half-century, Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> had helped run the city as city clerk, treasurer and finally as mayor in a homespun way that endeared her to the townsfolk. But she has announced she will resign April 12, just 19 days short of her 51st anniversary in city government. Council President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McManus </PERSON> said Monday he received Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>'s one-sentence resignation letter. `` I've been kind of expecting it,'' he said. Although Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, 77, has said her doctor has told her to `` take it easy,'' the letter does n't indicate why she is leaving. <PERSON> McManus </PERSON>, the acting mayor, said, `` We know as much now as we did.'' He said the council could choose a successor from a list of three candidates to be submitted by the <ORGANIZATION> Hunterdon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, but he is inclined to leave the seat vacant until the November elections. `` We seem to be doing fine,'' he said. `` I'm certainly happy to fill the void.'' With 3,900 residents, <LOCATION> Lambertville </LOCATION> does n't need a lot of governing. The old mill and ferry town, which spreads along the east bank of the <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, comes to life in the summer when visitors from <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> browse its art galleries, antique shops, quaint cafes, bookstores and magnificent Victorian homes. An 85-year-old, two-lane iron bridge carries cars and pedestrian across the wide, lazy river to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hope </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>'s ties to the town go back several generations She was elected in 1982 and re-elected in 1985, but stopped attending meetings in January, and shows up for work infrequently. She spoke briefly with a reporter one day last month while walking down <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> in town. Asked about her absence, Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> replied: `` Medical problems. Just say I ca n't work because of medical problems.'' `` My doctor says I have to take it easy. Now I do n't want to talk about it anymore.'' With that closing line, she walked briskly across the street and into a five-and-dime. So, townspeople can only speculate about what happened. Some thought it was a political rift over whether to rehire police Chief <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Venettone </PERSON>, who suffered a heart attack last year. The council in January overruled Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> and allowed him to return. Others thought it had roots in the city's fiscal mess. In a 1987 audit, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> concluded that the mayor had taken it upon herself to maintain financial records and payroll documents which the treasurer was required to handle. According to the audit, the minutes of the monthly council meetings were not properly recorded. Vouchers lacked proper signatures and invoices. The treasurer signed blank checks in advance, which is prohibited by the state. `` There was nothing criminal, but there were certain things being done up there that were n't according to <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>,'' said department spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Harpster </PERSON>. `` It was a mom-and-pop operation.'' Since that time, the Council has asserted its independence and some say Ms. <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON> has not taken that well. But no one really knows for sure. What is certain, however, is the lifelong residents hold her in high regard. `` I like her very much,'' said <PERSON> Mabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, 83. `` I always thought she was very nice. She's always good with people of limited incomes.'' `` She's a woman who's cared for the city tremendously,'' added businessman <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Honasan     04-06 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Honasan,0287</SECOND>
<HEAD>Renegade Officer Condemns Aquino, Vows To Pursue Struggle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fugitive leader of a coup attempt last year claims President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> is incapable of ensuring the suvival of the nation and he withdrew a pledge to avoid hostile acts against her government. A statement carrying the signature of former Lt. Col. <PERSON> Gregorio </PERSON> `` Gringo'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, 39, was made available to news organizations Wednesday by sources close to the renegade officer. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> escaped from a prison ship in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> last Saturday. Chief military spokesman Col. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON> said a nationwide search has turned up no trace of him. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> led an attempted coup on Aug. 28 in which at least 53 people were killed. Among the hundreds wounded was Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s only son, <PERSON> Benigno </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> noted in the statement that his faction promised last November to refrain from hostile acts against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to give her time to fulfill promises to improve the government. `` We are now withdrawing that declaration,'' the statement said. `` It has become obvious by its own actions, that the Aquino administration is incapable of ensuring the very survival of this nation over the next few years. We have to act and act boldly.'' <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON>, who was arrested Dec. 9, said he and others jailed in previous coup attempts had been detained for months without formal charges or trial. <PERSON> Honasan </PERSON> played a key role in the Feb. 22, 1986, military uprising that toppled President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> after thousands of civilians joined the revolt. But he became disillusioned with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> after she succeeded to the presidency, accusing her of weak and inept leadership in the face of the 19-year-old communist insurgency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-AIDS     04-06 0906</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-AIDS,0934</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mexico Using Novel Approach To Combat AIDS</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Alarmed by the fast spread of AIDS in the country, <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> authorities have begun a campaign called <ORGANIZATION> Cascade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, a novel approach that enlists those most likely to be afflicted to spread the word. The campaign is aimed directly at male and female prostitutes, the homosexual community, street gangs and the poor in the hope that what they learn about AIDS prevention will `` cascade'' down to others in their own vernacular. Most of the effort is concentrated in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, a metropolis of 18 million people, where high-risk people are hard to reach through newspapers and other standard means. `` We are teaching them to become health care promoters and sending them into their communities,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Glorias </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION>, an arm of the federal <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. `` We believe that using the media to give information is not enough to change behavior patterns. Only face-to-face contact can do that,'' she said. `` The best way is for them to reach their own communities in their own language. That includes prostitutes reaching out to prostitutes, homosexuals to homosexuals, even deaf-mutes to deaf-mutes.'' According to the center, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> had 1,126 confirmed AIDS cases as of Feb. 1, and the number is doubling every seven months. For every confirmed case, an additional 50 to 100 people are becoming exposed to the virus, said Dr. <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Sepulveda </PERSON> <PERSON> Amor </PERSON>, the department's director of epidemiology. <PERSON> Sepulveda </PERSON>, who is also president of the government's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on AIDS Prevention, estimated during a recent interview the number of people confirmed to have AIDS will reach over 25,000 by 1991, making it the second or third leading cause of death for people in the 25 to 44 age group in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, which has a population estimated at 81.7 million. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> the number of AIDs cases reported since June, 1981, has reached 57,024. Since it was founded last year, the information center has broadcast its services on radio and television and through bumper stickers, posters, keychains and matchbooks with condoms attached. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> recently received a donation of 10 million condoms from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. The center also has trained dozens of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> residents in its Cascade Education program, offering instructional rclasses but leaving the actual teaching process to each individual. `` We give them the basics, then leave the style of presentation in their own hands,'' <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said. The center's staff also trains street-gang leaders and visits jails to teach police officials and prisoners. <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said many of the Cascade volunteers from the streets originally visited the center to be tested for the AIDS virus and, with counselling and support, have joined the program. She said the best of them are those who have tested positive. One male prostitute in the program, only known by his nickname of <LOCATION> Jaimito </LOCATION>, regularly visits <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> markets to sing a `` ranchero'' song he wrote and recorded called, `` What is AIDS?'' <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> called <PERSON> Jaimito </PERSON> `` one of our great promoters.'' A deaf mute who also is a male prostitute is another is Cascade promoter. `` He uncovered a whole sub-culture of deaf mutes who prostitute themselves off to make a living,'' <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said. `` We found that many feel they have no other way to earn money.'' An initial <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> survey indicated that about 30 percent of the male homosexual community in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> has been exposed to the AIDS virus. <PERSON> Gerardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> <PERSON> Zurita </PERSON>, a Cascade volunteer leader, said cultural prejudices have made it very difficult for homosexual men to seek help. `` There's incredible discrimination against homosexuals, who are isolated from the centers of the country,'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said. `` Teaching them about AIDS is difficult. They are forced to hide from the police and other government authorities.'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> brings youths from what he calls `` controlled groups'' of prostitutes to the center to be examined and learn about AIDS prevention. `` But there are others we ca n't get to, who are more preoccupied with making a living than with taking care of their lives,'' he said. <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> and other health officials say the Cascade approach is essential not only in reaching previously hidden subcultures but in confronting many myths about AIDS. `` We've come across many beliefs,'' <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said. `` Some say AIDS is punishment from God, and others, that witchcraft can ward it off. In a country with cultural setbacks that include religious beliefs, ignorance and cultural taboos that do not allow the use of condoms, we found that this program has worked.'' Currently, <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said the center is receiving 50 visits and 100 telephone queries a day from people wanting to find out about AIDS. `` It's new that they should come out at all,'' she said. `` The very lowest class is the most at risk, and the hardest to get to. There's a disrespect for life -LRB- among them -RRB-; they do n't care if they die.'' As in other countries in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the center had to overcome initial resistance from the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in distributing literature and promoting the use of condoms. Clerics are one way of reaching rural areas, <PERSON> Ornellas </PERSON> said. `` We have n't even started with rural people, where you have whole families living in a single room. Children learn about sex in one room. What's going to happen when AIDS reaches these rural areas?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Grassroots     04-06 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Grassroots,0841</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinians Unite for Survival and Rebellion</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL BIREH, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A web of unity has spread through the occupied lands in four months of violence, drawing Palestinian into committees for everything from tending emergency gardens to running the rebellion. `` I think the idea is that this uprising is going to go on a long time,'' said <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, an Arab-American who promotes creation of civic action groups. Boys and businessmen of this middle-class town turned the earth of a vacant lot this week and planted squash, tomatoes and cucumbers so their neighborhood will have fresh produce during curfews imposed by the Israeli army. Last month in <LOCATION> Arura </LOCATION> village, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter spoke with young Arabs who stood midnight watch to warn of approaching soldiers. Nurses who got through an army blockade of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shufat </LOCATION> refugee camp in February said health workers had formed a loose network that could rush aid to areas where where Palestinians clashed with soldiers. `` There are medical committees, agricultural committees, defense committees,'' said <PERSON> Saeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Erakat </PERSON>, political science professor at <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Najah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Many of these committees work in the open,'' and more secret groups organize strikes, protests and political activities in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, he said. <PERSON> Erakat </PERSON> said the young leaders of secret groups generally are affiliated with factions of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` They may be new faces, but they will be new faces of leadership of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` These are leaders who have become leaders because they are doing something to attack the occupation.'' An underground network of PLO-affiliated leaders has shown its strength by demanding, and getting, mass resignations of Arab policemen in the occupied territories and nearly universal acceptance of commercial strikes. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s attempts to crush the leadership with mass arrests have not stopped the clandestine leaflets. Communique No. 11 told Arabs to boycott institutions linked to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and form `` popular committees in every place, in city, village, camp and street.'' Leaflets urge people to `` cultivate the land'' increase self-reliance, police themselves in the absence of Arab policemen and start local manufacturing operations to lessen dependence on the Israeli economy. <PERSON> Raja </PERSON> <PERSON> Shehadeh </PERSON>, a Palestinian lawyer, said neighborhood groups had multiplied in tandem with economic and social hardships created by the conflict that began Dec. 8. `` I think it's happening a lot, especially for security and self-sufficiency,'' said <PERSON> Shehadeh </PERSON>, who leads a human rights group in <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION> called Law in the Service of Man. `` People are experiencing a siege.'' <PERSON> Awad </PERSON>, the Arab-American head of the Center for the Study of Non-Violence in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said groups of 10 to 20 families have formed throughout the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, with the largest numbers in <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. `` In <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jalla </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> school, instead of having a playground for kids they cultivate ... beans, cucumbers, onions, tomatoes,'' he said. `` I think the idea is that this uprising is going to go on a long time and the Israelis are going to push hard. ... The next step is to make the Palestinians feel hungry.'' Arab strikes and Israeli restrictions have complicated deliveries of fresh produce, but canned and packaged goods are in ample supply and there is no evidence of hunger. Many residents have stockpiled food. Others buy groceries from farmers or merchants' homes rather than shops. When fresh produce is available, Palestinians often can not buy it because of curfews. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON>, a businessman in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bireh </LOCATION>, said two dozen households in his neighborhood formed a committee at the end of March, when the army sealed off the occupied territories for three days. He said his four new hens had laid their first eggs. Less than a week later, he joined six men and eight children in cultivating a vacant lot. While they worked, army trucks rolled past shops that were closed for most of the previous week by a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> ban on afternoon work and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s refusal to let them open in the morning. The businessman, who asked that his last name be withheld, said the committee also had decided to start first aid classes, form security patrols and build an emergency stock of food. `` We made a request to every house to buy a big bag of flour'' and arranged to buy food from store owners even when their shops are closed, he said. `` People are now thinking of collecting wood for baking,'' <PERSON> Omar </PERSON>'s wife said. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> cut off supplies of fuel oil and gasoline two weeks ago. <PERSON> Samir </PERSON>, another committee member, said the grassroots groups would be harder for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to handle than labor unions, social associations and schools. `` There is no infrastructure the Israelis can control,'' he said. `` To put it down, they'll have to arrest everybody,'' and in that case `` you're not succeeding. You've lost control.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-06 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0564</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EDWARDSVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What's a birthday without a party? Or, in the case of this Southern Illinois city, what's a party without a birth date? A city committee planning <LOCATION> Edwardsville </LOCATION>'s 175th birthday bash has disbanded, stymied over the actual year the community of 12,480 was born. `` You know, everybody was going every which way _ really, nobody could agree on one date,'' <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Krumeich </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Birthday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Celebration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. `` That was the main problem. That was the stumbling block.'' Shortly after the committee was formed last summer, it learned that a common pleas court held its first session in the town in 1813, <PERSON> Krumeich </PERSON> said. Two history books set the year of <LOCATION> Edwardsville </LOCATION>'s founding in 1819, but its incorporation as a town did not come until 1853 and its incorporation as a city came 20 years after that. `` See the dilemma?'' asked former committee member <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfskill </PERSON>. `` We could n't seem to uncover when the actual date was. That was the problem.'' City officials will take up the issue of the city's birth in the future, said Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, but he added no celebration will be held this year. `` I hate to see that go by without any celebration,'' <PERSON> Krumeich </PERSON> said, but, he added, `` We also have a 200-year celebration down the road.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WAVERLY, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, the well-traveled weatherman with the common touch, is being invited to add his talents to a cow-chip toss billed as `` the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Annual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Championship </ORGANIZATION>.'' The local <ORGANIZATION> Lions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> plans to invite <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, the weather forecaster on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show, and Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> to join other contestants in seeing how far they can hurl a 6-inch-wide cow chip, said organizer <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>. `` Contestants can lick their fingers, but that's optional,'' <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> said Tuesday. The toss will take place Sept. 10 outside <ORGANIZATION> Waverly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> said. He advised a friend to start giving his 300 head of cattle laxatives because organizers will need about 500 chips. `` We're billing it as the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Annual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Championship </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON> said. `` If someone objects, we'll call it the Southern Ohio Championship.'' Invitations were being sent to <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> and <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> this week, he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Overtaxed taxpayers who feel rubbed the wrong way by the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> will be offered a chance to relax April 15 when a massage school offers free `` income-tax stress relief.'' The <ORGANIZATION> East-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Therapy </ORGANIZATION> celebrates its re-opening that day, the deadline for filing federal income-tax returns, with free massages by appointment at its new location. Certified public accountants, who will probably be too busy April 15, will be offered the free half-hour massages the following day. `` Since we are a school of massage therapy, we asked ourselves who would be most stressed out on April 15? It would be people who deal with income tax,'' college director <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlinski </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` It was sort of a natural.'' The college, started in 1972, offers training in massage and plans to offer walk-in massages at its new downtown location. `` What we're trying to do is offer a service to busy downtown professionals who are under a lot of stress,'' spokeswoman <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Verridjen </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Argentina-Plant     04-06 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Argentina-Plant,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Power Plant Opened In Argentina</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEUQUEN, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> inaugurated a $ 900 million geothermoelectric plant on a volcanic peak northwest of <LOCATION> Neuquen </LOCATION>, the first facility of its kind in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The 670-kilowatt plant, made in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with Israeli technology, is on top of 9,570-foot Copahue volcano in the <LOCATION> Andes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, 740 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>. The site is 190 miles from <LOCATION> Neuquen </LOCATION>. It was inaugurated in a ceremony on Tuesday. Costs of acquiring the plant, which will be powered by thermal energy from the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, were shared by the national and <LOCATION> Neuquen </LOCATION> provincial energy departments and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Copahue </ORGANIZATION>. Officials say the plant is capable of supplying a cheap, cost-effective source of power to commercial businesses in much of the region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Bomb     04-06 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Bomb,0157</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Defuse Fire Bomb Planted In Department Store</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police defused an incendiary bomb planted in a department store belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> Debenhams </ORGANIZATION> chain, which previously has been targeted by animal rights activists for selling fur coats. The bomb was found Tuesday by an employee in the third-floor, furniture section of <ORGANIZATION> Debenhams </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, a busy shopping thoroughfare in central <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, shortly after the store closed at 6 p.m. -LRB- 1 p.m. EDT -RRB-, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard said. The store was evacuated and part of <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> was closed to traffic. Inspector <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chilvers </PERSON> said a bomb disposal unit took nearly three hours to defuse the device. He said police were investigating whether the bomb was linked to the previous attacks by an animal rights group. No group immediately claimed responsibility. <ORGANIZATION> Debenhams </ORGANIZATION> has been a target of firebomb and other attacks by the <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for more than four years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PhoneWarning     04-06 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Phone Warning,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>FCC Looking Into Practices of New Phone Operator Services</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is advising consumers to beware when using hotel, hospital and pay telephones to make operator-assisted calls. The agency has received 260 complaints since January from irate callers who were billed by a company they had never heard of, at rates that were several times the rates charged by the major long-distance companies. In one case, the charges were 10 times higher, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> said. The complaints have prompted the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> to begin looking into the practices of alternative operator services, known as AOS companies, which have emerged to compete in a $ 7 billion-a-year market that until recently was served only by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` We've never seen a situation quite like this addressed by the commission,'' describing the complex nature of the problem AOS companies pose, said <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s telephone enforcement division. `` We do n't want to have a knee-jerk reaction that could kill an industry,'' he said, adding that the commission needs more information before deciding whether federal action is warranted. AOS companies began forming within the past two years ago to fill the void left when <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T stopped paying commissions to hotels and motels on the long-distance calls made by their guests. Atleast some of the AOS companies kick back money to the contracting hospital, hotel, motel or other business. The AOS companies, now estimated to number around 40, handle calls mainly made by the transient public in hotels, motels and at pay phones as well as hospitals and universities. They handle credit-card, collect and third-party billed calls. Typical complaints, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> said, are that callers are given no indication that an AOS company is handling their calls or that they will be billed at higher rates than those of the company whose long-distance credit card they are using. AOS rates are not regulated by the FCC. The commission regulates the rates <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T can charge but not the rates of any other long-distance companies because none is large enough to control market prices. In complaints investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>, the AOS companies have refunded the disputed amount, <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON> said. At an establishment served by an AOS company, callers who dial `` 0'' for an operator are routed to the AOS. An operator gets billing information and then sends the call over a line the AOS leases from one of the long-distance carriers, like <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T or <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Many of the callers who end up connected to an AOS company are those using a credit card issued by a local <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> phone company or <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>, since use of those cards require callers to start by dialing a `` 0.'' Other companies' cards require callers to dial a local or 800 number to place their call. Most of the AOS companies have billing contracts with the <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies, which means callers receive the AOS charges along with their monthly local <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> phone bill. Some AOS companies also accept payment by other credit cards such as <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION> and Visa. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> advises that callers ask an operator what company they work for, what rates they will be charged and how they will be billed before placing the call. If they are dissatisfied, they should find another phone, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> says. Several states have begun considering regulation of AOS companies because of complaints and some have issued consumer alerts. AOS companies say theirs is a new and growing industry to which consumers have n't yet become accustomed. The major AOS companies say their operators are trained to identify themselves to callers before placing their calls. <PERSON> Vogt </PERSON> said, however, that some AOS companies can place automated calls, which substitute `` bong'' tones for a live operator to instruct callers on how to proceed with a credit card. There is no federal requirement for AOS companies to identify themselves, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AmericansArrested Bjt   04-06 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Americans Arrested, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Overseas Arrests of Americans Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of Americans caught in foreign drug busts jumped 22 percent last year, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported in an effort to scare <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tourists out of taking controlled substances on overseas vacations. `` As we approach the busy travel season, many Americans are getting ready for that long-awaited trip abroad; for some, the trip will become a nightmare,'' the department said Tuesday in a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Police abroad seized 1,242 Americans on drug charges last year, compared with 1,013 in 1986, the report said. The biggest increases in drug-related arrests of Americans were in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, where governments are under pressure from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to get tough on narcotics. Of the 3,041 Americans taken into custody in foreign countries, 41 percent were suspected of drug violations. `` Americans have been arrested for possessing as little as a third of an ounce of marijuana,'' the report said. It added: `` Those Americans who assume there is no real danger in buying or carrying just a ` small' amount of drugs on their overseas trip may be in for a very unpleasant surprise. `` Many travelers also assume that, as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens, they are immune from prosecution under foreign laws.'' That was underscored Tuesday by a Spanish court's conviction of <PERSON> Conan </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, a 23-year-old <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> photographer, on cocaine importation charges. Despite <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government belief that <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> was an innocent traveler duped by an acquaintance into carrying the drugs into <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, he was sentenced to six years in jail. The 10 countries that arrested the most Americans on all charges last year were <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, 990; <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, 346; <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, 267; the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, 196; <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, 128; <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, 124; the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, 74; <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, 60; <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, 53 and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, 52. At year's end, 596 Americans were serving jail sentences overseas. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> have inmate transfer treaties that permit offenders to serve their sentences in jails in their homeland, but fewer prisoners than normal were able to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year because <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> federal prisons did n't have enough space Riots among Cubans at federal penitentiaries in <LOCATION> Oakdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>. and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, aggravated the crowding. The largest number of inmate mistreatment complaints from Americans abroad came from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, notably those in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> prison near <LOCATION> Hermosillo </LOCATION>. About one-fourth of the 164 Americans arrested in that area of northern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> complained of mistreatment and `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials found such reports credible and made a vigorous formal protest in August,'' the report said. Since then, no reports of mistreatment at that prison have been received, the report said. Several countries prevented <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance to Americans with dual nationality. TheSoviet Union, as in the past, refused to grant access to three prisoners with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nationality and obstacles also were raised in cases in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION>, the report said. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> also received complaints from American tourists detained at the border for alleged customs violations. Most of the Americans were fined in dollars _ scarce currency in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> _ and released within 24 hours. The number of Americans incarcerated in <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> declined last year, mostly because that country relaxed punishments against foreigners accused of breaking the Islamic ban on alcoholic beverages. Instead of sentencing liquor possessors to jail, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> now usually deports them, the report said. Americans in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> benefited from a round of pardons granted on the 60th birthday of the king. Several <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prisoners were released and a few others had their sentences reduced. Still, 30 Americans remained in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>'s `` substandard'' prisons at the end of the year. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spent $ 46,000 on medical assistance and food for needy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prisoners, more than $ 20,000 of which went to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> inmates in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, according to the report.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-06 0942</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,940</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lower Costs, Higher Prices Benefit Hog And Cattle Farmers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The long-awaited financial turnaround for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture has been led by a two-year economic boomlet in the livestock sector, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. `` Since the fourth quarter of 1985, hog and cattle farmers have benefited from generally higher prices and lower feed costs,'' the report said. `` Feed expenses declined by $ 2.4 billion during 1985-87, while hog and cattle -LRB- sales -RRB- receipts increased by $ 4.7 billion.'' Further, poultry and egg sales increased $ 1.5 billion in 1986 before declining last year. According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists, the net cash income of farmers _ what's left over from gross cash income after deducting cash expenses _ rose to a record $ 57 billion in 1987 from $ 52 billion in 1986 and $ 47.3 billion in 1985. Some decline is expected this year to between $ 50 billion and $ 55 billion. The report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> was in the current issue of Agricultural Outlook magazine and was written by <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kodl </PERSON>. `` More than 80 percent of the $ 10 billion increase in net cash income from 1985 to 1987 went to livestock producers,'' the report said. `` Strong growth in net cash income was shared by most major livestock enterprises in 1986, and by hog, dairy and beef farms in 1987.'' The darker side was among crop producers who saw feed grain receipts decline from their 1985 peak, contributing to the recent financial stress on <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> crop farms. `` However, the strong rebound in livestock earnings has provided an important offset in this region,'' the report said. `` Five of the top 10 cattle producing states and seven of the top 10 hog producing states are located in the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> plains </LOCATION> -LRB- from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> -RRB- and western Corn Belt -LRB- <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> -RRB-.'' The gains in livestock receipts and big increases in government payments translated into increases of 70 percent to 80 percent in the net cash incomes of farmers in the two regions, the report said. `` Farmers used their higher incomes to pay down more than $ 6 billion of farm business and household debt annually during 1984-87,'' the report said. `` They are now in a position to reap substantial benefits in 1988 from continued livestock profits and from recovering crop profits.'' The overall debt crunch of the early and mid-1980s `` has subsided,'' the report said. `` By the end of this year business debt in agriculture likely will have fallen $ 55 billion to $ 60 billion, or nearly one-third, since 1983.'' It added: `` Farmers' recent financial progress is evident in the closely watched debt-to-asset ratio, which measures the degree of lender security and the farmers' use of their earnings and capital to finance farming operations.'' After climbing to 23 percent in 1985 _ which meant farers owed $ 23 for every $ 100 worth of assets _ economists said the debt-to-asset ratio nationally declined to an estimated 17 percent to 19 percent by 1988.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been given approval by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to buy an additional 2 million metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat at subsidized prices. Acting Undersecretary <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said Tuesday that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has already bought more than 4.9 million tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat under previously announced authorizations under the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. Under EEP arrangements, exporters can sell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. The subsidies have ranged from less than $ 20 to more than $ 40 per ton of wheat, or in the range of 54 cents to $ 1.09 per bushel. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> also has been a big buyer of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, with purchases totaling more than 11.8 million tons in the last year. An additional 1 million tons of <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> wheat for the Soviets were authorized earlier in the week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public comments are being sought on how to define a `` person'' for purposes of determining federal limits on payments to farmers, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. There are limits on federal payments to individuals, including benefits paid under commodity price support programs, the Conservation Reserve Program and some other programs where direct payments are made. Additionally, the proposed rule would determine whether foreigners will be eligible to receive certain program payments. In budget legislation late last year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> included a number of provisions designed to tighten loopholes in <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> farm payment regulations, beginning with 1989 crops. The law provides, for example, that to qualify for payments a `` person'' must be actively engaged in farming by providing a significant amount of capital, equipment or land, and personal labor or management to the enterprise. A basic limit of $ 50,000 per person annually is set on direct `` deficiency'' payments, but this can be ballooned to as much as $ 100,000 maximum depending on a person's interest in other entities. The term `` person'' can include individuals, corporations, associations, charitable organizations or other entity as determined by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. A recent study by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says the law requires the secretary of agriculture `` to give fair and equitable treatment to trusts and estates and the beneficiaries thereof, and provides that spouses may be separate persons if their farming operations were separate prior to their marriage and continue to be operated separately.'' Written comments can be sent by May 6 to: Director, Cotton, Grain and Rice Price Support Division, ASCS-USDA, P.O. Box 2415, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20013.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Amnesty-Libya     04-06 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Amnesty-Libya,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Human Rights Group Urges Libya To Abolish Death Penalty</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> appealed to the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> people's congresses to support Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>'s stated aim to abolish the death penalty in the north African nation. The London-based human rights organization said the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader called on the people's congresses to hold a special session soon to discuss his proposed changes in human rights' laws, including the abolition of the death penalty. The congresses are supposed to have absolute power over government policy under the socialist system devised by <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> in 1977. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> opposes the death penalty as cruel, inhuman and degrading punishment. Its abolition, the organization said in a statement Tuesday, would be a `` major step in the respect of human rights by the Libyan Jamahiriya,'' or `` the masses,'' which is how <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> refers to itself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WealthyTaxpayers Bjt   04-06 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wealthy Taxpayers, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wealthiest 1 Percent Pays 26 Percent of Taxes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of high-income Americans has risen sharply during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, and so has their share of the total federal tax burden. The 1 million or so couples and individuals whose incomes put them among the nation's wealthiest 1 percent of taxpayers paid 26.1 percent of all personal income taxes collected in 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. That share is up from 18.1 percent in 1981, when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office. In its study issued Tuesday, the department did not say what income level would place taxpayers into that highest 1 percent. But it issued a parallel set of statistics showing that during the same period, the share borne by those making over $ 100,000 rose from 15.2 percent of the total to 30.6 percent. Meanwhile, the portion of taxes paid by those with incomes under $ 50,000 _ the majority of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> _ dropped from 66.8 percent in 1981, before enactment of across-the-board tax cuts, to 45.7 percent in 1986, the department said. Those in between, making $ 50,000 to $ 100,000, paid the rest, with their share rising from 18 percent to 23.7 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> attributed part of the higher tax payments by the wealthy to `` the extraordinary level of capital gains realized in 1986 in anticipation of the 1987 rate increase on capital gains.'' In 1986, the maximum tax rate on capital gains, which are profits from the sale of stock, real estate and other investments, was 20 percent. Knowing the rate would rise to 28 percent in 1987, investors sold billions of dollars worth of assets in the closing days of 1986, which boosted their total incomes for that year. That sell-off helped capital gains account for nearly 25 percent of the total income of the richest 1 percent of Americans in 1986. In 1985, capital gains accounted for 15 percent; in 1981, 11 percent. By contrast, capital gains make up on the average less than 2 percent of the income of the other 99 percent of Americans. The preliminary analysis is based on a sampling of tax returns filed last year, reflecting income earned in 1986. The study made no attempt to fully explain the growing share of taxes paid by the richest Americans. However, once its analysis is complete, the administration is likely to claim that the increase results from the big 1981 across-the-board tax cut that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> enacted at <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s behest. That law slashed the top marginal rate from 70 percent to 50 percent. It since has been cut to 33 percent. The administration reasons that reducing tax rates gives workers and investors incentive to produce and save more. Inflation and economic growth have helped boost incomes and, thus, increase the number of taxpayers who make more than $ 100,000 a year. In 1986, about 12 of every 1,000 couples and individuals topped that level. The analysis found those taxpayers paid $ 43 billion in taxes in 1981, $ 77 billion in 1985 and $ 115 billion in 1986. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> says more than 1.2 million couples and individuals earned over $ 100,000 in 1985, an increase of 63 percent over 1982. The number earning over $ 1 million a year more than doubled from 1982 to 1985, to 17,312. Between 1981 and 1986, taxes paid by those with incomes between $ 50,000 and $ 100,000 increased from $ 51 billion to $ 89 billion. The burden on those under $ 50,000 dropped from $ 190 billion to $ 172 billion. About half of Americans have incomes under $ 35,000 a year, including those who are too poor to pay taxes. They paid 7.5 percent of the individual income tax in 1981 and 6.4 percent in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GrayingAmerica Bjt   04-06 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Graying America, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Median Age Sets Record High</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans are easing into their middle years, as growing numbers of maturing Baby Boomers boost the nation's median age to a record high of just over 32 years The 35-44 age group represents the leading edge of the post-World War II Baby Boom and is the fastest-growing segment of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday. And the population segments aged 85 and over and 75-84 rank second and third in growth since 1980, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> said. This combination helped boost the nation's median age to 32.1 years as of last July 1, the highest ever. `` The ` Graying of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>' is ... documented by its increasing age,'' observed bureau statistician <PERSON> Louisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. Up from 31.8 in 1986, the median means that half of all Americans are older than that age and half younger. By race, blacks remain younger than whites, although both groups are maturing. For whites, the median age hit 33 for the first time, up from 32.7 in 1986. Black median age was 27.2, up from 26.9 and the first time that group had surpassed 27. The nation's median age first reached 30 in 1950, but the rapid growth of the Baby Boom that was then occurring pulled it back down in the following years. The Baby Boom consists of the estimated 20 million Americans born between 1946 and 1965. With the maturing of the Baby Boomers, the median has begun moving in the other direction. The growing elderly population has also helped raise the median, as improved medical care extends lifepsans. `` The repercussions of the Baby Boom are many and varied,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` They will continue to affect the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for many years to come.'' They are now at the age where they have more discretionary income and the effect can be seen in the nation's culture and marketing, she said. The generation's arrival spurred a boom in sales of baby products. It then proceeded to overwhelm the school system, following up with creation of a national orientation toward teen-age music and styles. Now, as the Baby Boomers set up more and smaller households, they are prompting a boom in housing sales and household goods, marketing experts say. `` Further down the road, once they begin to reach retirement age, they will obviously have a great effect on the direction the country takes,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> added. Meanwhile, the Boomers are being followed by the much smaller Baby Bust generation, leaving fast-food outlets, retail stores and others offering `` first jobs'' searching for employees, she said. The Boomers boosted the 35-44 age group by 33.8 percent between 1980 and 1987 to some 34.4 million people, the bureau reported. The 25-34 age group remains the most numerous with 43.5 million members, but that is up only 16.8 percent from 1980, the study noted. When Americans now in that age group move on, they will have few replacements. Between 1980 and 1987 the 18-24 group declined by 9.7 percent to 27.3 million, and those aged 14-17 fell 11 percent to 14.4 million. Even the 5-13 group slipped 1.1 percent to 30.8 million, but those under 5 jumped 11.6 percent in the Baby Boom echo. They totaled 18.2 million. The second-fastest growing segment was aged 85 and over, increasing 28 percent to 2.2 million. The 75-84 group was third, jumping 20.3 percent to 7.7 million. Americans in the 65-74 group increased 13.4 percent to 17.7 million. Turning to the small groups born in the Depression and World War II: The 45 - to 54-year-old group increased only 2.1 percent to 23.3 million and those 55-64 were up 1.5 percent to 22.0 million
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Austria-Iranian     04-06 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Austria-Iranian,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Reportedly Wounded In Chemical Gas Attack Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of more than 30 people flown to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> for treatment of mustard gas poisoning suffered in alleged chemical weapons attacks in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war has died, a doctor said. <PERSON> Zaindi </PERSON>, a 20-year-old Iranian volunteer soldier was one of the most seriously injured patients brought to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on March 29. Dr. <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Freilinger </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> plastic surgery, said <PERSON> Zaindi </PERSON> had improved, but then got worse and died of his injuries Tuesday. The plane made its first stop in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Freilinger </PERSON>, who has treated more than 30 alleged chemical weapons attack victims since 1984, had the Iranian removed from the plane for treatment in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> because his condition was too serious for him to be able to bear the continued trip. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> charged the Iraqi air force in March dropped cyanide and mustard gas bombs on three Kurdish towns in <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> that had been captured by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, killing 5,000 Kurds and injuring 5,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TV-USAToday     04-06 0596</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TV-USA Today,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spiffy `USA Today - The Television Show' Previewed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's fast, it's colorful, it's as spiffy as can be. It's `` USA Today'' on TV. Executive producer <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> unveiled a prototype of the syndicated, daily television show and his four-person anchor team Tuesday at one of a series of news conferences, this one in the Rainbow Room, upstairs from his old office at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> where he was executive producer of `` Today.'' `` <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> _ The Television Show'' premieres on Sept. 12, but is already a hit, having been sold in 118 markets covering 85 percent of the country. That gives it, higher coverage than any syndicated show except `` Wheel of Fortune,'' <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. The promotional reel <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> showed reporters promised stations considering buying the show that it would take them `` into the'90s.'' `` It's a fast-paced world and I think a lot of the media has n't caught up,'' said <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, after showing the tape The pace of the promotional show, complete with commercials, was fast to spin heads. Not surprisingly, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> assured reporters that `` USA Today'' wo n't be a `` traditional'' news show but rather will rely on upbeat human-interest stories, polls and interviews. Since it's based on the colorful, successful, young national newspaper, it `` does n't have any baggage from the past,'' he said. `` We do n't have to worry about what <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON> said.'' The show is the first product from <ORGANIZATION> GTG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>, the partnership between former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinker </PERSON>, who is also former president of <ORGANIZATION> MTM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION>, the publisher of <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> and the nation's largest newspaper group. GTG is also producing network entertainment shows. `` <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> _ The Television Show'' will be a half hour daily, an hour on weekends. The show will be fed to stations each day via satellite at 4:30 p.m. Eastern time. <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said 96 of the stations will broadcast the show in what he considers its ideal time period, the hour between the evening news and the beginning of prime time. <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> has assembled a good-looking cast of network veterans to anchor the four segments, based on the four sections of the newspaper: <PERSON> Edie </PERSON> <PERSON> Magnus </PERSON> from <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> as `` Front Page'' anchor; <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, also formerly with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, as `` Money'' editor; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Macatee </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> for `` Sports'' and <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, also formerly with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, for `` Life.'' The show will preview the next day's edition of `` USA Today,'' but not necessarily have the same stories as the newspaper. `` It will be topical, but to be successful it will have to be different,'' said <PERSON> Magnus </PERSON>. `` We will be doing what would be the next day's lead the night before.'' <PERSON> Macatee </PERSON> suggested he might have coaches other than baseball managers wear uniforms for a segment. `` Or let's have the head of an airline dress like a pilot for a day to see how it fits, see how people react,'' he said. A daily poll will be the centerpiece of the show, <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON> said. The promotional tape featured a poll on marriage, using clips from movies to illustrate the results, for example, `` Body Heat'' illustrating a question about infidelity. Academy Award-winning composer <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, who wrote the theme, was featured in an interview in the promotional tape describing the music, much like the show, as having `` a happy, laid-back feeling, but with a sense of urgency.'' <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION> is n't the only newspaper getting into the act. The <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monitor </ORGANIZATION>, which has a radio show, is holding a news conference later this week to announce its own television show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880406-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-06-88 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     04-06 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
