<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2330EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vanuatu     12-20 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vanuatu,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Arrested, Charged With Inciting Mutiny</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT VILA, Vanuatu (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> was arrested on Wednesday and charged with inciting mutiny in a deepening political crisis in this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> state, the Australian <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> faces a maximum sentence of life imprisonment, and the agency quoted Public Prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter-Wright </PERSON> as saying additional charges would be levied against him. On Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> acted to remove <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> from office for his failed attempt two days earlier to form an interim government pending national elections in February. Legislators accused him of treason, gross misconduct and other major offenses. <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON> tried last Friday to dissolve <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and to dismiss elected Prime Minister <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> and replace with <PERSON> Sokomanu </PERSON>'s nephew, flamboyant, Australian-educated politician <PERSON> Barak </PERSON> <PERSON> Sope </PERSON> <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> has been in power since <LOCATION> Vanuatu </LOCATION>, formerly known as the New Hebrides and under Anglo-French rule, became independent in 1980. The <ORGANIZATION> AAP </ORGANIZATION> said the president was charged during a five-minute appearance at <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magistrate </ORGANIZATION>'s Court. It said Senior Magistrate <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcinski </PERSON> asked the president if he had anything to say, and he replied: `` Your Honor, I would like to see my lawyer first.'' The president, clad in a sport shirt and shorts, waved to spectators as he walked from the court and was led away to a police vehicle, guarded by about 12 uniformed officers, the <ORGANIZATION> AAP </ORGANIZATION> said. Four members of the abortive interim government, including <PERSON> Sope </PERSON>, already have been charged with sedition. All five men are scheduled to apply for bail later Wednesday before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The crisis culminates a yearlong power struggle between <PERSON> Lini </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sope </PERSON>, whose foes blamed him for recent outbreaks of violence in his bid for leadership. This island nation of 130,000 people lies 1,200 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-KennedyComplaint     12-20 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kennedy Complaint,0428</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-Ager Says Joe Kennedy Tussled With Him After Near-Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager complained to police that Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> pushed him Tuesday and struck his head against a car after the two were involved in a near-collision, but the youth later said he would drop charges. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>, 17, said he would not pursue his complaint against <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> because the congressman had apologized. <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> said he was not hurt. <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> said he filed assault and battery charges in <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION> Tuesday but would drop them Wednesday. `` Mr. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> came over to my house and he apologized and I accepted his apology,'' <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Tuesday evening. A spokesman for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> had sternly reprimanded the teen-ager for speeding after the near-accident but had not hit him. He said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> visited the teen-ager later to `` clarify matters'' but that he did not apologize for anything. <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> could not say whether <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> had pushed <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 36, was elected last month to his second term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He is the eldest son of the late Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and a nephew of the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and of Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> police spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Santry </PERSON> said <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> filed a complaint saying that he was driving up a hill in the city's <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> neighborhood about 12:40 p.m. Tuesday and passed <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s car. Both drivers veered off the road to avoid a collision, the complaint said. `` Both parties got out of their cars and the suspect then grabbed the victim and pushed him into the victim's car,'' <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>'s complaint said. `` The victim's head hit the car.'' <PERSON> Santry </PERSON> said police would not pursue such as case unless <PERSON> Avila </PERSON> filed a complaint in court, and he could confirm only that a complaint was filed at the police station. <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said that as the father of two young boys who play in the neighborhood, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was upset at the sight of the speeding car. <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>'s car forced the congressman's off the road. `` <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> gave a very stern reprimand to the young man driving the other vehicle,'' <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said. He said the boy and his father later met with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. `` After hearing <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>'s side, the father and the son were going to withdraw the complaint,'' <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON> said. A man answering the telephone at the boy's home said he was <PERSON> Avila </PERSON>'s father but would not comment and would not give his name.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NewYorkSurvey     12-20 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New York Survey,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Finds New Yorkers Are Dissatisfied Boosters</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most New Yorkers have low opinions of their schools, subways, public safety and race relations _ but they would overwhelmingly recommend the city as a place to live, according to a survey released Tuesday. The survey by the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> found 64 percent of those interviewed were dissatisfied with street safety, 60 percent with the subways, 55 percent with the public schools and just over 50 percent with race relations. But 77 percent would recommend the city to a friend and more than 80 percent would recommend their neighborhoods. In unveiling some preliminary findings, the university's graduate school said the survey was the first of what will be an annual poll about the makeup of the city that can be used for guidance by government and private policy makers. It would help bridge the 10-year gap between federal censuses and go beyond the census by including such data as religion and attitudes about social and political issues, the university said. Survey takers conducted telephone interviews in English or Spanish with 1,470 adult residents of the city during the summer and fall. They reported a margin of sampling error of plus or minus three percentage points. Some other findings of the survey: _ Sixty percent of the respondents grew up in homes where languages other than English were spoken _ Seventy percent want the city to spend more on bilingual education and a like percentage go along with legal abortion _ Three out of 10 know someone who has AIDS or AIDS-related complex
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0728 12-20 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0728,0695</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Ouimet and Fritz; Separates moved for AMs as a0640 on
Robinson and a0743 on Ouimet. Ouimet also moved on the business
wire. McCallum also moved on the sports wire.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Max Robinson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who became the first black news anchorman on American network television but soon saw his life beset by personal and professional problems, died Tuesday from complications of AIDS. He was 49. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> started his broadcasting career as a disc jockey in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1965. In 1978, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> television station <ORGANIZATION> WTOP </ORGANIZATION>, where he had won top ratings as an anchorman for a decade, to join <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> as the first black to anchor a network news show. He co-anchored the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Evening News from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s tenure at <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was troubled as he zealously waged a battle against racism at the network. He charged the network with racism in a speech at <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1981. After <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' death in 1983, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> was made sole anchor of the newscasts, and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was relegated to weekend anchor stints and news briefs. In 1984, he joined <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> television station <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>John McCallum</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCallum </PERSON>, a former syndicated sports columnist and author of 35 books, died Saturday of cardiac arrest at age 64. <PERSON> McCallum </PERSON> wrote for <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> newspapers for a number of years and then moved to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He wrote a sports column for the <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a national news service. <PERSON> McCallum </PERSON> was best known for works on sports figures, including `` The Tiger Wore Spikes,'' about baseball great <PERSON> Ty </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>, and `` Dumb <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>,'' about a boxer in the <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> era. He also wrote books on figures such as the late <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>, actress <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Beck </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Joseph Nixon</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WABASH, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, a chairman emeritus of <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> newspaper chain, died Tuesday after a short illness. He was 75. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> began his career as a newspaperman in 1934 at the <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dispatch </LOCATION>, owned by his father, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. He later managed the <LOCATION> Elizabethton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>, the Wabash Plain-Dealer and <ORGANIZATION> Peru </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> for the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> chain. He returned to <LOCATION> Wabash </LOCATION> in 1954, where he was president and publisher of four <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> newspapers. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> became chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Nixon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the parent company of <ORGANIZATION> Nixon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, in 1980. He was later named chairman emeritus and continued working until two months ago. The <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> chain, based in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, publishes 11 newspapers in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> with a combined circulation of more than 85,000. <ORGANIZATION> Nixon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> also owns a commercial printing division, a cable television franchise in <LOCATION> Frankfort </LOCATION> and other publications.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Alphonse Ouimet</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alphonse </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouimet </PERSON>, a former president of the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> who helped introduce television to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> 40 years ago, died Tuesday. He was 80. <PERSON> Ouimet </PERSON> went to work for the <ORGANIZATION> CBC </ORGANIZATION> as an engineer when it was founded 52 years ago. In 1958, he became president and held that post for nine years. In the 1940s, he studied the operation of television in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and played a major role in introducing it to Canadian audiences. After leaving the <ORGANIZATION> CBC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ouimet </PERSON> headed a <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> conference on satellite technology in broadcasting and served as president of <ORGANIZATION> Telesat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION> from 1969 to 1980.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Emanuel Fritz</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERKELEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Emanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON>, a forestry and conservation authority who was known as `` Mr. <PERSON> Redwood </PERSON>'' because of his expertise, died Thursday at age 102. <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> helped create <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s state forest program and was co-founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the forerunner of the East Bay Regional Park system near the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. He was a professor of forestry emeritus at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>. He joined the faculty in 1919, retiring in 1954. <PERSON> Frtiz </PERSON> lived the longest of any present or former professor at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, the university announced Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Quake-DonorWarning     12-20 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quake-Donor Warning,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Armenian Group Vows Background Checks of Fund Raisers After Warning</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A national Armenian relief group said Tuesday it will conduct background checks of all its fund raisers after learning that a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> volunteer had a criminal record. The Armenian <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, a group with 300 members and offices in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, said that in the hectic days following the Dec. 7 quake, `` background checks were not conducted on those who had volunteered to assist.'' One of the volunteers at the <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relief </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, a group affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, was a man convicted of violating state drug laws, authorities said. When the man appeared on a WBZ-TV newscast to appeal for donations and medical supplies, <LOCATION> Woburn </LOCATION> police spotted him. The man later was ordered out of the relief office, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     12-20 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0332</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brady Bunch Reunion Pulls CBS Out Of Ratings' Cellar</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` A Very Brady Christmas,'' CBS' reunion of the 1970s sitcom family that lived on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, was this season's top-rated made-for-TV movie and gave <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> a Christmas gift _ a break from third place in the ratings. It was the first time this season that <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> finished out of last place. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week, and `` The Cosby Show'' was the No. 1, the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said. But `` A Very Brady Christmas,'' broadcast Sunday, was last week's No 2 prime-time show, with a 25.1 rating and a 39 share, lifting <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> to second place over <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, where `` The Brady Bunch'' ran from 1969-1974. Each rating point represents 904,000 homes with television. The share is a percentage of sets in use. The rest of the top 10 were: `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS; and `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, tied with `` 60 Minutes,'' CBS. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average prime-time rating last week was 15.4. CBS had 13.1 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.8. `` ABC World News Tonight'' won the close news race with an average rating of 11.0 and a 20 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' got out of third, possibly due to anchorman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON>'s travels to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, and had a 10.9 and 20, edging the `` CBS Evening News,'' with a 10.7 and 19. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Midnight Caller'' episode that drew fire from homosexual rights groups because of its storyline about a man with AIDS purposely engaging in high-risk sex, ranked 33rd, about what it has been ranking this season. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> began a guest-star stint on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Wiseguy,'' boosting the crime drama to 32nd place. The lowest-rated network shows last week were: `` <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>,'' `` Mission Impossible,'' `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Circus,'' `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>,'' `` West 57th,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' `` TV 101,'' `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' `` Knightwatch'' and `` Burning Issues.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GayRodeo     12-20 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gay Rodeo,0461</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Effectively Cuts Gay Rights Issue From Lawsuit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA MYERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has rejected the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>'s bid to join a lawsuit over the forced cancellation of the 1988 Gay Rodeo National Championship, effectively removing gay rights as an issue in the dispute. In denying the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>'s motion, the judge determined the issue that has pitted conservative residents against homosexual organizers was not civil rights, said <LOCATION> Churchill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> District Attorney <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON>. `` There was an effort to make this some kind of gay rights forum. They wanted to turn this into a three-ring circus. But it did n't work The judge said the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> ca n't play,'' <PERSON> Pasquale </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Chase </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>, said her group was giving up despite the outcome of Monday's hearing before District Judge <PERSON> Archie </PERSON> <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> in <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON>. `` We're still trying to come up with a way to get involved,'' Ms. <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> said. `` We just have to prove that discrimination occurred ... that there was an effort to try to keep an unpopular group out by using laws that are too broadly applied.'' The National Gay Rodeo championship was canceled in mid-October just days before its scheduled opening after <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> signed a temporary injunction preventing the event from being held at a private Fallon arena. The 20-acre <PERSON> Stockman </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> was leased from owner <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantry </PERSON> after the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rodeo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> had been turned away by public arenas in <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON>. In granting the temporary injunction, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> agreed with the county, saying the health and safety of the community was at stake because of expected crowds of up to 1,000 that would strain police and emergency services. <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> said the rodeo organizers also did not have the proper county license for the event. The judge's decision was upheld by the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which said the case did not raise questions of homosexual rights or freedom of expression. County officials acted to halt the rodeo after about 50 <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON> residents presented them with a petition signed by 1,519 people who did n't want the event in their community. The county is seeking a permanent injunction to block future rodeos on Lantry's property because officials claim it is not large enough or properly equipped. Lantry, with the help of <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> attorneys, is fighting the permanent injunction. <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> set a May 17-19 trial on the issue after denying ACLU-backed motions, including one to move the case from <PERSON> Fallon </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> said appeals would likely follow and the gay rodeo association was expected to seek damages from the county for more than $ 20,000 in losses because of the cancellation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeficitCommission Bjt   12-20 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deficit Commission, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Deficit Panel Still Shaky, Despite Bush Action</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made his appointments for the final two spots on the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, but doubts persist over how successful the panel will be in breaking a seven-year deadlock over the budget deficit. The high-level commission was created to help the new president deal with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s biggest economic failure, huge budget deficits that have more than doubled the national debt. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced he was choosing former Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON>, R-Nev., and former <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Congressman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> `` Lud'' <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON>, a Democrat and one of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s closest friends Under law, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was required to pick one Democrat and one Republican to complete the 14-member commission, which is headed by Democrat <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. Supporters once believed the bipartisan panel represented the best hope of breaking the impasse between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s opposition to tax increases and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'s refusal to trim domestic spending enough to tame the budget deficit. But even with the appointments, many observers said the commission faces a nearly impossible task of reaching a consensus among panel members who have squabbled openly over such issues as taxes and the need to trim defense spending. `` What <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has done is give the commission a renewed look of respectability, but the members are a long way from reaching a consensus on a credible plan that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will accept,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, head of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consulting firm that bears his name. The commission once had hoped to complete its work before Christmas but <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> has said the panel may not issue its recommendations until next September. At that time, the panel could serve as an emergency vehicle which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could use to throw together a compromise with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in order to avoid automatic spending cuts under the Gramm-Rudman deficit reduction law. But <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> said Tuesday that he hoped the commission would try to meet a March 1 deadline specified in the law creating the panel. The law did provide an escape clause that would allow the new president to delay the report until Sept. 1. The commission has scheduled 16 days of hearings in January and February to begin making decisions on a deficit-cutting plan even though those sessions have been clouded by a court battle over whether the commission can deliberate in secret. During the campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had derided the commission as a stalking horse for tax increases, something he has pledged repeatedly he will not accept. But in making his announcements Tuesday, he tempered his earlier skepticism, noting that he had named <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> one day after the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> ratified the Nov. 8 vote electing him president. `` The swiftness with which I am making these appointments underscores the importance I place on the need to reduce the federal budget deficit,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON>'s appointment had been expected, but the choice of <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> was a surprise and came after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> apparently rejected the advice of some aides that he select <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellmon </PERSON>, who as a ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in the 1970s had gained a reputation as a political pragmatist. By picking <PERSON> Laxalt </PERSON> over <PERSON> Bellmon </PERSON>, some observers said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> decided to go with more of a hardliner against taxes to insure that his `` no-new-tax'' pledge is adhered to. `` From everything I know about him, he would be against taxes and would want to look on the spending side for deficit reductions,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahn </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rahn </PERSON> is a leading anti-tax supply sider who had been considered as a possible choice for the commission himself. The other 12 members of the commission, evenly split between Democrats and Republicans, were appointed by congressional leaders and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made the appointments Tuesday in order to reassure financial markets of his seriousness in cutting the budget deficit. But he said it remains to be seen how seriously the president-elect will take the panel's findings. `` The suspicion is that regardless of what the commission says, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will ignore it,'' <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Crutsinger </PERSON> covers economics for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Korea 1stLd-Writethru a0630 12-20 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0630,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Roh Frees 281 Political Prisoners; 1,581 Others Rehabilitated</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout with new material and editing, UPDATING with
prisoners freed. No pickup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By M.H. AHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government freed 281 political prisoners throughout <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on Wednesday and restored the civil rights of 1,581 others in a sweeping amnesty to restore political peace. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said prison terms of 92 other political prisoners were reduced and 61 radical students were removed from police wanted lists. The government ordered the amnesty involving 2,015 of what it called `` politically motivated offenders'' as part of efforts to defuse a nationwide furor over demands that former President <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> <PERSON> Doo-hwan </PERSON> be punished for human rights abuses and corruption under his authoritarian regime. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> appealed to the nation last month to forgive <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> and promised to free political prisoners as part of a series of measures to wipe out vestiges of <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>'s government. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, a former general and ally of <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>, has pledged to introduce full democracy. Dissident groups accused <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> of betraying his promise to free all political prisoners and claimed about 300 remained in jail. Justice officials said 224 `` anti-state criminals'' still were behind bars, but said nearly all were Communist North Korean spies or dissidents convicted of violent crimes. The main political opposition parties welcomed the amnesty. They had frequently demanded such action as a way toward national reconciliation and democracy, but said they would still press for action against <PERSON> Chun </PERSON>. Among those released Wednesday were <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyun-jang </PERSON> and <PERSON> Moon </PERSON> <PERSON> Boo-shik </PERSON>. Each was serving a 20-year term for leading a raid on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cultural center in <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION>. One person died and three were hurt when the center was set afire in the protest over <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for the Chun government. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-kun </PERSON>, a leading dissident who won the <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> this year, had his civil rights restored. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON>, who was released last June, drew five years in 1986 on charges of overthrowing the government and spreading pro-North Korean propaganda. <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> claims he was forced to make a false confession under torture. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said the amnesty was the second since <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> succeeded <PERSON> Chun </PERSON> last Feb. 25 and involved the largest number of political offenders in a single amnesty.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-VisaFraud     12-20 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Visa Fraud,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former U.S. Diplomat Sentenced In Iranian Visa Fraud</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL PUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A senior diplomat who served as anti-fraud officer at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> was sentenced Tuesday to five years in federal prison after pleading guilty in a scheme to illegally sell visas to Iranian nationals. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>, former first secretary and consul in <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, was sentenced by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Lenore </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON> on conspiracy and fraud charges. <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>, other American citizens and Iranian nationals were accused of conspiring to unlawfully sell visas to Iranians wanting to emigrate to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Many of the Iranians had already been rejected for visas, or were otherwise ineligible to obtain them. As much as $ 5,000 was paid for a single visa, and $ 15,000 bought visas for a family of five, according to the indictment. <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>'s alleged co-conspirators, visa broker <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Arjad </PERSON> and his associate <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosales </PERSON>, traveled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> collecting passports and money from Iranian nationals, said <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION>. Those passports were then taken to <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> at the embassy, who would issue non-immigrant visas to the Iranians without the required documentation and personal interviews, <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON>, who was the embassy's anti-fraud officer and supervised visa operations, also falsified information on the visa applications and on confidential outgoing cables to other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassies to justify the illegal visas, <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> said. The indictment listed 12 sales that took place in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Istanbul </LOCATION> between July and December 1986. Some of the Iranian aliens who tried to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sates </LOCATION> have pleaded guilty in the case. <PERSON> Fennell </PERSON> has since resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     12-20 0957</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0993</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON> and <PERSON> Waylon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> are friends and country singers. Now they have something else in common: successful coronary bypass operations in the same hospital. Cash, 56, was in critical but stable condition in intensive care Monday after 2 -LCB- hours of surgery to restore normal blood flow to his heart with a double bypass, doctors said. `` His surgery went fine,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardin </PERSON>, who helped perform the operation. `` There was no evidence of any damage to his heart.'' Doctors have not said when Cash may be moved out of intensive care or when he may be released, according to hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, 51, who had a triple bypass a week ago, was moved into a private room over the weekend and doctors hope he will be home for Christmas, Ms. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A love story written by <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, starring <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON> and featuring three marriages but only one kiss, has been previewed by an audience at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. `` The Jeweler's Shop,'' the motion picture version of a play written by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> in 1960 when he was <PERSON> Karol </PERSON> <PERSON> Wojtyla </PERSON>, the Bishop of <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, was shown to 7,000 guests at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s Paul VI Hall Monday night. Directed by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> -LRB- `` Around the World in 80 Days'' -RRB-, the film is devoid of sexual tension except for the lone kiss between <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Olivia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hussey </LOCATION> -RRB- and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Occhipinti </PERSON> -RRB- after he proposes. The film recounts the three intertwined love stories of two young couples in war-torn 1939 <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and their oldest children, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Monica </PERSON>, who later fall in love. A jeweler, played by <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON>, sells the lovers their wedding rings, and a priest named <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Olbrychski </PERSON> -RRB- performs each marriage and counsels the couples through their hardships. `` Nothing takes up more space on the surface of life than love,'' <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> says, `` and nothing is more unknown and mysterious.'' Made in English and dubbed into Italian, French and German, the movie is scheduled for international release in February. The play, which was peformed on Italian radio in 1979, a year after the author became pope, has been translated into 15 languages. The only other published play written by a man who would become <PERSON> pope </PERSON> was `` History of Two Lovers'' by <PERSON> Enea </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Piccolomini </PERSON>, who was crowned Pope <PERSON> Pius </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> in 1458.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON> continues to walk and take other forms of exercise as part of his recuperation from a near-fatal motorcycle accident two weeks ago, a hospital spokesman said. `` All the indications are that he is going to make a total recovery,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>. `` His condition is still listed as fair. He still needs to be watched. He had a very serious accident,'' Wise said. <PERSON> Busey </PERSON>, 44, had brain surgery after he hit his head on a curb Dec. 4 when he fell from the motorcycle he was riding without a helmet. Police blamed <PERSON> Busey </PERSON> for the accident, but said no charges would be filed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Urich </PERSON>, who has played action heroes on `` Vegas'' and `` Spenser: For Hire,'' expects to shift gears and play a <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt-type </PERSON> character next season in an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> series from the producers of `` Family Ties.'' The half-hour show, tentatively titled `` American Dreamer,'' was inspired by an hour-long episode of `` Family Ties'' in which <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> stood on a darkened soundstage and harked back to various incidents in his life. `` We're going to constantly break the fourth wall, and if I had to describe it briefly, it'd be ` Our Town' for television,'' <PERSON> Urich </PERSON> said in a recent interview. <PERSON> Urich </PERSON> described his character as `` kind of a writer, like a -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> newsman -RRB- <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuralt </PERSON> guy, trying to get back in touch with <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and his sense of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and belonging there, but trying to live in the'90s.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GIBBON, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 17-year-old girl struggling to recover from a shooting accident that required the amputation of her leg just above the knee got some unexpected encouragement from Sen.-elect <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, whose leg was amputated below the knee after he was wounded in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, called <PERSON> Lana </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillming </PERSON> after hearing of her accident. `` I notice those sorts of things,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senator-elect and former governor said. `` I just told her I've got a lot of feeling for her and that I am her friend.'' `` He said he would be a real friend and gave me his telephone number to call if I ever needed to talk,'' Miss <PERSON> Gillming </PERSON> said. `` He also gave me the name and telephone number of his personal doctor in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION>.'' Miss <PERSON> Gillming </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON> told her an artificial leg eventually will allow her to function normally. `` That gave me a real good outlook for the future,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> went to a news conference in a different capacity: he worked as a television reporter for a day. <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> attended a news conference Monday about parking violators, then hit the pavement to tape some footage on the sidewalk. `` I was impressed,'' said cameraman <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, who kept the governor in focus for more than an hour. `` His stand-up could rival most of our reporters. It was a pretty long stand-up, 10 or 12 seconds, and he remembered most of it the first time.'' The stint was part of <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>'s Work Day program through which he seeks to get a better understanding of the state's work force. How did he like it? `` It takes more concentration when you are on this side of the microphone,'' said <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>. `` I've never been a believer you can be completely objective.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChildAbuse 1stLd-Writethru a0585 12-20 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Child Abuse, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0585,0887</SECOND>
<HEAD>Public Aware _ But Five Kids Still Die Daily</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 7th graf, `One day...', to UPDATE with
published report that city agency had failed to tell judge about
woman's history of child neglect. Picks up 8th graf, `Ninety-five
percent...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The public has glimpsed the nightmarish world of domestic violence through <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s testimony in the <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> case. But experts say more than increased awareness is needed to save the lives of children like 6-year-old <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> and, now, 5-year-old <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON>. `` We were seeing five deaths a day -LRB- nationally -RRB- before <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> died, and five deaths per day since then,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Krugman </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Kempe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> and Neglect in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. `` I ca n't blame the public. I do n't think the public knows what to do,'' said <PERSON> Krugman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> made headlines when she died in November 1987 _ a symbol of a system gone wrong. She made front-page news again last week, at the trial of <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> _ the man she knew as <PERSON> Daddy </PERSON>, the man accused of murdering her. But last Wednesday _ when the brutal beating death in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> of 5-year-old <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> grabbed the headlines away _ it was the same old story; only the name had changed. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Abigail </PERSON>, and the mother's boyfriend, <PERSON> Adrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, were unemployed. They lived in a city-owned housing project in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>. On the surface, they had nothing in common with the <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> family _ except that children in their home also were battered. One day after police found <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> standing over <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>'s limp body, they returned to the apartment and found <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>'s 9-year-old half-brother, <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON> <PERSON> Lebron </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON>, quivering in a closet, badly beaten with 10 bones broken. Family Court authorities charged Monday that welfare officials knew that Ms. <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> had a history of child neglect but failed to tell a judge about it, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said in Tuesday's editions that during a 1986 custody hearing, welfare officials called the woman a good mother even though the city's <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION> had filed a neglect petition against her three years earlier. `` Ninety-five percent of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public knows child abuse exists _ that's not the issue anymore,'' said <PERSON> Krugman </PERSON>. `` My impression is people make some cosmetic changes -LRB- after rekindled awareness of child abuse -RRB-; it's like firing a football coach when you've got bigger problem than just the coach.'' `` Now, we need a new kind of public awareness _ that physical abuse of children, the <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> type cases, are preventable if people want to do something.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> estimated there were 1,132 child-abuse fatalities in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year; <PERSON> Krugman </PERSON> puts the figure at 2,000 to 5,000. There were 2.25 million official reports of abused children nationally in 1987, including 25 percent who were physically abused and 14 percent who were sexually abused, the committee's report said. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> fit into both those categories, police said. She also fit into a third category: at least 103 children died of abuse last year in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Authorities say those numbers are n't likely to decline despite widespread publicity about child abuse and the <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> case _ live national television coverage on Cable News Network, a cover story in <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>, hours of local TV coverage of Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>'s testimony. But it will have some positive effect, they believe. `` The <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> case puts the spotlight on the topic,'' said Detective <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, coordinator of domestic violence programs for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police. `` This case is very important because it is that much more detailed, and serves to show the dynamics of violence in a family situation.'' Agreed <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Digirolamo </PERSON>, executive director of the Governor's <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Domestic Violence: `` There clearly is some increase in awareness. The deaths of <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> also illustrated one of the more frightening aspects of child abuse: it crosses all lines of race, economics and geography. And domestic violence is rarely limited to just one family member, experts in the field say. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> was a lawyer. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, his live-in lover, was a children's book editor. They lived a comfortable existence in a historic building in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'s upscale <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>. And, authorities said, their two illegally adopted children were ill-treated. When <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was found in a coma Nov. 2, 1987, the other child, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, was sitting in a dirty diaper, tethered to a chair and drinking spoiled milk. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> also had been badly battered. In both the <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> cases, drugs were apparently involved _ another disturbing trend which has contributed to the rising number of child abuse cases. Ms. <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> has detailed how she and <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> freebased cocaine while <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> lay unconscious in another room. Neighbors of <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Cortez </PERSON> said they were also drug users, smoking marijuana and crack. From July 1, 1987, to June 30, 1988, the city <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> estimated 14 percent of its 55,286 reported abuse cases were tied to drugs _ a 67 percent jump from the previous 12 months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-InauguralMemories Bjt   12-20 0895</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Inaugural Memories, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Illustrations of Inaugurals Past</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the days before newspapers had the ability to print photographs, special artists were dispatched to great national events _ including presidential inaugurals _ to record the event on sketch pads. That era is recalled, in these days before the inauguration of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as the nation's 41st president, in a small Capitol exhibit. It displays the views that artists for `` <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s Weekly,'' `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON>'s Illustrated News'' and other publications provided of the inauguration of every president from 1853 to 1905. Entitled `` Hail To The Chief,'' the exhibit also recalls the circumstances that gave each of those ceremonies its own flavor. An 1853 sketch shows President-elect <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> and outgoing President <PERSON> Millard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fillmore </PERSON> striding through the Capitol Rotunda on the way to the inaugural platform on the East Front, the traditional site of inaugurals until President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took the oath of office on the West Front in 1981. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s vice president, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, was sworn in by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> counsel in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, the only president or vice president-elect ever to take the oath of office outside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Convalescing from a serious illness, <PERSON> King </PERSON> died six weeks later. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> objected on religious grounds from swearing his oath. He exercised an option permitted him by the Constitution and affirmed it instead. He is the only president to have done that. The drawing of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>'s inauguration in 1857 shows the scaffolding and hoists being used to build the new <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> wing of the Capitol. By the time <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> was inaugurated four years later the new high dome of the Capitol is shown half completed. By the time of <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s second inauguration in 1865 the dome is complete, crowned with the statue of Armed Freedom on top. An 1861 illustration shows <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> and <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> en route to the Capitol in an open carriage, passing a shop sign reading `` Great Book Sale.'' The exhibit's text recalls that when <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> reached the inaugural stand, he could not find a place to put his `` hallmark stove pipe hat.'' <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s unsuccessful rival for the presidency, reached out his hand for it. `` If I can not be president, at least I can hold his hat,'' he said. In 1869 the nation's preeminent war hero, Gen. <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, was sworn in as president and his predecessor, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, broke a precedent, Insulted by <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>'s refusal to accompany him on the traditional ride down <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> refused to take part in the inaugural ceremonies. The general served two scandal-plagued terms and the 1877 inaugural drawing shows him looking on as <PERSON> Rutherford </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> takes the oath. <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, a Republican, had lost the popular vote to Democrat <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tilden </PERSON> but some <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> votes were in dispute. The issue was settled by a special commission and the nod went to <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>. Since March 4, the date of presidential inaugurations in that era, fell on a Sunday that year, the ceremonies were postponed until Monday, March 5. But to ensure that the nation not be without a president, <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> took the oath secretly on March 3 in the Red Room of the White House. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> was inaugurated in 1881 and for the first time women were front and center on the inaugural platform, moving from the seats in the rear traditionally reserved for them. His wife, mother and the wife of President <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> all sat in the front row. When <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON> completed the presidential oath, he turned and kissed his mother, the first mother ever to see her son inaugurated as president. Beginning the first of two non-consecutive terms in 1885, <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> took the oath on a family Bible inscribed to <ORGANIZATION> S.G. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION>. It had been given to him by his mother before he dropped his given name, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON>. The illustration for the <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> inauguration in 1889 shows <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> taking the oath surrounded by a sea of umbrellas. Officials had wanted to move the ceremonies in out of the rain but the president-elect overruled them. The year 1889 was also the centennial of the inauguration of the first president, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> made the most of the celebration, playing the role of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> at several events in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. If he cares to, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can follow suit in 1989, the bicentennial of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s inauguration. The artist who depicted <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON>'s inauguration in 1897 shows spectators viewing the scene from the roof of the newly completed <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. In 1905, <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>'s Rough Riders gathered to ride in <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION>'s inaugural parade. But they ran into a problem: There were n't enough cavalry horses for them to ride. So they used horses borrowed from the horse artillery which were accustomed to hauling cannons, not passengers. The horses did n't follow orders and, the exhibit text notes, `` The Rough Riders literally lived up to their name.'' At the ceremonies, <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> wore a ring containing a lock of <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s hair loaned to him for the occasion by Secretary of State <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hay </PERSON> who had served as <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> secretary. By that time the era of the `` special artist'' was nearly over. The era of the press photographer was about to begin.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knutson </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ElectoralCollege Bjt   12-20 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Electoral College, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Switched Vote Only Surprise in Electoral College Vote</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> elector who says the nation has `` outgrown'' the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> provided the only surprise during the constitutional ritual officially electing <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as the nation's 41st president. <PERSON> Margarette </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> switched her Democratic ballot _ voting for <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> for president and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for vice president _ as she and 537 other electors carried out their constitutional duty. Otherwise, all voted as pledged to give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Republican running mate <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> each 426 electoral votes, far more than the 270 needed for election over <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. The switched ballot gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> one vote fewer than the 112 presidential electors he earned in winning 10 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. `` I did it for a reason, and the reason was to make a statement about the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, nurse `` It was fine then -LRB- when it began -RRB-, but we've outgrown it.'' For example, <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> said, she and the 269 other female electors `` could have put a woman in'' as president if they had n't wanted to vote for the nominated candidates. `` I wish I had voted for <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> now,'' she said. The <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> vote set the stage for another suspense-free ceremony on Jan. 4, when a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> meets and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, as vice president, is to open the sealed ballots and formally declare himself the president-elect. Although other electors voted as expected, many agreed with <PERSON> Leach </PERSON> about the antiquated but constitutionally required <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> system devised by the Founding Fathers two centuries ago. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> elector <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schouweiller </PERSON> called it `` silly'' and `` archaic.'' `` However,'' she added, `` I suspect it will be with us for a long time to come.'' After casting their votes for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s 11 electors voted 9-2 to pass along some unsolicited advice to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the form of a resolution urging the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> be scrapped. `` The system is fatally flawed,'' said elector <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Longley </PERSON>. `` We should not be in a position to decide upon who should be president. It should be decided most appropriately by the American people.'' Although the Constitution does not require electors to vote as their state's voters directed, there have been few deviations over two centuries of elections. Before <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>'s change, there had been only eight `` faithless electors.'' Democratic electors in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, and a Republican in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, did n't carry through with suggestions that they might cast symbolic votes for another candidate for president or vice president. `` I have reservations about Mr. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' said <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> elector <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spivey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` But our president -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB-, who I do not have reservations about, has seen fit to choose him, so I'm going to go with what he says. ... I should have abstained, probably.'' Some states carried out brief ceremonies steeped in history, while others made a party of the event. Still others got the formalities of voting and paper-signing over within 10 minutes. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, telephoned electors pledged to him in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and addressed a ceremonial gathering of his electors in the <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` I'm sorry I'm not here in another capacity,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` But I want you to know there's nothing that compares to running for the presidency of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` I wish the president-elect well,'' he added. `` But I also know there were some things we were fighting about in the campaign that are going to be there on January 20th, and they're important.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will be sworn into office Jan. 20. Many electors said they had received mail from people urging them to deny <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> his election as vice president. Some said they were n't enthusiastic about <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, but they were n't buying the idea of dumping him. `` I love <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and I'm very enthusiastic about that, but I'm not real happy with the selection of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>,'' said elector <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> chairman who voted for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> anyway. `` I think the process should be changed and I hope it will be changed,'' he said. Among the other electors who voted for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> were <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s son <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>; his designated White House chief of staff, Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> football coach <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign supporter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SpacePlans Bjt   12-20 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Plans, Bjt,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Blueprint Envisions Mars Missions, Martian Moon Station</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> is laying the groundwork to send the next generation of astronauts beyond the Earth's orbit early in the 21st century, with missions to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION> and a space station on a Martian moon among the possibilities. In a report released Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said the nation must make a `` modest investment of resources'' during the 1990s to prepare the nation for a range of opportunities in space. `` This ability is critical to <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> leadership in space,'' said the report titled, `` Beyond Earth's Boundaries: Human Exploration of the Solar System in the 21st Century.'' The report examined several strategies for exploring the inner reaches of the solar system, including establishing a manned lunar observatory, setting up a space station on the <LOCATION> Martian </LOCATION> moon Phobos or sending astronauts to the red planet itself early in the next century. The ambitious blueprint addresses President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s directive on space policy issued last January. The directive sets as a long-range goal `` to expand human presence and activity beyond <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> orbit into the solar system.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, assistant administrator of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Office of Exploration, said `` there's every indication'' the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will support that policy. The underpinnings of any strategy to send space explorers to the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> and beyond in the next two decades will be increased <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> funding for development of new technology, life sciences research, unmanned robotic missions, development of a new fleet of launch vehicles able to lift heavier loads, and continued commitment to Space Station Freedom, which is planned for Earth orbit in the mid-1990s. If those conditions are met, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> could send astronauts to <LOCATION> Phobos </LOCATION> in 2003 or to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION> in 2007 or establish by 2005 a lunar base from which astronauts could build a Mars outpost in 2015, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>, who headed the Office of Exploration during production of the report. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> said the agency has not developed reliable cost estimates for the missions studied in the report. `` We are not talking about missions that are cheap,'' he said, but `` we think these are affordable.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said such missions probably could be accomplished at less real cost than the Apollo program, which put <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> astronauts on the moon in 1969. At its height, the Apollo program cost about 4 percent of the federal budget annually, which in today's dollars would be about $ 25 billion, he said. `` You ca n't do the civil space program on the cheap,'' he said, noting the nation now spends about $ 11 billion annually on <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> programs. The fiscal 1989 federal budget is about $ 1.1 trillion. `` We're not a poor nation. We can figure out how to do these things if they're important to us,'' he said, adding that international cooperation could help support these missions. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> must leap many technological hurdles before it can accomplish the goal of establishing a permanent human presence in space, but `` I do n't see any show stoppers there.'' <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Project Pathfinder, under whose umbrella much of the research will be done, gets $ 40 million this year and the same amount next year, despite <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s request for $ 100 million. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said annual funding for the program must increase to $ 100 million soon. The report focused on four case studies for sending astronauts to the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION>, Phobos and <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. One scenario would send astronauts to Phobos and then on to Mars; another would launch astronauts directly to Mars; a third would establish a manned observatory on the far side of the moon; and a fourth would use an outpost on the moon as a stepping stone to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON>, who is now special assistant to the director at <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, emphasized that the four case studies are not proposed missions, but rather vehicles for assessing exploration techniques and validating assumptions. A key finding, <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> said, is that a mission to Phobos could significantly offset the scale and uncertainties of a direct mission to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. An Earth-to-Mars mission would require many new technologies, including advanced propulsion and braking systems, and would require advanced operations such as in-orbit assembly, long-term storage and in-orbit transfer of propellant. Much work in the life sciences also would be needed, and because the mission would last more than 14 months artificial gravity might be needed to maintain the health of the crew, the report said. Phobos is believed to be an asteroid `` captured'' by Mars' gravity and is thought to contain a substantial amount of water and carbon-based materials, which could offer potential sources of rocket fuel that could be tapped for exploratory missions to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION> `` Phobos is an attractive way to go to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` I would be surprised if Phobos is n't a part of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> going to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Robbery     12-20 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Robbery,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bank Robber Dies In Siege After Policeman Killed In Raid</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos LON3,4,5</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COVENTRY, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bank robbers killed one policeman and seriously wounded another in the central <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> city of Coventry Monday before holing up in a suburban house where one robber shot himself to death, police said. One of the alleged robbers gave himself up but the other ignored police attempts to negotiate and then shot himself in the head in a back room of the house, said <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Midlands </LOCATION> Assistant Chief Constable <PERSON> Mervyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Police Superintendent <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> said the officer who died was an unarmed patrolman in his mid-30s. He was thought to have died instantly after being shot at point-blank range with a double-barreled shotgun. Police said he had stopped the raiders' getaway car soon after the robbery at the <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in which $ 1,100 was stolen. The robbers then switched cars and drove onto a highway where they were rammed by an unmarked police car. Police said a patrolman in that vehicle was shot in the stomach. The gunmen then ran across a golf course before forcing their way into the home of a plumbing contractor and his family. It was not known whether they took any hostages. Police said the wounded officer, also in his 30s, was recovering in hospital. A third officer was being treated in hospital for shock.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Argentina-Electricity     12-20 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Argentina-Electricity,0571</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moon Over Buenos Aires _ For Lack Of Artificial Light</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At night, the brightest light shining in this <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> city of 10 million is cast by the moon. Spotlights on public monuments, the flashing neon glare of billboards, lights in office towers, store windows and even on a Christmas tree near a main thoroughfare have been turned down or even off by government order. There is an electricity shortage. Streetlights have been dimmed by 50 percent. Drivers, who usually careen along narrow, often cobblestone streets downtown with only their cars' parking lights have taken to turning on low beams. The problem stems from seasonally low levels of water in the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Limay </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Neuquen </LOCATION> rivers that feed hydroelectric stations and the shutdown for repairs or maintenance of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s two nuclear power plants. The system `` is working at the limit of its capacity, and we should be prepared for whatever eventuality and are running the risk of a total outage,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Larriqueta </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. Portenos, as residents of this port city are called, have had to make do with rotating, scheduled outages of five hours a day since last week. City residents have become accustomed to summertime electricity shortages as the city has grown faster than its public services can handle. Blackouts, which have occurred half a dozen times since 1965, are relatively rare, however. The last occurred in November 1985. The latest scheduled outages have meant walking up flights of stairs for lack of working elevators, sweating in late spring heat for lack of air conditioning, and dodging four, five and sometimes six lanes of cars at rush hour for lack of functioning traffic signals. Beginning today, the hours of the three government-controlled television stations in this capital city will be cut back to 12 hours _ noon to midnight. The two private stations have been requested by the government to do likewise. The usual hours of operation are 7 a.m. to 3 a.m. Nighttime events like horseracing at the <LOCATION> Hipodromo </LOCATION> and concerts have been canceled until further notice unless the facility has its own source of electricity. Soccer games, usually played at night to avoid daytime heat, have been rescheduled for the afternoon. At the huge Salto Grande hydroelectric complex on the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> north of the capital, only one of 14 turbines was operating Tuesday. The rest were idled by lack of water. The Atucha nuclear power plant, about 60 miles north of <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>, has been shut down since August for repairs to its cooling system. The Embalse station, 465 miles to the west of the capital, is undergoing routine maintenance. About three weeks ago, the government for the first time in years ordered clocks to be set back one hour to take advantage of the extra daylight. The time change will stay in effect at least until Jan. 15, when one of the nuclear plants should be back on line, said <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, director of planning at the the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION>' energy secretariat Water levels probably wo n't rise until seasonal rains return in May, he said. On the lighter side, energy restrictions will be lifted the following two weekends for Christmas and New Year's, a government spokesman said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w Ex-CongressmanReadiesRunForTopDemocraticPartyJob     12-20
0397</FIRST>
<SECOND>Ex-Congressman Readies Run For Top Democratic Party Job</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: News conference scheduled for noon EST; may be topped</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KATHERINE RIZZO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> is entering the race for chairman of the national <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with support from <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senators but without the backing of his state's top two <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> scheduled a news conference today to make his bid official. He has won the support of Sens. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, but <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruvulo </PERSON> and Vice Chair <PERSON> Thea </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> on Monday lined up behind another candidate, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Democratic Chairman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON> was among the first to announce his candidacy for the job being vacated by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON> on Monday announced the support of 13 other state party leaders from the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. They include the state party chairs from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> as well as vice chairs from several states. <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> said he's confident <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members who examine his background will be convinced he's right for the job. `` I've built a ward organization; I've run a city council; I've run an $ 800 million business,'' <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> said Monday `` I have the communications skills to talk to the people who are going to financially energize any political party in this country.'' `` I believe I have a very viable chance to win,'' <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON>'s decision followed a lengthy testing-the-waters period. `` I've been very much encouraged by people I respect deeply, people like -LRB- former <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman -RRB- <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> and others,'' <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> said, adding that he's also lined up the backing of several members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> as well as the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1984 campaign manager, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1988 campaign manager, <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinkney </PERSON>. That's significant because one of the contenders for the post is <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, a longtime party activist most recently associated with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON> is a former congressman and <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> president who dropped out of public life after a 1976 Democratic Primary loss to <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>. <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Reps. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoes </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Tip </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> last week signed a mailgram urging union leaders to back <PERSON> Stanton </PERSON>. The party's new leader is to be chosen at a meeting in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Feb. 9 and 10.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-People-Sills     12-20 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-People-Sills,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beverly Sills Given Farewell Party</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> gave departing general director <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> a farewell party Monday night, and the grand ballroom of the Plaza Hotel resounded with celebrity toasts. `` She is so warm, effervescent and fun, you immediately forget her incredible voice. When you do, she gets really annoyed,'' teased actress <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> concluded, `` You have garnered as much love as you have praise for your work as an artist and business woman, and I toast you.'' <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> noted that she has had a `` meaningful relationship'' with the opera company for 33 years and two months. She was its coloratura superstar and for the past 10 years its general director. Following her resignation the opera announced she would be succeeded in March by <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>. `` I have reached the age of 59, and 50 years of my life have been spent in opera,'' she said. `` Interesting things are being offered to me. I feel a third career is somewhere out there right around the corner.'' <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> program `` 60 Minutes'' suggested in his toast that <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> become mayor of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, or as he put it, `` her honor, the prima donna.'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, who spoke at a reception before the dinner, suggested that <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> become a TV interviewer. The master of ceremonies, TV interviewer <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, sang original lyrics spelling `` Beverly,'' beginning with `` B is for the beauty of your soul, dear.'' Then she invited the audience to sing a second time through. Songwriters <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Comden </PERSON> and <PERSON> Adolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> sang, very fast, words they'd written to the finale of <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>'s `` Fourth Symphony,'' ending with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Sills </PERSON>' nickname, `` Bubbles, Bubbles, Bubbles.'' Actress <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> praised Miss <PERSON> Sills </PERSON>' acting in opera and said, `` Let me make you our national city treasure.'' Actress <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldon </PERSON> said about the honoree, `` There is this possibility for human radiance that can transcend all kinds of troubles and make life really worthwhile.'' Actor <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Cariou </PERSON> called Miss <PERSON> Sills </PERSON> `` an artist of life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-UraniumPlant     12-20 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Uranium Plant,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Department Expects Agreement on Ohio Plant Cleanup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A consent decree may be reached by the end of the week for the cleanup of a federally owned uranium enrichment plant in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official says. An agreement to clean up the <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION> Gaseous Diffusion Plant near <LOCATION> Piketon </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> was announced last month by <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> and state Attorney General <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. However, the plan still was under review by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, spokesman <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmets </PERSON> said. A senior department official, who asked that he not be identified, said the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` may have a decision by the end of the week on a consent decree'' that would involve court supervision of a cleanup. When <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> and <PERSON> Celebrezze </PERSON> announced the $ 50 million cleanup plan last month, they said it was significant because the federal agency would be bound by state law and regulation. The <LOCATION> Piketon </LOCATION> plant processes uranium for fuel for commercial nuclear power reactors. It generates toxic wastes such as polychlorinated biphenyls, or PCBs, solvents and metals, as well as radioactive materials. When the agreement was announced Nov. 22, <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> said he hoped it would serve as a model for other tough cleanup cases, such as the government-owned Fernald plant near <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. Environmental officials say that plant has dumped radioactive waste improperly, possibly contaminating ground water, since it began processing uranium for nuclear weapons in 1951. The <LOCATION> Piketon </LOCATION> plan calls for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to be subject to orders issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which would supervise the cleanup of about 6 million pounds of waste. Last month, officials said the agreement still needed to be incorporated into a federal court consent decree.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LsCrisis     12-20 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls Crisis,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regulators Propose Reinsurance Agency To Oversee Thrift Clean Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal regulators are proposing the creation of a new agency, possibly drawing money from banks, credit unions and savings institutions, to oversee the clean up of the money-losing savings and loan industry. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates the nation's 3,000 <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls, on Monday sent the broad outlines of the proposal to the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which is formulating the incoming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's plans for dealing with hundreds of insolvent savings institutions, agency spokesman <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Wall </PERSON>, in a speech to a group called the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, proposed what he called a `` reinsurance agency'' for all federally insured financial institutions. On an unrelated topic, Wall also said the bank board is offering to make foreclosed properties from failed savings institutions available to house the homeless in a half dozen cities. The bank board's insurance fund, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, has been paying for a record number of <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L rescues this year primarily through promissory notes pledging future income from an assessment on still-operating institutions. Wall has argued previously that the fees paid by <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls to the <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>, as well as by banks and credit unions to separate insurance funds, were meant to cover a `` normal'' level of failures, not the `` catastrophic'' level of the current thrift crisis. Through Monday, regulators said they have resolved the cases of 159 insolvent thrifts this year. More than 400 insolvent <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls remain open and hundreds of others are close to insolvency. The reinsurance agency would oversee three insurance funds _ for banks, <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls and credit unions. It could collect premiums from all three, spending them when one of the funds got in trouble. It also could serve as the mechanism for further borrowing to pay for the thrift crisis or as the conduit for any money <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wanted to spend on the cleanup. <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> board member <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, in an interview, said the proposal leaves open who will pay for the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L cleanup and whether a new agency's expenditures would be counted toward the budget deficit. `` I do n't think it is intended to be a back door way of getting them -LRB- banks and credit unions -RRB- to pay for the <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>'s current problems,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. `` The concept is both a funding mechanism and a forward looking means of dealing with catastrophic costs'' in the future. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in weekend editions that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, in its 1990 budget, will acknowledge for the first time that some taxpayer money must be spent on the thrift industry problem. An administration source, who declined to be named, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates the cost of restoring the thrift industry to health at $ 60 billion to $ 75 billion if interest rates remain unchanged and as high as $ 105 billion if interest rates increase by two percentage points. The figures were first reported by The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. Regarding the proposal to use S & amp; L properties for the homeless, <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said the bank board is talking with six or seven cities in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and in the North and <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. He declined to identify them. <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said the bank board would lend the properties _ in some cases commercial buildings near soup kitchens _ to municipal governments, which in turn would pay to administer them as temporary shelters. `` That ball is in their court at this juncture. They have to decide if they have the funds,'' he said. `` We would like to get it done in the winter when this housing would be most useful to the homeless.'' Discussions with the cities started several months ago, <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> said. Another effort, to persuade private groups to purchase foreclosed homes from the bank board and rehabilitate them for poor families, began about a year ago, he said. Wall disclosed the homeless initiative on the same day that President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in announcing the appointment of Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, as secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, said his administration would seek innovative solutions to the problem of homelessness.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881220-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-20-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FAA-HighDensity     12-20 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FAA-High Density,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>FAA Proposes Change in Airport `High Density' Rule</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
