<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAssessment     09-13 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Assessment,0284</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Board Approves 4.4 Percent Assessment Increase</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The board of directors of The Associated Press approved unanimously a 1989 general assessment increase of 4.4 percent for newspaper and broadcast members. The increase takes effect Jan. 15, 1989, for <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s 1,463 newspaper and 5,700 broadcast members. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> board chairman and chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, noted that the increase was below inflation estimates of 5 percent to 5.5 percent for next year. `` The increase continues the recent trend of assessment adjustments less than the general rate of inflation,'' he said Tuesday. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said `` stringent cost controls and new revenues from nonmember sources'' enabled the board to restrict the increase to 4.4 percent and still fund major service improvements now under way. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s proposed operating and capital budgets were examined by the board on a detailed, line-by-line basis. The budgets provide for expansion of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s news staff, mostly in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, to help meet the needs of <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s 28 percent increase in newspaper membership over the past five years, <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said. The budgets also provide support for the new high-speed PhotoStream and GraphicsNet systems, as well as for total replacement of editing systems in all domestic bureaus. The general assessment increase will be combined with the fifth step of the phase-in of the circulation-based newspaper formula for those not yet on card with the new formula, which was adopted in 1985. Changes in circulation will also be reflected in the new assessment for each newspaper member. Each member will receive exact figures on the assessment change in October, <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LyingOfficial 1stLd-Writethru   09-13 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lying Official, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0674,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Board President Says He Lies To Uncover Leaks</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: UPDATES throughout with mayor removing board president,
comments from Hollis new conference.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON> removed the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> president on Tuesday after he admitted lying to board members as a way of finding out who leaks stories to the media. <PERSON> Meldon </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>, who was appointed by the mayor to a one-year term as board president in December, will remain on the board. The mayor appoints the nine board members, who serve as volunteers. <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>, an attorney, admitted earlier Tuesday that he used poor judgment in planting three different versions of a story to track down news leaks and said that he would resign if the mayor asked him to. `` Whether or not I retain the public confidence ... is ... a matter for the public to decide, for the mayor to decide and for the school board to decide,'' <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> said at a news conference Tuesday afternoon. <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON> called <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>' actions `` a terrible mistake in judgment.'' `` My view is that the public can tolerate an official being wrong on an issue,'' <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON> said. `` What people generally find intolerable is an official lying to them.'' Tape recordings of <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>'s remarks Monday to the <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, a political club, show he said he leaked false information to school board members `` to see if they were lying to me.'' `` I know who's doing the lying,'' he said in the speech. `` I know who it is. I feed them the lies, then they run out and lie to the press.'' <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> said Tuesday he could not recall using the word `` lie'' in describing the way he released information on how candidates for school superintendent would be interviewed earlier this year. He said he believed leaks were undermining the selection process, because some candidates threatened to withdraw if their candidacies were made public. He said he had become a political target and the object of news leaks because of his attempts to uncover favoritism in the awarding of grants in the school system. Board member <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutman </PERSON> said Tuesday that he was bewildered by <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON>' remarks. `` I think there's something wrong with the man. I do n't even know what he's talking about,'' <PERSON> Gutman </PERSON> said. `` The whole thing is getting uglier and uglier. We are trustees -LRB- with -RRB- the most important responsibility in the city.'' Some board members, <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> said, `` walk out of meetings and tell you we have a deal and then before I can get to my office the press is calling me asking me ` did you all decide so and so.' `` I know who they are. I know who is doing the leaking. I know who is doing the lying. That's OK. It will be taken care of in time,'' <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> acknowledged dissension within the board. However, he took issue with an article in Monday's editions of The -LRB- <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun, which said the school board was in a revolt. Problems arose last spring between <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> and board members when they were prevented from participating in the selection of a new school superintendent. Problems resurfaced in July when <PERSON> Hollis </PERSON> decided to hire a new executive director and several board members said they felt the full board should have voted on the post.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Snakes     09-13 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Snakes,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Of Reptiles Will Be Limited To Four Snakes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT COQUITLAM, British Columbia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new law prompted by <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s slithering, squeaking menagerie is forcing him to get rid of 146 of his snakes. Responding to neighbors' complaints about living next door to a house filled with 150 snakes _ and several hundred rats and mice needed to feed them _ the municipal council voted Monday to limit to four the number of snakes or rodents in a household. `` They do n't belong in a residential neighborhood; in an urban setting, 150 of anything is too much,'' said <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keryluk </PERSON>. `` I would n't want to live next door to a house where I know there are snakes or rodents in large numbers.'' <PERSON> Keryluk </PERSON>, co-chairman of the council committee that proposed the bylaw amendment, said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> keeps his reptiles and rodents in cages. `` The concern in the neighborhood is about the rodents or the snakes breaking loose,'' he said. `` What if an uncaring person were to break into his house and kick some of the cages apart?'' <PERSON> Alf </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who lives across the street from <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, said he complained about the snakes 2 -LCB- years ago after he found one in his yard. `` It was over 6 feet long and had a head about the size of an orange,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` It was sunning itself half on the wall of my patio and half on the ground.'' <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has a large variety of snakes, but <PERSON> Keryluk </PERSON> said he believes none is venomous. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> did not return messages left on his home answering machine. The amendment to the animal regulation bylaw, which excludes pet stores and schools, also prohibits venomous snakes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6MilesUpandSleepyII-1stAdd     09-13 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy II - 1st Add,0608</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNDATED: the trip.''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON> and others hook pilots and engineers to monitors while they fly. They hope to see whether crew members make more mistakes when such physical signs as body temperature and heartbeat suggest they are less alert. Much of that data is still being collected and analyzed. But <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON> said it's clear that by the third night of such schedules as the San Francisco-London-Seattle tour, the cockpit crew becomes increasingly lethargic. Dr. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Carskadon </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> has shown in the laboratory what <PERSON> Graeber </PERSON> sees in the cockpit: The effects of lost sleep accumulate over time. `` Most people, particularly those who are trained as pilots are, can cope with the effects of chronic sleep deprivation fairly well most of the time,'' she said. `` But ... a vulnerability is set up that puts them at risk for catastrophic events to occur.'' Experts say that when people are tired, they become sloppy. Motivation flags, inertia sets in. They take short-cuts and ignore small details. Flying a big plane, however, is mostly a matter of paying attention to small details _ setting instruments, following checklists, getting weather reports, watching dials. `` It's the errors of omission that occur because of lapses in attention that are the hallmark of fatigue-related accidents,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Czeisler </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. Such omissions would include not `` noticing an indicator that's not right, anticipating a problem before it occurs, thinking many steps down the line,'' he said. Sometimes pilots and flight engineers fall asleep. On long cruises, especially over oceans, this is not terribly dangerous as long as someone in the cockpit stays awake. But sleep is contagious. The sleep experts say their research has turned up many tales of entire crews nodding off. Another concern is micro-sleep, a shadowy state in which people are half asleep. With the brain waves of sleep intruding on those of wakefulness, people in this condition can continue to perform duties while only vaguely aware of what's going on around them. `` It's much worse than being, frankly, fully asleep, because they can continue to carry out routine tasks,'' said <PERSON> Czeisler </PERSON>. `` If they were truly asleep, someone else at least might notice.'' These problems occur, in part, because jet travel ignores the circadian timekeeper, the product of millions of years of evolution on a planet rotating once each 24 hours. Each day, the clock oversees a symphony of changes in body temperature, alertness and hormonal secretions, all of them geared to roughly a 24-hour cycle. For most people, the daily swing reaches its low point from 3:30 to 5 a.m. This is when they are sleepiest. There is another, less pronounced, valley of drowsiness in the afternoon from 4 to 5. The body temperature is also lowest at these times. Consider the pilot who leaves <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on a late-night, cross-country flight. Even if he slept during the day, he's likely to feel sleepy early in the morning as his body temperature falls. By the time he checks into a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> hotel, his body temperature is rising again _ his body clock is telling him to wake up. Even though he is tired, sleep is difficult. He awakens feeling ragged and has to fly again. `` The pilot who flies across multiple time zones faces the problem that his body continues at the old time zone,'' said <PERSON> Dinges </PERSON>. `` He is forced to try to sleep when his body clock wants him to be awake and to be awake when his body clock wants him to sleep.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEXT: Solutions _ As Simple as Naptime?</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0008EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese-Ethics Bjt   09-13 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese-Ethics, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese Attorney Says Ethics Office Impugns Former Attorney General</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lawyer for <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> says the former attorney general's reputation has been impugned unfairly by a <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> memorandum on <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> that declares that `` simply avoiding criminal conduct is not the mark of public service.'' Ethics office director <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> said Monday that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> failed to meet federal ethics requirements by hanging onto $ 14,000 in telephone stock and by assisting longtime friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON>'s based his memo on the results of a criminal investigation completed this summer by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>. Although <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> declined to prosecute <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, he concluded that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> probably broke federal conflict-of-interest laws twice by handling matters affecting the telecommunications industry at the time he held the phone stock. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> declared he had been vindicated because he had not been prosecuted. But <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> said: `` A major purpose of this memorandum is to remind and inform that simply avoiding criminal conduct is not the mark of public service.'' The critique was sent to ethics officers in the federal government. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocap </PERSON>, a lawyer for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, said in a statement: `` We are dismayed'' by <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON>'s memo, that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s `` integrity and reputation have been unfairly impugned.'' <PERSON> Rocap </PERSON> said <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> `` apparently read the McKay report,'' but not the rebuttal to it filed by <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s lawyers. In it, they said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s behavior had met the highest ethical standards. <PERSON> Rocap </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> had rejected a request to meet with <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s attorneys. A letter last Wednesday from <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s lawyers said the findings would be based on `` undisputed facts'' and that the request for a meeting was therefore being denied. <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> also may have violated a presidential executive order on ethics and accompanying regulations, a question under review by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s office of public responsibility. The executive order says federal employees should avoid any action which might create the appearance of, among other things, using public office for private gain, giving preferential treatment or adversely affecting the confidence of the public in the integrity of government. `` There is no more clarion standard ... than that which exhorts an employee to avoid any action that adversely affects the confidence of the public in the integrity of the government,'' <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> said. `` While Mr. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s personal reputation could not but have suffered as a result of this investigation, the public's confidence in the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> has also suffered One need only look at the well-publicized personnel resignations in the department to see why this standard is at issue.'' Concerned over the impact <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continued tenure was having on the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, former Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and criminal division chief <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> resigned in protest in March. <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON> noted that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> promised in 1985 when he became attorney general to sell the phone stock because it presented a potential conflict of interest. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> listed the stock on subsequent financial disclosure forms as having been sold. In reality, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, without informing the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> or the ethics office, transferred the stock to his financial manager, <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Chinn </PERSON>, who is under indictment along with <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> attorney, on charges of racketeering in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> scandal. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> finally retrieved the stock and sold it last year after he came under criminal investigation. In addition, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s agreement with the ethics office stipulated that he would remove himself temporarily from any matter involving <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, a longtime friend of the attorney general who had represented him in an independent counsel's investigation in 1984. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> was owed legal fees as a result. But during the period <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> had agreed to recuse himself from involvement with matters concerning <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> telephoned then-national security adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> to arrange a meeting for <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> in connection with a proposed $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline. `` This office did not accept Mr. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s ethics agreement lightly, does not accept his failure to comply with it lightly and will not accept other nominees' agreements lightly in the future,'' <PERSON> Nebeker </PERSON>'s memo said. `` These agreements serve an important purpose not only for the individual involved but for the public. This investigation of Mr. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> is a stark example of the results of inattention to such an agreement by an official.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-6Miles-FAARules     09-13 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-6 Miles-FAA Rules,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Regulations Date Back to 1930s</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-6 Miles Up and Sleepy II</HEAD>
<HEAD>By FRED BAYLES</HEAD>
<BYLINE>and</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Today's federal rules for pilot rest and duty hours come out of the era of the DC-3, when propeller-driven airliners droned along at speeds less than 200 mph and took eight hours to fly from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Revised in 1964 and again in 1985, many of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulations </ORGANIZATION> differ little from rules first issued in the 1930s. Crews for large airlines on domestic routes ca n't be scheduled to fly longer than eight hours between required rest periods. They ca n't fly more than 30 hours in seven days; 100 hours a month and 1,000 hours a year. Crews may exceed the eight-hour limit if their scheduled flights are delayed by weather, traffic or equipment problems. Commuter airline pilots may fly 34 hours in 7 days; 120 hours in a month and 1,200 a year. Crews must be given at least nine hours' rest in a 24-hour period. However, that can be cut to eight hours if the next rest period is increased by two to three hours, based on an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> formula. Three-member international crews can fly up to 12 hours a day; they must get 18 hours' rest if they fly more than 24 hours in 72 hours or 20 hours within 48 hours. Larger crews can fly longer; two-member crews can fly only eight hours between rest periods. However, the rules do n't speak to duty hours _ measured from the time a pilot reports to the airport, usually an hour before first takeoff, through the day's schedule including sitting on the ground between flights, to departure after the final flight. Such reckoning can stretch a crew's time on the job to 16 hours. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> limit their pilots' hours by calculating duty time, the number of takeoffs and landings, the time of day and the number of time zones crossed None of these factors is considered under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial regulations. The latest <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> rules are the result of so-called `` regulation by negotiation.'' Union and airline representatives met in 1983-84 with <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials and a mediator to work out minor changes in domestic rules. These rules are often used by airlines and their unions as a baseline for schedules stricter than government guidelines. `` Our own rules go on beyond the FAR -LRB- federal air regulations -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hof </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight operations. `` We find the FAR is a place to begin.'' <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> strongly denies federal regulations run second in safety to union contracts. `` Our standard is not the thinnest ice you can skate on,'' he said. Yet in 1975 an <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> investigation of a series of Pan American crashes in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> raised questions about the adequacy of <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> regulations. Dr. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohler </PERSON>, then chief of the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s Aeromedical Applications Division, suggested <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> regulators look to the factors that the Europeans use to set flying limits. `` It was the feeling at the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to leave it up to the unions to negotiate relative to their airlines' specific type of flying,'' said <PERSON> Mohler </PERSON>, now head of aerospace medicine at <ORGANIZATION> Wright </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` It seemed to make sense, up until deregulation.'' With deregulation, airlines stretched into new markets, added new routes and faced new competition. Efforts to cut costs and keep fares low put pressure on various parts of the industry, including the pilots. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Airline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the average pilot flies 13 percent more each month today than 10 years ago. <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> says he has an open mind to change. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> is supporting fatigue research being done by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> on several airlines. `` I do n't know of any carrier that wo n't voluntarily do all they can to ensure efficiency in the cockpit,'' he said. `` But I do n't believe we know all that we will know about this phenomenon As we understand it better, the scheduling, I think, will reflect that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DebonedMeat     09-13 0443</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deboned Meat,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumer Group Attacks Proposed Change on Hot Dog, Sausage
Labeling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A consumer group says it will fight to retain federal rules requiring food processors to acknowledge when finely ground bone is used in hot dogs, sausage and other meat products. <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, decried an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> proposal issued Monday that would require that such ingredients as ground bone be included on package labeling only when the material exceeds 10 percent of the meat portion of the finished product. Under current regulations, so-called mechanically separated meat or MSM can comprise up to 20 percent of the meat portion of certain products, which include hot dogs, luncheon meats, sausage, scrapple, canned spaghetti with meat sauce and other items. But labels must state that the product contains MSM. The department said that if the new proposal is adopted, <ORGANIZATION> MSM </ORGANIZATION> used in meat and poultry products `` would not have to be listed in the ingredients statement on the label as long as it does not exceed 10 percent of the meat and poultry portion of the finished product.'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said the proposed rule change was `` politically motivated'' by the outgoing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which he said could have made the proposal long ago. `` They want to get all of the junk and crud and sleaze done before they leave -LRB- office -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> said. He said his Washington-based consumer group would challenge the proposal during the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> hearing process. MSM is produced by putting the bones and attached meat remnants of a slaughtered animal through a grinder and forcing the mixture through sieves. Although most of the bone is strained out, some small particles _ about the size of black pepper flakes _ wind up with the salvaged meat in the final mixture. Mechanically deboned meat has been approved for use in certain foods since 1978. However, the industry complained that the stricter initial regulations called too much attention to the finely ground bone, and the product failed to gain widespread use. Department officials said the proposal to allow up to 10 percent <ORGANIZATION> MSM </ORGANIZATION> in products without labeling `` reflects a petition submitted to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'' by four processors: <ORGANIZATION> Bob </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Odom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sausage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; and <ORGANIZATION> Owen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sausage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The proposed change in regulations will be open for public comment until Nov. 8. Those can be sent to: Policy Office, Attn: <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>, Hearing Clerk, <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION>, Room 3171-S, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20250. Persons wishing to make oral comments should call -LRB- 202 -RRB- 447-6042.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Nuclear     09-13 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Nuclear,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Stifles Mexico's Nuclear Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CANDICE HUGHES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>XALAPA, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An unlikely coalition of wealthy housewives and cattlemen is spearheading opposition to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s first nuclear power plant The plant, <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION>, has been a pet project of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for more than 20 years. But the party, which lost ground to the opposition in the July 6 general election, announced soon afterward that it was delaying the plant's startup. `` After July 6, nothing is the same,'' said <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Labastida </PERSON>, a founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Mothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veracruz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anti-nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, one of several groups that have been working to get the plant mothballed or converted to non-nuclear fuel. The coalition of urban housewives and cattle ranchers fighting the project includes members of the governing party. `` A social consciousness is growing in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. One point is nuclear energy,'' said regional planner <PERSON> Tomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>, who just finished a book critical of <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION>. `` In it you will see a new face of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' Many residents in <LOCATION> Xalapa </LOCATION>, 140 miles east of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, oppose the plant, which is located 40 miles outside the city on a winding road dotted with roadside stands laden with local honey, cheese and fruit. Thick stands of sugar cane carpet the steamy coastal plain where white power pylons march down to the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the green lagoon that gave its name to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s first nuclear plant. Inside the 13-story Unit One containment building, uranium fuel rods wait in a dry concrete pool next to 657-megawatt reactor from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The men who are building the plant say they are confident of its safety and are ready to turn on the first of two reactors. `` The first unit is ready. It's a political decision now,'' project spokesman <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON> said recently. Critics say the reactor, made by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and its containment building are dangerous and obsolete. The <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmer </PERSON> plant in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which had a reactor of the same design, is being converted to coal fuel. The owners sued, alleging the reactor design was flawed, and won an out-of-court settlement of more than $ 78 millon. The Union of Concerned Scientists says all similar plants should be phased out because the containment building could leak radioactive materials. `` The Nuclear Regulatory Commission has concluded there is a 90 percent chance that it -LRB- the containment building -RRB- will break if there is a meltdown,'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, a nuclear safety engineer, said from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> is all that is left of a grand plan for a nationwide network of 20 nuclear plants. The idea died when oil prices plunged, but <PERSON> Laguna </PERSON> <PERSON> Verde </PERSON> lived on, despite a price tag that rose from $ 263 million to $ 3.5 billion. The project was announced in 1968. Construction began in 1973, and for years the project moved quietly along, providing thousands of jobs. Opposition to <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> began in April 1986 after the nuclear accident at <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, another founder of Mothers of <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION>. The explosion and fire at the Soviet plant killed 31 people and sent a cloud of radiation around the world. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electricity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> countered criticism of <LOCATION> Lagunda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> with a public relations campaign, but the opposition kept growing. Mothers of <LOCATION> Veracruz </LOCATION> turned a group of traditional Mexican housewives into a feisty band of activists that sent telegrams to public officials, organized phone banks and printed booklets about nuclear energy. `` Waking people up, waking people up. That's been the hardest thing. To make them realize you can do something,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Labastida </PERSON> said. Local cattlemen joined in, some even offering to help pay to turn <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> into a non-nuclear plant. Last year, cattlemen and housewives blocked traffic by linking arms across the road leading to the plant. The plant has two reactors, one ready to be started up. The governing party did n't say how long it would delay that procedure.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietMilitary     09-13 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Military,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Urged To Develop New Proposals On Arms Control</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX17</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should develop new proposals for U.S.-Soviet conventional arms control talks in case Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> succeeds in cutting back on military spending, says a key congressman. The plans should be prepared even though there's no indication <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has yet been successful, said Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` A central element of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s ` new thinking' is that the Western threat can be reduced by political means _ that is, arms control _ which then reduces Soviet defense requirements,'' the report said. `` For <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, arms control can cut the size of the Western threat and a revised military doctrine can scale back the military's response to that threat,'' it said. The panel's defense policy subcommittee concluded Monday that `` to date, there have been no significant, identifiable changes traceable to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s drive to scale back defense spending.'' The study by the Democratic-run panel was based on a series of hearings, including testimony from the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, and other experts in government and private industry. Republican members of the panel issued a dissent, disputing the majority's implication that the Soviets may be moving away from what the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> legislators said is a drive to achieve nuclear superiority over the West. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has called for economic and military reforms aimed at shifting more spending into consumer goods and away from the huge Soviet military structure, <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> noted. `` <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform agenda for the military is driven primarily by domestic concerns, not military or strategic factors,'' the study said. `` The equation is simple: In order for his economic reforms to succeed, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> must shift resources from the defense sector to civilian use.'' The current five-year plan began in 1986 and was developed before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took power in March 1985, <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> said at a news conference. Some changes may be seen in the Soviets' next five-year plan, he said. `` There is a growing consensus among the experts that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> intends to shift some of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s economic capacity from military to civilian use,'' said <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>. `` What the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ought to be doing is probing. ... We should move cautiously and carefully, but we should move,'' he said. `` We need some concrete proposals in conventional arms.'' He was referring to the long-stalled talks aimed at reducing non-nuclear weapons and troops in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The upcoming `` year we're looking at is a critical year,'' <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> said. `` It's too bad the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is in transition.'' As the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration winds down, no new proposals are likely. In addition, a new administration will take six to eight months to prepare its plans, no matter whether Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is elected president, <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have a difficult time estimating Soviet military spending, since the Soviets do n't publish details about their programs. The Soviets appear to be spending about 18 percent of their gross national product on defense, compared to about 6 percent for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the study said. But the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> GNP is much larger. Soviet military spending increased about 2 percent annually in the decade before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took power, and has increased about 3 percent in each of the past two years. The study cited the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces -LRB- INF -RRB- treaty, which includes strict verification procedures and bigger cuts in the Soviet arsenal than in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> stockpile of weapons. The <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> minority, led by Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ala </LOCATION>., the ranking Republican on the committee, criticized part of the report `` This report accepts, without the slightest qualification, the idea that the Soviet leadership has accepted the implications of nuclear parity _ implicitly meaning that the Soviets reject the concepts of superiority, pre-emption, first use and victory,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> members said. `` The apparent justification underlying this assumption appears to be a decade of both Soviet public statements and arms control activities. However, neither can be taken at face value as evidence of a meaningful transformation in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear doctrine,'' the dissent said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bangladesh-Scene     09-13 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bangladesh-Scene,0651</SECOND>
<HEAD>Waiting For Help _ And For The Waters To Recede</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANCHHARAMPUR, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the past two weeks, the 15,000 people of this town have been living in flood waters. They say they have received almost no help from the government, although the town is only 25 miles east of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, the capital. Even in normal times, <PERSON> Banchharampur </PERSON> is isolated, like thousands of other towns and villages in this country that is now three-quarters submerged by overflowing rivers. There are no roads connecting the town to the outside world. The trip from <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> takes five hours by motorboat across winding rivers and through inundated rice paddies. Most people in <LOCATION> Banchharampur </LOCATION> are weavers or landless farmers who have not been able to work since the flood waters from the <LOCATION> Titash </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reached their houses Aug. 29. <PERSON> Firoz </PERSON>, who delivers goods from the market when it is n't flooded, and his wife <PERSON> Hana </PERSON>, said they tried to get medical help for their 7-year-old daughter <PERSON> Rahima </PERSON>, who had a fever. `` Government medical workers came here once, but the crowd was too big and they left before we could see them,'' <PERSON> Firoz </PERSON> said. Townspeople said eight people drowned or died of diarrhea or dysentery caused by drinking contaminated water. He said his family had received 4.4 pounds of free rie from the government, and had to borrow money from other villagers to buy more. A grain seller named <PERSON> Farid </PERSON> said he had only two baskets of low-quality rice to sell. The government and foreign relief agencies are struggling to reach millions of marooned flood victims by helicopter and boat. But with at least 65,000 villages spread across 55,000 square miles _ an area the size of <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> _ the task is slow. On Sunday, fresh vegetables reached Banchharampur by boat from unsubmerged fields 12 miles away, but the prices had soared by as much as 175 percent since the floods began June 13. <PERSON> Sattar </PERSON>, his wife <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> and their three children normally eat 4.4 pounds of rice a day. Since the flood, the family has been getting by on 2.2 pounds or less of rice a day, <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> said. She uncovered a tin cooking pot, displaying an inch of rice in the bottom. `` This is all we have left. We have no more money,'' she said, speaking in Bengali through an interpreter. The family has purchased rice with <PERSON> Sattar </PERSON>'s last earnings as a porter, and money from the family's only salable item _ a chicken <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> managed to save when they abandoned their straw house, where the flood water has reached the roof. `` We stayed in our house until the water got as high as <PERSON> Saliha </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> said, drawing her oldest child close to her. <PERSON> Saliha </PERSON>, wearing only a pair of cotton shorts and a jewelry stud in her nostril, stood about three feet tall. <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> _ who like many Bangladeshis does n't have a family name _ said she did not know her daughter's age, but the girl appeared to be about 10. <PERSON> Alia </PERSON> said her family took refuge with 20 other people in one room of a hostel built for college students, where the water was 18 inches deep. The families piled wooden benches on top of each other in two tiers, creating a wobbly wooden platform above the water. The highest path through the village is a foot under water. Some people are living in houses where women wade waist-deep in water to cook food on boards propped just above the water. But life in the village went on. The government-run bank was open, although the few customers stood ankle-deep in water. At the deed registry office, clerks sat on platforms above the water with a black goat tethered in their midst.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EmptySeat     09-13 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Empty Seat,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Even Without Biaggi, Congressional Office Carries On</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> office for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s 19th Congressional District, phones still ring, mail comes in, letters go out. The only thing missing is a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Until Aug. 5, the district was represented by Rep. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, a Democrat who for nearly 20 years represented the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> and part of <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, who was convicted of racketeering last month in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> trial, resigned rather than face almost certain expulsion by his colleagues. But even without an elected representative, the work of the congressional office goes on. House rules provide for keeping offices running in the event that a member resigns, dies or is expelled. Constituents still get some services; what they do n't get is their own advocate who can sponsor and vote on legislation and perform work in committees. In the case of <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>'s constituents, they lost their voice in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year when <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> agreed to stop voting on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor after being indicted for accepting illegal paid vacations. He later was convicted of that charge in a separate trial. Deputy Clerk <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said that when a vacancy occurs in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, `` The clerk of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> becomes in effect the supervisor or manager of the vacant offices until a successor is elected.'' The clerk usually selects one of the former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> member's senior staffers to run the office, <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON>, <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>'s longtime administrative assistant, was appointed to run the office upon the congressman's departure. `` We are carrying on the way that not only <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> would expect of his staff and the years of experience that we have, but also using our own standards of what we believe we should do,'' <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON> said he still talks daily to <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, who has returned to the <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, and that the business of the congressional office inevitably comes up. `` I do n't know if there are rules about discussing business,'' <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON> said. `` ... His advice and guidance and counsel, do I still need it for what I do everyday? Absolutely, sure.'' <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said such communications are to be expected, and voiced confidence that <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON> `` understands his role and what he's doing. <PERSON> Blancato </PERSON> said he has no sense of role reversal during conversations with <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>. `` Every time I speak to him ... in a philosophical way, even if it is n't in a literal way, I'm stll speaking to my boss,'' he said. Even the hurdle of sponsoring legislation is not insurmountable without an elected representative. If the appointed administrator believes some problem requires legislation, `` He can talk to the other members of the delegation from that particular state and ask them to support the issue,'' <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said. `` These are not unusual situations,'' <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said. `` We have had vacancies for various reasons over the years.'' Ten seats, including one belonging to the delegate from <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>, have been vacated since the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> began almost two years ago, <PERSON> Colley </PERSON> said. Most of those seats have been filled through special elections. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> has called no special election to fill <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>'s seat, so whoever is elected on Nov. 8 wo n't begin serving until January 1989. Chances are good that <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> will be re-elected to the seat he vacated, but he has said he would not serve. If he wins, it is expected that he would quit again and a special election would be held.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     09-13 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Estimates Show Huge Losses In June, July</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The huge losses to 1988 harvests came mostly in June and July, when drought and searing heat shriveled corn and soybean yields across much of the nation, new <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates show. Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Ewen </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, the department's chief economist, said total grain production this year is expected to drop to 191 million metric tons, down 31 percent from 1987. Total supplies of grain for 1988-89, which include inventories at the beginning of the season, are forecast at 366 million tons, down 24 percent from last year. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said at a news conference Monday that `` crop development now has progressed to the point where production can be forecast with a reasonable degree of confidence.'' The corn yield, for example, was estimated at 78.5 bushels per harvested acre, down from 119.4 bushels last year, the largest drought-induced reduction in yield on record, he said. From 1965 to 1987, the September estimate overstated corn production on nine occasions and understated it on 14 occasions, <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said. In the case of soybeans, the September estimate overshot final production in 12 years and understated it in 11. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said rainfall in the last month `` has improved the conditions of pastures and ranges, although more precipitation is needed to restore them to normal.'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said he is holding to an earlier prediction that consumer food prices will go up an average of 3 percent to 5 percent this year, with about 1 percent of the rise caused by drought. A further increase is expected in 1989. The new <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates showed the corn harvest, which is under way, is expected to be at a five-year low of 4.46 billion bushels, down 37 percent from 7.06 billion bushels harvested in 1987. Even so, that was down by less than 1 percent from the forecast a month ago. In May and June, before the drought tightened its grip, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> projected the corn harvest at 7.3 billion bushels, based on trends and an assumption of normal weather. Those projections were revised downward in July to 5.2 billion bushels, assuming farmers got normal weather the remainder of the season. In August, the forecast was lowered to 4.48 billion bushels, the smallest harvest since 1983, when drought and federal acreage curbs reduced output to 4.17 billion bushels. The soybean harvest was estimated at a 12-year low of 1.47 billion bushels, down 23 percent from 1.9 billion bushels produced last year but virtually unchanged from the August forecast. Estimates last spring called for about 1.88 billion bushels, and the July projection was 1.65 billion bushels. Production of all wheat was projected at 1.81 billion bushels, down 14 percent from 2.1 billion produced in 1987 and 1 percent below the August forecast. In May and June, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> forecast this year's wheat output would be up slightly. The July projection was 1.84 billion bushels, and the August forecast was 1.82 billion bushels. Corn is the largest and most important crop grown by American farmers and, as a feed ingredient, is essential to the production of meat, poultry and dairy products. Soybeans, which provide high-protein meal and quality vegetable oil used in food processing, also are vital to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food production. No new estimate of winter wheat production was included. Last month's forecast, which was carried forward into the September report, was 1.55 billion bushels, down 1 percent from last year. New estimates for spring planted wheat included durum, 49.2 million bushels, down 47 percent from 1987 production and the smallest harvest since 1961. The new estimate was also down 10 percent from August. Other spring wheat was estimated at 206 million bushels, down 54 percent from last year and 3 percent below the August forecast. Cotton production was estimated at 14.7 million bales, down 2 percent from August but only slightly below the 1987 crop. The crop was projected at 13.7 million bales in July. Overall, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crop production this year is expected to drop to 88 percent of a 1977 base used as a comparison. That would be the lowest since 1983. Crop production last year averaged 106 percent of the base year. The record was 117 percent reached in 1985, 1982 and 1981.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Rowan-Shooting     09-13 0492</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rowan-Shooting,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inspector Says Rowan Violated Weapons Law</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX16</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A District of <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> police inspector testified that syndicated columnist <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> broke a local gun control law when he fired on a backyard intruder in June. Following a pre-trial hearing Monday that included testimony from police Inspector <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said he would rule by Friday on a motion that weapons charges against <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> be dismissed. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, 63, has been charged with using an unregistered revolver to wound a teen-ager who was intruding in the backyard of his home. He also has been charged with unlawful possession of ammunition for the handgun. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>, who has written and spoken frequently on behalf of gun control, maintains that his son, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent, was told by city officials he was not required to register the weapon used in the June 14 shooting. <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> testified that he had complained repeatedly to police about trespassers and said that death threats heightened his concern over intruders. The columnist, who contends the police knew he had a gun, said he had warned a police officer that if anyone ever confronted him on his property late at night, he would have to shoot them and he did n't want to do that. The officer, <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chatman </PERSON>, contradicted <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON>'s testimony, saying, `` He never made a statement to me about any action he was going to take.'' <PERSON> Chatman </PERSON> said he'd been to the <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> house between 10 and 20 times in the last few years, all on complaints about trespassers using the pool. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, who has worked in the district's gun records division since 1976, said <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> had broken the law that prohibits anyone but the registered owner from using a weapon. He acknowledged that city police officers and federal law enforcement agents are not required to register weapons, but he insisted that only those individuals are allowed to use the weapons. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> added that it is a violation of law for other family members even to touch an agent's weapon. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> does not require agents to register with local authorities weapons used for official duties, according to <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> McElhaney </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. He declined to say whether a .22 - caliber revolver, the weapon used in the shooting, would normally be approved for use by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a lawyer, testified Monday that he spoke three times with police about whether the weapon should be registered and was told he need n't register it, but never got a written statement on the matter. The senior <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> shot <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 19, of suburban <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, on the night of June 14 after he caught <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and three other youths taking an unauthorized swim in his pool. If convicted on the misdemeanor weapon and ammunition charges, <PERSON> Rowan </PERSON> faces a possible maximum penalty of two years in prison and a $ 2,000 fine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hispanics     09-13 0369</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hispanics,350</SECOND>
<NOTE>EDs: For release 8 a.m. EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Republican Task Force Issues Recommendations on Developing
Hispanic Talent</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans today released a set of recommendations to encourage full development of Hispanic talent, including a trade policy with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that benefits businesses on both sides of the border and expanded education initiatives to lower the illiteracy and dropout rates. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> task force on Hispanic affairs said in issuing its recommendations that four advisory committees had examined Hispanic education and literacy, economic development, employment, and health. `` By taking a fresh look at these and additional issues on the threshold of the 1990s, we intend to re-energize and refocus attention on the needs and potential of Hispanic Americans,'' the report said. `` We do not see this potential as different from other Americans. Rather, we want to ensure that Hispanic Americans have access to the opportunities and support systems already available to most Americans for many generations,'' said the committee, led by Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>. The task force's recommendations include: _ Expanding national and local initiatives to reduce illiteracy and combat a high Hispanic student dropout rate _ Advocate programs at the federal, state and local levels and in the private sector that provide managerial skills assistance to small minority businesses _ Pursue an aggressive trade policy with <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to benefit businesses on both sides of the border _ Improve the recruitment of qualified Hispanics into managerial and professional positions in the private and public sector _ Promote health and disease prevention efforts, with an emphasis on fighting AIDS _ Support better access to bonding and insurance for small firms The committee said it hoped its efforts would boost the nation's appreciation for `` one of our rich cultural treasures _ the American of Hispanic descent. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> is the official caucus of <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> senators. In addition to <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, other members of the task force are Sens. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BurrowingNuke     09-13 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burrowing Nuke,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Pursues Development Of Earth-Burrowing Warheads</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is pursuing the development of nuclear warheads that would penetrate the earth before detonating and which could be a more effective weapon against Soviet underground command centers. <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials said Monday that <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> had authorized development of the so-called `` burrowing nukes'' that have been under study for years. Military scientists are convinced they would be far more powerful against underground bunkers than other nuclear devices that explode on the surface, even if they do n't pack the same explosive power. The new weapon, which is highly classified and the responsibility of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, is formally known as an earth penetrator. The Energy Department disclosed in June 1987 it had begun preliminary development work on the warhead needed for a burrowing missile because it expected the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to request one. According to a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman and other <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> sources, that request now has been formally made. The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will be expected to step up its work on warhead design while the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> pursues missile development and integration work. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bodyani </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Acquisition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> last month recommended approval of an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> statement on the need for the weapon and <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> subsequently approved it. She said the final authorization was dated Aug. 19 `` and approves this program as a new start.'' She would not discuss program details such as funding and anticipated deployment schedules. Another Pentagon official, who insisted on anonymity, said <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> had directed the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> to provide cost estimates and predicted performance data for a more rudimentary version of the weapon that could be produced by modifying an existing missile or bomb. `` There will almost certainly be an interim earth penetrator,'' this official said. `` But the authorization clears the way for the broad-based research needed to produce a brand new weapon.'' The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration recently has begun spotlighting Soviet construction of underground bunkers, saying it appears the Russians are convinced they can protect their leaders while waging a nuclear war. Earlier this spring, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported in its latest edition of the publication `` Soviet Military Power'' that such construction had been under way for 40 years and the bunkers could `` accommodate thousands of people.'' A burrowing warhead would not have to penetrate more than a few feet before posing an increased threat to a bunker, but `` it's not easy'' to develop a warhead that can withstand the shock of striking and burrowing through the ground, one official said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LaunchDanger     09-13 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Launch Danger,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA, Air Force To Limit Journalists at Shuttle Launch Site</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: News conference scheduled for 2 p.m. EDT; top prospects
uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The viewing area from which reporters and spectators have watched 25 space shuttle launches at the Kennedy Space Center will be off-limits to most onlookers when shuttles start flying again because of safety concerns, officials say. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> on Monday announced the new precautions at the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, space facility, citing studies that `` have shown that the danger to persons on the ground is much greater than was understood should an accident occur.'' The restrictions cover the viewing area that overlooks launch complex 39, where space shuttle Discovery is being prepared for space. A press viewing area 3.5 miles from the launch pads has been used by media representatives since the shuttle program began. Invited guests, including astronauts' families, watched from a nearby VIP area, and Kennedy Space Center workers and their families also were able to watch from certain areas. Under the new plans, most nearby areas will be cleared just before and during the launch. Details of the plans were to be explained at a briefing today at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The plan drew protests Monday from Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., who said at the Kennedy Space Center that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>, Space and Technology had argued against such a change in a letter sent Friday to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` I do n't think an iron curtain should be placed about the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> when we're getting back into space,'' said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a member of the committee and chairman of its subcommittee on space science and applications. `` The press has been very much a part of the manned space flight program for 29 years and to arbitrarily say that some of that press has to be excluded is not right,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials said the new rules were developed after studies of the Challenger explosion in January 1986 and the loss of an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Titan 34D the following April. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> range safety officers monitor each launch and have the responsibility of blowing up any rocket that strays out of control. During the Challenger accident, the solid-fueled rocket booster engines broke away and were destroyed by the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> range safety officer. A study of this accident, and of the Titan 34D loss, gave new understanding of the dangers to people near the launch pad, the announcement said. `` Under certain conditions, a solid rocket booster released from the vehicle as a result of an accident would follow an unknown ballistic trajectory rather than begin to tumble on course as had been previously thought,'' the announcement said. Also, the statement said, it was learned that if out-of-control boosters had to be destroyed in flight, `` the boosters fragmented into thousands of pieces and the explosive properties of unburned solid motor propellant were greater than originally determined in laboratory tests.'' `` Because of this new information,'' the statement said, `` <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> have determined that the prudent action is to minimize the population at the close-in viewing areas.'' Accredited journalists will be able to work in the area `` except for the hours just before the launch and the launch itself,'' the statement said. During the prohibited period, only `` media with an immediate need for the facilities at the press site will be allowed.'' The rest, it said, will view the launch from a site on a causeway. The alternate site will be equipped with a countdown clock, audio commentary and video monitors. About 3,000 members of the media have requested accreditation for the first post-Challenger launch, that of Discovery, which is expected to occur in about two weeks. The exact number that will be permitted at the press site has not been disclosed. The letter to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from the congressional committee, headed by Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said, in part, `` Although we have no doubt that the new assessments leading to this proposal are well intended, the calculation of such risks is highly uncertain.'' It asked the president to intercede and permit continued access to traditional viewing areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-FamilyLeave     09-13 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Family Leave,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Democrats Urge Bush to Support Family Leave Bill</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Political jockeying over family issues is taking a new turn in the wake of Republican presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s remark that women with newborns should not face loss of their jobs if they take a few weeks off. House Democrats jumped on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s comment Monday and urged the vice president to support a family leave bill that both chambers are expected to vote on this month. `` We would welcome your support for and participation in the consideration of the bill so that it may be enacted into law this year,'' five legislators, backed by <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leaders, told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in a letter. The Family and Medical Leave Act would require employers of more than 50 to grant unpaid, job-protected leaves to parents of newborn, newly adopted or seriously ill children; seriously ill employees; and workers who must care for sick parents. Democratic nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a longtime supporter of the measure, reiterated his view in a letter Monday to Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., and Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., two of the bill's chief The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said the bill would `` bring us one step closer to a more humane workplace for all Americans.'' In the letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> and four other <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members said the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has opposed the family leave act since its introduction in 1985 by <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>. `` However, the press has reported a willingness on your part to reverse this historically held position and endorse family and medical leave legislation,'' the lawmakers said. Last Friday before a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> women's group, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> departed from his text and also from the administration's hard-line opposition to government-mandated family leaves. `` Look, we also need to assure that women do n't have to worry about getting their jobs back after having a child or caring for a child during a serious illness,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not elaborate on the remark at the time, but his campaign is developing a more detailed proposal The letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was signed by <PERSON> Clay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> and Reps. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Mont.; <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, D-Calif.; and <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, D-Calif. <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON> is chairman of a leadership task force on the bill and <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> is chairman of the Education and <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, in his letter to <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, left no doubt he agrees that job-protected leave should be available to men as well as women and for personal illness as well as a child's medical crisis. `` A father who needs a few weeks to care for his sick son, a worker who has cancer, or a mother who brings home a new baby _ they should not have to sacrifice their jobs,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wrote. The House bill, which counts 16 Republicans among its 151 co-sponsors, would require employers to make 10-week leaves available to parents of newborn or newly adopted children. Medical leaves of up to 15 weeks would have to be available. Businesses employing fewer than 50 would be exempt for at least three years. The small business community is fighting the family leave bill on the grounds that it would create hardships for their companies and that the government should n't dictate employee benefits. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, has estimated the bill would cost businesses less than $ 200 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MissingWife     09-13 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Missing Wife,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Charged in Suspected Death of Missing Wife Despite Lack of
Corpse</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCKVILLE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION> man has been charged with murdering his common-law wife although police said they `` do n't even know where to begin looking for the body'' of the woman who disappeared in July <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Tu </PERSON>, 58, was arrested at a <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, hotel on Saturday, a day after <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> police charged him with first-degree murder in the suspected death of 42-year-old <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Tu </PERSON>. Police said scientific and circumstantial evidence led them to conclude that the woman had been slain at the couple's home in <LOCATION> Rockville </LOCATION>. `` We do n't even know where to begin looking for the body,'' said Capt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKenna </PERSON>, the county's chief of detectives. Police said they interviewed people who spoke of discord in the couple's marriage. Other factors cited by the police were allegations that <PERSON> Tu </PERSON> threw out his wife's favorite love seat shortly after she disappeared, traces of blood found where the love seat had stood in the home and Tu's departure for <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> before he was scheduled to take a polygraph test. Tu, a marketing employee of a real estate development, told friends and relatives in July that his wife had gone to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> to help a friend who was ill. Police said the friend reported she had not seen the woman and had not been expecting her <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Tu </PERSON>' grown son and daughter from an earlier relationship reported her missing to police on Aug. 10. Tu was questioned by police on Aug. 13 and 14 about his wife's absence and agreed to take a lie detector test, but left the state before doing so. Detectives said Tu was being held at the <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> pending extradition proceedings. The couple had lived together for about 10 years, police said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hurricane-Gilbert 4thLd-Writethru   09-13 1177</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane-Gilbert, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0786,1214</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Hurricane Slams Jamaica; 30 Reported Dead</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 29 grafs to CORRECT attribution on report of 30
deaths and UPDATE with amateur radio reports of more damage in
Jamaica and power outages in Haiti, Dominican Republic; midnight
EDT location; PICKS up 19th graf pvs: Cayman Island...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LLOYD WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> slammed into <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> on Monday with torrential rains and 115 mph winds, ripping the roofs off buildings and spawning flash floods and mudslides. One report said 30 people were killed. <PERSON> Doren </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, general manager of <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cayman </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that a lawyer in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> called the radio station and said at least 30 people had died across <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> as the brunt of the storm lashed the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island Monday afternoon. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said his station's correspondent in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> reported that hundreds of families had fled their homes because of rising floodwaters. The hurricane pounded <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> on the southwest coast and <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Ocho </PERSON> <PERSON> Rios </PERSON> on the north. In <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, 115,000 people were evacuated from their homes as a precaution in five eastern provinces when <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON>'s winds brushed the island, said <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> <PERSON> Latina </PERSON>, the government news agency. Authorities in <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> said looters stole mattresses from a hospital, the roof was torn off a home for physically handicapped people and a firefighter was hurt when heavy winds blew him off his truck. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said his office was in touch with a meteorological office in <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> as the eye of the storm passed over city. On the leading edge of hurricane, winds gusted to 140, he said. `` Then on the trailing edge of the eye wall, there were winds just as strong and they said they could n't see anything outside their windows,'' Sheets said. `` It was quite a frightening experience for them.'' At midnight EDT, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> was centered near latitude 18.5 north, longitude 79.5 west, or 135 miles east-southeast of <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION>, the National Hurricane Center reported. `` The hurricane is moving toward the west near 17 mph,'' the center said in a statement. `` This motion will bring the center of the hurricane over or near <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> in the early morning hours Tuesday.'' The <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, are flat and have few sheltered areas, the center said. In <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s capital with 750,000 people, the initial 30-minute shock of the storm let up as the hurricane's eye moved across the city. Skies brightened, winds died and people waited for an hour before the second blow arrived. Amateur radio operators in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said they received reports of buildings collapsing and severe power outages across <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Shelby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, said he monitored a report from a radio operator staying at the <LOCATION> Wyndham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> seven miles east of <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> `` and the building was shaking badly by his description.'' `` They've been without power in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> since last night for the most part and telephone service has been real, real spotty,'' <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> said. Another ham radio operator went off the air after reporting storm damage at his house near <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> said. `` When he got back on the air, he said most of his house had disappeared,'' <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON> said. `` It's been a heart-rending listening to them all day.'' Amateur radio operator <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maragni </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Coconut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said he also received transmissions indicating widespread and heavy damage in <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. `` They've had the airport with severe damage,'' <PERSON> Maragni </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Monday night. `` They had to evacuate the <LOCATION> Montego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> meteorology center approximately about 8 o'clock this evening -LRB- EDT -RRB-, so I've been unable to get any reports out of there.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebaugh </PERSON>, a National Hurricane Center forecaster, said some hangar roofs blew off at the international airport in <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> and some runway aircraft were damaged. All flights were canceled on the island. Amateur operator <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Estevez </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said he has been speaking with other radio operators in the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> since Monday morning. <PERSON> Estevez </PERSON> also said he heard a report from <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> saying the top of a city hospital was blown off and the main television station on the island was not broadcasting. `` People were telling me they saw trees and stuff flying around,'' said <PERSON> Estevez </PERSON>. `` But so far I have n't heard of anyone being killed.'' He said reports from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> indicate widespread blackouts and some damage along coastal areas from high waves. Heaviest damage reports were in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>, however. `` The eye of the storm moved right lengthwise down the island,'' Sheets said at 5 p.m. EDT. `` They're getting five to 10 inches of rain -LRB- in <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> -RRB-, and so the mudslides, flash floods and all of that will be continuing for the next six to eight hours.'' Sheets said the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> has a dearth of sheltered areas. `` They're very flat, there's not a lot of places people can go to get refuge,'' he <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said at 9 p.m. EDT that <PERSON> Little </PERSON> <PERSON> Cayman </PERSON> had been evacuated, as well as lower-lying areas of Grand Cayman. `` Everyone is waiting with bated breath,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> in a telephone interview. `` It is calm here at the moment but we are expecting to take the brunt of it.'' <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> airlines was running flights every two hours to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to evacuate as many people as possible before the hurricane hit, said airline spokesman <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Chisolm </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> reached <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> after skirting southern <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Hurricane warnings were issued Monday for the south coast of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> east of <LOCATION> Camaguey </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Cayman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, while warnings were discontinued for the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>, a policeman suffered a broken leg when a fence fell on him, another resident was injured when a wall collapsed and a firefighter answering an emergency call was hurt when the wind blew him off the fire truck, the disaster office reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Mona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for paraplegics reported its roof had been blown off. Police reported people were stealing mattresses from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> and there was scattered looting in the <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION> suburbs of <LOCATION> Westchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Portmore </LOCATION> and <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON>. There was an unconfirmed report that prisoners had escaped from <LOCATION> Kingston </LOCATION>'s Gun Prison. <ORGANIZATION> Jamaica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the office of Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON>, was the crisis center. <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> said in a radio interview that he would seek international aid. Most of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION>'s 2.3 million people stayed home and boarded up their windows. <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> <PERSON> Latina </PERSON>, monitored in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said 40 mph winds from the hurricane prompted authorities to evacuate more than 115,000 people from the eastern provinces of Tunas, <LOCATION> Guantanamo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Granma </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Holguin </PERSON>. The region is about 90 miles north of <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> at its closest point. More than 80,000 head of livestock in that area also were moved to safer ground, the agency said. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> reported its bases at <LOCATION> Guantanamo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roads </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, had taken precautions but appeared safe.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-13 0415</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHITMAN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two clowns who fell in love at a clowns' convention took a shot at tying the knot in a ceremony that was a regular circus `` I take Chubby Cheeks to be my awful wedded husband,'' Sparkles the clown said in the weekend ceremony. `` I promise to love, honor, and bathe him ... And I will not nag at him for eating candy bars, ice cream and cookies.'' The bride clutched fake flowers and sported gold tinsel hair, twinkling gold eyelashes and size 18 shoes. Before the vows, Chubby Cheeks, trembling from matrimonial jitters, tried to make a run for it. `` My mother cooks better than her!'' he shouted as he tried to wobble to freedom in his white baggy pants and oversized shoes. He was headed off and returned to the side of his bride, where he said: `` I take Sparkles to be my lawful-wedded wife, I promise not to eat peanut butter and cookies before going to bed, I will help with the housework, I promise to take out the garbage and hang up my clothes every night, and I promise to visit her relatives without any argument whatsoever.'' Chubby Cheeks, whose real name is <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Milly </PERSON> <PERSON> Fantucchio </PERSON>, who plays Sparkles, met at a Clowns of <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> meeting three years ago. Sunday's ceremony at Castle Land amusement park, where the couple works as clowns on summer weekends, was a dress rehearsal for a more traditional ceremony later this month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new dairy is bringing back the milkman and a rich, creamy milk for special customers is this opulent resort town. <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> plans to start home deliveries of milk and other dairy products this fall with milkmen who have undergone police background checks. `` We're giving people a comfort level, saying, ` These guys are OK. You can allow them on your property and they wo n't steal your silverware,' `` said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who founded the dairy with <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiro </PERSON>, naturally, drives a cream-colored <ORGANIZATION> Rolls-Royce </ORGANIZATION>. In keeping with its upper-crust standards, the dairy is n't using just any milk. While most Americans drink milk from Holstein cows, <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milk </ORGANIZATION> has opted for the richer product of Jersey cows. `` A <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> milk has more of everything,'' said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. Young and <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiro </PERSON> hope to take their product to select towns and cities nationally at prices about 25 percent above the store-bought variety.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DukakisNotebook     09-13 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Notebook,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Speech Gaffe; Glenn on Rambo; Philly Minus A Major Protest</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> never will win an award for stirring oratory but generally he can be expected to deliver his speeches, aided by a TelePrompTer, without major gaffes. But even the unemotional <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had to step back from the microphone and laugh at himself after flubbing a line in a speech on national security Monday at a union hall in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. The Democratic nominee had just finished railing against Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his role in the Iran-Contra affair and promised that a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> admininstration never would sell arms to a terrorist nation. His text then called for the following line: `` I do n't question <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s patriotism.'' Instead, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said: `` I do n't question <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s terrorism. He immediately realized his error and, after taking a few seconds to laugh along with his audience, delivered the line from the text.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> also is not high on the list of great orators in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> but he delivered a lively and emotional defense of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> before the same <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> audience. Criticizing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration budget and trade policies that <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said were responsible for the massive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had failed to use his `` enormous'' powers to protect <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade interests. `` They've talked like Rambo and they've acted like <PERSON> Bambi </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said to the roaring approval of the partisan audience. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, the first man to orbit the earth, used his stature as an American hero to defend <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the flap over his veto of a 1977 bill that would have required <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> teachers to lead students in reciting the Pledge of Allegiance. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> vetoed the bill after being advised it was unconstitutional, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other Republicans have raised the issue in not-so-subtle attacks on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' patriotism. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, declaring himself to be `` very irritated'' by the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> attacks, stood in front of a huge American flag as he denounced the Republicans. `` That Pledge of Allegiance to the flag of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is your pledge, it's my pledge, it's our pledge and it's <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' pledge,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> also accused the Republicans of ignoring the final six words of the pledge: `` with liberty and justice for all.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' visit Monday to <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> was without a major protest, in stark contrast to an event he held here on Labor Day as part of his fall campaign kickoff. A small group of anti-abortion protesters gathered outside the union hall where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> delivered a speech on national security and a handful also met the Democratic nominee outside a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> television studio. The relative calm came just a week after a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> event in a nearby neighborhood was disrupted by about 100 anti-abortion protesters whose chants drowned out most of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' remarks to residents of a narrow street where he held an outdoor meeting. The advance man who arranged the Labor Day event has since been fired by the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880913-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-13-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChickenSoup     09-13 0206</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chicken Soup,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hospital Has Chicken Soup for the '80s</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLYOKE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
