<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush Bjt   12-17 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tower Selection Takes Bush To Halfway Point Of Filling Cabinet</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is halfway through picking his Cabinet with the selection of former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> as defense secretary and he now is focusing on candidates to run the government's housing, health and transportation agencies. Trying to wrap up major appointments before Christmas, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to announce at least three more Cabinet choices early next week. These will include conservative Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> as secretary of housing and urban development and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> mass-transit official <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> as secretary of transportation, sources involved in the transition said Friday. They also said health educator <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> continues to be the leading candidate for secretary of health and human services but had not been offered the job. If chosen, he would be the first black in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Cabinet. Moreover, former Republican Rep. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> was said by sources to be a leading candidate to become Energy Secretary. Sources also reported <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had chosen <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellmon </PERSON> and former Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> -LRB- Lud -RRB- <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> to be his appointees to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which is charged with recommending ways to reduce the federal deficit. <PERSON> Bellmon </PERSON> is a former senator who once served as ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, while <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> has been a friend of the president-elect since their days together at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>. In naming Tower to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday he was `` totally satisfied'' with <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION>'s fitness to serve after a detailed <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> background check into his connections with the defense industry as well as with allegations of womanizing and drinking problems. Tower, commenting on the allegations, said `` I got up every morning and laughed myself silly over what I was reading in the newspapers.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, predicting the selection would be greeted with `` wide support abroad and at home,'' said he believed Tower had been strengthened by the ordeal. He said the exhaustive investigation into Tower's professional and personal life had yielded a `` clean bill of health.'' After announcing the choice of Tower, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> fielded questions from reporters. He said that `` there is no expectation that we will or wo n't'' have a summit meeting with Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> next year. He said he did n't want to signal unwillingness to build on recent progress in U.S.-Soviet relations, but also did n't want to `` send out the other signal'' of acting too hastily. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said he `` would n't overstate the importance'' of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> talks with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> that opened Friday in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>. He stressed that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has embarked on a dialogue and not a negotiation. Tower was the seventh Cabinet member named by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, leaving seven slots still unfilled. Tower said that in running the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, he would have to produce `` as much if not more defense for less money.'' Tower hinted at manpower reductions throughout the armed services. But, he stressed, `` I would not advocate, for the immediate future, any significant troop reduction in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' The appointment completes <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of a national security team. He previously named former <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> as secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION>, chose retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Gen. <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> as national security adviser and said he would retain <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> as director of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Tower has held a variety of sensitive posts since retiring from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1985, including stints as an arms control negotiator for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and as head of a review board, popularly known as the <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, appointed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to probe the Iran-Contra affair. Some conservative critics have contended that Tower's support for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION> plan for a land and space-based shield against missiles has been lukewarm. Tower told reporters that `` I do n't have any reservations'' about the Strategic Defense Initiative. However, he added, `` I understand the value of SDI, not just as a deterrent potential but also as a very, very valuable negotiating tool.'' Asked if that meant he thought of it only as a bargaining chip for arms-reduction talks, he responded, `` Not a chip, leverage, negotiating leverage.'' In another development, a transition source said campaign strategist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON>, who is serving as co-chairman of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s transition team, has ended many days of deliberation and decided to go to the White House as deputy chief of staff
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra Bjt   12-17 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Veteran to Lead Prosecution At North Trial</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war veteran has been selected as lead trial prosecutor in the Iran-Contra case against fellow former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and ex-White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>, 44, who like <PERSON> North </PERSON> was wounded while leading a Marine infantry platoon in action, was chosen on Friday by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> to head a three-lawyer team that will try North. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> had said he would like to try the North case himself. But he said in a statement Friday that he would continue to deal with problems posed by a wealth of classified documents and supervise the continuing investigation of the Iran-Contra affair. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s spokesman, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Wieghart </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s war record, which was not mentioned in the statement, was coincidental to his being named head of the prosecution team. But <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>'s Purple Heart for his combat wound is a serendipitous qualification for the lead prosecutor in the case against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, who has made patriotism and his own <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> service a hallmark of his public defense since the Iran-Contra affair unfolded two years ago. North, 44, who earned two Purple Hearts for combat wounds, wore his Marine uniform when he testified before the congressional committees that investigated the arms-for-hostages deals. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> announced his courtroom team in advance of a hearing next Wednesday by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to begin final preparations for North's trial, which could begin as early as late January. The former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide, who retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> as a lieutenant colonel following his indictment last March, is accused of conspiring to illegally divert profits from the U.S.-Iran arms deals to the Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Keker </PERSON>, who is on leave from his <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> law firm, will be joined by associate independent counsels <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zornow </PERSON>, 33, and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bromwich </PERSON>, 34, both former federal prosecutors in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zornow </PERSON> investigated and helped try several major municipal corruption cases in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` This commits three of our most experienced criminal lawyers to the case,'' <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> repeatedly had expressed an interest in trying the case against <PERSON> North </PERSON>, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>'s decision to order separate trials for each of the defendants and the continuing complications of classified documents and congressional immunity given <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> forced a re-examination of those plans, according to a source who spoke on condition of anonymity. Besides the original grand jury that indicted <PERSON> North </PERSON> and his co-defendants, a new panel began meeting this fall to consider possible perjury by participants in the Iran-Contra affair. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> must be free to oversee the investigations and negotiate with intelligence agencies about disclosing classified information that <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> says must be included in the proof against North. <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mixter </PERSON>, who has been handling the prosecution's case during closed proceedings on secret documents in the North case, was named a member of the team of lawyers for <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>'s trial. <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> upon graduation from <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1965 and was commissioned a second lieutenant. Sent to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1966, he was wounded while leading an infantry platoon near the Demilitarized Zone. He left the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> in 1967 and studied law at <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He later served as law clerk to retired <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Chief Justice <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LaRouche Bjt   12-17 0975</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LaRouche, Bjt,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>LaRouche Says Conviction is `Obscene Miscarriage of Justice'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Political maverick <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> says his conviction of tax and mail fraud conspiracy is `` a wrong, gross, disgusting, obscene miscarriage of justice,'' and predicted he will die a martyr's death if sent to prison. `` They do n't want a living political martyr in prison, they want a dead one,'' said <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, claiming he was the victim of a hate campaign by the news media and a frameup by a pro-Soviet `` friends of glasnost'' clique in the Justice and State departments. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, 66, a perennial fringe candidate for president, told reporters he felt no remorse or sympathy for his followers, many of them elderly people, who had loaned his organization millions of dollars and gotten little or none of their money back. `` They have been wronged, not by us but by the government,'' he said, explaining that when several of his groups were forced into bankruptcy proceedings in April 1987, the government seized loan repayment funds. After less than 12 hours of deliberation, a federal trial jury on Friday found <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and six associates guilty of mail fraud and conspiracy for raising more than $ 30 million in loans from supporters without any intention of repaying them. In addition, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> was convicted of scheming to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> by having all his personal expenses paid by various corporations he controls and claiming he had no taxable income. Government prosecutors said <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> has not filed federal income tax returns for any year since 1978. Chief U.S. District Judge <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> set sentencing for Jan. 27, and allowed all seven defendants to remain free on their personal recognizance. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> faces a maximum penalty of 65 years in prison and fines totaling $ 3.25 million. All seven were found guilty of all 48 counts contained in an indictment returned by a federal grand jury on Oct. 14 after a two-year investigation of the LaRouche organization's financial affairs. The six convicted <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> associates, who face lesser maximum penalties, are <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertz </PERSON>, the leader's chief fund-raiser; <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Spannaus </PERSON>, legal coordinator for <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, and fund-raisers <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Billington </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Small </PERSON>. Defense lawyers said they planned to appeal the convictions. They repeatedly denied that <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> had sought to cheat federal tax collectors, and insisted that his fund-raisers had promised in good faith that the terms of the loans would be honored. Government prosecutors led by Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said the LaRouche people were lying when they solicited the loans with promises of prompt payment at preferred interest rates. In 1986, they said, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> associates were making an estimated $ 500,000 in improvements to his heavily guarded <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, estate, including a swimming pool and riding ring, while they were defaulting on millions of dollars in loans from supporters. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, who did not testify during the four-week trial in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, stood erect facing the jury of eight women and four men as a clerk recited their guilty verdict on all 13 counts against him. He sat down without a word or a gesture. Small nodded and smiled almost imperceptibly as he was convicted. Ms. <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> broke into tears and fell into the arms of a woman friend after she left the courtroom. Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Markham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> said he did not regard the outcome of the complex, hard-fought court case as a victory. `` I consider this an obvious conclusion to a long pattern of false statements to trusting senior citizens,'' he said. `` Their dreams for their retirement are gone. It's a sad case.'' Defense lawyer <PERSON> Kenly </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, who represented <PERSON> Spannaus </PERSON>, said the jury's decision probably was influenced by `` the size of the debt incurred and the failure to pay that debt back according to the terms and conditions.'' The jurors `` probably felt it would be a long time before they would be paid back, if at all,'' <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> said. He speculated that the jury also was influenced by the `` very controversial views'' held by <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> and his supporters on political issues, which seemed `` inextricably entwined'' with the defaulted loans issue. The LaRouche movement embraces numerous unorthodox positions and relies heavily on conspiratorial theories to explain world events. Some adherents have advocated quarantining AIDS victims. Others have alleged that former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> are involved in conspiracies At a news conference held in his <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> apartment suite shortly after the verdict was announced, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> said he himself was the victim of a conspiracy conceived by leftist government opponents, promoted by liberal dupes in the news media and carried to a climax Friday by `` a runaway jury ... with no regard for facts.'' <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> said he was convinced that his conviction is tantamount to a death sentence at the hands of fellow prison inmates. `` The way the jury voted, I'm dead,'' he said, adding that the government's goal was `` not to put me in prison but to kill me.'' <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> said he will leave behind the legacy of an international `` anti-Bolshevik resistance'' led by followers who are `` prepared to fight and die to save civilization'' from world conquest by the communists. `` We will kill and die if necessary to restore the kind of government the founders of this country fought to create,'' he said. <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> said he and his followers are not afraid to die. `` We are not a bunch of sentimental slush heads,'' he said. A separate criminal case involving <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON> is scheduled for retrial in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> starting Feb. 27. In that case, <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>, six aides and five of his organizations are charged with conspiring to obstruct a federal grand jury investigation into allegations that more than $ 2 million was raised for <PERSON> LaRouche </PERSON>'s 1984 presidential campaign through credit card and loan fraud.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-Profile     12-17 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Profile,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tower Backed Defense Buildup, Has Been Defense Consultant</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has turned for his defense secretary to a former senator who strongly backed the military buildup of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years and worked as a consultant for major military contractors after leaving <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, a 63-year-old Texan, retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 after 24 years including a stint as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. After leaving the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Tower went into business as a defense consultant. He also has served as an arms negotiator for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and he headed the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s Iran-Contra investigative panel. He was widely mentioned as a candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> job _ by most accounts the only one he really wanted _ under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never made the move. Tower comes to the job now at a time when the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> faces acute budget pressures because of the federal budget deficit and the array of costly new weapons systems developed as part of the military buildup. `` The bottom line is that we must provide at least as much, if not more, defense for less money,'' <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> said after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced his nomination Friday. The announcement followed a lengthy background check that brought a public airing of Tower's private life, including an acrimonious divorce, talk of drinking and womanizing, and questions about the propriety of naming someone to the job who had worked with so many defense companies. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> dismissed `` a lot of rumors that proved to be groundless'' and said, `` I am totally satisfied in that regard.'' The president-elect apparently decided that Tower's extensive financial ties to weapons companies that he will do business with as <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary was not a bar to service. Asked if Tower would stay out of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> matters involving corporations for whom he has consulted, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I expect so, but I do n't know. I expect he would, just like anybody coming in. ... I think we'll bend over backward in that regard.'' According to public records and associates, Tower's consulting firm of <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> has been on annual retainer with the following defense contractors: <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Textron </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> LTV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> and British Aerospace. In addition, Tower's firm received about $ 100,000 a year under a contract for consulting services to <ORGANIZATION> Hicks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> McLean </LOCATION>, Va.-based aerospace consulting firm headed by <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, a former undersecretary of defense. Through <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>' firm, Tower indirectly provided advice to still more defense contractors. Tower's firm received $ 96,000 a year from <ORGANIZATION> LTV </ORGANIZATION>. Although other fees were not revealed, an associate, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Billmire </PERSON>, acknowledged some were in the range of $ 100,000 a year. `` There are some retainers in the neighborhood of that figure, and others that are substantially less,'' <PERSON> Billmire </PERSON> said. Tower also received income from speeches _ about $ 15,000 each for the 30 or so a year he gives, according to his agent <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>. He has a second consulting firm, Dallas-based Tower, <ORGANIZATION> Eggers </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, which is described as providing financial services and advice. Tower was a former board member of a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> bank, <LOCATION> First </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. With his <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> firm, <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> was part of a group that unsuccessfully bid to buy the financially troubled bank before it was taken over by North Carolina-based <ORGANIZATION> NCNB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Billmire </PERSON> described Tower's work for the defense contractors as providing advice on the direction of future defense projects and advice and information on government budget processes, including the transfer of money among projects <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON> said he signed a contract for Tower's services in order to gain the benefit of his advice and opinions about what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> was likely to do on defense issues. In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Tower was a supporter of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Strategic Defense Initiative and the MX missile. But he was said to be angered by the administration's failure to agree on a missile deployment plan and he moved to block development until an acceptable plan was found. Tower left the arms negotiating post after 14 months, and in late 1986 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> named him to head his Iran-Contra investigative panel. Its report laid part of the blame for affair on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s management style _ but had little to say about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s involvement. In naming Tower, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was bringing a fellow Texan to the upper levels of his administration. Tower was the first Republican elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> since Reconstruction. He is a native of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and was a college professor before running for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. He was elected in 1961 in a special election to fill <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s seat, after <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> became vice president.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-Reax     12-17 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Reax,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tower Can Expect Friendly Reception in Senate Hearing</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As a former senator, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> will receive a certain deference at his confirmation hearing as <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s new defense chief. But he may also face serious questioning about his willingness to shoehorn <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending into a newly limited budget. `` I would say John Tower will be accorded special respect, but no special privilege,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., the senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> told reporters he had consulted with committee chairman <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., and that hearings on Tower's nomination would probably take place the week of Jan. 20 He said while Tower would undergo careful questioning, he ultimately will be confirmed. `` The day after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirms him he'll move into harness and step out,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said. `` He'll require no on-the-job training.'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, in a statement, said the confirmation hearings would focus on Tower's plans for meeting defense challenges over the next four years, including who will be appointed to senior <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> jobs, how congressionally mandated reforms will be put in place and how security will be maintained in a time of tight budgets. Some of those who will sit in judgment on Tower when he goes before the committee were there when Tower chaired the panel during the first four years of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. `` It will be a love feast,'' predicted <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaffney </PERSON>, a former top <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official now at the Center for Security Policy, a conservative <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> research organization. `` He's tough, he's shrewd, he's smart,'' said one of those former colleagues, Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, R-N.H. `` He's not likely to be hoodwinked by the Soviets. He is certainly well prepared in terms of expertise and experience.'' One issue likely to emerge during the confirmation hearings is how the nomination of <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON>, the former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> assistant secretary who is a central figure in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> procurement scandal, got past Tower when he chaired the committee. Tower has said his panel never was given access to an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> background report on <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> that contained damaging allegations and might have kept <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> from getting the senior job. Committee member Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., has asked President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to explain why those allegations never surfaced in 1981, when <PERSON> Paisley </PERSON> was nominated The long <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> background check on Tower, and talk about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s reported desire to put a strong manager in as Tower's second-in-command, have weakened the new nominee, said Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Colo </LOCATION>. She said that will make him more open to attack for coziness with the `` You have a new secretary who never saw a weapons system he did n't like,'' <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters. `` He is tainted in being able to run a tough, aggressive Pentagon.'' `` Over his career this is not somebody who has staked out a reputation as a tough, budget-cutting, six gun-toting decision maker,'' said <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, defense director of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, an independent analysis group. `` In the early 1980s, -LRB- while chairman of the committee -RRB- he signed off on the biggest peacetime buildup in defense since the end of World War II. He defended it, he pushed it through,'' <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said. `` The mission today is very different,'' he said. `` It's how do you get defense spending under control? He's got to be a guy who's learned how to say no, and I've not seen that in his past. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Korb </PERSON>, another former <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official now at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal research organization, said Tower will face a severe test. `` The question is whether he will be able to put together the team that can take a $ 400 billion program and put it into a $ 300 billion budget,'' <PERSON> Korb </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gaffney </PERSON>, however, said Tower's role should be to advocate <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending and fight against cuts. `` Tower is not going to have to prove anything except that he has the wisdom and tenacity to minimize the damage done to national security by people trying to effect draconian cuts in the defense budget,'' <PERSON> Gaffney </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower-Thumbnail     12-17 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower-Thumbnail,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Bush Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Thumbnail Look at Bush's Choice For Defense Secretary</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a look at <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice for defense secretary. AGE: 63. EDUCATION: Tower received his undergraduate degree from <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and did graduate work at <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> and Political Science. BACKGROUND: The son of a Methodist minister, Tower was in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> during World War II. After the war, he worked as a radio announcer and insurance salesman before teaching political science at <ORGANIZATION> Midwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. CONGRESSIONAL SERVICE: He was narrowly elected to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1961, winning a special election to fill the seat vacated by <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> when <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> became vice president. On the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, he made a name for himself as an expert on the details of weapons systems and defense policy. After Republicans gained control of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1980, Tower became committee chairman. He became the chief legislative champion of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s defense spending build-up and a deeply conservative critic of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. CONSULTANT: He retired in 1984 to become a high-priced <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consultant. In November 1986, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> picked Tower as chairman of the three-man presidential commission investigating the Iran-Contra affair. PERSONAL LIFE: A 1987 divorce from his second wife, <PERSON> Lilla </PERSON>, was granted after a legal battle in which she alleged that Tower had committed `` marital misconduct'' and carried on affairs during their 10-year marriage. Tower's deposition responding to the charges was sealed by agreement of both parties. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigation </ORGANIZATION> conducted an extensive background check into rumors of Tower's extramarital affairs and drinking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Theologian'sSuit     12-17 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Theologian's Suit,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Professor Says University Erred In Basing Suspension On Vatican
Order</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANITA WOMACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> administrators were wrong to have allowed the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> to influence their decision to suspend an ordained priest from the school's theology department, a <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor has testified. `` The church does not have a juridical role in the academic world'' because academic freedom is ultimately left to peer judgment, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> McBrien </PERSON>, chairman of Notre Dame's theology department. He testified at a non-jury trial Friday in support of the Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, who, in a suit against <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, contends his January 1987 suspension violated his academic freedom. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s disagreement with church teachings on homosexuality, birth control and other positions were pubished in his book `` Faithful Dissent.'' Afterward <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials revoked <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s `` canonical mission'' to teach <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> theology <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> sued <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> after it suspended him from its theology department on grounds that his writings were at odds with the faith. Cardinal <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON>, archibishop of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and chancellor of the university, testified on Thursday that the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> had the authority to decide when an ordained priest no longer spoke for the church. <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> testified that in suspending <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> he was enforcing the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s order. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> had taught at the school for 22 years. <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> was founded in 1885 as one of a few `` pontifical universities'' directly governed by the church. In his testimony Friday, <PERSON> McBrien </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s theological department, which had been held in high regard in recent years, now enjoys less respect from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> academic community, in part because of the Curran suspension Cardinal <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernardin </PERSON>, the former chairman of the board of trustees of <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, testified Thursday that the university was compelled by the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s action against <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> to suspend him from the theology department. `` If we were to directly defy the Holy See,'' the school risked having its charter revoked, said <PERSON> Bernardin </PERSON>, who is now the archbishop of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The trial continues on Monday, but lawyers representing both sides said a list of witnesses was being negotiated and had not been finalized.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-17 0082</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0089</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 10; 13; 14; 21; 35.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 8-8-8-0.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 03; 07; 11; 17; 24; 27.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 04; 05; 25; 27; 33; 39. Bonus: 78059.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 02; 06; 11; 13; 33; 37. Supplementary 43.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-4-2-0.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 2-7-1; 3-3-4-2; 9-6-7-2-4; 4-3-7-1-2-5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Tenants'Lawsuit     12-17 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tenants' Lawsuit,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>ACLU Files Lawsuit In Protest Of Housing Project Sweeps</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> filed a lawsuit against the city Friday, accusing housing officials of `` systematic warrantless searches'' of tenants and their visitors in an effort to crack down on drug selling. <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> officials later agreed to relax some of the security rules, but the lawsuit was not withdrawn from <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, said agency spokeswoman <PERSON> Katie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>. The lawsuit stems from a security crackdown by the housing agency, which is trying to evict squatters and violent gang members who use the projects as havens for drug deals. The lawsuit seeks to stop searches of tenants and their apartments and to establish `` reasonable regulations'' on visits by family members and other guests. Under the existing regulations, `` all guests of residents in the building have to sign in with the guard at the front door and show a piece of valid identification,'' Ms. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. `` The policy has been that guests are asked to leave the building at midnight and are not allowed in until 9 a.m.,'' she said. No overnight guests are allowed unless the tenant has received prior approval. The lawsuit says housing officials and police `` have indiscriminately detained and searched tenants' persons and homes, going through drawers closets, personal effects'' and other items. `` These searches have been carried out without the consent of the tenants and any prior notice. If tenants object, they have been threatened with arrest,'' the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. The lawsuit cites the case of a tenant who was forced to find another babysitter for her sister's children after housing officials ordered the children out of her apartment at midnight. Under the new rules, `` The guest upon entry, will identify him or herself to CHA personnel,'' but will not need a piece of identification, although the tenant must confirm that the person is a guest, Ms. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. Overnight visitors would be issued guest cards, and residents could have long-term guests for a period of up to two weeks. Ms. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> planned to present the proposals to the plaintiffs, and planned further discussions with the city. `` Our intent in all our security procedures is to provide for the safety and welfare of our residents and that will continue to be our objective,'' she said. The defendants are the housing agency, the city and police Superintendent <PERSON> LeRoy </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrooperShot     12-17 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trooper Shot,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Trooper Shot</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WACO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state trooper was shot in the head Friday night when he responded to a request for help from a sheriff's department, the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION> was in critical condition at <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in the central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> city, a spokeswoman said. <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> was shot about 9:30 p.m. when he responded to a <LOCATION> McLennan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's department call for assistance at <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, an unincorporated community near <LOCATION> Northcrest </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION> suburb, the <ORGANIZATION> DPS </ORGANIZATION> said. One person was arrested and <ORGANIZATION> DPS </ORGANIZATION> officials said another person might have been involved. Law enforcement agencies began an extensive search, involving about 200 officers, for the second person, said <ORGANIZATION> DPS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. The initial call from the sheriff's office involved a report of a man with a gun drawn, authorities said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FighterCrash     12-17 0175</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fighter Crash,0179</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jet Crash Lands in Bay Near Alameda Naval Station</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALAMEDA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> F-14 fighter jet crashed Friday night while trying to land. Both crewmen escaped injury, according to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. The aircraft went down in the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Estuary </LOCATION> a short distance before a runway at the northern end of the island housing the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>, 5 miles east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. One crewman was rescued by a passing tugboat, and the other was picked up by a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescue boat. The plane apparently sank. Both the pilot and the radar officer were taken to a naval hospital following the 7 p.m. accident, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. Both were in `` very good condition'' and were being observed for possible effects of shock because they were in the water a short time before rescue. It was not known whether either of the men were able to eject before the crash. The F-14, known as the `` Tomcat,'' is a two-seat carrier-based fighter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Karate-Kick 1stLd-Writethru a0412 12-17 0239</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Karate-Kick, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0412,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Karate-Kick Killer Convicted of Criminally Negligent Homicide</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to CORRECT `Uviller' to `Wallace'. SUBS last
graf with 2 grafs to include families' reaction to verdict</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man was convicted of criminally negligent homicide Friday in the karate-kick death of another man outside a bar. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, 21, initially indicted on a murder charge in the death of <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>, 25, slumped in his seat when the verdict was announced after 13 hours of deliberations over two days. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Rena </PERSON> <PERSON> Uviller </PERSON> released <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> on bail until sentencing Feb. 2. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> faces up to four years in prison. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> was accused of picking a fight with <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON> and his five companions outside a bar on Jan. 24 after one member of the group offended <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>. When <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON> told him no one wanted to fight, <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> spun 360 degrees and delivered a booted kick to <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>'s throat, knocking him back onto the pavement, according to testimony. <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON> died a short time later. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> was arrested two weeks later in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. The judge threw out the murder charge Tuesday, leaving just the first - and second-degree manslaughter and criminally negligent homicide charges As the jury foreman announced the verdict, both the victim's family and <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>'s family burst out crying and <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON>, hugged her son `` It's extremely disappointing,'' <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Klagsbrun </PERSON>, the victim's father, said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GrinchPinched     12-17 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grinch Pinched,0321</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grinch Spirited Away From Christmas Display</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Grinch </PERSON> was pinched from a hotel display, giving the storybook character a taste of his own medicine. The downtown Quality Inn has put up an eggnog reward for information leading to the return of the lanky larcener. `` We're missing a 6-foot green <ORGANIZATION> Grinch </ORGANIZATION>. AWOL in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>, manager of the downtown Quality Inn said Friday. No leads turned up Friday, although <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> said an ice carver would be bringing in an ice sculpture of the cold-hearted <ORGANIZATION> Grinch </ORGANIZATION> to replace the missing statue. Police were aiding in the search for the statue, said department spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>. `` We have a report of stolen property, a 6-foot papier-mache statue from the famous Dr. <PERSON> Seuss </PERSON> children's story,'' he said. `` We have no information as to its whereabouts.'' <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> said the theft was detected early Thursday after a party in a hotel ballroom where the <ORGANIZATION> Grinch </ORGANIZATION> was on display. `` There ca n't be that many gangly green Grinches wandering around <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> said. `` He's quite tall _ got a Christmas hat on.'' The <PERSON> Grinch </PERSON> was part of a Christmas display worth about $ 800, <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> said. Thieves left the sleigh on which the <ORGANIZATION> Grinch </ORGANIZATION> had perched. According to the children's story by Dr. <PERSON> Seuss </PERSON>, `` The Grinch That Stole Christmas,'' the dour green character makes off with a town's Christmas decorations and presents after becoming enraged by the sounds of Christmas cheer But the <ORGANIZATION> Grinch </ORGANIZATION> relents and returns the booty to <LOCATION> Whoville </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON> said hotel staff hope the heist is the work of a prankster who will decide to restore the decoration. `` We're offering a reward of a substantial amount of eggnog for anybody with information leading to the reapprehension of our friend,'' he said. `` I do n't know what the insurance company's going to say about it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-17 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0851</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> says he feels like he's on the right track when he gets to spend time playing with his 250 model trains. `` The noise of the trains running and whistling can get pretty loud, but watching the trains just removes my head from thinking about work,'' Ol' Blue Eyes said in this weekend's edition of <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> Weekend magazine. When <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> was an 11-year-old boy growing up in <LOCATION> Hoboken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, he desperately wanted a train set, `` but I did n't know how my family could ever afford it,'' <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> said. `` One day, my mother pawned her fox fur piece to buy my first train set, a windup engine and an oval track. I never forgot that. It was probably the only decent thing she had to wear and I was old enough to understand the sacrifice.'' So, now, at his <ORGANIZATION> Rancho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirage </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, home, <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> has an 18-by-30 train station with the 250 model traincars. Five trains can run simultaneously on independent loops, running through <LOCATION> Hoboken </LOCATION> or an Old West town and passing by a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> riverboat with a billboard announcing a sold-out <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> concert.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Basinger </PERSON>, currently starring in the comedy `` My Stepmother is an Alien,'' has filed for divorce from her husband of eight years, her attorney said. The divorce petition filed in <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday cited irreconcilable differences as the reason for the breakup between Miss <PERSON> Basinger </PERSON>, 35, and artist <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Britton </PERSON>, said attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Balaban </PERSON> on Friday. The couple married on Oct. 12, 1980. `` My Stepmother is an Alien'' also stars <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Aykroyd </PERSON>, who plays a widowed scientist who falls in love with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Basinger </PERSON>, a creature from space. She also has appeared in `` The Natural,'' `` Fool for Love,'' `` 9 -LCB- Weeks,'' `` Blind Date'' and `` <PERSON> Nadine </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cellist <PERSON> Mstislav </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, who is of Armenian descent, gave his first solo concert in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in nearly 20 years in a benefit to raise money for the earthquake victims in his homeland. The audience of about 2,000 stood in silence at <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>'s request at the end of the performance Friday, which included works by <PERSON> Johann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebastian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bach </PERSON> and British composer <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Britten </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostropovich </PERSON>, 61, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen, was due to take part in a second charity concert in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> today which Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> planned to attend. At the end of the performance, the Archbishop of <ORGANIZATION> Canterbury </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Runcie </PERSON>, paid tribute to the Armenian people for `` their sufferings, their talents and their achievements.'' `` We have felt something of all three tonight,'' <PERSON> Runcie </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: St. James's is correct.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lord <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Windsor </PERSON>, whose father the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kent </ORGANIZATION> is a cousin of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, was arrested for possessing marijuana but was released without charge after receiving a warning from <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard. <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>, 18, was arrested with a friend in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> James </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Buckingham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION> on Wednesday night, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard said in a statement Friday The two were taken to a nearby police station where officers issued a caution _ a formal warning _ about possession of illegal drugs before allowing them to leave. It said they were not charged because the amount of marijuana involved was small. It did not specify the amount of the drug and gave no other details. But a <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> Yard spokeswoman, who declined to be named, denied they were treated leniently simply because <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION>, who is 19th in line of succession to the throne, is a member of the royal family.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> is back home after his release from a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> hospital where he had surgery to correct a cerebrospinal fluid leak, his agent said. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> underwent the procedure at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said agent <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> on Friday. `` He is expected to return to performing in about a month,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. The 47-year-old pianist-songwriter with flowing silver hair is known for the hits `` Tightrope,'' `` Lady Blue'' and `` This Masquerade,'' returned Friday to his home in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said the condition caused <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> some sinus problems. `` He's still having headaches but that's about it,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prince <PERSON> Edward </PERSON>, youngest son of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, criticized a government move to cut welfare benefits for 16 - and 17-year-olds as a threatening blow to young lives The 24-year-old prince said Friday the teen-agers were `` prey to pimps and -LRB- drug -RRB- pushers'' and because of a shake-up in welfare payments `` by accident, I'm sure, their plight is about to get worse.'' `` This blow is only one of many which can wreck a young life,'' <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> said in a speech during the presentation of an award to a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> charity group. The government on Friday proposed a new law aimed at stopping unemployment benefits for an estimated 50,000 people who do not actively seek work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SocialSecurity     12-17 0486</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Social Security,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Many Who Sought Personalized Benefit Statement Have Not Mailed
Application</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Social Security Commissioner <PERSON> Dorcas </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> says many of the millions of people who flooded her agency with phone calls last summer for a new personalized benefit statement have not yet taken the trouble to complete the application. `` More than 6 million people have asked us for the statement. But only 35 percent of them have sent it back to us,'' <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> told reporters Friday. `` It's still hanging on their refrigerators.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> had trouble fielding all the phone calls requesting its Personal Earnings and Benefit Estimate Statement -LRB- PEBES -RRB- when it became available in August. But <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said the bottleneck on the phone lines has been cleared and `` we're ready, willing and able to provide them now. I would really like to have everybody have a PEBES in their stocking.'' The toll-free number to call is 1-800-234-5772. Operators are on hand to answer the calls at various Social Security centers from 7 a.m. to 7 p.m. local time on weekdays. Those who call after working hours or on weekends will get a recording capable of taking messages. Once the form is mailed back, it takes the agency three weeks to crank out the estimates of future monthly retirement benefits, as well as how much a worker and family gets if he or she becomes disabled or dies. The agency also provides a year-by-year list of workers' wages and Social Security taxes. In other matters, <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said she and the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> were unable to get included in President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s fiscal 1990 budget a proposal to eliminate a Social Security's earnings The earnings test reduces benefits of beneficiaries under age 70 who earn more than certain amounts. The thresholds this year are $ 8,400 for those ages 65-69 and $ 6,120 for those under 65; in 1989 they are $ 8,880 and $ 6,480 respectively. She also said, `` I'm hearing from seniors at town hall meetings that they are not pleased about the -LRB- income tax -RRB- surtax that's coming'' to pay for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>'s new catastrophic insurance benefit <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said she `` would n't be surprised'' if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> took another look at whether to levy the 15 percent tax surcharge on the elderly to pay for the insurance, which starts in January. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> wants all 130 million American workers to request their earnings records at least once every three years both to ensure their wages were reported correctly, and to get a better idea of what to expect from Social Security upon retirement. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> hopes that people armed with that information will save more and rely less on the government for their retirement income. Currently, more than half the elderly rely on <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> as their main source of income. But the program was always intended just to be part of retirement income, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Koop-DrunkenDriving     12-17 0581</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koop-Drunken Driving,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panels Urges Restrictions On Alcohol Advertising</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal panel is calling for restrictions on alcohol advertising and higher state and federal excise taxes in an effort to reduce drunken driving by discouraging alcohol consumption. Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> accepted an inch-thick packet of recommendations Friday at the close of a three-day workshop he convened, and he vowed to use his high public profile to publicize the report. While stopping short of urging an outright ban of beer, wine and liquor advertising, the panel said such ads should not be allowed on college campuses `` since a high proportion of audience reached is under the legal drinking age.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> told the workshop participants that his office had little money or power to implement policy, but promised to provide start-up funds for a non-profit, private corporation to serve as a clearinghouse for groups seeking ammunition to use in the war on drunken driving. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said that, for his part, he intends to be an aggressive but not shrill soldier. `` I intend to ignore those who would lynch or execute a first offender in drunk driving just as I will ignore those who would say it has not yet been proven that alcohol is responsible for impaired driving,'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> told the workshop. `` I intend to pursue whatever leadership role I may have between these two extremes as I have with other issues and to transmit to that leadership whatever energy, enthusiasm and credibility I have in this war against impaired driving.'' The panel's other recommendations called for: _ Elimination of alcohol advertising and promotion and sponsorship of public events where the majority of the audience is under the legal drinking age _ Elimination of advertising that portrays activities that are combined with alcohol use _ Banning of sponsorship of athletic events by the alcohol beverage industry _ Blocking the use of celebrities who have a strong appeal to young people in alcohol advertising and promotion _ Requiring that the warning labels <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> recently voted to require on alcoholic containers also be required to appear clearly and conspicuously in all alcohol ads No specific monetary figures were contained in the section on taxes, but the panelist said excise tax rates at both the federal and state level should be equalized among beer, wine and liquor and indexed to rise automatically with inflation. The advertising section was most controversial, largely because the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasters </ORGANIZATION> and the advertising industry had declined to participate in the workshop, claiming it was stacked against advertisers' interests. `` In fact, the research the ad industry provided the panel demonstrates that there is no existing evidence that links advertising and alcohol abuse,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> in a statement Friday. NAB President <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> last month: `` At best, this workshop is designed to politicize the emotional tragedy of drunk driving. At worst, it is a total abuse of the policy-setting process.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, who had not responded publicly to that charge, lashed back at the end of his remarks Friday. `` I wanted everyone to hear the <ORGANIZATION> NAB </ORGANIZATION>'s point of view not only because broadcasters are very influential, but because they also have so much at stake in this issue,'' he said. `` Hence, they certainly have the right to be here.'' <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said he felt the criticism of the workshop was unfair and said he was `` taken aback'' by what he called <PERSON> Fritts </PERSON>' `` unfortunate choice of words.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan     12-17 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Says America No Longer The Dominant Global Power</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in the last major foreign policy speech of his presidency that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> `` no longer enjoys preponderant power'' in the world. As a result, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, his Oval Office successors and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must not treat each other as `` adversaries'' but must work more cooperatively if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is to be successful in pursuing its interests in the global arena. `` It is precisely where <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president have worked together, as in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, or resolved differences, as in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and many aspects of U.S.-Soviet relations, precisely there, -LRB- where -RRB- our policies have succeeded, and we see progress,'' the president on Friday told students and faculty at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>, on the campus founded by <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>. `` But where <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president have engaged each other as adversaries _ as over <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies have faltered and our common purposes have not been achieved,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he thought that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in recent years had taken on too great a role in making foreign policy. Instead of linking his own support for the Contra rebels to the difficulties in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> blamed <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' `` on-again, off-again indecisiveness on resisting Sandinista tyranny and aggression'' in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> for leaving the area `` a region of continuing danger.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> complained about the War Powers Resolution, which gives <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> a veto power over the commitment of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops abroad after a 60-day period. He lamented attempts by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to `` manage complex issues of foreign policy by the blunt instrument of legislation, such as unduly restrictive intelligence oversight, limits on arms transfers and earmarking of 95 percent of our foreign assistance, denying a president the ability to respond flexibly to rapidly changing conditions.'' In his speech, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also lauded Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, saying `` let us credit him'' for his reforms. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> added that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> must remain skeptical about the U.S.-Soviet relationship because `` serious problems, fundamental differences remain.'' `` Yes, we welcome Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s recent announcement of a troop reduction,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` but let us remember that the Soviet preponderance in military power in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> remains _ an asymmetry that offends our Jeffersonian senses _ and endangers our future.'' `` So we must keep our heads, and this means keeping our skepticism,'' he said. He credited <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> with taking `` some daring steps'' to bring about reforms that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said would have been unthinkable under former Soviet leaders <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>. The president said the superpowers are `` coming closer'' to agreement on a <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reduction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Talks </ORGANIZATION> treaty, saying that `` where the portions of the draft treaty disputed by one side or the other are put in brackets, we are slowly seeing the brackets disappear.'' The president also credited <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s `` strong and steadfast'' support of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s statehood for persuading the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to moderate its views toward the Jewish nation. `` That resolve has now paid off'' with the opening of a U.S.-PLO dialogue aimed at advancing peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech came in the wake of his decision to reverse a 13-year <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy of refusing to have contact with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. `` Where we are strong and steadfast, we succeed,'' he said. `` The country stood firm for years, insisting that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> had to accept <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist ... and renounce terrorism.'' During a brief question-and-answer session with students, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> called the opening to <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> `` a great step forward.'' But he said that peace will be achieved only `` when the principals come together to negotiate.'' White House officials have said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> plans a farewell address to the nation sometime in January _ probably from the Oval Office. But spokesman <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Popadiuk </PERSON> said Friday that he did not know of any other foreign policy addresses scheduled in the remaining 35 days of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CasablancaPiano     12-17 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Casablanca Piano,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Casablanca Piano, Oz Witch's Hat Sold At Auction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KILEY ARMSTRONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s holy relics have changed hands. A piano played by <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> in `` Casablanca,'' the hat worn by the Wicked Witch of the West in `` The Wizard of Oz'' and <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>'s script for `` Gone With the Wind'' were all sold at auction Friday The Japanese trading company <ORGANIZATION> C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Itoh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> outbid developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> to buy the piano for $ 154,000, on behalf of an anonymous `` Casablanca'' fan in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` It's because many Japanese are fans of the old'40s movies,'' said a company representative, <PERSON> Mashahiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanaoka </PERSON>. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, who was in the audience bidding, went home without comment immediately after the piano sold at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s auction house in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. The green and beige upright piano, used in the flashback sequence of the 1942-43 <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> classic, had a pre-sale estimate of $ 75,000 to $ 100,000 by <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. Frankly, a dear price was paid for <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>'s script from the 1939 film `` Gone With the Wind'' _ $ 77,000, bid by telephone by <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> disc jockey <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Purtan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s had listed an estimate of $ 3,000 to $ 4,000 for the leather-covered script with <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>'s name embossed in bold. The auction catalog said <PERSON> Gable </PERSON> gave the script to an <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> studios </ORGANIZATION> secretary who was a `` close personal friend.'' An anonymous private collector in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> submitted the winning bid of $ 33,000 for the witch's hat. The black pointed hat was all that remained of the wicked witch when <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> accidentally melted her with a bucket of water. Nine stemware glasses from <PERSON> Rick </PERSON>'s Cafe Americain in `` Casablanca,'' estimated at $ 1,000 to $ 5,000, sold for $ 3,020. A Masonite advertising board used at the movie's 1943 premiere, estimated at $ 5,000 to $ 7,000, was sold for $ 22,000. The `` Casablanca'' piano was from the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> flashback scene at <LOCATION> Le </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aurore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cafe </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> -LRB- Bogart -RRB- and <LOCATION> Ilsa </LOCATION> -LRB- <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> -RRB- discuss love, marriage and the impending German occupation while <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Dooley </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> -RRB- plays `` As Time Goes By.'' Later, <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Ilsa </LOCATION> meet again at <PERSON> Rick </PERSON>'s Cafe in <LOCATION> Casablanca </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> plays an encore on another piano. `` You played it for her. You can play it for me,'' <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> said. To which <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> replied, `` But I do n't think I can remember.'' `` If she can stand it, I can. Play it!'' <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> commanded, in a line that has since been widely misquoted as `` Play it again, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>.'' Many famous props, such as the ruby slippers from `` The Wizard of Oz'' and the sled from `` Citizen Kane'' were made in multiples. However, `` This piano from the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> scene is truly unique in that it was actually used throughout the entire <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> cafe sequence,'' the auction catalog said. The piano also was used in 1943 in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Savings Bond drive featuring <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StealthCost 1stLd-Writethru a0405 12-17 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stealth Cost, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0405,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cost of New Bombers Put At More Than Half-Billion Dollars Apiece</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: RECASTS first two grafs; picks up 3rd graf bgng: ``Aldridge
told...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The $ 516 million-per-plane pricetag for the B-2 stealth bomber makes it the most expensive aircraft ever built, but <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> says whatever the radar-evading plane costs, it's worth it. The stealth bomber, which resembles a huge, tailless manta ray, is expected to make its first flight early next year but will not be ready for wartime use until 1992 at the earliest, <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> told a news conference the design, development and construction of 132 planes was expected to cost $ 68.1 billion by the time production ends in mid-1995. Expressed in terms of the original estimate, the price tag has grown from $ 36.6 billion to $ 42.5 billion in fiscal 1981 dollars _ an increase of about 16 percent, <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said. Those figures do not reflect cost increases caused by inflation since 1981 or that projected in future years. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must authorize and appropriate money for production, and the figures assume it will do so at the pace the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> proposes. <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said a stretchout of production would boost the per-plane cost by 20 percent or more. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> gave the public its first glimpse of the aircraft at a ceremony in <LOCATION> Palmdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, last month. About one-third of the total cost of the long-range bomber is being spent on research and development. The actual production cost amounts to $ 305 million per plane, <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said. `` Whatever it costs, it's worth it,'' <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said. `` How much is deterrence worth? `` This thing is a significant contributor to the strategic deterrence of our country. The Soviets know it. They know the capabilities this aircraft can provide.'' <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON>, reviewing the results of a long-running internal review of the B-2, said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> had decided to slow production of the bomber during the early years of the program and to accelerate production at the end. He refused to offer specific numbers, but he said the acceleration at the end of the program would be such that production of all 132 of the planes would be completed a year early, in mid-1995. The latest cost projection includes estimated savings of about $ 3 billion, the secretary continued, thanks to the changes in production and a decision to purchase more than 100 of the planes under a single, multiyear contract. Few of the planes will be built while the bomber is undergoing flight testing in the early years, <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> explained. Once the flight testing is completed and the design frozen, a multiyear contract can be negotiated to achieve the most economical rate of production, he added. <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said a large portion of the cost increase _ about $ 1 billion in fiscal 1981 dollars _ `` results from a major redesign effort in 1983.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> secretary said the redesign was ordered because the stealth bomber originally was meant only to fly at high altitude. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> decided in 1983 that the plane should be able to fly at low altitude as well and that forced a redesign of its flying wing shape, he said. The B-2 gets its stealth name from the claim that it will be extremely difficult to detect by enemy radar due to the extensive use of exotic composite materials, its lack of sharp surface angles, and a cross-section that offers a very small profile to radar. It is built mainly by <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. At $ 516 million per copy, the B-2 would eclipse the new B-1B bomber, which cost about $ 280 million per copy, as the most expensive plane in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> inventory The newest model of the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial aircraft, the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, sells for roughly $ 125 million. <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON>, appearing before <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> reporters on his last day in office before joining the <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the B-2 would fly for the first time `` as soon as it's ready,'' probably early next year. He said the first operational B-2 would be delivered to <ORGANIZATION> Whiteman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, in mid-1991 and that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> probably will select three additional bases to house them. It probably will be at least 1992 before the plane is certified for `` initial operational capability,'' meaning it could fly in a war, <PERSON> Aldridge </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     12-17 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>FEC Selects McDonald As Chairman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> has selected Democratic Commissioner <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> as its chairman for the coming year. <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> was appointed to the regulatory panel in 1981 and served as chairman in 1983. He succeeds <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Josefiak </PERSON>, who retains his seat on the six-member commission. Commissioner <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> was selected vice chairman. <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> members are presidential appointees, serving six-year terms, with three Democrats and three Republicans serving at any one time. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> formerly was general administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and secretary and chief clerk of the <ORGANIZATION> Tulsa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> is charged with regulating the federal election process, including all congressional and presidential campaigns. The panel enforces the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1974 which governs limitations on campaign contributions and spending and requires public disclosure of campaign finances.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>US, Soviets End Round of Talks on Nuclear Testing Without Accord</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators have reached virtual agreement on ways to measure some underground nuclear tests, but a final agreement still eludes the two sides. The result is further postponement of possible <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratification of two nuclear test treaties completed more than a decade ago. The treaties would limit underground blasts to 150 kilotons. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said he would submit the 1974 accord on weapons tests and the 1976 agreement on tests for civilian purposes only if agreement were reached on air-tight procedures to guard against cheating. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has accused the Soviets of carrying out tests that probably exceeded the permissible ceiling. Some American experts doubted the Soviets had violated the treaties, which both sides are supposed to be observing even though the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has not approved the pacts.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Court Upholds NRC On Importing Nuclear Fuel From South Africa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nuclear plant fuel may still be imported to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> despite anti-apartheid sanctions enacted by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a federal appeals court has ruled. A split three-judge panel of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> here ruled that the petitioners lacked legal standing to challenge the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to allow continued importation of uranium hexafluoride from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s 1987 decision was challenged by seven members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, four private organizations and two individuals, including an unemployed uranium miner and an anti-apartheid activist. The petitioners had contended that the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> failed to enforce the anti-apartheid sanctions passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 that forbid continued importation of South African uranium and uranium oxide. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> had decided that the sanction law did not ban uranium hexafluoride, a gas that is used to power nuclear reactors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hungary-ThemePark     12-17 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungary-Theme Park,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Communist World's First Large Theme Park By 1993</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A theme park dubbed the Communist world's first <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> will be built near <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> by a joint Austrian-Hungarian venture, the state <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. The <ORGANIZATION> Fanni-World </ORGANIZATION> company in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Hungarian </LOCATION> government have signed a `` declaration of intention'' in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> whereby the Austrian side would contribute $ 50 million or 70 percent of the amount needed for the venture, <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The Hungarian side is to pay another $ 20 million for the park, the report said. It said organizers planned to scour the <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> market for other capital needed to complete the project, but it did not say how much more will be needed. The park is scheduled for completion by 1993. The Marxist-oriented park will be `` an educational, as well as recreational complex'' with the equipment to be imported from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, French, Japanese and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> firms, <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> said, without elaborating. The park is planned eight miles from downtown <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. In recent years, about 12 million tourists visited <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> anually and organizers expect the facility to be toured by 30,000 people a day when completed, the news agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel Bjt   12-17 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel, Bjt,0666</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israelis Accuse Radicals Of Trying To Undermine U.S.-PLO Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> accused radical Palestinians of trying to undermine the U.S.-PLO talks by staging violent riots in the occupied territories that left at least four Arabs dead. <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> and other officials refrained from direct comment Friday after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegates held their first face-to-face meeting in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, but they reiterated their opposition to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s decision to speak to the organization <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision was `` a grave mistake.'' `` You abandoned an important principle in the general American policy, the principle of opposing terrorism and waging war against it,'' he said on <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> spoke after the 90-minute meeting between <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> and a four-man <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegation in <LOCATION> Carthage </LOCATION>, a suburb of the capital city <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>. The defense minister said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should demand the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> make <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> prove he was sincere when he said last week that he renounced all forms of terrorism. `` Our first demand from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should be, put <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> to a test, demand from him to come out and tell all the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> in his voice, in Arabic, to stop terror,'' <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said. Despite his opposition to the American-PLO dialogue, <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said it could lead to a decrease in violence. `` It was clear to us that a large part of the -LRB- <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> -RRB- population will see the events of the week as their achievement, and will try to moderate their role in violence,'' he said. `` But it was also clear that radical elements who oppose these moves ... will try to heat up the area,'' <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, the No. 2 man in the left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headed by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, echoed his party leader in saying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should counter the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> initiative with its own peace plan, `` even if it would not be accepted in the foreseeable future.'' He spoke on one of the bloodiest days of the Palestinian rebellion against Israeli rule in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. In Friday's clashes, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers shot to death four Arabs, and <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> doctors said as many as 32 were wounded. It was among the worst violence since April 16, when <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops killed 14 Palestinians during riots protesting the assassination in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> of <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> military The latest deaths brought to 328 the number of Palestinians killed in the yearlong revolt. Thirteen Israelis have also died during the unrest. Meanwhile, aides to Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc leader recognized the need for a credible Israeli peace plan. <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s spokesman, said the prime minister was considering `` new moves.'' `` Be sure that Mr. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> is preparing a peace move which will surprise everyone,'' <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> said, refusing to disclose details. Newspaper reports said the plan was to unilaterally establish a limited self-rule for Palestinians, as envisioned in the Camp David accords mediated by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1978. Friday's confrontations in the occupied lands were inspired by the death Thursday night of a teen-ager from a gunshot wound suffered Nov. 25, according to doctors at <LOCATION> Anglican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. Army officials said the riots appeared premeditated and began in numerous areas even before the teen-ager's funeral in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> city of <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> commander Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Gabi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ofir </PERSON> said the high casualty toll `` resulted from the fact that we had to disperse riots in many locations.'' Doctors said 20 people were wounded in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, four of them critically. The army confirmed four killed and nine wounded. Soldiers wounded five Palestinians in villages near <LOCATION> Tulkarem </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, including a 9-year-old boy shot in the neck, <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> witnesses said. Doctors said seven young men were wounded at the <LOCATION> Rafah </LOCATION>, Nuseirat and Jabaliya refugee camps in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Indonesia-EastTimor     12-17 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Indonesia-East Timor,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Timor To Be Opened Up To Outsiders</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Rudini uses only one name.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>JAKARTA, Indonesia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colony of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> will be opened to outsiders by Christmas, officials said. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> has been closed to foreigners since <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> troops invaded the small island territory in 1975 following an outbreak of strife between rival nationalist movements and the end of <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> rule. International humanitarian organizations estimate as many as 100,000 people, one-sixth of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>'s population, may have died in the hostilities and from the disease and famine that ensued. <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> subsequently annexed <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> as its 27th province. Since then, people traveling to and from the territory have needed certificates issued by security authorities. The home affairs minister, <PERSON> Rudini </PERSON>, said Friday that the security situation in the area had improved, allowing a relaxation of controls. International groups have called repeatedly on <LOCATION> Jakarta </LOCATION> to allow humanitarian organizations into <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> to observe the human rights situation. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> also has called on <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> to withdraw and allow residents of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION> to determine their own future. Nationalist guerrillas on the island continue to resist <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881217-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-17-88 0259EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TeacherShooting Bjt   12-17 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher Shooting, Bjt,0717</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-ager Kills Teacher, Wounds Another Before Gun Jams</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIRGINIA BEACH, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
