<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--AirportDeer     12-24 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Airport Deer,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Takeoff Aborted After Deer Seen on Runway</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> crew had to postpone their takeoff when a group of eight deer strolled across the runway. There was no sign of a sleigh or a jolly man in a red suit, witnesses said. The crew of another plane noticed the deer Friday and radioed <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION>'s control tower, which notified the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> pilots, said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Raynesford </PERSON>. <PERSON> Raynesford </PERSON> said no passengers were injured during the aborted takeoff, which he called `` an unusual event but really rather routine.'' The flight, which was headed to Minneapolis-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Airport </PERSON>, got off a few minutes later, he said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Psychiatrist-Sex     12-24 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Psychiatrist-Sex,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychiatrist Held Liable For $1.9 Million For Liason</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A jury ordered a psychiatrist to pay nearly $ 1.9 million to a female patient with whom he had sex numerous times over a 12-year period, billing her for each visit. The <ORGANIZATION> Multnomah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury deliberated for five hours Thursday before reaching its verdict against Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. The woman, a 55-year-old former elementary school teacher, was awarded $ 832,000 in general damages for pain and suffering, $ 1 million in punitive damages and $ 43,800 in lost wages. Testimony and evidence presented during the two-week trial indicated <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON> began treating the woman in 1967 and started having sexual relations with her in 1975. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Huegli </PERSON>, the woman's attorney, said <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON> ended the sexual relations in early 1987 while he was being investigated by the state <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiners </ORGANIZATION> about allegations that he was having sex with another patient. <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON> admitted he lied to the state board about the number of patients with whom he had sexual relations. In early July, the board suspended him from practice for 90 days, fined him $ 5,000 and placed him on probation for 10 years. <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, told jurors during closing arguments that her client is `` not going to be practicing medicine under any circumstances after this case is over.'' <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON> admitted <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON> had inflicted physical damage on the patient, but she contended it was not permanent. <PERSON> Huegli </PERSON>, however, said other doctors thought the woman suffered permanent brain damage from what he called a `` long, insidious, poisoning regimen'' of drugs prescribed by <PERSON> Petroske </PERSON>. <PERSON> Huegli </PERSON> said <PERSON> Petroski </PERSON> billed the woman for all her visits, including the ones in which they engaged in sex.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-UnitedTurnaround     12-24 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-United Turnaround,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Airlines Flight Doubles Back After Engine Trouble</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Chicago-bound <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet with 311 people on board dumped fuel over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> and returned for a safe landing Friday after it developed engine trouble. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> Flight 108 reported problems with the DC-10's rear engine, shortly after takeoff from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Abel </PERSON>. Frightened passengers who disembarked from the disabled plane told of hearing two loud bangs shortly after takeoff. After dumping fuel over the ocean, the pilot landed the plane about 2:20 p.m. PST. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> investigators were checking the engine, and there was no immediate determination of what caused the trouble. The plane has three engines and is designed to be able to fly even if two out of three are disabled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BarricadedNuns     12-24 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Barricaded Nuns,0491</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesting Nuns Will Spend Christmas Separated From Colleagues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TODD RICHISSIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORRIS TOWNSHIP, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two groups of feuding nuns at a monastery here will be separated by an iron gate as they celebrate the same Christmas Mass unreconciled after a 2 -LCB- - month standoff Five nuns who remain locked in the monastery's infirmary have said they will not rejoin eight other nuns until the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> answers their pleas to end the dispute over liberalizations of their order. `` They'll watch the midnight Mass from the where they are, through the bars,'' said Sister <PERSON> Eliane </PERSON>, a Carmelite who lives at the Most Blessed Virgin Mary of <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carmel </LOCATION> but is not among the 13 cloistered nuns. `` They'll all be doing the same thing, only they wo n't be doing them together.'' The five nuns will watch the Christmas midnight Mass through two small openings covered by an iron gate in the infirmary, which overlooks the darkened chapel of the monastery, Sister <PERSON> Eliane </PERSON> said this week. The rebel nuns locked themselves in the infirmary Oct. 4 to thwart what they say was their imminent eviction from the monastery. They said their mother superior, <PERSON> Prioress </PERSON> <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, wanted them kicked out for speaking against such liberalizations as the introduction of television and sweets to the monastery. <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> has said the dispute revolves around the barricaded nuns' unwillingness to follow her orders. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials so far have declined comment. The standoff at first was marked by a bitter media campaign, with Sister <PERSON> John </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, one of the protesting nuns, fielding reporters' questions by telephone, and <PERSON> Sister </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> holding a news conference to lambaste the nuns' `` attempted anarchy.'' Both sides have been virtually silent since. Meanwhile, friends and family of the nuns are trying to make the holiday a little brighter. The infirmary is decorated with a 2-foot Christmas tree adorned with red ribbons, an Advent wreath and small felt banners plastered with biblical passages, Sister <PERSON> Eliane </PERSON> said. `` They're not down in the dumps or anything, but they're anxious to hear from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>,'' she said of all the nuns who live at the monastery. `` It's obvious that it's not going to be settled before the holidays. We're just hoping it wo n't be too long after the new year.'' Christmas dinner also will be segregated. A man who caters a Christmas meal of fish for the monastery each year will carry on a tradition that was started by his late brother, a priest, Sister <PERSON> Eliane </PERSON> said. The donor, whom she would not identify, said he would provide dinner only if all the nuns share the food. They will, but they'll maintain their separate quarters, Sister <PERSON> Eliane </PERSON> said. `` Christmas is Christmas no matter what your problems are at the time,'' she said. `` We all plan on making the most of it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RedCross-Armenia     12-24 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Red Cross-Armenia,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Red Cross Focusing On Long-Term Aid To Soviet Armenia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has begun focusing on long-term plans to help earthquake-stricken Soviet <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> rebuild its destroyed and damaged health care facilities. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, said the pipeline of emergency aid supplies is full and flowing well, and no further immediate aid is needed at this time. Priority attention is being given to the construction of a new general hospital, he told a news conference Friday. The earthquake destroyed the only one, killing all doctors and staff inside the building. In a related development, the office of President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said his son and grandson are flying to <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> over the Christmas weekend to deliver toys and medical supplies to earthquake victims. <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 35, a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> real estate developer, and his son, <PERSON> George </PERSON>, 12, will spend about six hours in <LOCATION> Yerevan </LOCATION>, the Armenian capital, on Christmas Day. The Bushes are traveling to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> as volunteers for <ORGANIZATION> Americares </ORGANIZATION>, a private relief agency that has chartered a DC-8 cargo plane to transport supplies to the region when 55,000 people were killed in the earthquake and about 500,000 were left homeless. <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has received $ 3.5 million in cash contributions and pledges for <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> disaster relief and that more money is coming in `` every hour.'' He said the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> will use the funds to help replace health and medical facilities that were destroyed by the Dec. 7 earthquake. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> will be prepared to help fill any gaps that appear at the request of the Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, he said. <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said priority long-term needs in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> include: _ The building of a general hospital to replace one that was totally destroyed in the quake _ The creation of a facility to make and install artificial limbs _ The establishment of a permanent tracking center to trace families of earthquake victims _ A disaster preparedness program to reduce deaths and injuries in the event of another earthquake in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> _ The rebuilding and expansion of a destroyed school for handicapped children <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON>, who returned Thursday from an inspection tour of the disaster areas in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, said 27,000 railroad cars of relief supplies have arrived so far in addition to 148 planes carrying emergency equipment. He said Soviet officials have been conscientious in keeping track of the incoming supplies. They have promised to return expensive equipment to donors or to seek permission to use it elsewhere once it is no longer needed in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, he said. There have been reports of confusion and inept rescue efforts at the disaster scene, but <PERSON> Schuster </PERSON> said he believes the work went well given the immensity of the destruction and the relative inexperience of Soviet officials in disaster relief. `` Given the size of the disaster, I think they responded well,'' he said. `` It's impossible to have a disaster site in which there is not confusion initially.'' In addition, he said, it should be noted that in the first day or so, `` all of the people present were affected; they all lost family members.'' `` The people displayed wonderful warmth and dignity,'' <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said. `` Time after time they expressed their thanks to the American public, particularly to thank those in the <LOCATION> American-Armenian </LOCATION> community,'' he said. `` When they stopped to thank us on the streets the profusion of gratitude made it difficult to hold back tears _ theirs and ours.'' <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> helped deal with the crisis effectively and offered all forms of cooperation to its American counterpart. `` Bad times bring good people together,'' <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said. In addition to the $ 3.5 million in cash and pledges, <PERSON> Schubert </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has received more than $ 8 million worth of medical and other supplies and shipped them to <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. These include kidney dialysis machines, blood collection bags, plaster dressings, needles and syringes, finger splints, bandages, antiseptics, sutures, cervical collars, antibiotics, orthopedic pins, ultrasound machines, plastic eating utensils, blankets and plastic sheeting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ContinentalSettlements     12-24 0246</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Continental Settlements,0252</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Suits In Continental Airlines Crash Resolved by Settlement
Master</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two of 17 lawsuits filed after the crash a <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner last year have been settled out of court, according to court documents filed by Friday's deadline. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> Flight 1713 crashed on takeoff during a snowstorm Nov. 15, 1987, killing 28 of the 82 people on board, and injuring 54. The 15 remaining lawsuits are scheduled to go to trial beginning Jan. 9. Also Friday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Finesilver </PERSON> denied motions from the airline for dismissal of punitive damage claims, rejecting <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>'s contention that various provisions of the Federal Aviation Act pre-empt traditional areas of state regulation. He also ruled that <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law could be used to calculate damages, rather than <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> law which more severely limits such damages. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>'s parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, is based in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. Details of the two settlements disclosed Friday, both of which involved passengers who survived but were seriously injured, were not released. Initially, 36 lawsuits were filed but several have been settled out of court and several other new suits have been filed. Lawyers for Continental say <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> airport officials are responsible for allowing snow and slush to build on the runway and that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> allowed flights to continue throughout the snowstorm. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> also contends that the crash occurred because of swirling winds created by a jumbo jet that landed shortly before Flight 1713 took off.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Grain-Soviets     12-24 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grain-Soviets,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Allowed To Buy US Wheat At Cut-Rate Prices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has authorized the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to begin a new round of subsidized wheat purchases from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Acting Undersecretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said Friday that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has been allocated 2 million metric tons of wheat under the department's Export Enhancement Program, or EEP, which allows designated foreign buyers to buy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at cut-rate prices. The Soviets bought about 9 million tons of wheat under <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> arrangements during the 1987-88 year that ended Sept. 30 but so far has not ordered any for 1988-89 delivery. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> also said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will be allowed to buy up to 16 million tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain in the 1988-89 year. The limit under a recently extended agreement between the two countries was 12 million tons. Meanwhile, the department said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has bought more corn, which does not carry the <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> subsidies. Both wheat and corn are included in the agreement. The <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> arrangement allows <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> exporters to sell wheat and other designated commodities to specified countries at reduced prices in order to meet foreign competition. The exporters then collect free government surpluses of grain or other products as bonuses, or subsidies. Earlier this week, for example, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> announced an <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> wheat sale to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> that carried a subsidy rate of $ 23.10 per ton, or about 63 cents per bushel. Officials also said Friday that the Soviets bought an additional 750,000 tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn, bringing the total sold to 8.78 million tons in the agreement's sixth year, which began Oct. 1. Last year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> totaled slightly less than 5.2 million tons. Wheat sales in 1987-88, all subsidized, totaled slightly more than 9 million tons. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 39.4 bushels of corn or 36.7 bushels of wheat or soybeans. The 750,000 tons of corn would be about 29.5 million bushels. Corn prices have been averaging about $ 2.61 per bushel at the farm level, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates, meaning that the latest sale could have a farm value of around $ 77 million. Besides the corn and the likelihood of wheat for 1988-89 delivery under the pact, the Soviets have ordered 500,000 tons of soybeans and 532,500 tons of soybean meal, plus 500,000 tons of grain sorghum. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Nov. 28 signed an extension of the previous five-year grain agreement, which had expired on Sept. 30. The extension of the previous pact will run through Dec. 31, 1990.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FmHADeadline     12-24 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FmHA Deadline,395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Easing Some Requirements For Delinquent Borrowers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Under pressure from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is easing some of the paperwork requirements for delinquent borrowers. But it says a 45-day deadline for responding to overdue notices wo n't change. A growing number of lawmakers have been urging the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> agency to extend the deadline, which gives farmers 45 days in which to respond after receiving official notices to begin settling overdue loan accounts. The notices were sent out last month to more than 80,000 delinquent borrowers who owe FmHA more than $ 8 billion. `` There's just no way legally we can stretch it -LRB- the deadline -RRB-,'' acting agency Administrator <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Verne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ausman </PERSON> said Friday. `` We must hear from the farmer within that time.'' Several basic `` response'' forms must be completed and returned within 45 days as the minimum requirement. <PERSON> Ausman </PERSON> said that in order to ease paperwork requirements for late repayers, <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> county offices will accept supporting documents for the applications after the 45-day deadline, but that such agreements must be worked out with those offices. The notices were sent out to FmHA borrowers who were at least 180 days delinquent in repaying loans. The notices informed them of loan servicing and restructuring options, and said failure to respond would trigger `` acceleration'' of loan collection, a step toward foreclosure or forced sale of assets. `` We have advised our field offices to use a test of reasonableness with borrowers who, through no fault of their own, are unable to complete all the forms on time,'' <PERSON> Ausman </PERSON> said. `` For example,'' he added, `` if because of illness or other circumstances beyond his or her control, a farmer could n't obtain all the information he or she needed, we wo n't be hard-nosed if they have given us completed response forms, and farm and home plans. But we will be looking for evidence of a good-faith effort on the part of the borrower to get all the forms in a timely manner.'' <PERSON> Ausman </PERSON> said that as a minimum, the documents that must be sent in within 45 days include: _ Form FmHA 410-1, Application for <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> _ Form FmHA 431-2, Farm and Home Plan, including the balance sheet _ Attachment 2, Acknowledgement of Notice of Program Availability, or Attachment 4, Response to Notice Informing Me of <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>'s Intent to Accelerate My Loan
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ShuttleBoosters     12-24 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle Boosters,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Advisory Panel Raises Doubts About Effort To Ensure Shuttle Safety</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A scientific advisory panel says it has concerns about <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to continue improvements in the design of the space shuttle's booster rockets. <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Guyford </PERSON> <PERSON> Stever </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> panel, said Friday that although <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> has flown two successful missions since the 1986 Challenger accident, he has a `` broad concern'' that the space agency continue to monitor and evaluate the redesigned booster rockets. `` Success breeds confidence, and that's what you want, but it can also threaten you with complacency,'' <PERSON> Stever </PERSON> said in an interview. He added, `` I do n't see complacency developing, but I do know they have budget problems, and how they'll solve that is difficult to say.'' <PERSON> Stever </PERSON>'s panel, in its final report delivered to <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, cited two new problems with the redesigned boosters used in the Sept. 29 launch of the shuttle Discovery: _ Small pieces of cork used to cover external diagnostic instruments and their electrical leads were lost during flight and one piece is believed to have damaged thermal tiles on the orbiter <PERSON> Cork </PERSON> is also suspected of causing extensive damage to tiles on Atlantis, which was launched Dec. 2. _ Metal-to-metal seals were scratched and pitted <PERSON> Stever </PERSON> said that removal of the seals could raise shuttle program costs, but he said the scars were small and did not threaten safety. The report also lists nine problem areas that need to be addressed before the redesign effort can be considered complete. Among the remaining tasks are strengthening of the conical base of the booster rocket, more testing of booster segments to determine their potential to be reused safely, improving materials for bonding booster parts, developing alternative materials for O-ring seals and more test-firing at cold temperatures, the report said. In the Challenger accident, one of the O-rings between the booster segments failed, allowing hot exhaust gases from the rocket to leak and cause the explosion that destroyed the shuttle and killed its crew of seven. Cold temperatures also contributed to the O-ring's failure. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said it will `` carefully consider all the group's recommendations. <PERSON> Stever </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials have told him the agency has plans to carry out some of the tasks cited in the report, including a cold-weather test scheduled next month, and is considering the others on the list. The booster rockets worked for 24 flights before failing on the Challenger mission, <PERSON> Stever </PERSON> pointed out. Referring to the redesigned booster rockets, he said, `` we do n't consider it a bad design, it's just that things could be improved further. The report also recommends several risk-reduction steps, including maintaining technically competent personnel familiar with booster design to evaluate and improve quality control, assembly and launch operations and maintaining ground-testing and in-flight performance measuring programs. It also recommends insulating the budget for these safety activities from `` competitive pressures'' from other programs. The panel of independent scientists was set up at the request of the White House-appointed <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> commission that investigated the Challenger accident. The commission asked the panel to monitor <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s compliance with its recommendations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RobinsonMemorial     12-24 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robinson Memorial,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Says Robinson Tried To ``Change the Temperature''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former ABC News anchorman <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who died of complications resulting from AIDS, was eulogized by the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a man who `` would n't adjust, would n't knuckle under the face of ... racism.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, a close friend of <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s, delivered the eulogy Friday at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> church where friends and co-workers of the nation's first black network television anchor paid their last respects. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, `` would n't adjust, would n't knuckle under the face of obvious and not so obvious racism.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> had been ill for more than a year when he died Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> at age 49. `` <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> never adjusted,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` He sought to transform. He was not a TV thermometer who measured things and spilled them back out. He tried to be a thermostat _ to change the temperature.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told reporters that he talked to <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> about how he had contracted AIDS and that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> told him: `` It is not homosexuality but it was promiscuity. ... Let my predicament be a source of education to our people.'' Among those attending the ceremony were ABC News President <PERSON> Roone </PERSON> <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON>, 60 Minutes reporter <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION> anchorman <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. `` I think ABC News is a better place today than it was before <PERSON> Max </PERSON> was there,'' said <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON>. `` A lot of that is due to his efforts.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> began his broadcasting career as a radio station disc jockey in his hometown of <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1965 and three years later became the first black to anchor newscasts at a major TV station, appearing on the 6 p.m. and 11 p.m. news on Channel 9 <ORGANIZATION> WTOP </ORGANIZATION>, now <ORGANIZATION> WUSA </ORGANIZATION>, with co-anchor <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> then left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> after 10 years at the top of the ratings to join <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> as the first black to anchor a network news show. He was one of three anchors at <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, along with <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>. The frustrated <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> made headlines publicly denouncing racism at the news organization during a speech at <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in February 1981. <PERSON> Arledge </PERSON> was supervising news coverage when <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was an anchor, and he changed <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>' three-anchor format after <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> died in 1983. At that point, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> inherited the job as sole anchor of the newscasts, and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was assigned to do news briefs and weekend anchor. In 1984, he left <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and joined <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The following June, he entered a hospital specializing in alcohol rehabilitation suffering from emotional and physical exhaustion, according to <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON>, director of communications at <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ-TV </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Aronson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> never returned to the station, and did sporadic freelance work after that. He is survived by his mother, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, and stepfather, the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, both from <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and four children, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>, <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> and <PERSON> Malik </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> also leaves three surviving siblings, <PERSON> Jewel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepperd </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> <PERSON> Yancey </PERSON> and civil rights activist <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, the head of <ORGANIZATION> TransAfrica </ORGANIZATION>. All live in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Obit-Gonella     12-24 0208</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Gonella,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lobbyist John Gonella Dead At 71</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonella </PERSON>, a former aide to President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> lobbyist, died Friday at his <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> home at age 71. <PERSON> Gonella </PERSON>, most recently an assistant to the vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroads </ORGANIZATION>, began his career in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1949, when he moved here to work as an information officer for the embassy of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. He was a press spokesman and congressional liaison with a number of firms before joining the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s congressional relations office in 1965. He joined the Johnson White House staff in 1966 and served as a congressional liaison through 1969. <PERSON> Gonella </PERSON> worked as a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consultant for two years and then worked from 1971-77 on the staffs of Sens. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. During the 1950s, <PERSON> Gonella </PERSON> also wrote a golf column for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gonella </PERSON>, a native of Dollar, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Glasgow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> with degrees in economics and political science. He served in the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> during World War II and came to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 1948, where he was a professional golfer and radio and television newsman before moving to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> a year later.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FreePress     12-24 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Free Press,0335</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newsgathering Perils Rose In 1988</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-five journalists were slain around the world in 1988, seven fewer than in 1987, but other forms of violence and intimidation against news gatherers increased, according to a survey of press freedom. During the year, 225 journalists were arrested or detained in various countries and 24 expelled, <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> said Friday in its annual survey. Fourteen were kidnapped or disappeared, 28 wounded, 90 beaten or otherwise assaulted, 43 were targets of death threats and 12 had their homes raided or destroyed, it said. It said 40 newspapers or radio stations in 12 countries were closed and that nine were bombed, burned or destroyed. Also, more than 200 instances of lesser harassment occurred. The anti-press actions occurred in 70 countries, compared with 57 countries the year before. `` The figures do not reflect other forms of official and unofficial editorial censorship, and diverse methods of economic and political pressuring of the mass media,'' said the survey report by <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sussman </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> senior scholar. `` The statistics are a clue, however, to those official actions which generate self-censorship by journalists.'' The figures for 1988 are as of Dec. 10. The world survey rated press conditions as `` most free'' in 57 countries, including most states of the Western alliance, and `` least free'' in 83, including the communist bloc and much of the Third World. Nineteen other countries were described as `` intermediary'' and included some of <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and scattered Third World nations. It said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>, whose press is in the most-free category, was slipping by using its Official Secrets Act to try to block publication of some stories. It said that such least-free nations as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> had improved by displaying more openness while remaining centrally controlled. <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> describes itself as a non-partisan national organization that monitors political and civil rights and tries to strengthen free societies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     12-24 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCKVILLE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drivers who overstayed their parking meters received a surprise holiday message _ in meter _ from <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Parking employees in the county north of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, put a few lines of poetry on the windshields of violators Thursday instead of the usual $ 10 tickets. The 4-by-8 inch cards bore this greeting: `` The meter was red as time had expired `` In the rush of the season we knew you'd be tired, `` A parking ticket would just make you blue `` In the holiday spirit this just would n't do, `` So during this time of friendship and good cheer `` Season's Greetings to you and best wishes all year.'' The holiday gesture cost the county approximately $ 10,000 in potential fines, officials said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TEMPLE CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For 56 years, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON> and <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Dutton </PERSON> have been exchanging Christmas cards _ or rather one Christmas card, sent back and forth year after year. The greeting features a bagpipe-playing Scotsman with the verse: `` Hoot! for a Jolly Christmas! I'll send a card to wish ye a Christmas full of cheer. I'll send my name in pencil so ye'll use the card next year.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON> first sent the card to her friend in 1932. `` I thought it was funny,'' she said. `` So I did sign it in pencil along with the date, mailed it off to <PERSON> Grace </PERSON>, and forgot all about it.'' Sure enough, a year later it returned with Ms. <PERSON> Dutton </PERSON>'s name signed below Mrs. <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON>'s. `` We signed and dated it every year, in pencil of course, first on the front, then on the back, until we ran out of room,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON> said. The exchange continued even after Mrs. <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON> moved to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> with her husband to do missionary work for several years with the <ORGANIZATION> Nazarene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The friends say their relationship has been as durable as the card. `` We keep in touch, and see each other several times a year,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Sedat </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For those who are n't resolving to tighten their budgets for the new year, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> hotel is offering `` total indulgence'' for `` as long as you want it or can afford it'' _ at a mere $ 3,000 per night. Beginning Jan. 3, the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ritz-Carlton </ORGANIZATION> will join with the new $ 2 million Spa at The <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> a block away to offer guests a night of `` unparalleled, unremitted pampering,'' according to the hotel's promotional literature The $ 3,000-per-couple package _ tax and tips included _ offers limousine pick-up, a night in the posh hotel's Presidential Suite, unlimited food and drink and `` all the spa services that two people can indulge in individually or collectively.'' Spa guests may attend an exercise class, use the health club's weightlifting and cardiovascular equipment, or swim in a four-lane pool that features `` artistic falling leaves across the bottom in colorful tiles. Next is an hour of massage _ Swedish, polarity, cross fiber, sports or shiatsu _ or a choice of herbal steam wraps, Austrian mud body treatment, seaweed body wrap, cellulite treatment, clay body wrap, brush and tone treatment, or a Swiss shower. The package also includes a detailed fitness evaluation and nutrition advice, a facial, blow-dry and, for women, make-up consultation and application. In addition to its classic French cuisine, the hotel also offers low-calorie, low-cholesterol and low-sodium dishes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OilSpill 1stLd-Wriththru a0697 12-24 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Spill, 1st Ld - Wriththru, a0697,0441</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oil Spills In Pacific After Tug Hits Barge</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: UPDATES throughout with size of slice increases to 30 miles;
at least 50 birds found with oil on feathers; oil seen on beach,
other detail. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WESTPORT, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fuel oil from a leaking barge began washing ashore on resort beaches of the southwestern <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> coast Friday, and at least 50 birds were found with oil on their feathers, officials said. The barge trailed an oil slick that grew to 30 miles long and 100 feet wide in the hours after a Thursday night collision with a tugboat, <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> officials said. Authorities closed 1 -LCB- to 2 miles of beach in the <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shores </LOCATION> area near here, on the north side of <LOCATION> Grays </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, where oiled birds were found. The area contains numerous wetlands and marshes that are home to migratory waterfowl. Rescue teams were being mobilized to try and clean and save as many birds as possible, authorities said. `` The latest reports I'm getting indicate an average of 12 dead or distressed birds are being found every quarter of a mile along the beach,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, a spokesman for the state Divison of Emergency Management. The leaking barge was towed south to the mouth of the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which separates <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. It bobbed 25 miles offshore Friday night while authorities waited for daylight to assess how best to repair it. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state officials estimated some 70,000 gallons of oil had spilled from the barge, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Steelquist </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION>. The oil was leaking from a tank holding about 250,000 gallons of oil, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Eldo </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLong </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. In all, the barge held about 2.75 million gallons of oil, but only the one tank was leaking. <PERSON> Sause </PERSON> <PERSON> Bros </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Towing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Coos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, operators of the barge and its tugboat, hired crews to clean up the beaches. The accident occurred Thursday night as a tow line either broke or was being adjusted in heavy seas between the tug <ORGANIZATION> Ocean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and the barge, named the <LOCATION> Nestucca </LOCATION>. The accident occurred about two miles off <LOCATION> Grays </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, on the southwestern <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> coast. The barge had been scheduled to make a delivery at <LOCATION> Grays </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, then head to <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sause </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bros. </LOCATION>. Officials said they would have a better idea Saturday of the extent of the damage to beaches and wildlife <LOCATION> Grays </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrisette </PERSON> said he could smell oil in the air and the sand was darker than usual.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-24 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 06; 13; 25; 36; 38.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     12-24 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 03; 06; 13; 25; 36; 38.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 2-2-3-7.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 04; 11; 15; 22; 31; 36.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 16; 29; 31; 34; 36; 39. Bonus: 48423.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 09; 23; 24; 26; 33. Supplementary 39.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 7-2-1-3.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 4-6-6; 3-6-5-9; 6-7-9-8-8; 1-0-6-2-2-4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Crash-Alert 1stLd-Writethru a0419 12-24 0895</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash-Alert, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0419,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>FAA Posts Worldwide Airport Alert To Tighten Security</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 8th graf pvs, McArtor said, to ADD that Heathrow not
alerted; SUBS 13th graf, ``We will, to DELETE redundant reference to
McArtor; recasts 17th graf pvs, bgng While the; picks up 18th graf,
In many</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has advised airports worldwide to tighten security because of concern _ not yet confirmed by investigators _ that a terrorist bomb may have caused the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> crash in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said Friday the alert was prompted by the crash, the heavy Christmas travel period and `` what obviously can be considered a heightening of world tensions'' regarding terrorist activities. The advisory to beef up security applies to both major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airports and airlines and foreign airports served by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carriers, he said. <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON>, in an interview with reporters, declined to discuss specifically Wednesday's crash of <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> Flight 103, in which all 258 people aboard perished. There has been widespread speculation _ and some preliminary indications _ that an explosion may have caused the crash, although no clear evidence of terrorist involvement has yet to surface. Suspicions of sabotage were prompted by the unexplained sudden breakup of the plane, a claim of responsibility and disclosures that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government had been warned of a plot to bomb a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight between <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in December. The ill-fated Flight 103 originated in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, with a change of planes in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> had imposed `` a very heightened level of security'' at <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> airport after the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> alerted the airline in early December that an anonymous threat had been received by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, from a caller who said a bomb would be planted aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flight from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>'s precautions at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Heathrow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, from which Flight 103 had departed 54 minutes before the crash, were still under review. British officials at the airport said they had not been notified about the specific threat. At <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said, <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> briefed gate personnel about the possible threat, kept ground baggage handlers and caterers `` under constant surveillance'' and checked all luggage by X-ray instead of only at random. All passengers and their bags also were matched prior to boarding, he said. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, leaving the White House for a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> vacation, mourned the victims of the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> disaster and asked Americans to `` say a special prayer'' this Christmas for families and friends of those killed in the crash. Meanwhile, some aviation safety and crash investigation experts _ though not directly involved in the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> investigation _ suggested that while the investigation in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> may take months the cause of the crash is expected to be found. `` It will be a massive job to reconstruct the pieces,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schleede </PERSON>, chief of aviation accident investigation at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. `` But they're going to solve it because the evidence will be there.'' `` We will know what brought down <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> 103,'' <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said, but he cautioned `` it could take months.'' Neither <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Schleede </PERSON>, who has been briefed daily by telephone by <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> officials at the crash site, would discuss specifically the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> findings so far. But <PERSON> Schleede </PERSON> and other experts noted in interviews that the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> crash investigators have some advantages. For example: _ Most of the aircraft appeared to have escaped serious fire damage, with the exception of a destroyed right wing where a fuel tank exploded In many crashes where a plane remains intact and burst into flames, critical clues are lost because of the intense heat that bends metal and destroys evidence. _ The wreckage, although strewn across the countryside, is not exposed to ocean elements that could destroy critical evidence If the plane had continued on course it would have been over the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> in less than an hour. _ The cockpit voice recorder and flight data recorder were recovered in apparently good shape In the coming days, investigators will pay close attention to how parts of the aircraft are bent, tangled and singed and whether there is evidence of a chemical residue normally left by an explosive. They also will search for fragments that might have been used as a detonator and closely examine luggage and parts of luggage as well as aircraft wreckage holes left by flying fragments. Such holes leave a distinctive pattern if caused by an explosion, one expert said. Some of the wreckage will be reassembled as closely as possible to the original aircraft and metallurgists will try to determine how the pieces broke apart. The flight data recorder, which monitors the performance of the aircraft, and the cockpit voice recorder will be examined further and their times coordinated. A key question is whether all of the plane's electrical systems were knocked out simultaneously, one veteran investigator said. It is known that Flight 103 in rapid order lost its radar transponder, radio contact and both flight and cockpit voice recorders, this investigator said. If all of these functions failed simultaneously, there is strong evidence of a massive electrical failure, possibly cause by an explosion near the forward baggage compartment, which is adjacent to the electrical and computer systems on the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, experts suggested.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Smith     12-24 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Smith,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Actor-Dancer Tucker Smith Dies of Cancer at 52</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who played the <ORGANIZATION> Jets </ORGANIZATION> gang's cool lieutenant Ice in the Oscar winning movie `` West Side Story,'' has died. He was 52. The actor-dancer died from neck and jaw cancer Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said his publicist, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Liberman </PERSON>. After the landmark 1961 movie, which won 10 Oscars, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> joined the stage version of the musical in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Liberman </PERSON>. He also appeared in the films `` Hearts of the West'' and `` To Be or Not to Be.'' His stage credits included `` Parade'' with <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, `` Vintage 60,'' and `` Anyone Can Whistle'' with <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Remick </PERSON>. He also toured internationally with his own nightclub act. He is survived by three daughters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-24 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0743</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> is suing a hotel chain he claims did n't give him any respect when it hired an actor to impersonate his voice in radio commercials. The commercials for <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Irving </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, carried a disclaimer that said the voice was an impersonation of <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON>. But the comedian's lawsuit contends the disclaimer was n't clear because it was followed by the actor saying Dangerfield-style, `` You mean this guy ai n't a real announcer? He really had me fooled.'' The advertising campaign was launched in the summer without permission from <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> or his agent, according to the suit filed recently in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, an attorney for the chain, was unavailable for comment late Friday. There was no response to a message left with the hotel's management company, <ORGANIZATION> Emerson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Rooney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> will have their run of `` Sugar Babies'' cut short in January because the musical is losing money, a spokeswoman for <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Savoy Theater said. The Broadway hit opened in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Sept. 20 and had been expected to run at least six months, but the cast has been told the curtain will come down Jan. 7. `` The last couple of weeks, audiences have only been about 40 percent. They spent a lot of money advertising the show, but it had almost no effect,'' the spokeswoman said Friday. `` There is no sign of things getting any better, so the only thing to do was to close it.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>STATELINE, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> says his efforts to modernize his mother's kitchen with Christmas presents were for nought _ she insisted on treating the gifts as trophies. `` I tried to give her presents I really thought she needed _ an electric toaster, a waffle iron, a percolator coffee pot; She loved them all,'' the comedian said. `` But did she use them? No. `` She put them all on top of the refrigerator like they were trophies from the Olympics and she'd get really mad if anyone took them down and tried to use them.'' <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON>, who is to appear at a hotel-casino Jan. 3-8, said he particularly remembers looking up at a shiny new toaster while browning bread the hard way. `` For years, we still made our toast in the bottom of the oven,'' he recalled recently. `` You put it in, wait a while, then turn it over and burn your fingers while that terrific stainless steel toaster ... sat on top of the refrigerator. `` My mother was a little strange about Christmas.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Esai </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> is giving up his holiday feasting for a three-day fast to protest the use of pesticides by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> grape growers. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>, who starred in the 1987 hit movie `` La Bamba,'' accepted a crucifix made of dried grape vines from union leader <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> at a ceremony Friday. The cross was worn by <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, during his 36-day fast that ended Aug. 21. It has been passed on since then to politicians and celebrities including the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>. The union claims the pesticides have caused cancer in farm worker families. <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> plans to fast through Christmas Day.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vikings </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> is recuperating from a broken collarbone after being struck by a taxi while jogging with his dog. <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON>, 50, was crossing a street in nearby <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gatos </LOCATION> on Thursday when a car driven by <PERSON> Festus </PERSON> <PERSON> Banjo </PERSON>, 46, turned a corner and hit <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> with its right front bumper, police said. <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> was knocked unconscious and was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. The dog was n't hurt. `` We're fine,'' <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> said from his hospital bed Thursday night. `` It was a rainy morning; I did n't see the car at all. I was lucky. It could have been worse. The last I heard, the car was n't hurt too badly.'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gatos </LOCATION> police said Banjo would be cited for violating a pedestrian's right-of-way. <PERSON> Kapp </PERSON> led the <ORGANIZATION> Vikings </ORGANIZATION> to the Super Bowl in 1970 and later coached the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California-Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> football team for five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MotherMurder 2ndLd-Writethru a0716 12-24 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mother Murder, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0716,0460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second-Degree Murder Verdict Set Aside in `Baby Blues' Case</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to CORRECT that judge did issue finding of
not guilty by reason of insanity, adds detail on unusual nature of
ruling, judge's comment after hearing. Picks up 5th graf pvs, `Mrs.
Massip...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The second-degree murder conviction of a woman who claimed the `` baby blues'' caused her to run over her infant son with a car was set aside Friday by a judge who found the woman innocent by reason of insanity. <PERSON> Sheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Massip </PERSON>, 24, who testified that post-partum depression drove her to kill the colicky, constantly crying boy, was not guilty of murder, said <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>. `` I do not believe the prosecution's evidence established that she had the requisite mental state of malice aforethought,'' the judge said. He said while he knew his ruling was unusual, he felt he had no choice. Unless overturned on appeal by the prosecution, the judge's ruling invalidates a Nov. 17 jury verdict of second-degree murder, which called for a sentence of 15 years to life <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> delivered what he referred to as an `` unprecedented'' decision: first reducing the charge against her from second-degree murder to voluntary manslaughter, then ruling that she was not guilty by reason of insanity. The decision, however, still leaves the defendant eligible for commitment to a mental hospital for up to 11 years. `` This is new ground that we plowed today,'' the judge said in an interview with the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times after issuing his ruling. `` I do n't know of another court that came to a decision like the one I ded to set aside the jury verdict altogether. `` I know people will say I've overstepped my bounds. But the more I thought about it, the more I realized I did n't have any choice but to find her insane. ... She was bonkers.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Massip </PERSON> welcomed the verdict. `` I was praying the people would understand,'' she said outside court. `` The jury did not understand, but I'm thankful that the judge did.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Massip </PERSON> testified at the trial that on April 29, 1987, her own 23rd birthday, she hit her 6-week-old son, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, on the head with a garden tool, then put him under the wheels of the family station wagon, ran over him and put his body in a trash can. Defense witnesses said an exceptionally bad case of post-partum depression, a hormonal ailment known as the `` baby blues,'' was to blame. Defense attorney <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Grimes </PERSON> said the young mother was wracked by lack of sleep and hallucinations and that she heard voices telling her to put the boy out of his misery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Honduras-Nicaragua     12-24 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Honduras-Nicaragua,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honduras Threatens To Take Nicaragua Before Int'l Court of Justice</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Central America, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoya </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> may file a countersuit against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> before the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. His accusation that <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Sandinista army has intruded into <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> territory, killing soldiers and civilians, came after the court announced Tuesday it will rule on a complaint filed by <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> against <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> on July 28, 1986. <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> said his country is ready to defend itself against <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s accusation that <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has aided the U.S.-backed troops, known as the Contras, by allowing them to use Honduran territory as a staging ground for a war against the Sandinista government. <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> told reporters the decision by the court in The Hague did not surprise him. But, he added, `` We have enough proof that the Sandinista army has entered Honduran territory. ... We have documented proof of numerous armed attacks and that have resulted in the death of Honduran soldiers and civilians.'' <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoya </PERSON> said the Contras have taken refuge in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> because they were driven there by the Sandinista army. He said they are not fighting in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> now. <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> said he considered the Contras to be political refugees and predicted <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid for them would be renewed in 1989, after <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is inaugurated president.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CajunChristmas Bjt   12-24 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cajun Christmas, Bjt,0578</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heaux, Heaux Heaux: Levee Bonfires Lead Papa Noel to Cajun
Christmas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Down here, where folks wish you a `` Joyeux Noel'' instead of `` Merry Christmas,'' <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>'s sleigh gives way to <PERSON> Papa </PERSON> <PERSON> Noel </PERSON>'s Cajun canoe and people build bonfires to light his way on Christmas Eve. `` I do n't know how that sleigh would run down here. If it needs snow he'd be in trouble. I guess that's why he comes down the river in a pirogue'' _ a flat-bottomed canoe, said <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON>, the police and fire chief of <LOCATION> Gramercy </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gramercy </PERSON> has a population of 3,600, except for Christmas Eve when upwards of 40,000 people crowd into town for the lighting of the bonfires along the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> levee, <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> said. For 260-plus years the bonfires have blazed to guide <PERSON> Papa </PERSON> <PERSON> Noel </PERSON> down the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> to the small south <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> communities about 30 miles north of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. `` The bonfires are an old tradition passed on from my grandfather and his grandfather and all the other grandfathers, I guess,'' said the 65-year-old <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON>, who has been in charge of building the bonfires for 50 years. People began building the structures they'll torch on Christmas Eve almost a month in advance. `` They used to be just simple teepees but about eight years ago people started getting real imaginative in what they made. Now it's amazing to see what they come up with,'' <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> said About 100 bonfires a year in the shape of riverboats, plantation homes, cabins and Viking ships spring up on the river banks along a three-mile stretch. In fact, the builders' imaginations soared to such heights that size restrictions were imposed. Bonfires can be no larger than 12-feet wide and no taller than 25 feet. `` Those are about the only restrictions,'' <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> said. The crowds attracted by the celebration bring traffic that backs up for miles along State 44, but <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> said he does n't consider it a problem. `` It may be a problem for the folks in the cars, but not for us. They can only go about three or four miles an hour so it's not dangerous and they can watch the bonfires just fine,'' he reasoned. Not everyone will be stacked up in traffic. At least six river boats will carry thousands of people upriver from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> to watch. `` This is the second year we've done it, and we sold out before we even advertised or planned it this year. We added a third boat, the River Rose, and still have better than 200 people on a waiting list,'' said <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Viator </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orleans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paddlewheels </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. For between $ 35 and $ 55, those on the various ships get dinner, champagne, jazz and about an eight-hour trip, cruise officials said <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> and his 12-man crew worked almost three weeks to build a 38-foot-long pyre that looks like a shrimp boat. They cut willow trees, which he said burn best and make a `` beautiful fire,'' and carefully assembled them. <PERSON> Oubre </PERSON> said watching his creations go up in smoke each year is n't sad in spite of the work and time that go into them `` No, that's why you build them,'' he said. `` You've got it in mind all the time to see them burn so you look forward to that part most of all.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StolenChristmas     12-24 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stolen Christmas,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presents Stolen by Children Turn up Under Neighbors' Tree</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DEFUNIAK SPRINGS, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several children broke into a neighbor's house in this <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> town, stole presents from underneath a Christmas tree and placed them under their own tree, authorities said. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dixie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumpert </PERSON> returned from a shopping trip Wednesday evening to find a window broken, their Christmas tree toppled and three presents missing, police said. A broken cane fishing pole and a brick were on the floor near the tree. Deputies say they believe the brick was thrown through the window and the fishing pole was used to reach inside to pull the gifts within grabbing range. <LOCATION> Walton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's deputies said they followed three sets of child-size footprints to a mobile home across the street and confronted the mother of two of the children. `` The deputies knocked on the door and she was kind of surprised when she saw the presents under the tree,'' <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumpert </PERSON> said Thursday. When the children could n't explain to deputies or their mother where the presents came from they admitted they had taken them from the Shumperts' home, rewrapped them and put them under their own tree, said sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutton </PERSON>. Also, he said, two bathroom rugs missing from the neighbors' back porch were wrapped as a Christmas gift. The culprits were two boys, ages 9 and 11, and a 12-year-old girl, <PERSON> Sutton </PERSON> said. The two older children were charged with burglary, petty theft and criminal mischief and then released to their parents pending an appearance before a juvenile judge. No charges were filed against the youngest child. The Shumperts said the stolen gifts were intended for their daughter and two grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Canada-USTrade     12-24 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Canada-US Trade,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>House Of Commons Gives Canada-U.S. Trade Agreement Final Approval</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OTTAWA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Canada-U.S. free trade agreement won final approval early Saturday by a vote of 141-111 in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. It was the final reading for the trade agreement's enabling legislation, and the new pact is scheduled to take effect New Year's Day after approval by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which is to complete its work next week, has promised not to oppose the trade legislation. Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Progessive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> won a second consecutive majority government in Nov. 21 elections, signed the trade agreement with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in January. The opposition had bitterly opposed the pact, claiming it would cost Canadians jobs. The agreement is to phase out all remaining tariffs between the two neighbors over a 10-year period. A smiling <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said early Saturday that the deal will bring economic prosperity. `` People will look back on this and say it was a good day for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Homeless-Cash     12-24 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Homeless-Cash,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dead Homeless Man Carried $5,200 In Cash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 63-year-old homeless man was found dead on a city sidewalk with $ 5,200 in cash on him, police said. The victim was identified Thursday as <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, based on fingerprints taken when he was arrested for vagrancy in 1949, said homicide Detective <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Marraway </PERSON>. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> had no known address in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> was found Monday in a cubbyhole outside a boiler plant in a housing complex. He was covered by several blankets, and his feet were bare. Police originally suspected <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> froze to death, but an autopsy showed he died of natural causes, said <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy Coroner <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Coles </PERSON>. Officers searched <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> on the sidewalk and said they found a wad of bills worth $ 1,250 in his pocket. The coroner's staff later found a packet containing $ 4,000 strapped to his thigh. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> apparently saved the money from his wages as a laborer unloading food trucks in the city's produce section, known as the Strip District. The coroner's office is trying to locate <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' relatives, who would inherit the money, <PERSON> Coles </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-CentralAmerica 1stLd-Writethru   12-24 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Central America, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0436,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaragua-Honduras Bickering Puts Peace Talks In Jeopardy</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: SUBS 3rd graf, `Honduran Foreign...' to restore dropped word
in quote. Inserts 2 grafs after 18th, `In both...' to add rebel
attack. Pickup 19th pvs, `The regional...</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bickering between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> is threatening a summit planned for next month by Central American leaders anxious to end the civil wars and hostilities in the region. The latest stumbling block comes from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> agreed this week to hear <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s claims that <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has been harboring and supporting U.S.-backed rebels, known as Contras, who are fighting <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government. Honduran Foreign Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> said Wednesday the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision threatens the future of negotiated settlements to the region's problems. He said the court's move is politically charged and sets `` a judicial precedent totally incompatible with peace negotiations.'' In addition, President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has threatened to boycott regional peace talks unless <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> drops its World Court case. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> met earlier this month in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. There they agreed that heads of state would convene in January in an effort to breathe new life into the stalled August 1987 peace plan. The plan sets three-month deadlines for cease-fires in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. It also mandates that governments of all five nations enact political amnesties and democratic freedoms and reconcile with political opposition groups. It calls for an end to outside aid for rebel insurgencies and a ban on the use of one country's territory to destabilize another. The peace proposal was written by President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, who was awarded the 1987 Nobel Peace Prize for his effort. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> says anti-government Nicaraguan rebels and refugees camp exist on Honduran territory because of a lack of democratic freedoms in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. `` For reasons of national security, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> does n't want the Contras,'' <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said. `` Nor do we desire the presence of more than 60,000 refugees from <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.'' However, <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> can not eject the Contras because, `` We would be accused of being responsible for massacres and violating human rights.'' <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> denounced what he called the Sandinista practice of using international organizations to pressure other nations. But <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> hailed the court's decision, and Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> should accept it. The same court ruled in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s favor in 1986 in a suit against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support of the Contras. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has refused to recognize the court's jurisdiction in the area. As the main judicial organ of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, the court has no enforcement powers. The <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> plan sought to end the Honduran problem as well as long wars in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. But the heady days following the 1987 signing later turned to disappointment and frustration. The four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> _ blame <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and its largest backer, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, for the persistent turmoil. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> says the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is trying to militarize the region and find a pretext to invade <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. In both <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, talks between leftist guerrillas and the two U.S.-backed governments have fallen apart. Wars rage on with no end in sight. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> on Friday, leftist rebels attacked the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> with car bombs and explosives, killing at least three people and wounding at least 35, officials said. The assault on the military headquarters compound and on a nearby government health clinic appeared to be part of a major rebel offensive. The regional talks did lead to a cease-fire agreement in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> last March that sharply curtailed fighting there. A month earlier, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government cut off military aid to the Contras. About 10,000 Contra fighters have now moved back to base camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. The presidents last met in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> on Jan. 15, the date set by the <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> plan to mark the end of the wars and full democracy. Instead, they signed a statement vowing to continue their efforts. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, whose government is fighting growing rebel activity, said further meetings would be useless unless concrete progress could be made.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerExplosion 3rdLd-Writethru a0440 12-24 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Explosion, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0440,0749</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tanker Explodes Into Huge Fireball, Kills Seven</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with complete death toll now at
eight, including traffic death; picks up 7th graf, ``Authorities
issued ...;'' INSERTS 1 graf after penultimate graf, ``Authorities
tentatively ...,'' with detail.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos MX2,4; LaserGraphic NY38</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WOODY BAIRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10,000-gallon propane truck exploded Friday on a highway, killing seven people, sparking a huge fireball and sending the tanker crashing into a house 125 yards away, officials said. Six people were admitted to hospitals, including one who later died and another in critical condition, and five others were treated and released. A traffic jam caused by the crash led to an accident that claimed a eighth life. `` I heard the explosion and saw the tanker flying through the air. It fell on the house and just blew up,'' said <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, a witness. The wood-frame, duplex house was destroyed and a 10-year-old girl inside died, authorities said. An elderly woman also inside the house died later of her burns. The six other deaths, including the driver of the truck, and most of the injuries occurred mainly on Interstate 240 near downtown as the fireball engulfed the truck and several other vehicles, said fire Capt. <PERSON> Benny </PERSON> <PERSON> McDow </PERSON>. The people taken to hospitals suffered mostly from burns, <PERSON> McDow </PERSON> said. One was listed in critical condition early Saturday in the burn unit of the <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and four other people were also hospitalized. O Authorities issued tentative identifications, but said dental records would have to be used for positive identification, because some of the bodies were so badly burned. The propane truck apparently skidded off an exit ramp on Interstate 240 as the driver tried to turn onto Interstate 40 toward <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McDow </PERSON> said. The roadway was dry. `` He was trying to exit and lost control and hit a retaining wall,'' <PERSON> McDow </PERSON> said. `` That exit there is short. It's one of those tight turns.'' <PERSON> Jed </PERSON> <PERSON> Tennison </PERSON>, who works at a sheet metal plant near the crash scene, said he rushed to a highway overpass when he heard the explosion. `` There was a guy on fire rolling on the road and there was another just lying on the ground where somebody must have put him,'' <PERSON> Tennison </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gaines </PERSON> <PERSON> Tennison </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jed </PERSON>'s father and manager of the sheet metal plant, said he felt the shock of the blast and looked out to see what had happened. `` I thought it was an earthquake,'' he said. `` The whole sky was white, just lit up. You could feel the heat inside the building.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a deputy chief in charge of fire department crews on the scene, said victims killed by the blast had little chance to escape the flames. `` There was a huge fireball, maybe 700 to 800 feet. It engulfed three or four cars,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. In addition to the destroyed duplex, the fireball damaged five houses, three on one side and two on the other side of the six-lane highway, authorities said. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Edgeston </PERSON>, who lives two doors away from the destroyed duplex, said a truck axle with four wheels attached ended up in his kitchen. He suffered a cut on the head but was not seriously hurt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stonecipher </PERSON>, a city fire marshal, said the tanker ruptured on one end and blasted off like a rocket when the fuel ignited. `` It was like an unguided missile,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> planned to send a team of investigators, said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Authorities tentatively identified the victims as <PERSON> Shelanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Towles </PERSON>, 10, killed in her house; <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>, 29, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, the propane tanker driver; and four people who were in vehicles near the exploding truck: <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, 34, <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wardlow </PERSON>, 40, <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiles </PERSON>, 30, and her father-in-law, <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiles </PERSON>, 70, both of <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION>, Miss. The elderly woman who was inside the duplex with <PERSON> Shelanda </PERSON> was not identified because her family had not been notified, said police traffic Lt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Krepela </PERSON>. After the accident, traffic backed up for several miles north and south of town. A second truck driver was killed when his 18-wheeler plowed into the rear of a car tied up in the traffic jam, police said. That driver was identified as <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>, Ark.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DesperateAddict Bjt   12-24 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Desperate Addict, Bjt,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Addict Won't Be Home for Christmas _ And He's Glad</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ALAN HARPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A crack addict desperate for treatment brought police his paraphernalia, then smashed windows at two precincts before a judge relented and sentenced him to a drug program he calls his `` best Christmas gift yet.'' `` I will thank him for giving me an opportunity for starting my life back over. He is an understanding man, one of very few,'' <PERSON> Alexis </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> said Friday of <ORGANIZATION> Bronx </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, 34, said his life had bordered on the insane until <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> sentenced him to 90 days in a drug treatment program. As a crack cocaine addict, <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> lost his job as a construction worker. He stopped paying bills. He became irresponsible and dirty. His wife of two years, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Coulter </PERSON>, feared for their 11-month-old son and her two daughters, now 12 and 13. Last July, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Coulter </PERSON> threw him out of their home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s tough <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> section `` because I was doing wrong,'' he said. `` She is a Christian and I did n't want to be around her.'' `` It's bad to see a good husband turn into a monster. I've known him nine years and I had never seen that side of him,'' Miss <PERSON> Coulter </PERSON> said. `` I was praying he would get into a program before it was too late. He was getting out of hand.'' <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> knew he was getting out of hand, so he turned for help. He applied for admission at several <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> hospital programs and one in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. `` They all told me they were filled up. Until February or the end of January. That was too far for me to look forward to,'' <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> said. On Oct. 28, he sought help from the desk sergeant at the 47th Precinct. That did not work, so <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> tried something else: He placed a syringe and some crack vials on the sergeant's desk. `` I did n't know what else to do,'' <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> said. `` They roughed me up. They were very shocked that I did this. They did n't understand.'' And neither did the judge who handled the case, releasing him two days later without sending him to treatment. On Nov. 5, <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> tossed a chair through the window of the 48th Precinct. Another judge put him in the streets without treatment. On Nov. 14, he threw a padlock through a window of the 46th Precinct. He was processed by a third judge who did not offer treatment. `` I told them I needed help,'' <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> said. All the pending cases of drug charges and criminal mischief came together Dec. 1 before <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, who decided to do something. `` I got a call from the judge on Tuesday the 20th. From the judge himself,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sierra </PERSON>, a worker at and graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Out </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> `` It was strange. To me, a judge has a lot to do. He went out of his way to help this particular person. The probation report was not favorable.'' <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> said the program, which is funded by donations and other churches, has 58 beds and 600 people on the waiting list. One bed was available and <PERSON> Vega </PERSON> got it. <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, who had previously written to the program, was given a 90-day sentence Wednesday to Way Out. `` He's got a long way to go here,'' <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> said. `` It is a strain on his life. We are a very strict program.'' `` Strict'' means no leaving the program for two months, no visitors, no cursing, no smoking and plenty of prayer. The <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Attorney </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>, commended the judge and said `` this case dramatizes the critical need for treatment upon demand for all individuals addicted to drugs.'' No one knows it better than <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, who said, `` I think -LRB- the judge -RRB- gave me the best Christmas gift yet, to redeem my life back over.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881224-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-24-88 0405EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Soviet-Quake Bjt   12-24 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Quake, Bjt,0644</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crews End Search For Survivors, Focus On Cleanup</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LENINAKAN, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
