<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 2329EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0716 12-09 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0716,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heavy Snow In The Central Appalachians</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with Tennessee plane crash,
traffic deaths in Virginia; picks up 4th graf pvs: ``There's just .
..</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavy snow fell on the central Appalachians during the morning Friday, and high wind blowing out of the desert over southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> fanned brush fires that destroyed homes. Up to 10 inches of snow fell in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, over the Mountain State's southern mountains and over the coal fields near the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> border. Up to 10 inches also fell across the mountains of southwestern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, a twin-engine airplane carrying 40 pounds of cocaine and $ 7,000 cash crashed into a snowy field outside <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, killing its pilot and its sole passenger. Police said the cocaine was valued at $ 450,000. Authorities said heavy wet snow was falling and the ceiling was down to 400 feet at the time of the crash that killed pilot <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chestnut </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Trotwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Jeffery </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hicks </PERSON>, 23, of <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, officials said. The plane was en route from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, with a fuel stop in <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> when it apparently lost an engine, said <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. At least three traffic deaths in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> were blamed on slippery roads. Numerous schools were closed in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and power was out to thousands of customers in the state's <LOCATION> Pulaski </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Radford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> counties. `` There's just no way we can count the number of accidents without polling each trooper and seeing how many he investigated,'' said <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> state police Sgt. G.A. <PERSON> Farthing </PERSON>. `` I'd be hesitant to even give a number.'' <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Shenandoah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the Skyline Drive near <LOCATION> Winchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, was closed because of heavy snowfall, and some visitors were stranded at visitor centers along the drive. Advisories warned of a chance of snow elsewhere in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, eastern <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s Eastern Panhandle. Squalls produced locally heavy snow around the lower <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> and heavy snow warnings were issued for northeastern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and for the eastern <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> counties of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state. Light snow fell around the southern shore of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and over <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. A storm slowly tracking across northern <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> threatened to produce heavy snow over parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. A winter storm watch was posted into Saturday for the state's central highlands, south-central mountains, and east-central and southeastern plains. A snow advisory was issued for parts of western <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Strong, gusty <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> wind continued to blow across southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for a third day with gusts to 60 mph reported at <LOCATION> Rialto </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peak </LOCATION>. More than 20 homes were damaged, some of them destroyed, northwest of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and thousands of people were evacuated. Elsewhere, showers were scattered from northern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> across the <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> coast, with light rain and drizzle over the northern <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>. Afternoon temperatures remained below freezing from northeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> through the Great Lakes region and much of the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to the northern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Temperatures around the nation at 2 p.m. EST ranged from zero degrees at International Falls, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, to 83 at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Friday morning's official low was 22 degrees below zero at <LOCATION> Hibbing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>. For Saturday, snow was forecast from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region and the northern half of the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> Rain was forecast from southeastern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> through the <LOCATION> southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to southern <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and northern and central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Snow also was forecast over parts of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and northwestern <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Scattered showers were forecast from the coast of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and western <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, with snow at higher elevations. Highs only in the teens or single digits were predicted from the Dakotas through the Great Lakes to northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>; in the 20s in the rest of the region from eastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> through the upper half of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to the northern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>; above 50 from coastal <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> to the southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and from the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast to southern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>; above 60 from the central coast of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to southwestern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>; in the 60s and 70s across the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>; and in the 70s in southwestern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Israel-Politics     12-09 0410</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Politics,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>Labor Party Votes to Reopen Talks with Likud Bloc</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMAT GAN, Israel (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> voted by an overwhelming majority Thursday to re-enter negotiations with the hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc on forming a joint national unity government. The decision was a reversal of the party's 110-member Executive Bureau, which last week voted against further talks. It also was seen as a boost to the leadership of Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, who pushed hard for a vote in favor of new negotiations. `` If this were not the vote, people would say it was a personal defeat, so I suppose it's a personal triumph,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told reporters after the results were announced. The vote of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> was 637 to 348. Just under 1,000 of the committee's more than 1,300 members attended the session in this <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> suburb. Both <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> and the party's No. 2 man, Defense Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON>, made emotional pleas in favor of reopening talks with <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. They pledged, however, that they would agree to join a coalition government only if it would advance the peace process and was committed to reforming the electoral system. `` For 11 years the <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> has been in power,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> told the committee. `` Almost all that is dear to us has been affected. What should we do? Be proud and go home, or try to find a solution and change the system?'' He added, virtually screaming into the microphone: `` I did not come to arrange negotiations, but to examine our souls.'' Likud first came to power in 1977, and <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> and Labor have governed <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in an uneasy coalition since inconclusive elections in 1984. Israeli elections Nov. 1 again ended indecisively, with <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> winning 40 seats to <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s 39. The remaining 41 seats were divided among smaller parties. Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> has been asked to form a new government and needs the support of Labor or several of the smaller parties to achieve a majority in the 120-seat parliament, or Knesset. Intense bargaining has been going on since the election. On Thursday, talks were held between <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> leaders and the <ORGANIZATION> Tehiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, a nationalist party with three seats in the new parliament, and a tentative agreement was signed that would give a <ORGANIZATION> Tehiya </ORGANIZATION> member the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> portfolio, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television reported. <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> officials also met with three other small parties, but no agreements were reached, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RideauClemency     12-09 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rideau Clemency,0376</SECOND>
<HEAD>Convicted Killer At A Loss Over Governor's Decision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANGOLA, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite the urging of parole officials, Governor <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> has refused to grant clemency to <PERSON> Wilbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON>, a convicted murderer who became a nationally recognized prison editor. `` I wish somebody would tell me what to do, and I'd do it,'' <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Thursday, a day after <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> rejected the state <ORGANIZATION> Pardon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>'s recommendation for a reduction of sentence. <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON>, 47, is serving life in the state prison for a 1961 <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> bank robbery during which he kidnapped three employees, shot and wounded two of them and killed the third by cutting her throat. <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> was arrested shortly afterwards and confessed in front of television cameras. He spent 10 years on death row until the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> struck down the state's capital punishment law in 1972. The board's second recommendation of reduced sentence would have made <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> eligible for parole. In rejecting it, <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> cited the strenuous objections of <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON>'s prosecutors and victims. <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON>, who has won numerous national prizes as editor of the prison news magazine The Angolite, said he thinks he was turned down because his success with the magazine has kept him in the limelight. `` We've got a system that encourages anonymity. It encourages prisoners to do nothing, not to distinguish themselves,'' he said. `` If you want to get out of prison, you're supposed to keep your mouth shut and let everybody forget about you,'' he said. <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> said he is not sure what to do next. Since the pardon board agreed with him, it would add nothing to get another hearing. <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> said he can only hope that <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> will change his mind. `` I would love to meet the man,'' <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> said. `` I wish I could sit down with him. Anything he wants to know, let me present my side.'' Although serving life, <PERSON> Rideau </PERSON> is frequently on the road, traveling under guard to lecture at state universities, appear on national television shows and cover state board meetings for the magazine. He and other editors have been singled out for national recognition by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, private foundations and other organizations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DogRescue     12-09 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dog Rescue,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Groomer Saves Dog's Life with CPR</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ACUSHNET, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pet shop owner <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> says she does n't mind kissing dogs, but she'd rather not perform mouth-to-mouth resuscitation again. `` All I thought about was what do I do with the tongue,'' <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> said Tuesday after reviving a greyhound with cardiopulmonary resuscitation. <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON>, who runs a pet grooming store, said she had just finished bathing and clipping the toenails of Escape, a 13-year-old retired racer, when the dog collapsed Saturday. She heard a thud and turned to find the dog sprawled out on a pet table, tongue hanging out and eyes rolled back. When she could find no pulse, <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> said she assumed the dog had had a heart attack and began CPR _ a procedure designed to restore normal breathing and heartbeat. <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> pressed on the dog's chest and cupped her hands over the dog's mouth to breath air into its lungs. `` After a few minutes, I heard a cough and then a gurgle. I continued working on her until she could breathe on her own,'' said <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON>, `` Now it seems funny, doing mouth-to-mouth with a dog. At the time, though, I was only thinking about how to keep the dog alive,'' she said. <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> said she took a CPR course after a friend developed heart problems, and it was the first time she put her training to use. The dog, owned by <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Acushnet </LOCATION>, is recovering at home and is being treated with nitroglycerin, <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON> said. Tests showed Escape's heart suffered some damage, she said. Escape's veterinarian, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fairhaven </LOCATION>, said it is difficult to say whether Ms. <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON>' actions saved the dog's life or whether the heart resumed beating on its own. <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> called Ms. <PERSON> Lopes </PERSON>' response admirable but cautioned against untrained people performing CPR on animals. He said the best thing to do is call an animal hospital.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Lewis     12-09 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Lewis,0445</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jerry Lee Lewis Has Little Left, Lawyer Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock' n' roller <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, facing a $ 2 million tax debt and other bills, has few personal possessions he could use to pay off creditors, a bankruptcy lawyer says. `` There's not much left,'' <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagemeyer </PERSON>, an attorney representing <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> in federal <ORGANIZATION> Bankruptcy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> here, said Thursday. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, 53, filed for bankruptcy Nov. 8, citing debts of more than $ 3 million and income of about $ 5,000 a month, <ORGANIZATION> Hagemeyer </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has been squabbling with <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> since 1975, and tax agents have seized cars, furniture and other property from him several times over the years. `` There have been at least two sales by the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> that I know of,'' <ORGANIZATION> Hagemeyer </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>' bankruptcy petition lists a residence valued at $ 30,000 near <LOCATION> Nesbit </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, and other personal property worth about $ 6,000. In a hearing Wednesday, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said the income from an upcoming movie based on his life would fall well short of his debts. Responding to inquiries from bankruptcy trustee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said a contract he signed eight years ago puts his income from the movie at $ 200,000 to $ 250,000. <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON> asked if <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> expected to perform any consulting work or other moneymaking activities for the producers of `` Great Balls of Fire'' starring <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Quaid </PERSON>. `` No sir,'' <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. `` I've suggested some things. We do n't see eye to eye on some things They're pretty well set on what they want to do.'' The movie about <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>' tumultuous personal life and the early years of his rock' n' roll career is being shot in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>. In is petition, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> listed 22 creditors, but his major debts are to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> concert promoter who sued in 1978 after the rocker failed to show up for a scheduled performance, <ORGANIZATION> Hagemeyer </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> failed to show up to oppose the lawsuit and a judgment was filed against him for more than $ 450,000. With interest, he now owes about $ 950,000, the attorney said. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> went to trial on tax evasion charges in 1984, but was acquitted of charges he intentionally hid money from the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. At the time, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> said he owed the government more than $ 650,000. The singer's income comes primarily from performances, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingham </PERSON>, an attorney representing <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> on matters other than the bankruptcy petition. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, who recorded such early rock' n' roll classics as `` Whole <PERSON> Lotta </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakin </PERSON>' Going On'' and `` Great Balls of Fire,'' told the bankruptcy trustee he has not received any record royalties in the last few years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastGermanCensorship     12-09 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East German Censorship,0715</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Germany Launches Censorship Drive Against Soviet Reforms</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GIRARD C. STEICHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, once the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s staunchest ideological ally, has embarked on an unprecedented campaign of censorship aimed at bridling the spread of the Kremlin's new reform policies. The seriousness of the campaign became clear Nov. 20 when <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Communist government slapped a first-ever, open-ended ban on a Soviet publication, a magazine called Sputnik. The campaign has pitted <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s aging and conservative leaders in the most dramatic form yet against reformers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, whose re-examinations of Soviet history have led to a public debate on a scale unheard of in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. East German leaders have long resisted President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of glasnost, or openness, and other reforms, on grounds that such critical discussions of problems in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> are unnecessary. Recent speeches by <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders have reiterated the government's rejection of the Soviet reforms course. However, the recent actions have signaled the boldest moves yet by the government to distance itself from the debate in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and to insulate the nation's population from the popular changes. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policies enjoy enormous support among East Germans who hope his influence will bring about change in one of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s most tightly controlled societies. East German party leaders have occasionally blocked the distribution of newspapers from <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact neighbors in the past _ during the 1968 <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and the early periods of labor unrest in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Selected issues of Soviet magazines have also been blocked. But until the decision on the monthly magazine Sputnik, no outright ban had ever been imposed on a Soviet magazine. The decision was followed quickly with an order removing five Soviet films dealing with Stalinist themes from theaters across the country. Authorities also canceled an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> cabaret production that poked fun at the government's reluctance to accept <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform policies The banning of Sputnik followed its publication of articles critical of the late <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s communists before <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> took power in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1933. <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, who died in 1953, holds a special place in official <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> as a liberator in World War II and as the Soviet leader who helped found the new communist nation in 1949. East German leaders were outraged over an article in Sputnik's October issue that suggested that <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> `` had been a mere puppet of <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'' after the two nation's signed a mutual non-aggression pact in 1939 and that <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s communists had indirectly aided <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s rise to power by not `` joining together with Social Democrats'' to stop The Sputnik article also charged that German communists followed `` Stalin's order to stop all anti-fascist propaganda'' after the pact was signed. <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> invaded the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1941. Distribution of the October Sputnik was ordered halted shortly after it appeared in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` These -LRB- historical -RRB- issues go to the very root of their -LRB- communist East German leaders' -RRB- existence,'' said <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heym </PERSON>, a prominent East German author, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` These -LRB- articles -RRB- upset the picture of the world they want to depict.' <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, the East German leader, along with a substantial number of the nation's ruling Politburo members were members of the prewar German <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and pride themselves on having fought fascism. <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> was imprisoned by the Nazis and thousands of communists were slain. Shortcomings of the movement or of party leaders at the time have not been a matter for debate in the East German media. In an article defending the Sputnik ban, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> organ Neues Deutschland charged that the publication `` not only distorts Soviet history, but the history of the German <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` The magazine, and we say this openly, defames German communists.'' While carefully emphazing that Sputnik was `` not an official organ'' of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Neues </PERSON> <PERSON> Deutchland </PERSON> added that `` distorted visions of Soviet history, distributed here, are incompatible with our friendship with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.'' Soviet officials defended the magazine, saying it `` mirrors a plurality of opinion in the Soviet press.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Stats     12-09 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Stats,0243</SECOND>
<HEAD>CDC Statistics On U.S. AIDS Cases</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest statistics on acquired immune deficiency syndrome in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as reported this week by the national Centers for Disease Control:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Number of Cases</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Total cases reported since June 1981: 79,823. Cases, year to date: 29,390. Total deaths: 44,826, or 56 percent of all cases.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Transmission Categories</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Homosexual or bisexual males: 48,625, or 61 percent. Intravenous drug abusers: 15,533, or 19 percent. Homosexual male and drug abusers: 5,662, or 7 percent. Heterosexual cases: 3,442, or 4 percent. Transfusion or blood cases: 2,144, or 3 percent. Hemophilia patients: 837, or 1 percent. Children of parents with AIDS or at risk: 991, or 1 percent. Undetermined transmission cause: 2,589, or 3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Age and Race</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Childhood cases -LRB- under age 13 -RRB-: 1,278, or 2 percent. Cases among whites: 45,972, or 58 percent. Cases among blacks: 21,151, or 26 percent. Cases among Hispanics: 11,962, or 15 percent. Cases among Asians or Pacific Islanders: 478, or 1 percent. Cases among American Indians or Alaskan natives: 85, or 0 percent. -LRB- NOTE: These statistics are through Dec. 8 and have been rounded to the nearest whole percent. Cumulative totals are for AIDS cases reported since June 1981, and include 75 cases subsequently found to have occurred prior to that date. -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChinookCrashes     12-09 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chinook Crashes,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinook Accidents in Recent Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Honduras-US Crash, Bjt</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of some accidents in recent years involving the twin-rotor <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> CH-47 Chinook helicopter. _ Feb. 25, 1988, an Army CH-47D crashed in a cow pasture near <LOCATION> Chico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, killing 10 soldiers and seriously burning eight. _ Nov. 20, 1987, an Army CH-47 crashed and burned in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, injuring two soldiers. _ May 15, 1987, an Army CH-47 caught fire and made a forced landing in dense woods near <LOCATION> Monticello </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, killing one soldier and injuring three. _ Feb. 27, 1987, a <ORGANIZATION> Chinook </ORGANIZATION> helicopter belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> crashed near <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stanley </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, killing all seven aboard. _ Nov. 6, 1986, a Chinook 234, a civilian version of the helicopter, crashed in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, killing 45 people. The company that operated the helicopter said gearbox fatigue probably caused the crash. _ May 13, 1986, a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chinook </ORGANIZATION> crashed into a mountain on <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falkland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, killing three crewmen. Officials said visibility was poor at the time. _ April 9, 1986, an Army CH-47D collided with an AH-1S Cobra helicopter over <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stewart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, killing eight soldiers. _ July 11, 1985, a CH-47D being tested before delivery to the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> crashed in a marshy area in southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, killing two crew members. _ April 21, 1985, a CH-47D taxiing on the ground in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> was destroyed when one rotor stopped turning and was struck by the other. Eight soldiers were injured, and the Army grounded its fleet of Chinooks for a month and a half to replace rotor transmission bearings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PolisarioFront     12-09 0274</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Polisario Front,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marxist Guerrillas Fighting For Western Sahara</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Plane Downed, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RABAT, Morocco (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Marxist guerrillas called the <ORGANIZATION> Polisario </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> have been fighting for 13 years for independence of the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>, near where two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> AID planes came under missile attack on Thursday. <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> occupied most of the former <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION> in 1976 after claiming it as Moroccan since early in the century. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> immediately recognized the <ORGANIZATION> Polisario </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s struggle for independence, and about 70 nations, mostly members of the non-aligned group, followed suit. <LOCATION> Mauritania </LOCATION> occupied the southernmost third of the territory in 1976 but gave up its claim to the area in 1979 and <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> annexed it. The Polisario, with extensive help from <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, waged an aggressive guerrilla war. With a heavily armed guerrilla force of 20,000 men, Polisario almost captured the Mauritanian capital, <LOCATION> Nouakchott </LOCATION>, in 1976, disrupted phosphate mining at the Sahara mining center of <PERSON> Bou </PERSON> <PERSON> Craa </PERSON> and attacked shipping off the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coast with heavily armed rubber boats. <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> deployed virtually its entire 120,000-member army and guerrilla activity nearly came to a halt. But the operation was expensive in money and lives, and by 1986 <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> had lost about 15,000 men _ matched by losses on the Polisario side. This year <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Polisario </ORGANIZATION>'s main foreign backers _ decided it had more to gain by reaching a direct understanding with <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>, and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has been mediating peace talks between <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> and the guerrillas. Under a tentative agreement, about 2,000 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers would monitor a referendum that would result in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sahara </LOCATION>'s independence or affiliation with <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HolidayGrieving     12-09 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Holiday Grieving,0617</SECOND>
<HEAD>Holidays Are Tough Times To Deal With Loss Of Child</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED WHITE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Holiday chimes may sound a somber note for families grieving over the loss of a child, but a psychiatrist suggests survivors start new traditions in memory of the departed. `` Families in mourning have to be told it is all right to have fun,'' says <PERSON> Abby </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON>, writing in the December issue of American Journal of Diseases of Children. `` Laughter is the best medicine for helping the bereaved cope with their loss. Having a good time does not mean that the parents loved their child any less,'' she said. `` In fact, they may be showing more love because by enjoying themselves, they are bringing their family closer together.'' In getting through the holidays, families must decide what is comfortable, Ms. <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> said. `` Changes can make things less painful,'' she said. `` A different tree with different decorations. Opening the presents at a different time. A different menu for dinner.'' Some families put a small Christmas tree on the child's grave, Ms. <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> said. Others light a candle or order special plants or flowers. Accompanying her article are some `` do's'' and `` do n't's'' for those spending time with bereaved parents during the holidays. Do: _ Talk about special qualities of the child they have lost. _ Allow them to express as much grief as they are feeling. _ Reassure them that they did everything they could. _ Pay attention to surviving siblings. But do n't: _ Say you know how they feel unless you have lost a child. _ Say the parents should be over the loss. _ Change the subject when they mention their dead child. _ Say they can always have other children. _ Point out that at least they have other children. Ms. <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON>, a child psychiatrist at <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, says religion can be a source of comfort, but she cautions that surviving children might misinterpret some explanations. In one case, she said, the behavior of a 4-year-old boy was poor after his brother's death. `` When asked about this behavior change for the worse, he replied that he was not going to be so good that <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> would want him. This child had been told that his brother was so wonderful that <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> wanted him to live with him in heaven,'' Ms. <PERSON> Wasserman </PERSON> said. The Compassionate Friends, an international organization dedicated to helping parents overcome the loss of a child, recently sent out holiday suggestions to its 600 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> chapters. `` Sometimes the toughest part of all is the anticipation,'' said <PERSON> Therese </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodrich </PERSON>, director of group's national office in suburban <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>. `` You turn on the television and people are telling you to get the shopping done. It's all around us,'' she said in a telephone interview Thursday. `` Some people like to buy a gift that their child would have liked, and then give it to the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> or a church group.'' Other suggestions include urging families to change their holiday routines, mention the loss of their children in Christmas cards and discuss them when they feel comfortable with the subject. Mrs. <PERSON> Goodrich </PERSON>, whose 14-year-old daughter was killed by a car in 1971, says the first holiday without a child is the hardest. `` When a child dies, our priorities get shook up. We want to show a little more love,'' she said. `` I think people just need to be gentle with themselves. That's the main thing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganRdp Bjt   12-09 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Rdp, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Mellow Reagan Finds No Reason to Mistrust Gorbachev</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphotos WX9,10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in a twilight assessment, says <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has never shown any reason to be mistrusted and in fact is steering the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> away from its old goal of `` a one-world communist state.'' In what was probably his final White House news conference, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said `` trust but verify'' remains his byword in dealing with the <LOCATION> Russians </LOCATION>, but he offered an optimstic assessment of how U.S.-Soviet relations stand at the end of his eight-year tenure in office. `` The path remains open and the pace of peace continues,'' he said. For half an hour, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> fielded questions Thursday night in an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Room </LOCATION> decorated with Christmas trees hung with silver tinsel. He said it was the Russians _ not he _ who have changed, but his old anti-communist fire was dampened. On a pressing domestic issue, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he would be `` deeply disappointed'' if President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, after assuming office next month, raised taxes to help cut the deficit, which grew to $ 155 billion this year. But he quickly added, `` I do n't think it's going to happen.'' The chief executive also told reporters the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ultimately will have to negotiate with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to win release of American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` We would be ready to talk with them,'' he said of the Iranians. In addition, he said <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> did not go far enough in saying his organization accepts the existence of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as a state and condemns terrorism in all forms. `` He has left openings for himself where he can deny that he meant this or meant that, that sounded so clean-cut,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. On a day after his fifth and final meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> opened the meeting with reporters by reading a warm statement on the state of superpower relations. Asked if he believed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was trying to make the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> a less threatening nation, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> replied without hesitation, `` Yes, I do. `` And I think he recognizes that their massive buildup has been responsible for the great economic crisis that he faces there in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Asked point-blank if he trusted <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` He has n't shown me any reason yet that I should n't.'' However, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the motto `` trust but verify'' is one that properly guides Soviet policy, too, and said he did not think <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> `` would gamble on believing that he should n't protect his own interests, also.'' Whether or not the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> ever become allies, as they were during World War II, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said it was entirely up to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>. It could happen, he said, `` if it can be definitely established that they no longer are following the expansionist policy that was instituted in the communist revolution that their goal must be a one-world communist state.'' The president said `` certainly there are indications'' the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> is moving that way. `` I do think that there is evidence that they do n't like being the pariah, that they might want to join the family of nations and join them with the idea of bringing about or establishing peace.'' He said he would like to see that happen. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> seemed cool to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s call for a ceasefire in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, followed by a <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nations-sponsored </LOCATION> peacekeeping force and broad-based government. `` I'm not sure the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> would like that or that the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> is prepared to do such a thing,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. Moreover, he said it would be unacceptable to stop arming the Afghan rebels unless the Soviet-backed regime ended military operations. The president said he was `` very grateful'' for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s announcement of a 500,000 cutback in Soviet troop strength but said <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> still would have superiority in conventional weapons <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also expressed confidence that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> believed as he does that Contra forces fighting the government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> are freedom fighters and worthy of continued <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support. On the subject of American hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ultimately would have to negotiate with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> because the Iranians control the kidnappers. Concerning that prospect, he said, `` There are conditions that have to be met also there. Anytime that they are ready to come forward on an open basis, we would be ready to talk to them.'' `` We can not enter into negotiating in the sense of what kind of ransom to pay or you're just encouraging more hostage-taking. But there are other channels,'' he said. Later, spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> elaborated: `` We'll be glad to talk, but we've never been able to get them to do that.'' Reflecting on the highs and lows of his presidency, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said his `` greatest burden'' was to have to order troops into `` danger ... to where their lives are threatened, to where their lives are taken.'' He later expanded that, noting the continued captivity of hostages in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. His greatest joy, he said without hesitation, was the economic recovery _ the longest ever during peacetime. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> refused to say the news conference was <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s last one, but <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said it was.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReaganonRussia Bjt   12-09 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan on Russia, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: He Denounced Them, Now Says `That Was Four
Leaders Back'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Taking office nearly eight years ago, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the leaders of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> themselves had said they would `` commit any crime'' to achieve world domination. Now he's inviting <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to come visit him in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> With <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> fresh from his fifth meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in less than four years, it was inevitable that a reporter at what may be his last <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news conference would remind him of what he said about the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> leadership at his first one. On Jan. 29, 1981, just nine days after he was inaugurated, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told reporters, `` I know of no leader of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since the revolution, and including the present leadership, that has not more than once repeated ... their determination that their goal must be the promotion of world revolution.'' Furthermore, he said, the Soviet leaders `` have openly and publicly declared that the only morality they recognize is what will further their cause, meaning they reserve unto themselves the right to commit any crime, to lie, to cheat, in order to attain that ... `` Thursday night, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s words were different. `` That was four leaders back before this one,'' he said. `` I think there have been some changes.'' Asked directly whether he trusted <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the president said, `` He has n't shown me any reason yet why I should n't.'' Quickly he added, as he so often does, that his motto is `` trust everybody, but cut the cards.'' His remarks were sprinkled, however, with complimentary references to the Soviet leader. At the end of his private meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> on Governors Island in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> on Wednesday, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> handed the Soviet leader a photograph with the inscription that they had `` walked a long way together to clear a path for peace.'' `` And so we have,'' he told the news conference. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never met as president with any of the three other Soviet leaders who held office and died during his administration _ <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>, <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON>. But he has met with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in 1985, in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, in 1986, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1987 and both in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and on Governors Island in 1988. He seemed eager to keep in touch, saying the Soviet leader had invited the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> to travel to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and that the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> had reciprocated with an invitation to the Gorbachevs to visit <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The outgoing president and his wife will live in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> after his term ends Jan. 20, and say they will also spend time at their ranch in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ynez </LOCATION> mountains north of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has never been to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. In the course of superpower summitry during his second term, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, there has been a `` serious movement and even some breakthroughs.'' He applauded <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s offer to reduce Soviet troop strength by half a million troops, but said there was `` still room for negotiations'' on the subject because the Soviets would retain an advantage in troops in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. `` The path remains open and the pace of peace continues,'' the president said. Asked whether he believed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was transforming the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> into a less threatening nation, he replied, `` Yes, I do.'' He said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s hasty return home, prompted by the devastating earthquake in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>, was `` a sad final note to what has been an otherwise successful _ and I use the next words advisedly _ happy and historic visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Asked to assess <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s long-term chances for political survival, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said: `` Well, I realize, and I think we all should, that he is battling a bureaucracy, because whether it's a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> bureaucracy or one of our own, the first rule of bureaucracy is protect the bureaucracy.'' `` And it would mean some great changes for some of the `` Nomenklatura,'' as they call their bureaucracy there, if he institutes the reforms that he's talking about,'' he continued. `` But, on the plus side for him, it's very evident that the people of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are on his side. And I have to believe that the Nomenklatura is going to have to think twice with regard to how far they would go in trying to block him when the man in the street over there wants the things that have been seen.'' __ greater than EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> covers the White House for The Associated Press
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Glance     12-09 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Glance,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Reagan Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are highlights of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s news conference Thursday night.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOVIET UNION</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said `` extraordinary things'' have occurred in recent years to improve U.S.-Soviet relations. But he added that the Soviets would retain conventional troop superiority even if <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> makes planned troop reductions. The president said he believed <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was trying to make the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> less threatening. Asked whether he trusted the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader, he replied, `` He has n't shown me any reason yet that I should n't.'' But he quickly reasserted his policy of `` trust but verify.'' He said he would someday like to see the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as allies `` if it can be definitely established they no longer follow expansionist policy.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DEFICIT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> rejected an assertion that tax cuts he sponsored had contributed to the federal budget deficit. He blamed anew congressional spending habits, specifically those of the Democrats, for the red ink. `` We came in inheriting literally deficit spending built into the structure of government,'' the president.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TAXES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he would be `` deeply disappointed'' if President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sought to raise taxes after taking office, adding `` I do n't think it's going to happen. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he believed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could trim the deficit without raising taxes or cutting Social Security.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>A LOOK BACK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 His hardest job as president: `` I do n't think there is anything tougher than to have to order the young men and women in our military today ... to have to send them into danger, order them into some place where their lives are threatened, where their lives can be taken.'' He said the economic recovery was the best part of his presidency.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>AFGHANISTAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would not unilaterally halt aid to the U.S.-backed rebels seeking to overthrow the Soviet-sponsored <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> regime. He called <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s proposal for a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping force in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> an `` exceptional'' proposal but said he was not certain the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> would endorse it. The president said the `` puppet government'' would have to step down for lasting resolution of civil strife.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MIDDLE EAST</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The president said <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> `` left openings for himself'' to back away from his statement this week of support of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> reiterated that the <LOCATION> Unted </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would enter into dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief only `` once it is clear-cut that he's ready to recognize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as a nation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Reflections     12-09 0345</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Reflections,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Discusses Ups and Downs of Presidency</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Reagan Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Reflecting on the peaks and valleys of his presidency, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said his toughest burden has been sending young Americans into battle and laboring to win the release of others held hostage. At two different points in his nationally broadcast news conference Thursday night, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> talked of difficult moments in the Oval Office. Asked what task he had found most difficult, the president quickly cited the sending of troops into combat. Saying that `` I think I am prouder of them than of anything that has happened'' during his nearly eight years in office, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> added: `` I do n't think there's anything tougher than to have to order these magnificent young men and women in our military ... into danger.'' `` That's got to be something that any president would hesitate on and have to say was the greatest burden,'' he said. At another point, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> cited the continuing captivity of nine Americans held by pro-Iranian elements in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, saying it was `` one of those things ... you go to bed with every night.'' During <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s presidency, more than 200 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel were killed during a bombing of a Marine barracks in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, several thousand troops were sent into combat during the invasion of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, in which 19 American soldiers were killed, and 37 crewmen aboard the USS Stark were killed in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> when their ship was struck by missiles fired by an Iraqi fighter. When asked what he most enjoyed about the presidency, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> replied that `` there are a number of things to miss.'' But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said `` let me simply say one I enjoyed the most is the economic recovery.'' `` When I came here, for almost half a century, the debate on the -LRB- Capitol -RRB- <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had always been between more big spending programs, more power for the federal government, more intervention in private affairs by the federal government, as against those who were preaching less,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mitchell-HoldoutPrecinct Bjt   12-09 0536</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mitchell-Holdout Precinct, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Democratic Leader Visits Election Foe's Only Precinct</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALMADGE, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On a return to his home state, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> visited the only precinct that he did n't carry in November's election. Judging by the reception, he might win even its votes the next time around. The tiny <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> in <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON> was filled with half again as many adults as voted in the race. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> lost there, 18-12, but won in the other 672 precincts, capturing 81 percent of the statewide vote. `` I wanted to head up here and find out what I was doing wrong,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> told the gathering in this outpost of rural eastern <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who followed up his election victory by winning the three-way majority leader's race last week, had written letters to <PERSON> Talmadge </PERSON> residents inviting them to the meeting. He was applauded repeatedly inside the church, a white wooden building surrounded by a mustard-seed farm, and several people told him they looked forward to seeing him running for president. `` Boy, you'd never know I only got 12 votes, for all that told me they voted for me,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. Local citizens said they held nothing against the senator, a Democrat, but that his challenger, Republican <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON>, was more in tune with the Pentecostal community's beliefs, especially on abortion. <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON> is the director of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. `` Abortion was the issue here,'' said <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffin </PERSON>, the pastor who welcomed <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>. Rev. Coffin, in her introduction, reminded <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> that the success of majority rule in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is the ability to listen to the minority. `` Thank you for listening to a very small minority here,'' she told him. The toughest questions for <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> came from <LOCATION> Talmadge </LOCATION> resident <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Heim </PERSON>. He attacked <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and others who do n't oppose abortion in all instances as being in the same league as `` pimps, prostitutes and witches.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said he opposes federal funding for abortion but was not against the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s ruling which gives women the choice. He told <PERSON> Heim </PERSON> it was `` regrettable'' that he was associating people of different viewpoints with scurrilous characters. The senator explained that he is a Roman Catholic but, `` I do n't know when life begins. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> fielded questions on local issues and the U.S.-Canada free-trade pact, which he opposed in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, and afterward joined the congregation for sandwiches and sweets in a basement social hall. Some of the people apologized for <PERSON> Heim </PERSON>'s attack, explaining that he was not a native of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Heim </PERSON> himself allowed that he was impressed by <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s visit. `` He comes here, exposing his flank,'' said <PERSON> Heim </PERSON>, `` He's quite a guy.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> chatted with <PERSON> Heim </PERSON>, reporting afterward that another facet of the encounter had been revealed. `` He said, ` I was a private and I always wanted to get an officer. This was my chance','' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who was an officer in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Counterintelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in the mid-1950s, said with a laugh. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said another, older man came up and said, `` Boy, I've had a lot of politicians come around before the election, but you're the first one to come around after the election
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-O'Haire     12-09 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-O'Haire,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Nuremberg War Crimes Prosecutor Dead At Age 77</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> lawyer who served on the prosecution team at the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> war crimes trials in <LOCATION> Nuremberg </LOCATION> after World War II has died, his law office said. The <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> law firm of <PERSON> O'Haire </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fiore </PERSON> and <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Maur </PERSON> said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Haire </PERSON> died of heart failure Thursday. He was 77. <PERSON> O'Haire </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Pittston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, and served in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> until he joined the <LOCATION> Nuremberg </LOCATION> prosecution team in 1946, the statement said. It said <PERSON> O'Haire </PERSON> set up the American law firm in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> in 1950. The statement said <PERSON> O'Haire </PERSON> would be buried in his native <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> on Dec. 16. No other details were immediately available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ReaganRelics     12-09 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Relics,0427</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Sending Relics of Presidency to Eureka College</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL VOGRIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EUREKA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s alma mater, tiny <ORGANIZATION> Eureka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, is sifting through a bonanza of presidential baubles, including the trademark jellybean jar and a cowboy belt buckle proclaiming `` the buckaroo stops here.'' `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has a deep affection for <ORGANIZATION> Eureka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and remains consistently in touch with us,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearne </PERSON>, the college's president. The school of 460 students about 20 miles east of <LOCATION> Peoriairport </LOCATION> news conference, saying the quake, which registered 6.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, `` had extremely grave consequences, devastation and grave loss of life.'' Armenian church officials in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> who are in contact with people in the region said the death toll may be as high as 70,000. Although he had only `` one working day'' in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said, `` I and my delegation believe that this was a very important day.'' The highlights of the visit were <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s announcement before the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> that he planned a major reduction in Soviet troop strength over the next three years, and his superpower luncheon with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the first Soviet chief to visit <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> in 28 years, said his <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> speech and a later reception gave him the opportunity to `` set out our views ... on the world today, and on the prospects of the world's development.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> called the Governors Island session with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` a good meeting, held in ... an open and trusting atmosphere.'' He said the one word he would use to characterize it was `` continuity'' and said all parties walked away, `` confident that our relations will expand and improve on the basis of cooperation, on the basis of mutual respect for each other's interests.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> later added, `` I think I would be remiss in my duty if I went home without saying how much we are grateful to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkers </LOCATION>, for the hospitality and feelings of friendship that they have been expressing over these days. So to all <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkers </LOCATION>, our very warm gratitude. We value that very much.'' He had planned to visit the first Soviet trade show in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, Central Park and the Metropolitan Museum on Thursday. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>, canceled a visit with children at an <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION> elementary school.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     12-09 0559</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0584</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attractive New `Aida' At Met</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Will stand for PMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An attractive new production of `` Aida'' at the Metropolitan Opera avoids the visual silliness of the two productions that arrived before it. This one makes dramatic use of the stage elevator to change sets. The opening night of the new `` Aida,'' a Met Opera Guild benefit, was tastefully conducted by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> and gloriously sung by <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> as <PERSON> Aida </PERSON>, <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> as Radames, <PERSON> Fiorenza </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossotto </PERSON> as <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sherrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON> as <PERSON> Aida </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Amonasro </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Plishka </PERSON> as the high priest. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> sounded sterling throughout. He surprised this listener by taking the optional lower ending, not the high C, at the end of `` Celeste Aida.'' Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, singing her first <PERSON> Aida </PERSON> at the Met, bloomed into full vocal glory in the third act. She had longing in her voice in `` O patria mia'' and some beautiful pianissimos. Her voice has matured marvelously and still has youthful freshness. In many operas, the love music is in the first act, before things start to go wrong. In `` Aida'' the love music is in Act 4, after things have gone so wrong that <PERSON> Aida </PERSON> and Radames are sealed in a vault to die. Their duet was so beautiful that the audience did n't immediately break the spell with huge applause at the end of it Miss Cossotto, who made her Met debut as <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON> in 1968, is a fine musician, using her voice to brilliant advantage. Her stage personality, while not flamboyant, is striking, placing <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON>' royal but hopeless love for Radames in the foreground in the first two acts Miss <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s more retiring demeanor put Aida in the background. <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON> was in brilliant voice and form. Amonasro may be a captive but he's full of vitality and vibrant with plans. <PERSON> Plishka </PERSON> sang with admirable authority. The costumes, by <PERSON> Dada </PERSON> <PERSON> Saligeri </PERSON>, were mostly white trimmed with gold. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> began, a hero, in all gold, and ended, disgraced, in a dark striped tunic. Some scenes were played near the front of the stage, in front of a wall with huge bas reliefs of two seated Egyptians. Then this would lift for a scene using more of the stage. The most dramatic theatrical stroke is having Amneris' room in Act 2 sink out of sight. First, soldiers are seen standing on top of the set that's descending, then a platform for the king and <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON> is revealed, then all the citizenry _ now joined at ground level by the soldiers _ wait for the triumphal entry scene. In the final scene, the elevator is used again, so the audience sees <PERSON> Aida </PERSON> and Radames in the vault and Amneris in a temple above them. There is no silly dance in Act 1 while Radames receives his armor and no fight to the death during the triumphal entry scene. There is a dance there, by choreographer <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, making his Met debut, but it is n't silly. <PERSON> Gianni </PERSON> <PERSON> Quaranta </PERSON>, who is Italian and won an Academy Award in 1987 for art direction for `` A Room with a View,'' designed the sets. <PERSON> Sonja </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisell </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> who was on the staff of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scala </LOCATION> for 15 years, did stage direction. Both, making Met debuts, proved to be stars of the show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirForceSafety     12-09 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Force Safety,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>A-10 Warplane Has One of Best Safety Records In Air Force Fleet</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Germany Crash</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warplane that crashed into an apartment building in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, killing four people, has one of the best safety records in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> inventory. The A-10 Thunderbolt II is an older model ground-attack plane designed to be highly maneuverable at low speeds and low altitude and to carry a lot of bombs and ammunition. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> said the crash was the 14th serious, so-called Class A accident since Oct. 1, when the current fiscal year began, although it was the first involving an A-10. At the same point in the last fiscal year, the service had experienced nine Class A accidents. Among the 14 accidents recorded since Oct. 1 have been two involving the new B-1B bomber; one involving a B-52 bomber, and one involving an F-16 fighter in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> last Monday that killed the general in charge of <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> personnel in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says it is impossible to predict what type of safety record it will post for the year based on little more than one month's passage. During fiscal 1988, for example, the service experienced a grim record for its F-16 jet fighter, and yet finished the year by posting one of its best overall safety records in history. `` Nonetheless, it is true that our mishap rate has suddenly spiked up and we do n't know why,'' said one <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> official who asked not to be identified. `` We continue to examine our training procedures, maintenance and everything else.'' Wednesday's crash involved an A-10 on a training flight that inexplicably slammed into an apartment building in <LOCATION> Remscheid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, killing at least four people, injuring dozens of others and destroying homes for more than a block. The A-10 is designed to support soldiers on the ground by attacking enemy tanks and other high-priority targets. The Thunderbolt first flew in 1975 and became operational with the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> in 1977. The plane is no longer in production, but the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has more than 700 of them in its inventory. Statistically, the A-10 over time has been the safest fighter or attack plane currently in the inventory. The aircraft has chalked up a major accident rate of less than 4 Class A mishaps per 100,000 flying hours over its lifetime _ which now consists of more than 1.75 million flight hours. A Class A mishap is one in which there is either a fatality or damage exceeding $ 500,000 to an aircraft. In the fiscal year ended Sept. 30, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> lost three A-10's, for a mishap rate of 1.37 per 100,000 flight hours. By comparison, the A-7 had a mishap rate of 6.04 per 100,000 flight hours; the F-16 a rate of 6.80 per 100,000 flight hours, and the B-52 a rate of 2.04 per 100,000 flight hours. The overall <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> rate for the last fiscal year was 1.63 serious mishaps per 100,000 flying hours _ representing 55 total accidents _ just slightly worse than the service's all-time best of 1.53 set in fiscal 1986. The surge in <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> accidents over the past month comes at a time when the other military services continue to report stable rates. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, for example, which enjoyed its safest year ever in fiscal 1988, is on track toward an even safer year. Since Oct. 1, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has experienced only four Class A accidents. It recorded 37 in all of fiscal 1988, or more than three per month on average.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iraq-POWs     12-09 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iraq-POWs,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>POWs Say Iranians Offered Them Money, Brides To Stay</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSUL, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Repatriated Iraqi prisoners of war claim Iranian officials offered them money and marriage in an effort to dissuade them from returning to <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. About 30 prisoners, repatriated for health reasons after the Aug. 20 cease-fire in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> conflict, said many Iraqi prisoners decided to stay in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> after such offers were made. There was no comment from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> on the allegations, made Wednesday after reporters were driven in government buses from <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Mosul </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> General </PERSON> <PERSON> Hospital </PERSON>, where the former prisoners are being treated. `` They would tell us, ` We will arrange for you to marry a beautiful Iranian girl, get you a well-paid job, a house and a car, if you ask for political asylum and stay on in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,''' said <PERSON> Osama </PERSON> <PERSON> Youssef </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON>, a 29-year-old soldier who was captured in 1981. Another recently freed prisoner, <PERSON> Raad </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammoud </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Saiidi </PERSON>, 25, who said he was captured along with his father and brother while working on a construction project in a border town in 1980 at the beginning of the conflict, said: `` The mullah -LRB- Moslem priest -RRB- at the prison kept telling me that he will arrange for me to marry a beautiful Iranian girl if I stay in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CorporateTaxes     12-09 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corporate Taxes,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey: Tax Changes Taking Bigger Corporate Bite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new survey shows that overhaul of the federal income tax is increasing the bite on corporations _ which is just what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended. One thousand corporations surveyed by Tax Analysts paid about $ 7 billion more into the federal treasury last year than they did in 1986, when the tax laws underwent major revisions. The 1,000 companies, spread out among 49 industries, paid an average of 24.72 percent of their earnings in federal income tax in 1987, the study found. That compares with 21.54 percent in 1986 and 20.94 percent the previous year. Three out of four corporations paid a higher rate last year than the year before. While a portion of the increase is due to higher earnings in 1987, most is attributable to the new tax law, said Tax Analysts, a Virginia-based research and publishing organization. `` Tax reform is working,'' said <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marovelli </PERSON> of Tax Analysts. `` More corporations are paying higher taxes. Fewer are avoiding taxes.'' A major goal of the 1986 tax overhaul was to shift a greater portion of the tax burden from individuals to corporations. Over five years, the total shift is expected to be about $ 125 billion. The most significant corporate changes enacted were repeal of the special treatment of capital gains, toughening of the alternative minimum tax, repeal of the investment tax credit and restructuring of depreciation allowances. The general corporate tax rate was cut, from 46 percent to 33 percent, which benefited all companies. However, because different types of corporations took advantage of different provisions under the old tax law, there are significant variations in how they are faring under the new law, said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Starcher </PERSON> of Tax Analysts. For example, a reduction in long-term accounting provisions more than doubled the average tax rate paid by aerospace companies, from 15.6 percent of earnings to 36.7 percent, the study found. On the other hand, apparel and furniture companies are paying generally lower taxes because they have the lower tax rates but lost relatively little in the other tax changes. According to the Tax Analysts calculations, the automobile industry paid the lowest tax rate last year _ a negative 6.93 percent _ while construction was highest at 58.9 percent. Both situations were exaggerated by special circumstancs, <PERSON> Marovelli </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the largest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automaker, had a one-time tax writeoff that made the entire industry's situation look worse than it was; without <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Marovelli </PERSON> said, the industry would have paid 17 percent. The high rate on the construction industry reflected the same accounting changes that affected the aerospace industry, as well as a curtailment in use of installment sales, which in the past had produced a tax savings for that industry. Other industry figures from 1987 included: insurance, 14 percent; paper, 19 percent; drugs, 22.1 percent; banking, 23.6 percent; railroads, 23.9 percent; petroleum refining, 24.9 percent; lumber, 29.2 percent; textiles, 29.4 percent; services, 31.7 percent; tobacco, 33.1 percent; apparel, 34.9 percent; commercial printing, 35 percent; newspapers, 36.7 percent; and retail groceries, 37.1 percent. Tax Analysts bases its calculations on corporate filings with the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Citizens for <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>, a labor-financed tax research group, reached similar conclusions in a study of profitable corporations released in September. That study concluded the number of profitable companies that paid no federal tax was cut by more than half last year _ to 16 _ and that the 250 companies surveyed paid an average of 22.1 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SausageStandoff     12-09 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sausage Standoff,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Holds Police Hostage With Two Pieces of Beef Jerky</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A prisoner being taken to a mental hospital used two pieces of beef jerky shaped like a gun muzzle to hold a police chief hostage for about 40 minutes before he was subdued while praying, authorities said. `` He was pretty cunning,'' <ORGANIZATION> Cisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rains </PERSON> said Thursday after the ordeal. `` It felt like a real gun.'' Rains said he was taken hostage by the prisoner, who had once been treated as a manic-depressive at the <ORGANIZATION> Wichita </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Falls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, Wednesday night in the bathroom of an <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> service station. Rains and <LOCATION> Eastland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> jail administrator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> had stopped at the service station on their way to <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where the 58-year-old prisoner was being committed at the request of relatives. However, the prisoner, who was not handcuffed, got into an armlock with Rains in the gas station bathroom. `` He was trying to grab my gun, and he told me he had a derringer in my back,'' Rains said. But the .22 - caliber derringer the man claimed to be holding turned out to be two rounded pieces of beef jerky, one on top of the other to simulate a double barrel, covered with a bread wrapper, Rains At first, Rains said, he did n't believe the prisoner had a gun. But then, he said, `` I felt something else in his hand. I could n't tell what it was. The man, who works as a truck driver, is a gun enthusiast and does own a derringer, Rains said. <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> rushed to assist Rains after his call for help but was held at bay by the prisoner, who stood behind the police chief. `` We just simply did n't know for sure, and it was n't the time to take a gamble,'' <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> said. While <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> and Rains attempted to calm the prisoner, an <ORGANIZATION> Austin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> hostage negotiator and special mission team were called to surround the bathroom. The man, who was not identified by police, attempted during the 40-minute standoff to convince the officers he did not need to go to the state hospital. `` He was trying to convince us that <PERSON> God </PERSON> was going to cure his mental illness,'' <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> and two <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> officers finally subdued the man after he dropped to his knees and began praying. No charges had been filed Thursday against the prisoner, who was transported to the state hospital after surrendering, an <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> police spokesman said. Rains said he may ask <LOCATION> Eastland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> District Attorney <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowell </PERSON> to file charges against the man. `` Had he had a real gun, he probably would have shot me in the back,'' Rains said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TrainingCrash 2ndLd-Writethru a0839 12-09 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Training Crash, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0839,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Force A-10 Jet Crashes in Desert</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE with identity of pilot</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TRACY, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> A-10 fighter crashed Thursday afternoon near the heart of the Tohono O'Odham Indian Reservation, but the pilot ejected safely, officials said. The plane, based at at <ORGANIZATION> Davis-Monthan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, crashed around 3:30 p.m. about 80 miles west of <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>. The pilot, identified as Capt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Nutterfield </PERSON>, 29, of <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>, was admitted to the base hospital, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Keck </PERSON>. Another A-10 crashed Thursday into an apartment house in <LOCATION> Remscheid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, killing at least four people. Despite the coincidence of the accidents, Ms. <PERSON> Keck </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> would not ground the base's A-10s. The Tactical Air Command late Thursday released a statement saying that the aircraft would not be grounded. `` I can tell you from this standpoint, we're not tying the two of them together,'' said the civilian spokeswoman. Officials said an investigative board left for the reservation, whose residents have complained for years about low-flying military aircraft. The pilot was the only occupant of the single-passenger jet, a unit of the 23rd Tactical Support Group, Capt. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Besich </PERSON> said. He said the aircraft was on a training mission. Ms. <PERSON> Keck </PERSON> said the jet crashed near the town of <LOCATION> Tracy </LOCATION>, about 20 miles northwest of the tribal capital of Sells. Reservation residents have complained for years about low-altitude flights from the <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> base, which flies many training missions over sparsely populated southwestern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. No one answered the telephone in Tohono O'Odham tribal offices in several attempts to reach the tribe for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0236EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-09 0755</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,755</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Long List Of Potential Agriculture Secretaries</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The name of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> is among the latest to surface on a long list of candidates to be secretary of agriculture in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, according to some farm organization officials. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, once a favorite in the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> guessing game, has indicated he will return to the private sector when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves office next month. Because of that decision, there does not appear to be a front-runner for the agriculture post. According to one source who demanded anonymity, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> may have changed his mind after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> named <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> as White House trade representative. She is a veteran <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> insider but has little hands-on agricultural experience. But the source said Thursday that <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> might be persuaded to take the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> and help with agriculture-related issues during difficult times still ahead in multinational trade negotiations under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, said he sees no clear favorite among the dozen or so names that have been mentioned for the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> post. `` I think the bag is so full now there is n't any more room for new names,'' <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. Among those believed to be in the running are <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Delano </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> farmer and former federation president, and <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleckner </PERSON>, its current chief. Asked about the possibility <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> might name a woman to head the department, which traditionally has had men in all but a few senior positions, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said he had heard <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> mentioned as a candidate. `` It would certainly be a very interesting appointment,'' <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` In the eyes of some people, it might even be revolutionary. Personally, I think it would be refreshing, but I'm not sure it's the time or place. I do n't know.'' A second <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Republican, Rep. <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, also has been mentioned for the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> post. A seven-term veteran of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is the ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee for agriculture. <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> here, said she had not heard either woman mentioned for the job but added, `` We could do a lot worse than either <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> or <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>, that's for sure.'' <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said she thought <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice would be `` someone who listens to his boss'' and follows the path set by the 1985 farm law and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policy calling for reduced federal support for farmers and subsidies for commodity exports at levels below the cost of production for family farmers. Some of those contacted Thursday said <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> farmer <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, the current deputy secretary to outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, has come on strong recently as a potential successor to <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> and has been gaining support among some Republicans on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, also of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, has been in the running too, along with former <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> soybean farmer. The list also includes Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, a conservative <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat who gave President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> a helping hand in some of his early congressional budget battles. Another recent addition to the speculation is <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Angell </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>'s board of governors. <PERSON> Angell </PERSON>, a Kansan, has a long background in banking and family agriculture. <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Haas </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION>, said her favorite would be <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> because of what she termed his `` very strong consumer record.'' But she added: `` The direction this -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB- administration will go is not likely to be pro-consumer. From the trend of the appointments so far, probably it will be more centrist.'' Environmental and conservation advocates are sitting well no matter who <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> puts in charge of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>, says <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, policy director for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said he would like to see <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> get promoted to the top job because of his record during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years as a supporter of sound conservation policies, including the Conservation Reserve Program established by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the 1985 farm law. That program's goal is to take up to 45 million acres of highly erodible cropland from production by 1990 and protect it for 10 years by planting grass and trees. More than half the goal has been met. But <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said he expected the program will be continued regardless of whom <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> taps to head the department.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CoastGuardReport     12-09 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Coast Guard Report,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Safety Not Considered When Coast Guard Shut Ship Traffic
Centers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, in deciding to close two of its largest ship-traffic control centers, failed to consider safety and environmental factors and incorrectly estimated the cost savings, a government study has concluded. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said economics was the main reason for closing the facilities, known as vessel traffic services, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> harbors. Yet because of incomplete recordkeeping, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> was not sure how much money it actually would save. `` Because the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> did not consider such information, it does not know if it made the correct decision in closing the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> -LRB- facilities -RRB-, two of the three largest in terms of vessel activity,'' said the report. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the closings will save about $ 3.5 million _ mainly due to lower personnel costs. That is $ 228,000 more than the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> itself had estimated. The ship-traffic control facilities are similar to air traffic control systems. They use a combination of radar, radio and closed-circuit cameras to monitor vessel traffic in waters where the possibility of accidents is high. The cuts were part of a plan to pare 1,060 military and civilian jobs nationwide in the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> and save the government about $ 48 million. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> facilities on Governors Island was closed last July while <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>' was decommissioned in March. The Coast Guard chose <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> because they would take less time to close and because it `` believed it could close the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> VTS's with a minimum of -LRB- public -RRB- resistance,'' the report said. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> is the nation's busiest harbor, handling more than 212,000 vessels in fiscal 1987, while <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is the third busiest, with traffic of about 157,000 vessels in the same period. The report criticized the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> for failing to consider a number of relevant factors in the closings, including `` prevention of accidents and fatalities and protection of the environment through prevention of oil spills and accidents involving hazardous cargoes.'' Although it took issue with the methods used by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> in reaching the closure decision, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> did not specifically say the closures were a mistake.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881209-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-09-88 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Thornburgh-Soviets     12-09 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thornburgh-Soviets,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jewish Group, Congressmen Criticize US Decision On Soviet Emigres</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
