<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Subsidies     04-28 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Subsidies,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Cities Offer Direct Subsidies to Offset Inflation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese cities will begin offering direct subsidies to urban residents to help them cope with the soaring prices of pork and other food, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. In <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, where vegetable prices almost doubled in the first three months of this year, residents will each receive a monthly subsidy of 10 yuan -LRB- about $ 2.70 -RRB- as of May 1, the report said. People living in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> will receive a similar subsidy starting sometime in the next few months, it said. The direct stipends replace government subsidies to state food shops designed to keep food prices at an artificially low level. That system has proved ineffective in stopping price increases as consumers demand more and better food and farmers turn to free markets where their goods command better prices. The daily said that starting this month, <LOCATION> Changsha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has subsidized residents 10 yuan a month for four main non-staple goods _ pork, vegetables, sugar and eggs. Since then, the price for fresh pork at state stores has risen from about 40 cents to 56 cents a pound, and sugar has gone up from 18 cents to 27 cents a pound. Retail prices nationwide rose 11 percent in the first quarter, the first time the government has acknowledged double-digit inflation. Prices of non-staple food items increased by 24.4 percent and vegetables jumped by 48.7 percent in the same period.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hirohito 1stLd-Writethru a0635 04-28 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hirohito, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0635,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Brave Rain To Greet Emperor On 87th Birthday</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New grafs 1-13 UPDATE with emperor addressing 17,000 well
wishers. Picks up 5th graf pvs. The remarks ... with minor editing</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto TOK1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN K. PAULSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 17,000 people, many waving <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> flags, braved a drizzling rain Friday to give birthday greetings to 87-year-old Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, the world's oldest and longest-reigning monarch. Accompanied by Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> and other members of the imperial family, the emperor made the first of three scheduled appearances on a veranda overlooking a cheering crowd in the Imperial Palace grounds. Missing was Empress <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON>, 85, who suffers back and leg ailments. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, protected by bullet-proof glass, said in a brief speech, `` Thank you for celebrating my birthday with me today. I am happy that so many of you have come today. I hope you will all have a happy future.'' His birthday is a national holiday. It was the emperor's second appearance in public since he was hospitalized last September after complaining of fatigue and nausea. Doctors performed a bypass then around an intestinal obstruction. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, once worshiped as a living god, also spoke to well-wishers at the palace grounds on New Year's Day. Despite a slow recovery after the operation and rumors of ill health, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> appeared relatively strong Friday, although he shuffled slowly as he walked. Commentators on Japanese television said he seemed to have regained about 90 percent of the strength he had before the operation. The crowd shouted `` Long live the emperor!'' and waved flags. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> gave his characteristic front-and-back hand wave in response. After about 2 -LCB- minutes, the imperial family filed back into the palace, led by the emperor. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has been on the throne since Dec. 25, 1926. He told a news conference this week he feels well after his surgery and needs years more to finish research in marine biology, his favorite hobby. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> said he had replanted an endangered plant species on the palace grounds and `` it is growing well because the imperial garden is similar to forest land.'' The emperor also remarked that World War II was his `` most unpleasant memory'' and urged the Japanese to pursue peace. The remarks were carried in Japanese by the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and translated by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The annual news conference, reduced from its usual 30 minutes to 15 because of concern about the emperor's health, took place Monday but the reports were not released until his birthday. `` I have recovered well ... I respect a doctor's advice and am trying not to overdo it,'' he said. ` Asked by the Japanese reporters about his memories of World War II, the emperor said: `` After all is considered, the war was my most unpleasant memory. I am pleased with people's efforts for peace after the war. Hereafter, I hope the people do not forget this matter and protect peace.'' He would not say say what caused <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to go to war, declaring: `` I do not want to answer the question because this will involve criticism against persons.'' In meetings with foreign reporters, the emperor has expressed sorrow for `` certain things'' that happened in the war, but said he acted as a constitutional monarch and had no personal role. He denied planning the attack on <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, but left many other questions unanswered. Foreign reporters were not allowed at the birthday news conference, during which he answered eight questions. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Yoshihiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Tokugawa </PERSON>, his former grand chamberlain, who retired this month at age 81 after serving more than half a century. `` He protected recordings of the emperor's announcement of the defeat in the war,'' the emperor said. `` With his language abilities, he prepared well for my friendly visits to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Soldiers entered the imperial palace Aug. 15, 1945, planning to seize the recording so the war could continue. <PERSON> Tokugawa </PERSON> was beaten with a pistol, but refused to say where it was hidden. When the recording was finally played, it was the first time most Japanese had heard their emperor's voice. In it, he urged his people `` to open an era of grand peace for the generations to come, by suffering the insufferable, bearing the unbearable.'' He did not use the words `` surrender'' or `` defeat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolAccident 4thLd-Writethru a0850 04-28 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Accident, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0850,0548</SECOND>
<HEAD>Auto Crashes into School Building;
^Eds: SUBS 2nd graf and 13th `Two 7-year-old ... ' to UPDATE with
four children now in critical condition.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARIO FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car careened across a playground and plowed into a crowd of children and adults about to leave an elementary school Thursday, killing a 4-year-old girl and a woman and injuring eight others, officials said. At least four of the injured were in critical condition. `` I called for 10 ambulances,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, principal at <ORGANIZATION> Cyrus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McCormick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` I told them there were bodies all over the playground.'' Witnesses said the car crashed through a chain-link fence and careened across the playground before running up a short flight of stairs to where the crowd was gathered in an entryway at the school. `` I was standing outside the school picking up my son when I turned my head and saw the car coming towards the door,'' said <PERSON> Marcella </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, 30, whose children, ages 8 and 5, attend the school. `` I just screamed and picked up my son with my hands and ran away. The car missed us by a yard and a half.'' `` There were mothers screaming, looking for their children,'' said <PERSON> Araceli </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, whose niece lives with her and attends the school. `` Almost every child that was on the floor had their mother next to them.'' The principal said the car pinned a child and an adult beneath it. `` Myself and a couple of the teachers and a janitor picked the car up and freed the bodies so they would n't be further crushed,'' he said. A woman driver reportedly left the car and walked from the scene, the car still wedged in the entryway. Patrolman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielman </PERSON> said police were questioning a woman who was picked up in the neighborhood minutes after the accident. No cause was given for the accident. <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>, a student at <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, said the car belonged to his family and that his mother apparently had come to the school to pick him up. `` I got on my bus. I just saw my car, I do n't know where my mother is,'' he said. A 4-year-old girl and a woman died at <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> hospitals, spokeswomen said. In critical condition in <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> were a 7-year-old boy and a 10-year-old girl, both with head injuries, and two children, ages 6 and 9, with leg fractures. A 7-year-old boy with head injuries was in fair condition. A 29-year-old parent was hit by the car and thrown into air but escaped serious injury, said <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Two children, ages 6 and 5, were taken to the hospital; one had head and neck injuries and was expected to be released, and the other had bumps and bruises and was in good condition, Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` The car smashed into the entrance where the kids were coming out,'' said <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Cepak </PERSON>, 78, who lives nearby. Third-grade teacher <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said he saw a youngster trying to calm one of the injured women. `` A child was stroking her hair and telling her everything would be all right,'' <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NewCaledonia 1stLd-Writethrua0721   04-28 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Caledonia, 1st Ld-Writethru a0721,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seized Hostage Negotiator Now Ordered To Negotiate For Terrorists</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 12-14 ``Conservative Premier...its end''' with 8
grafs to UPDATE with comments by Chirac and Mitterrand during
debate. Pickup 15th graf pvs ``Native Melanesians...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NOUMEA, New Caledonia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Separatist guerrillas who kidnapped 23 lawmen freed an anti-terrorism expert on Thursday and ordered him to negotiate on behalf of the terrorists, authorities said. Capt. <PERSON> Philippe </PERSON> <PERSON> Legorjus </PERSON>, chief of the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> anti-terrorism force in this French-held territory, was released from a cave on the island of <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION> and told to pursue negotiations with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> authorities, official sources in <LOCATION> Noumea </LOCATION> said. They threatened to kill their remaining hostages if he did not return to the rebel hideaway, a system of caves 110 miles north of here. Legorus, five police officers and an assistant prosecutor were seized by the Melanesian separatists Wednesday as they sought to negotiate the release of 15 other lawmen who had been kidnapped on April 22. The initial hostages were among 27 people kidnapped in a bloody attack at a police station that left four gendarmes dead. Twelve of those hostages subsequently were freed. The attack was part of widespread violence aimed at halting Sunday's French presidential elections on the island. Police said all the remaining hostages are being held in the <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION> caves. The Melanesian separatists, known as Kanaks, released Legorjus to negotiate with <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> authorities in <LOCATION> Fayaoue </LOCATION>, a village on <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Legorjus </PERSON> made at least one trip by helicopter from the cave on Thursday. `` When you open talks, you take risks,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Giraud </PERSON>, responsible for order in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> archipelego </LOCATION>, said in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pons </PERSON>, minister for overseas territories, said in <LOCATION> Noumea </LOCATION> that he has asked the government to outlaw the <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, which is seeking <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> `` It appears now that there is collusion between terrorist acts carried out in certain parts of the territory, including the taking of hostages on <LOCATION> Ouvea </LOCATION>, and the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> political group -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> said. Membership in a banned group is a crime under French law. In <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, Conservative Premier <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> referred to the Kanak front as a `` terrorist faction'' that does not represent the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonian </LOCATION> population. `` I will do everything so that this group is reduced,'' he said during a televised debate with Socialist President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, his rival in presidential run-off elections May 8. `` What counts today is the liberation of the gendarmes and judicial offical,'' <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> said. `` But what counts tomorrow is dialogue.'' <PERSON> Chirac </PERSON> did not clearly say whether he supported outlawing the front. Such a ban must be voted by the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, which meets again Wednesday. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> would have to sign the decree to make it law. <PERSON> Yeiwene </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeiwene </PERSON>, the No. 2 leader in the <ORGANIZATION> Kanak </ORGANIZATION> political group, said banning the organization `` would not settle the crisis in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> and will not stop the <LOCATION> Kanak </LOCATION> people from taking the fight for independence to its end.'' Since Friday last week, election-related violence has left six people dead on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION> and at least 10 wounded. Native Melanesians make up 43 percent of the population of 145,000, while 36 percent are Europeans and the rest primarily Asian or Tahitian. Many Kanaks desire independence, while most Europeans wish to retain ties to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. An estimated 4,000 French troops and gendarmes are in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Caledonia </LOCATION>. A <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> police officer was shot Thursday near <LOCATION> Canala </LOCATION> on the east coast of the mainland, according to the national police headquarters in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. He was listed in good condition at a <LOCATION> Noumea </LOCATION> hospital. The kidnappers have demanded the removal of police reinforcements from the islands. They asked that mediators be sent from <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> to discuss a new referendum on self-determination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u v AM-JetBlast Advisory   04-28 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jet Blast, Advisory,0027</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Eds: Upcoming shortly, a 4th Ld-Writethru to AM-Jet Blast UPDATING with the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> confirming one person missing.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>The AP</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RemembranceBall     04-28 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Remembrance Ball,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ball Held For Four Towns Submerged Under Reservoir</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRUDY TYNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a swirl of old lace and memories, about 100 former residents and 300 relatives gathered Wednesday to mark the night a half-century ago when four western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> towns were submerged to provide drinking water for <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garvey </PERSON>, the High Sheriff of <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, dressed in top hat and tails and holding the 7-foot mace of his office, called the dance to order and read a proclamation from Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> declaring 1988 a Year of Remembrance. `` We had to limit ticket sales to 400. That's all the hall would hold,'' said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, secretary of a consortium of local historical societies that sponsored the Remembrance Ball at the University of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. The dance tickets reprinted the black-bordered tickets to the firemen's ball in 1938 at the <LOCATION> Enfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>, where residents met to mark the last hours of the towns that were drowned to create the 38-square-mile Quabbin Reservoir. Their steps might be slower and their hair turned silver, but for former residents _ many in their 70s and 80s _ the memory was still fresh of that night when people jammed the little brick Town Hall, hung with red, white and blue bunting and draped in black, and spilled into the streets. `` The orchestra ... faintly sounded the strain of ` <ORGANIZATION> Auld </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Syne </ORGANIZATION>' ... muffled sounds of sobbing were heard, hardened men were not ashamed to take out their handkerchiefs,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> reported in 1938. Fifty years later, 38 people who attended the <LOCATION> Enfield </LOCATION> party held hands and marched around the hall. Their reminiscences, jotted down on their dance programs, were read aloud between dance tunes. `` We went to school at the <ORGANIZATION> Enfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>. We lived in the center of town. That's the deepest part of the reservoir now,'' said <PERSON> Joy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickenson </PERSON> <PERSON> Boch </PERSON>. The towns of <PERSON> Dana </PERSON>, <PERSON> Prescott </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Enfield </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> _ home for 2,500 people _ were submerged at midnight April 27, 1938 The reservoir took 20 years to build and cost $ 53 million and the lives of more than 20 workers. It now provides drinking water for 2.5 million people, half of the state's population. Although it's not the largest reservoir in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, none larger has been built strictly to provide drinking water.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NASAJudgment     04-28 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NASA Judgment,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quadriplegic Awarded $4.2 Million in Judgment Against NASA</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge Wednesday ordered the government to pay $ 4.2 million to a truck driver left brain-damaged and paralyzed in 1984 when he was hit by a piece of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> equipment being loaded onto his flatbed trailer. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Takasugi </PERSON> ruled that <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> employees were negligent in the accident involving <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitzke </PERSON>, 57, of suburban <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>. The accident left <PERSON> Spitzke </PERSON> a quadriplegic in need of 24-hour care, said his attorney, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Krepack </PERSON>. <PERSON> Spitzke </PERSON> was working as a driver for a heavy equipment hauling company when the accident happened at a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> research facility near <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Krepack </PERSON> said. The veteran trucker was helping to load a cargo lift trailer, which is used in the space shuttle program, onto his flatbed truck for transport to a <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> defense contractor when the load shifted and rotated, knocking him off the flatbed, <PERSON> Krepack </PERSON> said. The judgment was satisfactory to <PERSON> Spitzke </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON>, the attorney said. `` They would prefer that it never happened ... or the alternative, that they can make him well but unfortunately that ca n't be done,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CambodianReunion     04-28 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodian Reunion,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reunited Family Hopes to Find Lost Sister</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY48 and MR1 of April 27</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WINDSOR, Vt. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Somnang </PERSON> <PERSON> Rom </PERSON>, a 10-year-old Cambodian refugee, bounded off the airplane and into the arms of the elder brother who'd last seen him as an infant. The boy is part of a family that was reunited Tuesday night after a decade apart. They had been separated by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> takeover in that Southeast Asian nation. <PERSON> Somnang </PERSON> and his mother, <PERSON> Prak </PERSON> <PERSON> Soy </PERSON>, arrived in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, on Tuesday night for an emotional reunion with <PERSON> Sarin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rom </PERSON>, who came to this country in 1983 and has been trying to reunite with his mother and brother since learning they were alive. After the communist takeover of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, the father was taken away by soldiers and is presumed dead. Two siblings starved to death. A brother is missing. A sister is married and lives in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. The younger <PERSON> Rom </PERSON> and his mother spent Wednesday adjusting to a new life in <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. `` I heard a ball bouncing this morning at 5:30,'' <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Smiley </PERSON>, who lives below the family, said Wednesday. `` He learned how to use the camera and has been taking pictures all morning.'' <PERSON> Smiley </PERSON> said they turned lights off and on as they experimented with electricity and watched television for the first time. `` They could n't understand,'' <PERSON> Smiley </PERSON> said, describing their fascination with the tube. `` Somnang was jumping up and down.'' The red tape that delayed the reunion frustrated Sarin and the people of <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> who helped him, including foster parents, friends, local churches and community groups. Many came to the airport Tuesday to greet the family. `` There were so many delays,'' said <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON>, the Vermont Refugee Coordinator. `` We had to wait for so many governments to find a way.'' <PERSON> Smiley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sarin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rom </PERSON>'s foster mother, said the reunion is not quite complete. A 16-year-old sister, <PERSON> Romdoul </PERSON>, still remains overseas. She was reportedly abducted while in a refugee camp. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., said his office became involved because the entire community was backing <PERSON> Rom </PERSON> in his efforts to find his family `` We've been working with them for 17 months,'' <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> said. `` There were times when we did n't know whether we'd get anwyhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-28 0905</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0942</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Oscar-winning actor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> insists his marriage is intact, and suggests rumors that he and his wife, <PERSON> Diandra </PERSON>, are splitting may be an unhappy spinoff of his role as an adulterer in `` Fatal Attraction.' <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, who recently won an Oscar for Best Actor for his latest movie `` Wall Street,'' spoke to reporters Wednesday before a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> premiere of the film, at which Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> was a guest. Asked if his marriage to <PERSON> Diandra </PERSON>, a 30-year-old model, was over as some reports have said, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> said, `` It's not true and I really do not know how any of it got started. `` I suppose it was doing pictures like ` Fatal Attraction,''' a movie about how a family was thrown into crisis by the husband's adultery Asked whether he saw anything of his own personality in the character he played in the movie, he retorted, `` How long have you been married? Do you fool around?'' When the reporter declined to answer, he went on to the next question.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jazz trumpeter <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and his seven-piece band have resumed their year-long worldwide tour. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> had been hospitalized here for a leg infection that resulted from an injury he received while touring in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. He and his ensemble returned to the stage April 18 in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. After four dates in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, they left for <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> where the first date was Wednesday in <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>. June includes dates in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and back in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In July, he'll be in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>; August in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>; and September in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. The tour is <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' first with a full set of high-tech equipment and an extravaganza of multicolored lights.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Mayor <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, making good on her promise to leave politics after a series of shattering defeats, says she will begin work next week as an environmental relations consultant for a public relations firm. Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> said Tuesday she also has begun writing an autobiography, and will teach a course in government at <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The city's former chief executive lost her recent bid for the Democratic nomination for clerk of the <ORGANIZATION> Cook </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> after two unsuccessful bids to regain the mayor's office. Afterward, she vowed not to seek elective office again. She said she has accepted a job with <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a public relations firm in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. `` I will be working in public affairs, primarily on environmental issues,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON>, who noted that she was familiar with the subject from her work as <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s commissioner of consumer services in the 1970s.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>, the Academy Award-winning star of `` Kiss of the Spider Woman'' and the vacuous anchorman of `` Broadcast News,'' has won the first <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> Award for his `` outstanding'' performances. The award, an 8-inch crystal teardrop sculpture engraved with <PERSON> Hurt </PERSON>'s name, was presented to him Wednesday by the late actor's daughter, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, at an auditorium packed with more than 1,800 people Hurt was the overwhelming choice for the first Tracy Award, which honors actors for `` outstanding screen performances and professional achievement,'' said <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Tressel </PERSON>, student commissioner of campus events at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MORGANTOWN, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Blair </PERSON> <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON>, who portrays the devious lawyer <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' came to the defense of his former acting teacher during a tenure hearing at <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` I know the kind of woman she is, and I would not be where I am today without her guidance and teaching,'' said <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON>, who studied under <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Ambrosia </PERSON> while she was at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mellon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> D'Ambrosia </PERSON> applied for tenure at <ORGANIZATION> WVU </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 after teaching there for two years. Her request was denied and a state hearing examiner is conducting an appeals hearing, which is expected to conclude today. <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON>, 23, said Wednesday that <PERSON> D'Ambrosia </PERSON> is one of two people he consults for advice about his work. `` Through her I have been able to grow as an actor and I really attribute my success to her teachings,'' <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> said. `` Coming here and testifying on her behalf is my way of giving back a little of what she has done for me.'' Joining <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON> in his defense of <PERSON> D'Ambrosia </PERSON> was actress <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Waltz </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Nora </PERSON> in the movie `` <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> Beach Memoirs.'' <PERSON> Waltz </PERSON> also studied with <PERSON> D'Ambrosia </PERSON> while the instructor was at <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mellon </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two young instrumentalists were wealthier to the tune of $ 4,000 today as recipients of the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Segal </PERSON> Award, named for the former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> board. `` They are our hope for the future, and also for civilization,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Weissman </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday in presenting $ 4,000 awards to trumpeter <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, 21, a sophomore at the <ORGANIZATION> Juilliard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Wellington </PERSON>, 29, bassist, performing with the New York Philharmonic. The award was announced in 1986 when <PERSON> Segal </PERSON> retired as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> board. Money to help further careers of young artists connected in some way with <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> was donated by the board and <PERSON> Segal </PERSON>'s friends. The first recipients of the award were filmmaker <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, whose work has been presented by the <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Notare </PERSON>, soprano in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>'s national touring company They received the award last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--DirtyShorts     04-28 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Dirty Shorts,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Measures Germany's Personal Habits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DUESSELDORF, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Germans have a reputation for tidiness, but a study found most West German men do n't change their underwear every day. Only 45 percent of West German men and 70 percent of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> women change their underwear daily, professor <PERSON> Reinhold </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergler </PERSON>, who conducted the study, was quoted as saying in newspapers on Wednesday. <PERSON> Bergler </PERSON>'s survey indicated that 56 percent of French men and 94 percent of <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> women change their underwear daily. The Spanish were rated even better at 59 percent for men and 96 percent for women, the newspapers said. <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s daily <ORGANIZATION> Abendpost </ORGANIZATION> newspaper ran a front-page story on the study under the headline: `` Are German Men Pigs?'' <PERSON> Bergler </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Bonn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor, was quoted as saying he was surprised by the poll because Germans are brought up to live in clean surroundings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0230EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Peru-Violence     04-28 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Peru-Violence,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Rebel Measures Prolonged In Peru</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> prolonged a state of emergency in an isolated mining region where Maoist guerrilla attacks are common. In a decree signed by <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> and published in the official gazette <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peruano </LOCATION> on Wednesday, the anti-guerrilla measures were extended for 20 days in <LOCATION> Castrovierreyna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, a mining zone 150 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. The county covers a third of <LOCATION> Huancavelica </LOCATION> state, which adjoins <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> state, where the Mao-inspired <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla group eight years ago began an insurgency aimed at toppling <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s elected government The violence quickly spread to <LOCATION> Huancavelica </LOCATION>, one of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s most impoverished and isolated regions and later engulfed other highland zones. States of emergency, which limit civil rights, are now in affect in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> and parts of six other states where more than half <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s population lives
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Hollywood     04-28 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Hollywood,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Costs Pegged At $6.8 Million For Four Hollywood Unions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four Hollywood unions spent $ 6.8 million on treatment for 138 AIDS patients by early this year, but a representative of producers and studios says the problem is no worse than in other industries. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Counter </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Producers </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday he was sure that the figures from union health insurance funds were `` understated'' because some AIDS insurance claims may be reported as related diseases rather than AIDS. Counter's remarks represent the first time anyone has attempted to compile statistics on the number of AIDS patients whose care is being paid by health insurance funds serving the entertainment industry's five major unions. But he dismissed fears that AIDS can be spread by casual contact, including on movie and television filming sets, and said he was convinced the deadly disease, which cripples the body's immune system, can not be spread by so-called `` deep kissing'' by actors and actresses `` I do n't see that this problem is any worse or any less in our industry than in all industries,'' <PERSON> Counter </PERSON> said at a conference titled `` Managing AIDS at Work.'' He urged entertainment unions and companies to `` wage war on this disease on four fronts'' _ education, prevention, research and care. The insurer providing coverage for one of the industry's five funds _ the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AFTRA </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- Health and Retirement Funds _ refused to provide statistics on the number of its 22,000 members who have AIDS or the cost of their care, said alliance government affairs specialist <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, who compiled the statistics for Counter. The 138 patients reported by mid-February and the $ 6,821,000 cost of caring for them represent statistics reported by insurance funds for the other four major <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> union health funds, <PERSON> Counter </PERSON> said. Scientists say acquired immune deficiency syndrome is spread by intimate sexual contact, the sharing of needles by intravenous drug abusers and when passed from mothers to their unborn children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Malaysia-Caning     04-28 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Malaysia-Caning,0077</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teachers Want To Cane Naughty Schoolgirls In Malaysia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A survey of teachers indicates most think they should be allowed to beat mischievous schoolgirls with canes. Under Malaysian education laws only male schoolchildren can be caned. The Education Ministry's survey of 108 teachers at girls-only and coeducational schools showed 64 percent want permission to cane girls. The ministry made no decision on whether to amend the law.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Superconductivity     04-28 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superconductivity,0566</SECOND>
<BYLINE>New Class of Superconducting Material Enters High-Temperature Race
^By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new, high-temperature record for superconductivity in materials that lack copper has raised hopes that such substances may one day make superconductivity practical, scientists reported today. A mix of potassium, barium, bismuth and oxygen showed evidence of superconductivity at about minus 406 degrees Fahrenheit, researchers from <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> reported in the British journal Nature. That temperature essentially equals the 1986 mark that focused world attention on superconductivity. But it is well behind the current record for materials that contain copper, the chief focus of superconductivity research. Superconductivity is the ability of some materials to conduct electricity without resistance. Improved superconductors could lead to powerful computers, high-speed `` floating'' trains and other advances, scientists say. So far, all known materials must be `` supercooled'' to superconduct, and that limits their use. So scientists are trying to find superconductors that work at higher temperatures, even room temperature. Since the 1986 report of superconductivity at about minus 406 degrees, researchers have used copper compounds to superconduct at minus 243 degrees. The performance by a copper-free compound indicates `` a whole new ballfield'' for study, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleury </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION>. Still higher temperatures for copper-free compounds may yet be attained, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Laudise </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labs </ORGANIZATION>. The work shows copper can be replaced, and by a broader list of potential ingredients than many theories would have predicted, <PERSON> Laudise </PERSON> said. `` With so many possibilities, the chances of getting something that will have all the desirable properties in one material will be enlarged,'' he said. Those properties include ease of fabrication into wires and other devices and the ability to retain superconductivity while exposed to high currents or high magnetic fields, he said. The material's atomic structure suggests it may have one practical advantage over other known superconductors, <PERSON> Laudise </PERSON> said. Copper-based superconductors work best when the electrical current runs parallel to their stacked layers of copper and oxygen atoms. But the new material has no such layers. Instead, bismuth and oxygen atoms form interconnected sheets that extend along all three dimensions. That suggests that it may carry current equally well in all three dimensions, which could simplify making superconducting wires and other products, <PERSON> Laudise </PERSON> said. Studies of the earlier compounds had concluded that the copper-oxygen layers were essential for their superconductivity. The new material shows those layers are not always needed, although the temperature in copper-free compounds may go higher if researchers can create bismuth-oxygen layers, said <PERSON> Fleury </PERSON>. The finding `` is likely to give us a much better insight into the nature of high-temperature superconductivity'' than would emerge from studying just the materials with copper, he said. The Bell researchers were led by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cava </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bertram </PERSON> <PERSON> Batlogg </PERSON>. Other superconductivity experts said the report's importance will depend on whether copper-free materials can perform as well as previous superconductors. The more ingredients that can be used, the better the chance of finding a room-temperature superconductor, said physics professor <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is a first step, and a good one,'' he said. `` Once again, it just tells me we've just seen the tip of the iceberg'' for superconducting materials, said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Maple </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-28 0908</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Says It Will Rewrite Sugar Cane Rules Under Court Order</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plans to act quickly on a federal judge's order to rewrite its rules excluding sugar cane as a perishable commodity. Rewriting the rules could open the way for thousands of foreign field workers to become legal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents, an avenue barred to them if <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s original definition of sugar cane as a non-perishable crop were allowed to stand. Department officials said Wednesday the court's decision was under review and modified regulations could be expedited, although they declined to give a timetable. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, in a ruling released Tuesday, said the department `` arbitrarily and capriciously excluded'' sugar cane from the perishables list and to `` conduct further proceedings'' to determine the crop's status. The decision resulted from a lawsuit filed on behalf of sugar cane workers. Under the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> a year ago defined fruits, vegetables and other perishable commodities which are produced as a result of seasonal field work. The law's Special Agricultural Worker, or SAW, program allowed temporary legal resident status for foreign workers who formerly helped in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production of designated perishable crops. The law also provided avenues for alien workers to become <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens. By the department's definition, those crops not only included fruit and vegetables, but also wheat, sugar beets and a number of other commodities. Sugar cane was excluded from the list of perishables. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> French </PERSON>, the department's chief labor specialist in the development of the regulations, had relied on a telephone call to a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economist to determine the category of sugar cane as a crop `` despite the extensive written record'' on the matter. `` Based on this conversation and his own personal knowledge regarding the harvesting and labor practices in the sugar cane industry, Mr. French concluded that sugar cane was outside the scope of perishable commodities,'' <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> said. The agency, he added, rejected the impact of weather condition on crops because of the difficulty in measuring the impact or `` the overinclusive nature of such a criterion.'' French has been a special assistant for labor in <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> since Jan. 12, 1987, and had held previous posts in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, and as a labor relations consultant with <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. Although he declined to predict just when <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> would make the changes to comply with the court decision, French said, `` We're not going to drag our feet on this.'' The sugar cane revision could be handled internally by the department or could involve a public hearing, he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal quarantine restrictions to prevent the further spread of tiny bee mites have been reduced in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. However, the tiny killer mites _ <LOCATION> Varroa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jacobsoni </LOCATION> _ still remain a potential threat to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bee industry, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. All or parts of 13 states remain under federal quarantine restrictions. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said the revision for <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> retains `` only that portion of each state that must be quarantined to keep the <LOCATION> Varroa </LOCATION> mite from spreading.'' <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said the statewide quarantine in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> was reduced to parts of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON> counties, while the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> quarantine area was reduced to part of <LOCATION> Klickitat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Varroa mites were discovered in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last September in a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> apiary. Since then, they have been found in 12 other states: <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The original federal quarantine was effective on April 6 and restricted the interstate movement of bees and bee equipment from all 13 states. <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said the change in the original quarantine was partly because both <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> are enforcing restrictions on the movement of bees and bee equipment within their own borders. The mite is an external parasite of adult bees and their developing larvae, or brood. It causes decreased brood, deformed bees and a weakening of the colony's ability to pollinate plants and produce honey. Infestation can occur so gradually that the mites may not be noticed until severe damage is done.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says a highly contagious viral disease of poultry and other fowl has been found in pet birds in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. No domestic poultry has been involved in the outbreak, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON>, administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday. But laboratory tests confirmed exotic Newcastle disease in a three-week-old spectacled <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> parrot and in a young yellow-naped parrot owned by private individuals, he said. The birds and a number of others that were exposed to the infected birds were destroyed to prevent the spread of the disease. <PERSON> Glosser </PERSON> said the birds' premises in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloomfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, were placed under state quarantines. Federal and state authorities are tracing the disease to determine if additional birds or premises may have been exposed. Exotic Newcastle disease can cause death rates of 50 percent to 95 percent in poultry flocks. Officials say the disease poses no risk to humans who eat poultry or eggs, but in some cases people who handle infected birds can contract the virus, which in humans causes temporary eye inflammation and `` mild flu-like symptoms.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LiberaceTrial     04-28 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Liberace Trial,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nurse: Liberace Gravely Ill On Day Signed Final Will</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT MACY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> could barely carry on a conversation in the two weeks before he died and was gravely ill the day he signed his revised will, a nurse who cared for the glitzy entertainer testified Wednesday. The pianist could n't even find his way back to bed from the bathroom on the day of the signing, nurse <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Garber </PERSON> said at a hearing on a request by associates of <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>'s to remove <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> as executor of his estate. The testimony contradicted that of <LOCATION> Strote </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>'s attorney, who said that <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> sat at a table Jan. 22, 1987 talking with him and going over the estate papers before signing them. The papers named Strote executor. `` He'd say yes to anything to please -LRB- at that point -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON>. `` He just wanted to please anyone and be left alone.'' <PERSON> Gerber </PERSON> said she cared for <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> from the day he signed the will until he died of AIDS 13 days later, on Feb. 5, 1987. <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> could not put on his glasses or hold a book during his dying days at his <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> home, she said. `` He could n't have a conversation, he was too sick. The motor coordination was going so he'd have difficulty speaking,'' she said. `` He was so childlike he did n't know what he was saying.'' The five seeking to have <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> removed _ <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON>'s sister, his former manager, two housekeepers and a longtime friend _ were given a total of $ 1 million in the will, the terms of which were made public Wednesday. Testimony indicated three of the five received more in the deathbed will Strote drew up than in a will <ORGANIZATION> Liberace </ORGANIZATION> executed in 1982. <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> also left $ 50,000 in trust to take care of his seven dogs, which he often referred to as his `` babies.'' Strote has estimated the value of the estate at $ 11 million. His manager of 37 years, <PERSON> Seymoour </PERSON> <PERSON> Heller </PERSON>, has estimated the figure at $ 20 million. Strote on Tuesday defended the signing of the new will and two trusts. He said he had <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> examined by a doctor first, and the doctor was convinced <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> was `` in good condition and could understand'' the documents. `` I wanted to make sure he was physically able to go through the documents and understand them,'' <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> said <PERSON> Liberace </PERSON> signed the will and two trusts, but balked at a fourth document, a living will that would allow doctors to remove life support systems if they became necessary. `` He said ` I just ca n't sign this,''' <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> recalled. <PERSON> Strote </PERSON> said he felt he had to move quickly in tying down the entertainer's assets and cutting expenditures, which he said were running $ 100,000 to $ 200,000 a month, more than the estate was generating. `` I wanted to liquidate the property while his image and likeness were fresh in the minds of the buying public,'' Strote testified. An auction of Liberace memorabilia in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> earlier this month netted some $ 2 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Low-IncomeHousing     04-28 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Low-Income Housing,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Warns Against Dwindling Supply Of Housing For Poor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Privately owned housing for the poor could almost disappear within 15 years as owners default on mortgage payments or convert property to high-rent apartments and condominiums, a bipartisan commission says. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Low-Income </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday in a report to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> housing subcommittees that the cheapest way to ensure the poor have housing is to preserve and even fix up the current housing stock. It suggested that the federal government earmark $ 11.3 billion over the next 15 years to keep owners from converting the housing and to help owners who are having trouble making mortgage payments. An additional $ 6.4 billion should go toward continuing federal subsidies, the commission said. It also recommended an office should be set up within the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> to deal only with the issue. `` Everyone talks about the homeless as the tip of the iceberg,'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Parke </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>, executive director of the commission. `` We have described the iceberg. We are going to have a new generation of the homeless.'' <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said 70 percent of the people living in the subsidized housing have incomes below 50 percent of the median for their area. `` These are very poor people,'' she said. If the stock of privately owned subsidized housing should dry up, the poor may have no other housing options, she said Much of this country's low-income housing was built in the 1960s and early 1970s. Some of it is federally owned, some state-owned. The commission, in the report called `` Preventing the Disappearance of Low-Income Housing,'' discusses only privately owned properties subsidized by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> with mortgages insured by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. That amounts to about 645,000 units. The commission argues that without federal action, owners of 43 percent _ or 280,000 units _ will default and an additional 38 percent _ 243,000 units _ will prepay their mortgages in the next 15 years. <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON>, along with an <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said the federal government in the past has had to deal with scattered cases of defaults. Both <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Denery </PERSON> said that there also have been numerous instances of prepayments of mortgages by owners who want to free their properties from <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> restrictions and rent or sell to higher-income people. <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said the prepayment problem has been especially prevalent in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. But the commission concludes that both the prepayments and defaults will accelerate in the next decade as federal rent subsidy contracts expire. Also accelerating the trend is the new federal income tax law, which removed many of the tax incentives for investing in such housing. `` Everyone dealing with the project was surprised at the projected level of default,'' <PERSON> Gallagher </PERSON> said. `` Add that together with the prepayments and we see the number of units of low-income housing going steadily downward.'' <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, who is assistant secretary for housing and federal housing commissioner, said he supports the commission's basic premise _ that it is better to preserve existing housing for the poor rather than build new housing. He also complimented the commission for trying to look at lower-cost solutions to the problem, although he suggested that there may be even less expensive ways. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> said he opposes the commission's recommendation that a separate office to set up inside <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> to deal with preserving the privately owned low-income housing. `` I've had people specializing in this for a year and a half,'' he said. `` The issue also has the focus and attention of an assistant secretary.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Presidents Bjt   04-28 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Presidents, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan Dwelling on Past Presidents</HEAD>
<HEAD>By W. DALE NELSON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As he comes closer and closer to being a former president, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s thoughts seem to be turning to the men who have held the nation's highest office before him. In recent speeches, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has invoked the memory of <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> to make serious or humorous points, or both. All presidents refer to their predecessors from time to time, either favorably or not. By custom, each president gets to pick the pictures of former presidents that hang in the Cabinet Room. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, for instance, replaced <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> with <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON>. Now the president, who leaves office next Jan. 20, is quoting the wit and wisdom of presidents past, recalling how they dealt with the press and with their cabinets. On March 22, addressing Republican local officials at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> related a story that he said <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> told when he found all but one of his Cabinet officers were against him on an issue. The story was about a man who fell asleep during a revival meeting just before the minister said, `` All of you who are on the side of the Lord, stand up.'' As the man slept on, the minister intoned, `` All of you who are on the side of the devil, stand up.'' At that point the sleeper awoke, stood up and said, `` I did n't exactly understand the question, parson, but I'll stand by you to the end It does seem we're in a hopeless minority.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went on to tell the Republicans that they might be in a minority among city officials who claim the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> has shorted them, but their views are `` the majority beliefs in this <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' On March 30, presiding at the swearing-in of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> as secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told one about <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>. <PERSON> T.R. </PERSON>, he said, once told Saint <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>: `` Your choir is weak, inexcusably weak. You should reorganize it at once.'' Saint <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> says, `` All right,'' and gives T.R. the job. `` Well,'' said <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON>, `` I'll need 10,000 sopranos, 10,000 altos, and 10,000 tenors.'' `` But what about the basses?'' asked Saint <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>. `` Do n't worry about that,'' said T.R. `` I ` ll sing bass.'' Like Roosevelt, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>'s job now was to be `` a one-man bass section.'' On April 13, addressing the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Editors </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told stories about <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and their dealings with the press. `` Every morning before dawn, <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> would hike down to the <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION>, strip off his clothes, and swim,'' he said. `` And one summer day, a woman of the press, under orders from her editor, followed him. And after he'd plunged into the water, she popped from the bushes, sat on his clothes, and demanded an interview. And she told him that if he tried to wade ashore, she'd scream. So <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> hld the first press conference up to his neck in water. `` I know how he felt.'' Of <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, he said that once when <ORGANIZATION> LBJ </ORGANIZATION> was coming off the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor while he was vice president, he grabbed a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and shouted, `` You! I've been looking for you.'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> pulled the reporter into his office, started haranguing him and then, about halfway through, scribbled a note, buzzed his secretary, and gave it to her. The secretary returned with another note, which <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> glanced at and threw away. When the reporter finally got away, he saw <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s note lying on a desk. It said, `` Who is this guy I'm talking to anyway?
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArcticOil     04-28 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arctic Oil,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bill To Permit Drilling On Refuge Clears Subcommittee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Advocates of petroleum development in the nation's biggest wildlife refuge are gaining ground in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> but say they are fighting the clock to get their drilling bill enacted this year. Led by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and the oil industry, the advocates won another round against environmental groups on Wednesday as legislation to allow oil rigs into the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refuge </ORGANIZATION> was endorsed by the first House panel to vote on the issue. The bill was approved 17-9 by the <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on fisheries and wildlife conservation and the environment, setting the stage for expected approval next week by the full committee. Earlier this year, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted 11-8 for legislation to allow development of the potentially extensive oil deposits in the coastal plain of the 19 million-acre reserve in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The bill is awaiting floor debate. The issue has provoked a major struggle in the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> between environmentalists, who want no drilling in the refuge, and those who say the refuge offers the best chance to counter a growing national dependence on imported petroleum. An <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> study says development can be carried out in an environmentally sound manner and could produce oil to rival the <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> complex about 70 miles to the west. <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> accounts for about 20 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production. Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, one of the major <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> champions of drilling in the refuge, said Wednesday that time is growing short. Young quoted House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, as saying that because of a crowded calendar and time off for political conventions and reelection campaigns, a drilling bill needs to get to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor by mid-June to ensure approval by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> also has jurisdiction over the issue. Its chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., is sponsoring legislation to declare the refuge permanently off-limits to petroleum development The Interior water and power resources subcommittee is not planning to hold hearings on refuge legislation until early June. In the past, the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has been more sympathetic to environmentalist positions than many other House panels. The <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee approved a plan drafted by Rep. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, to allow phased oil leasing over a decade but bar development in a 260,000-acre are used for calving by a migratory caribou herd. Drilling in the refuge would be exempt from the Refuge Administration Act of 1966's requirement that development be compatible with a refuge's basic purpose of preserving wildlife habitat. That law requires developers to prove compatibility, a difficult task. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' bill, however, would force opponents of developing the coastal plain to prove that such activity would have significant and adverse long-term effects on habitat, also seen by subcommittee lawyers as a difficult task. The bill would prohibit export of any petroleum extracted from the 1.5 million acre coastal plain and would require any ocean transport of this oil to be done on ships registered in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The legislation also would create a new 23.5 million-acre Teshekpuk-Utukok National Wildlife Refuge to the west of <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and place a five-year moratorium on any petroleum leasing in the new refuge. Drilling foes repeatedly failed in attempts to amend the bill. Rejected proposals included variations on the theme of putting off a decision on the coastal plain until completion of a national energy policy study emphasizing conservation and renewables.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-OhioPrimary     04-28 0327</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ohio Primary,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Early Senate Race, Two House Frays Draw Attention In Ohio</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT E. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> are off on one of the earliest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaigns <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> has seen in years, with both sides looking beyond Tuesday's primary to November. Most of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s incumbent congressmen are getting a free ride in their primaries, but a hot race is on for the seat of retiring GOP Rep. <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, and one incumbent Democrat has a well-known challenger. <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON> has no opposition in the Republican primary, and <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, a two-term Democrat, is opposed by <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON>, a political newcomer from <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> who has hardly been heard from since filing in February. <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, who early on admited that <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> had the edge in name recognition, already has spent more than $ 1 million, much of it on media ads. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>'s campaign manager, said the senator's roughly $ 840,000 in spending this year was proof <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> does n't intend to `` let the mayor go unanswered <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>'s district seat, in rural <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> where Democrats seldom win anything, has drawn the incumbent's son, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, a Bowling Green attorney, into a primary race against <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>, of <PERSON> Port </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> <PERSON> Damschroder </PERSON>, of Fremont. <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> is known statewide after 21 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and an unsuccessful bid for governor two years ago. The younger <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, a candidate in his father's conservative image, has accused <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> of being too liberal for the district's voters <PERSON> Damschroder </PERSON> has raised far less money than either of his better known opponents. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, Rep. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakar </PERSON>, who seeks her sixth term, is pitted in the Democratic primary against <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kucinich </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> mayor who has attracted large numbers of blue-collar votes in the past. <PERSON> Kucinich </PERSON> is relying on name recognition to help him in the campaign against the popular Ms. <PERSON> Oakar </PERSON> in the heavily <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> district.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Canada Bjt   04-28 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Canada, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canadian Leader Gets Nothing From Reagan on Acid Rain</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: prenoon EDT top planned; morning meetings with Bush, Byrd and
at Canadian embassy.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Canadian Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> seeking more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> action to reduce the acid rain that he likens to `` dumping garbage'' on his country, but he got no promises from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. During a one-hour meeting on Wednesday, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> held to the administration's 7-year-old position that more research is needed before targets are set for reducing the pollution blamed for acid rain. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> had used the meeting and a subsequent speech to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to renew Canadian pleas that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> follow his country's lead by setting specific pollution-reduction targets and timetables. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s program will cut pollution levels there to half the 1980 levels by 1994, <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` But that is only half the solution, because the other half of our acid rain comes across the border, directly from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, falling upon our forests, killing our lakes, soiling our cities,'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has rebuffed pleas from Northeastern states as well as <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> to set targets and timetables, calling instead for more scientific investigation to establish the most effective cleanup methods before spending money on acid rain reduction. A senior <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said that <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> gave <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` some private ideas'' on how they might narrow their differences on the issue. The talks, however, did not alter the administration view that there is little possibility an acid rain accord sought by <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> will be reached before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves office next January, the official said. Prior to his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> visit, <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> acid-rain emissions drifting into his country are tantamount to `` dumping garbage'' on <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. Using more elegant language in his speech to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, he said, in effect, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is doing the same to its own environment. `` The one thing acid rain does not do is discriminate,'' he said. `` It is despoiling your environment as inexorably as ours. It is damaging your environment from <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and threatens marine life on the <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seabord </LOCATION>.'' He welcomed additional research into ways to reduce emissions from coal-fired furnaces, but said more action is needed. `` <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> will continue to press fully its case to rid our common environment of this blight, and we shall perservere until our skies regain their purity and our rains recover the gentleness that gives life to our forests and streams. And we hope the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and people will respond exactly the same way,'' he said. `` The cost of reducing acid rain is substantial, but the cost of inaction is greater still,'' he added. While the leaders remained apart on the acid rain issue, they joined in an appeal to both nations' legislatures to ratify the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement, designed to abolish tariffs and further enrich what is already the world's biggest trading partnership. <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> noted that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sells more goods in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> than it does to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> combined. `` This is a good, balanced and fair agreement, the most important ever concluded between two trading partners,'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> also said they do not believe the pact will be endangered by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s threatened veto of a trade bill being considered in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, the official reporting on their meeting said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also gave his permission for the Canadian purchase of tightly-held <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear submarine technology. The Canadians are considering the purchase of 10 or 12 nuclear-powered attack submarines from <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. If they choose the British `` Trafalgar'' class subs, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> permission will be required because the submarines use American power plants. An amendment to current U.S.-Canadian agreements would also be required and thorough <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> discussion of the issue is likely. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said `` the president's decision to transfer classified technology must rest on national security interests, not political considerations.'' He said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will explore the issue `` extensively.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> set aside their differences over acid rain and accentuated the positive at a White House state dinner Wednesday evening. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> lauded his Canadian counterpart as `` a good neighbor and a firm friend,'' and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> reciprocated by calling <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` honest and wise.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-28 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0631</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a spray of rhetoric, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> exterminated a bill that would have made the praying mantis <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s official insect. There was little alternative when Rep. <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Aydlette </PERSON> strode to the podium with his tongue firmly in cheek and suggested a down-home alternative: the cockroach. <PERSON> Aydlette </PERSON> noted that the state already had plenty of symbols: among them a state bird -LRB- <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> wren -RRB-, a state flower -LRB- yellow jessamine -RRB-, a state dance -LRB- the shag -RRB-, a state fruit -LRB- peach -RRB- and a state dog -LRB- <PERSON> Boykin </PERSON> spaniel -RRB-. `` I do n't think we need to name anything else, but if you are so inclined and insistent on naming a bug, I submit to your approval ... the cockroach of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, or the palmetto bug,'' <PERSON> Aydlette </PERSON> said, drawing belly laughs from his colleagues. `` This thing's been around <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> for 50 or 60 billion years and has n't changed. Insecticides do n't do much to it. They race these things every year at the College of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. They do fly in formation at night. And we have heard tales of them hauling off small animals,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Charleston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> said he preferred just defeating the proposal, but insisted on his choice of insect if the discussion continued. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> decided to drop the subject of state symbols altogether.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NENANA, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ah spring! For most of the nation, it's a time of fragrant flowers and verdant renewal. In <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, it's when the ice breaks. So momentous is the event that since 1917 <LOCATION> Nenana </LOCATION> has held its Ice Classic, an opportunity for area residents to predict the exact moment of the ice break-up on the <LOCATION> Tanana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. This year, three <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> residents shared the $ 130,000 prize for being the only ones out of 146,300 entries to correctly guess when the 3-to-4-foot-thick ice would begin flowing down the river: 10:15 a.m. Wednesday. `` It kind of took everyone by surprise,'' said <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, contest manager. `` It's the first time the ice has ever gone out on April 27.'' The prize was split among <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicoll </PERSON>, a construction worker, <PERSON> Mac </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 43, an accountant, and his 62-year-old brother, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, a retired postal worker who lives in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The brothers have been buying Ice Classic tickets for about 20 years. `` It's a real suprise to us, because the ice was 46 inches thick, about 7 to 9 inches above normal,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. `` But we've had a very warm spring, temperatures overnight have been around 42 degrees You can see the base logs of the tripod now. They were buried 21 inches into the ice.'' Last year the ice went out May 5 at 3:11 p.m. The $ 155,000 prize was split among 19 people.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Identical twins <PERSON> Charlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Reavis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Darlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>, were sharing a room again, just as they did when they were children 22 years ago. But this time it was a hospital room, where the <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> sisters were both cuddling newborn infants. <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Reavis </PERSON> was born Saturday and his cousin, <PERSON> Tara </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooke </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>, was born Monday. Both babies were delivered at St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where their mothers shared a recovery room `` We're used to sharing a room,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` This is just like being at home _ fighting over the TV and sharing the bathroom. `` After <PERSON> Charlene </PERSON> had her baby on the 23rd, I just called up the hospital and told them to reserve the next bed for me.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reavis </PERSON> noted that the coincidence was n't quite complete. `` She broke our chain,'' she said, pointing to her twin. `` She had a girl.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0400EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Contra-Divisions     04-28 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contra-Divisions,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Split as Talks Start</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA </BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nicaraguan rebel leaders headed into talks today with their negotiating position weakened by a split between military and political chieftains, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other sources. The Contra chain of command remains intact only because an attempt by veteran rebel leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> to oust military commander <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> a week ago was unsuccessful, the sources said. The dispute between <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> has been simmering for years and came to a head following the temporary truce signed last month by the rebels and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said that at a meeting last week in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, the five <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> directors split 2-2 with one abstention on a proposal for <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>'s removal. Another source said he was not aware a formal vote had been taken. <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> ostensibly takes orders from the five-member civilian directorate but believes he should have more influence over the decision-making process, according to the sources. <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> has maintained that civilian control over the movement is essential and sees <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> as a threat to that objective. According to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, it would be a mistake to have ousted <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> because `` he is the glue which holds the movement together.'' With <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> gone, the official said, the Contras would splinter and cease to be a credible fighting force. The sources, all of whom insisted on anonymity, said the mistrust among the Contra leaders is expected to weaken their negotiating position at this week's talks in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. Although <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> has expressed support publicly for the peace process, the sources said he believes the agreement signed a month ago put the rebel fighters at a severe disadvantage. The Sandinista government and the Contras agreed to a 60-day cease-fire and to try to negotiate a permanent settlement. Thus far, the two sides have agreed on the location of seven cease-fire zones to which the Contras would transfer once ground rules for activities in these areas were spelled out. But as today's talks were getting under way, this remained a key area of disagreement and the Contras have yet to resettle in the designated zones. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> Secretary General <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON> has written to Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that he believes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food shipments to Contra rebels based in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> are illegal. <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON> is a member of the commission assigned to verify compliance with the temporary truce. The dispute involves $ 47.9 million in humanitarian assistance approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> four weeks ago after the Contras and the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> signed their agreement. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> was assigned the task of managing the aid program and has sent 125.6 metric tons of food by truck to Contra camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> starting last week. Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last Friday of concealing weapons and ammunition in the shipments. AID denied that allegation, asserting the trucks were inspected and found to be free of lethal equipment by members of the Honduran clergy before the trucks departed the Honduran capital of <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>. The Sandinista government insists that inspections can be carried out only by the verification commission. In his letter to <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Baena </PERSON> <PERSON> Soares </PERSON> said he believes the shipments `` do not fall within the provision of the instruments which regulate the deliveries of humanitarian assistance.'' An AID official, speaking Wednesday only on condition of anonymity, said there was nothing in last month's agreement or the aid legislation which would preclude delivery of assistance to rebels in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. The administration also has been worried about signs of increasing hunger among the thousands of rebel fighters. Many have crossed into <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> in recent weeks in search of food.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0402EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending     04-28 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arms Control Restrictions Figure In Pentagon Budget Battle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Democrats say they are are pushing for arms control restrictions opposed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as `` a way of keeping the lid on the nuclear arms race.'' But Republicans such as Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Broomfield </PERSON>, R-Mich., argue that the restrictions `` have long been overtaken by events. The fight is over Democratic-backed proposals which are being considered as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> debates and votes on the annual bill authorizing the Pentagon budget. The restriction have been added for the past three years by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and while some were later dropped during the lengthy congressional budget process, several remained. `` We're pushing these things because we need to keep the pressure on, keep pushing the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON>, D-Wash., said the restrictions `` are a way of keeping the lid on the nuclear arms race. On Wednesday, the House:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ Voted, 252-159, to ban any tests of Star Wars anti-missile defense systems which would violate the `` narrow'' interpretation of the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile treaty _ Voted, 240-174, for a ban on spending for any weapons that would violate the numerical restrictions on various types of atomic weapons that are contained in the 1979 SALT II treaty President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says the Soviets are violating the unratified treaty and he wo n't be guided any longer by its restrictions. The House is also likely to approve restrictions on testing of anti-satellite weapons and ban all but the smallest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear tests, <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> noted. Both amendments were also approved last year. Legislators on both sides noted that the amendments are virtually the same as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has considered in past debates over the Pentagon bill. `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is committed to arms control and he has proved it, convincingly, and everybody has to acknowledge that,'' said <PERSON> Broomfield </PERSON>. He referred to the treaty signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> Dec. 8 which eliminates medium-range nuclear missiles, and to negotiations aimed at achieving a more far-reaching pact calling for deep reductions in long-range atomic weapons. Referring to Democratic critics of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Broomfield </PERSON> said: `` Many of these true believers have been unable to recognize these new realities ... Some of these amendments are three years old. It's time to put them out of their misery. But <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> noted that `` the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is a partisan body and there are a lot of people here who feel very strongly about these issues.'' He suggested that the restrictions have had an impact. `` For example, I think we would have violated the SALT II limits by much more than we have without the pressure from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said 18 months ago that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would no longer be restricted by the SALT II limits. The restrictions were tacked onto a bill authorizing $ 299.5 billion in <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending for the fiscal year that begins Oct 1. The total is about the same as this year's defense budget and it resulted from last December's `` budget summit'' between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> which was designed to lower the federal budget deficit. The bill that passes the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will have to be reconciled with the separate measure which will be passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. That chamber is moving more slowly on the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget, which is now being written by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880428-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-28-88 0403EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FairHousing     04-28 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fair Housing,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strengthened Legislation Against Housing Discrimination Clears
Committee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
