<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0002EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Reagan-UN 3rdLd-Writethru a0795 09-27 1055</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan-UN, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0795,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Finds Cause for Hope That Regional Conflicts Are Ending</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Restores dropped material from pvs 1st Ld-Writethru, a0696</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in a farewell speech Monday that this was `` a moment of hope'' for peace in the world and that a new U.S.-Soviet treaty to sharply reduce nuclear arms may be concluded next year. He called for an international war on drug traffickers, terrorism and hostage-taking, and vowed to maintain <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for an armed insurgency against the leftist government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. He said the Sandinistas were pursuing `` the oldest, most corrupt vice of all _ man's age-old will to power, his lust to control the lives and steal the freedoms of others.'' But with his presidency nearing an end, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> struck a mostly philosophical stance as he told the 43rd <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> session of 159 nations that civil wars and foreign occupations were giving way around the world. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the trend was spurred by `` a new era in Soviet-American relations'' marked by the continuing withdrawal of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and a treaty last year to abolish intermediate-range nuclear missiles. He said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators were making steady progress on another accord to sharply reduce long-range bombers, missiles and submarines. While completion of the pact this year was `` highly doubtful,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` I can tell you a year from now -LRB- it -RRB- is a possibility, more than a possibility.'' On the conventional front, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said East-West talks to reduce non-nuclear forces, tanks and other mobile weapons in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> `` will begin soon.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had demanded a Soviet commitment to give equal attention to human rights. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> met last week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. Afterward, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said the Soviets had promised to release 27 additional political prisoners, to make changes in their emigration procedures and to undertake other reforms. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s statement indicated the human rights obstacle had been removed After the speech, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> met with Foreign Ministers <PERSON> Esmat </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel </PERSON> <PERSON> Meguid </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on prospects for peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Chatting with reporters during a picture-taking session, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he had `` high hopes'' for release of the nine American hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by pro-Iranian forces. `` But I'm superstitious about calling a no-hitter before the game is over,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. The former baseball broadcaster appeared to be referring to the progressive release of French and West German hostages _ and being reluctant to talk about it for fear of upsetting the situation. But <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said `` there is no morsel of information that gives us reason to be more hopeful.'' In the session with <PERSON> Meguid </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, the president called the 1979 peace treaty between their countries `` a monumental achievement which has changed the face of the region.'' He said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal was to move beyond it to an overall settlement that took into account the `` legitimate rights'' of Palestinian Arabs. According to <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> sources, who declined to be further identified, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said that his government would not deal with <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> ration Organization so long as they were involved in terrorism and violence and speak of trying to force <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> back to the partition lines set by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> in 1947. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, meanwhile, said despite elections in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in November the parties should keep working for negotiations since `` a vacuum is very dangerous.'' In other developments on a busy day in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>: _ Met twice with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> to assess prospects of ending the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war It was <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first meeting with <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> since the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s announcement on Sept. 13 that the president was releasing $ 188 million the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had withheld from the organization to show displeasure with <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> budgetary and hiring _ Scheduled a meeting with Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, the former ruler of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Oct. 11 The purpose is to underscore <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for his forces as they compete with the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> to take control of the country from pro-Vietnam authorities. _ Met with President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mugabe </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> to register <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resolve for successful completion of negotiations that simultaneously would withdraw Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> _ Met with leaders of <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> countries after deciding to end the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military convoy of U.S.-flagged <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> oil tankers <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials stressed American warships would remain in the gulf prepared to come to the aid of commercial ships under attack. The president's speech was the most upbeat of the seven speeches he has made before the world body. From <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, and in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> is trying to formalize a cease-fire to end the eight-year war between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, prospects for peace are bright, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said earlier Monday that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had decided to end the 14-month program of providing <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> escorts to re-flagged Kuwaiti oil tankers in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, but he still would maintain a naval presence there to aid threatened ships. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> acted `` after reviewing the current cease-fire ... which has been in effect since August 20, and consulting with allies and friends in the region.'' In his speech, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` I stand at this podium, then, in a moment of hope _ hope not just for the peoples of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but for all the peoples of the world.'' In arms control, he said, `` the logjam is broken'' by the ban on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet intermediate-range missiles, progress toward a Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty and the onset of negotiations between the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact on conventional forces. `` History teaches caution,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. But his speech was upbeat, and he traced the improvement in U.S.-Soviet relations to the first summit meeting he had held with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> nearly three years ago. `` So if future generations do say of us that, in our time, peace came closer, that we did bring about new seasons of truth and justice, it will be cause for pride,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--Snowbirds 1stLd-Writethru a0713 09-27 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Snowbirds, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0713,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Snowbirds Member Drunk In Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 4th graf to CORRECT spelling of colonel's name.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>RECTOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A member of the Canadian Snowbirds precision military flying team was drunk when he crashed his car and died on the day he was to perform at an air show, authorities said Monday. Capt. <PERSON> Wesley </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON>, 28, of <LOCATION> Camrose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alberta </LOCATION>, had an alcohol concentration of 0.191 percent in his blood, said <PERSON> Skip </PERSON> <PERSON> Rusciewicz </PERSON>, deputy coroner for <LOCATION> Westmoreland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> law recognizes 0.10 as the level of intoxication. The crash occurred on a private road around 1 a.m. Saturday, police said. The Snowbirds were to perform 14 hours later. The pilots are not allowed to consume alcohol within eight hours of a flight, said Col. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Thibault </PERSON>, commander of Canadian Forces Base in Moose Jaw. Two other team members were injured in the crash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FAA-McArtor     09-27 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-FAA-McArtor,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>FAA Chief Says Air Safety Improving</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Aviation safety is improving, and technology and training programs are now in place to prevent most major air disasters, the director of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Monday. `` I reject any notion from anybody that would assert that aviation safety is somehow declining,'' <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said during a visit to the <ORGANIZATION> Mike </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monroney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Near-collision reports are down 67 percent from last year; pilot errors are down 63 percent and controller errors are down 18 percent, <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said. Also down are aviation-related fatalities and delays, he said. `` Aviation safety is improving. That does not mean aviation safety can not continue to improve. We have a lot of work to do. But we should never be caught in the trap of assuming that accident rates reflect aviation safety,'' he said, explaining that as air travel increases, the number of accidents also would increase. Technological advancements in such things as radar, combined with improved pilot training programs have reduced the danger of wind shear to air travelers, <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said. `` Wind shear has been with us since the dawn of aviation. But just now, we have the technology and the training that can recognize these microburst conditions,'' he said. He referred to sudden shifts in wind direction and speed caused when a mass of cooled air rushes downward out of a thunderstorm, a condition that can especially endanger planes taking off and landing. Just last week, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> announced that airplanes themselves will now be required to carry equipment that can detect wind shear, and to display steering commands so pilots can escape the conditions, <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> said. In addition, he said all airlines are now training pilots in simulators to recognize conditions of wind shear and to escape from them safely. He said the 1985 crash of a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> that killed 137 people probably could have been prevented if such measures had been in place at the time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0249EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Cooperative     09-27 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Cooperative,0557</SECOND>
<HEAD>China's First Consumer Cooperative Formed In Beijing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A neighborhood trying to buck bureaucracy, middlemen and rising inflation has created <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first consumer food cooperative in 30 years. The Tiantan Residential Area Consumer Cooperative in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> opened in April and already has 9,000 members who paid 5 yuan -LRB- $ 1.30 -RRB- a share for access to fresh and sometimes cheaper vegetables, milk, eggs, matches, food oils and other consumer goods. `` Our only purpose is to serve the people,'' said the co-op's general manager, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingson </PERSON> It is run entirely by people living near the landmark Temple of Heaven in southern <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Consumer cooperatives existed in the early years after the Communist government came to power in 1949, but were taken over by the state in 1957, `` when our economy became more developed,'' <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said. The idea has been revived three decades later as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> goes through the painful process of ending price controls and letting the value of most food products be determined by market forces. Prices for many vegetables and other food items have doubled in the past year amid an overall inflation rate of around 20 percent. The reluctance of farmers to grow low-profit crops, difficulties in transport and widespread profiteering in scarce commodities have added to the price spiral, the most serious problem facing the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> economy today. The Tiantan Neighborhood <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> decided to start the co-op, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said, mainly to `` eliminate all kinds of troubles happening between producers and consumers.'' The cooperative has signed contracts with several farm villages outside <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for supply and delivery of cucumbers, milk, sesame oil and other items, which are stocked in some of the 40 shops now run by the cooperative. Most of the 100 people working for the cooperative are retired from regular jobs or unemployed, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Zhang </PERSON> <PERSON> Xuyuan </PERSON>, 69, said she came out of retirement to run a little corner shop that sells soft drinks, canned goods and fresh foods because `` I wanted something to do.'' Now, she says she works up to 12 hours a day and takes home a wage pegged to the shop's sales and averaging about 100 yuan -LRB- $ 27 -RRB- a month, on a par with a factory worker's salary. Shoppers, she said, are `` quite satisfied, they've got no quarrels'' with the cooperative products. <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said the little groceries barely break even, but the cooperative is earning good profits from several larger retail stores. He said shareholders should receive dividends larger than interest rates on bank savings deposits. He added that as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> switches to a commodity-based economy, the government permits consumers to have various shopping options. The co-op, he said, will be a `` little brother'' to state-owned food shops and will not hurt the free markets that now supply urban residents with much of their better-quality if more expensive food. Although elimination of middlemen will mean better prices for co-op members, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said, prices will generally be pegged to those in state stores but that holding the line on price rises will be tough. He expressed confidence, however, that the co-op could provide good service at reasonable prices, `` and make things a little easier for our residents.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Botha-10Years     09-27 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Botha-10 Years,0779</SECOND>
<HEAD>Enthusiasm Scarce As Botha Marks 10 Years In Power</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> completes 10 years in power Wednesday, pressing ahead with policies that have disenchanted blacks and whites across <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s political spectrum. Not interested in charming his way to popularity, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> has presented himself as a stern, dedicated patriot leading his country on a precarious path between outright racism and black majority rule. Lately, his balancing act has won little praise. Growing numbers of right-wing whites feel he has gone too far in extending power to blacks, while white liberals and a solid core of blacks believe he has fallen woefully short. The criticisms, and increasingly frequent calls for new leadership, sometimes rankle <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, but he is unapologetic. `` My attitude is that I am doing what I believe to be right and in the interests of the country,'' he recently told a television interviewer who sought an assessment of 10 turbulent years. In his early years in power, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> had a broad mandate from whites for his twin goals of maintaining stability while moving away from rigid apartheid. The Sunday Times, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s largest newspaper and a critic of the government, commented this month, `` Mr. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s place in history is assured. It required courage to lead his people out of the cul-de-sac of apartheid, even if the final destination of their new course remains uncharted.'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, 72, became head of the white-minority government on Sept. 28, 1978, when <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> members elected him prime minister over more moderate and more conservative rivals. He had been in the Cabinet since 1961 and became defense minister in 1966. His first speech as prime minister stressed a theme that remains dear to him _ the paramount importance of national security in the face of a purported communist-led `` total onslaught.'' A year later, in one of his most quoted remarks, he sounded a different theme, telling whites: `` We must adapt, otherwise we will die.'' In 1984, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> helped push through a new constitution that brought Asians and people of mixed race into the previously all-white <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, but continued to exclude blacks. One result was black anger that ignited two years of nationwide political violence. The constitution abolished the post of prime minister, and <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> became president. His critics say he has steadily increased the power of the executive branch since then while weakening <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Since 1984, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> has been credited with the repeal of several of apartheid's most hurtful laws, including those that banned interracial marriages and required blacks to have a permit to be in whites-only areas. These reforms, along with promises of limited power-sharing with blacks, triggered a wave of defections by <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s fellow Afrikaners from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to the extreme-right <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Botha </ORGANIZATION>'s anniversary comes as the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> verges on losing support of a majority of whites for the first time since it gained power 40 years ago. The party won 55 percent of the vote in whites-only general elections in May 1987, while 26 percent went to the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and 19 percent to liberal candidates. The Conservatives are believed to have gained strength since then and could outpoll the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in nationwide local elections Oct. 26. Many liberals believe <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> has gone as far as he is willing to go toward substantive reform. The president has declared that some aspects of apartheid are non-negotiable _ he rejects equal voting rights for blacks and insists that whites retain segregated neighborhoods and schools. `` We are forever told that President <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s government has chosen the path fo reform and should be given a chance,'' wrote black newspaper editor <PERSON> Khulu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sibiya </PERSON>. `` What chance, when they move one step forward and three backwards?'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, whose government has detained thousands of black activists during a 27-month-old state of emergency, says most blacks view him favorably. Opinion polls suggest otherwise. This month, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> held his first summit meetings in black <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. He visited <LOCATION> Malawi </LOCATION>, a longtime friend of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>, a longtime adversary. Some critics say <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> is more willing to take chances in the international arena than at home. `` One has to say that P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> lacks imagination,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Soal </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> member for the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` He has failed to deal creatively with black political aspirations.'' Even some of <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s own Cabinet ministers feel he should step down, said Soal. `` Is there someone with the guts to tell him?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0252EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Analysis     09-27 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Analysis,0714</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despot Ne Win May Still Be Calling The Shots In Burma</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ne Win, who resigned two months ago after 26 years of despotic rule, is widely believed to still be the top man in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> orchestrating moves to put down the anti-government uprising. Many Western diplomats and <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> believe <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON> has been calling the shots since he stepped down July 23 as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Burma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that has ruled the country for a quarter century. `` I would say the almost universal perception and opinion among Burmese is that Ne Win is still the government of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>,'' a Rangoon-based diplomat said. Ne Win, 77, has remained out of public sight since he resigned, and there is no indisputable evidence he remains the most powerful figure. But observers characterize the men who have led the government since he stepped down as long-time associates of Ne Win who dare not make any major move without his assent. Diplomats said military commander Gen. Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> visited Ne Win at his home in the plush northern <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> suburbs around scenic <LOCATION> Inya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> before launching a coup Sept. 18 that began a harsh crackdown on pro-democracy protesters. The Rangoon-based diplomat said `` a number of -LRB- other -RRB- meetings have been held at critical times'' between Ne Win and top officials. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, who became head of the party and state to succeed Ne Win in July, was a military leader known for his ruthlessness and long-time political association with Ne Win. When protests against <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>'s authoritarian rule increased in August, he was replaced by civilian <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who served as Ne Win's legal adviser and wrote a flattering book about him called `` <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> and General Ne Win.'' <PERSON> Tzang </PERSON> <PERSON> Yawnghwe </PERSON>, an author and son of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s first president, described <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> as `` one of the few Burmese intellectuals who sincerely and deeply admired Gen. Ne Win.'' <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> was removed from power by <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> when promises to hold the first multiparty elections since 1960 failed to end massive anti-government street demonstrations and a crippling general strike. <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, who was promoted to armed forces commander in 1985, is regarded as a hardliner who during most of his 39-year army career has loyally followed orders from Ne Win. Ne Win `` did n't raise up a generation of leaders but raised a generation of followers to do his bidding,'' a Bangkok-based diplomat observed. Another diplomat said the three successors are generally viewed as `` absolutely beholden'' to the charismatic Ne Win, whose unquestioned supremacy over the capable, well-organized 186,000-man military since his 1962 coup is seen as the key to his lasting power. The opposition so far has been unable to draw into its fold the rank-and-file soldiers and their officers, who in the past week shot and killed largely unarmed, peaceful demonstrators and broke up dozens of protest centers throughout the nation. `` What striking about it is the ruthlessness of his -LRB- Ne Win's -RRB- tactics,'' the Bangkok-based diplomat said. Japanese <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> expert <PERSON> Minoru </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiryu </PERSON> suggests, however, that events of recent weeks do not follow a `` Ne Win scenario,'' since the coup leaders abolished virtually all the state organizations built up by the military strongman. Ne Win first came to prominence as one of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s `` Thirty Comrades'' who played a key role in the fight for independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. He ended <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s shaky post-independence experiment with democracy by leading the 1962 coup. Ne Win quickly vowed to lead his country on a neutralist, egalitarian and moralistic `` Burmese road to socialism.'' But inefficiency, corruption and black marketeering soon spread throughout the system and <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, rich in natural resources and once the world's largest exporter of rice, is now one of the world's poorest nations The failure to oust Ne Win and his cronies despite the popular uprising has led to `` certainly a tremendous mood of depression and disillusionment in the country,'' the Rangoon-based diplomat said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Biers </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> news editor in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and is assisting in coverage of the <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> crisis.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0254EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-MoneyTalks Bjt   09-27 0621</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Money Talks, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Political Millions Dash Proxmire's Illusions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An illusion has been dashed for <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, who won his last <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> election in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> by shaking scores of thousands of hands and spending $ 145. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> since 1957, won that election in 1982 with 64 percent of the vote and without spending a dime on television commercials. But in the scramble to succeed him _ a scuffle that began when he announced earlier this year that he would not seek re-election _ a new reality of the American political process emerged. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> has found that money does in fact talk. The senator predicted the result earlier this year even before <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>'s voters picked free-spending millionaire businessman <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, who never has held public office, as the Democratic senatorial nominee over a list of veteran politicians. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> described to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> the way he had established a victorious and enduring political career by shaking hands and ringing doorbells. He also correctly described what can happen when all that hard work comes up against big money. `` Meet just as many voters as you can _ day after day, month after month, year after year,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said in a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> speech. `` The numbers are critical,'' he said. `` They add up. You can literally meet hundreds every day. By campaigning on main streets and shopping malls for seven or eight hours a day you can hit a couple of thousand. `` Go out to baseball and football games, state fairs, busy summer festivals ... and you can meet as many as a thousand an hour _ literally. `` Keep that up year after year and you build remarkable long-term support,'' he said. `` When you run statewide a few times ... an astonishing number remember you. Many of the hundred-thousand people you met in your 1952 campaign for governor still remember meeting you when they vote in 1982. `` With every election that passes you have more of those beautiful voters in the bank.'' It was a `` magic'' that never failed him. But it was not a road that <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, a relatively unknown face, chose to follow. According to <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> got his name recognition with money, not by meeting voters one after the other. `` All that magic can blow away like a puff of smoke in a hurricane when your opponent turns up with $ 2 million or $ 3 million to buy television time and the good judgment of the experts to tell him precisely how to build on it,'' he said. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s Republican opponent, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, minority leader of the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, also is mounting an extensive and expensive television campaign but is expected to be outspent by <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, who had pumped $ 4 million into his campaign by the end of August. <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said that as a result of <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s heavy spending in the Democratic primary campaign, `` the three Democratic candidates, qualified by years of service in public office and with long campaigning, were left far behind in the dust.'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>'s conclusion: `` Building constituent support one on one, serving well in public office, can help build a political career, but there is no substitute for money, and lots of it, wisely spent in buying the most seasoned and shrewd media advice and the television time to ring that bell. `` The candidate who has come from nowhere has been a smashing success in business,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said. `` He may, if elected, serve the country and our state as an excellent senator.'' `` But as a retiring senator who followed the other painstaking route of years of one-to-one hard campaigning work,'' <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> said, `` I am disillusioned _ and more than a little jealous.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-NukeFleetProtest     09-27 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuke Fleet Protest,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Battleship Nearly Sinks Yacht Carrying Anti-Nuke Protesters</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER O'LOUGHLIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The USS New Jersey nearly ran down a yacht carrying anti-nuclear demonstrators as the battleship maneuvered into <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> harbor today through a flotilla of yachts, canoes and surfboards. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s skipper, Capt. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, said his 57,000-ton battlewagon would probably have sunk the yacht had it had not been dragged clear at the last moment. `` If it had not been for that police boat pulling it off we'd have split it in half,'' <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> said `` The guy on that police boat was very brave.'' The police boat managed to secure the yacht and tow it clear seconds before the battleship steamed by. Other protesters in assorted small craft attempted to get alongside the ship and plaster it with anti-nuclear slogans, but were kept away by a cordon of police and Australian navy speed boats. Police and <ORGANIZATION> navy </ORGANIZATION> divers jumped into the water to arrest two protesters. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, 46, of <LOCATION> Bluefield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said demonstrators, some of them from the international environmental group <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION>, risked their lives coming so close to the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> because turbulence from the ship's four 18-foot propellors could have sucked them under water. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> is visiting <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> with an international fleet of more than 40 warships to celebrate the bicentennial of European settlement of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Anti-nuclear demonstrators were protesting the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s presence because it carries Tomahawk cruise missiles The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> refuses to confirm or deny whether the missiles carry nuclear warheads. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, built in 1943, is powered by old-fashioned oil-fired steam engines. It was followed into <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> by the British aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> Ark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> and four warships of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. Sailors from 16 nations will march through <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>'s streets on Thursday. On Saturday, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and his wife the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> will review the fleet from the deck of an Australian warship, HMAS Cook.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0301EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Ozone Bjt   09-27 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ozone, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Stance On Ozone-Destroying Compounds Is Cheered By
Environmentalists</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists hailed a call by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> for a global ban on ozone-destroying chloroflurocarbons and related compounds. `` We're glad to see they've come around to our way of thinking,'' said <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> of Friends of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. The announcement Monday by <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> marked a shift from his view that there was plenty of time to consider what, if any, steps were needed to tighten the terms of an existing international treaty on reducing <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> production. That treaty, signed by 45 major nations, pledges signatories to a 50 percent cut by 1998. The <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds are widely used as refrigeration fluids, solvents and foam blowing agents and, outside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, as aerosol propellants. Related bromine compounds are used in fire extinguishers. Some can last for more than a century, rising to the stratosphere where they eventually break down to liberate chlorine. A major study of ozone by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> last March found ozone depletion of as much as 3 percent at mid-latitudes and attributed it to chlorine. Without cutting off production of CFCs, chlorine and bromine will continue to build up in the atmosphere, destroying high-altitude ozone that protects the Earth from the sun's ultra-violet rays, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said in a new analysis released Monday `` It is increasingly clear that we as a global environmental community must use the -LRB- treaty -RRB- to go even further to eliminate these chemicals which damage the stratospheric ozone layer and threaten our future,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said in a statement. `` Regretfully, our new analysis predicts an even worse scenario than anticipated,'' he added. Up to now, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> had resisted environmentalist recommendations for a CFC-phaseout. In his remarks Monday, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> mentioned no specific timetable for a phase out. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, an environmentalist group, said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> announcement `` underlines the seriousness of the emergency we are facing.'' <PERSON> Doniger </PERSON> predicted the report would `` have a lot of impact'' on major <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> producers abroad. Also on Monday, the major trade association of <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> makers and users, the Alliance for a Responsible CFC Policy, announced it, too, now believed the nations of the world should aim at `` phasing out ... CFCs to the maximum extent feasible.'' <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fay </PERSON>, executive director of the users-producers group, said the phasing out approach probably would mean some CFCs would continue to be in use into the 21st century. `` We will be working with other trade groups around the world trying to line up support'' for a phaseout of <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> production and use, <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> said. Environmentalist groups have suggested 1995 as a target date for ending CFC production. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, co-author of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> analysis, said the failure of computer models to predict past ozone depletion leads <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to shy away from ozone predictions and to zero in on chlorine buildup instead. Any increases in chlorine raise the risk of ozone depletion, he said. Currently, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates worldwide atmospheric chlorine at 2.7 parts per billion. Others last year put the figure at 3 parts per billion, which represents about a 25 percent increase in the past decade. By some estimates, half the total comes from natural sources such as sea spray. In the past, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has said an immediate 85 percent reduction in the major <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds would be needed to keep chlorine from rising. But those estimates did not include non-CFC chemicals that yield chlorine, notably methyl chloroform, the most widely used industrial solvent. If use of that compound continues to grow, the current level of chlorine in the atmosphere would triple by 2075, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. Even if the growth of methyl chloroform use was halted, the level of chlorine in the atmosphere would double by 2075, it said. `` An immediate 100 percent reduction in the use of all -LRB- of the most powerful -RRB- compounds and a freeze in methyl chloroform would be needed'' by all countries to stabilize chlorine, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. By `` immediate,'' it said it meant 1990. This would permit use of less powerful <ORGANIZATION> CFC </ORGANIZATION> compounds to grow throughout the next century while still holding the chlorine increase to less than 1 part per billion by 2100.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0302EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SundayBattle     09-27 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sunday Battle,0751</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plan For Sunday Ferry Sailings Inflames Hebridean Passions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TARBERT, Outer Hebrides (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's a whiff of fire and brimstone in the <LOCATION> Outer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hebrides </LOCATION> these days as the islanders of <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> prepare to defend their Sabbath against a ferry invasion from the Scottish mainland. Life is rugged in these treeless, windswept peatlands, and Sunday is the high point of a week otherwise spent fishing, tending sheep and weaving <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> tweed. Pubs and playgrounds close on Sundays, flights are suspended, TV and newspapers are shunned and the only travel is to church. Thus to these flinty Presbyterians, the decision by the <ORGANIZATION> Caledonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MacBrayne </ORGANIZATION> ferry company to begin Sunday sailings next summer is a threat to civilization as they know it. They see tourists and trucks shattering the Sabbath peace. The company has sought to allay these fears by modifying its itinerary so that ferries will sail out but not in, but the islanders say Hebridean harbor staff will still be forced to go to work instead of to church. `` The people of these islands value their principles, their Sunday, their way of life, and we are determined to protect these to the bitter end,'' says <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdo </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, a hotelier in <LOCATION> Tarbert </LOCATION>, where the ferry is to dock. But other forces are at work. <PERSON> Calmac </PERSON>, as the ferry company is known, is to be privatized under Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s drive to sell off state-owned industries, and it says that once exposed to market forces, ferries can not lie idle on Sundays Thus the Thatcherite imperatives of free enterprise are bumping up against ancient traditions in what The Sunday Times in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> calls `` <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s deepest cultural battle.'' <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> McLeod </PERSON>, a fisherman, vows to lead a blockade of <PERSON> Tarbert </PERSON>'s tiny harbor when sailings commence next summer, and <PERSON> Calmac </PERSON>, which has served the Hebrides for more than a century, says it may ask the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to step in <PERSON> Calmac </PERSON>, warns <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, is `` sailing into a horrendous Hebridean hurricane.'' Denunciations have poured forth from the pulpits, and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stornoway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> and Local Advertiser is filled with angry letters. `` Sunday sailors will be cursed,'' writes reader <PERSON> N.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLean </PERSON>, while <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> MacRae </PERSON> turns to verse: `` The forces of evil are in battle array @ to destroy the Sabbath wherever they may ... We would resolve, as Shadrach of old @ That we will not bow to their image of gold.'' At a time when much of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is jumping through hoops in the chase for tourists, it's refreshing to find a place that is actively fighting to keep them out. <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Matheson </PERSON>, head of the Hebridean local authority, concedes that `` some see us as cranky individuals,'' but she believes the cause is just. `` We have a day apart. The mainland of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has no day apart. It suffers from the most appalling problems of urbanization, anti-social behavior, vandalism,'' he said in an interview in his office in <LOCATION> Stornoway </LOCATION>, the Hebridean capital. `` Now why on earth are we going to change by giving up our day apart which we deem to be so precious?'' <ORGANIZATION> Calmac </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Paterson </PERSON> says he understands the islanders' sensitivities, but believes that plenty of islanders want a Sunday service, and he sees nothing unChristian about using it. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> McKibbin </PERSON>, a retired <LOCATION> Stornoway </LOCATION> businessman and lone voice in favor of Sunday sailings, says the opposition is confined to one segment of the archipelago _ the adjoining islands of <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. On these islands the population of 22,000 is solidly Presbyterian. Further south, on the Uists, <PERSON> Benbecula </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Barra </LOCATION>, the 9,000 islanders are predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, Sabbath rules are less stern, and there have been few objections to Sunday sailings. <PERSON> Calmac </PERSON>'s compromise plan entails the ferry leaving <PERSON> Tarbert </PERSON> on Sunday for Uig on the mainland and not returning to <PERSON> Tarbert </PERSON> until Monday. But <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> says it's `` the thin end of a wedge,'' because once the principle is established, Sunday sailings into <PERSON> Tarbert </PERSON> will follow. <PERSON> Paterson </PERSON>, he says, is an Englishman who can not understand the islanders' preoccupations. `` I was born in this village, I was brought up in it, and I intend to make sure that it's not going to be eroded by <PERSON> Sassenachs </PERSON>,'' he said, using the Scottish pejorative for Englishmen. `` You must not become a slave to tourism,'' he said, `` because you lose your identity once that happens.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-Marshall     09-27 0877</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Marshall,0901</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alabama Center Recovers From Challenger, But Warns Space Is Still
Dangerous</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTSVILLE, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No matter the care taken and the tests conducted, eventually there will be another space accident and the <ORGANIZATION> Marshall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> probably will once again be the target of the nation's anger and anguish. That, says <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, director of <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, is a truth engineers learn to live with at the <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> center that designs and develops the most dangerous parts of a space machine. `` Ours are the two high-risk elements _ the shuttle main engine and the shuttle solid rocket,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said in an interview at the facility in the forested hills of northern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. `` In 9 chances out of 10, when there is a catastrophic failure, it will rest with those two elements.'' `` When a mission goes good, the focus is going to be on the operations end,'' he said. `` When things go amiss, the attention is going to be right here ... It's not an unfair thing. We're big boys and we know that's the job we've got.'' A presidential commission concluded that the explosion that destroyed Challenger and killed its seven crew members on Jan. 28, 1986, was caused by a flawed solid rocket booster that blowtorched against the external tank. <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> engineers became personal targets of blame. Their judgment was ridiculed, their diligence belittled and their competence questioned. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulloy </PERSON>, who headed the solid rocket booster program at <LOCATION> Marshall </LOCATION>, received hate mail and endured the collapse of a 23-year career at <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, director at <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, resigned, with parting, bitter shots at the press. Ten other managers also left, retiring or seeking jobs in private industry. None of the more than 3,400 workers at <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> escaped the stain. `` It was devastating,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON>, an engineer who analyzes stresses on the spacecraft. `` Everybody was pretty low. There was not so much a sense of guilt as of loss. There was also the sense of professional embarrassment. Something had gone terribly wrong and <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> was responsible.'' The drumbeat of blame, recalled <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, an organic chemist and materials expert, seemed to last forever. `` All the nails were driven in place and we were just hanging there and they were still beating on us,'' he said. `` Eventually it got to be too much ... We had accepted the responsibility. What we had to do then was make it right.'' That involved the most massive effort at reevaluation, repair and redesign ever attempted by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>. Teams of engineers at <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> dissected every piece of hardware developed at the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> center. Every design was reexamined. Every test was checked over and new ones were ordered where needed. Work days stretched from 10 to 12 to 14 hours, and, for many, weekends were forgotten. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said more tests were made on the main engines and on the solid rocket boosters than were conducted before the shuttle first flew in 1981. The goal was not to find out if the equipment was just `` good enough,'' but to demonstrate that it was better than it had to be. The full-scale solid rocket engine, with a new design for the flawed joint, was fired five times at a test site in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> by its manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. There were hundreds of other firings using sub-scale models or partial propellant loads. In one full-scale test, flaws were intentionally introduced to see if the new rocket had a margin of safety. It was a test never before attempted in the solid rocket industry. `` A lot of people inside and outside the agency did n't like that test because they thought it was pushing the engine too far,'' said <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. If it had failed, it could have caused a long delay in shuttle flights. But <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> engineers insisted because, he said, they `` believed in our design and wanted to go out on the test stand and prove it.'' The new rocket engine passed the test with margin to spare. Before Challenger, engineers recalled, dissent against consensus technical views was discouraged. Public differences of opinion were rare and quickly silenced. `` You were part of a team and it seemed a betrayal to take a contrary view,'' said one engineer. Challenger changed that. `` The accident strengthened the hand of the engineers in the trenches,'' said <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON>. `` Before, if you objected to something the manager could say you were overcautious because we had never had an accident. Now if a manager wants to yield to schedule pressures, we tell him that he's on his own.'' The new openness has resulted in conflicts unknown before Challenger. In one case, some experts believed a material in a solid rocket part needed one more test and refused to approve its use despite pressure from a manager. At conferences, it has become common for engineers to stand up and object to positions taken by their own managers. `` You admire a guy who has the courage to take a position different from the crowd,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` But that does n't mean it's a democracy. You're not going to launch with a democracy. You've got to have certain people in the system who make decisions and go.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WelfareOverhaul Bjt   09-27 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Welfare Overhaul, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Welfare Agreement Means System Is Headed For Major Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's welfare system is headed for a major overhaul with the conclusion of complex negotiations on a five-year plan aimed at moving welfare recipients into jobs and helping them collect more child support. The initiative agreed on Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> negotiators had been close to death all summer as negotiators sought a balance between conservatives favoring mandatory work and liberals concerned about increasing benefits to the needy and motivating people to enter the mainstream workplace. `` This was a critical day,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, chairman of the subcommittee that handled the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> welfare bill, emerging from Monday's pivotal meeting. `` There are some who will not be happy'' with the outcome, <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> said. But when asked if the package would fly when presented to about 50 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees late this afternoon, he said, `` Yes.'' `` I am very pleased,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> conferees and the Democratic vice presidential nominee. `` I think it's a good final resolution of the differences ... an excellent compromise.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s domestic policy adviser, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Hobbs </PERSON>, a participant in Monday's meeting, offered a conditional endorsement of the compromise. `` If it's okay with the conferees and if it comes down the way I understand it, it's probably okay,'' he said. The $ 3.34 billion welfare plan comes in above the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s own $ 2.8 billion measure but would cost less than half of the initial $ 7.1 billion plan passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. The cornerstone of the compromise is a Job Opportunities and Basic Skills -LRB- JOBS -RRB- program offering welfare parents _ including those with preschool children _ services such as job search help, education and job training. Child care and transportation aid would be available to participants. States would have to be serving 7 percent of eligible welfare recipients by 1990 and 20 percent by 1995. States would be given $ 600 million for the JOBS program in 1989, rising to $ 1.3 billion in 1995. People moving into jobs would qualify for a year of transitional child care and Medicaid benefits. Twenty-seven states now provide welfare benefits to households with two unemployed parents. The welfare bill would require those states to continue and, effective in 1991, would require others to provide at least six months of benefits a year to such families. Starting in 1994, one adult in each two-parent welfare family would have to perform 16 hours a week of community work, on-the-job training or other specified work activities. People under 25 without high school diplomas would be able to substitute participation in an education program leading to a diploma or its equivalent. The bill also makes new demands on states to step up child support collections from non-custodial parents, including tougher paternity determination requirements and mandatory wage withholding upon the court award of support payments. The 16-hour-a-week work requirement would affect only about 7 percent of the welfare caseload but was a primary obstacle to achieving agreement on the overall bill. A handful of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> liberals resisted the provision almost as fiercely as the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration insisted it be retained.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shuttle-MortonThiokol     09-27 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle-Morton Thiokol,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>Discovery Launch Marks Milestone On Morton Thiokol's Long Road
Back</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PEG McENTEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON>, maker of the rocket booster that caused Challenger's destruction, hopes a successful launch for Discovery will begin an awakening from a 32-month-long corporate nightmare. It will be the `` final demonstration to our customer <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and the country that solid rocket motors are going to be a reliable contributor to future shuttle successes,'' said <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, vice president and assistant general manager of space operations at <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Wasatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. Less easily dispatched are the specters of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigation, lawsuits by frustrated former employees and a plague of rocket fuel-related accidents, including an MX missile motor fire that killed five employees last December. The presidential commission that investigated the Jan. 28, 1986, shuttle disaster found that an O-ring seal on the right booster rocket had stiffened in freezing pre-launch temperatures, allowing superheated gas to escape and trigger an explosion. Worse, the commission learned that several <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> engineers had argued the night before that just such a disaster could occur, but were overruled by superiors who told <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> the launch should proceed. In the relentless glare of the postmortem, <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> embarked on an exhaustive booster redesign that kept some 3,000 workers busy on the field joints as well as the case-to-nozzle motor joint, the nozzle assembly and hundreds of smaller components. `` It's been a very difficult period,'' said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` I do n't think any company is ever prepared for the kind of intense scrutiny that you get following a tragedy like Challenger. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> engineer who had argued against the Challenger launch, was made vice president of engineering for space operations _ overseer of the booster redesign. His guiding principle in the $ 500 million effort has been redundancy: multiple seals, bolts and clamps to contain the 1.1 million pounds of solid fuel that burn in just two minutes. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> has borne the redesign cost and <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> agreed to reap no profit. Engineers have conducted five $ 20 million full-scale test-firings of the redesigned boosters, as well as hundreds of sub-scale and component tests. A sixth full-scale test is planned for December. With 8,000 employees and an annual payroll of $ 220 million, <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> is <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'s largest private employer. The Chicago-based company also produces munitions, salt and specialty chemicals, and manufactures first-stage motors for the MX, Trident 2 and Midgetman strategic missiles and propulsion systems for tactical missiles. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, a company vice president, said aerospace profits _ which account for more than a quarter of the company's overall profits _ fell from $ 96 million in fiscal 1986 to $ 73 million in 1987, then rose to $ 80.8 million in 1988. Even as <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> struggled to recover from Challenger, accidents further begrimed its public image. On Dec. 29, 1987, five men were killed when 108,000 pounds of fuel in an MX missile segment exploded, destroying a $ 6.2 million building at the complex 75 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The state cited <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> for six safety violations. Just last week, the company acknowledged that an old model of a nozzle inlet ring had been used in a motor test-fired in August. Analysis proved new versions had been placed in Discovery's boosters <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> also has been sued by former employees, among them <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Boisjoly </PERSON>, another engineer who protested the Challenger launch and later resigned. His lawsuits, seeking $ 3 billion, were recently dismissed. In mid-September, two former consultants, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Agee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Laine </PERSON>, filed suit contending they were fired for attempting to bring redesign problems to light. Their suits also claim the company violated racketeering laws by filing false reports on its contractual obligations with <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Agee </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` West 57th'' Saturday that the entire booster system was unsafe and that he `` would n't even want to be around when they assemble the boosters and stack them prior to launch.'' Discovery's boosters, of course, have long been in place, assembly on a second set is nearly complete and a third set is being shipped to the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION>. And <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the Kennedy Space Center, expressed confidence in the redesign and testing the boosters have undergone. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Thiokol </PERSON> also is the subject of an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> inquiry into allegations by <PERSON> Agee </PERSON>, a contract engineer who worked undercover for the agency during his 4 -LCB- - month tenure as a safety analyst <PERSON> Agee </PERSON> alleged that, among other things, the company had concealed hazards from <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MinimumWage Bjt   09-27 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Minimum Wage, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrat Loss On Wage Bill Means No Hike This Year In Minimum Pay
Rate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some 4.7 million Americans will have to wait at least another year for the first raise in the $ 3.35-an-hour minimum wage since 1981 as <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> concede a major election-year legislative defeat to a Republican filibuster. Refusing to bow to <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> demands for a broad-based subminimum floor under the 50-year-old minimum wage, Democratic leaders on Monday gave up all hope of raising the pay base by 40 cents to $ 3.75 an hour in January. `` There is no point in our continuing to pound on their door,'' Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> `` I'm now conceding that the Republican filibuster was successful.'' Even before Monday's action, the bill faced an uncertain fate in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where there was intense opposition from some southern and midwestern Democrats. `` I think it's a pretty good result,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` This bill could n't pass the House. It was n't going to pass the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> unless it was modified.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> had been stymied for more than a week by parliamentary maneuvering on both sides as the two presidential candidates, Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, watched from the sidelines. Lacking the 51 votes to effectively couple an increase with their desire for a 90-day, 80 percent subminimum for newly hired workers, Republicans refused to allow any votes on the bill itself or amendments. Democrats, meanwhile, lacked the 60 votes necessary to limit the debate and shut off the filibuster despite the defection of eight <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> senators to their cause last Friday. Each side sought to blame the other, with Democrats maintaining that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could have turned the vote around with a few phone calls to Republican lawmakers. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> three weeks ago had said he could support a modest increase _ never specifying how much _ but only if it was coupled with the creation of a broad subminimum `` training'' wage. `` Perhaps the word from the vice president's campaign has not gotten through to our friends on the other side,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` Perhaps it has gotten through. Either way the results are evident. Some 15 million workers are the loser.'' The bill, sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., would have raised the minimum wage in three annual 40-cents-an-hour increases to $ 4.55 by 1991, directly benefiting some 15 million workers now paid less than that, according to <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> Republicans blamed <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s refusal to compromise on a lower figure, such as the $ 4.25 an hour suggested once by <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> or $ 4 an hour as urged by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, R-Ind. But they said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s refusal to compromise on the so-called training wage, or the `` youth training wage'' as <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> called it, overshadowed everything else. `` The real reason this is being pulled down is that the senator from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> knows we were on the very edge of passing the training wage,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, the leader of the Republican opposition. `` The fact is that the international trade union movement in this country will not accept a training wage,'' <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> said. `` They consider the minimum wage as their single idea.'' <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> had introduced an amendment calling for the 80 percent subminimum for the first 90 days a new employee is on a company's payroll, saying it would `` give a chance to those unskilled, undereducated youths who can not get into the system any other way. To prevent a vote on the amendment, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> immediately introduced a substitute that would slightly expand a currently allowed but little-used $ 2.85 subminimum for full-time students working less than 20 hours a week. `` If his passes, mine would be gone,'' <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> said early in the debate, complaining as did other Republicans that their subminimum proposal was being denied a fair hearing under <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules that favor whichever party holds a majority. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> called <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>'s subminimum amendment a `` Bush hire'em and fire'em wage.'' Without any requirements for training or age restrictions, employers would have an incentive to replace their workforces every 90 days with a new group of workers paid the subminimum rate, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. Republicans had also pushed as an alternative to a minimum wage increase an earned income tax credit that would have funneled about $ 6 billion in federal subsidies over four years to families headed by minimum wage earners. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said that alternative, which Republicans conceded would have to be financed through a tax increase, would leave taxpayers `` subsidizing employers who exploit their workers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SmokingLaw     09-27 0768</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smoking Law,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tobacco Companies Take Aim At Oregon Ballot Measure</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRAD CAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALEM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The tobacco industry is mounting an expensive campaign to try to snuff out an <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> ballot measure that would create the nation's toughest anti-smoking law. But opponents of Measure 6 will have their work cut out for them because a recent statewide poll found strong public support for it. Tobacco companies are using mass mailings of brochures, newsletters and voter registration kits in hopes of scuttling Measure 6 on the Nov. 8 ballot. `` We're going to spend a lot of money,'' at least several hundred thousand dollars, said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> lobbyist who's running the campaign to defeat Measure 6 `` We're going to make a major effort on this.'' The anti-smoking proposal would toughen the 1981 Oregon Indoor Clean Air Act, which makes most public buildings off limits to smokers, except in designated smoking areas. The new proposal, if approved, would wipe out designated smoking areas and ban smoking in virtually all indoor work areas and enclosed places frequented by the public. Violators would be subject to civil penalties of up to $ 250. Smoking still would be allowed in bars and taverns, tobacco stores, and hotel and motel rooms. The <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lung </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> led a petition drive to win a spot on the ballot for the proposal. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Odisio </PERSON>, who is coordinating the campaign for the <ORGANIZATION> Lung </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said non-smokers should not have to put up with secondhand smoke in public facilities or workplaces. `` What we're talking about is a public health measure,'' <PERSON> Odisio </PERSON> said. `` We know that secondhand smoke causes disease, including lung cancer in otherwise healthy non-smokers.'' `` Study after study has shown unhealthful levels of tobacco smoke in non-smoking sections,'' she said. That is disputed by <PERSON> Maura </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> R.J. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reynolds </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's no substantive, scientific support for the contention that environmental tobacco smoke causes any significant threat to the health of non-smokers,'' she said. In a telephone interview from the company's office in <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> called Measure 6 a dangerous abridgement of the rights of a minority group _ smokers. `` Even if you're a non-smoker, you should be careful of government infringement on other people's rights,'' she said. `` Maybe next they're going to try to restrict whether people eat red meat or attend rock concerts that neighbors find too noisy.'' A former <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, voices similar concerns about possible infringement of civil liberties. In a letter distributed by opponents of Measure 6, <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> warned that it would `` authorize search warrants to root out evidence of illegal smoking, and even bring about police arrests of fine-ignoring citizens.'' <PERSON> Odisio </PERSON> dismisses those concerns as unfounded, saying no one has been fined or taken to court for violating the current law. `` It's a self-enforcing law,'' <PERSON> Odisio </PERSON> said. `` It is passed with the understanding that most <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> citizens are law-abiding.'' She said 42 states have some sort of statewide restriction on smoking, including such things as banning smoking on elevators, and that 36 of those restrict smoking in a wide variety of public places with designated smoking or non-smoking areas. The proposed <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> law, she said, would be the first to drop all designated areas. Other groups pitching in to try to defeat the measure are the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, and the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> Restaurant and <ORGANIZATION> Beverage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The president of the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bowling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>, said Measure 6 would hurt his industry because a lot of bowlers are smokers. `` If they would not be allowed to smoke for that two-hour period, they would drop out of the sport altogether or cut down on the number of times they bowl,'' he said. <PERSON> Wells </PERSON> estimated bowling alleys would lose at least 10 percent of their customers if Measure 6 passes, and argued that the existing law has been a success in providing separate accommodations for smokers and non-smokers. <PERSON> Odisio </PERSON> said the proposal is part of a nationwide trend. `` It's just a case of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> being one small step in front of everybody else,'' she said. `` We're not way out in left field, we just happen to be at the front of the parade.'' A poll conducted for The Oregonian newspaper in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> Sept. 6-7 asked 400 registered voters how they would vote on several measures that will be on the statewide ballot. Measure 6 was favored by 62 percent of those surveyed in the telephone poll and opposed by 36 percent. The rest were undecided. The margin of error was 4.9 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-VeepDebates Bjt   09-27 0984</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veep Debates, Bjt,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Solid, Error-Free Debate Performance Key to Unmaking of Quayle
Issue</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Now come the vice presidential nominees in a different kind of debate _ a confrontation in which Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will be out to prove that he does n't deserve to be a campaign issue. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Republican running mate and Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate for vice president, meet on Oct. 5 in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, in a 90-minute debate patterned on the match between the presidential nominees. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s competence has come under almost daily challenge from Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, and lately, from <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. The patrician <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has shelved senatorial courtesy in favor of long-distance attacks on his cross-aisle colleague from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. And <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> debate etiquette presumably will not apply next week, at least on <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s side of the stage. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, 41, a second-term senator, could try to deflect debate attacks by using the elaborate courtesies of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in handling his senior colleague. Debating <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> Sunday night, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> gave a hint at that strategy by saying that he, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> were the only three candidates in the race who are knowledgeable on defense issues. Campaign debaters customarily are out to raise their profiles, to promote themselves and their positions as issues to be considered by the voters. But <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> could best serve his ticket by reversing that with a solid, error-free debate showing, nothing flashy or fancy, just a workmanlike performance to try to silence the critics _ and lower his profile as a Democratic target. Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, testy when he was questioned about criticism of his chosen running mate in the presidential debate, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who is 41, is an outstanding young man who has stood up to `` outrageous, brutal ... very unfair pounding ...'' since his nomination. `` He'll do very, very well'' in the debate, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The Democrats think <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is a salable campaign issue for their side, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> takes a slap at him in almost every speech. `` I doubt very much that <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was the best qualified person for that job,'' he said Sunday night. `` And as a matter of fact, I think for most people, the notion of President <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is a very, very troubling notion.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, campaigning with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, returned the gibe. `` After last night, for most people the notion of President <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a very, very troubling notion today,'' he said. With the Democrats questioning his competence, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is in a position to succeed without really scoring in the vice presidential debate, if he can hold his own and undercut the opposition claim that he is in way over his head. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> can do that by showing the voters that he is n't a dummy, that he can answer questions under the pressure of a nationally-televised debate without misspeaking, that he is up to his assignment. The best vice presidential candidates are those who serve as spokesmen and campaigners for their nominees but do n't make waves. The people running to be No. 2 tend to attract the most attention when they err, or when their records come under critical scrutiny. Both have been happening in <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s case, ever since the question of family influence in his Vietnam-era <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> enlistment blew up into controversy just as he was nominated at the Republican National Convention. Four years ago, Rep. <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>'s family income taxes and her husband's business affairs became a focus of inquiry and thus a problem for the Democratic ticket on which she ran. In 1976, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s debate remark that World War I, World War II, <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> were `` all Democrat wars'' created a troublesome issue for the Republican ticket. Once such questions become issues, they tend to snowball. For <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, the Guard uproar was followed by questions about his admittedly mediocre college record, and his admission into night law school. Errors in his campaign statements have since been added to the dossier, things like his tongue-twisted effort to say that a good defense beats a good offense _ or was it the other way around _ and his slip in saying that he did n't live in this century. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> took it from there. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has called the Republican record on energy `` as empty as <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s resume.'' Acknowledging that he and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> differ on some issues, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said that is healthy. `` What would have happened if <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had a vice president like <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>; a vice president strong enough to think for himself and speak up for himself ...?'' he asks his campaign crowds. `` We have n't had that kind of vice president for the past eight years, and I do n't know of anyone who thinks we'll have him in the person of <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>.'' The name has become a laughter and applause line at Democratic rallies. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> draws it out slowly, scornfully, and sometimes his supporters recite it with him. In their debate, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rebuked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for ridiculing the name and said the original <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> was killed in World War II. Full name or nickname, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has become a target, and his problems are taking a Republican toll. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON>, who conducts public opinion polls for the White House and the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, says the <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> nomination thus far has been more negative than positive for the ticket, with <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> viewed as the stronger nominee. `` The question is to what extent do people vote for the ticket because of the vice president,'' <PERSON> Wirthlin </PERSON> said. `` In the past, that has not been a big issue.'' The Democrats are campaigning to make it one this time. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s best opportunity to block them comes next week in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDITOR'S NOTE - Walter R. Mears, executive editor of The</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered national politics since 1960.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Klan-IndependenceHall     09-27 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Klan-Independence Hall,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Klan Likely To Apply To Rally At Independence Hall</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> have been negotiating plans for a `` white pride day'' rally at Independence Hall in November, a park official says. The park service expects to approve an application for a permit to hold the rally at the hall, where the Declaration of Independence and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Constitution were signed, Chief Ranger <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Burn </PERSON> said Monday. The application has not been filed yet, but will be soon, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogel </PERSON>, a Klan official who lives in <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. For the past two weeks, the <ORGANIZATION> KKK </ORGANIZATION> and the park service have been discussing police protection, parking and other concerns associated with the rally scheduled for Nov. 5 at the hall, <PERSON> Burn </PERSON> said Burn said the application probably would be approved because `` under the First Amendment and the regulations we operate under, there's not much room for denying -LRB- it -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, an executive board member of the Philadlephia branch of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, agreed the Constitution gives the <ORGANIZATION> KKK </ORGANIZATION> the right to rally. But, she said, `` It is sad to see that people who have accepted violence as a way of life toward people who are not their race or creed can imbue others with their hatred. `` I do hope there will be some black faces there,'' she said. The Klan might invite other right-wing groups, such as the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Natiional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fogel </PERSON> said. In May, about 40 people dressed in <LOCATION> Klan </LOCATION> robes marched in <LOCATION> Parkside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, in suburban <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. They were greeted by a crowd of about 1,000 counter-demonstrators.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSMonth     09-27 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Month,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>October Is AIDS Prevention, Awareness Month</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With more Americans aware of AIDS than ever before, federal health officials are urging the nation's governors and clergy to emphasize prevention during October _ AIDS Prevention and Awareness Month. A similar designation was made last October, when a flashy broadcast, print and direct mail advertising campaign was launched. Many of those television spots _ all identified by the phrase `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> Responds to AIDS'' _ still are running and are tied in with a pamphlet called `` Understanding AIDS'' that was mailed to every <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> household last spring. `` Despite efforts such as this, we need to keep alerting the public about AIDS,'' <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said in a recent letter asking each of the nation's governors to declare October AIDS Prevention and Education Month. A survey issued last month by the <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> shows Americans now consider AIDS to be the most serious problem facing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. In January 1987, AIDS had ranked ninth. `` The widespread media attention focused on the AIDS dilemma is obviously being heard across the country,'' said <PERSON> Fabian </PERSON> <PERSON> Linden </PERSON>, executive director of the board's <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. The survey was conducted for the non-profit, business-supported group by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which polled 5,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> households. `` In a sense the department ... has been successful in making the public aware about the fact that AIDS is a danger, but obviously we still have the problem of making sure people are heeding the prevention aspect of it,'' <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said in a recent interview. While 73,394 Americans had been diagnosed with AIDS as of Sept. 19, thousands more are known to be in earlier stages of the disease and the government estimates that up to 1.5 million people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are infected with the AIDS-causing virus. Because of growing data about the disease's long incubation period, medical experts are increasingly fearful that most, if not virtually all, of those infected eventually will become sick and die of AIDS. In letters to members of the clergy, distributed through central offices of the nation's churches and denominations, <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> and other top <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> officials asked the religious leaders to set aside the third weekend of October to `` relay potentially lifesaving messages about AIDS.'' `` Such a message could be as simple as urging your congregation to call the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>'s National AIDS Hotline ... but we hope you will want to talk to your congregation at greater length about this topic of such extraordinary importance to us all,'' said the letter, also signed by Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> and Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>, the assistant <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> secretary for health. Enclosed with the letter were sample questions and answers about AIDS. Not mentioned in the material sent to priests, rabbis and ministers was the health service's position that condoms can be a barrier, although not 100 percent effective, against passing the infection during sexual contact. Another part of this year's more focused October campaign is letters to university presidents and deans along with a videotape for college students entitled `` AIDS: Why Should I Care?'' In a letter to the deans, <PERSON> Windom </PERSON> said one-fifth of the AIDS cases reported so far `` have occurred among people 20 to 29 years old. `` Since the average incubation period ... is seven years or longer, it's clear that any of the ... 14,000-plus patients in this group were high school or college age at the time of their infection,'' said <PERSON> Windom </PERSON>. `` We must leave no stone unturned in teaching students about the potential risks posed by AIDS and how they can avoid them,'' he wrote. The video includes appearances by such well-known performers as <PERSON> Dionne </PERSON> <PERSON> Warwick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chita </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nell </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mariel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Busey </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseSpending     09-27 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Spending,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress And White House Said To Be Near Accord On Defense Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional and administration officials are close to a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending compromise that would remove one of the last major obstacles to passage of all legislation needed to pay the government's bills by the Oct. 1 start of a new fiscal year. The two sides are near agreement on the complicated <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> measure, according to congressional sources who declined to be identified Monday. The proposed compromise would remove some of the restrictions imposed earlier by the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s cherished Star Wars anti-missile defense plan, the sources said But overall, the Strategic Defense Initiative, as the program is formally known, still would receive $ 4.1 billion, the same amount that was in the bill <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoed on Aug. 3, the sources said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had sought $ 4.8 billion for <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, compared to the $ 3.9 billion the program now receives. Approval of a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> bill is the major remaining hurdle to be cleared before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> finishes work on all 13 appropriations bills needed to finance the government starting Saturday. The last time all 13 spending bills were finished by the start of the new fiscal year was 1948. <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leaders are pushing to finish the bills and avoid giving the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a potentially embarrassing election-year issue. After yearlong budget battles, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> sent the president a 1,400-page, $ 600 billion catchall spending bill last December, nearly three months into the present fiscal year. In <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s State of the Union address, he threatened to veto any similar giant spending bills this year, and scores of lawmakers signed letters pledging to support him. This year's appropriations work was made easier by the budget summit agreement between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and congressional leaders last November. That pact settled many broad spending questions for fiscal 1989, but disputes over various provisions within several individual bills have caused delays. Lawmakers have said the dispute over the defense bill was the most serious and that its resolution would make it likely that all 13 bills would be finished on time. Many Democrats fear that if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> does not finish its appropriations work on time this year, the president and Republicans will use that failure to paint the majority party as inefficient and incapable of adhering to budget processes. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has thus far signed four appropriations bills and two others have been sent to his desk. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending compromise also drops a restriction added by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on testing of depressed-trajectory missiles, a type of atomic-tipped weapon being developed by the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the sources said. The bill provides $ 300 billion for all <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spending, the same as the earlier bill. That would be a slight decrease from the current $ 302 billion <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880927-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-27-88 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Abortion     09-27 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Abortion,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rejects Estranged Husband's Effort To Block Abortion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
