<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CyanideDeaths 3rdLd-Writethru a0770 05-09 0824</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cyanide Deaths, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0770,0845</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Convicted in First Product-Tampering Case</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 21st graf ``Information about...'' to restore first
reference to Dwyer.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE TIBBITS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal court jury convicted a woman Monday of killing her husband and another woman by lacing their Extra-Strength Excedrin with cyanide in the nation's first trial in a death by product tampering. The 12-member jury deliberated almost five days before returning the verdict against <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>. One juror held out for acquittal until the final vote, said the jury foreman, <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, 55, Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>, 44, of suburban <ORGANIZATION> Auburn </ORGANIZATION>, was convicted on each count she faced, two of causing death by tampering with a product involved in interstate commerce and three of tampering. The first two counts could result in life sentences. King County Prosecutor <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Maleng </PERSON> said he would wait until after sentencing, scheduled for June 17, to decide whether to file state murder charges. When the verdict was read by the clerk, Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> bowed her head. The charges stemmed from the June 1986 deaths of her husband, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>, 52, and of Sue <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON>, 40, also of <LOCATION> Auburn </LOCATION>. Both died after ingesting the poisoned painkillers. The deaths touched off a nationwide tampering scare and prompted Excedrin manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> Bristol-Myers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> to recall its capsuled, non-prescription medications. Seven people died in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in 1982 from cyanide-laced Extra-Strength Tylenol, but those deaths remain unsolved. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Weisberg </PERSON>, spokesman for the New York-based Bristol-Myers, said the company was `` gratified by the jury's verdict, and particularly appreciative of the efforts of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and other law enforcment authorities. `` Product tampering is intolerable to society. When it occurs every effort must be made to identify those responsible and to bring them to justice,'' he said. `` We're very pleased it's finally over. It was a tough case for the jury to decide,'' said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Maida </PERSON>, who said she would ask for an `` appropriately severe'' sentence. She did not elaborate. Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> said she hoped `` it will be a deterrent'' to future drug-tamperers. During the trial, Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> portrayed Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> as an `` icy, hard human being,'' unhappy in her marriage and beset by financial problems, and accused Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> of poisoning her husband to collect on his life insurance policies. Ms. Snow was an innocent stranger caught in Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>'s scheme to make her husband's death appear random, the prosecutor said But federal public defender <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> was the victim of a daughter who lied when she said her mother had discussed killing <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> with a drug overdose or by hiring a hit man. The prosecution said Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> put tainted painkillers on shelves of local stores to make her husband's death appear random and to lead doctors, who had concluded <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> died of emphysema, to the true cause of his death. Only Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> had the motive, opportunity and ability to commit the crimes, Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> told the jury in closing arguments May 2. <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> called Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, 28, unreliable and noted that pharmaceutical companies had offered a $ 300,000 reward to anyone who provided information leading to an arrest. Further, the prosecution could not link Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> to cyanide purchases, <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> said. Earlier Monday, a juror said she had received an anonymous phone call Friday in which the caller asked, `` Do n't you all know that she failed the lie detector test?'' Information about the polygraph test had been kept from the jury, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON> said neither the panel's trouble reaching a decision nor the phone call would force a mistrial. He gave <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> a choice of substituting an alternate juror for the one who received the phone call, but <PERSON> Hillier </PERSON> declined. Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> said in her closing arguments that Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>'s plan failed because she was careless in mixing the poisonous capsules, greedy for insurance benefits and owned two of the five tainted bottles of painkillers found. The odds of one person buying two bottles of cyanide-laced pain capsules at different stores on different days were `` astronomical,'' Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> said, noting that more than 15,000 bottles had been examined in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> area. Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> also told jurors that Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> might have gotten away with the scheme if she had been more careful about the bowl she chose for mixing the potassium cyanide with Anacin and Excedrin painkillers. Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON>, a tropical fish enthusiast, used a bowl contaminated with Algae Destroyer, a compound used to clean fish tanks, the prosecution alleged. Traces of the compound were found in the five tainted bottles of Excedrin and Anacin, Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> also tripped up in leaving fingerprints on library books about poisons and cyanide, Ms. <PERSON> Maida </PERSON> said. But Mrs. <PERSON> Nickell </PERSON> testified she did the library research to find out more about her husband's death and to protect children from dangerous foliage around her rural home.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mitterrand     05-09 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mitterrand,0525</SECOND>
<HEAD>French President Has Moved From Left To Center</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-France-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Socialist President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> has been a prominent face on the French left since the end of World War II, but in recent years he has moved markedly to the political center. His first two years in office, 1981-83, involved implementation of long-held Socialist ideas and were largely a failure. The radical philosophy of `` rupture with capitalism'' foundered on the rocks of economic reality. After trying to spend their way to prosperity, the Socialists succeeded only in running up the national debt without being able to stop runaway unemployment. In the face of a growing crisis, the government was forced to reverse course and institute austerity. When the right ousted the Socialists from control of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in March 1986, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> needed to appeal to a wider electorate if he was to have any hope of re-election. Ironically, after <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>'s popularity had fallen to historic lows at mid-term, it soared after the right regained control of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, leaving him with little real power in domestic affairs. The French seemed to like the balance of power. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, 71, quickly assumed the role of the wise grandfather, referred to affectionately by many as `` Tonton,'' a child's term for `` uncle.'' <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> was first elected May 10, 1981, in a Socialist tidal wave that ousted center-right President <PERSON> Valery </PERSON> <PERSON> Giscard </PERSON> d'Estaing and then, a month later, the conservatives and centrists who had held power in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> for 23 years. The founder of the modern <ORGANIZATION> French </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> has now made four presidential races. He was defeated by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON> in 1965 and by <PERSON> Giscard </PERSON> in 1974. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> was born Oct. 26, 1916 in <LOCATION> Jarnac </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. He earned degrees in law and letters in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. He was drafted in 1938, and during the German invasion of May 1940 was shot and captured. He escaped from a POW camp in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and returned to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. After the occupation of the Vichy zone by the Germans, he created a Resistance network. His career-long feud with Gen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON> began during the war when <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> refused to join his Resistance group with <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaulle </PERSON>'s. It was during his Resistance days that he met <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON> <PERSON> Gouze </PERSON>, whom he married in 1944 shortly after the liberation. During the chaotic postwar <LOCATION> Fourth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> held 11 Cabinet posts, including interior and justice minister. In the early 1970s, <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> took the moribund <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and built it into a major force. But the Union of the Left he forged with the Communists fell apart in 1977. It was not until the final days of the 1981 presidential election that the two major leftist parties again joined to defeat <PERSON> Giscard </PERSON> and oust the conservatives. <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON> shocked much of the West when he brought the Communists into his government. But that union only lasted three years, until 1984, when the Communists pulled out in a dispute over economic policy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Defense-Treaty Bjt   05-09 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense-Treaty, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arms Control, NATO Issues on Tap in Senate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is facing fights over arms control and <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> this week as it considers both a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> budget bill and the historic U.S.-Soviet treaty eliminating medium-range nuclear weapons. First, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will begin work on the military budget, an annual fight which generally involves wide-ranging decisions on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s far-flung commitments. The bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> authorizes $ 299.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, and targets increased spending for non-nuclear weapons in the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` This issue of conventional weapons in <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> is something that we paid an awful lot of attention to this year, given the treaty,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the panel He was referring to the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty signed Dec. 8 by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. It eliminates both nations' medium-range missiles, and <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> and other supporters say <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s non-nuclear defenses will have to be bolstered after the missiles are gone. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is tentatively scheduled to begin work on the treaty Wednesday. During the Pentagon bill debate, amendments are likely both to increase spending for <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and call on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies in the 16-nation alliance to pay more of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s costs. Also expected are proposals providing advice to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> from both conservative Republicans and liberal Democrats about the arms control policies he should follow in the last six months of his administration. Similar attempts were made the past two weeks in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> during that chamber's work on its version of the Pentagon budget bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved nuclear arms control restrictions opposed by the administration, along with cuts in Star Wars missile defense spending which were so deep that <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> threatened to advise <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to veto the bill. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is expected to give final approval Wednesday to its Pentagon bill. Similar action by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will send the separate measures to a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee to reconcile the differences. Both measures propose $ 299.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> in the fiscal year starting Oct. 1. One difference is that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted $ 3.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION>, as Star Wars is formally known, while the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill proposes $ 4.6 billion. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wanted $ 4.8 billion. The House also voted to order <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to send the military into the fight against illegal drug traffickers. Anti-drug amendments are likely in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> although not as sweeping as the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> proposal, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said. In mid-week, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is scheduled to turn to the INF pact, which <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> wants ratified before he goes to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on May 29 for his fourth summit meeting with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. With 67 votes needed for ratification, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders have predicted that 90 or more senators will vote to approve the pact. But the debate over the treaty has been clouded by a dispute over whether both the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the Soviets agree on several points, such as the definition of `` weapons'' and whether the pact bans `` futuristic'' weapons such as lasers. There also are questions about the latitude which will be allowed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> inspectors who will be stationed inside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to verify compliance. While the focus on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor is on national security issues, congressional leaders also are preparing to send <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> the omnibus trade bill. The measure has been passed by both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> but instead of being sent to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, it remains stalled on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> while leaders seek to revise it and perhaps avert a threatened presidential veto. Last week, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 253-159 to drop the bill's curbs on export of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> oil, one of two provisions <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has said would justify a veto. The other is a requirement that companies with 100 employees or more give 60 days' notice of plant closings and large layoffs. The measure approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is a technical resolution. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders still are trying to get the technical resolution onto the floor without undue delay. If they can not, they probably will abandon plans to drop the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> provisions and just send the bill to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> unchanged from the form in which it won final passage two weeks ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     05-09 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0746</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0421 to fix heading</HEAD>
<HEAD>Salvadoran Crisis Creates Fear For Democracy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Monday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>An AP Extra</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A political mess has raised doubts about the future of democracy in this important <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally and put the dreaded word `` coup'' on the lips of just about everyone _ from the president on down. However, the military has vowed to let democracy unravel its own tangles, and most people said they were betting against military intervention. Coup rumors have circulated since a week ago, when a dispute over control of the legislature prevented effective installation of the 60-member congress elected March 20. President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> told journalists Thursday: `` Yes, we are in the midst of a crisis.'' But he added, `` I believe the armed forces are absolutely convinced that this -LRB- a coup -RRB- would be a fatal course for the country because every coup implies a division in the armed forces ... and in the middle of a war that would mean a gigantic danger for national security.'' Leftist rebels are fighting U.S.-backed government forces in an 8-year-old war that has claimed an estimated 65,000 lives. Thirty deputies of the rightist <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>, or <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, took their seats May 1 and claim to constitute the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>. The governing <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, including <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, contend that <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> lacks the majority necessary to install the congress and make laws. The Christian Democrats were resoundingly defeated in the legislative election, losing their parliamentary majority. `` Right now, the country has no legislature,'' <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rey </PERSON> <PERSON> Prendes </PERSON> said at a news conference May 2. He is the party's candidate in presidential elections set for March. The two main parties, along with the smaller <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conciliation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, spent the end of last week trying to negotiate an end to the impasse, but they failed. Positions appeared to have hardened. The Christian Democrats and the <ORGANIZATION> Conciliation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, who claim 30 deputies between them, have formed an informal alliance to block <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>'s control of the legislature. One of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>' 23 deputies is claimed by <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, which charges the seat was stolen through electoral fraud. That dispute is before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, but the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> do not recognize its jurisdiction in the matter. Government, opposition and military representatives have said the governmental crisis could deepen if the court rules for <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, granting it a 31st seat and an outright majority. <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> says the Assembly has 59 members meanwhile and that it already has a majority with 30 votes. The Christian Democrats, in a parallel session, have seated the disputed deputy in defiance of the court. Meanwhile, the military has watched warily from the sidelines. Col. <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, chief of operations of the joint chiefs of staff, said military intervention would do much more harm than good. `` Nationally, it would be the rupture of the democratic process,'' he said. `` Internationally, it would mean isolation that would bring major repercussions. And to break the democratic system would be to provide justification for the guerrillas' position that we do n't want democracy in this country.'' <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> receives more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid than any country in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>. Last year's economic and military assistance was about $ 620 million. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has repeatedly held up <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> as an example of Central American democracy. Military intervention presumably would bring strong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bipartisan reaction and possibly a drastic cut in aid. Though a coup appears unlikely, a top government source close to the president said the military is exerting strong pressure on politicians to resolve the impasse. The source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the armed forces had `` imposed a deadline'' but declined to give details. Gen. <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Blandon </PERSON>, head of the joint chiefs of staff, said last week: `` This -LRB- dispute -RRB- confuses things and is not beneficial to the democratic process. It is irresponsible behavior on the part of the deputies in whom the people deposited their trust.'' <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarenga </PERSON>, named by <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> as the new president of the <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, agreed that damage had already been done: `` This mess leads the people to the conclusion, which is logical but not necessarily correct, that the guerrillas are right when they say our democracy does not work and is not the way to resolve our problems.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PoliceTests Bjt   05-09 0585</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Police Tests, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Department Eyes Way Cities Test Police Candidates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is reviewing a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> literacy test for would-be law enforcement officers that is failed by three out of four blacks and two out of three Hispanics. The federal inquiry is intended to determine whether the test discriminates against minorities seeking jobs in nearly 300 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law enforcement agencies. Minority groups tend to be underrepresented in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law enforcement, and critics say hiring practices may contribute to the prevalence of white faces in blue uniforms. If the department concludes that the test is discriminatory, `` we'd have to take appropriate steps to address that problem,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Burstion-Wade </PERSON>. The test indicates whether a job candidate reads and writes at high-school level, skills presumed necessary if the candidate is to understand the laws being enforced. One section requires the person to complete a sentence by picking the correctly spelled word from three choices. Other sections test grammar. Another section asks the test taker to choose the clearest of three sentences discussing the same topic. The wrong answers contain `` extremely basic, obvious ambiguities,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boatright </PERSON>, an attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> Officer Standards and Education. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has looked at numerous other state, city or county writing or reading tests for their effect on minorities, and employment criteria for physical strength and agility and their effect on women. Exams reviewed by the agency have ranged from the <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, county police test to the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> toll facilities police force's height and weight restrictions. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, during the past 7 -LCB- months, passing rates were 69 percent for whites; 67 percent for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>; 59 percent for Asian-Americans; 36 percent for Hispanics; and 27 percent for blacks. Overall, 55 percent of the people who took the test between Sept. 1, 1987, and April 21 passed it, according to the law enforcement standards commission. People who fail may repeat the exam. As of Feb. 17, the state had 41,916 licensed law enforcement officers, 7.3 percent of whom were black, according to the most recent figures from the commission. Figures from the 1980 census show 12 percent of Texans are black. The commission had the test developed in the mid-1970s and used <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> criteria in drafting it. `` We offered to run it by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> and they refused,'' said attorney <PERSON> Boatright </PERSON>. `` We're perfectly happy that they're looking at it now.'' One of the 283 law enforcement agencies using the test is <LOCATION> Lufkin </LOCATION>. Police Chief <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> says he does n't fault the exam for the absence of black officers on his force, although blacks make up about one-fourth of the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> town's population of 30,000. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> says basic literacy is essential for an officer, and to help prepare candidates he has enlisted the help of an adult learning center which offers preparation for the high school General Equivalency Diploma exam. The local agency is offering a six-week course to raise reading comprehension and writing skills up to five grade levels, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said. `` We want black officers,'' <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said. `` We would have a better rapport with the black community if we had black officers out there serving them.'' Only one black out of 13 passed the test in <LOCATION> Lufkin </LOCATION> in June, when it was offered last. The person who passed was a reporter who took the exam as part of a news assignment for the <ORGANIZATION> Lufkin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reporter'sNotebook     05-09 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reporter's Notebook,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Road With Dukakis: Stargazing, Coal Trains and Tarmac
Football</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democratic front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says he `` would n't know a horoscope from a telescope,'' but he decided to see what the stars had in store for him after reading reports President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s schedule has been affected by advice his wife gets from an astrologist <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told a crowd at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> fund-raiser last week that his horoscope for that day indicated he would be taking on new challenges and having to make tough decisions. `` It is pointless for you to remain in your current position,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor read, drawing giggles. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he also decided to check the horoscope of Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, whose legal troubles draw frequent gibes from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> during campaign appearances. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s horoscope, the candidate said, indicated that he should find happiness `` elsewhere.'' `` I'll drink to that,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said as the crowd roared in approval.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not generally known for his humor. But he drew laughs from a group of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> coal miners when he said his ride into the mine on a cramped rail car was just `` a little bumpier'' than the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> subway he often takes to work. Minutes later, asked if the mine was the first place he had campaigned where there was not a <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> restaurant, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor smiled and said: `` There are <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> restaurants everywhere.'' Fellow Greek and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> confidant <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitropoulis </PERSON> chimed in: `` And if there is n't one, there will be soon.'' Going out of the mine, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> mistakenly turned toward a vein heading deeper into the mountain. After a miner set him straight, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> threw his hands in the air and said, `` I'm sure glad you guys know where you're going because I certainly do n't.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Tarmac football is the latest craze in the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidential campaign. Aides to the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor and reporters traveling with him routinely toss a football around when they arrive at airports before the candidate. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> himself has joined the fun lately, running pass routes on airport tarmacs in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> last week, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who played basketball in high school, and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>, a standout college hoop player at <LOCATION> Providence </LOCATION>, took turns as quarterback and receiver. `` OK <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, go deep,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said before throwing a perfect spiral to the mayor. `` It certainly beats going around hitting people like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does,'' said one <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide, referring to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s habit of throwing light punches or giving back slaps to people he meets while campaigning.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-AdvertisingAntics Bjt   05-09 0804</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Advertising Antics, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Election's Not Over, But There Were Clear Winners and Losers
Among Ads</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only a handful of television viewers witnessed one of the best ads of the 1988 presidential campaign _ 10 seconds of <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> stuffing pizza into his mouth at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> eatery. `` It got on the air one day before he withdrew,'' said <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s media consultant. The ad showed a mischievous-looking <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> using his fingers to subdue some errant pizza cheese, and instantly turned the off-putting general into a likable human being. Political media observers, from academics to admakers, say few if any TV spots this year have broken new technical ground or connected emotionally with voters. Among the notable exceptions was Democrat <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s `` $ 48,000 <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION>'' spot _ a trade tirade aimed at Korean tariffs that price <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> autos out of the Korean market `` The populist impulses in the <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> ad, the defiant expression, identified with the electorate's feeling of powerlessness,'' said <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON>, a professor and author of two books on political ads and speeches. `` It was a moment of empowerment. It let the voters feel good.'' <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON> also nominated the pizza ad, saying it forced the viewer to reconsider <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s somewhat negative and militaristic image. The clear message was that `` if you knew him, you'd like him,'' she said. The short spot shows <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> with a piece of cheese hanging between his mouth and his pizza slice. He pulls it up to his mouth with his finger, realizes he's on-camera, and winks. Meanwhile, a narrator is saying with mock seriousness, `` Former Secretary of State <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>. The man with the best credentials of anyone to be president, who's also a lot more like you than you think. Vote for him.'' Also on the air for only one day was another favorite _ a <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> ad questioning whether <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had left any legacy in the numerous jobs he has held. The ad depicts a man's shadow walking across a virgin expanse of snow, crunching as he goes, yet leaving no mark. `` After 20 years of walking in the footsteps of giants, is n't it odd that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has left no footprints at all?'' a narrator asks. `` It's almost like he was never there.'' `` That was the most effective line he had going. It was a good ad. It had the ring of truth and it was appealing,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>, a professor, analyst and author. But <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, coasting on his <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> victory, did n't use the ad in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>. Nor did the campaign carry out plans to reshoot it in the sand for use in Southern Super Tuesday states. It aired once in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, snow and all, then was pulled. `` They were believing the press clippings that they were on the way to the nomination,'' said <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>. `` I almost think <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> thought it was time for healing -LRB- after <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> -RRB-. And he was trying to lower that negative of being too harsh.'' Other effective ads included <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s attack on <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for promoting Belgian endive as a remedy for farm woes, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ads mocking <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s populist message and flip-flops on issues. <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON> makes a case for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s standard biographical ad _ a fast-paced montage of photographs that begins and ends with the printed words, `` A president for the 90s.'' It is being used virtually everywhere and has been the only <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ad on the air in several states. `` It suggests solidity and stability and puts in place basic premises about what he's done,'' <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON> said. `` It's not the funniest, it's not the glitziest, but it is the most effective except for the <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> ad.'' <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> won nominations for the worst TV spots of the campaign season, as did the information-packed <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> ads produced by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Garth </PERSON> for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary. `` The <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> spots in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> were awful, disgraceful. They were just tepid. I felt they were very poorly communicating <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s message,'' said <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON> <PERSON> Du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> was skewered for visual gimmickry and amateurish production. <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON> cited one spot in which `` he rotates like a statue and you see his squared-off jaw and he looks straight into the camera. I expected it to be an ad for aftershave.'' <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> `` looks very strange'' in many of his ads, <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s initial ads `` made him appear rather evil. They emphasized his harsh nature,'' said <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>. The early <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> ads tried to put the best face on <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>'s military background by noting, for example, that no wars were started by presidents who had been generals. But they used ponderous music and ominous images and some gave the impression of `` <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Caesar </PERSON> returns to the Rubicon,'' said <PERSON> Jamieson </PERSON>. `` It was almost terrifying.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Crime     05-09 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Crime,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Braces For Bush Attacks On Crime Issues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER B. DALY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 During last year's legislative session, <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> relegated a capital-punishment bill to committee, effectively killing it. <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> supports the death penalty. But he also supports <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ and his move spared the governor from having to veto a death-penalty bill. The incident illustrated how carefully the Democratic presidential front-runner is treading when it comes to crime and punishment. But Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has already attacked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on some crime issues, and made it clear that there's more criticism to come. At a news conference in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> last week, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> faulted both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> for not supporting the death penalty for `` drug kingpins.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> opposes the death penalty under all circumstances. Another potential point of vulnerability is the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prison system, one of the most overcrowded in the country. With 6,600 inmates, it is 72 percent over capacity. The legislature, pushed by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, allocated nearly $ 1 billion to expand capacity, but it will take years to ease the overcrowding. And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> ran into a storm of protest last year when <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, a convicted murderer, walked away from a weekend furlough. He was arrested later in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and convicted of raping a woman and beating her husband. The <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> case prompted angry calls for elimination of furloughs for first-degree murderers serving life sentences. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> defended the furlough program for months, on grounds that it helped prison administrators by giving lifers an incentive to behave and gave him a record for judging commutation requests. But after key members of the legislature deserted him and opponents gathered enough signatures to place a furlough ban on the fall ballot, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> reversed himself and dropped his opposition to the ban. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> graduate and member of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, is generally considered a liberal on domestic issues, including some criminal matters. In addition to his opposition to the death penalty, he favors controls on handguns. However, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dismayed some liberals when he instituted a statewide program of police roadblocks to stop motorists to check for drunken drivers. He has also backed a bill that would tighten criminal sentencing and _ for the first time in state history _ allow prosecutors to appeal sentences they consider too low. As governor, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> created a statewide anti-crime council to coordinate the efforts of prosecutors, judges, legislators, police and citizens. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has never missed one of the council's monthly meetings, says he would create a similar federal program In his campaign literature, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> touts a 14 percent drop in crime in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> since 1983 and the lowest homicide rate of any industrial state. However, most experts attribute the decline to the aging of the state's population, combined with a low unemployment rate. And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> does n't mention the embarrassing fact that <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> remains the nation's auto theft capital. Overall, state Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Harold </PERSON>, a Democrat who chairs the legislature's <ORGANIZATION> Criminal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, gives <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> high marks. `` As an attorney and as someone who's sat in the governor's chair, he has a tremendous overview He's a traditional liberal in his theories, but if something's not working, he wants to change it and get on to the next case,'' <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> said. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, a professor of criminology at <ORGANIZATION> Northeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said governors can actually do little about criminal behavior _ and presidents even less. But he said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> should be credited for his attention to criminal issues he can influence. `` When you look at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he appears to have liberal leanings, but ones that do indeed seem to be supported by facts,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagans'Astrologer Bjt   05-09 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagans' Astrologer, Bjt,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nancy's Astrologer Objects to `Circus Atmosphere'</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: Jayj in 7th graf is CQ</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> woman who gave stargazing advice to first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says she is `` a serious, scientific astrologer and ... I really do n't like this circus atmosphere.'' <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> confirmed in a telephone interview from her <LOCATION> Nob </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> home Sunday that Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had consulted her since 1981, as reported by former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, in his book, `` For the Record,'' scheduled to go on sale today, said that `` virtually every major move and decision the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> made ... was cleared in advance with a woman in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> who drew up horoscopes.'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> said he did not know her identity. Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, however, said, `` I ca n't deny that she has consulted me. I am very uncomfortable, however, with the situation because normally I never discuss the identity of my clients, and I never discuss their affairs.'' `` I am a serious, scientific astrologer and I am really not one of these clowns, and I really do n't like this circus atmosphere,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, who has been practicing astrology since 1960 and has written three books on the subject. <PERSON> Jayj </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, a member of the board of directors of the Association for Astrological Networking, said Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> is `` a specialist in political consulting'' who lectures on `` geopolitical'' astrology. `` She's viewed as a competent professional, and a specialist,'' <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> heiress and Republican political activist, said she did astrological work for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1980 presidential campaign. She declined to give the details. `` After the assassination attempt, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> asked me if she could consult me because she was worried about the president's safety, as well she might be,'' Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> said She said Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> telephoned her at `` various times,'' sometimes on Saturday afternoons from Camp David, the presidential retreat in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, as <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> reported. `` I certainly never controlled the president's actions,'' she said. `` Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would want to know if something was a safe time and I certainly advised her on that.'' Ms. <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> said her advice is based on the exact time and place of a person's birth. In a separate interview with television station <ORGANIZATION> KRON </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, the astrologer said she advised the first lady `` when it was unsafe to fly.'' She added, `` I never had any contact with the president.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReganProfile     05-09 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Regan Profile,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regan More Suited To Financial Than Political Jungle</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Regan's Record Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From the day that <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> moved from head man at <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> to secretary of the treasury in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Cabinet, the World War II combat veteran found the White House to be alien territory. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>'s gruff <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> manner had served him well on Wall Street but failed to help him survive the political battleground of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> or his conflicts with a determined first lady. `` When I was chief executive and I said ` Jump,' people said, ` How high?''' he recalled shortly after coming to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1981. When he said the same thing as treasury secretary, he added, people asked, `` Well, do you have an environmental impact statement, what do you mean by high?'' Nevertheless <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> quickly made his mark, winning the president's praise as `` a very fine salesman'' for the tax-cutting policies that were a hallmark of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. In 1985, <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, then the White House chief of staff, got <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s approval to switch jobs. `` As a former <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> colonel and Wall Street star, he fancied the view from the boss's elbow,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>, who had been <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s deputy, later wrote. `` Once <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> took over as chief of staff, there was only one man in charge,'' <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Speakes </PERSON>, then the chief <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, recalls in his recent book. `` The early reports were glowing,'' said <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>. `` No hint of an accident waiting to happen.'' Troubles soon came, however. When the president underwent cancer surgery in July 1985 <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> aroused First Lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s ire by ordering a White House helicopter to fly him to <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. According to <PERSON> Speakes </PERSON>' account, he decided after a telephone call from Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that he would go by automobile, as she did. After <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s prostate operation the following year, the first lady and the chief of staff again found themselves at odds. She thought he was scheduling her husband for too much activity too early in his recovery. Then came the revelations that the administration had sold arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> while seeking freedom for American hostages and that some of the money had been funneled to help the Contra rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. When the presidential board headed by former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> made its report on the controversy in February, 1987, it found <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> responsible `` for the chaos that descended upon the White House.'' `` He, as much as anyone, should have insisted that an orderly process be preserved,'' the board said. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> protested, `` Does a bank president know whether a bank teller is fiddling around with the books? No!'' This, however, was not the world of finance, but the world of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> politics. The capital quickly sensed that <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> was on the way out, and there were widely believed reports that Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was helping him on his way. The end came on Feb. 27, 1987, when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> chose former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> as his new chief of staff. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, hearing the news from then-national security adviser <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> who had seen it on a Cable News Network broadcast, responded with a one-sentence letter of resignation. Now, 15 months and many sentences later, <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> is giving his side of the story in his book `` For the Record: From Wall Street to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' The book, being published Monday, reveals that Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used astrology to determine the timing of the president's speeches and travel. Once again, judging from the president's reaction, <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> may have chosen the wrong adversary. `` I would have preferred it if he'd decided to attack me,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Friday, `` and apparently from what we hear he's chosen to attack my wife, and I do n't look kindly upon that at all.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Regan-Excerpts     05-09 1124</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Regan-Excerpts,1090</SECOND>
<HEAD>Excerpts From Regan Book</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Regan's Record Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Following are excerpts from <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>'s book, `` For the Record: From Wall Street to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Virtually ever major move and decision the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> made during my time as White House chief of staff was cleared in advance with a woman in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> who drew up horoscopes to make certain that the planets were in a favorable alignment for the enterprise. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> seemed to have absolute faith in the clairvoyant powers of this woman, who had predicted that `` something'' bad was going to happen to the president shortly before he was wounded in an assassination attempt in 1981.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 At one point, I kept a color-coded calendar on my desk -LRB- numerals highlighted in green ink for ` good' days, red for ` bad' days, yellow for ` iffy' days -RRB- as an aid to remembering when it was propitious to move the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from one place to another, or schedule him to speak in public, or commence negotiations with a foreign power.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 A full month after the president's release from the hospital, his schedule was still a dead letter because Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s ` Friend' had not provided a list of auspicious days The whole month appeared inauspicious for the president.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 There was no choice but to humor the first lady in this matter. But the president's schedule is the single most potent tool in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, because it determines what the most powerful man in the world is going to do and when he is going to do it. But humoring Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> we gave her this tool _ or more accurately, gave it to an unknown woman in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> who believed that the Zodiac controls events and human behavior and that she could read the secrets of the future in the movements of the planets.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The president was deeply concerned about the hostages, but an inventory of the time he spent on this problem in a given month would undoubtedly show a very low total _ minutes rather than hours. Like that first meeting with -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> Adviser -RRB- <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, the events that snowballed into the catastrophe that came to be known as the Iran-Contra affair made little impression at the time that they happened. Much of what happened was hidden from the president -LRB- and incidentally from me -RRB- by <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> and his successor as national security adviser, Adm. -LRB- <PERSON> John </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and by the remarkable young Marine who was a virtual stranger to both of us, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 On Nov. 12, only nine days after the story broke, the pressure from the <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> was so great that the president has no choice but to talk to a congressional delegation. ... The president told them that we had, in fact, supplied arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, but it was only a small amount and we had not swapped arms for hostages. Some of those men were skeptical ... <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> never lied to them; -LRB- or in my experience, to anyone. -RRB- And there is no question in my mind that he believed that he was telling the truth. He knew, of course, that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had shipped anti-tank and anti-aircraft missiles to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and that certain Iranians had exerted influence over terrorists in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> to facilitate the release of the American hostages. But in <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s own mind that did not constitute a swap of arms for hostages.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The president ... is a ruddy man, with bright red cheeks. He blanched when he heard <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s words. The color drained from his face, leaving his skin pasty white. ... Nobody who saw the president's reaction that afternoon could believe for a moment that he knew about the diversion of funds before <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> told him about it. He was the picture of a man to whom the inconceivable had happened.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 It was <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for whom Western observers, and especially <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> were unprepared. ... She is a stylish, handsome woman with an intense and intelligent manner. It was she, far more than her husband, who kept the conversational ball rolling. ... At this dinner party ... she did not hesitate to make use of the opportunities offered to her to educate the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on the intellectual and philosophical basis of the Soviet policy. ... After the door had closed behind the Gorbachevs, -LRB- Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB- said, `` Who does that dame think she is?''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who had already shown signs of irritability, now became angry ... ` You're more interested in protecting <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> than in protecting <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON>!' she cried. ` He's got to go. He ca n't do his job; he's an embarrassment to <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON>. He should be out.'
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` The parts on abortion have got to come out,'' -LRB- Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> -RRB- said -LRB- about the State of the Union address. -RRB- I pointed out that the president had particularly wanted some language on this subject included in his address. `` I do n't give a damn about the right-to-lifers,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> retorted. `` I'm cutting back on the <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> stuff, too. It's too long and it's not appropriate. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s got to be shown to be in charge.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The president himself sent out no strong signals. He listened, encouraged, deferred. But it was a rare meeting in which he made a decision or issued orders.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 In the four years that I served as secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, I never saw President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> alone and never discussed economic philosophy alone and never discussed economic philosophy or fiscal and monetary policy with him man to man. From first day to last at <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, I was flying by the seat of my pants. The president never told me what he believed or what he wanted to accomplish in the field of economics. I had to figure these things out like any other American, by studying his speeches and reading the newspapers.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 I'm sorry, Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON>, but I wo n't be in any more. This is my last day. I've been your secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> for four years and your chief of staff for two. You do n't trust me enough even to tell me who my successor is and make a smooth transfer. I deserved better treatment than this. I'm through. I'm very disappointed.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 I wish to state that my admiration for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as president remains very great. My judgment of him as a man, in light of my final experience as his chief of staff, underwent a certain change, but this is irrelevant. ... any man who had seen as much of the world as I had seen when I came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> knew better than to put his trust in princes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Regan-Quotes     05-09 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Regan-Quotes,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Regan's Record Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Readers of <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>'s book, `` For the Record,'' might be confused by lack of quotation remarks around most of the quotations from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. In reporting his conversations with the president, the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chief of staff consistently put his own words inside quote marks, but leaves them out in reporting the president's remarks Thus, a typical passage reads: Hi, <PERSON> Don </PERSON>, the President said. Is this a good time to talk? I said, `` Could n't be better, Mr. President.'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> explains it this way; `` Out of deference to the office and the man, I have not enclosed language attributed to the president in quotation marks except in cases where his words have already appeared in print elsewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Mozambique-War Bjt   05-09 0929</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mozambique-War, Bjt,0956</SECOND>
<HEAD>As War Drags On, Mozambique Reaches Out To Its Enemies</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>By GREG MYRE</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAMPULA, Mozambique (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government, mired in a civil war that is sinking the country ever deeper into poverty and famine, is making overtures toward its two main enemies. The 12-year-old war is stalemated, and <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s Marxist leaders now appear interested in making a deal with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to complement generous amnesty terms offered to rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> Mozambique </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION>. Since the amnesty law took effect in December, an estimated 500 to 700 guerrillas have surrendered with a government promise that they will be not be punished for their war activities. Also, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s president, <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Chissano </PERSON>, sent Cooperation Minister <PERSON> Jacinto </PERSON> <PERSON> Veloso </PERSON> to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> on April 26 with a conciliatory message for President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>. The possibility of a summit meeting was discussed. A day earlier, <PERSON> Chissano </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Gavin </PERSON> <PERSON> Relly </PERSON>, chairman of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s giant <ORGANIZATION> Anglo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, to discuss possible business ventures. <PERSON> Chissano </PERSON> continues to accuse <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> of supporting the rebels in violation of a 1984 non-aggression pact, a charge <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> denies. However, <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>'s decision to renew high-level contacts with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> suggests it forsees no quick military solutions to the war, which the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says has claimed an estimated 100,000 lives in the past three years. The fighting in northeastern <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION> province, visited recently by a group of Western journalists, is representative of the deadlocked war in many parts of <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION>. The rebels roam the countryside at will, attacking villages to obtain supplies and often kidnapping residents as forced laborers. Government troops fight an almost entirely defensive war, attempting to protect economic installations and to keep transporation routes open, but seldom seeking out the rebels in the bush. Eighteen of the 21 district capitals in <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION> province have been attacked since last October. Refugee camps are swelling and food is in short supply in most areas. Hospitals dispense aspirin and anti-malaria tablets, but not much else. Repeated rebel sabotage on the railway that runs across the province prompted a European consortium to halt repair work until the government can guarantee their security. `` The frequent attacks disrupt the villages and discourage people from staying and planting crops,'' said <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyambir </PERSON>, the provincial governor. `` We are trying to reorganize the military and stabilize the civilian situation.'' Nyambir and other local officials cited several incidents that highlight the military's shortcomings. Nyambir pointed on a map to the three main rebel camps in <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION> province, but said the military has never been able to carry out attacks against the locations. When rebels raided the northern coastal city of <LOCATION> Angoche </LOCATION> last year, they they were repelled by the military, local officials said. However, the rebels kidnapped 300 civilians and the army made no attempt to pursue them. Because of poor communications, word of rebel attacks on remote villages can take a week to reach the city of <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION>, the provincial capital, <PERSON> Nyambir </PERSON> said. He said the provincial government has been unable to promote the amnesty campaign because <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION>'s radio station is n't powerful enough to broadcast much beyond the city limits and leaflets have n't been published because the printing press is broken. Nonetheless, 16 rebels seeking amnesty turned up in the town of <LOCATION> Moma </LOCATION> on April 9, but local authorities had no idea what to do with them, <PERSON> Nyambir </PERSON> said. It took a week before someone could reach <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION> and receive instructions on how to handle the surrendered men. The war has made <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> one of the poorest countries in the world and is the primary cause of a famine in which an almost 6 million of the country's 14.5 million people need food assistance. There are more than a million refugees inside the country and 700,000 Mozambicans have fled to neighboring states, including <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The rebel movement, created in 1977 by what was then white-ruled <LOCATION> Rhodesia </LOCATION>, opposes the Marxist policies of the <ORGANIZATION> FRELIMO </ORGANIZATION> party government, but beyond that its aims are vague. No government acknowledges supporting the rebels and they appear to have generated little support among the civilian population with their repeated raids on villages in which they often kidnap residents and force them to carry supplies and grow food at rebel bases. `` Nowhere have I found support -LRB- for the guerrillas -RRB-,'' said <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>. `` I've only found fear and terror.'' Those who have been kidnapped say the guerrillas make little effort to explain their positions. `` They showed me a picture of their leader and told me that when they come to power everyone will have a car,'' said <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Alouta </PERSON>, 31, who was kidnapped by the rebels in July and escaped a month later. `` I did not believe what they told me or understand what they were fighting for.'' The rebels threatened to kill anyone who left their camp and made no attempt to become friendly with the captured civilians, <PERSON> Alouta </PERSON> said. Refugees at several different camps in <LOCATION> Nampula </LOCATION> told similar stories. In the town of <LOCATION> Ribaue </LOCATION>, some residents said they sleep in the surrounding woods to avoid being kidnapped in one of the rebels frequent nighttime attacks. The hospital and the local administration building were destroyed, but a cotton gin manages to keep going, despite four guerrilla raids in the past year. The nearby village of <LOCATION> Lalaua </LOCATION> sits empty following a rebel attack in early April in which 50 huts, about a quarter of the village, were burned. The rebels did not occupy the village, but residents are afraid to return, saying they fear a repeat attack.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0134EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-RunningAgainstCarter 1stLd-Writethru   05-09 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Running Against Carter, 1st Ld-Writethru,710</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 3rd graf to restore Dukakis' first name</NOTE>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Bush Nostalgic for the Good Old Days of 1980</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A movie called `` Rappin'' is playing on <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Box </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> this month _ five times this month, to be exact _ in which the credits are accompanied by a song whose repetitive refrain is simply, `` Ca n't stop, wo n't stop. Ca n't stop, wo n't stop. It might be the anthem for the current <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. He ca n't stop, wo n't stop, running against <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. The vice president is trying to take advantage of the fact that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the probable Democratic nominee, often comes across as a cool, detached technocratic official in the Carter mold. But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s tactic may backfire if voters decide the similarity ends there. `` Malaise'' is n't prominent in the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dictionary. He likes to talk about hard work and miracles. He says, incessantly, that he wants to be a builder, not a great communicator. He could give lessons in upbeat. Nonetheless, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is hoping that when voters look at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> they will see <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> interest rates, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> oil prices, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> wringing his hands at Camp David, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> confronting a rabbit with his canoe paddle, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> agonizing while the American flag was being burned and the embassy looted in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. Actually, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is more than hoping that will happen; the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> standard-bearer is trying to make it happen. Reagan-Bush ousted Carter-Mondale in 1980 and crushed Mondale-Ferraro. The temptation to relive these races must be more than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his staff can bear. Once <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> emerged as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s likely opponent, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign manager quickly labeled the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor a `` Northern-fried Carter'' and the concept became a staple on the campaign trail <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> loves to ridicule `` gloom and doom'' Democrats. In <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, last week he spoke gleefully about `` the gloom and misery'' emanating from the Democrats' camp. On Tuesday, he said, `` Let <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> go around here talking about pink slips, despair, pessimism in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. I'll be the guy out there talking about hope and opportunity.'' Whatever he is, however, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no gloom and doom Democrat. Speechwriter <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON> recently told <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Broder </PERSON> about the guidance he got when he signed on with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in 1987: `` The first thing he said was: Do n't be negative about the hopes for the country and do n't be overly negative about the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration.'' <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> writer that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> described `` a problem he saw in the 1980 and 1984 campaigns, the over-preoccupation with what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ca n't do at home or in the world He said that was n't his experience in life, or in the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governorship.'' There has been some unmistakable gloom and doom in the Democratic party psyche, but it was the upbeat candidates _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ who survived the 1988 primaries. And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is n't likely to make it easy for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to pin the Carter malaise on him. `` The best <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is yet to come,'' he says after running down what he sees as the shortcomings of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. `` ... We're going to build a future of hope and pride and opportunity. Still, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wo n't stop. `` It all sounds like <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> reborn again for the third time,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said about the 1988 Democrats. In <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> `` hangs over the Democrats like a shadow, an unwanted reminder of the last time they were in the White House.'' In <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, he said no matter whether the Democrats nominate <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, `` It's going to be a very clear choice on the issues ... as clear as 1980, or as clear as 1984. `` I do not want to see this country go back to the failed policies of the past. Here's where things were when we started: `` Interest rates were 21 -LCB- percent. Inflation was double-digit. ... Every family getting wiped out. Employment going the wrong way. This pride in our country down, the military weak. And somebody said to me after I cited those horrible statistics, ` What are you doing? Running against <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>?' `` I said, ` No, I do n't want to run against <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. But we do n't want to go back to the policies that the liberal Democrats had under <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> that led us to those days of malaise.''' If only <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> were on the ballot.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant bureau chief in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought Bjt   05-09 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought, Bjt,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drying Up Reservoirs, Fields In West, Southeast, Texas And
Minnesota</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Drought has threatened water supplies in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION>, forced some <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> ranchers to sell starving cattle and allowed topsoil and crop seeds to blow away in the northern Plains. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, residents were ordered to reduce water consumption by 25 percent. <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> residents were asked to cut usage by 10 percent. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> also has imposed water conservation rules. In northern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, 70 people attended a 24-hour vigil last week to pray for rain. `` It's almost like you saw in the typical 1930s scenes where clouds of dust are moving across the fields,'' says <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Kollman </PERSON>, district conservationist in <LOCATION> Norman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> `` You see drifts of dirt almost like snowdrifts in the road ditches. There is lots of dirt in the air and lots of dirt in the houses.'' In the West, two straight winters of poor rainfall and scanty snowfall in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> led to drought. In the Southeast, parts of the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> have been receiving below-normal rain since 1984. In <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the drought began last fall. Parts of the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> enjoyed above-normal rain last summer, but less than expected snow last winter. `` I'm not sure how much longer -LRB- the area -RRB- can take it. It's scary,'' said extension agent <PERSON> Judee </PERSON> <PERSON> Wargo </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where rainfall since October has measured 0.73 inch, compared with an average 3.17 inches for the period Last week, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON> said <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> and <PERSON> McMullen </PERSON> counties needed federal disaster assistance because of drought. <LOCATION> Starr </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has had just over 5 inches of rain since Sept. 1, a period in which it normally would receive most of its average annual rainfall of 20 inches. Ranchers have had to sell cattle for lack of hay and forage. In <LOCATION> Jim </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wells </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> west of <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, extension agent <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said ranchers have started burning thorns off prickly pear cactuses so cattle can eat them. But even the cactus is drying up in some areas, said <LOCATION> Starr </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> emergency official <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>. Despite above-normal rain in <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> in April, `` the drought is still on with a passion,'' said state climatologist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is having its worst water shortage in 11 years, officials said. Winter precipitation was normal or above normal until the end of January. `` But February and March of this year were dismal, drought-producing months,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Barbato </PERSON>, a hydrologist with the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Statewide, snow-melt runoff in rivers through mid-summer is expected to be an third of normal, said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>, chief of the state's newly activated drought center in <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>. As in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, some ranchers in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s central valley are selling cattle and appealing for federal grain subsidies. Portions of southern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> have been classified as in a severe drought and sections of eastern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> are in an extreme drought, said <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, snow survey superintendent for the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Soil Conservation Service. Rainfall in April was near or above normal for the whole state, but <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> depends on winter precipitation for most of its water. Snowpacks around the state range from 81 percent of normal on <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hood </LOCATION> to 3 percent of normal in <LOCATION> Klamath </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> is at its lowest level since the 1936-1937 dust bowl years. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s mountain snowpack this winter was only 75 percent of normal, meaning less to feed streams during the spring and early summer. Irrigation reservoirs in the state's eastern and central part range from 98 percent full to 10 percent. `` If we get into a normal July and August _ normally very dry months _ we're going to have some real trouble,'' said <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Farnes </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> snow survey team. The weather service says a mild drought is in effect across northern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and eastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Farmers in parts of <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> have stopped planting for lack of rain, and sugar beet seeds that were planted are blowing off some fields. Thousands of acres of grass grown for lawn seed have dried up, while high wind last week blew away tons of topsoil. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mickelson </PERSON> on Friday declared 12 counties state disaster areas. In the Southeast, drought has hit the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION> especially hard, with the rainfall between June 1984 and April 56 inches. `` That's better than a year's normal rainfall for the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. You're seeing impacts on recreation, hydro generation, water quality,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> TVA </ORGANIZATION>'s chief of reservoir operations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cambodia-Remains     05-09 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-Remains,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING to fix cycle designator</HEAD>
<HEAD>State Department Quietly Sends Cambodia Message On U.S. Remains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has quietly sent <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> officials a message in an effort to win the release of the remains of 80 American soldiers the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government claims to have from the Vietnam War, a congressman disclosed. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, in a verbal communique delivered through the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> two weeks ago, offered <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft and military honor guard to pick up the remains <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, along with Reps. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, D-Ind., has been lobbying <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials to pursue an offer made to the congressmen by a high-ranking <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> diplomat during the lawmakers' visit to <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> in January Cambodian officials said they were willing to release the remains, but have insisted that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials receive them, not an intermediary. <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> said American diplomats had been reluctant to pursue the remains question with <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has no formal diplomatic ties with the Communist regime. But the congressman said last week that the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sent the message offering the honor guard and transportation after two high-ranking members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> _ Reps. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, D-Ala., and G.V -LRB- <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, D-Miss. _ also applied pressure on the administration. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lambertson </PERSON>, deputy assistant secretary of state for east <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> affairs who has been handling the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> remains issue for the administration, did not return telephone calls Friday. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on the condition of anonymity said the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> has `` succeeded in engaging the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> regime on this issue -LRB- on behalf of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> -RRB- and we hope its going to work itself out.'' `` We are encouraged,'' said the official, who refused to discuss details of the talks or confirm that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military escorts and aircraft have been offered. <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON> in late March sent a telegram to <PERSON> Tep </PERSON> <PERSON> Henn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>'s ambassador to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, saying they would pick up the remains and personal effects. <PERSON> Tep </PERSON> <PERSON> Henn </PERSON>, in a telegram dated April 21, responded that he found the congressmen's message `` encouraging,'' but set no specifics for turning over the bodies. The congressmen sent another telegram to the ambassador last week confirming the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s offer and suggesting early June as a possible time for a transfer. Some have questioned whether <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> can have 80 soldiers' remains since the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates that only 82 soldiers were lost in <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> terrority during the war No <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> remains have ever been returned by <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. The identified remains of 179 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers have been returned from <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> since 1973 _ 152 from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, 25 from <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and two from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, according to Lt. Col. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The congressional group also hopes to win the release of a <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> man who was arrested in <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> territory one year ago. No reason was given for the arrest of Sterling <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Animas </LOCATION>, and it was not known why the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran was in the region.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PollutionOptimism Bjt   05-09 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pollution Optimism, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Research Findings Brighten Air-Quality Prospects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Smoggy air in the nation's cities may become significantly cleaner than official projections indicate, new discoveries about auto pollution suggest. Planned new federal regulations to make gasoline less volatile _ harder to vaporize _ may cure a problem only now being recognized, some analysts say. This is the evaporation of gasoline from cars in use, called `` running loss.'' All cars have systems designed to control evaporation while parked. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> has assumed the system also prevents significant vapors from escaping when the car is driven. On a hot day, it now appears, the system can be overwhelmed and release five to 25 times more unburned gasoline than is permitted in exhaust. The findings are so new that no one has had a chance to calculate their effect. But they suggest that plans for less volatile gasoline may significantly reduce this previously underestimated contributor to smog. `` Official predictions have been under-predicting'' future improvement with the less volatile gasoline in use, said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, a partner in <ORGANIZATION> Sierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, air pollution consultants. Gasoline vapor is the major raw material for urban smog. Chemical reactions with other pollutants in sunlight produce ozone, which can make your chest feel tight. In proposing a regulation to cut maximum summer gasoline volatility by 22 percent from the current voluntary standard, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> hinted at the new findings last August. But it said results were too preliminary to use, and did not disclose numbers. However, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> disclosed numbers at an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> briefing last week. He said <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has results showing that `` running loss'' can reach 10 grams -LRB- about half a liquid ounce -RRB- per mile; his own tests show a maximum of 2 grams per mile. The current limit in exhaust is 0.41 gram per mile. While declining to reveal specific test results, <LOCATION> Tad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wysor </LOCATION>, an engineer in the Emissions Control Technology Division of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> lab, said of the 10-gram figure, `` We have n't seen anything that it's wrong but there's not a lot to back it up.'' <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> wants to know whether this has been happening all along, or whether, as <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> believes, only recently because of the rise of fuel-injected engines _ more than 80 percent today compared with practically none in the mid-1970s. Fuel injection systems continuously recycle uninjected fuel back to the tank, carrying heat from the engine compartment and making the fuel hotter. This causes a pressure build-up which, with today's fuel, overwhelms the under-hood charcoal canister that captures and recycles the vapor. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, director of automotive emissions control for <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s environmental activities staff, said `` You ca n't put a big enough canister under there'' to capture all running losses, but <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s volatility regulation `` definitely'' will eliminate them. For several reasons, volatility has surged in the 1980s. That causes more evaporations and more ozone. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has known that cars passing its stationary emissions test while using fuel of 9.0 pounds vapor pressure, typical of 1975, flunk badly on today's fuel, which may be 11.5 pounds or higher. <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> says that on one part of the test, <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> researchers found 16 times as much emissions using 11.5-pound fuel compared with 9.0-pound fuel. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> last week published the annual list of areas failing to meet national ozone standards. The list rose from 62 to 68 names, and environmental groups said the data showed that smog is getting worse. Most analysts have blamed the failure to reduce ozone levels more quickly on the failure of states and <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to require stricter controls such as vapor recovery systems on gasoline stations. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> and Territorial Air Pollution Program Administrators, said running losses could be a reason some areas violate the standard, but, `` I do n't think this is clearly the major reason.'' Still, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Wysor </PERSON> said, `` If all these things fall into place, it's logical to expect this is a big source and another explanation that could be offered as to why attainment -LRB- of the standards -RRB- has been so hard.'' <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimated that volatility controls will reduce emissions of ozone precursors by 8 percent in polluted areas that do not have strict controls of their own, as <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> does. This did not include elimination of running losses. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said his impression from conversations at a recent meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Automotive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> was `` if we could get -LRB- both running and stationary -RRB- evaporative emissions under control we could reduce emissions by 10 to 15 percent,'' with `` exponential benefits'' to public health.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880509-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-09-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese     05-09 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese Defended by Employee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
