<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-TaxBill 1stLd-Writethru a0755 10-07 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tax Bill, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0755,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Final Action on Tax Bill Delayed as Senate Deals With Unrelated
Amendments</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 8th graf pvs bgng, `The bill's' with 3 grafs to UPDATE
with Manassas battlefield vote; Should stand for AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Friday beat back a series of unrelated amendments to a catchall tax bill, including one designed to benefit 2 million owners of home satellite dishes. But consideration of such proposals delayed until next week final action on the tax bill, which includes a `` bill of rights'' for taxpayers involved in disputes with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, and special relief worth $ 2.7 billion over three years for various groups, including farmers, artists and first-time homebuyers. By nightfall, an angry majority leader, Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, counted more than 100 proposed amendments still awaiting action and coaxed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> into cutting off any `` This list is crazy, nuts and getting crazier all the time,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` We ought to settle down and get our senses.'' Within two hours, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> announced senators had agreed to drop all but 29. Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> sided with <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, noting amendments dealing with everything but taxes, including sanctions against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, aid to the <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> rebels and a move to halt commercial development of the historic <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> battlefield in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. `` This is the typical tax bill,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` Everybody cleans out their desks and their trash cans and says ` we'll put it on the tax bill.' We've reached the point that if somebody does n't take the bull by the horns, we'll never finish.'' On the <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> battlefield issue, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 50-25 to approve an amendment by Sen. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., requiring the federal government to seize 540 acres of land to prevent further development on the site about 30 miles west of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> The House has approved the same provision, but the <ORGANIZATION> interior </ORGANIZATION> secretary has said he will recommend that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> veto it. In siding with <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> defeated a plan by Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., to authorize the taking of only 80 acres and allow development of housing on adjacent areas The tax bill's main purpose is to correct errors in the big tax overhaul enacted in 1986. But since this is the only tax bill with a chance of becoming law this year, senators view it as the last opportunity to have their pet amendments considered. But there is no assurance it will become law. The version approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is considerably different and there is some doubt that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> can negotiate a compromise before quitting next week. In a long day of debate over the bill, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> considered and rejected amendments calling for: _ An end to what Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Tenn., called discrimination against owners of home satellite dishes by television His amendment was aimed at helping the 2 million dish owners, most of them living in rural areas, whose television and satellite dish have become prime sources of contact with the outside world. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s amendment would have required that programs provided to cable systems be made available to dish owners, and ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> to extend network programming into isolated areas that can not receive broadcast signals. Opponents, led by Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, said the amendment was unnecessary, that `` there are no unfair trade practices in pricing and distribution of satellite programming.'' Managers of the bill said <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>'s amendment had no chances of becoming law as part of the tax legislation. _ An 18-month study of whether government workers should get equal pay for jobs of comparable worth Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., proposed the study and was opposed vigorously by conservatives, who said it would lead to new federal requirements for what any worker could be paid <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> called the dissent `` blind opposition to knowledge.'' _ A symbolic endorsement of the right of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to finance abortions for poor women _ Raising from $ 17 a month to $ 38 the maximum tax-free mass-transit benefits that an employer could furnish workers Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, offered the amendment in the name of fairness, saying the government already provides a much higher subsidy for corporate executives to park their limousines. He would have paid for the change by doubling, to a maximum of $ 7,700, the tax imposed on gas-guzzling cars _ most of them luxury imports.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>JL1115p7</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Fashions     10-07 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Fashions,0787</SECOND>
<HEAD>Armani Show Reconfirms Position As Milan Fashion Leader</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIELA PETROFF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> has done it again. No matter how much you steel yourself against the charm of the designer and his staff, or shut your eyes to the sumptuous surroundings of his dowtown <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> palazzo, and blot out the beauty of past collections _ it is to no avail. The clothes speak for themselves and confirm that <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> is the leader of the <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION> runway. `` Ravishing,'' exclaimed <PERSON> Kal </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruttenstein </PERSON>, fashion director at <ORGANIZATION> Bloomingdale </ORGANIZATION>'s, after Wednesday night's show which took the fashion crowd by surprise with evening wear that excelled the daytime clothes, usually the Armani forte. `` Breathtaking'' sighed <PERSON> Elin </PERSON> <PERSON> Saltzman </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Saks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fifth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Avenue </ORGANIZATION>, as she kissed a satisfied Armani backstage. But a comment by <PERSON> Janie </PERSON> <PERSON> Samet </PERSON>, fashion editor of the French daily <ORGANIZATION> Le </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Figaro </ORGANIZATION>, was worth a thousand adjectives. `` Il est le seul.'' -LRB- He is the only one -RRB-, she pronounced, implying that only he in the school of Italian ready to wear could pose a threat to French fashion. Usually <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> is a step ahead of the pack, showing the direction fashion will take the following season. He was the first to present androgynous women and one of the earliest to send short skirts and lingerie tops down the runway. This season he preferred to flow with the tide, presenting a quiet, calm Spring-Summer 1989 collection, with delicate ethnic touches and a romantic maiden air, inspired by the avant-garde minimal designer <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gigli </PERSON>. It is the softness of the fabrics more than the cut of the clothes that give the collection its ethereal mood. Even <PERSON> Armani </PERSON>'s daytime suits with his new jacket rounded at the shoulder and hem and curved gently at the waist, worn over a long slim skirt, or wide pants, are stitched in such airy tweeds they could float down the runway all on their own The blouse, always a strong point at <LOCATION> Armani </LOCATION>, becomes so light that at times it looks like a chiffon scarf tied around the midrift. Fabrics are either checked or striped or printed in floral and geometric patterns. His evening wear is adorned in exquisite gold and silver embroidery and beading, reminiscent of Indian fabrics. To emphasize the softness of his collection, <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> takes the edge out of the hemline, leaving it unevenly stitched and un-ironed, as if it had been tucked up in a hurry. This do-it-yourself look spells grim days ahead for seamstresses and private maids. As the day goes on fabrics get lighter and sheerer. A series of cocktail suits were in Liberty and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> porcelain prints with matching stockings. Then came the negligee gowns, or elongated slips in simple navy satin, worn over a chiffon, fringed shawl. Embroidery started out slowly as piping on an otherwise simple gown or Tuxedo suit, to cover increasingly large areas of cloth until it became the entire dress. Thus a youthful strapless gown was made up entirely of chiffon flowers bunched together to look like an Old English porcelain bouquet, and long skirts, pants and even shorts with matching tops were lavished with gold and silver threading and beaded craftsmanship. The latter was a throw-back to the ornate Indian embroidery popular in the 1960's as confirmed by the Indian evening bags which completed the look. When they were not dazzling with jewels, his evening gowns were <PERSON> Ophelia </PERSON> - like in wispy chiffon, with a criss-cross bodice, and long skirt, with a dainty underskirt peering through Chiffon, in ombre pastel shades and creamy pinks was also used for pants and skirts alike to go with richly embroidered evening jackets. To make sure the look remained innocent, <PERSON> Armani </PERSON>, the perfectionist, showed the flatest heels of the week. More slippers than shoes, closed in the front, but strapped at the back, they usually were made out of fabric. <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> who tried the boudoir look several years ago, but did n't seem to like it, shied away from the bare-breasted nude look which has been the shock item on the runway this week _ except for a single black chiffon gown in which white embroidered piping served a double purpose: it concealed bare breasts, while at the same time it framed a bare midrift right down to the navel The Armani price tag for the Spring-Summer 1989 is not outrageous, just expensive. A jeweled jacket costs approximately $ 3,000 to $ 3,500 depending on how elaborate is the embroidery, while an entirely embroidered outfit can run as high as $ 7, OOO. The dilemma is do you buy a new car, or do you dress <PERSON> Armani </PERSON> and walk.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-PlaneCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0778 10-07 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Plane Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0778,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sightseeing Plane Crashes, Kills 42</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to UPDATE with total number aboard. Pickup
3rd graf pvs `It said...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sightseeing plane with 46 aboard crashed into a hotel and exploded shortly after takeoff from a northern <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> city Friday, killing all but four on board, an official daily said Saturday. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said the four others on the Soviet-built Ilyushin Il-14 were injured, and some workers in the hotel also sustained injuries in the accident in <LOCATION> Linfen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> province, about 400 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. It said the passengers on the piston-engine light transport plane were all employees of a local knitting factory. They had paid $ 4.30 each for a 15-minute air tour of the region. The daily said the plane went down one minute after takeoff, crashing into the roof of the Xinqiao Hotel. Four passengers managed to escape seconds before the plane exploded. The four crewmembers were all killed. The sightseeing service, operated by a local air company, had just begun on Oct. 1, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s National Day. <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shichang </PERSON>, director of the knitting factory and one of the four on board who escaped, said his group had seen a television report on the sightseeing flight and decided to take it `` as we have earned a lot of money recently. We never imagined we would have this disaster.'' It was the second major plane accident of the year in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, following the crash of a Soviet-designed Ilyushin Il-18 four-engine turboprop operated by the national airways <ORGANIZATION> CAAC </ORGANIZATION> in January that killed 108 near the southwest <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> city of Chungking. In August another <ORGANIZATION> CAAC </ORGANIZATION> jetliner skidded off the runway at <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> airport and plunged into the harbor, killing six crew members and one passenger.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DodgerBlues     10-07 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dodger Blues,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Dodgers Are Coming Back _ To Queens</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been 31 years since `` Dem Bums'' became beach bums, since <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Malley </PERSON> moved the <ORGANIZATION> Brooklyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The wounds have yet to heal. Today, the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> return _ to <LOCATION> Shea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, not <LOCATION> Ebbets </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION> _ to play the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> for the National League pennant. But to many Brooklynites, this homecoming to the borough of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> will be happy only if the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> go down in defeat. `` The old <ORGANIZATION> Brooklyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> were a very special team, in a very special time, in a very special place. The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> are not really the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Brooklynite </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Macrillo </PERSON>. `` They do n't look like the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>, they do n't sound like the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>,'' she continued. `` It's very easy to root for the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION>.'' Ms. <PERSON> Macrillo </PERSON>'s cheers are echoed by the many <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> fans who swore off the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> on Oct. 23, 1957, when <PERSON> O'Malley </PERSON> moved the team of <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, Pee Wee <PERSON> Reese </PERSON> and <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Snider </PERSON> closer to <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> than <LOCATION> Coney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Boxing publicist <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudd </PERSON> describes `` Dodgeritis'' as a borough-wide lethargy brought on by the shift; state Sen. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartosiewicz </PERSON> spent years trying to get support for an `` Ebbets Dome'' and a new team; <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> columnist <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamill </PERSON> writes of his vow to `` never forgive, never forget'' the late <PERSON> O'Malley </PERSON>. `` They abandoned us, they left us. I feel no compunction to root for the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON>, founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Brooklyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION>. `` When they left us, I was angry. ... When they left, they took the soul. The soul left <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Ebbets </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>, home of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>'s beloved Bums, was razed in 1960. As far as many younger fans know, the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> have always played in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s Chavez Ravine. `` I think a lot of this is passe now and over with,'' said <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knicks </ORGANIZATION> public relations man <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Agostino </PERSON>, a die-hard <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> fan who wrote a book about the team's history. `` I do n't read as much into this as other people do. `` If you were 15 when the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> left, you're 46 now. What do you remember about the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION>? They've been gone 31 years. The <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> have been playing for 26 years.'' Try telling that to <PERSON> Hamill </PERSON>, who welcomed the <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> to the playoffs with a vitriolic column in which <PERSON> O'Malley </PERSON>'s name was preceded each time with an epithet. `` Some wounds never heal,'' wrote <PERSON> Hamill </PERSON>, who broke a three-decade boycott of <ORGANIZATION> Dodgers </ORGANIZATION> home games this week to root for the <ORGANIZATION> Mets </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- who, by the way, have eight native Californians on the roster -RRB-. `` I go to the enemy camp'' _ <LOCATION> Dodgers </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, that is _ `` as a hostile witness,'' he wrote. `` And the vow still holds. Never forgive. Never, ever forget.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-BRF--China-Tiger     10-07 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Tiger,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Escaped Tiger Causes Panic, Injuries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tiger escaped from its cage, attacked a boy and triggered a panic that left 40 people unconscious during a circus in rural china, a newspaper reported today. The Workers Daily reported that the tiger broke out of its cage after being hit by its trainer for failing to carry out a trick during a show in northern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> province last month. It said 40 people were knocked unconscious when hundreds of spectators surged toward the exit. One primary school student was attacked by the tiger and required 48 stitches in his face. The daily did not say how the tiger was subdued and returned to its cage. It said a similar accident involving the same circus troupe had occurred the previous month and called for improved safety measures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Medflies 1stLd-Writethru a0752 10-07 0400</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Medflies, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0752,0408</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents Brace For Spraying Against Medflies</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 3 grafs to UPDATE with spraying under way; picks
up 3rd graf: `The National ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three pesticide-laden helicopters took off on an aerial spraying mission Thursday night to fight the Medfly infestation that has set up a base in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> and the city's toney <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Side </LOCATION> `` They're currently over <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenney </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> controller at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> where the choppers departed from shortly after 8 p.m. The spraying program is the first step in an all-out attack against the Mediterranean fruit fly, a pest that destroys about 250 varieties of produce. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> again forecast coastal fog for the area Thursday night, but officials moved the starting time up 2 -LCB- hours to 8 p.m. hoping to beat the rolling fog bank. The spraying was ordered because 47 Medflies were found in yards since Sept. 26, a serious infestation that if allowed to spread would threaten fruits and vegetables that are a major part of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s $ 15.5 billion-a-year farm economy. The Thursday flight was set for a 35-square-mile area of 100,000 residents that includes middle-class stucco homes, mansions, swank Rodeo Drive shops and luxury car dealerships, all subject to the honey-like stickiness of the Malathion spray. Along with parts of <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, officials are spraying sections of western <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and the adjacent cities of <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>. At <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Cadillac </PERSON> on the corner of <LOCATION> Olympic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bundy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Drive </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, a caravan of about 100 shiny Caddies left the sales lot Wednesday night for an underground parking lot at a bank building six blocks away, sales manager <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said Thursday. He said several of the cars were returned to the sales lot Thursday morning for potential tire-kickers, with the luxury car exodus to be repeated at nightfall. The pesticide poses no health risks, health officials say, but the sticky corn syrup bait mixed with the Malathion could mess up a car's paint job. Museums in the area covered their outdoor statues. Agricultural Commissioner <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Spaugy </PERSON> said the fight to save the state's farm industry knows no economic boundaries. `` We're encouraging people to cover up their Rolls Royces just like they would cover up their Pintos,'' he said on Wednesday
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Debate-Distortions Bjt   10-07 0885</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Debate-Distortions, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Both Sides Say Opponent Played Fast and Loose With Debate Facts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON> once said there were three types of lies: lies, damned lies and statistics. Republicans and Democrats are arguing about all three in the aftermath of the <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle-Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> debate. Each side accused the other vice presidential hopeful of playing fast and loose with the facts in Wednesday night's encounter. A Republican truth squad put out a six-page analysis of `` Bentsen Distortions and Errors'' on Thursday, while Democrats confined themselves to five pages on `` <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s Factual Mistakes.'' In less polite parlance, that means lies on such subjects as Social Security, poverty and just how well <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> knows European leaders. Here is a look at some of the points in dispute:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>POVERTY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` Poverty has n't gone up in this administration. It has n't gone down much either.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> says that in 1980, 13 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population, or 29.3 million people, were living in poverty. The rate rose to 14 percent, or 31.8 million people, in 1981, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first year in office, peaked at 15.2 percent or 35.3 million in 1983, then gradually dropped back to 13.5 percent, or 32.5 million, in 1987, the latest year available. Measured since 1980, the poverty rate is up by one-half percentage point; measured since 1981, it is down by that much. In either case the actual number of poor people is up, since the population has grown.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOCIAL SECURITY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 When <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` voted eight times to cut the benefits on Social Security,'' the Republican fired back, `` You know that I did not vote to cut Social Security benefits eight times. What I have voted for and what Senator <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> has voted for is to delay the cost-of-living adjustments.'' He said <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, too, had twice voted for freezes, and that <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> took a similar position at a governors' conference. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokesman, did not dispute those votes, but said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` does n't understand that freezing or delaying the <ORGANIZATION> COLA </ORGANIZATION> cuts benefits. ... The bottom line is smaller checks.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PACS and HONORARIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, asked about being the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s biggest recipient of political action committee money _ $ 1.5 million for his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> re-election campaign, said, `` I do n't find it embarrassing at all.'' He said his $ 10,000-a-place `` breakfast club'' for lobbyists was `` a real doozy'' of a mistake, but `` perfectly legal, and you have all kinds of such clubs on the Hill.'' But <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s $ 10,000-a-seat club was considered unusual, although other congressional leaders do arrange regular briefings and entrees for favored donors. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, who accepts no speaking fees, charged that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has `` collected over a quarter of a million dollars of honorariums now, speaking to various interest groups.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s camp said he donated almost $ 20,000 of his honoraria to charity in 1986 and $ 14,302 in 1987. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules prohibit senators from keeping speech fees above 30 percent of their salary.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ENVIRONMENT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> apparently mixed up his CFCs and CO2 when he praised <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration efforts to grapple with the ozone problem. `` For the first time, we are talking about the impact of C02 to the ozone layer,'' he said. But CO2 _ carbon dioxide _ does not deplete the ozone layer; chlorofluorocarbons, or CFCs, do. Carbon dioxide does add to the global warming phenomenon known as the `` greenhouse effect'' _ another environmental problem.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>BOSTON HARBOR</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 After <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> did `` virtually nothing'' to clean up <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, `` the dirtiest waterway in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> charged that a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> veto of a clean water bill had `` made it impossible to move ahead at that time on <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>.'' But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> dragged his feet on the cleanup back in 1978, the final year of his first term as governor, when he prepared an application to the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> seeking a waiver from the 1972 Clean Water Act requiring secondary treatment of sewage being pumped into the harbor. His successor completed the application in 1979. By the time the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> rejected it in May 1983, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was governor again. Under court pressure, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and the state legislature created a public authority to undertake the $ 6 billion cleanup _ without the 75 percent federal funding available in the 1970s.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FOREIGN AFFAIRS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` I've been to <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> many times to meet with our negotiators as we are hammering out the INF treaty. I've met with the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> political leaders _ <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, Chancellor <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. I know them. They know me.'' According to a visitor's log kept by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made only one visit to the Swiss city during the nearly four years the <ORGANIZATION> Intermediate-Range </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> treaty was under negotiation. That was in February 1987. He also visited <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> last Feb. 7-8 and met again with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms control negotiators, but that was two months after the treaty was signed. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> spokesman, said he believed the senator met <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> when the West German chancellor stopped by a dinner <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had with <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s chief of staff at a conference of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> a year or so ago. <PERSON> Nesbitt </PERSON> said he knew of at least one meeting with Thatcher: Last July when the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister attended a dinner with senators on a visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VeteransDepartment Bjt   10-07 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Veterans Department, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Votes Cabinet Status for VA; Supporters Say Changes Will Be
Minor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Elevating the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to full Cabinet status will involve only changing a few signs outside the building, proponents said after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted overwhelming support of the change. Rep. <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, D-Miss., said the cost of the change approved Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will come to less than $ 1 million in 1989 and will give the nation's 27 million veterans direct access to the White House The <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> has estimated that converting the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> into a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> department would cost $ 33 million over five years. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> vote sent the compromise bill, making the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> the government's 14th Cabinet department, to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which was expected to add its approval. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> backs the move, and it was his public announcement of support last summer that gave impetus to the legislation. House approval came on a voice vote, overriding objections from opponents who called the move an act of election-year pandering that will result in increased future costs for veterans programs. `` This is an act of great hypocrisy,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., who said he had heard numerous colleagues complain privately that the legislation should not be adopted `` Why does <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> do things like that? We do it because of special interests,'' <PERSON> Porter </PERSON> said. `` Members are in craven fear of retribution at the polls. I think the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are looking to have people of courage to govern them. You ca n't serve every special interest in our country without ever adding up the bottom line.'' The new <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, which would go into effect in March, would represent the fifth new Cabinet department since 1960. Opponents pointed out the irony of it receiving support from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who began his presidency promising to eliminate two Cabinet departments _ Education and Energy _ an idea he later abandoned. The Veterans Administration, according to supporters of the legislation, already has the fifth-largest budget among federal agencies and merits being put on par with other Cabinet departments to ensure that the money is properly administered `` This says to the millions of men and women who've worn the uniform of our armed forces that we care,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N </LOCATION>. He said placing a veterans' advocate at the table with the president and other Cabinet members will give greater voice to their needs. A primary sponsor of the measure, Rep. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, noted that the <LOCATION> VA </LOCATION> hospital system is suffering from a $ 600 million budget shortfall and that Cabinet status would help it make the case for full financing. `` This will go a long way toward guaranteeing that the veterans of the future are going to be taken care of,'' <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> said. According to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> serves 27 million veterans and 49 million dependents or survivors with a budget of $ 30 billion. It will dispense $ 14 billion in income maintenance and $ 626 million for education and rehabilitation assistance this year. The agency and its 240,000 employees administered 90,000 patient beds in 534 health facilities and will see 20 million outpatients this year. It runs 109 national cemeteries and will bury 300,000 veterans this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0125EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicalWaste     10-07 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medical Waste,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Passes Bill To Track Medical Waste From Start to Finish</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is moving to slap controls on medical waste, from the vials of AIDS-infected blood washing up on <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> beaches to the used hypodermic needles picked out of trash bins by children in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. The vehicle to attack the growing problem of carelessly discarded medical waste is a bill that would require a so-far reluctant <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to set up a system to track the waste from creation to disposal. The legislation, given impetus by this summer's publicized cases of infectious materials littering ocean and Great Lakes shorelines, was passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday by a 390-28 margin. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has approved a more limited control blueprint. Lawmakers in both chambers say they see no difficulty working out a joint product that can be sent to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourns next week. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, says action is needed because `` the illegal disposal of medical waste is spreading like an epidemic across the country. This waste is not just repulsive, it can literally kill people. `` According to recent federal studies, as many as 18,000 people each year may contract hepatitis B from accidental contact with medical waste,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. `` Hundreds of those infected will ultimately die from the infection.'' The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan would cover waste produced by hospitals, clinics and labs in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> states of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. The program, however, could become national in scope because any other state could decide to have its waste covered by the plan and gain authority to act against incoming waste not meeting the tracking system's requirements. `` This is a national problem,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore. `` The medical waste system in this country is broken It is overloaded, and in effect it is starting to regurgitate what it can not keep down.'' Expected to form the basis for the final bill, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan would apply to 10 types of medical waste, including blood, hypodermic needles, scalpels and surgical and laboratory waste that has been in contact with infectious agents. The enumerated items would have to be segregated from other medical waste. The tracking system would have to contain assurances that a generator knows the waste reached a disposal facility. The legislation does not, however, set any standards for actual disposal, such as burning or using a hazardous waste landfill. Supporters said there was no time this year to work out these details. They add, however, that it already is illegal to dump such waste into waterways. Violators of the tracking requirements could be slapped with a civil fine of up to $ 25,000 for each day of violation and a maximum criminal penalty of two years in prison and a fine of up to $ 50,000 per day of violation. <PERSON> Luken </PERSON> said the medical waste problem goes beyond the beach foulings that closed stretches of oceanfront in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> the past two summers. `` Last year, careless doctors in <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- and <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> put contaminated needles and vials of infected blood into dumpsters,'' he said. `` Kids found the needles and blood vials and played ` doctor' with them _ splattering blood on each other and giving each other injections that could have proved fatal.'' House members said they believe <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> already has the authority to act against medical trash under various hazardous waste control laws. In 1978, the agency announced plans to regulate medical waste, but six years later it said lacked evidence those wastes were causing enough harm to justify regulations. Instead, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> released a package of advice to hospitals on handling and disposal. Since then, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has formed a task force to rethink the issue. `` EPA has dragged its feet on this matter,'' <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON> said. `` EPA told us that as of this summer, they had budgeted exactly one staff position to deal with the medical waste issue. That is why we need this legislation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Mother'sMilk Bjt   10-07 0787</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mother's Milk, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Reports New Means Of Fortifying Mother's Milk</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Stands for PM-Farm Scene</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new recipe has been developed for fortifying mother's milk to help premature babies `` barely bigger than a man's hand'' survive and grow normally, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said `` The immune properties found in mother's milk are so much more important to preterm infants because they are subject to many more infections than full-term infants,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON>, physician in charge of the project at the Children's <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. But extremely premature babies, some of them weighing less than two pounds at birth, require more concentrated nutrients than mother's milk provides, he said. Most currently get a preemie formula based on cow's milk until they reach about three pounds and are growing well. After that, some may be switched to mother's milk mixed with a commercial fortifier. Concern about the practice of feeding the formulas to the tiny infants during their first month of life prompted <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> and a former colleague, Dr. <PERSON> Cutberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, now at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, to look into ways of using breast milk from birth. Their research at the center, which is based at <ORGANIZATION> Baylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> and is funded by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, included tests of commercial formulas and new recipe possibilities. The work was described in a report issued Thursday by the agency. <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> said the new recipe includes mineral salts that are readily absorbed by the infants, and protein and energy from powdered skim mother's milk supplied by the center's own human milk bank. Although the recipe is being used for research purposes, <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> said he doubts whether it will be feasible to produce a commercial fortifier made from human milk, noting that there are n't many human milk banks for this purpose But he said the findings from the recipe research should lead to better fortifiers so that very low-birth-weight infants can have the infection fighting factors present in breast milk when they most need it right after birth. The milk would still have to be taken from the mother with a breast pump, fortified with the forumla and fed to the baby through a tube. The initial concern has been to get enough protein and energy into the tiny babies, and `` we did n't pay much attention to minerals,'' <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> said. Calcium and phosphorous were the main problem, a lack of which could `` compromise growth, impair healing of chronic lung disease and lead to bone malformations,'' <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> said. The scientists came close to matching the `` in-the-womb retention levels'' of these minerals by adding calcium lactate and sodium or potassium phosphate to mother's milk. Infants averaging only 2.2 pounds at birth retained 86 percent of the calcium and 80 percent of the phosphorous they would have retained if still in their mother's uterus and are `` the best rates we have seen,'' <PERSON> Schanler </PERSON> said. According to <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, who now directs nutritional sciences at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION>, the government's <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> requires formula companies to add a minimum amount of calcium without sufficient regard to its form. `` That's not enough for these tiny infants,'' <PERSON> Garza </PERSON> said. `` You need to look at the form as well as the amount.'' For example, <PERSON> Garza </PERSON> said, the calcium salt added to commercial formulas is tribasic calcium phosphate, which is not very soluble. `` It's like rock,'' he said. `` Most of it probably does n't get absorbed -LRB- into the infant's system -RRB- but comes out in the stool. Calcium lactate is much better utilized.'' Although the scientists recognize that human milk has less calcium and phosphorous than both regular and preemie formulas, they say the minerals are in a form more easily absorbed by the infants. Also human milk may have unknown factors that enhance infants' absorption and retention. Formula companies have not been able to duplicate these conditions in commercial preparations and compensate by increasing the concentration of minerals, the report said. Another former colleague, Dr. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, a physician now at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, said the higher concentrations of minerals in commercial formulas may benefit the very low-birth-weight infants after they leave the hospital. After discharge, the mothers either chose to continue on unfortified breast milk or switch to regular infant formula. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, who tracked the infants for a year, found that the breast-fed babies had a lower bone mineral content than those who got commerical formulas. But they grew equally well on either, he said. Body weight, length and head measurements were the same for both groups. <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> recommended that pediatricians regularly evaluate the mineral status of nursing preemies, but he added that `` the risks do not outweigh the benefits of breast feeding.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirbusShootdown     10-07 0613</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airbus Shootdown,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychologists Say Military Needs To Better Understand Stress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Psychologists who studied the downing of an Iranian civilian airliner in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> say the military needs to better understand stress and should spend more on psychological research and improve its crew training. The judgment of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> cruiser crew that mistakenly shot down the Iranian plane July 3 was clouded by misconceptions caused by stress, the psychologists said. `` There is much knowledge about how decisions go wrong and how they can be improved that is not being put to use in military decision-making,'' Dr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Slovic </PERSON>, a psychology professor from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION>, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel Thursday. Dr. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Zornetzer </PERSON>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s office of naval research, responded that the service does try to consider stress and is spending $ 12 million a year on basic research into psychological questions. Another $ 18 million is being spent to apply the results of that research to <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> programs. While progess is being made, he said, `` it must be clearly recognized that these research problems are among the most difficult and complex in the entire research spectrum.'' The hearing by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> policy subcommittee was part of the panel's examination of the destruction of <ORGANIZATION> Iran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> Flight 655 that killed all 290 people on board. It was shot down by the cruiser <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> in the mistaken belief that the commercial jetliner was a military plane diving toward the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation attributed the incident to stress-related mistakes made by the crew of the Aegis-class cruiser, one of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s most sophisticated warships. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said crew members, under battle-caused stress after just finishing a firefight with Iranian gunboats, misread or misinterpreted a variety of electronic data from the Aegis computers. Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the panel, said, `` Misinterpretations of data provided by the Aegis weapon system and chaotic communications in the command center have pointed up troubles with man's ability to make fast, accurate decisions in combat. Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nisbett </PERSON>, a psychology professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>, noted that the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> crew was on alert for an attack by Iranian planes. The crew members interpreted the data to see what they expected to see, he said. `` Expectations can color what people think they see, and what they remember, to a far greater degree than is recognized by common sense,'' <PERSON> Nisbett </PERSON> said. `` Magicians and card sharks have long made a living on this principle, and in the last 30 years or so psychologists have learned a great deal about the scope of the principle in daily life events,'' he said. <PERSON> Nisbett </PERSON> also noted the example of the USS Stark, which was hit by an Iraqi missile in May 1987, killing 37 seamen. Top officers on the Stark were disciplined for not firing their weapons against the Iraqi plane, and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ships in the region were on a high state of alert after that. The Vincennes crew wanted to avoid another incident like that involving the Stark, <PERSON> Nisbett </PERSON> said. Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmreich </PERSON>, a psychology professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> crew members did n't communicate among themselves well enough. `` The communications problems evident in the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> incident closely parallel those uncovered in analyses of the causes of crashes in civilian and military air transport,'' he said. Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pew </PERSON> said another risk arises from the highly automated, computerized nature of modern warships like the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>. `` Research is badly needed to understand when and just how much automation to introduce in situations where the ultimate control and responsibility must rest with the human operators,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Reagan-Disruption 4thLd-Writethru a0764 10-07 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan-Disruption, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0764,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Disrupts Reagan Appearance</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 10th graf pvs bgng, `He just,' to
UPDATE with Secret Service questioning McKnight, releasing him</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man claiming he had been the subject of government mind control experiments disrupted an appearance by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> before a <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> fund-raising dinner Friday night. The man made a long and rambling argument that he had been mistreated, while guests at the $ 1,000-a-plate event attempted to drown him out with applause. The disruption occurred just after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> concluded his address to the crowd. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, standing just behind the lectern he'd used for his speech, seemed puzzled as he strained to hear the man. Secret Service agents on the scene made no attempt to approach the man, who identified himself as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>, 58, of <PERSON> Inkster </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>. But after several moments of yelling toward <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who was approximately 150 feet away on the podium, the president interrupted him. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went to the microphone and said that he was having difficulty hearing the man, although he said the protester seemed to `` feel strongly'' about what he was saying. But the president, showing increasing impatience and anger, shouted that `` I do n't think it's fair to subject the people to all of this. Why do n't you write it in a letter and send it to me.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> had arrested the same man in 1985 when he tried to deliver papers about mind control to former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> during a <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> appearance. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, asked later if <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had felt endangered by the intruder, said, `` No, not at all.'' `` He just said, ` Who was that man and what did he want anyway?''' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, paraphrasing the president. Secret Service Special Agent <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON> said late Friday that <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> was interviewed and released. No charges were filed. `` He was interviewed. He made no threats against the president. He meant no harm to him. That's the main thing the Secret Service was interested in,'' <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON> said. Few incidents of this sort have plagued <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in recent years as security surrounding him was tightened substantially following his shooting on March 30, 1981 by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> remains confined to a mental hospital in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> After <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the man to be quiet, the concluding part of the president's portion of the program proceeded and he left without incident. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> did not say how he had gotten into the event, nor whether he had paid the $ 1,000 fee. But pressed on that, he said, `` I just walked in.'' The man stood apart from the dinner tables in an area not far from the president occupied by a pool of reporters admitted to cover <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech. It was apparent that <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents determined the man was not presenting any physical threat to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and therefore no attempt was made to rush him. `` I was quiet and let him speak. I was quiet and stood here,'' <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> told reporters. During his tirade, <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> had asked, `` Why do n't you take the mind control machine off of me, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>?'' `` Why do n't you use it on the communists that's here in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, and why do n't you get rid of communism in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>?'' he said. Several boos emanated from the well-heeled crowd of Republican donors, many of whom were heard shouting, `` Get out and shut up!'' <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> was arrested on April 24, 1985, when he tried to deliver to <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> a three-page typewritten document saying he was the victim of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government mind-control device. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>, who listed an <LOCATION> Inkster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, address on the document, said the device injured his eyesight and muscles and his ability to learn and to have sex. Two Secret Service agents knelt beside both sides of his chair after <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> completed his speech. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> resisted the agents and was taken to the rear of the room with his arm behind his back. <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> told reporters Friday night that he was treated for three weeks at a state psychiatric hospital in <LOCATION> Northville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, following the Carter incident. He produced a photocopy of what appeared to be a report from a <ORGANIZATION> Northville </ORGANIZATION> staffer, who said <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> `` rambled'' about the mind-control device. A woman who answered the telephone Friday night at the <ORGANIZATION> Northville </ORGANIZATION> hospital said state law prevented her from giving any information about current or former patients. She hung up without giving her name. There were two McKnights listed in the Inkster telephone directory. <PERSON> Lula </PERSON> <PERSON> Belle </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON> said neither she nor her daughter were related to <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McKnight </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0121EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BusinessOutlook Bjt   10-07 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Business Outlook, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 9 a.m. EDT; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Business Leaders See Strong Growth, Then Slowdown To Stem
Inflation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's top business leaders today offered an optimistic view of economic prospects, predicting growth will slow enough next year to avoid a severe acceleration of inflation. The Business Council, composed of 62 chief executives of the country's largest corporations, predicted that the economy, as measured by the gross national product, will grow 4 percent in 1988, the best in four years. `` We are living in a continued strong economy,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest bank. `` We are very close to full employment, and the inflation numbers ... are generally felt to be in pretty good shape.'' The new GNP prediction, reflecting the consensus of the chief economists of about 20 member corporations, is 1.6 percentage points better than the prediction last May when the executives last gathered for their semiannual retreat at this resort town in the mountains of western <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Some economists in the spring still were worried about lingering aftershocks from the stock market crash of October 1987. Growth proved to be stronger than nearly anyone anticipated, and now the concern is that it is too vigorous and likely to fuel inflation. But the Business Council's economists are projecting GNP growth of 2.5 percent next year and less than 2 percent in 1990, in line with what the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> considers necessary for a `` soft landing'' of the economy to a sustainable, non-inflationary expansion. The economists were expecting more inflation, an increase from a 4.2 percent rate this year to 5.1 percent next year, but `` no one expected a return to the high inflation rates of the late 1970s and early 1980s,'' their report said. They also foresaw a modest rise in interest rates next year followed by some easing in 1990. The rate on 30-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bonds, which tend to run about 1.5 percentage points below fixed-rate mortgages, should increase from an average of 9.1 percent this year, peak at 10.2 percent over the next 18 months and average 9.5 percent in 1990, the council said. The business executives were troubled, however, about the prospects for reducing the federal budget deficit to meet the targets of the Gramm-Rudman law and for shrinking the trade deficit without a further decline in the value of the dollar. `` The business community generally remains very concerned about the twin deficits and of what we are afraid and convinced will be the undesirable price we'll pay for it if we do n't solve it,'' said <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Pfizer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the health care company. The economic panel saw only negligible improvement through 1990 from the current budget gap of about $ 150 billion. The Gramm-Rudman law, however, calls for a deficit of $ 136 billion in 1989 and $ 100 billion in 1990. The trade deficit is expected to shrink from $ 170 billion in 1987 to $ 134 billion this year and to below $ 100 billion by 1990. But the business executives said the dollar, which fell steadily through 1986 and 1987 before beginning to rebound this year, will have to start falling again. A cheaper dollar makes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods more affordable on overseas markets. The economic panel predicted the dollar would be worth 120 Japanese yen and 1.68 German marks, down from 134 yen and 1.88 marks currently. `` I think it's unfortunate that the dollar firmed from the first of the year. I think we were closer to the right range earlier in the year than we are today,'' said <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Butcher </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. The economic forecast was issued at the beginning of a two-day conference at which the executives will hear from speakers including <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanker </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>; Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, co-chairmen of a blue ribbon commission studying the budget deficit; and Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., and Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, D-Pa., chairmen of the congressional budget
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxBill Bjt   10-07 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Bill, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate OKs Bill Excluding Interest on College-Bound U.S. Savings
Bonds</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: Top prospects uncertain</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is eagerly lending its support to a plan, already endorsed by Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, that would help lower - and middle-income families use <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings bonds to finance higher education The proposal would provide a tax exclusion for interest earned on a bond that is redeemed to pay for college or vocational education. Its sponsor, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., said the plan is simple and risk-free, giving `` children security in their future without creating a new bureaucracy or spending program. Even though it was recommended by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in his budget, endorsed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his presidential campaign and passed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday on a 94-0 vote, there is no assurance it will become law. That is because the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> attached it to a catchall bill whose main purpose is to correct mistakes and clear up ambiguities in the far-reaching tax overhaul package enacted in 1986. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill also includes a variety of special tax cuts costing about $ 2.7 billion over three years, plus the tax increases to pay for them. By comparison, the version approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has about $ 7.5 billion worth of tax cuts and increases. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration opposes several parts of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> bill, and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders are reluctant to give in to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on some of those provisions. With <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> pressing to adjourn next week for the year, it may be difficult for <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators to agree on a compromise. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders hoped to wrap up work on the bill today. Senators spent most of Thursday debating an amendment that would have raised taxes on cigarettes, liquor, wine and beer to pay for part of a big anti-drug bill. The tax increase is likely to be considered again next week when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> considers the drug legislation. The amendment, sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, was defeated on a 60-33 vote. A substitute by Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, that would have cut a handful of spending programs, including legal-services aid and low-income energy assistance, to fight drug abuse, failed 72-22. Earlier, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> wasted little time approving <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s amendment to help families pay for education The provision is not in the House-passed tax bill. Under the proposal, which <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> first introduced a year ago, a family could avoid paying taxes on the interest earned on bonds that are redeemed to pay for college or vocational schooling. The full exclusion would be available to families with incomes under $ 60,000 and would be reduced gradually as income rises, disappearing for those whose earnings reach $ 80,000. Present law allows the owner of a savings bond to avoid taxation on the interest earned until the bond is redeemed; the interest is exempt from state and local taxes. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s plan would simply turn the deferral into an exclusion if the bond is used for education. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic presidential candidate, has proposed a different method of helping finance higher education. He would create a program under which students could borrow their tuition and repay it through payroll deductions after they graduate. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said his exclusion would not increase the federal budget deficit. Included in his amendment is a provision offsetting the costs of the benefit by eliminating in most cases the personal exemption now claimed by parents for a dependent who is 24 or older and a full-time student. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill to which <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s proposal was attached has dozens of special tax benefits for farmers and other off-road users of diesel fuel, first-time homebuyers, corporate research efforts and workers who receive educational or legal assistance from employers. The measure includes a `` bill of rights'' for taxpayers involved in disputes with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Not voting on the savings bond interest exemption were Sens. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, R-Neb.; <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, R-S.; and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MovieAntitrust     10-07 0371</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Movie Antitrust,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>20th Century Fox Charged With Contempt In `Block Booking' Movies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Twentieth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has been charged with contempt of court for allegedly forcing some theaters to book unpopular movies in exchange for the right to show popular films. An indictment returned Thursday by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> accuses the company and an employee of violating the terms of a 1951 antitrust order in booking movies, including the blockbuster `` Aliens,'' from 1984 to 1987. The alleged `` block bookings'' were made by <PERSON> Leila </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, who managed <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>'s Indianapolis-Milwaukee branch office, the grand jury said <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, a subsidiary of <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, denied wrongdoing. The action was brought under a consent decree settling a 1930s-era antitrust battle in which the government broke the big movie studios' control of the nation's theaters. Among the practices barred by the consent decree is block booking, or requiring a theater to agree to show one or more movies, often unpopular films, in exchange for the right to show a successful movie. The grand jury accused <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> of violating a provision against block booking in a 1951 consent decree the company signed that stemmed from the antitrust case, according to an announcement by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> that was released in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The indictment alleged that <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> improperly entered into distribution agreements with theater companies for several hit movies. The announcement did not name the theater companies involved. The indictment alleged that from January to July 1985, exhibition of `` The Flamingo Kid'' was conditioned upon theaters also taking the less popular `` Johnny Dangerously''; from July 1984 to January 1985, `` Cocoon'' was `` block booked'' with `` Prizzi's Honor''; from July 1985 to January 1986, `` Aliens'' was paired with `` Space Camp'' and `` Big Trouble in <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>''; and from March 1987 to June 1987, `` Mannequin'' was booked with `` Black Widow. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said it has a program to ensure compliance with the consent decree that includes employee education. `` Even the alleged offending conduct is, as the charge itself demonstrates, confined to only a portion of a single Fox branch involving a limited number of films,'' the company said in a news release.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Mammography-Medicaid     10-07 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mammography-Medicaid,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congresswomen Push for Medicare Payments for Mammography
Screenings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two congresswomen say they will push for legislation next year to allow full Medicare coverage for elderly women seeking mammography screenings, the X-ray technique used to detect early signs of breast cancer. `` We need to promote preventive medicine, not just pay for care once an illness has set in,'' Rep. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. Mrs. <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON> said the Medicare Catastrophic Coverage Act, enacted into law earlier this year, included a $ 50 reimbursement provision for the mammograms. `` A $ 50 mammogram is not readily available in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the congresswoman said. `` The average cost for a mammogram ranges from $ 80 to $ 200.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON> said the only place a woman can receive a mammogram for $ 50 is mobile van clinics. `` Most women, especially older women, simply will not submit to being examined by a stranger in a van in the parking lot of a shopping mall,'' she said. `` Not only is a woman more likely to undergo the test when under the care of someone she knows and with whom she is comfortable, but doctors are more able to identify changes over time, and are able to provide the analysis, counseling and follow-up that are necessary to effectively care for patients,'' she said. A bill introduced by Mrs. <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON> would remove the $ 50 cap, making Medicare coverage for mammogram screenings the same as for mammograms for women already diagnosed with breast cancer. The Office of Technology Assessment has estimated that screening women over 65 could reduce the breast cancer mortality rate by 50 percent after five years, according to Mrs. <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>. `` Breast cancer took the lives of 45,000 women in 1987, of which 28,000 were over age 65. Many of those lives could have been saved if mammograms were readily available and affordable to those women,'' she told a Capitol news conference. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> recommends that women over 40 undergo mammography screenings annually.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Guinness-Johnson     10-07 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guinness-Johnson,0288</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guinness Weighs Placing Johnson's Time In Record Book</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Editors of the Guinness Book of Records are debating whether to list Canadian sprinter <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> as the world-record holder for his 9.79-second 100-meter run at the Olympic Games in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 26, was stripped of the gold medal he won in the race Oct. 24 after testing positive for performance-enhancing anabolic steroids, banned by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Olympic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The committee erased his time from the books. The <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amateur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> banned <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> from competition for two years, while the Olympic committee awarded the first-place prize to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rival, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, who had finished second with a time of 9.92 seconds. `` It would be ridiculous to say he -LRB- <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> -RRB- did n't run the 100 meters in 9.79, because he clearly did,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> Newport </PERSON>, deputy sports editor of the Guinness records book, said Thursday. The annual publication lists world records for everything from sporting events to the heaviest human to the longest mustache. `` There's no denying he did the time,'' <PERSON> Newport </PERSON> said. `` That can not be taken away from him. We have to consider him for inclusion, although it has put us in a difficult position because of the drugs.'' Editors of the Guinness Book of Records will hold a series of meetings to consider the issue, <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> said, but he could not predict a date for their decision. Events from the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> games are too late for the book's 1989 edition, due on bookshelves Oct. 14. The Jamaican-born <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> already appears in an appendix to the 1988 edition of the Guinness book for his previous 100-meter record run of 9.83 seconds, set Aug. 30, 1987 in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TobaccoExports     10-07 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tobacco Exports,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tobacco Export Program Comes in for Capitol Hill Heat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm lawmakers are turning political heat on <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials over a tobacco export program marked by abuses that have become the focus of a <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> investigation. `` I think this is the worst disaster for an agriculture program that I have seen in my eight years in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, said Thursday at a hearing of his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> tobacco and peanuts subcommittee. At the heart of the controversy is a program providing exporters with credit guarantees assuring they will get their money for American agricultural products they send overseas even if the foreign buyers fail to pay. More than $ 30 million in such guarantees have been provided for tobacco shipments alone this year by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. But farm lawmakers are upset by an array of abuses and other problems besetting the program. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is investigating allegations that 14 companies obtained guarantees for exports by saying their shipments consisted entirely of American tobacco when they actually were a foreign and domestic blend. Lawmakers are irked by a <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> policy that provides guarantees for exports of blended foreign and domestic tobacco, although only for the American portion. They say the program is supposed to help farmers by spurring exports and thus should be limited to 100 percent American shipments. The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> also stands accused by lawmakers and congressional investigators of not finding fraud even when the service was warned specifically about it two years ago. And <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> on Thursday clashed with service Administrator <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON>, saying his claim that guarantees always were provided for the American portion of blended shipments was the opposite of what he told the panel four months ago and at variance with investigative findings. The question is a sore point with tobacco-state lawmakers who contend that a policy revision from <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> last month opens the door to credit guarantees for blended shipments for the first time. `` This is a coverup, Mr. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said. `` I resent that,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> replied. `` I do n't care if you resent it or not,'' <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said. `` You were covering up a fraudulent practice in the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>.'' Initial reports of blended shipments covered by guarantees emerged from <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in 1986, bringing congressional demands for an investigation. At the time, the service dismissed the concern as unfounded. Followup by the inspector general, however, determined that tobacco exports consisting of blended foreign and domestic products had been covered by guarantees as if they were 100 percent American. `` It makes my blood boil,'' Rep. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, said. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said he was `` infuriated'' by the disclosures, but added that he had seen no reason to question the assurances of exporters. He said the Iraqi report was put down to a rumor started by a rival exporter. The chairman then called on witnesses from the inspector general's office and the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, an investigative arm of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, who had testified earlier and were still among the spectators. Officials of the inspector general's office of the congressional <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> told the hearing that their investigation indicated guarantees were provided only for exports that were 100 percent American. They said they were told that the only exception was for a type of baby food that contained a small amount of oil not produced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> told the panel the baby food example indicated that `` the possibility existed'' that blended exports could receive credit guarantees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-07 0854</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0887</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even in its final day, the famed <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>'s Pharmacy drew celebrities such as <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON> and Meryl Streep before demolition crews began to make way for a $ 50 million theater, shopping and dining complex Hollywood stars, studio chiefs and even President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> bid a nostalgic farewell Thursday to their old haunt. Legend, but not fact, has it that actress <PERSON> Lana </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> was discovered as a high school ingenue sipping a soda at <LOCATION> Schwab </LOCATION>'s in 1933. But it is known that <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaplin </PERSON> used to walk behind the counter and make his own sodas, and that <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> was a frequent customer. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, one of the <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>'s regulars who found work outside of show business, sent a telegram to its owner, <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>. `` Dear Leon, Do you remember when the only thing I was running for was a casting call?'' read the White House telegram. `` I wish you the best, sorry it's gone.'' The message was signed `` <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> and The Gipper.'' <PERSON> Schwab </PERSON>, 78, closed the store in 1983 after 52 years in business to make way for the development that will replace it at the corner of <LOCATION> Sunset </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Crescent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heights </ORGANIZATION> boulevards.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WEST HOLLYWOOD, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Eden </PERSON> says she's hoping to land a truly wicked role to dispel her image as a goody-goody genie Miss Eden portrays a supermarket checker suddenly thrust into high society in tonight's <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> movie `` The Secret Life of <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>.'' `` Of course she's nice,'' Miss <PERSON> Eden </PERSON> said in an interview. `` What else would I play?'' And that's the problem. `` I make my living acting and nice roles are what people buy,'' she said. `` I have n't been playing nice people my whole life by choice, but this is a business after all.'' The buxom genie in the old television series `` I Dream of Jeannie,'' Miss Eden, 54, has played a couple of not-so-nice roles, but she still dreams that someday someone will give her a small but really nasty role in a big movie. `` Then the real <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Eden </PERSON> will step forward,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> McDaniel </PERSON> is planning to mark his 30th anniversary in country music by performing a charity concert on Halloween in his hometown, <LOCATION> Okmulgee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla </LOCATION>. The Oct. 31 concert will benefit the town's <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON>, a spokesman for the singer. <PERSON> McDaniel </PERSON> is known for his hits `` Baby's Got Her Blue Jeans On,'' `` <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> Saturday Night'' and `` God Made Love.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following moved on the business wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> is trying to get consumers to go in for an oil change. For their salads, that is, not for their LeBarons. The <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> chairman dropped by <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday to promote Villa Nicola olive oil, vinegar and wine, products of the <LOCATION> Tuscany </LOCATION> region of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> bought an estate in 1984. `` You ca n't get this many people out when you're showing a new car,'' <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> said as about 200 shoppers crowded around the gourmet foods section for a taste and an autograph. <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> said his family used to bring olive oil and wine from his estate to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> friends, who eventually said, `` Why do n't you put a label on it and sell some of it? he recalled. Now, <ORGANIZATION> Villa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nicola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> markets extra virgin olive oil, balsamic and <LOCATION> Chianti </LOCATION> vinegars and red table wine, all of it produced in the area around the estate, which is named after his father. If the company _ run by his daughter, <PERSON> Lia </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagy </PERSON>, and son-in-law, <PERSON> Ned </PERSON> <PERSON> Hentz </PERSON> _ ever turns a profit, the money will go to the <ORGANIZATION> Iacocca </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which funds diabetes research.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LYNCHBURG, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rev. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> plans a retirement village on his <LOCATION> Liberty </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> that will offer senior citizens everything but a graveyard. `` No plans for a cemetery,'' <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> quipped Thursday as he unveiled blueprints for the $ 210 million <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Village </ORGANIZATION>, which he hopes will house some 3,000 residents on a site overlooking <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the Christian school he founded. <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> said he has already had numerous inquiries from people interested in paying `` entrance fees'' ranging from $ 59,000 for a ground-floor studio apartment to $ 176,000 for a three-bedroom penthouse. The residents also would pay an additional $ 850 to $ 1,600 per month as a service fee. When they die, or if they otherwise leave the apartments, at least half of the entrance fee will go to their estate. <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> said residents will probably be the same sort of elderly Christians who watch his `` Old-Time Gospel Hour'' program and make donations to his ministry, although the development will be open to anyone over age 60 who can pay the entrance fee. The venture, which includes restaurants and stores, will be funded and built by <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <ORGANIZATION> Belleair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bluffs </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, a private developer. The project will need city approval, and <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> was careful Thursday to indicate he was not planning to stage a repeat of any of his past feuding with <LOCATION> Lynchburg </LOCATION> over taxes he refused to pay.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-YugoslaviaQ&amp;A     10-07 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Yugoslavia Q&amp;A,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>Problems Complicated By Government Structure</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Yugoslavia, Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s complex, cumbersome government structure and diversity of nationalities are major factors in its worsening ethnic and economic problems. Here is some background in question-and-answer form: Q: How does the government work? A: <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> is a federation of six republics and two autonomous provinces that are administrative parts of the largest republic, <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>. Power rests in the League of Communists, or <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Each republic and province has its own party hierarchy for political leadership and its own government for administration. Each republic and autonomous province sends representatives to the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION> leadership, headed by a 23-member Politburo, and the nine-man federal presidency. Leadership of those two bodies rotates annually. Only the premier of the federal government, which is primarily responsible for overseeing the economy and national defense, holds office for four years. The premier can be removed by a majority vote of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Q: Why is the system so complex? A: The 23 million Yugoslavs include about 30 nationalities. In an apparent attempt to prevent ethnic strife after his death, President <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> approved a 1974 constitution giving broad powers to each republic and province. He decreed that all decisions on major political questions must be approved by the leaderships of all republics and provinces, and national leadership posts would rotate annually to keep any republic from dominating. Q: What happened after <PERSON> Tito </PERSON>'s death in 1980? A: Unanimity is so hard to achieve that federal decision are weak compromises, and the largely state-run economy has deteriorated as a result. The foreign debt is $ 21 billion, unemployment 15 percent and the annual inflation rate 217 percent. More than 1,500 strikes were reported in 1987. Economic and political differences have grown between the rich northern region, which looks to the West, and the poorer, more backward south. Q: What is causing the current unrest? A: A mixture of ethnic strife, economic crisis and an ineffective political system. One fundamental element is the ethnic dispute in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>, a backward autonomous province in south that was the heart of medieval <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>'s great empire. <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> now is dominated by predominantly Moslem ethnic <PERSON> Albanians </PERSON>, who have the highest birthrate in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and are 90 percent of the province's 2 million people. Minority Serbs, most of whom are <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION>, say they are being harassed and began holding rallies in July. Serbs in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> found a supporter in the Serbian Communist party leader, <PERSON> Slobodan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>, who is trying to impose more Serbian control on <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> and the other autonomous province, <LOCATION> Vojvodina </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Milosevic </PERSON>'s opponents accuse him of using the street protests to seek greater national power for himself and <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881007-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-07-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DelaMadrid     10-07 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-De la Madrid,0774</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Says Relations With US Difficult But Make Mexico More
Independent</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
