<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Liberia 1stLd-Writethru a0622 03-22 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Liberia, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0622,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Twelve Arrested In Alleged Coup Plot</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with expanded government account
of plot, background. No pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MONROVIA, Liberia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police arrested 12 men, including an opposition party leader, in foiling a plot to overthrow the government and assassinate President <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, Information Minister <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowier </PERSON> said Tuesday. <PERSON> Bowier </PERSON> told a news conference seven plotters were still at large, including an army captain and two sergeants. He said those arrested included <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kpolleh </PERSON>, leader of the banned <ORGANIZATION> Liberia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, party lawyer <PERSON> Cephar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mbandi </PERSON> and four soldiers,. The minister said the plot was uncovered on March 16. He said it was a conspiracy `` to destabilize the government, create internal strife and overthrow the government by assassinating the president of <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bowier </PERSON> said arms, ammunition and military uniforms were found in a building in the <LOCATION> Sinkor </LOCATION> district of <LOCATION> Monrovia </LOCATION>. Investigations continued but the situation was under control, he said. Bowier read from a prepared statement and declined to answer questions. Journalists were warned not to run editorial comments or cartoons on the plot before the defendants go on trial. The minister gave no court date. The Unification party on Monday released a statement expressing concern over the arrests of <LOCATION> Kpolleh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mbandi </LOCATION>. It said several properties owned by <PERSON> Kpolleh </PERSON> and his family were destroyed during investigations by security forces and that his wife narrowly escaped being raped. It did not elaborate. <PERSON> Bowier </PERSON> advised reporters not to believe any press releases issued by the <ORGANIZATION> Unification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, saying it was banned and its statements had no credibility. <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, who came to power in a bloody April 1980 coup, has been the target of several assassination attempts. An attempted coup on Nov. 12, 1985, resulted in more than 600 deaths and the destruction of the village of the ringleader, former Brig. <PERSON> Gen </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Quiwonkpa </PERSON>, who was killed in the attempt. <PERSON> Quiwonkpa </PERSON>, who had been living in exile, led the attempt following elections that opposition leaders and independent observers said were rigged. <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s oldest republic, was founded in 1847 by freed <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> slaves. Descendents of the slaves, who were a minority, controlled the government until <PERSON> Doe </PERSON>, from the <ORGANIZATION> Krahn </ORGANIZATION> ethnic group, stormed the presidential mansion in April 1980, killing then-President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolbert </PERSON>. The economy declined under the rule of the former army master sergeant. Major Western creditors suspended aid to <LOCATION> Liberia </LOCATION> pending payment of debts. Last year the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> sent 17 financial experts to <LOCATION> Monrovia </LOCATION> to oversee operations of the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Nicaragua 2ndLd-Writethru a0842 03-22 1005</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Nicaragua, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0842,960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Asks House Republicans to Back New Contra Aid Effort</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts 2 grafs after 18th graf pvs, bgng:``The spot ...'' to
UPDATE with poll results.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sought Tuesday to revive his stalled effort to aid the Nicaraguan Contras and said congressional Democrats will be to blame if the supply-starved rebels fade from existence. In an hour-long meeting on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appealed to <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members to unite behind a new effort to push through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> some kind of help for the Contras, whose last <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid ran out Feb. 29. Later, speaking at a fund-raising reception for the re-election campaign of Sen. Chic Hecht, R-Nev., the president, as he has before, linked last week's incursion into <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> by troops of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government to the defeat of his request for funds for the rebels `` The logistical preparation for the incursion began just after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> voted to reject our package of aid to the democratic resistance,'' he said. `` This was a precise and carefully planned operation that showed the influence of outside advisers and must have required several weeks to plan.'' Rebel supporters said their chances of prevailing on the divisive issue were improved by the incursion, which was making some moderates nervous about leaving the rebels without aid. `` Some were quite pale in their appearance when they realized there was this incursion,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Miss </LOCATION>., the chief <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> vote counter `` We think there is some potential there to get a few more votes than we had in the past.'' One member of the `` swing'' group, Rep. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., said he was preparing a compromise aid package and was seeking the support of other moderates `` All we are trying to say is that leaving the situation as it is, is unacceptable,'' <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> said. `` We are determined to get continued assistance to the resistance, and if we stick together, this time we'll make it,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the closed meeting with lawmakers, according to a text of his remarks provided by the White House. He declined to offer details on what kind of package he was asking for. Alluding to Democratic efforts to thwart any military aid for the Contras, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> added: `` Those who led the fight against our package of assistance to the democratic resistance can not escape responsibility'' if the rebel forces wither. Later, in a session with local-government <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> officials, the president again pointed the finger of blame at <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats. `` The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership, who played hardball to win the vote to cut off aid, now says it wo n't accept responsibility for the destruction of the freedom fighters. But if the freedom fighters are extinguished and communist rule is consolidated in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people will be the ones to decide who is responsible,'' he contended. Democrats immediately tossed the blame back, insisting that it was Republicans who were responsible for the narrow <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> defeat of a package of strictly `` humanitarian'' aid _ food, clothing, medicine and shelter _ on March 3. `` What we're seeing is a public relations campaign here,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` The Republicans are very nervous about it because the finger's pointed right at them. House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, renewed his offer to vote quickly on a package of purely humanitarian aid if Republicans will ask for discussions. But he said any proposal containing military equipment would be subject to normal committee review. `` The door is open, the welcome mat is laid,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. The continued wrangling seemed to make the rebels themselves despair of any quick action to renew the money flow, and they released a television advertisement to begin airing this week that makes a direct appeal to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> viewers for contributions. `` Your <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> abandoned us,'' <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Palazio </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> lobbyist for the rebels, says somberly in the spot. `` We have nowhere to turn but to individual Americans like you.'' The spot, which asks for money for `` medicine, blankets and food for our families and children,'' was to begin running this week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s home town. A <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Post-ABC News poll of 1,007 Americans found that 55 percent of those surveyed opposed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s dispatch of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops last week to train in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, and 62 percent thought the troops would become involved in the fighting. The margin of error was plus or minus 4 percentage points. The poll, conducted by telephone interviews Thursday through Monday, found that 40 percent of those surveyed favored aid to the Contras and 56 percent opposed it. It was the highest support figure since the 43 percent level recorded on July 15, 1987, the day after former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> testified before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The White House has encouraged a bipartisan group of Contra supporters in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> who are proposing a one-year, $ 48 million package of non-lethal aid that also would give the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> the right to deliver previously stockpiled weapons. Under that plan, the president also would have the right to get a quick vote in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on sending new military aid under certain conditions. MacKay's version, still being drafted, would contain a compromise on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s future ability to demand a quick vote. In contrast with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill, <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON>'s would let the president trigger an expedited vote, but would not let him dictate the kind of aid package to be voted on. That would be left to normal legislative procedures, he said. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> visit that the administration has not yet aligned itself with any specific bill, but would like to have a package introduced soon and a vote before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leaves next week on an Easter recess. `` We'd like to have a vote before then,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. But House Republican Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> said it would be difficult to bring the matter to a vote before the week of April 11, when <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns to session.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-UN-Afghanistan     03-22 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Afghanistan,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Geneva Talks on Afghanistan, Attention `Centers On Washington'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> mediator <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> spoke Tuesday of the slow pace of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> peace talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, but cautioned that lack of quick movement does not mean a stalemate. Negotiators at the U.N.-sponsored talks apparently were waiting for new signals from the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> meeting between <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> met with the Afghan delegation for less than 30 minutes Tuesday and with the Pakistani team, which speaks for the Afghan guerrillas, for more than an hour. He later spoke briefly to reporters, admitting that there was `` very slow progress'' but that it `` should not be confused with a deadlock.'' There was a short-lived rumor that the Afghans, led by Foreign Minister <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON>, were preparing to leave <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Wednesday. But a Pakistani negotiator, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the talks would proceed on schedule. <PERSON> Wakil </PERSON> said earlier there was no reason for suspending the talks. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s chief representative, acting Foreign Minister <PERSON> Zain </PERSON> <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON>, has said <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> was prepared to stay in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> `` as long as it takes'' to conclude a peace settlement. The talks are stalling over the question of what <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> government should oversee implementation of the settlement and over future Soviet military aid to <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> demands that <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> assistance cease at the same time as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the anti-Marxist guerrillas fighting the Soviet-backed <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has rejected this as interference in relations between two sovereign states. `` Attention now centers on the discussions in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' a Pakistani source said. <PERSON> Noorani </PERSON> said last week that the superpowers may `` at least find it easier to settle among themselves'' the aid issue. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> intervened militarily in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> at the end of 1979 to support the government in its fight against the Islamic guerrillas. Approximately 115,000 Soviet troops are still there. Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says he wants to withdraw the Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> this year if agreement can be reached at <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Chile-Editor     03-22 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chile-Editor,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissident Editor Jailed on Charges of Defaming Military</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A military prosecutor on Tuesday jailed <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Herreros </PERSON>, director of the leftist magazine <ORGANIZATION> Cauce </ORGANIZATION>, for purportedly defaming <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s armed forces in an editorial, a magazine spokesman reported. <PERSON> Herreros </PERSON> was taken to <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>'s main prison after being questioned by prosecutor <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON>, according to <PERSON> Alvaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Briones </PERSON>, a senior <ORGANIZATION> Cauce </ORGANIZATION> editor. Under <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s military government, the armed forces codes empower prosecutors to indict and jail civilians brought before military courts. The editorial written by <PERSON> Herreros </PERSON> and published by Cauce in June 1987 criticized the influence given to the military courts in recent years. According to lawyers and human rights activists, more than 90 percent of those tried by military courts in the last five years were civilians, including a number of journalists. <PERSON> Acevedo </PERSON> has five days to file formal charges against <PERSON> Herreros </PERSON> or release him, according to the military code. The suit against <PERSON> Herreros </PERSON> was started by the army. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> has been ruled by the armed forces since a coup ousted the elected government of Marxist President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Allende </PERSON> in September 1973.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0458EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PershingLaunches     03-22 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pershing Launches,0142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pershing 2 Missile Launches Successful</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Army successfully test-fired five <ORGANIZATION> Pershing </ORGANIZATION> 2 missiles slated to be banned from deployment under a treaty with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The treaty, signed Dec. 8 by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, does not require either side to withdraw or destroy missiles until it has been ratified by both governments. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to approve the pact in late spring. The unarmed missiles were successfully fired Monday under battlefield conditions, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> said. The Pershing is a field missile _ each of which costs $ 4 million _ launched from its own assembly that can be carried by a truck. The Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces, or INF, treaty, calls for the destruction of all missiles with a range of 300 to 3,400 miles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     03-22 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0501</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Keeps Rolling in the Ratings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, predicting its biggest season win yet, continues to add potentially successful new series to its schedule, while <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, facing its first last-place ratings finish ever, ca n't get its new comedies arrested <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> fared best with new fare last week, adding the critically praised nostalgia comedy `` The Wonder Years'' to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> top 10. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s pilot for `` In the Heat of the Night'' tied for 15th in the rankings, though it remains to be seen how the series will do on a weekly basis. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, failed with its attempt to add new comedies to its Monday and Tuesday nights. The best performer was `` <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>,'' which ranked 31st. For the week that ended Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had an average, prime-time rating of 15.8; CBS 12.9 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.6. With four weeks left in the season, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> leads with a 16.3, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 13.9 and CBS 13.6. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> would have to beat <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> by two points a week to tie for second. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> has never finished a season in third place in the 35 years that <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> has done television ratings. The `` CBS Evening News,'' however, was still in first place, with an average rating of 11.6. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' had a 10.8 and `` NBC Nightly News'' 9.7. The rating is a percentage of the nation's 88.6 million households with televisions. Here is last week's top 10: `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` 60 Minutes'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Night Court'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Murder, She Wrote'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and `` Growing Pains'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. Half of the top 10 shows were repeats, as the networks, faced with a strike by scriptwriters, began to conserve new episodes for the May sweeps. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> added `` Eisenhower & amp; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>'' to its Monday night lineup, moving `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place'' to Tuesday, where the rest of the lineup dragged that critically acclaimed series down to 65th of 77 rankings. The other new comedies CBS tried on Tuesday were steamrollered by <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s normally strong lineup, including `` The Wonder Years.'' It replaced `` Growing Pains,'' which moved to Wednesday night where it continues to be a top-10 show. CBS' `` Coming of Age,'' starring <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Dooley </PERSON> as an acerbic former airline pilot struggling to adjust to a sunny retirement village, was 59th. At a dismal 75th was `` My Sister <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' a formerly high-rated comedy reprised by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> to fill in for the new `` The Dictator,'' which was delayed by the <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> strike. `` Trial and Error,'' a Hispanic `` Odd Couple,'' was 76th. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> did well with a TV version of the classic film `` Inherit the Wind,'' starring <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Robards </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>. It ranked 14th. `` In the Heat of the Night'' was a pilot for a potential fall series starring <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> in a remake of the hit movie.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     03-22 0746</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0834</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's Top-Rated TV Shows</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ``Eisenhower &amp; Lutz'' ran twice during the week</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of March 14-20. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation, `` P'' indicates premiere and `` NA'' indicates not available. Shows from 21 on include only the weekly ranking. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 88.6 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 28.2 rating, 25 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.2 rating, 22.3 million homes. 3. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5 rating, 19.9 million homes. 3. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5 rating, 19.9 million homes. 5. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.3 rating, 19.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.0 rating, 19.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- P -RRB- `` Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.4 rating, 19 million homes. 8. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.9 rating, 18.5 million homes. 9. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.8 rating, 18.4 million homes. 10. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2 rating, 17 million homes. 11. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.1 rating, 16.9 million homes. 12. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5 rating, 16.4 million homes. 13. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1 rating, 16 million homes. 14. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Inherit the Wind,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 15.9 million homes. 15. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON>'s Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9 rating, 15.8 million homes. 15. -LRB- X -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.9 rating, 15.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 17.5 rating, 15.5 million homes. 18. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9 rating, 15 million homes. 18. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` ABC Monday Night Movie: Broken Angel,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9 rating, 15 million homes. 20. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6 rating, 14.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4. 22. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 22. -LRB- P -RRB- `` Aaron's Way,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 24. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Day by Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 25. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 26. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 15.3. 27. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 28. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 29. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 14.6. 30. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 31. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.2. 32. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` CBS Sunday Movie: Hot Paint,'' CBS, 14.1. 33. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Facts of Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 33. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.0. 35. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 35. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7. 37. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6. 38. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 13.5. 39. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and the Fat Man,'' CBS, 13.5. 40. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` NBC Monday Night Movie: Danger Down Under,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 41. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Eisenhower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.0. 42. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 43. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.7. 43. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` ABC Sunday Night Move: Octopussy,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 45. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Supercarrier,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 46. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 47. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 47. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.1. 49. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 49. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 51. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 11.8. 51. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Cagney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.8. 51. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Snoopy,'' CBS, 11.8. 54. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Slap </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 55. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 56. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Crime Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 57. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Dolly,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 58. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.1. 59. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Coming of Age,'' 11.0. 60. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` A Year in the Life,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 61. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 10.5. 62. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Highwayman,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 63. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Spenser: For Hire,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 64. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 10.1. 65. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s Place,'' CBS, 9.9. 65. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` 48 Hours,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 99. 67. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` High Mountain Rangers,'' CBS, 9.8. 68. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Thorns,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 69. -LRB- X -RRB- `` NBC Family Special: Place at the Table,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 70. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Probe,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 71. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 8.7. 71. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Disney Sunday Movie: Little Spies, Part One,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 73. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Ohara </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 74. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Hotel,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 75. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` My Sister <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.3. 76. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` Trial and Error,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 76. -LRB- P -RRB- `` Buck <PERSON> James </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 5.9. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... with Children,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 5.0. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 4.4. 81. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Werewolf,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 4.1. 82. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' FOx, 3.8. 83. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 3.3. 84. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Women in Prison,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 3.0. 85. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Boys Will Be Boys,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 2.9. 86. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Adventures of Beans Baxter,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 2.1. 87. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Mr. President,'' <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, 1.7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HiddenGarden     03-21 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hidden Garden,0839</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Outlook Is Grim' For Tropical Jungles, Scientist Says</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The destruction of millions of acres of tropical jungles each year by peasant farmers and others is a problem for the developed nations as well as the Third World and requires economic and educational solutions, say scientists at a leading plant research institution. The Missouri Botanical Garden, known for its man-made tropical atmosphere in the so-called `` Climatron'' designed by <PERSON> Buckminster </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, is working to halt the decimation of the world's real tropical jungles. `` The outlook is pretty grim,'' said biologist <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Raven </PERSON>, director of the garden. `` Although tropical forests once covered at least 12 percent of the globe _ an area about twice the size of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ they have already been reduced to about half that.'' `` Currently, the forests are being cleared or degraded at the rate of about 60 million acres a year. That's an area about half the size of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said roughly half of all known plant and animal species on Earth are found in the tropical forests. At the current rate of destruction, as many as 60,000 species of plants will be extinct by the year 2020. `` The plant-rich tropics supply man with a wealth of food crops, medicines and other useful products,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Forero </PERSON>, director of research at the garden. `` But they are being destroyed rapidly.'' The chief culprits, <PERSON> Forero </PERSON> said, are loggers and slash-and-burn peasant farmers. The loggers obviously need the trees to stay in business and the farmers often have to destroy the forests to feed themselves and their families. And the scientists say the situation can only get worse unless something is done to stop it. `` At present, over half the people in the world live in countries that are at least partly tropical, excluding <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Forero </PERSON> said. `` Nearly a third of these people are already living in extreme poverty and with current rates of growth, the human population of these countries will double in less than 30 years.'' `` How can you tell these starving people that you are going to save the very things they have to destroy in order to sustain their already meager existence,'' asked <PERSON> Raven </PERSON>. `` Education and political and economic stability are obviously the keys. That and understanding.'' Which is why, <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said, the garden has committed itself to an all-out effort to explore, document and save the forests. With a staff of 70 researchers and technicians, including many who live permanently in the tropics, the garden makes up one of the world's largest active field research programs in tropical botany. The goals, the scientists said, are to collect the plant species before they become extinct and to teach the impoverished farmers how to live in the forest without destroying it. With the growing knowledge of genetics, they said, it is important that the genes, the biological blueprints, of the endangered species be saved. `` To lose this genetic capital through massive extinctions just as we are developing our capabilities to explore its potential would indeed be a tragedy,'' <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said. `` The developments in genetics make the specter of extinction even worse,'' <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said. `` For each species of plant or animal lost to extinction, you're losing the potential for another 20,000 to 30,000 variants in the future. Many of the plants, scientists say, could almost certainly be developed into cheaper, easy-to-grow sources of highly nutritious food. Others could be converted into abundant sources of new medicines. Another important part of the garden's program is to lend technical assistance to and train scientists from developing tropical countries through cooperative agreements. `` Unfortunately, only 6 percent of the scientists working on the problem live in the countries involved,'' <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said. `` We must change that. Momentum to implement the innovative conservation and development strategies needed to deal with these urgent problems ultimately must come from the affected countries themselves,'' <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said. The backbone of the garden's research, the scientists said, is its herbarium, or plant collection. Along with the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Botanical </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Garden </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> herbarium is one of the three largest in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and among the 12 largest in the world. Started by garden founder <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> in the 1850s, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> herbarium now contains samples of more than 3.5 million species and is expected to expand to 4.5 million within the next decade. Pointing to a large map showing the locations of the garden's researchers in Central and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Raven </PERSON> said of the encroachment on the forests: `` It wo n't be stopped soon `` But there are encouraging signs. What people have to learn is that conservation and development are really two sides of the same coin.'' `` Producers and consumers have to learn that they have a common problem. It can all be done, but it wo n't be easy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VietnamMagazine     03-22 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam Magazine,0721</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Magazine Is Part Of Revival In Vietnam War Literature</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE ESPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An old generation is remembering the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war and a new generation is curious, stirring a revival of the controversial era in books and movies. Now comes a new publication, a slick magazine simply named <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, whose premiere issue went on sale today. `` Our timing could not have been better because right now, look at all the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> movies that have come out,'' said publisher <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oehler </PERSON> in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Leesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where the magazine is published by <ORGANIZATION> Empire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` Look at all the major emphasis now on video, on books. It's <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Everyone now is talking about <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Oehler </PERSON> said 150,000 copies of the first issue were printed, including 50,000 for subscribers and 100,000 for newsstand sales across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and in 16 other countries. The magazine, a quarterly, sells for $ 2.95 a copy on newsstands and for $ 9.95 for the four issues by subscription. <PERSON> Oehler </PERSON> said the response has been so overwhelming from wholesalers, subscribers and the media that the magazine will probably go to six issues a year in 1989. Many of the subscribers are <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans, a large number of them in prison. `` I've gotten hundreds of letters from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans in prison,'' said <PERSON> Oehler </PERSON>. `` They're so happy to hear that a magazine is coming out.'' Each issue will run 68 pages with a regular format of four feature stories and six departments including editorial, fighting forces, bases and installations, arsenal and book reviews. The initial issue includes an interview with Gen. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weyand </PERSON>, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s last military commander in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and a story on <ORGANIZATION> Tan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Son </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nhut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, the command center for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s forces in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> which was called the `` Pentagon East.'' It also includes 32 pages of color photographs and maps. The cover shows two soldiers defending their post with a machine gun. In the editorial in the premiere issue, the editor, retired Col. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Summers </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, explains the goal of the magazine: `` Thirty-eight years after <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> involvement in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> began, 15 years after the withdrawal of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces there, and 13 years after the fall of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>, the war there truly remains an enigma. The goal we here at <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> magazine have set for ourselves is to find the key to unlock that enigma.'' In an interview, <PERSON> Summers </PERSON> said that in visits to colleges he has found great interest in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> among young people who want to know what really happened there. He said there seems to be a misunderstanding of the war especially among this generation, many of whom were not even born when <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers were pouring into <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1965. `` There is the perception that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was defeated by a guerrilla army,'' he said. `` That's not true. The American military withdrew from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> 2 -LCB- years before the fall of <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>. The North Vietnamese did not defeat the American military when they seized <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION> for a very simple reason: There was no American military there to defeat. One of our objectives is to refute some of the myths.'' Summers, 56, is widely known and respected as an authority on military affairs. He served in both the Korean and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> wars. He is a columnist for the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Syndicate </ORGANIZATION>, a contributing editor for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report, and the author of two books, including the widely acclaimed `` On Strategy: A Critical Analysis of the Vietnam War. The magazine's editorial review board includes Gen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Westmoreland </PERSON>, former commander of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, and authors <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnow </PERSON> and <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Santoli </PERSON>, both of whom have written books on <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Asked if the presence of <LOCATION> Westmoreland </LOCATION> and other former <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> officers on the board will leave the impression that the magazine will give only the official view, one that was often discredited during the war, <PERSON> Summers </PERSON> said: `` We've tried to get the voices as diverse as possible. I do n't think <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnow </PERSON>'s an apologist for the war I do n't think I'm an apologist for the war Certainly my book was very critical of the war. And so was <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Santoli </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AgStationCentennial     03-22 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ag Station Centennial,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agricultural Experiment Station Marks 100th Anniversary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT LEE ZIMMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>URBANA, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Midgette </PERSON> bends and removes spikes from railroad ties, and <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Korthals </PERSON> blows smoke through a scale-model hog house. They are among 3,000 scientists, administrators and graduate assistants on staff at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Experiment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION>, which celebrated its 100th anniversary Monday. But the center, one of 66 in the country, is about more than agriculture. `` I've yet to see one person ... who did n't think there were exciting things going on here,'' said station director <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Holt </PERSON>. `` One thing is clear _ research is crucial to the future of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> agriculture and our society in general.'' In one laboratory, <PERSON> Midgette </PERSON> compared the strength of railroad ties made from different woods, looking for the longest-lasting material. An African oak was so hard that it caused a bolt to break in a machine that measures the force required to pull out a spike. `` It snapped and went straight up,'' said <PERSON> Midgette </PERSON>, who figures this African oak will out-last conventional ties. `` We've got indentations in the ceiling.'' Korthals pumped smoke into the clear plastic model of a hog house to demonstrate how the air moves through the building with various ventilation systems. He said it should help farmers select the most efficient design for their own swine buildings. The 320 research projects funded by the station last year involved subjects such as agricultural economics, veterinary medicine, home economics and food science. The center has a $ 25 million budget from state and federal appropriations, as well as gifts, grants and contracts, many from the private sector, <PERSON> Holt </PERSON> said. It began in the Morrow Plots, site of the longest-running continuous corn experiment in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>. The test plots were created in 1876, the year Gen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Custer </PERSON> and 264 cavalrymen were killed at <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bighorn </LOCATION>. Much of the station's research still is aimed directly at production agriculture. Visitors on Monday saw a rainfall simulator used to study the effects of soil erosion, experiments on the biological control of insects, and research into the possible use of wild soybeans to improve commercial varieties. They also saw work being done to create new human foods from soybeans, to study tree growth and to learn more about infant nutrition and child development.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Irish-Assess     03-22 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Irish-Assess,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fear Funeral Violence May Signal New Round Of Bloodshed</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The murderous rampages that left five people dead at two <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> funerals last week have aroused fears that <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> is sliding into a new cycle of violence after several years of relative calm. In the past month, 15 people have died _ twice the 1987 monthly average. The dead include three <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas gunned down in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> on March 6 in the incident that touched off the latest mayhem in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. `` A firm grip will be required to halt the slide of the province toward still further bloodshed and anarchy,'' the News Letter, a <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> newspaper, warned Monday. `` There is no time to lose,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> Belfast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>. `` If there is a political vacuum _ and there is _ the initiative will always seem to be with the paramilitaries.'' `` There wo n't be anarchy and there wo n't even be a return to the level of violence in the early 1970s when 700 people died in a year,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bew </PERSON>, a political science professor at <ORGANIZATION> Queen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, said in an interview `` But the graph is starting to go up, up, up,'' he said. With police talking of about 30 suspects in Saturday's violence, Roman Catholic areas of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> are bracing for a wave of arrests that could provoke further clashes. Ever since the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s struggle to drive <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> out of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> climaxed with the death of 10 hunger striking prisoners in 1981, the province seemed to be lapsing into relative calm. The death toll was dropping steadily and there even were signs of economic rejuvenation. The <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>, having narrowly failed to assassinate Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> with a bomb in 1984, was suffering repeated military and political setbacks. The Anglo-Irish Agreement of November 1985, which gave <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> a say in the running of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, was bolstering <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> moderates against <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> radicals. The killing of the three guerrillas, allegedly as they were plotting a car bombing in <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>, was portrayed by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as a triumph for its anti-terrorism strategy. But the fact that the guerrillas were unarmed outraged many Catholics as well as the Irish government. That reaction in turn angered many Protestants, who believed that the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> got what it deserved. As the three were being buried, <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michael </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> emerged from behind a tombstone lobbing grenades and firing into the mourners. Three died and 68 were wounded. Three days later, at the funeral of one of the cemetery victims, a car sped toward the cortege. The mourners, keyed up and fearful of another <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> attack, pounced on it. When they realized the occupants were two British soldiers, they dragged them out, beat them with iron bars and stripped them. The two men were then hauled away and shot dead by <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> gunmen. The two episodes revealed the hatred that can still erupt from a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> majority that regards itself as being under siege, and from a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> minority for whom <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> proves there is no British justice in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The incidents all but obscured four other deaths since <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION>: a policeman, an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> man and two civilians _ a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> woman and a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> man. In the context of a conflict that has claimed 2,638 lives since 1969, those four would be regarded as par for Ulster's grisly course. The funeral deaths, however, were graphically captured by TV cameras, and they stunned and disgusted <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> and British citizens alike. `` Scum of the earth,'' stormed the Sun, a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> daily. In <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> lamented: `` This was the shocking face of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'88.'' Many Catholics reacted to Saturday's killings with shock and disgust, making no attempt to excuse them as a response to the previous cemetery bloodbath. The Irish News, a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> daily, called it `` a satanic rejection of the Christian faith.'' `` The initial reaction is shock that something so barbarous could happen,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s moderate, mainstream Catholic party.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Eliason </PERSON>, news editor in the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> for 3 -LCB- years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ExiledLeaders     03-22 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exiled Leaders,0287</SECOND>
<HEAD>United States Has Encouraged Several Leaders to Choose Exile</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has urged <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, to leave the country and live in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> has encouraged other world leaders to give up power and go into exile. Among them: <PERSON> Syngman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhee </PERSON> _ The <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> president went into exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> in May, 1960 following widespread political unrest and allegations that he had rigged the presidential election. He died in 1965. <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON> gave up power during the Islamic revolution and flew to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in his private plane on Jan. 15, 1979. He was allowed temporary refuge in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for medical treatment, but was not allowed to live in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> permanently. He went to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and then to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, where he died in 1980. <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> _ The Nicaraguan president fled the country Jan. 19, 1979 under pressure from the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> and after the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> refused to support him. A Sandinista-led coalition took power. <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> lived in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> and was assassinated on Sept. 7, 1980. `` Baby Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> and his family fled <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> on Feb. 7, 1986 aboard a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> plane following months of unrest. His departure ended the political dynasty founded in 1957 by his father, <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> `` Papa Doc'' <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON>. <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> is in exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> _ Fled the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> with his family aboard a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> jet on Feb. 26, 1986 in the face of mounting opposition by political foes and the military. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is in exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CBS-Hewitt     03-22 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CBS-Hewitt,0683</SECOND>
<HEAD>`60 Minutes' Producer Marks 40 Years at CBS</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, who marks his 40th anniversary with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> today, recalls that he landed his first job at the network after a friend suggested his experience at a newsphoto service might come in handy. `` I said, what does <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> want with picture experience? Radio does n't need any pictures. He said, ` No _ television.' I said whata-vision?'' Today, the 65-year-old outspoken creator and executive producer of `` 60 Minutes'' is looking beyond current television technology, foreseeing a time when networks are superfluous and television news is beamed directly into subscribers' homes. <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON> began his career as associate director and later producer of the network's first television newscast, `` <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> With the News'' and later the `` CBS Evening News'' with <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON>. He remembers covering the coronation of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> with <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON> and flying back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> aboard a chartered airliner editing the kinescope that viewers would see on the news _ no videotapes, no satellite transmissions. `` I did n't think there was ever going to be satellites, bounce signals off a star, are you crazy?,'' he said, laughing. But <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>, who considered buying <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> a few years ago, thinks it's feasible to one day broadcast news directly to homes News services already are beaming footage to local television stations, so <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>'s idea is not so far-fetched. `` I think that the network news departments, they might not even work for a network 10 years from now,'' he said. `` There might not be any networks because it may be an outmoded delivery system. `` I'm not sure you do n't have a large newsroom somewhere and you just have direct broadcast ... feeding news into people's homes, for a price same way they pay for a newspaper.'' He also foresees delivering newspapers into home printers by satellite. `` I think about it more than most people, as you can see. And I wonder how long the networks in their present form will be around,'' he said. Some other samples of <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON>'s opinions: _ `` 60 Minutes'': `` I've always said all we do in this broadcast is shine lights on people in dark corners, and if people in dark corners are doing things they should n't be doing, all we did was turn the light on.'' _ The importance of pictures on television: `` The accepted wisdom in television was always you put words to pictures I do n't believe that. You put pictures to words. You start with the words. The audio is always more important to me than the video.'' _ Televised presidential debates -LRB- <PERSON> Hewitt </PERSON> produced the famous 1960 meeting of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> -RRB-: `` It's still a terrible format and we should n't be doing them They should have real debates. ... The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate should head up a team of two or three debaters who are really good and can really cross-examine the other side and give them a hard time, and they ought to do it in front of a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and it will produce something other than this sterile show where what it is is a joint press conference, not really a debate.'' _ This year's election: `` I do n't think there's enough caffeine in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to keep the electorate awake during a Dukakis-Bush campaign. _ Politicians: `` I do n't put politicians on the air if I can help it, because I instinctively do n't believe them I believe they're only interested in getting themselves elected, and they only say what they think will get themselves elected. _ Ratings: `` No matter what I think about ratings, and whether they're accurate and everything, I do n't say anything because they've been awfully good to me. _ The future: `` I know where I'll be in nine years I'm going to be here. My contract is n't up until I'm 74. Ironclad, nobody gets out. Now the question is, will there be a CBS? I think so. Some form. Maybe not this form.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Scotus-Rdp Bjt   03-22 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus-Rdp, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Considering Major Child Abuse Issue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is considering whether abused children should have the right to sue public officials for failing to protect them from their parents. But the justices have decided to avoid another children's rights issue: whether public school students enjoy any constitutional protection against paddling or other corporal punishment by teachers and administrators. The court announced Monday that it will tackle the parental abuse issue in the case of a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> boy, <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON>, who suffered serious and permanent brain damage from beatings by his father. The boy's suit accuses social workers and officials of gross negligence in ignoring evidence that he was being brutally victimized. A lower court threw out the suit. A high court ruling is not expected until 1989 on whether to revive the suit against the <LOCATION> Winnebago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> and two of its employees. The agency was accused of violating the rights of <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> by failing to rescue him from his father's beatings, even though it allegedly had known about the abuse since 1983, when the child was 4 years old. <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> has been institutionalized since 1984, suffering from injuries that destroyed half his brain and left him profoundly retarded. The boy's father, <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON>, since has been convicted of child abuse and sentenced to two to four years in prison. <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON>'s ex-wife, Melody, sued the social services officials on grounds they violated the child's constitutional right not to be deprived of liberty without due process. Mrs. <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON> was divorced from her husband and living in <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, when she was informed her son had suffered serious brain damage. <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON> had custody of his son. The 7th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, in throwing out Mrs. <PERSON> DeShaney </PERSON>'s suit, said the social welfare agency and its employees `` though blameworthy, did not cause <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON>'s injuries'' but `` merely failed to protect him from his bestial father.'' The appeals court also said welfare agencies should not be placed in the predicament of removing a child from home and facing suit by the parent or leaving the child there and risk being sued by the child. Putting officials in that position `` is unlikely to improve the welfare of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families and is not grounded in constitutional text or principle,'' the appeals court said. In the paddling case, the court, without comment, let stand a federal appeals court ruling in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> case that `` at some degree of excessiveness or cruelty'' such punishment violates constitutional rights. Another appeals court has rejected that view, clouding the picture. The high court in 1977 ruled that such disciplinary measures never can amount to the `` cruel and unusual punishment'' banned by the Constitution's Eighth Amendment. The decision barred students from suing teachers and school administrators in federal court over alleged Eighth Amendment violations, but left them free to sue in state courts under state laws. In the 1977 decision, however, the court said it had not considered whether corporal punishment can violate `` substantive rights under the -LRB- 14th Amendment's -RRB- due process clause.'' The 10th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> last April cleared the way for a trial in <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s federal lawsuit against Penasco, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, school officials over two paddlings she received in elementary school. The appeals court said the kind of punishment alleged in the lawsuit can sustain a federal lawsuit even if a lawsuit could have been filed in state court. In other developments, the court: _ Agreed to consider killing a key provision of a law designed to promote competitive bidding on government contracts At issue is the proper boundary between presidential and congressional power. _ Agreed to decide in a case from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> whether states may impose sales taxes on most books, newspapers and magazines while exempting religious publications
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NewsLeak Bjt   03-22 0583</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-News Leak, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Did Thomas Jefferson Invent The News Leak?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As a capital institution, leaking confidential information to the press has a rich heritage and long roots. Those roots may be longer than one might think. The news leak, in fact, may stretch back to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, or at least his political allies. That possibility was made clear last week as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was reminded that the day marked the 188th anniversary _ March 18, 1800 _ of the issuing of the very first contempt of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> citation. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Duane </PERSON>, editor of the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION>, was cited for contempt for having failed to appear as ordered to explain how he had obtained the text of a controversial but secret <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill and caused it to be published. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in that era still met in secret and all of its deliberations were held to be private, not public, matters. According to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> historians, the secret bill was the product of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s Federalist majority and concerned a bid to change the method of settling disputes over presidential electors <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> was vice president and leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic-Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. His supporters feared a plot to deny him the presidency in the upcoming elections. So, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said, `` <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>'s allies in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaked a copy of the bill to <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Duane </PERSON>.'' `` Offended Federalists demanded an investigation of <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> and his illicit sources,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. Vice President <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s presiding officer, was directed to read <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> a list of prepared questions about who had given him the bill, he said. <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> asked for additional time to seek counsel, a request <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> quickly granted. `` That was the last the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> saw of <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Duane </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> recounted. `` When he failed to reappear, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> issued a contempt citation in his name. <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> hid out through the remainder of the congressional session.'' When the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> convened the situation had changed. <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON> had won the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and his party had captured majorities in both the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. `` Needless to say,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, `` the new <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority had no intention of pursuing charges of contempt against <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Duane </PERSON>.'' The first congressional investigation of a news leak was quietly shelved.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, sifted through 40 years of memories last week after announcing he will end his congressional career at the end of the year. <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, presided over the hearings which, on July 24, 1974, resulted in a vote to impeach President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. Within days <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> resigned his office. A decade later, on May 30, 1984, <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON> was en route from the capital to his home in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON> is such a frequent flier on that route that the airlines, as a matter of courtesy, customarily assigned him a seat in the second row of the aircraft so that he could board and depart easily and quickly. But on the day in question, Chairman <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON> got bumped to the rear of the plane. Who had the clout to oust <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON> from his accustomed seat? Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s the one. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> also had a home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and was traveling with his <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> bodyguards. The entire group got the front-of-the-plane seats. The two men did n't talk. `` I did n't even see his face,'' <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON> recalled. `` I saw the back of his head.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Gephardt Bjt   03-22 0850</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gephardt, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gephardt Bets It All In Michigan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As struggling Democratic presidential hopeful <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> was wooing workers at a giant steel mill here with his trade-and-populism message, one of them handed him a button that read: `` Survival.'' The button referred to saving <ORGANIZATION> McLouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> through employee ownership, but it also aptly summed up <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s political goal in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. Without a win here, it could be all over for the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> congressman. But he hopes workers like the ones he campaigned among Monday will keep his bid alive. `` If we do n't do well here, obviously we are n't going to be able to continue the race,'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION> on March 10. Brushing aside questions about his future if he loses, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said over and over again Monday, `` I'm going to do well in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>.'' Asked if he would run for re-election to his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat if he loses Saturday, he declared: `` I'm going to win.'' `` I imagine he does have to'' win, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> attorney general and chairman of <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s effort in the state. But he was quick to say winning might not mean coming in first. <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who has strong black support in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> and its suburbs, could be first. He said <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> must beat <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the front-runner in delegates. `` If <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> beats <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, his campaign is revived,'' <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> said. But the polls do not support that prospect. A survey conducted March 15-17 for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> the lead, with <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> far behind. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had 33 percent, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> 31 percent. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> had 10 percent, with the rest of the field trailing. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said the polls do not tap the caucus-goers accurately, as the campaign expects only 100,000 to 150,000 Democrats to attend, a small fraction of the party faithful. `` I think a lot of people will be surprised by how well he does here,'' said <PERSON> Chick </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahoney </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Chick </ORGANIZATION>'s Rooster Lounge south of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> campaigned Monday. `` But it's going to be tough.'' To turn the poll findings on their head, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> has a message with a great deal of appeal in this state still shuddering from the massive changes in the auto and steel industries facing foreign competition. He denunciation of foreign trade practices _ epitomized by his rhetoric and ad saying `` a $ 10,000 <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> K-car costs $ 48,000 in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'' _ draws big applause from blue collar crowds. At the McLouth mill and at <ORGANIZATION> Chick </ORGANIZATION>'s on Monday, that line drew big cheers. `` He's the only one to take a stand on trade, a strong one,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hindman </PERSON> outside the McLouth mill south of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. `` ` Some of the people here were out of work for 4 -LCB- years,'' added <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridings </PERSON>. `` That's why we like <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> is short of time and money to get his message out. <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> said the campaign has promised to spend between $ 300,000 and $ 500,000 on ads in the state. One campaign aide who spoke on condition of anonymity said, `` As fast the money comes in, we spend it.'' A key to <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s victory is what the union leadership does in the state. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> have not endorsed anyone nationally, although their state affiliate in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> played a major role in his victory in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. That means <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> is trying to pick up support local by local and district by district. At the McLouth plant, he won the backing of district director <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lester </PERSON>. And <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Local </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 2659 </ORGANIZATION> official, said many members will follow the district leader's suggestion. That backing must be repeated over and over again across the state for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> to win, for this caucus is not a simple process. The voting does not take place in the usual precincts across the state but in 567 locations that may not be familiar to the voters. That puts a premium on organization, which has been the trademark of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' effort this far. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> ad, which worked so well in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, has come in for criticism in this state where autos are the economy. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> brushed aside suggestions the ad is inaccurate in its claim that the $ 10,000 <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> car would cost $ 48,000 in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. And he got some help in that from <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>, with whom he met on Monday in <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. Asked if the <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> ad's figure was correct, <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> has the point correct, whatever the details. `` Damn close to it. Maybe it's only $ 35-40 ,000, but do n't lose sight of it, it's still a big difference between $ 7,000 here for a comparable car,'' <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> said to reporters outside the <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> said he was responding to a story in Monday's editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> saying a K-car would cost about $ 33,000 in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and that none is sold there. And <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, in an interview with the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, conceded that many of those taxes are levied in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on domestic consumption.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Israel-Media     03-22 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Israel-Media,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Banning Reporters Won't Necessarily Ease Israeli Image Problem</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Banning reporters and photographers from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> could prove to be a public relations blunder for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and might not be effective anyway, several media observers say. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Annenberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION>, said it would be `` bad policy'' for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to impose more restrictions on reporters covering unrest in the occupied territories. `` It would be a public relations risk _ one I hope they do n't take,'' <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> said He said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> could jeopardize its reputation as the only true democracy in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials cite in providing millions of dollars to the country each year. But the Israelis are obviously watching the situation in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to determine if the advantages of restricting the press outweigh the disadvantages, he said. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s widely condemned white government has succeeded in dampening outside interest in that country's racial problems by banning coverage of any security activities, experts agree. The order went into effect in June 1986. But Gross doubted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would be able to `` keep the lid on'' coverage of the occupied territories in a way the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> have virtually halted reporting in black areas. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s domestic political opposition and a thriving domestic press could prevent a blackout on coverage of the territories, he said. Local Israeli army commanders already have authority to close areas in the occupied territories at random, and they have been doing so with increasing frequency. A parliamentary committee in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> is studying whether to ban the media formally from the territories. <PERSON> Yael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dayan </PERSON>, a well-known <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> peace activist, said during a recent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visit that tough restrictions on the press would likely fail, because Israelis demand news and have an aggressive press corps. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> to Protect Journalists, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-based </LOCATION> group that monitors conditions for journalists worldwide, said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> might be able to stave off intense scrutiny by banning cameras. `` But in the long run the greater public interest is served by allowing the press access,'' he said. The committee opposes restrictions on reporters. Some Americans have joined Israeli government officials in complaining that reporters, particularly those working for foreign television networks, have helped incite rock-throwing Palestinians in the territories. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> has said a television ban would be justified, and former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> reportedly told prominent American Jews during a meeting that banning television cameras would be a good idea. <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> says his remarks were distorted. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> of Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting criticized a `` censorship lobby'' for supporting restrictions that, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, would be considered an unacceptable violation of freedom of the press. `` It would be one more comparison with <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, and it would hurt <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' he said. FAIR is a liberal <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> group that examines the media. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friendly </PERSON>, former president of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION>, said it would be wrong to ban reporters from the occupied territories. `` That ca n't be right _ that's what <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> did,'' he said. But Friendly said television coverage, with its time constraints and powerful pictures, can fail to portray a story accurately. ` What is also wrong is letting the picture run away with the story,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mortimer </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON>, editor-in-chief of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report, had the same complaint. `` Television has polluted the public debate because it is inherently difficult for pictures to give context, history and meaning to events,'' he recently wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TrainCollision     03-22 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Collision,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Workers Injured In Trail Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DIXON, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Northwestern freight trains collided head-on Monday, injuring eight workers, three of them seriously, police said. An eastbound train with four engines and about 130 cars collided with a westbound train consisting of a switch engine and a single car while both trains were going 20 mph to 30 mph, police said. Officials were investigating the cause of the accident late Monday. The collision occurred about noon in the southwest part of <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, a town of 15,000 in north-central <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, and the crash could be heard up to a mile away, police said. Eight employees were on the trains at the time of the accident, and were taken to <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> <LOCATION> Bethea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkerson </PERSON>, 35, of Rock Falls; and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Holdren </PERSON>, 56 and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonder </PERSON>, 38, both of Sterling, were listed in serious condition late Monday, hospital officials said. The other five workers were treated and released.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxChanges Bjt   03-22 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Changes, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tax Fight Pits Farmers Against Mercedes Owners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Because senators like to see farmers smile, your next <ORGANIZATION> Mercedes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benz </ORGANIZATION> could cost an extra $ 1,800. If you do n't get the connection, that's just the way <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> works sometimes. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted Monday to grant farmers and some other taxpayers relief from the 15.1-cent-a-gallon tax on diesel fuel used for logging, farming, oil drilling, mining, fishing and other off-the-road business purposes. But since budget constraints require that every dollar of tax relief be offset by a dollar of tax increase on somebody else, the committee's bill would double the tax on fuel-guzzling cars _ mostly expensive imports whose miles-per-gallon do n't meet federal standards. Other sources of revenue for the diesel relief and a new `` taxpayer bill of rights'' include a few distilleries that dodge some of the $ 12.50-a-gallon tax on liquor by watering down products with a grape-based alcohol, and any number of people whose tax refunds could be grabbed to pay an overdue government loan. After all that, farmers may have to wait six months for their tax relief. There is some doubt <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> can complete action on legislation before April 1, when off-the-road diesel users are to begin paying the tax. They would have to wait for a refund until they file their income-tax returns next year. `` I just do n't want to go back home and explain to my farmers why we've set up this ridiculous bureaucratic nightmare,'' moaned Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., noted the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is due to recess Easter To go back home with no settlement of the farmers' problem, he said, `` would be like us walking through a field of scorpions barefooted. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., said the committee should, in effect, ask the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to ignore the budget problem so farmers can be relieved Farmers and other off-road diesel users were caught up in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' efforts last year to reduce cheating on the fuel tax. The solution was to change the point of tax collection to the producer or wholesaler, and to require that those legally entitled to an exemption pay the tax and then apply for a refund when they file their income-tax returns the following year. The typical farmer would thus allow the government interest-free use of $ 320 of his money, some of it for up to a year. The panel's bill does nothing for another big group with a complaint: about 82,000 state, county and city government units that, starting Jan. 1, are now having to pay the 9.1-cent gasoline tax and apply for a refund later. The Finance Committee package, still subject to action by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, would: _ Allow diesel bought for off-road business use from wholesalers to escape the tax altogether Tax-exempt buyers from retailers would have to pay the tax and get a refund next year. This would cost the government $ 543 million through 1993. _ Create a `` taxpayer bill of rights,'' clamping down on perceived abuses by the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> This would lose $ 517 million over five years. _ Extend through June 30, 1989, the expiring authority for the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> to withhold tax refunds from people who owe student loans, farm loans and other federal debts This would raise about $ 400 million. _ Double the tax on new cars whose fuel efficiency does not meet federal standards, raising $ 375 million through 1993 In the current model year, the tax hits only expensive foreign cars, such as the $ 38,000 <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> 780, which gets 21.2 miles per gallon, and the $ 61,130 Mercedes 560SL. Their guzzler taxes would rise to $ 1,300 and $ 3,600, respectively. _ Limit use of a `` wine flavors credit'' under which some manufacturers of distilled spirits avoid a significant share of the $ 12.50-a-gallon liquor tax by mixing some products with a grape-based alcohol This is expected to raise $ 360 million over five years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Money     03-22 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Money,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robertson Alters Figures on Spending</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican presidential candidate <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, faced with bumping up against the federally-imposed campaign spending limit, revised some of his state spending figures downward in his newly filed campaign financial statement. The spending allocations for nine states showed lower cumulative expenditures in the report filed Monday than the figures <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> reported a month earlier. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s staff did not return a phone call Monday to answer questions about the revisions. In his report filed Monday with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the former TV evangelist reported he had spent $ 19 million through Feb. 29 against the spending cap of $ 23 million that applies to expenditures for the entire primary season. Even with the downward revisions in some state spending figures, the total was still more than the $ 17.6 million in spending against the cap that he reported through the end of January. Candidates who receive federal matching funds must agree to stay within the spending limit. The reports candidates filed Monday show new financial activity for the month of February as well as cumulative totals. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s revisions were in figures reported for <LOCATION> Califonria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. The biggest was in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> where his previous report showed an allocation of $ 1.1 million, but the new report shows an allocation of $ 746,514 through February. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who has spent more overall than any other candidate, also reported he borrowed another $ 1.9 million in February. He has taken out more than $ 9 million in loans since he began his campaign last year, and ended February with $ 8.4 million in debts and $ 7.4 million in cash on hand. Financial reports filed by his rivals show that Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> also has narrowly outspent Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has built a huge lead over both <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in the GOP race. Democratic contender <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the governor of Massachussetts, continues to raise more money than his rivals, all of whom have resorted to borrowing. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> raised $ 2.9 million in February, including federal matching funds, compared with less than $ 2 million each by Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> borrowed and repaid $ 149,000, during February, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> borrowed $ 292,352, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> borrowed $ 500,000. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> did not take out loans in February, which is the month covered by the new financial statements. But his aides have said he borrowed $ 1 million before the March 8 Super Tuesday contests in 20 states, and $ 300,000 before the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> primary March 15. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s receipts for February were $ 2 million, giving him $ 8.8 million for the year, including federal matching funds based on contributions raised privately. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> raised $ 1.5 million during February, $ 8.7 for the year, his report shows. But despite raising and spending more money through February, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> failed to interrupt the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> push toward the August nominating convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has won 788 delegates so far to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s 178, according to The Associated Press delegate count. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> raised $ 5 million for the month, including his $ 1.9 million loan, which brought his total receipts this year to $ 18.3 million. For the month, he spent $ 3.1 million, to <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s $ 5.3 million and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s $ 4 million. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> has spent $ 18 million against the spending camp, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> $ 14.1 million. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> ended February with $ 836,445 in the bank and $ 716,107 in bills. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had $ 6.7 million in cash on hand _ more than any other candidate in the race _ and had $ 251,225 in debts. Among Democrats, <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> ended February with $ 1 million in debts and only about half that in available cash. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> was $ 825,199 in debt, and had $ 760,755 in cash on hand, the reports showed. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> owed $ 845,857, and had $ 428,420 on hand. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> had $ 342,964 in the bank and $ 91,858 in debts. But that was before <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> took out $ 1.3 million in loans during March, according to capaign aides. Figures detailing those transactions will appear in the financial reports due next month. Candidates who run up debts generally do so in the knowledge they will be receiving federal matching funds to help pay off the loans. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had $ 2.9 million in cash on hand at the end of the month, and $ 569,344 in debts. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was the Democrat closest to the spending cap, at $ 11.4 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880322-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-22-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TMIWater     03-22 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TMI Water,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Utility Moving To Boil Away Contaminated Water</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
