<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrappedWhales 2ndLd-Writethru a0803 10-27 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Trapped Whales, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0803,0854</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Icebreakers Make Last Ditch Bid To Release Whales</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 13 grafs to UPDATE with plunging temperatures newly
endangering whales' escape, quotes, details; picks up 6th graf:
`Eskimos with ...</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto staffing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE BARTLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BARROW, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Faced with thickening ice, plunging temperatures and the imminent departure of two Soviet icebreakers, rescuers late Thursday made a last-ditch effort to free two whales threatened again by the arctic icepack. The <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales, freed from nearly three weeks confinement in their icebound breathing hole off <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barrow </LOCATION>, moved closer to open water via man-made breathing holes and channels cut in the ice by the Soviet ships. But as night fell Thursday, the whales were in the last breathing hole cut for them, with about 300 meters of ice between the hole and open water, said rescue coordinator <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>. Temperatures Thursday hovered around 15 degrees below zero and were expected to drop to minus 20 to 25 degrees below overnight, cold enough to begin freezing over the adjoining open water of the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. Rescuers left a portable generator to power de-icing equipment at the whale's last breathing hole and light a beacon for the icebreaker <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Arseniev </PERSON>, which was to make two or three final runs to try to free the whales. `` This should free them,'' <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said. `` Hopefully, the whales will see the opportunity to leave. We've given them the best shot tonight.'' <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said the Soviets had to leave Thursday night. The plunging temperatures quickly refroze the channels the icebreaker had made earlier Thursday. Eskimos broke out chain saws and cut dozens more breathing holes leading away from the clogged channel toward the open sea. By nightfall, the workers were encountering dangerously unstable ice as a result of the icebreakers' earlier efforts. As they did Wednesday, the whales readily followed the path cut for them by the Eskimos. As night fell, they had advance as far as the last breathing hole. In a new tactic, rescuers carved 30 new holes Thursday in hopes that the whales would follow the holes away from the channel and eventually reach open water via another route the Soviet ships were clearing. `` They're ready to go home'' after nearly six months at sea, said Rear Adm. <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` We felt also with the weather creeping in like this, we had to do something tonight.'' Everyone hopes that when daylight arrives Friday, both the Soviets and the whales will be gone, <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> NOAA </ORGANIZATION> ice analyst <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Huffard </PERSON> said the open water was definitely beginning to freeze, but he remained optimistic that the whales could escape if they could get beyond the edge of the pressure ridge battered down by the icebreakers earlier in the week. Eskimos with chain saws had cut a series of breathing holes that allowed the whales to swim well away from the original hole to which they had been confined. The whales grew accustomed to the cutting and during a frenzy of work Wednesday, in which 50 new holes were cut, the whales repeatedly surfaced in the new holes before the last block of ice was removed. Since the whales were accustomed to the noise of the saws, that sound might be used to coax them forward toward open water, said <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, a biologist with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The Eskimos eventually worked the marine mammals to within a quarter-mile of a channel carved through the 18-inch-thick ice by two Soviet icebreakers late Tuesday and early Wednesday. Then the icebreaker <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Arseniev </PERSON> reopened the partially frozen channel. The man-made channel, aimed at guiding the whales to an natural open `` lead'' through the ice and eventually to open water, partially refroze during the night, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> said. He said the whales were `` conditioning themselves back to reality'' after nearly three weeks of confinement in the ice off the coast near <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barrow </LOCATION>. He also announced a crackdown on access to the whales by reporters and others. He said pilots entering restricted air space over the whales were subject to fines of $ 25,000. A biologist for the North Slope Borough, <PERSON> Geoff </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, said Thursday that the whales continued to appear healthy. The fate of the whales may never be known. Scientists involved in the rescue that cost more than $ 800,000 did n't attach radio transmitters to the whales to track them, in part because of concern that the devices would only add to their stress, said federal marine mammal biologist <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>. A whale that was trapped with the pair nearly three weeks ago apparently died last week. The endangered <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> gray whales have one of the longest migration routes of all mammals, 6,000 to 8,000 miles from summer feeding grounds in the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> to the warm water off <LOCATION> Baja </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Their population has risen to about 20,000, growing at an annual average of 2.5 percent for the past decade, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GodAndDeath     10-27 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-God And Death,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Famous Consider God And Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One millionaire said he is sure he will go to heaven when he dies but another thinks death really is the end. A third thinks of heaven as eternally watching cricket. The thoughts emerged in a new book today, `` My God,'' compiled by actress <PERSON> Hayley </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON> and rock music manager <PERSON> Marcus </PERSON> <PERSON> Maclaine </PERSON>. They asked famous people for their personal concept of God and what happens when they die. Succinct replies came from novelist <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON> <PERSON> Amis </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> general director <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON>. They answered `` None'' and `` Nothing.'' Lord <PERSON> Forte </PERSON>, millionaire hotel owner and caterer, was more optimistic. `` I am certain that Heaven _ and I am confident I will not be sent elsewhere _ will be a beautiful place, but I have no fixed conception of what it will be like. I am prepared to be pleasantly surprised,'' he said. Musician <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON>, the former Beatle and also very rich, thought God was a shortenened version of good and that `` When you die you conk out.'' <PERSON> Yoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, widow of murdered Beatle <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lennon </PERSON>, said: `` God is the unknown power which is within. Death is a transition.'' Author-scientist <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> does n't believe in God but added, `` I'm very interested in him.'' <PERSON> Astrologer </PERSON> <PERSON> Patric </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> replied: `` All I know for sure about God is that it is n't me.'' <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, the best-selling novelist, said he had no idea what would happen to him after death, but hoped he would find himself on top of the pavilion at Lord's cricket ground in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> watching the game. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, president of the 850,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Amalgamated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, replied: `` I only pray that when I die there will be no pickets at the <PERSON> Pearly </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, only a sign saying ` Vacancies, apply within.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--PassTheHat     10-27 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pass The Hat,0157</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airline Passengers Pay For Refueling</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 French vacationers returning from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> had to pass the hat for gas money after the pilot of their DC-9 made an unscheduled refueling stop in southern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, the national daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repubblica </ORGANIZATION> reported. The crew of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet decided to forego a scheduled refueling stop in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> on Saturday and land instead in <LOCATION> Brindisi </LOCATION>, despite the fact that the airline had no refueling facilities or service account there, the report said. Crew members discovered upon landing that airport officials in <LOCATION> Brindisi </LOCATION> would not accept credit cards as payment for fuel. They then realized that they were a little short on cash. As the plane sat on the runway, the passengers gradually realized the situation and, reluctantly, began to gather money among themselves, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Repubblica </PERSON> said. Wednesday's report did not say how much money was needed to pay for the refueling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Schifrin     10-27 0825</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Schifrin,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Songs of the Aztecs'
^Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 What could easily be one of only operas ever performed in ancient langauge of the <ORGANIZATION> Aztecs </ORGANIZATION> will be staged at the Pyramids of <LOCATION> Teotihuacan </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Tenor <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, singing in <LOCATION> Nauhatl </LOCATION>, will star in the premiere of <PERSON> Lalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON>'s `` Songs of the Aztecs'' on the stone stage of the Square of the Moon, built centuries ago by ancient Meso-Americans. <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON> will conduct the <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philharmonic </ORGANIZATION> at the Oct. 29 event, a benefit to launch a campaign for the restoration of the Aztec Temple of <LOCATION> Teotihuacan </LOCATION>, an hour's drive from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> has pledged $ 100,000 toward the restoration. The composer said doing an opera in <LOCATION> Nauhatl </LOCATION> was not a serious problem. `` The chorus and singers are used to the phonetics of a foreign language,'' he said. `` I thought it would be better to do it in the original language. With a translation, the use of a dictionary and grammar, I was able to work it out. <PERSON> Chocolatl </PERSON> was a secret drink of the <LOCATION> Aztecs </LOCATION>. We say chocolate. Our word coyote comes from their coyotetl.'' He was helped by a Nauhatl authority, Dr. <PERSON> Georges </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaudo </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Toulouse </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON> wrote the music after finding some pre-Columbian poetry, in Spanish, by <PERSON> Nezahualcoyotl </PERSON> -LRB- 1432-72 -RRB-. `` -LRB- It -RRB- was so beautiful I decided to use it,'' he said. `` The last line of the poem is, ` It can not be in vain why we come to this <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>; let us leave some flowers; let us leave some songs.''' For the Oct. 29 performance, 10,000 chairs will be set up, a new sound system built and TV screens put in to provide subtitles in Spanish and English. `` We're trying to make some of the prices very popular,'' he said. `` A thousand people are going to pay very, very high prices. I can not tell you how much money it takes to preseve something that is very important. ... To know where we're coming from is going to help us to know where we're going.'' The pyramids at <LOCATION> Teotihuacan </LOCATION> date from 100 B.C. to 100 A.D. The site of the concert, <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON> said, is in the City of the Gods in a square of stone, the Square of the Moon. `` The square is raised; it's exactly the place for the full symphony, full chorus, soloists and conductor, where musicians used to play 500 years ago,'' he said. `` It was a stage; they built it for us. Along a stone avenue are ruins of temples and stairways. The whole place looks very impressive. We go to <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to find architectural riches but we have it right here.'' That <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON> is the composer of so esoteric a work may surprise those who know him either from his jazz days with <PERSON> Dizzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> or as a composer of more than 80 film and TV scores. <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON>, who is 56, was born in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>, where his father was concertmaster of the <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Philharmonic </LOCATION>. He studied composition and piano at the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Conservatory, and returned to <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> where he became a composer, arranger, conductor and pianist, in pop, jazz and classical music. `` I've seen opera since I was a child. I had a dramatic instinct. This is probably one of the first times I'm saying this openly but I think movies are the opera of today,'' he said. `` In ` The <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> Kid,' where I had <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> playing along with a symphony orchestra, it was not pop music. This was really serious music _ to me, and I think to many people. `` The score of ` Bullitt' is being played by symphony orchestras now. I did an arrangement of symphonic sketches from the score of ` Cool Hand <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>.''' He moved to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1958 and played piano in <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON>'s quintet from 1960-62. He composed `` Gillespiana Suite'' for the first record he on which he played with Dizzy. `` Many people think I went to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> to make money,'' she said. `` I did n't have any idea about how much money I was going to make. There is a group of composers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and there is no outlet to play their music. <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON> was the only example since <PERSON> Haydn </PERSON> to have his own orchestra to play his own music. The reason I went to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> was, there was an outlet for hearing your music you composed.'' Lately, he has done less film composing and more conducting. Last December, he became music director of the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Philharmonic. Their first recording together, <PERSON> Ravel </PERSON>'s `` <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Goose </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Stravinsky </PERSON>'s `` Petrushka'' and <PERSON> Schifrin </PERSON>'s double bass concerto with soloist <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Karr </PERSON>, is being released this fall `` I think music is to be shared, and not only through mechanical means like records. You can be in a theater or even a stadium, doing something for several thousand people. That is very thrilling.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RobinKilled     10-27 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Robin Killed,0469</SECOND>
<HEAD>Holy Homicide, Batman! Boy Wonder Is Blown To Bits</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He's punched out the Penguin, wrestled the Riddler and crushed the Catwoman. But after 48 years of crime-busting, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> _ yes, the Boy Wonder, <PERSON> Batman </PERSON>'s earnest if excitable teen-age sidekick _ has been blown to bits by the Joker. Death comes next week for <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> when <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comics </ORGANIZATION> distributes <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> issue No. 428, the third installment of the four-part `` A Death in the Family,'' in which the younger half of the Dynamic Duo is dynamited by the clown prince of crime. `` It was very odd. I realize all this stuff is made up, but everybody here felt like the family of an accident victim, waiting for the doctor to come out and say, ` There's still hope,''' said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, editor of the Batman series. The Joker, by the way, is doing more than undermining the quality of life in <LOCATION> Gotham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> these days; his incendiary eradication of <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> comes under his duties as <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s new ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. But it wo n't be the Joker, <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> creator <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, or <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> facing murder charges for the killing of <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> _ it's the readers of the Batman comics who voted in a phone-in poll to off the teen superhero born in 1940. A 900 number was set up on Sept. 15-16 by <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION> to allow fans to phone in the fate of <PERSON> Robin </PERSON>, who _ in case you have forgotten _ is the ward of <LOCATION> Gotham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> millionaire <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>. It was the first time <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION> has allowed its readers to decide a character's future, said <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, who also killed off <PERSON> Batgirl </PERSON> in the late 1960s. The final totals: 5,343 for the death penalty, 5,271 against. Oooof! There is some good news. The dead <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> is NOT <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Grayson </PERSON>, the original <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Batman </PERSON>'s campy cohort on the television program; <PERSON> Grayson </PERSON> split with the Caped Crusader in 1984, grabbed a new costume and became Nightwing, head of a new crime-fighting team published under the title `` The New Teen Titans,'' <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION> said. The not-so-dearly departed <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> was <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON>, a kid off the streets who became <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>'s new ward and the readers' new whipping boy. Angry letters to the editor labeled <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> `` a vindictive, vengeful little brat'' and `` a wimp;'' another letter urged the editors to `` waste him.'' The editors, with the approval of the fans, did just that. <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> promises <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> wo n't be coming back; the comics, unlike television's `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' will not take the easy way out, he promised `` We're not going to pull a <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Ewing </PERSON>. There will be no dream sequence,'' said <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>. `` He's dead. He's gone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Space     10-27 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Space,0761</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Enters Satellite Business From Lonely Mountain Valley</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>XICHANG, China (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turbaned peasants trudge by, prodding water buffalo and lugging firewood, and taking little notice of the towering hollow structure from another time and for another universe. Surrounded by green mountains in an isolated corner of <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> province, the Xichang Satellite Center and its 11-story gantry is the takeoff point for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s entry into the international satellite launching market. The base, normally closed to foreigners, is on display as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> enters final negotiations with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on issuing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> licenses for the launch of three <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> satellites. They would be the first American satellites put into orbit by a non-Western country. Agreement has been reached on safeguarding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technology secrets during the launch process and establishing <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s liability in case of accident. Officials meet again in November to work out how to ensure that Chinese prices, much lower than those charged by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space shuttle or European Ariane services, wo n't jeopardize the American commercial launching industry. Xichang's first commercial venture could come as early as 1989 with the launch of <ORGANIZATION> Westar </ORGANIZATION> 6, an old satellite retrieved by the space shuttle in 1984, for AsiaSat, a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> consortium. An Australian company, <ORGANIZATION> AUSSAT </ORGANIZATION>, intends to put two <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> communications satellites into orbit in the early 1990s. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> decided in the mid-1970s to build a rocket base in this remote area because it is easy to defend, sparsely populated and has clear winter days well suited for launches. But while the base is part of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s march to the 21st century, it is surrounded by reminders of the Middle Ages. The site is 40 miles north of Xichang, a small town accessible from the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION> by twice-a-week airplane flights or a 12-hour train ride. On the road from Xichang, women wash clothes in streams, water buffalo pull wooden plows through rice paddies, and barefoot children scamper around mud-baked houses. Farmers spread their grain on the road so truck wheels can help grind it. Between launches, the base looks abandoned. The site, run by the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, employs 1,200, but new buildings to house the 141-foot Long March III rockets and satellites during pre-launch testing are almost empty. Windows in the gantry blown out during the last launch in March have yet to be replaced. About four miles from the launch pad, only two engineers sat at monitors in the gymnasium-like control center. A smaller control center, built into the mountains at the launch site, was not shown to visitors. Site officials say the simplicity of the operation is a main reason for its competitive prices and high success rate. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> reportedly can undercut space shuttle or Ariane prices by as much as 30 percent. <PERSON> Tong </PERSON> <PERSON> Lianjie </PERSON>, deputy director of the center, said the price advantage is `` mainly because our launching facilities are simple, reliable and practical.'' He said the equipment, all produced in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, is relatively cheap and `` technical personnel in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have fairly low salaries. We will not seek a high profit, although of course we will seek a profit.'' <PERSON> Tong </PERSON> gave assurances <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will not pose a threat to other satellite services. `` Because of the limited number of launches, we ca n't be that competitive in the international market.'' Center officials said military control over <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s space program is another reason for its successes. Since 1970, when <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> became the fifth nation after the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to launch a satellite with its own carrier rocket, it has had 23 successful launches and one failure. `` Military discipline is better than that of civilians, who spend half the time smoking cigarettes and the other half working,'' said <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Yongde </PERSON>, deputy director of the center. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s space program, overseen by the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astronautics </ORGANIZATION>, is concentrating on building a more powerful version of the Long March III and adding a second launch pad at Xichang by early 1990. This will give <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> the ability to put a payload of up to 8.8 tons in orbit, compared with 1.4 tons at present and 12 tons for the space shuttle. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has had feelers about its launching services from more than a dozen countries and has signed an agreement with <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> for future joint development of satellites for the study of Earth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     10-27 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0872</SECOND>
<HEAD>Respect For Rights Hasn't Hit Home In Salvador</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cartoon shows a government soldier facing a guerrilla. Each holds an assault rifle, but piled on the soldier's bent back are a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military adviser, a human rights monitor, and papers documenting rights abuses. The guerrilla stands tall, unencumbered. The drawing in the office of Col. <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON>, chief of operations for the joint chiefs of staff, illustrates how human rights are considered a burden by many Salvadoran officers. Interviews with soldiers, diplomats and judicial authorities suggest that only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure and fear of losing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid keep the army in line. Abuses by the armed forces are far fewer than in the early 1980s, when death squads were killing hundreds of people every month, but two peasant massacres and a gang rape in recent weeks have raised concern. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday that hundreds of suspected government opponents have been killed in the past two years by death squads, usually made up of troops and police. `` We're only at the beginning of a long road toward respect for human rights, obviously not at the end of it,'' said Judge <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Zelaya </PERSON>, who is handling the rape case. The increased death squad activity comes with President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON> suffering from cancer and leftist leaders re-entering the country after guerrillas agreed to let their political groups participate in a March 1989 presidential election. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, a centrist, has vigorously opposed death squad activity; leftists who fled because they feared for their lives said they felt they could return because death squad activity was down. At the same time, politically motivated slayings by leftist guerrillas have reportedly increased. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> has received more than $ 3 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic and military aid this decade, more than any country in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> lawmakers have said continued aid depends on growing respect for civil liberties. Officers and troops are not afraid to say they see respect for human rights as a burden. `` It limits our action,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> of the elite <PERSON> Arce </PERSON> <PERSON> Batallion </PERSON> during a recent patrol of guerrilla-dominated hills in northern <LOCATION> Morazan </LOCATION> province. Cpl. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> said thousands of civilians killed by death squads in the early 1980s `` deserved what they got.'' Paratrooper Sgt. <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Orellana </PERSON> said he favored `` the 1932 solution'' to defeat leftist guerrillas at war with the U.S.-backed government. He was referring to the slaying, by forces of then-dictator <PERSON> Maximiliano </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, of up to 20,000 peasants to quell a rebellion by a few hundred against landowners. One recent massacre took place Sept. 21, when soldiers detained most of the residents of the hamlet of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and accused them of collaborating with rebels. The soldiers took seven men and three women to a ravine, tied them up and killed them with grenades and rifle fire, according to neighbors and relatives of the dead. Seven were shot in the head from less than six inches away, an autopsy showed. A judge issued arrest warrants for four soldiers, but none has been handed over to judicial authorities. Human rights groups said they feared the investigation into the massacre _ the first mass killing of civilians in four years _ would make ordinary soldiers scapegoats and not focus on the responsible officers. <LOCATION> Americas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Watch </LOCATION>, a private organization that monitors rights in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION>, issued a report on <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> on Oct. 2. It said killings declined between 1984 and late 1987 before rising again and notes that no Salvadoran officer or death squad member has been prosecuted and punished for a human rights violation. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said dumped bodies frequently are found decapitated, dismembered, strangled or showing marks of rape or torture, such as burns and machete wounds. <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> said death squads intimidate government opponents by publishing `` death lists'' in newspaper advertisements and delivering coffins to the homes of intended victims. <PERSON> Zelaya </PERSON> has been handling the case of a 20-year-old who says she was raped by 13 soldiers in the town of <LOCATION> Apastepeque </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zelaya </PERSON> asked the commander of the cavalry regiment whose soldiers allegedly raped the woman for the names of the men on duty the day of the attack. He received no response. In the most recent incident, several men in army uniforms arrived the night of Oct. 14 in the hamlet of <LOCATION> Tres </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ceibas </LOCATION>, 11 miles north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, and pulled four young men from their homes. Minutes later, several shots were heard. Relatives found the bodies of the four, shot in the head, about 40 yards away. Rights groups blamed the army. The armed forces said the killers were guerrillas masquerading as soldiers. The <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> has noted a sharp rise in politically motivated slayings of civilians this year. Execution-style killings of civilians by the rebels are likewise up sharply. However, the guerrillas usually take responsibility for such slayings, which they call `` bringing to justice.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OccultinSchools     10-27 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Occult in Schools,0610</SECOND>
<HEAD>School Children Practice Occultism, Devil Worship</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOAN FISCHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The popularity of occultism, including devil worship, is growing among <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s young, and a newspaper said some even engage in the practices during breaks at school. Parents, public officials and church leaders say 10,000 teen-agers may be involved in occult practices ranging from seances to `` black sabbaths'' in which animals are sacrificed at cemeteries. A front-page report Oct. 8 in the influential <PERSON> Frankfurter </PERSON> <PERSON> Allgemeine </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeitung </PERSON> carried the headline, `` The Occult Is Spreading in Our Schools.'' It cited instances of pupils using breaks between classes for occult practices and said: `` Participants withdraw from other teen-agers. Their thoughts constantly revolve around the puzzling world of the spirits.'' In September, a meeting of the national parents' council issued a statement declaring: `` The rise of occultism and magic practices -LRB- among pupils -RRB- indicates spiritual and psychological deficits in our society.'' <PERSON> Hans-Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuser </PERSON>, spokesman for the North-Rhine <LOCATION> Westphalia </LOCATION> state culture ministry, said: `` Teens are using occult beliefs as they would a drug. This is more than just an individual case or a passing fad.'' He said officials the number of reports from schools was growing, especially from religion teachers. `` Often the pupils themselves get scared they might have gone too far in their occult practices and turn to their religion teachers for help,'' <PERSON> Neuser </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> by telephone. Religion is a subject in most West German public schools. Occult practices among teen-agers `` range from experimentation with pendulums or glasses to devil-worship ceremonies calling for animal sacrifice,'' <PERSON> Neuser </PERSON> said. The first practice mentioned involves calling on spirits to guide a dangling pendulum to letters or words placed beneath it. In other ceremonies, spirits of deceased friends or relatives are asked to move a glass, coins, or a table in response to certain questions. Among factors blamed for the turn to occultism are youth unemployment, broken homes and pessimism about the future. Two teen-age members of a group practicing devil worship were convicted of murder by a <LOCATION> Muenster </LOCATION> regional court in October 1987. They slit the wrists and throat of another cult member in what was to be a group suicide. Youngsters killed a cat during a `` black sabbath'' at a Dortmund cemetery and ripped out its intestines, the <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION> newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> am </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sonntag </ORGANIZATION> reported on Feb. 21. <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>, the weekly news magazine, published a photograph Oct. 12, 1987, of a note it said was written by a ninth-grader in Lahnstein and intercepted by her teacher. `` I asked <PERSON> Lucifer </PERSON> yesterday who is possessed by the devil,'' it said, and listed the names of 11 other pupils, the magazine reported. The Rev. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Lutheran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Views </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION> said: `` At least 10,000 teen-agers are involved to one degree or another in various occult practices,'' A Lutheran pastor in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION>, the Rev. <PERSON> Hans-Juergen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruppert </PERSON>, said teen-age adherence to traditional religions is declining in concert with occultism's rise. `` Teens are in increasing numbers turning away from traditional religion and turning to the occult as a replacement,'' he said. `` We have to increase contact with them through church youth groups and by strengthening their bonds to religion. The danger is that these children may continue drifting away from society.'' <PERSON> Neuser </PERSON> expressed fear of a deeper effect: `` This involvement happens while the youngster is still forming a sense of values and responsibility. If distant powers are supposedly controlling his behavior, he never has to take responsibility for his actions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Election     10-27 0664</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Election,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Violence Mars Campaign Among Religious Parties</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the Ultra Orthodox neighborhood of <LOCATION> Mea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shearim </LOCATION>, a bearded man in a black coat and hat used a stick to rip down a political poster, prompting an angry outburst from a passer-by. `` I do n't mind campaign posters, but this is a personal attack,'' explained Rabbi <PERSON> Mordechai </PERSON> <PERSON> Shlesinger </PERSON> as he tore down the poster, which attacked a rabbi aligned with the Agudat <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON> party. The incident reflects increasing tensions in the campaign leading up to Tuesday's elections, especially among religious parties whose swing votes may determine the next prime minister. The campaign in religious areas has been marked by telephone threats and vandalism, including swastikas painted on walls. Apart from the religious tensions, <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> has been doused with water and targeted by stone-throwers. Nine hecklers were arrested for blocking <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>' car on Tuesday. Religious parties are expected to control 13 to 15 pivotal seats in the 120-seat parliament, or Knesset. If election results between the big parties are as close as expected, both <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>'s left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bloc </ORGANIZATION> will court the religious parties to try to form a ruling coalition This will give the religious parties influence far beyond their numbers, especially in legislation touching on education and social affairs. Balconies, doors and walls are covered with colorful campaign symbols and posters in the normally staid <LOCATION> Mea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shearim </LOCATION> neighborhood of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> and in the religious town of <LOCATION> Bnai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brak </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. But some of the writing on the rough, ochre walls is threatening: `` Death to the leftists,'' says one. Another slogan warns a leading politicians, `` Your blood will be spilled.'' The issues in Mea Shearim are distinctly different from the war and peace questions being debated by Labor and <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>. On one wall, a swastika was placed next to the name of the <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal party with a strong stand against religious coercion such as the forced closing of theaters on the Sabbath. `` Murder the pathologists and archaeologists,'' said one scrawl, underscoring Ultra Orthodox demands to ban autopsies and prevent archaeological digs near cemeteries. The issue pits Agudat <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON>, which holds two parliament seats, against a splinter group, <PERSON> Degel </PERSON> <PERSON> HaTorah </PERSON>. Agudat <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON> accused its opponents of sending hit squads to vandalize property and attack Agudat followers. The independent Nation newspaper said the squads consisted of men with sticks and metal bars. <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravitz </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Degel </PERSON> <PERSON> HaTorah </PERSON>, denied the allegations. `` We tell our people not to hit back, even if they get blows,'' he said. In television ads, religious parties have stressed the need for more financial support to yeshiva seminaries and attacked social permissiveness they say has led to drug problems. Religiously observant voters account for about 20 percent of the 2.9 million eligible voters, and most of their political factions have drifted to the right in recent years. But leaders do not rule out a deal with Labor. `` Likud is closer to our views, but I do n't say now that Labor ca n't change this,'' Rabbi <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeev </PERSON> <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, leader of the Agudat <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON>. Labor members have been resistant to Orthodox demands for <LOCATION> Sabbath </LOCATION> observance and legislation outlawing non-Orthodox conversions. But <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON> said in an interview in his <LOCATION> Bnai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brak </LOCATION> apartment that it was `` very important that the country should at least publicly maintain an appearance of Judaism'' by observing religious law. The only liberal religious party is the <ORGANIZATION> Meimad </ORGANIZATION>, a new group that broke away from the larger <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Rippel </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Meimad </ORGANIZATION> candidate for parliament, said his party would try to heal the rift between religious and secular Jews. The party's views on the future of the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> are close to those of Labor. `` Although we believe that the land of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> belongs to us, we are willing to make territorial concessions for peace,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Fashion     10-27 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fashion,0482</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saint Laurent's Streamlined Classics</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Yves </PERSON> <PERSON> Saint </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> played it safe with streamlined classics in his ready-to-wear show for next summer. Short and edited down to essentials, the show Wednesday was a relief after other presentations that dragged out a hundred ways to create draped, flowered sheaths for a sex kitten. Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>'s fashion statement was short and pithy. And the clothes often looked like simpler versions of his last couture collection, just as deftly cut in their own way. In day wear, he led off with mariner-inspired suits _ in navy or white broadcloth pants or skirts just above the knee _ with a slightly fitted battle jacket or fitted blazer, both with brass buttons, and topped with jaunty sailors berets. Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> kept to his favorite shaped shoulders and short skirts, though he also dropped some hemlines in fluid, flared or pleated skirts to below the knee and longer _ to midcalf length in some pretty white belted sundresses with circular skirts. Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON>'s silk jersey sheath just barely caressed the body. In tiny stripes, it was crisscrossed by diagonal buttoned piping. A perfect little navy pleated dress with a white collar and bow could not have been simpler, yet had the master's touch. Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> did not go in for the pyramidal trouser line sweeping <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, but kept his pants long and straight in suits or narrow and cropped, matador style. For this peppy new line, he teamed the cropped pants with fitted jackets that had big puffy sleeves in colors like bright yellow and turquoise damasked cotton pique. With few exceptions, the color themes were played in a low key. Black, navy and white took precedence, with autumnal hues of beige, khaki and ochre not far behind. Jazzy colors popped up in bicolored suits in shades of turquoise, lime or corn yellow. The one flame red cotton poplin dress with balloon sleeves was a standout among all the sober clothes. There's good news for those who ca n't afford Saint Laurent couture: In ready-to-wear, he offered an excellent version of the tuxedo dress he did in 20 different ways for couture. Less successful but still fun was the bright bicolored suit with grape-bunch embroidery on shoulders and pockets, and even striated grape-shaped buttons. Catching the mood of the times, Saint <PERSON> Laurent </PERSON> concentrated on simple crepe de chine dinner dresses rather than rhinestone-encrusted ball gowns loaded with flounces, frou-frou and lace. Short kimono-wrapped silk dresses or variations on the shirtwaist in silk had a kind of studied throwaway simplicity. For a finale, there were gold-belted draped white crepe gowns. The show left some in the audience hungry for more, but there was nothing extraneous. Everything in this understated collection was wearable and chic.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-27 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites ,0567</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TEWKSBURY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Equipped with a gun, a nightstick and a regulation-size teddy bear, police officers in this town boast they're ready for any emergency. The idea of driving around with stuffed animals may not inspire a new television series _ `` T.J. Teddy''? _ but <PERSON> Tewksbury </PERSON> police officers are receptive to the the idea if it means helping children deal with traumatic events. `` When you've got a little kid who has been in an accident and who is hysterical, it's a good idea,'' said Officer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>. However, he added, the bears `` will stay in the trunk.'' The town's 13 police cars are equipped with two regulation, 7-inch teddy bears apiece. Police say the bears' first week on duty already has produced positive results. `` It calms the kids down a lot and creates a good feeling towards the police, too,'' said Deputy Police Chief <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosen </PERSON>. `` A lieutenant gave one to a child of a mother being interviewed concerning some domestic problems at her house.'' The bears were donated to the force by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pioneers </ORGANIZATION>, a charitable group whose members are current and retired phone company employees. The police department calls the group when a bear is given to a child so it can be replaced.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TYRONE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was love at first sight for <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Symons </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Martha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION> _ or rather, love at second sight, 60 years later. `` We knew almost immediately, as soon as we saw each other, that we would always be together,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Glasgow </PERSON>, 75, who became Mrs. <PERSON> Symons </PERSON> in a small wedding Tuesday here. The two were raised in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> and became childhood sweethearts, but `` we just broke up and went our separate ways'' six decades ago, said Mrs. <PERSON> Symons </PERSON>. They both married and raised families before being widowed. They were reunited when Mrs. <PERSON> Symons </PERSON>' sister, <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, played matchmaker recently and invited <PERSON> Symons </PERSON> to visit. `` It's just been wonderful,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>. `` I never saw two people more happy together.'' <PERSON> Symons </PERSON>, 77, of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, said his new wife has changed slightly `` for the better.'' But when he recently saw her after the long separation, `` it was just like it was 60 years ago.'' `` He has n't changed a bit, not one bit,'' the bride said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATTLE CREEK, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thieves stole 25 pumpkins from <PERSON> Ion </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Tharp </PERSON>, but the couple made out like bandits after receiving 32 pumpkins from sympathetic zoo workers and others from anonymous donors. `` Halloween is supposed to be a time of fun for children,'' said <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohn </PERSON>, a volunteer at Binder Park Zoo who helped arrange the delivery. `` Stolen pumpkins are n't fun.'' The Pennfield Township couple had arranged the 25 pumpkins on their front porch and yard to surprise two of their grandchildren, who arrived Wednesday for a two-week visit. The Tharps awoke Sunday to find the pumpkins stolen. The pumpkin pilferage was reported locally the next day, and donations soon followed. Two staffers from the zoo, which had stockpiled about 1,100 pumpkins for a Halloween event billed as the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zoo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boo </LOCATION>, delivered 32 pumpkins to the Tharps on Tuesday night. `` It's nice to know that there's a lot of good people out there,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Tharp </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsInspections     10-27 0360</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Inspections,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Pushing On-Site Inspection Plan For START Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is seeking agreement from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on an on-site inspection proposal his administration says will make a strategic arms reduction treaty verifiable while shielding `` legitimate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> secrets and interests.'' State Department Spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said Wednesday that the president recently made a number of verification-related decisions, `` including some on the approach we will take to so-called suspect site inspections.'' But he declined to spell out details while the U.S.-Soviet arms reduction talks are continuing in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. The two sides are seeking to work out 50 percent cuts in their arsenals of strategic, or intercontinental, nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said that while `` considerable progress'' has been made at the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks, `` much still remains to be done.'' `` Our intention in the START talks is to flesh out the details of our position, including the details of a START verification regime, so that there will be a complete <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> position on the table in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` START will have the most extensive verification regime in history, well beyond that of the verification measures of the INF -LRB- Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces -RRB- treaty.'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> added that `` We are convinced that these provisions will make the treaty effectively verifiable. At the same time, we must be careful to protect legitimate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> secrets and interests. ... We believe the proper balance has been made between those two considerations.'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has completed its negotiating position on space-based defenses with proposals intended to `` complement our initiative to permit the development, testing and deployment of all space-based sensors ...'' `` This element does not represent any change in longstanding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy on the ABM -LRB- Anti-Ballistic Missile -RRB- Treaty and its proper interpretation,'' he said, adding that administration policy on the conduct of the Strategic Defense Initiative, as worked out with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, also is unchanged. `` Testing of space-based components, which is permitted by the ABM Treaty, does not represent deployment of such components,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said and added: `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy remains that we will not accept any restrictions on SDI beyond those of the ABM Treaty.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--RealOldGlory     10-27 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Real Old Glory,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Council Replaces Out of Date Flag</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KEARNEY, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Old Glory hanging in the City Council chambers was so old it had only 48 stars. Mayor <PERSON> Justus </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobesh </PERSON> said Tuesday he bought a new flag after he noticed the red, white and blue in the old one had turned gray and yellow. He said it was easier to buy the flag himself than to try including it in the city's budget. `` All the years I've served on the council, I just thought this was a small contribution I could make,'' said <PERSON> Dobesh </PERSON>, who has been on the council for 13 years. When city officials removed the flag, they found it had only 48 stars, said city finance director <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Wessels </PERSON>. But no one knows when the old flag was bought.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WeatherOffices     10-27 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Weather Offices,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weather Service Facing Cuts Due To Budget Squeeze</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A money shortage is threatening the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> less than a month into the government's new fiscal year, although officials say no decision has been made on whether to close offices. An employee union said Wednesday it had obtained information from the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, parent agency of the weather service, indicating that as many as 40 weather offices could be in jeopardy. <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Witten </PERSON> confirmed that the agency is facing financial problems and said many options are being considered for saving money. He said no decisions have been made on any closings. A recently approved pay raise for federal workers, coupled with budget cutbacks, is expected to leave the weather service about $ 25 million short of its needs for the fiscal year that started Oct. 1. `` Basically, we're looking at the operation and seeing what we can do to meet that shortfall,'' <PERSON> Witten </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` Obviously the sooner you do it in the fiscal year the better, but the fact is we have n't decided on any specific reductions at this time. We're looking at a lot of options,'' he said. <PERSON> Witten </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has instituted a hiring freeze and is considering offering early retirement to employees who may be eligible to leave before the normal retirement age, as immediate ways to save money. Salaries are by far the largest item in the agency's budget. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement claiming that plans have been drafted to close as many as 40 of the 191 weather offices. Such a series of closings could have a serious impact on forecasting, particularly affecting airline operations, the group said. The Weather Service offices collect hourly observations, which are transmitted to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Suitland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, where a national forecast is developed. That is then sent to local forecast offices, which use it along with their local observations to issue local weather forecasts and alerts. This is not the first time <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> offices have been threatened with closings in efforts to save money. Each time, however, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has voted money to keep the offices open. Among the weather data collection offices that may be threatened, according to the employees group, are: Eastern region: <LOCATION> Mansfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Elkins </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; Reading, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Lynchburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Parkersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. Central region: <LOCATION> Alamosa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crosse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Sheridan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>.; Valentine, Neb.; <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. Southern region: <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Roswell </LOCATION>, N.M. Western region: <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Lewiston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Havre </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>.; <LOCATION> Walla </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Walla </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Milford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Burna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Klamath </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> region: <LOCATION> Kahului </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> region: <LOCATION> Barter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>; Homer, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. In addition, the employee association said there was the possibility that the <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, forecast office would be downgraded and that hours would be reduced at offices in <LOCATION> Flint </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sault </LOCATION> Ste. <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StealthBomber     10-27 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stealth Bomber,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Secret Bomber Is Target Of Scientist Group Criticism</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The secret Stealth bomber is n't even scheduled to be publicly unveiled until next month, but it already has become a target for critics who say it is n't needed and may not work. The latest complaints were raised in a report Wednesday by the <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientists </ORGANIZATION>, a private group which in the past has been sharply critical of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration arms control policies and defense decisions. `` There is no role for the B-2,'' the report said, using the formal name of the plane designed as a `` flying wing'' and made of high-tech materials that make the plane difficult to detect on radar. `` We should probably use the first B-2 prototype to gain some practical experience with this novel military technology, but there seems little reason to proceed now with the production of this bomber,'' it said. The Pentagon is scheduled to unveiled the bomber publicly Nov. 22 at the <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> plant in <LOCATION> Palmdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. Thus far, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has only released an artist's drawing. Congressional critics have raised questions about the plane's future, particularly as cost estimates have increased Both the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committees </ORGANIZATION> have backed the planes, but the two Democratic-controlled panels have also asked the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> to justify rising costs and assure <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that technical problems can be solved. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> is tentatively planning to buy 132 of the planes. The first estimates in 1981 were that the fleet would cost about $ 22 billion, but the figure rose to $ 43 billion by 1987 and the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> now estimates that 132 B-2s will cost $ 68.8 billion. That would make the B-2 the most expensive weapon system ever built. Production is tentatively scheduled to begin early next year. The B-2, along with the B-1 bomber, is intended to replace the aging B-52 as the newest components of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> three-pronged nuclear deterrent, which also includes submarine-launched missiles and land-based missiles such as the MX. The report by the <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientists </ORGANIZATION> said, `` The secrecy surrounding this project, intended to protect technological secrets from the Soviets, is also hiding an expensive project of dubious merits from Americans.'' <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials, when asked for comment, said they had not yet seen the FAS report. The FAS noted that `` two missions for the B-2 have emerged from the veil of secrecy.'' `` Some argue that the B-2 is needed to offset improvements in Soviet air defenses. ... Others argue that the B-2 is needed in order to attack Soviet mobile missiles such as the SS-24 and SS-25. Neither of these arguments in favor of the B-2 is particularly compelling,'' it said. The Soviets are likely to upgrade their air defenses, but even when they do, they will still be vulnerable to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weapons such as nuclear-tipped cruise missiles and the B-1, the <ORGANIZATION> FAS </ORGANIZATION> said. Using the B-2 to hit Soviet mobile weapons is risky because the plane would needed targeting information from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> satellites, the <ORGANIZATION> FAS </ORGANIZATION> said. Those satellites could be knocked out by <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> weapons during the early stages of any war, it said, leaving the B-2 without an effective way to locate its targets. `` In fact, the Stealth bomber is as much a first-strike weapon as the MX. Both systems are intended to destroy Soviet missiles before they can be launched against the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> FAS </ORGANIZATION>, which has also been critical of the MX. It concluded that `` the B-2 poses the same dangers as the MX and the Strategic Defense Initiative _ increased risk of nuclear war, further escalation of the arms race; and complication of arms control and reduction.'' The <ORGANIZATION> FAS </ORGANIZATION> study cited what it said are a number of technical concerns about the B-2. `` Problems with the stability of flying wing designs date back to the YB-49 flying wing in the 1940s,'' it noted, citing reports that a companion F-19 Stealth fighter has suffered several crashes. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has not confirmed those crashes. Even should all the problems be solved, `` there are a number of questions regarding the extent to which the B-2 and its stealth technology will be effective,'' it said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReagantheCalifornian Bjt   10-27 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan the Californian, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Unlike Bush, Reagan's Home-State Credentials
Unchallenged</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tale of two politicians: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, born and raised in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, moved to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> as a young man, made a career for himself in one of the state's leading industries, raised a family, entered <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> politics and was twice elected to office. He is dogged to this day by skepticism about his claim to be a Texan. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, born and raised in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, moved to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> as a young man, made a career for himself in one of the state's leading industries, raised two families, entered <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> politics and was twice elected to office. Nobody ever suggests that he is not a Californian. In fact, as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> flies off today for a round of pre-election politicking, much of his activity will be focused on the state he first visited as an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> sportscaster covering the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cubs </ORGANIZATION> in spring training. `` That's his home state. It's felt he can be very helpful here,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> as he outlined the Illinois-born president's itinerary right after the Republican convention in August. But if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s career as an oilman and his two terms as a congressman from a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> district do n't qualify the vice president as a Texan, how come a movie career and two terms as governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> make <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> an undisputed Californian? `` I wonder whether it does n't have to do with the important events in one's life whether one considers oneself a native of a particular state,'' says <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heslop </PERSON>, a professor of ethics at <ORGANIZATION> Claremont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McKenna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and a specialist in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> voting opinions. `` One of the most important events to all of us, I think, is where one's children go to school. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s children went to school in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.'' Of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s five children, one attended the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>, but the others went to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>, to <LOCATION> Tulane </LOCATION>, to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> and to <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. There are more reasons for the difference. For one thing, while Texans traditionally look askance at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Englanders </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was practically settled by Midwesterners. <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> was once called, in fact, `` The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Colony </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.'' `` The settlers of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> came mainly from the American heartland, from rural and small-town areas,'' historian <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wills </PERSON> wrote, `` but they invented something different, a kind of hick cosmopolis.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was right at home. Both his marriages were to women he met in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, but both were from the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> as he was. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> grew up in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. Even <PERSON> Louella </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON>, the gossip columnist who chronicled his marriages, was from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s home town of <LOCATION> Dixon </LOCATION>, Ill. Except for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has never maintained a home outside <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> since he signed a six-month contract with <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> in 1937. He had a home in <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palisades </LOCATION> before being elected president and plans to divide his time between a home in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and his ranch north of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION> starting Jan. 20. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s legal residence is Suite 271 of the Houstonian Hotel and <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, but he purchased a home in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, after becoming vice president. Whatever his residence, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporters in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> resent suggestions that he is not one of them. `` <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> is really his home and he loves the state,'' <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Farish </PERSON>, whose <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> company handles the vice president's assets in a blind trust, said in a recent interview. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, too, likes to remind <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> audiences that he's `` back home.'' Still, ponder this: When <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spoke at an Italian-American dinner of meat balls and ziti in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, this month, the band unhesitatingly struck up `` <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Here I Come.'' -LRB- The second line is `` Right Back Where I Started From.'' -RRB- If it had been <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, would they have played `` Deep in the Heart of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>?''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChronicCare     10-27 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chronic Care,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shortage Seen Among Health Care Workers For the Elderly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Continued low wages and difficult working conditions will lead to a shortage of health aides needed to care for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s elderly, according to a report prepared by advocacy groups. `` This nation is on the brink of a full-blown crisis in caregiving for the chronically ill,'' said <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Glasse </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Older </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, which joined with a government employees' union in commissioning the study `` An exploited, overburdened work force is caring for the frail, the sick and the elderly,'' <PERSON> Glasse </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Glasse </PERSON>'s organization issued the study jointly on Wednesday with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and Municipal Employees. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntee </PERSON>, president of the 1.4 million-member union, said chronic care workers `` are among the most exploited workers in our nation.'' `` The solutions to the crisis are obvious _ a higher minimum wage, improvements in Medicaid reimbursement, more stringent licensing and training requirements,'' he said. The groups' report compiled information from state and federal statistics from 1985 to the present. It painted a bleak picture of the 1.5 million health care aides caring for patients in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s more than 25,000 nursing and private homes. It said the majority of the workers are middle-aged minority women earning just above minimum wage without insurance coverage or overtime. Most leave their health care jobs within five years for those reasons. Given the conditions, <PERSON> Glasse </PERSON> said, it will be difficult to find the 500,000 health care aides the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimates will be needed by the year 2000. The report quoted the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> as saying more than half of nursing homes surveyed already report shortages of nursing aides. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION>, representing organizations providing home care, reported comparable shortages. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinlan </PERSON>, a consultant who compiled the study, noted that the number of persons requiring paid caretakers is increasing rapidly. She said many family members who otherwise would provide such care now must seek employment to make ends meet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-People-Hope     10-27 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Hope,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stumps For LA Supervisor Candidate; Opponents Charge Ulterior
Motives</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> says he has been going to bat for county Supervisor <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonovich </PERSON> because the politician's a `` softball pitcher.'' `` Softball and politics go hand in hand _ they're both underhanded,'' <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> joked at a $ 500-a-plate fund-raiser Tuesday night. But some opponents of <PERSON> Antonovich </PERSON> say the comedian is playing hard ball, trying to score a starring role in what they have labeled his latest road picture: `` <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranch </LOCATION>.'' Protesters outside the dinner said <PERSON> Hope </PERSON> is trying to win county approval for a road that would lead through the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mountains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> area to the entertainer's 1,500-home Jordan Ranch development in <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Hope denied he is trying to curry favor from <PERSON> Antonovich </PERSON>, but the supervisor's opponent, <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, has turned the matter into a political issue. `` He is entertaining at Mr. <PERSON> Antonovich </PERSON>'s fund-raiser ... I think with a purpose in mind,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said at debate last month. <PERSON> Antonovich </PERSON>, at the debate, said `` adequate roads'' were needed in the area and promised he would work with the community to reach an environmentally sound decision if <LOCATION> Ventura </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> approves the housing project.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     10-27 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 04; 11; 14; 22; 29 33.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 01; 04; 15; 22; 26; 46. Supplementry 35.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 8-8-3; 7-5-8-3; 4-9-3-1-3; 2-0-8-0-1-4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SenateMoney Bjt   10-27 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Money, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democratic Senate Candidates Outdistancing GOP Rivals in Fund
Raising</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Something strange is going on in this year's 33 election contests for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>: Democrats are raising more campaign money than their Republican rivals. By the end of last month, according to financial data reported to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the 33 Democrats running for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats had collected $ 83.6 million toward their campaigns. Their 33 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponents had pulled in $ 73.3 million. `` It is unusual,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, communications director for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the party's campaign arm. `` But it's incumbency talking,'' as well as givers' expectations that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will remain under <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> control, he said It is true that incumbents always have an easier time raising campaign money, and that <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> have more incumbents, 15, up for re-election this year than the Republicans, 12. And it also is true that most political analysts are predicting not only that Democrats will hold onto their 54-46 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority, but they may pad it by a seat or two come Nov. 8. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> incumbents actually fared slightly better than their Democratic counterparts in fund raising. The dozen Republicans averaged $ 3.8 million apiece as of Sept. 30, while the 15 Democratic senators averaged $ 3.4 million. But in nearly every other category _ open-seat races, challengers, and political action committee money _ the Democrats outdistanced their traditionally well-heeled rivals. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> chalks some of the differences up to unusual situations in a handful of states that skew the numbers the Democrats' way, and topping his `` unusual list'' is <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>. `` It's like running against a bank,'' he says of the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> who holds a substantial lead in the <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race against <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> minority leader <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bucks </ORGANIZATION> basketball team and heir to a family grocery store chain, spent $ 3 million, most of it his own money, to overcome better-known rivals in the primary, and may top $ 6 million by Election Day. <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, who is conceded to be better versed on the issues, was trailing 3-to-1 in fund raising and was down by more than 20 points in the last published statewide poll. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> has sought to make his spending a virtue, saying it means he wo n't be beholden to special interests. `` Nobody's senator but yours,'' is the tagline to his prolific TV spots. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> also points to <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, an open seat where former Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> has been regarded as the prohibitive favorite for years and has been treated by campaign donors more as an incumbent than as an open-seat candidate. <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> had raised $ 2.7 million, compared with $ 192,000 for his lesser-known <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> opponent <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawkins </PERSON>. In addition, Republicans say the presidential election has diverted attention from bids by quality <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates and made it harder for them to compete for a limited amount of campaign dollars. But Democrats have other explanations for their new-found parity with the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> in fund raising. `` The candidates we recruited are an impressive group of elected officials who have their own political bases and their own fund-raising bases,'' said <PERSON> Anita </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` Democratic challengers are not being outspent 2-to-1 or 3-to-1 like in previous years.'' Democrats, after a slow start, have learned to be competitive for special-interest money, as well, she said. <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> figures show Democratic <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidates overall have received $ 21.4 million from political action committees, while Republicans have collected just $ 17.5 million. The disparity led to a `` woodshed'' session last month at which <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., and chief fund-raiser <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Minn </LOCATION>., called leaders from business PACs to a meeting to scold them for supporting `` We're getting far fewer contributions than the Democrats are,'' said <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>. `` The message -LRB- at the meeting -RRB- was that business PACs should take a serious look at pro-business candidates. That they should look at the philosophies of the people they're giving to.'' Some Capitol Hill observers are predicting that the Democrats' catch-up in raising PAC money will lead Republicans, who have protected the current fund-raising system so far, to throw out the rules in 1989 `` This, I think, will be the last election we have under the current system,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, a political analyst and author of a political newsletter. `` I am convinced we're seeing big-time reform next year. Republicans just are not going to defend PACs any more. They will decide it's in their self interest.'' Republicans are not shut out of the picture entirely when it comes to money, however. Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., tops the money list for all candidates so far this year, having amassed about $ 12 million for his re-election bid, roughly double the amount his challenger, Lt. Gov <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, has raised. And in a hard-fought open seat contest in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, Republican Rep. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON> has outdistanced opponent Rep. <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowdy </PERSON> in fund raising and holds a nearly 4-to-1 advantage in cash on hand going into the crucial final weeks of the campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-TV     10-27 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-TV,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Waging an Airwaves War in Hopes of Capturing Presidency</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Is there a market niche among swing voters for a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor who's mounting an unprecedented television sales campaign for himself? Probably not, analysts say, but he's got the right idea. Saturation exposure is `` a perfectly reasonable strategy'' for Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, given his double-digit deficit in the polls and the proximity of Election Day, says <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>. `` But you've got to have a product to sell. You have to have something people want to buy,'' says <PERSON> Sabato </PERSON>. `` What they may not be accounting for is the fact that most people have apparently concluded that they do n't want <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to be president. Seeing him more often is not going to change that evaluation.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is waging an airwaves war to ward off the closing of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> minds, abetted by TV news and interview shows that are providing him with unprecedented blocks of free exposure to millions of viewers. The invitations are flowing to both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Republican nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. But while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the nearly prohibitive favorite, is still weighing whether and where to appear, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is taking on all comers. `` He's going on every TV show he can find except <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>,'' joked <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> government professor, pollster and author of two books about campaign media coverage. `` Do n't get me wrong, he's doing the right thing,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> added. `` But will this turn the election around? Of course not.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> latest extended appearance, 90 minutes on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Nightline'' Tuesday night, drew predictable raves from his own spin doctors and equally predictable put-downs from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> camp `` A terrific session,'' pronounced <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> adviser <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Engelberg </PERSON>. `` He got his pants chewed up,'' declared <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodin </PERSON>. More objective reviewers noted that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> passed up numerous chances during the interview to stress his new populist image as a fighter for `` Main Street'' Americans, a president who would be `` on your side.'' He also failed to reject a <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> suggestion that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has nailed `` yoabato said. `` That was the dullest interview I've ever seen <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppel </PERSON> conduct. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' answers just were n't that lively or interesting. And he missed so many opportunities to make useful points from his perspective. Something to warm him up, something to make him appear more human.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is running the usual 30-second TV ads and a 5-minute network spot summarizing his appeal. He has already appeared, in addition to `` Nightline,'' on the morning news shows and the <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> talk show on Cable News Network. His wife, <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, was on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Face the Nation.'' His running mate, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, was on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` This Week with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkley </PERSON>'' and was interviewed on the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> `` Evening News'' Wednesday night. A new <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll indicates about a quarter of the nation's probable voters still classify themselves as undecided. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will have a few more shots at them, including lengthy appearances on the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> evening newscasts and an interview with <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON> on the Fox network Nov. 6. `` Everything depends on his performance and how interested swing voters or soft <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporters are in hearing him make his pitch,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, a Republican consultant and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> commentator. `` He has everything to gain because he has nothing to lose,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> added. `` He's behind in every poll. He's behind in more than 40 states. His only hope is to get as much exposure for himself as possible and hope that what he says has some resonance with voters.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a self-professed Democrat, said he ca n't imagine <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> attracting anyone into his column `` by force of personality. But he ca n't hide now, he's got to come out. He's got to be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. And he will go down in an honorable defeat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881027-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-27-88 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-NuclearSafety 3rdLd-Writethru a0401 10-27 1089</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuclear Safety, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0401,1,050</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Nuclear Group Urges Safety Overhaul at Atomic Weapons Plants</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 14th graf pvs bgng, `The New,' with 2 grafs to UPDATE
with Rockwell spokesman's comments, edit for transition</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
