<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Ethiopia-Rebels     05-27 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ethiopia-Rebels,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ethiopian Guerrillas Claim Capture of Three Strategic Towns</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALAH ZARROUG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ethiopian guerrillas on Thursday claimed they captured three garrison towns in northern <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, including <LOCATION> Korem </LOCATION>, the site of a major government food relief station in the drought-stricken region. The towns were taken Wednesday, according to <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidane </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Tigrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> official. He said nothing of casualties. <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON> said a joint force of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> and the newly formed <ORGANIZATION> Ethiopian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> took <LOCATION> Korem </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Wollo </LOCATION> province, while <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> forces simultaneously captured the garrison towns of <LOCATION> Amba </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alage </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kasad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gudu </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Tigre </LOCATION> province, <LOCATION> Wollo </LOCATION>'s northern neighbor. The inaccessibility of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s northern region makes independent verification of government or rebel claims difficult. In <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s capital, <PERSON> Addis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ababa </PERSON>, government spokesman <PERSON> Teklu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tabor </PERSON> refused to comment. Western sources said they had heard no reports of any of the towns falling. Widespread crop failures last year have left 1 million people in need of emergency food aid in <LOCATION> Wollo </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Korem </LOCATION>, 250 miles north of <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>, has been a major government food distribution station. Government relief workers there have been handing out one-month rations to about 6,000 people a day. Fighting in <LOCATION> Tigre </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s northernmost province, <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION>, has crippled relief operations aimed at feeding an estimated 3.2 million drought victims in those provinces. There are 7 million drought victims nationwide. <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON> said the rebel operation was aimed at thwarting a big offensive President <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> is preparing for Tigre. The push started in <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> and stalled, said <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON>, repeating claims made by the <ORGANIZATION> Eritrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. The secessionist <ORGANIZATION> Eritrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> has been fighting for 27 years in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s longest civil war. The <ORGANIZATION> Tigrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> took up arms against the <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> government in 1974 demanding greater autonomy. <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> inherited the insurgencies 14 years ago when he, with a group of army officers, overthrew Emperor <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Selassie </PERSON>. The government and the two rebel fronts all are Marxist. <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON> rejected Zambian President <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaunda </PERSON>'s plea at the summit in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> of the Organization of African Unity that the rebels make peace with the government. `` There will be no peace in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> unless <LOCATION> Mengistu </LOCATION> is destroyed,'' <PERSON> Yemane </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Meese     05-27 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Meese,200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Bush, Meese Met Secretly To Discuss AG's Legal Problems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met privately with Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> recently to discuss political ramifications of the attorney general's ongoing legal problems, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, citing unidentified sources in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is vacationing, reported in Saturday editions that the secret meeting took place at <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s request shortly before May 16 The newspaper said it could not be learned what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. Two <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aides earlier this month called <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> a campaign liability, but the vice president denied he had authorized the statements. In the past, the vice president has declined to comment on whether the embattled attorney general should step down, claiming he did n't want to prejudge the case. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s financial dealings in several areas are under investigation by independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who is expected to issue a report in several weeks raising questions about <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s ethical conduct. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, contacted in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> about the Post story, said: `` We have no comment on that.'' <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> said he conferred with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> chief of staff <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, who decided that the campaign should not respond to the story.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TurtleRepair     05-27 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Turtle Repair,0279</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veterinarian Uses Auto-Body Resin, Fiberglass To Patch Up Snapping
Turtle</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICHESTER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A veterinarian who used auto-body resin and fiberglass cloth to patch up a wounded snapping turtle says his 22-pound patient is `` crawling around nicely.'' A woman who found the turtle in a pool of blood off Route 28 corralled it into a box and brought it to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Messenger </PERSON>. The snapper had been hit by a car on the highway, and by the time it got to Messenger, it had lost a lot of blood and chunks of its shell were missing. Despite Messenger's experience with exotic animals _ including a cobra from which he removed a mouth tumor _ he had never worked on a snapper before, let alone a 20-year-old equipped with jaws that could nip off a finger. `` It was very challenging,'' the veterinarian said Thursday. After cleaning out the wound and covering it with gauze, Messenger injected antibiotics into the turtle's tail to fend off infection. Then he let the turtle rest for a couple days before operating on Wednesday. After trimming away dead and damaged tissue, and using a saw to cut off damaged bone and shell, Messenger used auto-body repair resin and fiberglass cloth to repair the damaged shell. `` The prognosis is very good,'' Messenger said Thursday. `` He's crawling around nicely. Messenger said he will keep the turtle for a couple of weeks to watch its recovery, then let it loose near to where it was found. Meantime, he said, he will have to find food for it. `` I think I'm going to go out fishing,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Buffett     05-27 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Buffett,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investor Warren Buffett Has Bit Part On ABC Soap</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON>, a corporate takeover specialist whose company holds a major stake in <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> television, says he does n't expect an award for his appearance as a bartender in an episode of an ABC-TV soap opera. <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON> is joined in the scene for `` Loving'', scheduled to air today, by the show's creator, <PERSON> Agnes </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, chairman of apital Cities-ABC. `` They were wise. They did n't trust us with any dialogue,'' <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON> said Thursday. He said he has seen a tape of the show and was n't too impressed with his performance. `` For a town that produced <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brando </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON>, I'm a sad commentary, I'll tell you,'' he said. <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON>'s Omaha-based company, <ORGANIZATION> Berkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hathaway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, is the largest shareholder of <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cities-ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the television network. The scene is set in a restaurant where <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> plays a waiter and Miss <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> portrays a customer. During the scene, <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON>'s bartender character and waiter <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> are summoned by a headwaiter to eject an unruly young woman from the bar, <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON> said. None of the three cameo performers spoke in the scene, he said. <PERSON> Buffett </PERSON> said he was invited to appear on `` Loving'' by <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, whom he met at a dinner party at the Winter Olympics in <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Repression     05-27 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Repression,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Regime Intimidates Opposition With Beatings, Threats</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The regime of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has used detentions, beatings, threats and sexual harassment to intimidate Panamanians and quell what appeared only a month ago to be a rising wave of protest. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> does n't have to resort to slayings or to arranging for people to `` disappear,'' as has happened in some Latin American dictatorships. Panamanians themselves are the first to admit they are unaccustomed to violent abuse and are easily cowed by it. `` I took part in demonstrations until they detained me,'' said a 27-year-old lawyer, who asked not to be named for fear of reprisals. She was released after a half hour, but not before being insulted, threatened and fondled by policemen. `` We are not <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. We do n't have violence in our blood,'' said <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON>, secretary-general of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Romero </PERSON> was detained, interrogated and beaten May 5 when he returned from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, where he had gone to take part in a conference. He was expelled to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> the next day and allowed to return on Monday. `` There is a triumph of terror,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in an interview. `` The regime is waging psychological war, and it's winning. The Defense Forces, which includes police and armed forces and is under <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s command, did not return repeated telephone calls Thursday asking for a response to these allegations. Only three people have been killed in political violence since the U.S.-backed opposition campaign to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> began 11 months ago. There are no `` disappeared,'' the enigmatic status that military regimes in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> conferred on tens of thousands of opponents in past decades. But there is a secret police, G-2, whose members have demonstrated ruthlessness. The corps is informed by street spies called `` toads'' whose pervasive infiltration of everyday life is taken for granted. `` We're not fighters, but a folkloric people; beach, sun and sea,'' said a young professional jailed and mistreated for a week last month. `` I myself am that way. It's in our genes.'' The man said he was suspected of opposition activity and taken from his home after midnight by several agents to G-2 headquarters. He was stripped and his wrists handcuffed behind his back. Asthmatic and frail, he was forced to stand under a cold shower for half an hour, punched in the face and abdomen and beaten on the legs with a rubber hose, he reported. Then he was beaten on the toes with a blackjack, a pain he describes as `` terrible.'' Still nude and handcuffed, as he was to remain for 15 hours, he was thrown into a cell where he was told he would be raped by an inmate. Panamanian rights activists say a sexual element to physical or psychological abuse of detainees is common. They report that arrested people are frequently threatened with rape or sodomy. The young man was not sexually abused, he said. But when he was taken from the cell several hours later, he was blindfolded, his mustache was burned with a lighter and the barrel of a revolver was placed at his temple. `` They told me the cemetery was just down the road,'' he said. `` My life is the university, work and my girlfried,'' said the man, who fears reprisal if his name appears in print. `` Those seven days were like a parenthesis, a long nightmare.'' `` The day after I got out, there was a -LRB- anti-government -RRB- march. I did not even think about going,'' he said. `` Our security forces are more clever than the Argentines -LRB- of the 1970s -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeden </PERSON>, a lawyer who in the past year has represented dozens of people arrested on political charges. `` Fear is stronger than cadavers. People get used to cadavers, but they do n't get used to fear.'' He said that since a failed coup attempt in March, the prevailing paranoia has spread to the Defense Forces. He said the 18 officers and soldiers under arrest in connection with the attempt have been subjected to treatment as least as humiliating as that given civilians. `` The officers know that if they cast a funny glance at <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> or one of his inner circle, they will be under surveillance themselves,'' said <PERSON> Weeden </PERSON>. `` There's even more fear inside the armed forces than outside,'' he said. Except for the coup plotters, political detainees are rarely held more than a few days or a week. Most are required to pay between $ 150 and $ 350 for their freedom, though payments of up to $ 10,000 have been reported. Opposition leaders and human rights activists call the payments `` ransoms.'' Weeden thinks the lull in protest and street demonstrations is passing, a valley to be followed by a surge. <PERSON> Romero </PERSON> said he came back to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> even though his wife pleaded with him by telephone not to. `` I'm showing my face and going ahead to help smash the terror,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Rust     05-27 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Rust,0639</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilot Who Shamed Soviet Defenses Serving Time At Famed Moscow
Prison</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mathias </PERSON> <PERSON> Rust </PERSON>, the West German aviator who a year ago slipped across one of the world's most secure borders and landed a plane at Red Square, remains jailed at Lefortovo Prison with hopes fading for an early release. The dramatic May 28, 1987, flight shook the foundation of Soviet security and oiled the way for the ouster of Defense Minister <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokolov </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Koldunov </PERSON>, but Soviet citizens still grin at the audacity of the young pilot and his success in putting one over on the mighty Kremlin. Soviet jets scrambled when Rust crossed into restricted airspace over the republic of <LOCATION> Estonia </LOCATION>, but the Soviet Air Defense forces took no action to halt the flight. Then, with apparently no warning to security forces in the nation's capital, the single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> swept toward the heart of Soviet power and buzzed <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> landmarks such as <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>'s tomb and Spassky Tower. Rust, now 20, was sentenced Sept. 4 to four years at a general-regime labor camp on charges of malicious mischief. By mutual consent with the Soviet government, he is serving his time at the infamous Lefortovo Prison in eastern <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, which in the past contained <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> journalist <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniloff </PERSON> and U2 pilot <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>. A source close to the case, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Rust asked to remain at Lefortovo rather than transfer to a less restrictive penal institution because the little-used <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> facility is more easily accessible to his parents and West German diplomats who are allowed to make regular visits. At Lefortovo, Rust has been allowed more visits than he is officially entitled to. His parents, <PERSON> Karl-Heinz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Monika </PERSON> <PERSON> Rust </PERSON>, and his 16-year-old brother <PERSON> Ingo </PERSON>, have visited Lefortovo at least five times since June. Under Soviet corrections regulations, prisoners are allowed one visit every three months. A representative of the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> is allowed to visit once each month to bring mail, books and special foods to augment the prison diet. Rust's appeal of his four-year sentence was turned down late last year. The young amateur pilot from suburban <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION> has issued a personal request for clemency that does not require a formal reply. To date, there has been no reply. Soviet officials have commented privately that Rust will likely serve at least half of his term, to show that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> does not take such stunts lightly and to discourage any similar incidents in the future. Rust was accused during his two-day trial of endangering the lives of thousands of airline passengers when he piloted his borrowed <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> 172-B from <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> through the flight paths of foreign airliners headed for <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s Sheremetyevo Airport. Witnesses testified that he could have injured some of the hundreds of pedestrians at Red Square on the cool, sunny evening when he landed. Rust told the court he felt `` remorse and deep repentance'' and never intended to endanger or insult anyone. Before landing in the square, Rust piloted his blue and white craft at a low altitude through more than 500 miles of closely guarded Soviet territory. The dramatic stunt was followed by a short-lived moment of glory for Rust as tourists and Muscovites crowded around the plane that came to a rest between St. Basil's Cathedral and the red-brick wall surrounding the Kremlin. They asked for the pilot's autograph and took his picture as he reclined against the fuselage before his arrest. Less than 48 hours later, the ruling Politburo met in special session and sent <PERSON> Sokolov </PERSON> into retirement and fired <PERSON> Koldunov </PERSON> for negligence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e PM-APArts:Walters     05-27 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Walters,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walters Art Gallery Reopens After $6 Million Overhaul</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BA2 of 5@21</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JANE E. ALLEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three years after the original 1904 Walters Art Gallery closed for a $ 6 million overhaul, <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>'s Renaissance palace museum has been restored to the glory that railroad magnate <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> envisioned for one of the greatest private art collections in the world. The renovation has created for <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>' precious jewels, bronzes, paintings and sculpture _ what gallery director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> calls a `` seamless museum environment'' that is easy on the eye and alluring even to those not trained in art history. `` In a lot of ways, we think the public is going to see the collection for the first time,'' <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> said recently, pointing proudly to carefully concealed display spotlights designed to lure viewers. `` We direct people directly to the object through the lighting.'' The massive stone building with a marble-columned court fashioned after the 17th-century <PERSON> Palazzo </PERSON> <PERSON> Balbi </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Genoa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, is one of six comprehensive museums in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> bequeathed it to the city upon his death in 1931, along with the 22,000-piece collection. The leaking roof, blackened marble, drab painted walls and poorly lighted rooms <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> inherited when he left an art history post at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and arrived here are gone. In their place stands a pristine and colorful complex of rooms featuring gleaming stone; rich, silk moire; red, blue and gold cotton damask; polished woods, glass, lucite and plaster. The works themselves were carefully conserved to bring out colors and features hidden for centuries. The renovated gallery holds some of the 30,000-object collection spanning 5,000 years of history. A 1974 addition that stayed open during the renovation holds many of the works, while thousands more lie in storage. <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>, who made his fortune with the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION>, left the collection _ along with a $ 3 million endowment _ to his native city `` for the benefit of the people.'' The works include such masterpieces as one of three surviving 14th-century Italian perspective paintings called `` View of an Ideal City,'' an early life-size Italian crucifix from the school of <PERSON> Cimabue </PERSON>, the first <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> to come to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and one of only 12 known paintings by <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Der </PERSON> <PERSON> Goes </PERSON>. Now, however, their future is assured by a climate and light-controlled environment that is so high-tech that special louvers regulate the amount of natural light let in by skylights, and storage spaces for metal works vent outside to prevent oxidation from destroying other valuable pieces. <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> jokingly calls the project a `` modest calling.'' `` We wanted to create the finest facility possible for this collection of Renaissance, Baroque and 18th-century paintings and sculpture and decorative arts,'' he said. `` To do that was a special project. The building is a work of art. We had to respect at every turn the character of this landmark structure,'' said the medievalist who moved from the rarified atmosphere of art history theory to a comfortable position as ceaseless champion of his world-class museum. <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> is satisfied with the effort, financed with $ 1 million in city funds, $ 1 million in state funds and another $ 4 million in contributions. In fact, he considers the workmanship he got for the money a bargain, pointing out how the wood in new doorways matches original woods and marble-painted sculpture bases mimic the marble columns for a consistent look. Going room to room, <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> marvels at the miraculously preserved royal jewel cabinet in wax and wood made for <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Antoinette </PERSON>; a collection of European porcelains considered second only to the British royal collection at <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION>; and some of the nearly 1,000 pieces of jewelry spanning the styles from ancient <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> to art nouveau. The installation includes a 19th-century alcove modeled on a French goldsmith's shop for <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>' delicate Faberge enamels, an iris corsage ornament created by <ORGANIZATION> Tiffany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and an ivory orchid comb by <PERSON> Lalique </PERSON>. The gallery went up between 1904 and 1909, and before <PERSON> Walters </PERSON>' death, he would open the doors a few times a month, charge admission and donate the proceeds to charity just as his father, who began the collection, had done More recently, the gallery has been drawing 150,000 to 200,000 visitors a year, including 1,500 museum members who celebrated the official opening on May 15. The first visitors to the reopened gallery included former employees as well as local visitors seasoned by a lifetime of trips. One after another, they stopped <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> to thank him for restoring the collection to splendor. `` Just hearing these people convinces me we did the right thing,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u v BC-HolidayTraffic     05-27 0009</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0009</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Midnight EDT: 0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SirenSong     05-27 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Siren Song,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Professor's Dream Girl Plans To Move To Illinois</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DECATUR, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 61-year-old college professor who fell in love with a Scottish bank teller's machine-recorded voice soon will get a chance to hear that voice live when the woman of his dreams moves to his hometown. `` It sort of means reducing a fairy tale come true to reality,'' <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferry </PERSON> said Thursday night. `` It could be losing some of its magic to see her grocery shopping.'' But actually, <PERSON> Ferry </PERSON> said, both he and his wife <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> are delighted that <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>, a British radio talk-show host, has accepted a job with a radio station in this central <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> city of about 94,000 residents. It's all because of a newspaper column Ferry wrote after he heard a teller-machine recording with her voice. `` I think I'm in love with a woman I've never seen,'' Ferry wrote in his Feb. 4 column for the <ORGANIZATION> Decatur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Review newspaper. `` My infatuation is with the talking teller at the Money Network station at <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> downtown,'' he said. Intrigued, the newspaper tracked down Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>, 30, now a talk-show host in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, and arranged for her to visit <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION> last month. She and Ferry met _ with <PERSON> Mrs </PERSON>. Ferry, his wife of 25 years, looking on. Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>, who is single, had made the teller-machine recording three years ago in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> NCR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, which makes automatic-teller products. `` I think he's smashing,'' she said, after meeting Ferry, an education professor at <ORGANIZATION> Millikin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. For his part, <PERSON> Ferry </PERSON> said that what began as a romantic fling in a newspaper column has become a friendship. `` I said I was in love with a voice _ and I was,'' Ferry said. `` But I'm in love with my wife. I would hope that <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> is a good friend. `` I do n't really expect her to stay in <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>. I think her voice is so impelling that she will get offers and offers.'' Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> earlier this week that she has accepted a broadcast job with WDZ radio and will arrive Sept. 5. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON>, vice president and general manager of WDZ, said he began talking with Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> about the job soon after she made a guest appearance during her April visit. He said Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> will have a midday show Monday through Friday, with the format still to be worked out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Panama-NoriegaQuotes     05-27 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Panama-Noriega Quotes,0674</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Speech Brims With Populism, Defiance and Nationalism</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Panama</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s speech to the National Assembly Thursday was a mixture of defiance, nationalism and a brand of patriotic populism that has characterized <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> military leadership for two decades. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictments on drug trafficking charges, had been expected to give a status report on negotiations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to end the hostile face-off between the two countries. But he dealt little with the talks, which appear to have collapsed, and concentrated instead on Panamanian sovereignty. The general suggested that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> politicians look to problems and ethical issues at home before trying to solve them in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> also accused American presidential candidates of `` using the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> flag to win votes.'' Here are some excepts from the speech and a question-and-answer period that followed: `` Pardon the ignorance but we can not understand how these rich candidates in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> do n't use the flag to solve the problems of the blacks in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, of the poorer classes, of the minorities, of those who have no heat, of the foreigners ... those are pretty themes for democracies.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` The theme of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is going to constitute a source of propaganda for candidates who wish to hide their own problems, for candidates who wish to bury files that weigh down on the backs of that democracy.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is a quiet, respectful country. Here no American has ever had a problem. He has not been kidnapped, he has not been assassinated in the street, his embassy has not been burned as it was burned in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, so they should respect <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` They invent great problems in small countries in order to crush them.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` The Panamanian people are paying a very high cost for the bad information and bad decisions of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. It has converted a traditionally friendly country such as this one into a country full of strong feelings and resentment.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` There was never a trick. There was never a lie. The lies came from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The trick never came from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> nor from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. We always spoke highly, clearly, concisely and directly. There can be no negotiations ... because there must be conversations ... respecting with dignity the sovereignty, respecting the right of self-determination of Panamanians, the suspension of economic aggression, the departure of troops beyond those called for in the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaties </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, and respect for the constitutional decision by the Panamanian parliament that <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> is the president of the republic.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` The Defense Forces support the perfection and the deepening of democracy. But what we have is a democracy for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. It is not a democracy for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. What democracy is for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with the institution of the <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION> can not be here. We can not have the democracy of the <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION> here. We are all dark-skinned.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` We have the dignity of uniforms gathered from different academies of <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and the world where each one of us studied, but -LRB- the military -RRB- is cooked and prepared here in the reality that has to do with the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people ... an armed forces where the oligarchy is not and will not be present.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 -LRB- When asked if he or the Chiefs of Staff were deciding whether <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> would step down: -RRB- `` A commander does n't abandon his ship in stormy weather.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 -LRB- When asked who might want to accept American military bases if the bases were forced out of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>: -RRB- `` I do not know if other countries would accept them. I know that as a Latin American I would not recommend that they have -LRB- the bases -RRB- in their countries.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>---</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is the last Maginot Line of dignity.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Marcos 1stLd-Writethru a0409 05-27 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0409,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Leaves Hospital, Asks To Return to Philippines</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 6th graf: `Marcos said ..., to UPDATE
with comment from INS commissioner Ezell; picks up 7th graf:
`Marcos is ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTINE DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Philippine President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> ended two-day's hospital treatment for chest pains Thursday, saying he will ask <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials to let him return to his homeland for the funeral of his mother. `` I'd like to go home and preside over the funeral rites of my mother,'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said from a wheelchair during a news conference before he was discharged from <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said his application for permission for him and his family go to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and return to the <LOCATION> Unites </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at will would be submitted Thursday or Friday at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Immigration and Naturalization office in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>. When asked whether the application would be a request to return permanently to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> replied, `` Well, what else? I would like the ordinary rights of a citizen.'' Philippine President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, saying <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> poses a threat to national security, has repeatedly rejected his pleas to return for the funeral of his mother, <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON> <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON>, who died May 4 at age 95. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> should reconsider because, `` I've told them I will not bother them ... but will hold back the people from starting violence. She alone will not be able to hold them back.'' <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> Western Region Commissioner <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Ezell </PERSON> said he favored allowing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return, but said the final decision rests with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. `` We believe there is a humanitarian aspect that has to be considered,'' <PERSON> Ezell </PERSON> said. `` Whether or not you agree with everything that's happened, there is still a factor that <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is a human being who had a mother who has passed away.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is under `` a prevent departure notice,'' which means he needs permission to leave the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> district director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> said he did not know how long it would take for the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> government to respond to his latest request. He said no date has been set for the funeral. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, several aides, a nurse and his physician, Dr. <PERSON> Azucena </PERSON> <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON>, who said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> would be able to travel. <PERSON> Ignacio </PERSON> said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' chest pains were caused by arthritis or inflammation in the area of the left sixth rib. She said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> improved dramatically by resting and was being treated with painkillers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MoscowPoll     05-27 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Moscow Poll,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Finds Soviet Union Residents Unsure Of Effects Of Economic
Changes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Muscovites give <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> strong support for his overall program of change in their country, but only about half say they have seen tangible benefits of his program of economic change, a poll has found. Only 40 percent of participants in a poll conducted for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> said they expected their families' standard of living to improve in the next five years, according to the poll published in Friday's Times. And 18 percent of 939 adults in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> households with telephones predicted their standard of living would worsen, the poll said. An estimated 84 percent of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> households have phones. The margin of error for the poll was plus or minus 4 percentage points. The poll found strong support for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s overall program, with 78 percent supporting his domestic policies completely and 19 percent less than completely. The Times said they especially liked his calls for greater democracy and openness. The newspaper said one of the poll's most striking findings was that a sizable minority seemed prepared to question the monopoly of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. While 51 percent agreed that the one-party system in their country promotes development of democracy, 28 percent said they disagreed, the poll found. It also said many wanted the liberalization that had begun to be expanded to include competitive elections, private publishing and tolerance of public demonstrations. The interviews in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> were conducted by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sociological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> on May 7, 8, 14 and 15.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Reapportionment     05-27 0567</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reapportionment,0582</SECOND>
<HEAD>Feds Threaten Discrimination Suit Over LA County Supervisors'
Districts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal officials plan to sue <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> for violating the voting rights of racial minorities by diluting their influence when county supervisors redrew district boundaries in 1981, a source said Thursday. Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> informed the county by letter last week that he authorized the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to sue the county for allegedly discriminating against minorities in the 1981 reapportionment, said the source, who is familiar with the case but asked not to be identified. The Board of Supervisors must remap its five districts every decade and to divide the population evenly among them. But the 1981 plan allegedly diluted the influence of Hispanics and other minorities, the source added. County Counsel <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> was called for comment Thursday, but did n't immediately return the call. There has not been a Hispanic supervisor in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s 138-year history The county's only black supervisor, <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Brathwaite </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>, was appointed to the board in the 1970s and subsequently lost a bid for election. According to the 1980 federal census, there were more than 2 million Hispanics and 943,000 blacks among the county's 7.5 million residents. By 1985 there were 2.4 million Hispanics and 964,000 blacks, according to projections by the county <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Burstion-Wade </PERSON> confirmed <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights division, sent a letter to the county last week, but said she could n't comment on its contents In voting rights cases, such letters are sent to allow the target of a potential lawsuit to negotiate with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and `` avoid the cost and time of litigation, which does n't help anybody,'' she said by phone from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` However, if statutory violations can not be resolved, then certainly litigation is a real possibility.'' Asked what kind of relief the government seeks in such cases, Ms. <PERSON> Burstion-Wade </PERSON> replied: `` The relief would be to protect minorities from disenfranchisement.'' <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicano </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said he understood the federal complaint against the county would involve alleged discrimination against Hispanics. `` We have always felt that the Latino community has been without power in that they have been fragmented, and they have not been able to exercise their voting ability,'' <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> said. `` We are aware that county counsel has received a letter from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Deane </PERSON> <PERSON> Dana </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement. `` He is reviewing it and will be advising the board. Until that process is complete, we will not have any comment beyond that.'' <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>'s letter first was revealed publicly in Thursday editions of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, which cited anonymous sources. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> filed a similar lawsuit in 1985 that forced the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to shift a district from the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to the city's largely Hispanic east side. The suit led to the election to the City Council of former Assemblywoman <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Molina </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> based its 1985 complaint on the 1965 Voting Rights Act, which prohibits redistricting that causes minority residents to have `` less opportunity than other members -LRB- of the community -RRB- to participate in the political process and to elect representatives of their choice.'' The lawsuit claimed that the city's 1982 plan splintered the political influence of Hispanics by spreading them thinly over many districts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0456EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--NavyCrash     05-27 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Navy Crash,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Instructors Safely Eject From Navy Jet That Crashed in Woods</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GROVE HILL, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two flight instructors escaped serious injury when they ejected and parachuted from a TA4J <ORGANIZATION> Skyhawk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> training jet that crashed and burned Thursday in a forest, authorities said. Marine Capt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Renken </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Roorda </PERSON> were picked up by a search helicopter and returned safely to base, said Lt. j.g. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamberlin </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Meridian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roorda </PERSON> was being examined for a possible broken leg. <PERSON> Chamberlin </PERSON> said the jet, based at <LOCATION> Meridian </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, was on a routine training mission and crashed 11:45 a.m. Thursday in the Scotch Wildlife Management area in <LOCATION> southwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, 13 miles west of <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. The crash sparked a wildfire near <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> Highway 154 that was fought by state forestry fire crews. Law-enforcement agencies closed off the area pending an investigation of the crash by military and federal authorities. There were no other injuries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget Bjt   05-27 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Passes $1.1 Trillion Budget For 1989</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is moving with unusual speed toward final approval of a $ 1.1 trillion federal budget for the 1989 fiscal year, thanks to a little bipartisan cooperation and a lot of creative arithmetic. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved the spending plan by a 201-181 vote on Thursday shortly after <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators reached agreement on a compromise document after six weeks of haggling. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to give quick approval to the measure after the chamber returns early next month from its Memorial Day recess. The budget meets the spending ceilings for domestic, defense and international affairs programs set at last fall's budget summit by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and congressional leaders. It also obeys the Gramm-Rudman balanced budget law's $ 146 billion deficit target for fiscal 1989, which begins Oct. 1. If the red ink grows beyond that level, the law calls for automatic spending cuts to reduce the deficit to $ 136 billion. `` This, I believe, is a balanced approach,'' said <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, D-Pa. The numbers used in the document were shoehorned into the budget summit and Gramm-Rudman limits by lawmakers intent on avoiding fights over spending and taxes in an election year. The legislators used relatively rosy economic assumptions produced by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, rather than more pessimistic projections calculated by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. As the economy worsens, government spending grows and its revenue shrinks, producing more red ink. In addition, when their numbers threatened to spill over the budget summit's constraints, the lawmakers fiddled slightly with the definitions of the spending categories they used, allowing them to claim they had abided by their pact with the White House. Even with that craftiness, the budget might still surpass the $ 146 billion limit set by Gramm-Rudman. The law requires a fresh look at the spending plan's projected deficit in August, using updated readings of the economy's performance Rep. <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>, had told him Thursday that `` it would be a miracle'' if the automatic spending cuts are avoided. Despite that warning, 26 Republicans joined 175 Democrats in voting for the measure. Final congressional approval early next month would be unusually quick. The legislators, however, already have upheld their annual tradition of missing the April 15 deadline set in law for completing the budget. The measure contains $ 299.5 billion in new defense spending, $ 18.1 billion for international affairs and $ 148 billion for domestic programs for 1989. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 8.1 billion increase over spending this year is below the amount needed to keep pace with inflation. Education, health, social services and job training programs would all be given enough money to match inflation increases. Some other programs _ including AIDS research and treatment, anti-drug initiatives, space and air traffic control _ would be boosted enough to surpass the costs of inflation. The election-year measure would allow an additional $ 1.4 billion in anti-drug spending later this year if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> decide that an emergency exists. The extra money would have to be covered by spending reductions in other areas or by new revenues. In legislation passed in December, $ 14 billion in new taxes for fiscal 1989 already have been written into law. The budget approved Thursday includes no other additional revenues. The two chambers had differences of about $ 1 billion _ small ones in budget terms _ over how much money should be spent for science, space and education. In their compromise, the lawmakers agreed to $ 13 billion for space and science and $ 37.2 billion for education. They also agreed to a 4 percent pay raise for military personnel and federal civilian employees to take effect in January. The raise would apply to members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, who already earn $ 89,500 annually. If included in forthcoming appropriations bills, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would earn $ 93,080 a year, a raise of $ 3,580. The budget does not require the president's signature, and is used as a guideline by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as it passes the 13 appropriations bills that actually provide money for federal spending. But this year, its value seems even more questionable than usual because the two chambers have already begun work on their spending measures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ChemicalWeapons Bjt   05-27 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chemical Weapons, Bjt,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Express Optimism That Global Ban May Soon Be Near</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTON, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet experts accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of undermining progress on a global chemical weapons ban, but still expressed optimism that 20 years of talks would soon culminate in an agreement. Leaders of the 13-member Soviet delegation told a news conference that the talks sorely need a political initiative from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and British leaders. However, just days before <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> get together in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for their fourth summit, the Soviet chemical weapons experts took a tough line against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> resumption of chemical weapons production. `` Such steps undoubtedly run counter to the aims of a chemical warfare convention,'' said <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON>, chief Soviet negotiator at the 40-nation <ORGANIZATION> Geneva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Disarmament, where the chemical weapons ban talks have been taking place. The news conference Thursday ended the Soviets' three-day visit here, the first time they have been at a chemical warfare facility in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuntsevich </PERSON>, deputy commander of the Soviets' chemical troops, said current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production of binary weapons _ in which elements that are harmless on their own become lethal when combined _ is dangerous, `` uncontrollable and unverifiable. He said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to end an 18-year moratorium on chemical weapons production last December raised Soviet suspicions that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> plans to supply binary weapons to its <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies. Still, <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON> appeared more optimistic than his British counterpart at the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> talks, Ambassador <PERSON> Tessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Solesby </PERSON>, that a verifiable agreement on the development, production and stockpiling of chemical weapons can be reached soon. `` The international negotiations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> have actually entered the decisive stage of development ... We firmly believe that this convention will be achievable soon,'' <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON> said. `` In order to overcome the differences that still remain,'' he said, `` what we need is impetuses to solve the problems at a political level, not a technical level.'' But <PERSON> Solesby </PERSON> said getting <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> to give the negotiations a political push will not solve the main problem of verification. `` It is not a matter of lack of political will. ... It's the technical difficulties that remain,'' she said. The Soviets and their British hosts stressed the historic significance of the three-day visit to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Porton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Down </LOCATION> in southwest <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. But they disagreed on the size of the Soviet stockpile and the wisdom of setting a timetable for reaching a final agreement. <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON> said `` the successful outcome of negotiations depends on a time limit to settle and tackle all the unresolved problems.'' <PERSON> Solesby </PERSON> said: `` We do not feel artificial time limits are helpful.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said last year that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has a 50,000-ton stockpile. Western estimates have put it at 300,000 tons. <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON> insisted the Soviets had not lied about the size of their stockpile and said inspectors may see it as soon as an agreement is signed. He accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of inflating their estimates to justify the start of binary weapons production. He said the Soviet stockpile was now at parity with the American stockpile, which he also estimated at 50,000 tons. But <PERSON> Nazarkin </PERSON> expressed concern that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> binary weapons production could change the balance. The Americans have not disclosed the size of their stockpile but Western estimates put it at 30,000 tons. <PERSON> Solesby </PERSON> said <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> started producing binary weapons to counter Soviet production and replace its own aging stockpiles. During their visit to the 7,000-acre Porton Down facility, the Soviets held wide-ranging talks with British experts and watched <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> soldiers respond to a simulated enemy nerve gas attack. In July, a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> delegation will visit the chemical warfare facility at <LOCATION> Shikhany </LOCATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. Last October, specialists from the <ORGANIZATION> Geneva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> visited <LOCATION> Shikhany </LOCATION>, where they were shown chemical weapons which seemed to date from the 1950s. The following month, Soviet inspectors visited a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> chemical weapons disposal plant at <LOCATION> Toole </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, where they were shown techniques for destroying old gas munitions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PlantClosings Bjt   05-27 0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Plant Closings, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Data Shows Most Laid-Off Workers Did Not Have New Jobs Lined Up</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than three-fourths of the workers who lost their jobs to plant closings or mass layoffs last year did not have new jobs lined up when they went off their companies' payrolls, according to new government data Of the 406,887 victims of plant closings or large layoffs in 29 states in 1987, 78 percent, or 319,343, filed claims for unemployment insurance benefits, the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. The government tracked those people through state employment offices and found that 85,548, or more than one-fourth of them, exhausted their unemployment benefits _ an average $ 139 a week with a 26-week maximum in most states _ before finding new work. The report was hailed by advocates of the 60-day advance notice requirement that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> cited as a major reason why he vetoed the 1,000-page trade bill on Tuesday. `` With that kind of advance notice, many of these people would have had an opportunity to seek new jobs while currently employed and would likely not have had to draw unemployment insurance,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zaluskey </PERSON>, an economist for the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. The advance notice provision was approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> after surveys by the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> showed that two of every three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers caught up in such layoffs get no warning. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> said in a report last year that the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's reliance on `` voluntary'' notices is `` not providing workers with the ... ` best practice' minimum of two or three months to adjust successfully to job loss.'' The academy estimated that advance layoff notices would reduce by 25 percent the time a laid-off employee is out of work, saving hundreds of millions of dollars in unemployment benefits. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, however, said when he vetoed the trade bill that the layoff notice requirements would `` cost jobs and damage our economic growth.'' Business groups supportive of the bill in general had urged <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to veto the measure because of the layoff provision, which <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lesher </PERSON> called `` the camel's nose under the tent'' in a broad union agenda for more government control in the work place. The House on Tuesday immediately overrode <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, with Democrats rejoicing that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had given them an issue for rallying voters in the November election. Democratic presidential front-runner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` do n't understand that for working families ... there is nothing more painful than losing a job.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which passed the trade bill on a 63-36 vote that was short of what would be needed to override <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto, was expected to take up the measure again early next month. The report Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> was the first comprehensive examination of the mass layoff phenomenon ever released by the government. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 ordered government statisticians to start conducting the survey after the nation's unemployment rate soared to 11.4 percent and the rolls of the unemployed grew to 12.5 million during the first two years of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s administration. Since then, the jobless rate has dropped to 5.4 percent _ the lowest since 1974 _ with fewer than 7 million people now out of work in the longest peacetime economic expansion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. Of the 29 states surveyed in 1987, two _ <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> _ accounted for one-fourth of the total layoffs. Five other states _ <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> _ accounted for another fourth. The 29 states were <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. `` Slack'' or `` seasonal'' work was listed by employers in the survey as accounting for about half of the layoffs. The other biggest reasons cited for them by employers were completion of contracts, 7 percent; business ownership changes, 4 percent; and import competition, 2 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0115EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Japan-Circus Bjt   05-27 0489</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Circus, Bjt,0503</SECOND>
<HEAD>`The Greatest Show On Earth' Heads For Japan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARI TAKETA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the first time in its uniquely American history, <ORGANIZATION> Ringling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Barnum </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> <PERSON> Circus </PERSON> is staging a colossal three-ring assault on the land of sushi and sumo wrestling. `` We are coming to entertain you!'' boomed <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Holst </PERSON>, the show's associate producer and former ringmaster, at a <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> news conference Thursday Flanked by five clowns, two jungling acrobats and a hula-hoop artist, he smiled and intoned, `` It is our hope and our interest that you will smile and laugh, and hide your eyes in fear.'' For 15 weeks starting in July, Japanese kids of all ages will be dazzled by daring trapeze acts, animal tamers, 25 clowns, 16 elephants, 14 lions, and assorted camels, llamas, dogs and chimpanzees under a big top. Coordinating trans-Pacific transportation for beasts, about 300 humans and 100 tractor-trailer loads of lighting and sound equipment and supplies in the circus' first overseas trip are enough to astound. <PERSON> Holst </PERSON> estimates Ringling Bros. spent at least $ 10 million for the production. The big top goes up this summer in <LOCATION> Sapporo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION>. Organizers hope to attract as many as 1.2 million Japanese and already are planning a 25-week run in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> next year. `` We are not interested in the short-term profit,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>, Ringling marketing supervisor. `` We want to build a tradition. The Japanese public may have seen a circus before, but they've never the ` Greatest Show on Earth.''' Japanese got a sneak preview this week when <PERSON> Ringling </PERSON>'s promotional team unleased the clowns, jugglers, and hula-hoopist in full costume on the streets and television airwaves of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> `` Humor is universal,'' said blue-haired <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudert </PERSON>, whose nose was painted red. `` At first people are kind of surprised. But they really like slapstick.'' The ringmaster will continue to herald the acts in English, hoping Japanese audiences will pay close attention to his arm as he points to the various rings. Acts among the 130-member troop will include the Human Cannonball and the Globe of Death, in which two men on motorcycles race simultaneously inside a large chain-link ball, sometimes with their wives standing in the middle. `` We do n't know if what we're bringing will offend people,'' Gold acknowledged. `` Like today, -LRB- the Japanese sponsor -RRB- wanted to take the clowns around to some newspapers. I said, why do n't you take four, and I'll take one with me. `` He said no _ in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, four is an unlucky number. It means death,'' <PERSON> Gold </PERSON> said. He shrugged and raised his eyebrows. `` I did n't know that. Ticket prices will run $ 40 a head _ about the cost of a ticket to a rock concert here _ compared with a maximum of $ 12 in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We cost maybe twice the price of a movie,'' Gold said. `` But where else can you see 250 people and animals risking their lives?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Politics Bjt   05-27 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Politics, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan, Gorbachev May See Few Political Gains
From Summit</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Conventional wisdom says President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will benefit politically by the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit. But conventional wisdom is n't infallible. Consider the following: <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is enormously popular at home, but, as he prepares to leave office, little of that support appears to be transferring to Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> faces problems at home, but most stem from his stumbling efforts to reform Soviet society. His rivals on the ruling Politburo appear to agree on the need to improve relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, reduce international tension and fix the Soviet economy. It is the nature, speed and consequences of the fix that divide them, say the experts. Open elections and reliable public opinion polls are still a thing of the future in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and instead Western analysts will be watching a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conference at the end of June to determine how much confidence <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> inspires in his countrymen. Numbers, if not answers, are easier to come by in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Opinion polls show Americans overwhelmingly back arms control agreements, if they are negotiated carefully. A survey this month in the bipartisan Americans Talk Security series said 77 percent of those polled backed the treaty to eliminate medium-range missiles. The treaty, signed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at their <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> meeting last December, now appears headed for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratification in time for the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit. The survey said 82 percent backed a Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty to cut superpower strategic arsenals by half. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> both say a START deal is possible by the end of the year, but they remain divided over <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plans for a missile defense system, verification issues, and limits on heavy land-based missiles and air - and submarine-launched cruise missiles <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s success in bargaining with the Soviets to date may improve his treatment in history books, but it does not seem to help <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who according to a <ORGANIZATION> CBS-New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> poll last week was trailing the probable <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The poll gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 49 percent to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 39 percent. An <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll this week gave <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> 53 percent and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> 40 percent. One prominent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supporter, Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, said that `` the vice president is going to be running on a very powerful peace and prosperity platform. But the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people have found that so successful that they are looking at other issues. The very success of the Republicans has bred a public nonchalance to the big issues of our time.'' Critics of the Republican administration attribute progress in arms control to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> rather than to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who entered office declaring that the Soviets had broken every treaty they had signed with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` One of the calling cards of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is that these people have brought the Soviets into line by setting out tough policies and sticking to them,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendelsohn </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> group. `` But that's not what happened,'' said <PERSON> Mendelsohn </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, he said, changed because he decided it was in the best Soviet interests. Opinion polls indicate broad support for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s approach. The Americans Talk Security survey showed that 68 percent of those polled favored caution in dealing with the Soviets, compared with 28 percent who advocated seizing the opportunity presented by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may be losing his fight to stack the June party conference in his favor, said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Laqueur </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustafson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Of the 5,000 delegates to the conference, said <PERSON> Laqueur </PERSON>, 3,500 will be made up of government and party officials thought to oppose <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform efforts, and most of the rest are being selected to regional party organizations, many of them also hostile to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` The outlook is for a conservative membership,'' said <PERSON> Gustafson </PERSON>. And that could stymie <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s perceived drive to win a comfortable majority on the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the policy-making body which until now has put the brakes on his more radical ideas.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brumley </PERSON>, a Washington-based national security reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been covering U.S.-Soviet affairs since 1981, when he was a correspondent in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Crash-SEC Bjt   05-27 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash-SEC, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>SEC Seeks Jurisdiction Over Chicago Futures Markets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is declaring its independence from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration by pushing its own proposals in the regulatory turf war that has followed the October stock market crash. A sharply divided commission voted 3-2 to ask <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for jurisdiction over the stock index futures markets in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, an area now regulated by a sister agency, the <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Futures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. Members voting for the proposal noted that the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> already regulates the trading of stocks and stock options and said that it was only logical that the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> also oversee trading of futures contracts based on stocks. The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> has already lost on the issue in an interagency working group formed to develop administration policy on market reform. The panel, whose members represented the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION>, issued a report last week calling for no major legislative initiatives. Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> reacted with dismay to the working group's recommendations, which all but preclude the chances of a market bill this year Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, called them `` pitiful. However, the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>'s move to stake out an independent position pleased Democrats looking for a means to rekindle sentiment for change. `` The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> today distinguished itself from the do-nothing strategists of the rest of this administration,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee with jurisdiction over the stock markets `` The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> has demonstrated intelligence, courage and common sense,'' he said in a statement. Aides to <PERSON> Markey </PERSON> are drafting a bill that would transfer jurisdiction of equity-related futures from the commodity commission to the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>. However, two members of the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> do not want that authority. Commission member <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleischman </PERSON> argued that each commission was best qualified to oversee the separate markets. `` We come from different backgrounds. ... We wear different spectacles,'' he said. Commission member <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grundfest </PERSON> said he agreed with the goal of more consistent regulation, but said that seeking to take over part of the commodity commission's jurisdiction would only cause rancor and provoke a `` firestorm'' in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, where separate committees oversee the two agencies. `` I think we could have and should have proceeded on the path of cooperation. That could have gotten us a lot of what we wanted to achieve. ... We have instead embarked on a path I would describe as regulatory imperialism,'' he said. However, commission Chairman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> said that <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> control of stock and stock futures regulation flows logically from the recommendations of an earlier presidential task force, composed of members of the financial community. The so-called <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> task force, headed by investment banker <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, said the futures and stock markets are economically one. `` I think it's time we move to what I think is a rational way of regulating that interlinked market,'' <PERSON> Ruder </PERSON> said. He was supported by Commissioners <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> and <PERSON> Aulana </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> voted unanimously to offer four other recommendations to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and decided to withhold one for futher discussion. In one, the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> said it should have emergency power to call trading halts, delay the opening of markets or close them early. The commission would have to seek permission from the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to continue a trading halt beyond 24 hours, and the president would have the power to overturn any emergency action by the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION>. If enacted, the emergency authority would reverse the current arrangement, which requires the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> to seek presidential permission before calling a trading halt. The commission also asked for authority to require the reporting of securities trades of larger than $ 5 million. That is intended to make it easier for the agency to track index arbitrage, a form of computer trading involving the simultaneous sale of large groups of stocks and futures contracts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0433EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Budget-Glance     05-27 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Budget-Glance,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Budget Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are highlights from the federal budget for the 1989 fiscal year that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved Thursday by a 201-181 vote: _ Overall spending: The government would get $ 1.232 trillion in budget authority, which is the right to commit itself to that amount of new spending programs Of that, $ 1.099 trillion is for outlays, the amount of money the government actually would spend next year. _ Revenues: $ 964 billion, including $ 14 billion in new taxes that were enacted last December _ Deficit: The budget would create $ 135 billion in red ink Under the Gramm-Rudman balanced budget law, the maximum deficit allowable for fiscal 1989 is $ 146 billion. Anything over that would trigger automatic spending cuts in defense and many domstic programs. _ Interest payments on the national debt: The government will spend $ 152 billion this year paying interest on the $ 2.5 trillion it currently owes _ Defense: $ 299.5 billion _ International affairs: $ 18.1 billion _ Science and space: $ 13 billion _ Environment: $ 15.8 billion _ Agriculture: $ 25.5 billion _ Transportation: $ 28.6 billion _ Education and job programs: $ 37.2 billion _ Health: $ 49.8 billion _ Medicare: $ 103.7 billion _ Social Security: $ 278.1 billion _ Veterans: $ 28.8 billion _ Justice: $ 8.9 billion
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseBudgetRollCall 3Takes   05-27 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Budget Roll Call, 3 Takes,</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 201-181 roll call Thursday by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 1.1 trillion fiscal 1989 federal budget. A `` yes'' vote is a vote for the budget. Voting yes were 175 Democrats and 26 Republicans. Voting no were 47 Democrats and 134 Republicans. Y is a yes vote. N is a no vote. X denotes those not voting. Present denotes those who voted they were `` present'' at the time of the vote but id not vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on the issue. There are three vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, N; Stump, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Anderson, Y; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, N; Stark, Y; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Badham </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Konnyu </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, N; Packard, Y; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, Y, <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Gejdenson, Y; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, N; MacKay, X; <PERSON> Mica </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, Y; Pepper, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, X; Shaw, N; Young, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lipinski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, Y; Savage, Y; <PERSON> Yates </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Crane </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Fawell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hastert </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Visclosky </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, N; Coats, N; <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Nagle </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseBudgetRollCall 2ndadd   05-27 0388</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House Budget Roll Call, 2nd add,</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: In Rhode Island section, St Germain, no period, is CQ</NOTE>
<HEAD>WASHN: Dorgan, N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>OHIO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, Y; Hall, Y; <PERSON> Kaptur </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, Y; Oakar, X; <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> DeWine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gradison </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> McEwen </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Oxley </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Regula </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OKLAHOMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ English, N; <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Inhofe </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OREGON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ AuCoin, Y; <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Borski, Y; <PERSON> Coyne </PERSON>, Y; Foglietta, Y; <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Kanjorski </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Kolter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Walgren </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Yatron </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gekas </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Goodling </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shuster </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>RHODE ISLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <ORGANIZATION> St </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germain </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> X. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Derrick </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ravenel </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Spence </LOCATION>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TENNESSEE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lloyd </LOCATION>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Sundquist </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TEXAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Andrews, Y; <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, X; de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, Y; Hall, N; <PERSON> Leath </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, Y; Pickle, Y; <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, X -LRB- by tradition, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker seldom votes -RRB-. Republicans _ <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>, N; DeLay, N; Fields, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Sweeney </LOCATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>UTAH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Y. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republicans </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Nielson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VERMONT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sisisky </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bliley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, N; Slaughter, N; <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonker </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Chandler </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WEST VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Mollohan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON>, Y; Staggers, Y; Wise, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WISCONSIN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kleczka </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION>, Y; Obey, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Petri </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WYOMING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>End House Budget Roll Call _ 3 Takes</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880527-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Summit-Monitoring     05-27 0894</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Monitoring,880</SECOND>
