<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFires 1stLd-Writethru a0816 08-12 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0816,0653</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Road Reopened, Storm Sparks Idaho Fires</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with rain in Yellowstone, fires
in Montana and pilot killed in California; picking up 4th graf pvs
`Park officials.' SUBS 11th graf pvs `In Idaho' with 2 grafs to
include Montana fire and details of Idaho fire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>YELLOWSTONE NATIONAL PARK, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yellowstone National Park got its first significant rainfall since Memorial Day on Friday, and the rain and cooler temperatures aided firefighters battling a 40,000-acre fire. In <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the pilot of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> plane was killed Friday when his plane crashed while surveying a fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Sequoia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> about 35 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, authorities said. Fires also burned in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Yellowstone received about two hours of intermittent rainfall Friday. `` One short rain shower is not adequate to douse the fires. But it does help increase humidity in the air and it helps slow the fires down,'' said park spokeswoman <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON>. She said the temperature in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> cooled down Friday afternoon, the wind slowed and firefighters made some progress in their efforts to contain fires burning on nearly 200,000 acres of the park. Park officials on Friday morning reopened a road between <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> and Old Faithful that had been closed Thursday because of the fire and smoke. The fire, pushed east by winds whipping at up to 40 mph Thursday, had crossed the road in several spots near <LOCATION> Nez </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Perce </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> as it grew by about 3,000 acres during the day. The fire's north edge was about 1 -LCB- miles south of the <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> campground, which remained open, and wind was pushing the flames to the east into backcountry, <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON> said. The 20,260-acre Fan fire in the park's northwestern corner remained inside containment lines and burning had slowed on the Shoshone and Red fires, which had charred about 34,000 acres. Despite the fires, tourism in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION> remains high, <PERSON> Anzelmo </PERSON> said. `` We are continuing to see a very busy park with campgrounds and hotels full each night,'' she said. `` But the last two days, there have been fairly smoky conditions in the park and the vicinity, so that has been difficult for everyone.'' In <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, cool, cloudy weather slowed a 2,800-acre fire burning in the <LOCATION> Elkhorn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> southeast of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON> Friday. Fire crews continued the slow work of building fire lines by hand in steep terrain, forest officials said. The cool weather also helped 125 firefighters battling an 8,000-acre grass and range fire southeast of <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, fire crews carved a break line between the raging 4,000 <LOCATION> Walker </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire and the southeastern town of <LOCATION> Inkom </LOCATION> on Friday. Residents from 16 rural homes were evacuated Thursday when flames whipped by 60 mph gusts swept over thousands of acres of sage, grass and groves of trees. The families stayed away from their homes Friday, and residents of 32 other homes were warned they might have to leave their homes. No structures were lost and no injuries were reported. Hundreds of firefighters were strung out across the southern part of the state against the worst of more than 75 fires started by lightning Thursday. `` We're snowed under here just trying to get people on fires,'' <ORGANIZATION> Challis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> said. `` We're going to be really thin on resources.'' In the <ORGANIZATION> Nez </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Perce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>, where Thursday's storm sparked 20 new fires, some 180 firefighters tried to regain containment of the 1,000-acre Ruby Rapids fire after wind-driven flames broke through the containment line. Fire bosses hoped to recontain the fire by day's end and control it Saturday. Crews finally controlled the stubborn 1,500-acre Spring Canyon II fire in the <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> near the <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> border Thursday night, and fire bosses were hoping to begin demobilization this weekend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Fast-FoodBirth     08-12 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fast-Food Birth,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Gives Birth In Fast-Food Restaurant</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREEN BAY, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A vacationing couple stopped at a fast-food restaurant and left with a 5-pound, 4-ounce baby girl instead of the burger and fries they planned to purchase. <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Megan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, daughter of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Karla </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, was born Aug. 3 in a <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> restaurant in Magog, <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION>, about 35 miles from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> border. The child, the <ORGANIZATION> Nelsons </ORGANIZATION>' third, was n't due until Sept. 1, <PERSON> Karla </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` It was the weirdest vacation I ever had in my life,'' her husband said. The couple was driving with their son <PERSON> Adam </PERSON>, 1, to the wedding of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>'s brother in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> when Mrs. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said she had a backache and asked her husband to stop at a restroom. They saw a McDonald's sign and decided to stop for a bite to eat at the same time. Mrs. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 33, who said she experienced no other signs of labor, gave birth in the restroom and called for her husband. But he had taken <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> back to the car to wait for her. Mrs. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said she was trying to wash the baby in the restroom sink when a young girl entered and then went for help. Meanwhile, after several minutes of waiting in the car, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 29, said he figured something was wrong and he and <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> returned to the restaurant. `` I saw a bunch of people by the bathroom ... and my wife holding a baby,'' he said. `` It was just a shock to me.'' A rescue squad took Mrs. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and the baby to a hospital. As word of the unusual birth spread, the story was relayed in French on <LOCATION> Quebec </LOCATION> television and radio and in local newspapers, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. The couple discovered through a television report translated for them that the owner-operator of the restaurant, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, was going to pay for their hospital and ambulance costs, which totaled almost $ 1,700, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> also paid for some baby clothes, diapers and an infant car seat, according to <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Caron </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s restaurants. That was good news for the couple because they have no health insurance. `` We would have paid so much a month like we do all our other bills,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> is a cook at the Downtowner in <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, and his wife is a hostess at a <PERSON> Marc </PERSON>'s Big Boy, where she returned to work Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ShortestRiver     08-12 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shortest River,0527</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oregon Town Refuses to Concede Shortest River Title to Montana</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN CITY, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thanks to the meddling of a group of sharp-eyed <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> fifth graders, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s `` D River'' has lost its 30-year title as the world's shortest river, but not without a fight from miffed local officials. Editors of the <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> agreed to give the title to the <LOCATION> Roe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, after students there spent the past school year researching the river, which flows through a state park. The students concluded the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> is 201 feet, far shorter than the 440-foot D <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and submitted their evidence to the Guinness editors. `` On the basis of that, the <LOCATION> Roe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> was shorter,'' assistant editor <PERSON> Cyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said from the publisher's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office. News of the change was not well-received in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, however, where the D River has held the title of shortest named river for 30 years. `` Where a river begins and ends may be in the eye of the beholder,'' Mayor <PERSON> Dell </PERSON> <PERSON> Isham </PERSON> said Wednesday. In fact, <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> now insists the D is only 120 feet long, give or take 5 feet. City officials are preparing documentation to convince Guinness editors that they were right the first time and that the D River should regain its rightful title in the book's 1990 edition The deadline is past for next year's edition. Of course, the question being asked in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> is: How can a river shrink from 440 feet to 120 feet? At first it was funny, but fewer people are laughing now that it's clear <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is serious. `` It's fun to a point, but it has no end when people can come back and keep shortening it until it's kind of ridiculous,'' said <PERSON> Susie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nardinger </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> teacher who led her class in the river study. The <LOCATION> Roe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>'s acceptance into the records book is a matter of pride to the community's 60,000 residents, she said. `` Our students went about it perfectly innocently,'' she said. `` The victory has been marred because <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> came out with its claims and, in a sense, stole the limelight at the peak of their success.'' Signs soon will grace the banks of the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> to proclaim its world-class status. About 625 miles away in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, similar signs remain along the <LOCATION> D </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and there are no plans to remove them. <PERSON> Isham </PERSON> says the dispute is simply a matter of setting the record straight. <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> insists previous estimates of the river's length inaccurately measured from a point in the river that actually is part of Devil's <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> That point looked like part of the river because a landfill had closed in the banks of the lake, <PERSON> Isham </PERSON> said. A spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON> says the states' governors could get out their yardsticks and settle the issue once and for all. `` If it's a good, honest fight, we'll be there,'' <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Kantor </PERSON> said. `` But it'll always be the shortest river in our hearts.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EconomyGlance     08-12 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Economy Glance,0487</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Rising Interest Rates Affecting Markets</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 At a glance, these are among the latest economic developments:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PRIME RATE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Several major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks on Thursday raised their prime rate a half percentage point to 10 percent, just two days after the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> boosted its discount rate to 6.5 percent from 6 percent to stave off inflation. The increase brings the prime rate to its highest level since June 18, 1985, when it was lowered to 9.5 percent from 10 percent. It was the third time this year that banks have raised the prime, used to calculate a range of fixed and adjustable rate corporate and consumer loans.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RETAIL SALES</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Retail sales climbed 0.5 percent in July, the third consecutive monthly increase. Sales increased $ 632 million to a seasonally adjusted $ 134.0 billion, but economists say rising interest rates threaten to dampen even this modest growth in the months ahead. The rise followed increases of 0.4 percent in June and 0.8 percent in May.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CROP REPORT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has reported that drought and high temperatures have shriveled the harvest of the nation's No. 1 crop, corn, to an estimated 4.48 billion bushels, down 37 percent from 7.06 billion bushels harvested in 1987. The drought will cause consumer food prices to go up an average 3 percent to 5 percent from 1987. Before the heat and dry weather, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> had expected a 1988 food price hike of 2 percent to 4 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>STOCK MARKET</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Stock prices hovered in a narrow range Thursday, struggling to stabilize after the market's recent steep decline. Analysts said the market's drop over the past week had pushed prices down to levels where they attracted some buyers. But they also said widespread concern persisted over the recent rise in interest rates. The Dow Jones average of 30 industrials, which had fallen nearly 00 points over the five previous sessions, on Thursday rose 5.16 to 2,039.30.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>HOUSING ACTIVITY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realtors </ORGANIZATION> reported home prices soared on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> in the April-June period, propelled by that region's booming economy, while prices lagged in depressed oil areas. The median price of existing single-family homes jumped to $ 204,000 in the <LOCATION> Anaheim-Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a 20.1 percent increase when compared with the second quarter of 1987. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, with an appreciation rate of 19.1 percent, ranked second in the nation and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, with an increase of 15.5 percent, was third. The steepest declines from a year ago were in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where the median resale price fell 12.7 percent to $ 56,900. Nationally, prices rose 3.4 percent to a median of $ 88,900, meaning half of the houses sold for more and half for less.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0650EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChihuahuaDeath     08-12 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Chihuahua Death,0161</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Sentenced In Chihuahua Death.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men were sentenced to four to 12 months in jail for stomping a neighbor's pet <LOCATION> Chihuahua </LOCATION> to death. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Goff </PERSON>, 22, and <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, 19, both of nearby Imperial, were also ordered Thursday to spend five years on probation and 100 hours doing community service work for the <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION>. The group takes in stray dogs and cats and tried to find homes for them. Both men said they were sorry and embarrassed they stole Co-Co, a dog belonging to <PERSON> Olive </PERSON> <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Maximonvich </PERSON> of Imperial. <PERSON> Goff </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON> said they were drunk when they jumped into the <PERSON> Maximonvich </PERSON> family's fenced yard, tossed the animal into the street, took it to a nearby garage and stomped it to death. The dog's corpse later was burned over an open fire. Both men pleaded guilty to theft, cruelty to animals and criminal conspiracy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--FinickySheep     08-12 0112</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Finicky Sheep,0113</SECOND>
<HEAD>Australian Imported Sheep `Aloof,' Dislike Malaysia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sheep imported from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> do n't like <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> and refuse to crossbreed with the local species, an agricultural official said today. <PERSON> Osman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Jempol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, said his statements were based on the group's observation of 110 imported ewes, mostly from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, that were reared throughout last year Although the ewes were fed well and fertile, they were `` aloof'' and only one lamb was born to the flock, <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ismail </PERSON> spoke at the group's annual general meeting at <LOCATION> Serting </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilir </LOCATION>, 72 miles south of <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, the national news agency <ORGANIZATION> Bernama </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Contras Bjt   08-12 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contras, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: For Shultz, A Bad Week for Nicaragua Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> can point to some recent successes around the world lately. Then there's <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> While <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has seen progress in such areas as <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and southwestern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, this has been a particularly bad week for the administration in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> found little evidence of support either in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for his policies and considerable evidence that the Contra rebels are becoming a spent force. As <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was winding up his 10-day hemispheric tour Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for the first time since the Contra aid program began was rejecting a proposal for military aid for the rebels. A Democratic package was approved instead that includes the possibility of eventual military aid, but there are so many strings attached that administration officials are viewing it as a defeat. For one thing, the legislation does not ensure weapons delivery to Contras inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> even if all the other considitions for release are met. Meanwhile, the Contras themselves are looking more and more like a refugee force than a fighting force. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials dispatched to the border area of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> on Monday were horrified by new evidence of a policy gone awry. The last of a group of about 1,000 Nicaraguans, including 250 Contras and 750 Nicaraguan civilians, made it to the Honduran side of the border area after an arduous weeks-long trek through rugged terrain. Many were sick or hungry or both. Many were practically naked, their boots and clothing having disintegrated along the route. They went to the border because that's where the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, unable to send food to the rebels inside <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, has set up feeding centers for Contras and other refugees from <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s turmoil. Since the cease-fire in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> went into effect last March, thousands of rebels have sought refuge in that area. The question of assessing blame for the plight of the Contras, who oppose <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> government, will be debated for years to come. The Republicans will accuse the Democrats of betraying a brave people who took up arms on the promise of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support. The Democrats will counter that the commitment to start down that path was ill-advised to begin with. In any case, the peace process is moribund and the rebel cause has never seemed more hopeless. In the absence of military aid for the Contras, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> has sought alternate means of bringing pressure to bear on the Sandinista government to encourage a democratic evolution. At the start of his recent trip, he went to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, hoping to come away with a joint statement from four friendly Central American foreign ministers designed to prod the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> into making democratic reforms. The effort did not bear fruit, partly because the most reluctant of the four parties _ <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> _ did not want to sign a document that had the appearance of having a `` Made in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> `` label. Beyond that, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which has been generally accommodating in other Third World trouble spots, appears to have dug in its heels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, rejecting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> appeals for a reduction in military aid to the <LOCATION> Sandinistas </LOCATION>. At current delivery rates, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> will receive more than $ 300 million worth of Soviet lethal aid this year, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> estimates. So the view here is that the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>, despite persistent economic problems, are more entrenched than ever. They have unswerving support from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and irresolute opposition from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which soon may have the added burden of figuring out what to do with thousands of Contra fighters-turned-refugees amassed along the border of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, neither of which wants them. With no other obvious alternative, their best hope may be obtaining a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> green card, a problem that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s successor could well inherit
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedda </PERSON> has covered foreign affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1968.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Nuke-LargestFine Bjt   08-12 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuke-Largest Fine, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sleeping On Job At Nuclear Plant Sparks Record $1.25 Million Fine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record $ 1.25 million fine against the operator of a <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> nuclear plant whose workers slept on duty is meant to wake up utilities and show them that such violations carry a price, says a government regulator. <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, operator of the dormant <LOCATION> Peach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bottom </LOCATION> nuclear power plant in southeastern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, was hit Thursday with the fine, the largest in Nuclear Regulatory Commission history. Sleeping on the job was so common at Peach Bottom that on one occasion, a shift superintendent and three of the four reactor operators all dozed at once, according to testimony by an <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> official last year. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> also announced fines ranging from $ 500 to $ 1,000 against the 33 present and former reactor operators _ the first such civil penalties ever proposed for individual operators. It said the 33 fines `` involved sleeping and-or other acts of inattention to duty'' at the plant on the <LOCATION> Susquehanna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> called the levies `` proposed fines,'' explaining that both <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> and the operators have 30 days to either admit or deny the alleged violations. If they deny the allegations, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> staff will review their complaints before deciding whether to uphold the penalties. Peach Bottom, which is capable of producing 1 million kilowatts of electric power, was ordered shut down by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> on March 31, 1987. The commission said the plant posed `` an immediate threat to the public health and safety.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy executive director for regional operations, said in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> that the commission recognized that the utility had made `` extensive personnel changes'' since then and had ordered reactor operators retrained. But <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said the fines were necessary to demonstrate to the company and to other utilities `` the significance of the problem, and to ensure that corrective actions are long lasting.'' In addition, he said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> action should `` emphasize to all licensees that, in addition to the cost of corrective action, a licensee may face the additional costs of sanctions for significant safety violations.'' <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> officials said at a news conference in <LOCATION> Holtwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, that they had not decided whether to appeal the record fine. `` We have a period of time to evaluate and make that decision. We have not made it yet,'' Chairman <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paquette </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Paquette </PERSON> said no rate increases would stem from the fine and that the company does not expect to seek a rate hike until after its <LOCATION> Limerick </LOCATION> II power plant in suburban <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> becomes operational, possibly in 1990. <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said the company was `` relieved that the enforcement issue is finally behind us and that we may now fully focus our energies on the completion of the Peach Bottom restart plan.'' In addition to the fines, the commission barred the utility from placing `` in any operational position'' three officials who were top-level managers at the plant in 1987. The officials held the positions of operations engineer, superintendent of operations and plant manager. <PERSON> Corbin </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> McNeill </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, executive vice president for nuclear operations, said the officials are still with the company, but they have been assigned to other, non-nuclear responsibilities. The fine is the largest since <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> gave the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> authority to issue civil penalties in 1969. The previous high was a $ 900,000 fine against <ORGANIZATION> Toledo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for an incident in which the <LOCATION> Davis-Besse </LOCATION> nuclear plant in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> had a temporary loss of cooling water. <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION> that he was pleased with the fine, but wished the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> had gone further and suspended or revoked the licenses of control room operators. <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, which still hopes to obtain <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> permission to restart the plant, said the action has cost shareholders $ 86 million because of the cost of purchasing replacement power. Peach Bottom is owned by a group of utilities. <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> owns about 42.5 percent, <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Delmarva </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> own 7.5 percent each, and <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> owns about 42.5 percent and operates the plant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Pigeons     08-12 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Pigeons,0178</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Eyes Export Market For The Birds</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has begun breeding pigeons in a bid to boost the popularity of the much-maligned bird, a poor man's poultry considered a delicacy during biblical times The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> recently opened four pigeon nurseries housing 800 pairs of the birds in the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. Pigeon meat, more tender and pungent than chicken, was a favored delicacy during the time of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> and around 500 B.C., when poor people sacrificed the bird at Jewish temples. Pigeon meat has long been popular in <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> households, where many families raise the birds to vary their menu and as a cheap alternative to poultry. <PERSON> Zvi </PERSON> <PERSON> Karchi </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s research and development department, said he hoped to popularize the bird in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, where poultry is a dietary staple and Arab-style food is common. The newspaper also quoted <PERSON> Karchi </PERSON> as saying he expected <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to successfully compete with pigeon exporters like the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ReaganPolitics Bjt   08-12 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan Politics, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Denials Hardly Disguise Reagan Assistance</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Of course President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is playing politics these days, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s protestations notwithstanding. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would have a lot more to lament if the White House were playing it any other way. The vice president said the other day that he guessed it was inevitable for people to see political motives behind <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decisions on Cabinet appointments, vetoes and policy decisions `` But I certainly wo n't add any validity to the charge,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. It really is n't much of a charge. It is so standard as to be an election-year cliche. Politicians are always accusing each other of playing politics, which is rather ironic since that's what they do for a living. Besides, there's really nothing wrong with it. That is the way issues are defined and put to the voters. If they do n't like what they see, they can vote for the other candidate. Presidents have not always been so helpful to their vice presidents in campaigns to succeed them. <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> did n't do a lot for <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in 1960. <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s handling of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war issues in his final months probably hurt <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>'s ticket in 1968 Both those vice presidents lost. No president can deliver nomination, let alone election, to his vice president or any other candidate. But presidents certainly can help, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is. He has promised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> two campaign appearances a week from Labor Day on, and his White House actions in these waning days of his administration are at least as significant an assist. `` I'm just still working on the job here,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Tuesday when questions were raised about political motivation in his appointment of a Hispanic educator to become secretary of education. A month earlier, the vice president had promised an association of Latin citizens that he would choose a Hispanic for a seat in a Bush Cabinet. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was consulted before <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, was appointed to the education post. But he said he was n't claiming credit or responsibility for it. The influence, or interests, of the vice president were evident in an assortment of other <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> moves, including: _ His decision not to veto a bill to require advance notice to workers when there are to be plant closings or major layoffs <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> let the bill become law without his signature, rather than revive an issue the Democrats welcomed in congressional as well as presidential politics. _ The selection of <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> confidant, to become secretary of the treasury, succeeding <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who left the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> to take command of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign _ The veto of a $ 299.5 billion defense budget bill on grounds it sought to lock the administration into weapons programs favored by the Democrats Defense and foreign policy are issues on which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> believes he can master Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>; the veto guarantees a new round of action on defense spending during the campaign. _ The signing on Wednesday of a bill to pay reparations to Japanese Americans because of internments during World War II That's particularly significant in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which is where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> endorsed the idea during the primary election campaign. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> originally objected to the cost, but embraced a bill with a ceiling on appropriations. _ An apparent switch in signals on a Contra aid bill that passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday night over solid Republican opposition The Democratic bill provides $ 27 million in so-called humanitarian aid, but no arms for Contras fighting the government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The military aid issue was left open for possible action later. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> favors the full array of Contra aid. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee, has voted for it in the past. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is opposed to military aid to the Contras. Republican campaigners do n't want that ticket split forgotten. Not that the Democrats are without resources of their own. They do run <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and as opportunities arise this fall, they will use that control to the advantage of their candidates and the disadvantage of Republicans. And, in turn, Republicans will accuse them of playing politics.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>, executive editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered politics since 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-Award     08-12 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Award,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Chief Wins India's Nehru Award for International
Understanding</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> has won the 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Jawaharlal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nehru </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Award </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Understanding </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador announced. The prize has been awarded annually since 1965 for outstanding contributions to international understanding, said Ambassador C.R. Gharekahn on Thursday. He said it reflects general achievements, but he specifically mentioned the secretary-general's role in negotiating a cease-fire between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. The truce is to take effect Aug. 20. The award includes a cash prize of about $ 110,000. A jury of Indian officials selects the winner. The ambassador said <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> had agreed to come to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> for presentation of the prize, but a date had not been set. The award is named after <PERSON> Nehru </PERSON>, post-colonial <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s first prime minister. Previous winners include former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General U Thant, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, missionary <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, Dr. <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Salk </PERSON> who developed a polio vaccine, South African activist <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, Indian leader <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, and Swedish Prime Minister <PERSON> Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Palme </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Marcos-Mother     08-12 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marcos-Mother,0720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos' Mother Unburied Three Months After Her Death</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATAC, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than three months after her death, the body of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' mother is still unburied as her son's dwindling followers maintain a wake in hopes the government will allow him to come home. But civic leaders say that even here in `` <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> country,'' many believe the time has come to place the body of <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON> <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON> in the marble tomb prepared for her in the family cemetery in a swamp on the eastern edge of this town. Mrs. <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON> died May 4 at age 95, and her body was transferred the following month from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> to the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> ancestral home in <LOCATION> Batac </LOCATION>, a town of about 50,000 people about 240 miles to the north. Family members and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporters say no date for the burial will be set until President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> allows her deposed predecessor to return or until <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> orders the interment. The body has been embalmed at least twice, and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family mortician <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Malabed </PERSON> said the remains could remain unburied until the end of the year. The former president has lived in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> since a civilian-military uprising toppled his 20-year administration in 1986. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow him back for security reasons. `` To be frank with you, we have not been able to set a definite date,'' said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' sister <PERSON> Fortuna </PERSON> <PERSON> Barba </PERSON>, who attends daily prayer services before the open coffin in the family home. The mansion is now a museum. Pictures of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, hang from the walls alongside banners such as: `` God's will, I'll return to save my nation and people from communism.'' `` We're still hoping, perhaps against hope, that the situation will change and something good may come out of it,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Barba </PERSON> said. Whatever sympathy <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> may have hoped to generate by his appeal to come home appears to have dissipated in the months following his mother's death. Filipino newspapers rarely mention the ongoing wake. In a rare exception, The <ORGANIZATION> Manila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> recently suggested an epitaph: `` Here lies <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, died at age 95, buried at age 96.'' <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Farinas </PERSON>, provincial governor of <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> and a close friend of the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family, said if <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> believes he has no chance to return, `` he should give the word that his mother should be laid to rest.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Abaya </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic priest, said the arrival of Mrs. <PERSON> Edralin-Marcos </PERSON>' body generated considerable enthusiasm in <LOCATION> Batac </LOCATION> because many believed <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was returning for the funeral. Pro-Marcos politicians erected red, white and blue signs in <LOCATION> Batac </LOCATION> and in neighboring towns welcoming the former president to his provincial stronghold. But as the weeks dragged on without the Apo, or Grand Old Man, both the signs and the enthusiasm are fading. Under a rotation system, residents take turns attending daily prayers before the casket. But attendance has dwindled from hundreds to a few dozens each day. `` The feeling seems to be that the woman has suffered enough and should be laid to rest,'' <PERSON> Abaya </PERSON> said. Vice Mayor <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Yadao </PERSON>, a member of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> party, said townspeople were still eager for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return. <PERSON> Yadao </PERSON> said, however, that townspeople were losing patience with his nearly fanatical supporters from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> who came here for the wake. `` We have to provide for them,'' <PERSON> Yadao </PERSON> said. `` Sometimes, they are quarelling with themselves. She should be buried now. That is our tradition.'' He was referring to the practice of burying people within nine days of death. At <LOCATION> Laoag </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, about six miles north, the military has placed metal barricades, mounds of gravel and six concrete abutments on the runway, shortening it by 1,200 yards to prevent <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> from slipping in on a charter flight from abroad. Some <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> supporters vow to continue the wake indefinitely until their leader returns. But asked if the family were prepared for an indefinite standoff, Mrs. <PERSON> Barba </PERSON> replied: `` Well, I suppose if there is no hope, I'll get a call from him one day telling me to go ahead with it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FBIRacism     08-12 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FBI Racism,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Dismisses Major Parts of FBI Agent's Racial Harassment Suit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Major portions of a black <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent's racial harassment lawsuit against the government have been dismissed as technically defective, but the plaintiff's lawyer says the ruling ultimately will be a victory. Attorney <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> said many of the legal flaws found by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> in agent <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s complaint can be corrected and the case will go forward. The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> lawyer said <PERSON> Richey </PERSON>'s order Thursday leaves the essential element of the case intact. `` He has upheld our ability to get personal damages against the individual wrongdoers,'' <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> said. `` This is very important and was not a matter of certainty when we started this.'' In a highly technical opinion, <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> dismissed `` without prejudice'' most of the claims against 21 white <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, whom <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> contends engaged in a three-year campaign of harassment that included anonymous telephone calls, obscene mail and death threats. <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> also contends agents threatened his white wife with sexual assault. The `` without prejudice'' proviso <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> attached to most of the dismissals gives <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> an opportunity to file a new complaint to try to correct the legal defects identified by the judge. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> said the complaint, while raising `` repugnant and chilling'' allegations, `` contains defects in both pleading and legal theory that constrain the court to dismiss many of the plaintiff's claims.'' The judge, however, refused to dismiss common-law claims against three white <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents _ <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Veach </PERSON> _ whom <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> said spearheaded harassment when he worked in that city. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> also refused to dismiss <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s claim that his civil rights were violated under Title VII of the 1964 Civil Rights Act. But he dismissed 21 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents and top officials as defendants in that claim, saying only the attorney general could be sued as head of <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s agency. He also found that many of <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s claims against individual agents, particularly supervisors who allegedly ignored the racial harassment complaints, were pre-empted under other statutes by the Title VII claim. <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> chose to hail <PERSON> Richey </PERSON>'s decision to preserve the civil rights claim, saying it was the vehicle for the overall harassment and discrimination complaint. `` The individuals, at least temporarily, some of them, are off the hook, but the judge has clearly said the only problem is he does n't want Title VII and allegations about the individuals to be merged,'' <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> said. `` That is just a matter of filing an amended complaint which separates them,'' he said. But <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> conceded he will have difficulty sustaining claims against the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> supervisors and managers that <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> claims deliberately ignored his complaints. <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> said he was gratified by <PERSON> Richey </PERSON>'s stern warning to the defendants to stop referring to the racial harassment incidents as `` pranks.'' `` This utter lack of sensitivity is almost as disturbing as the alleged acts themselves,'' <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> said, adding that `` the court hereby warns defendants that a modicum of decency is expected for all those who file pleadings in this court.'' <PERSON> Kairys </PERSON> said, `` The judge really recognized how inappropriate it has been for the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> and their lawyers to fail to acknowledge that something other than pranks occurred here.'' The judge also dismissed altogether complaints against three agents arising from alleged racial harassment incidents when <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON> worked in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, field office in 1983 and 1984. <PERSON> Richey </PERSON> found that the statute of limitations had expired on those claims. The <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opportunity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> upheld many of <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s complaints about harassment in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> EEOC </ORGANIZATION>'s investigation of the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> incidents was suspended after the suit was filed <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>, 38, now works in the bureau's <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> office. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who admitted during an internal investigation that he forged <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s signature on an application for `` death and dismemberment'' insurance, is the subject of a grand jury investigation. The insurance policy was sent to <PERSON> Rochon </PERSON>'s home as part of what <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> called an attempt to get `` retribution'' for the black agent's complaints of racial harassment. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> was suspended for two weeks without pay but fellow white agents took a collection to pay his salary, according to statements made in court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NearCollision     08-12 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Near Collision,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Feds Checking Near-Collision Over Atlantic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal investigators are trying to determine why a jetliner was flying at the wrong altitude over the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and almost collided with another jetliner earlier this week. Word of the incident emerged Thursday when the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said it was investigating a report filed by one of the pilots, who estimated the two aircraft came within 200 to 300 feet of each other. The incident last Monday occurred about 700 miles east of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and involved <ORGANIZATION> Lockheed </ORGANIZATION> L-1011 jetliners flown by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> charter airline, and LuftTransport, a West German charter carrier, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Reb </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> pilot, said he was talking to his co-pilot when he suddenly saw the other plane through a side window of the cockpit. He immediately lowered the nose of his plane and descended 1,000 feet, according to an airline spokesman. At the time, both jets were cruising at about 550 miles per hour at 35,000 feet with <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> Flight 665 flying directly west and the LuftTransport Flight 410 heading southwest and converging, according to government and airline officials. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said the LuftTransport plane should have been flying at 31,000 feet. Flight 665 with 250 passengers and 12 crew members was bound from <LOCATION> Lisbon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Recker </PERSON>, executive vice president of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>, which is based in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. It could not immediately be determined how many people were aboard the other plane, but such European charter flights normally are heavily booked during the summer months, according to aviation experts. The LuftTransport jet was bound from <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Cancun </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The airspace over the ocean where the incident occurred is not covered by radar, but jetliners are assigned specific routes, speed and altitude by controllers at <LOCATION> Gander </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Newfoundland </LOCATION>, and at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. According to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>, the West German plane had just left airspace controlled by the Gander controllers and entered airspace controlled by the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> control center when the incident occurred. `` The -LRB- German -RRB- plane should have descended to 31,000 feet before it entered <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> airspace,'' said <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON>. <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said preliminary reports indicate that both planes were flying the proper route but that `` it looks like a case of the wrong altitude'' on the part of the LuftTransport plane. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigators planned to interview controllers at both <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and Gander to determine whether the LuftTransport pilot was assigned the wrong altitude. <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said both pilots saw the other aircraft. `` It was close and it's kind of frightening,'' said <PERSON> Recker </PERSON>. He said no one aboard the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> plane was injured during the incident and that it was over before the passengers were aware of anything unusual. LuftTransport is based in <LOCATION> Dusseldorf </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicalWaste-Congress     08-12 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medical Waste-Congress,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Moves On Medical Waste Issue Before Returning Home For
Recess</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lawmakers took several steps to fight the ocean dumping of medical waste before heading back to districts where waves of the infectious debris have marred the summer for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> resort towns and vacationers. A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee voted Thursday to stiffen federal penalties for illegal dumping as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> prepared to leave town for the August recess, and other lawmakers drafted separate measures to track hospital debris and make violators financially liable for lost revenue to coastal communities. Meanwhile, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> injected the topic into presidential politics, calling on Attorney General-designate <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to determine if the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> can be used to strengthen government anti-pollution enforcement. `` Our ocean should not be a dumping ground,'' the vice president said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called medical waste floating up on <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> beaches a `` national disgrace'' and termed the situation `` dangerous,'' just two days after the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that `` guidance and education'' _ not new rules on disposal of medical waste _ were the answer. <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> officials on Tuesday had told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel that they believe the debris does not pose a major health threat. In <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on crime approved legislation that would create a specific federal law against medical waste dumping, carrying penalties up to five years in prison, $ 250,000 in fines and forfeiture of assets such as ships used in illegal dumping. Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, the subcommittee chairman and sponsor of the bill, said current laws do not address medical waste dumping specifically and do not cover dumping in all circumstances. `` Even if they are apprehended, the current penalties amount to little more than a slap on the wrist,'' said <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, who represents <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> shore communities. `` By making illegal medical waste disposal a federal criminal offense, we will be raising the stakes considerably.'' Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, D-Mass., who represents resort towns on <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard and <LOCATION> Nantucket </LOCATION>, introduced legislation similar to <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' bill, but also including a liability provision Under the <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> measure, state and local governments would be able to recover lost tax revenues from violators. In addition, coastal homeowners could recover for damaged property and fishermen and tourist-related businesses could recover for lost business due to medical waste. `` While the medical risk associated with this debris is fairly low, it is intolerable that garbage finds its way into the ocean and onto our shores,'' said <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and Fisheries subcommittee on fisheries and the environment. Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., filed legislation calling for a manifest system to track medical waste produced in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last week passed a similar pilot program proposal for <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. The federal government has no mandatory tracking system, and <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials have said they will continue with voluntary efforts instead of imposing regulations. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Denit </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s office of solid waste, said the agency would use `` education and guidance'' to discourage companies from dumping medical waste at sea.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0207EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Money     08-12 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Money,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Has Cash To Spare For His Small Share Of Convention Cost</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> comes to the Republican convention with more money than anticipated after rationing everything from plane travel to office supplies to keep from going over the federal cap on spending, his staff says. Although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does n't have to worry about paying for the multimillion-dollar Superdome convention, he does have to pay related campaign costs such as housing and staff payroll. To make those ends meet, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been forced to keep a tight rein on campaign spending over the past few months to stay under the $ 23 million primary spending limit that is set for presidential campaigns. Candidates are allowed more than $ 4 million on top of that for fund-raising costs, which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also raised and spent. Entering the last six weeks of the campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> began July with less than $ 1 million to go before hitting the limit. He has only to make it through his nomination Wednesday night to get $ 46 million from the federal treasury for his fall race against Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Until then, his campaign is ruled by the primary limit. `` We've been penny-pinchers all along and we're very careful with our finances,' ` said finance spokeswoman Ede Holiday, who added, `` Obviously we are very close to our spending limit.'' She declined to say how close. Four Democratic state chairmen have accused <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of overspending the limit and filed a complaint with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> last week. Holiday said the campaign kept a tight budget that, as planned, will last just through the convention. `` We have plenty of money to do what we want to do at the convention,'' she said. Holiday would not say how much the campaign was spending for convention activity, but said the belt-tightening in recent weeks has left more money to spend on the convention than originally anticipated. One campaign official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said it was well in excess of the $ 300,000 that Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' staff says he spent at the Democrats' convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> last month. Some of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> staff are working voluntarily until they go on the general election payroll after the nomination, said Holiday. Staff members have talked about having to scrimp on office supplies, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> restricted his travel sharply in the waning weeks of the campaign to keep from topping the limit. The lion's share of the extravaganza in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> _ including the convention itself, communications equipment and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> office space in the Superdome, and balloons and banners _ will be paid for by the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and to a lesser degree the local host committee. The Republicans, as the Democrats did in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, receive $ 9.2 million from the federal treasury to put on their conventions. The money comes from the same taxpayer-supported federal fund that doles out primary matching money to the candidates and gives each general election candidate $ 46 million. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Mead </PERSON>, deputy convention manager for communications, said most of the money went into construction and logistics costs, while many of the decorations inside and outside the hall were paid for by the city of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Louisiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Host </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts centered on promoting <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> through such projects as decorating the airport, providing media kits about the area, and plastering the city with banners and billboards reading `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Host </ORGANIZATION> to the Future and the 1988 Republican Convention,'' said <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hymel </PERSON>, executive director of the committee's media and hospitality effort.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Handguns-NRA     08-12 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Handguns-NRA,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRA Attacks Congressional Backers of Handgun Waiting Period</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has served notice that even its strongest backers will feel its wrath if they support legislation to require a seven-day waiting period when buying a handgun. <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> letters mailed across the country urge the gun lobby's supporters to pressure members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to defeat the measure But even conservative Republicans who call themselves <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> supporters said Thursday that the mailings contain factual distortions, and some of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> members are downright angry. `` They ought to stop beating up on their friends,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., who is undecided on the legislation `` They are really screwing up their credibility with people who supported them for a long, long time.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> especially angered Rep. <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., who said the organization's letter attacking him personally is `` downright erroneous, false and plays on hysteria in an attempt to get me to change my vote. <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> said he supports the waiting period and wo n't change his mind The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> official who signed the letters, <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> was singled out because he wrote his constituents proclaiming his support for the right to keep and bear arms. `` You do n't have it both ways,'' said <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION>. `` Everybody knows this is a big gun vote. You're either for gun owners or against gun owners. `` If someone is going to vote for a bill that takes these rights away ... we're going to fight back. That's what sportsmen and gun owners expect us to do.'' The waiting period measure, part of omnibus drug legislation that the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> will vote on in September, would require a seven-day wait in the purchase of a handgun from a licensed dealer. The dealer must send to law enforcement authorities a sworn statement that includes a description of the gun, the serial number, and the name, address and birth date of the buyer. Police may, but are not required to, conduct a background check. Purchasers who would be prohibited from buying handguns would be those already ineligible under existing federal law: convicted felons, fugitives from justice, illegal aliens, drug addicts, those adjudicated mentally ill or committed to a mental institution, those dishonorably discharged from the military and people under indictment for a felony. Twenty-two states already have enacted a waiting period of varying duration. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> contends the waiting period would amount to a national registration of handguns, would cost `` hundreds of millions'' of dollars to enforce, and would require `` a bureaucrat's permission'' to buy a gun. Conservatives and liberals alike said all these assertions were wrong. But conservative <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members targeted for pressure said that perhaps the ultimate insult was the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s attempt to link them to liberals who support gun control. <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>'s constituents: `` I have in my hand a letter dated July 1988 from the <ORGANIZATION> Sensenbrenner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Re-Election </ORGANIZATION> proclaiming his fight for gun owners' rights ... HA. With support like that, you might as well have <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> representing you.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., is one of the most liberal senators and is a strong supporter of handgun control While other versions of the letter do not attack individual lawmakers, they make the same points about the legislation. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> contended that backers of the bill `` want the police to visit your home before you can buy a firearm, yet police right now do n't have the resources to send cruisers to investigate residential burglaries in many areas.'' <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON> defended the statement even though no such language is in the bill. He said it was a response to statements made by backers of the legislation that police would drive by homes to check addresses on a gun purchaser's forms. Responding to a criticism of <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON> acknowledged that the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> supported waiting periods in the early 1970s, but changed its mind a few years later when it found `` they do n't stop crime. It's simply red tape for honest people.'' Other lawmakers angered by the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> campaign included Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Calif </LOCATION>., a <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member who has backed past <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> positions; and Rep. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., who considers himself a strong supporter of the right to own <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON> called the attack on <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> `` a pretty desperate letter against one of their supporters.'' <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON> said, `` I am shocked and disappointed at the excessive language and tactics used by the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> in the letter to my constituents.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-Wright     08-12 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Wright,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush and Wright Tangle Over Investigation, Insults</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> locked horns at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> dinner party after <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said he was `` surprised and hurt'' that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had called for a special prosecutor to investigate ethics charges against him. Aides to the two officials described the Wednesday night episode after insisting on anonymity. They said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> retorted by complaining about the Democratic convention, where speakers referred to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as `` a toothache of a man'' and taunted `` Where was <PERSON> George </PERSON>?'' in suggesting he was an invisible vice president. The aides provided differing descriptions of the intensity of the exchange, which occurred at the annual House Gym Dinner given for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who use the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> athletic facilities. `` It was a polite, private discussion, not a heated exchange, no profanities,'' said the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> aide. In contrast, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aide said: `` It was quite a heated exchange with a lot of witnesses. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> started screaming and yelling that he -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB- had impugned his -LRB- <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s -RRB- integrity.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aide said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> used profanities. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday, but not to apologize, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s aide said The aide said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> `` reassured him there was no personal animosity of any sort,'' and the two agreed they could `` make contributions by maintaining a high standard in their personal relationship.'' <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, the campaign press secretary to the vice president, said, `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told me this morning, ` If you get any calls, you can be authorized to say that I talked to the speaker this morning and I appreciated his call.''' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have known each other since the 1960s, when they served together in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as junior congressmen from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s aide said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> approached the speaker at the dinner and asked how he was doing. The speaker said he was disappointed in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for calling for a special prosecutor to investigate <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> on ethical issues, particularly the financial arrangements involving the publication of a book by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and reports that the speaker had tried to get special treatment for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> bankers. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s actions are being investigated by a special counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s aide said the speaker has `` always enjoyed a personal rapport with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'' and has never had any personal harsh feelings toward him. `` On a number of occasions, including one with the press, he had defended <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from what <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> considered unwarranted attacks and bum attacks.'' He said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> in front of reporters defended <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from charges of being a wimp, and the next week <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called for the special prosecutor and `` came out with his attacks on <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>.'' `` Last night, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> reminded him of his defenses of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that should <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> be elected president, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> would be speaker, and the two would have to work together,'' the aide said. `` <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> never engaged in any personal attacks on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -LRB- and he -RRB- was surprised and hurt <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> gratuitously had gone out of his way to attack <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> personally. `` He said he had no personal hostility toward <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He was glad he had spoken to him. That's what a friend should do if he felt that another friend had let him down or done him injury.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 AP Writer <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> also contributed to this story, from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Burma-Analysis     08-12 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Burma-Analysis,0751</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Clear Indication Of How Burma Revolt Will End</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DENIS D. GRAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Those who follow the rapidly moving events are uncertain of the outcome in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, where unarmed citizens are angry enough to confront rifles and the government is willing to shoot them down. Diplomats and other observers sketch a variety of finales to the drama that began with President <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>'s accession to power late last month and has progressed through increasing levels of popular protest and violence. Security forces initially were restrained and disciplined, but soldiers opened fire Tuesday on thousands of demonstrators in the streets of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. Official reports say protest has spread to virtually every town and city in the the <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> nation of 38 million people. High school students in their mid-teens were the vanguard but witnesses say <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks, workers and ordinary townspeople have joined the mass denunciation of 26 years of authoritarian rule and economic deprivation. These are some of the results foreseen by diplomats in scenarios by diplomats in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>: _ Continued ruthless suppression of all protest by <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> and a loyal army until all opponents are rooted out or cowed into the passivity that characterized the political scene until recent events. _ The ouster of <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> by former strongman <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON>, who overthrew the democracy in 1962. He formally retired from political life last month, but some believe he still pulls the strings. _ An intensified and bloody uprising that would compel the army, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s most powerful institution, to overthrow the government and install a more moderate leadership. Unlike the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, where mass popular protest achieved greater political freedom, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> has no prominent personalities advocating democracy who could lead the growing but diffuse opposition. <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> Gyi </PERSON>, the most outspoken critic of the system, is 70 and retired from politics after falling out with Ne Win in the early 1960s. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON> has jailed the former army officer, a relative liberal. Protesters seem to illustrate this dearth of political alternatives by resurrecting old symbols and the images of leaders long dead. <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> marchers carry portraits of <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON>, the dashing fighter for <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> independence who was assassinated in 1947, and wave the peacock flag of days when <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> struggled against its British colonial masters. Like the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> under <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> has a strong military in which increasing disaffection is reported. Some diplomats speculate that elements of the army, as in the `` people power'' revolution that ousted <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, could provide the muscle to bring down <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, a former general. The military has been <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s privileged class since Ne Win seized power, however. Retired or active military officers currently hold all but two Cabinet positions, and even the rank and file has privileges civilians do not enjoy. Ne Win assiduously built, or bought, the loyalty of a generation and more of army officers. Although his proclaimed ideology has been a mix of socialist economics, Buddhism and isolationism, political control has rested with the military and the army-dominated government political party. `` I find it hard to believe such a man steeped in power since 1962 giving it all up in one fell swoop. Something smells here,'' said a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat based in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> who spoke on the condition he not be identified. He added, however, that if <PERSON> Ne </PERSON> <PERSON> Win </PERSON> returned the question remained whether the people now would accept `` the lesser of two evils'' even if he pursued urgently needed economic reforms. Some protesters still call the government the `` Ne Win regime'' and demand restoration of democracy. Marchers applauded loudly this week when passing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. Others say they are fighting for socialism minus <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Lwin </PERSON>, who is widely hated for ruthlessly suppressing dissent since the 1960s. `` The young people have n't known anything in their lives but this system,'' a Burmese intellectual said recently. `` They do n't know exactly what they want or how to get it. Many Westerners arriving from <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> say Burmese from many walks seem certain of one thing: They have had enough of leaders who provide neither freedom nor rice.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> bureau chief of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> and has reported on and from <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> for a decade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Thornburgh-Thumbnail     08-12 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Thornburgh-Thumbnail,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Thornburgh-Nominees</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a sketch of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to succeed <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> as attorney general: AGE: 56. FAMILY: The son of an engineer and grandson of a university professor, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> is married to the former <PERSON> Virginia </PERSON> <PERSON> Judson </PERSON>, a schoolteacher. His first wife, also named <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, was killed in an automobile accident in 1960 that left the youngest of his three sons brain-damaged. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> now has a fourth son by his second wife, whom he married in 1963. EDUCATION: He earned a civil engineering degree from <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1954. He returned to his native <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> and earned a law degree from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1957. JOB HISTORY: He was appointed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for western <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> in 1969. As a prosecutor, his targets included a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> customs agent, a county sheriff and a former <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> congressman, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> <PERSON> Whalley </PERSON>, who was convicted in a kickback case. In 1975, he was appointed by President Ford as assistant attorney general in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s criminal division. In 1978, the Republican <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> defeated former <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Flaherty </PERSON> for governor. He ran on a platform of cleaning up corruption in the Democratic administration of then-Gov. <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapp </PERSON>, a Democrat. He was re-elected in 1982, narrowly defeating former congressman <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ertel </PERSON> during a recession that made it difficult for incumbent <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates. Barred by law from seeking a third term, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> at the end of 1986 to head the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politics </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION>. POSITIONS AS GOVERNOR: <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>'s budget proposals held spending increases to less than the rate of inflation for eight straight years. He championed a controversial welfare reform law that limited cash benefits to three months a year for an estimated 68,000 people considered `` able-bodied.'' A sampling of his positions: _ On abortion, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> has a mixed record In December 1981, he vetoed an Abortion Control Act, saying he objected to sections that said life started at conception, that mandated a 24-hour waiting period, and that would have established criminal penalties for doctors who broke the law. On June 11, 1982, however, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> signed a watered-down version of the abortion bill, which required doctors to notify women about the risks of abortion and the availability of medical assistance for prenatal care and childbirth. Portions of the law were later struck down by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. _ On capital punishment, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said during both terms in office that he favored the death penalty for certain murders and for persons convicted of killing police officers and prison guards During his first term, the death penalty was reinstated in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>. During his second term, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> signed warrants setting execution dates for several convicted murderers. Appeals courts granted stays in each case. _ On gun control, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said while campaigning for his first term that he opposed further government regulation of the sale or purchase of firearms Subsequent public statements on this issue could not be found. While governor, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> signed a bill setting a mandatory five-year sentence for any person convicted of using a gun during a crime.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-GOPConvention-Schedule     08-12 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-GOP Convention-Schedule,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Bush Rivals To Address Convention</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although the main order of business of the four-day <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> next week is to nominate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for president, all of his vanquished rivals will get some time in the spotlight. Kansas Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and television evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> are to speak in prime time, according to a draft of the convention schedule released Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The others _ former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Pont </PERSON> _ will address the 2,277 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegates on Monday, just before <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the president's daughter and co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Russian comic <PERSON> Yakov </PERSON> <PERSON> Smirnoff </PERSON> will kick off the convention Monday morning by leading the delegates in the pledge of allegiance. Other celebrities scheduled to recite the pledge later in the week during prime time include musician <PERSON> Lionel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hampton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON>. The president _ in his farewell convention address _ will speak Monday night, following a tribute to his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>. Actress <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> will participate in a salute to senior citizens during the Tuesday morning session before the delegates get down to the work of dealing with reports from the convention's committees New Jersey Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> will deliver the convention's keynote address Tuesday night, followed at the podium by former President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday night, the delegates will give their presidential nomination to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, following a nominating speech by Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Among the six seconding speakers are <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> football Coach <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON>, Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the vice president's son. Also on the list are Republican activist <PERSON> Ninfa </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, who says she plans to speak Spanish during her remarks, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Councilwoman <PERSON> Joanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maritime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Chao </PERSON>. On Thursday night, the delegates will pick a vice presidential nominee and hear the acceptance speeches by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his running mate before adjourning.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880812-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-12-88 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-HouseSouthAfrica-SanctionsRollCall 3Takes   08-12 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House South Africa-Sanctions Roll Call, 3 Takes</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-South Africa-Sanctions Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 244-132 roll call by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday approved legislation to require the withdrawal of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investment from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and impose a near-total trade embargo. A `` yes'' vote is a vote for the bill. Voting yes were 220 Democrats and 24 Republicans. Voting no were 10 Democrats and 122 Republicans. X denotes those not voting. There are three vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, no; Stump, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, yes. Republican _ <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, yes; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, yes; <LOCATION> Mineta </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON> yes; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, X; Stark, yes; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Badham </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Konnyu </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Lungren </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, no; <ORGANIZATION> Packard </ORGANIZATION>, no; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, yes; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, yes, <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, no; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, yes.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, yes.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Chappell </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, yes; MacKay, X; <PERSON> Mica </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, yes; Pepper, X; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, no; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, no; <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, yes; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, yes. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, no.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> X. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, yes.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, no. Republican _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
