<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrainCrash 3rdLd-Writethru a0750 08-01 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Crash, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0750,0665</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crews Begin Clearing Tracks From Head-On Crash</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts one graf after 3rd graf to UPDATE with investigation
centering on accident's time. SUBS 10th graf, `Investigators
were...', with 2 grafs to UPDATE with interviews held, time
investigation. Picks up 11th graf pvs, `Investigators examined...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GREG SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALTOONA, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters put out a fire in a tanker car Monday night and authorities allowed 2,000 evacuees to return home for the first time since two freight trains crashed head-on and derailed. Police Chief <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> <PERSON> Adair </PERSON> said the fire was extinguished about 5 p.m. and the residents of northeast <LOCATION> Altoona </LOCATION> were allowed back in their homes about a half hour later. The two <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> trains, one of which included two tanker cars carrying as much as 20,000 gallons each of volatile denatured alcohol, collided shortly before noon Saturday. Two crewmen were killed and their bodies were recovered Monday after the last fire was out. The chief investigator said Monday the probe was centering on whether one of the trains was off schedule. Fire coming from one of the cars had burned out by Monday but authorities waited to allow residents to return because of the danger of explosion from the second tanker. Flames shot up to 20 feet over the weekend but had shrunk to about 1 -LCB- feet by Monday morning. `` If it fireballed, it would kill anything within its path for a quarter mile, with devastating effects up to a half mile, and the capability of throwing shrapnel from the cars a mile and a half. That's why we evacuated a mile and a half surrounding it,'' said <PERSON> Adair </PERSON>. `` That's with one of them exploding, and we had two burning at one time.'' Bulldozers and cranes were picking through the debris and clearing the tracks of the 86 derailed cars. `` It's a situation where one of the engines rode up over the other one in a head-on collision _ went clear up in the air _ and it just completely annihilated two engines,'' the police chief said. `` There is metal and twisted debris and wheels thrown all over the place.'' He said workers had removed about 16 hopper cars by mid-afternoon Monday and that the rail line could be open to traffic by midnight if the two tankers could be removed without problems. Investigators were trying to determine how the two trains came to be on the same track. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobranetski </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> investigating team, said the two surviving crewmen and other rail workers were interviewed Monday. <PERSON> Dobranetski </PERSON> said his inquiry has not determined `` whether one train left early or whether the other was running late.'' The westbound train was to have cleared the track by 11:56 a.m., while the eastbound train was n't scheduled to leave <LOCATION> Altoona </LOCATION> until 12:01 p.m., he said. Investigators examined the controls of the wrecked eastbound train and found nothing out of order, said <PERSON> Dobranetski </PERSON>. `` The emergency brake was being applied,'' he added. The crash killed <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Peers </PERSON>, 54, of <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckingham </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Winterset </LOCATION>, both longtime employees of the railroad. Their bodies were located under the two derailed tankers, but had not been recovered earlier because of the danger of explosion. Rail officials said the eastbound <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bluffs-Chicago </ORGANIZATION> train was pulling 78 cars, while the westbound train was pulling eight cars from <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>. The two employees on the eastbound train jumped to safety before the trains collided. Both victims were on the westbound train. `` He had an obviously dangerous job. He left home thousands of times and came back thousands of times,'' said Peers' son, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>. `` This time, he did n't.'' `` They all worry about something like this happening,'' said <PERSON> Buckingham </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Voy </PERSON>. `` But he was always more worried about someone else getting hurt at the crossings in a car or truck.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Heat-List     08-01 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Heat-List,0211</SECOND>
<HEAD>Heat Records Set or Tied in 23 Cities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of cities where high-temperature records were broken or tied Monday, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>: <LOCATION> Alpena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, 94, breaks 1975 record of 93; <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, 100, breaks 1987 record of 97; <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, 97, breaks 1935 record of 96; <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 100, breaks 1894 record of 98; <LOCATION> Eau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clair </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, 104, breaks 1964 record of 100; <LOCATION> Flint </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, 98, breaks 1955 record of 95; <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, 93, ties 1975 record; <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, 98, ties 1980 record; <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, 96, ties 1917 record; <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cross </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, 105, breaks 1964 record of 97; <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, 100, breaks 1975 record of 97; <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, 101, breaks 1987 record of 95; <LOCATION> Mason </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 98, breaks 1919 record of 97; <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, 103, breaks 1894 record of 95; <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, 101, breaks 1964 record of 98; <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, 92, ties 1975 record; <LOCATION> Ottumwa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 102, ties 1941 record; <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, 101, breaks 1987 record of 100; <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, 101, breaks 1917 record of 100; <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, 99, breaks 1955 record of 98; St. Cloud, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, 99, tied 1964 record; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bend </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, 103, breaks 1944 record of 96; <LOCATION> Waterloo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 101, breaks 1987 record of 99.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People-Nelson     08-01 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Nelson,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Drop Plan To Protest Nelson Concert</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police officers in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and three other states dropped plans Monday to picket a <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> appearance after learning the country-and-western singer will give a concert to benefit both police and American Indian causes. `` If everything goes as planned, we probably wo n't have any demonstration,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Leavitt </PERSON>, president of the state Fraternal Order of Police. Police nationwide have been critical of <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>'s appearance last October at a benefit for <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>, an American Indian activist serving two life sentences for the 1975 slayings of two <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents. <PERSON> Peltier </PERSON>'s supporters are raising money to pay for an appeal. The <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> FOP made plans to protest at <LOCATION> Nelson </LOCATION>'s Aug. 27 concert in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> after <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> police said they would picket the singer concerts last weekend in <LOCATION> Warwick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>. About 800 officers from four states demonstrated at the Friday concert but canceled their Saturday protest after <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> agreed to the new benefit concert
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0729 08-01 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0729,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Heat Hits Upper Midwest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 3rd and 4th grafs, bgng `The National...', with 3 grafs
to UPDATE with late-afternoon temperatures, which increases the
number of cities posting or tying records to 23. Also CORRECTS that
old Dubuque record was set in 1894, sted 1849; and CORRECTS that
old record in South Bend, Ind., for entire month of August was 100,
set in 1947, sted 96, set in 1944. Picks up 5th graf, `Temperatures
were...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Temperatures in the upper 90s or above 100 degrees lingered Monday across the middle <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, parts of the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and upper Great Lakes region. Temperatures of 100 degrees or above were reported as far north as southern <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, where high humidity was pushing heat index values up close to 120 degrees at some locations. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said 23 cities reported record highs for the date. <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, had 100 degrees, breaking the record of 98 set in 1894. Temperatures in <LOCATION> Eau </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, reached a record 104; and in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crosse </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, it reached 105, smashing a 24-year-old record by 8 degrees. In <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, South Bend established an all-time record for the month of August with a 103 reading, topping the old record of 100 set on Aug. 5 and 6, 1947. <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> also had all-time hottest August reading with 103. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> had its sixth day of the season with a reading at or above 100, padding a record broken earlier in the season. Temperatures were generally in the upper 80s and lower 90s elsewhere east of the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>. Clouds were keeping readings in the 70s and lower 80s in the southern high <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, in the upper 60s to lower 80s from northeastern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> to the northern half of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and in the upper 70s and lower 80s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Showers and thunderstorms were scattered from south-central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> through the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> to the southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> states. Daytime heating of a humid air mass over the nation's southeast brought afternoon showers and thunderstorms A weak weather disturbance over the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> was producing showers and thunderstorms over the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Keys </LOCATION>. Showers and thunderstorms were also developing along and ahead of a warm front curving through the northern Plains and the upper <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Sunny and dry weather prevailed across the rest of the nation. Rainfall totals for the six hour period ended at 2 p.m. EDT included an inch at <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, and a third of an inch at <LOCATION> Key </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. Showers and thunderstorms produced up to an inch and a half of rain in central <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> Monday morning Showers and thunderstorms in south-central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> produced an inch of rain at <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, with close to 3 inches reported west of <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alta </LOCATION>. Temperatures around the nation at 3 p.m. EDT ranged from 59 degrees at <LOCATION> Arcata </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, to 104 degrees at <LOCATION> Elkhart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. The nation's low Monday morning was 38 degrees at <LOCATION> Gunnison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. Tuesday's forecast called for scattered showers and thunderstorms from the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> region to the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> and across the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>, with showers and thunderstorms in northern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, western <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Scattered showers and thunderstorms were forecast for south-central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> through the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and central Gulf Coast states to the southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. High temperatures were to be in the 90s across much of the nation east of the <LOCATION> Rockies </LOCATION>, with readings near 100 degrees in the central Plains and the middle <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Highs were forecast in the 80s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and from the northern high Plains to <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, 80s and 90s in the West, with readings above 100 degrees in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION> deserts. Highs in the 70s were forecast from the northern Rockies across <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and northern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-Amish     08-01 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Amish,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ohio's `Plain Folk' Surviving Drought</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BETH GRACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNT HOPE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amish farmer <PERSON> Elam </PERSON> <PERSON> Swartzentruber </PERSON> believes he has something better than electricity and technology to help him through the worst drought in more than 50 years: faith and brotherhood. <PERSON> Swartzentruber </PERSON>, better known by his Amish neighbors as `` <PERSON> Elam </PERSON> E.,'' is one of approximately 30,000 Amish residents in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, 15,000 of them involved in farming. The Amish, a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> group formed in a split with the Mennonites in 17th century <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>, believe in simplicity. They dress plainly, are forbidden to have electricity in their homes and do not use motorized equipment on their farms. It is that difference from the way `` the English'' work the land that has protected the Amish and Mennonites from financial ruin during the drought that is plaguing the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. The Mennonites also follow simple ways, but are permitted to use some modern technology. Amish and Mennonite farmers in eastern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> say they have lost about half of this year's hay crop and have seen a marked decrease in the quality and size of their oat and corn crops. But <PERSON> Swartzentruber </PERSON>, 52, of <LOCATION> Millersburg </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Holmes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, said he expects no long-term financial problems because he does not have the debt other farmers must repay. And he said he always pays cash for grain and seed. `` I do n't talk too good, but I farm good,'' <PERSON> Swartzentruber </PERSON> said in his thick German accent. `` This is the worst I've seen it ever, but I think it wo n't get any worse.'' He said the drought has not hurt his dairy cattle or feeder hogs and he expects to make a profit selling milk. But next year's feed prices likely will rise, making it tougher to make ends meet. `` The Amish have been hurt by the drought, but not as much as you would think,'' said <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a local expert on the people and their customs. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> left the Old Order Amish years ago but is considered a close friend and liaison by the Amish and Mennonites. They often do things in addition to farming, such as woodworking, and because they are so thrifty they have money put away for emergencies, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` They may look poor, but that does not necessarily mean they are,'' he said. <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a Mennonite who farms 100 acres near <LOCATION> Fredericksburg </LOCATION>, also is an auctioneer at the weekly <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hope </ORGANIZATION> farm supply sale, raises registered European Haflinger horses and sells deer hides. He said he attended a recent auction that did not end until 10 hours later than normal. `` People, including the Amish and Mennonites, were panicking, selling everything that does n't make them money,'' <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` But not me. My father always told me ` When everybody runs, just walk.' `` I was lucky. I bought a lot of hay in April. It was n't foresight It was just luck. But you can be sure I'm hanging on to it.'' <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who is not related to <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, grows corn, hay and oats and raises dairy cows and hogs. He said only half of his oats and hay crops have come in. He does not hold much hope for his corn. `` I will lose a lot of money, but I _ as we all do _ have tried to operate as sharply as I could,'' said the 52-year-old farmer. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoder </PERSON>, an Old Order farmer who works 95 acres near <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hope </LOCATION> with his five young sons, said the situation there is not as bad as he first thought. `` At first it looked like we were n't getting any corn, now it is looking like we're going to get half a crop,'' he said. He said his second hay cutting, which normally yields 3,500 bales, this year produced 2,600. His milk production is down as is his profit from the sale of pigs. The three farmers all said the drought will not take too large a toll on the community because they take care of each other. An Amish farmer lost his barn two weeks ago when it was hit by lightning, but <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said area Mennonite and Amish farmers were organizing a barn-raising that would not end until the barn is reconstructed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Canada-SouthAfrica     08-01 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-South Africa,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Censorship, Military Aid and Sanctions Feature in Commonwealth
Meeting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BRADLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The flame of a white candle is blown out, and over a background of rhythmic black chanting an announcer tells viewers: `` Do n't let <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> keep the world in the dark.'' The television spot, paid for by the Canadian government, is the only state-sponsored message of its kind ever used to fight apartheid. It's being broadcast in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> as part of a `` Rekindle the Light'' festival surrounding a meeting of eight <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers that starts today and will examine ways to combat white rule in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. There's a public forum, film premiere and exhibition of photos and posters banned in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Tonight, during a jazz concert on the shores of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, thousands will be asked to light an anti-apartheid candle. Those at home are invited to put a candle in their window. `` We think we can make a difference,'' said Foreign Minister <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, referring to the dominance <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> gives to the South African issue in its foreign policy. The two-day meeting of the special committee of foreign ministers will consider: _ Canadian proposals for countering <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African censorship and propaganda through measures including the beaming of short-wave radio broadcasts into the country from neighboring states _ A review of the effectiveness of economic sanctions against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and ways to broaden them _ A study of <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>'s international financial links, including gold sales, continued access to loans and the effects of corporate divestment from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> _ And a report by <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s former head of state, Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Olusegun </PERSON> <PERSON> Obasanjo </PERSON>, on the military needs of black front-line states `` There will not be dramatic progress on any question here _ it's not that kind of a meeting,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said Monday, explaining that any recommendations must go to the entire 49-nation <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION>, which meets again in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> next year. The foreign ministers' committee was established at the last <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION> in October 1987, and envoys taking part come from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, whose colonial past links all member countries, is conspicuously absent because Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> opposes sanctions against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The British are on board, however, when it comes to military training to neighboring <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, noted <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> Secretary General <PERSON> Shridath </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramphal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ramphal </PERSON> said he hoped the meeting establishes `` the machinery'' for more military training. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> ruled out anything but `` non-lethal'' aid. <PERSON> Ramphal </PERSON> had reservations about Canadian proposals for countering South African news censorship. He said it was `` too one-dimensional'' to beam more news into the country, when getting news out is more urgent. `` We have not been as energetic in getting the truth out by non-conventional means and sources as the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> media has been in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>,'' he said. South African state-of-emergency regulations in effect since 1986 restrict reporting about unrest, security force actions, treatment of detainees, some forms of protest, and a broad range of statements the government considers subversive. Enforcement of the regulations has not been comprehensive. Under apartheid, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s 5 million whites control the economy and government and live apart from the 26 million blacks, who have no vote in national affairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DroughtConditions     08-01 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Conditions,0756</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latest Reports on Soil, Crop Conditions</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Following are the latest soil and crop conditions in some of the states hardest hit by the drought, based on an <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey of Monday's weekly reports by state agricultural offices. Percentages relate to the number of reporting stations listing a particular soil or crop condition.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALABAMA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SOIL MOISTURE: 3 percent very short, 40 percent short, 57 percent adequate. KEY CROPS: Soybeans 13 percent poor, 40 percent fair, 31 percent good, 16 percent excellent. Cotton 16 percent very poor, 17 percent poor, 45 percent fair, 20 percent good, 2 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>GEORGIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: Very short 18 percent, short 57 percent, adequate 25 percent. KEY CROP: Peanuts 6 percent excellent, 46 percent good, 43 percent fair, 5 percent poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ILLINOIS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 86 percent short, 14 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 4 percent good, 41 percent fair, 42 percent poor, 13 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 67 percent short and 33 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 93 percent short and 7 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 3 percent good, 36 percent fair, 49 percent poor, 12 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IOWA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 95 percent short, 5 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 93 percent short, 7 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 2 percent excellent, 13 percent good, 36 percent fair, 34 percent poor, 15 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KANSAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 35 percent adequate, 65 percent short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 41 percent adequate, 59 percent short. KEY CROPS: Corn 11 percent excellent, 50 percent good, 10 percent fair, 28 percent poor, 1 percent very poor. Soybeans 36 percent excellent, 45 percent good, 16 percent fair, 2 percent poor, 1 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KENTUCKY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 7 percent very short, 62 percent short, 31 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Tobacco 2 percent very poor, 9 percent poor, 54 percent fair, 33 percent good, 2 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MICHIGAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 80 percent short, 20 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 1 percent excellent, 12 percent good, 35 percent fair, 32 percent poor, 20 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MINNESOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 84 percent very short, 16 percent short. KEY CROP: Corn 27 percent very poor, 43 percent poor, 24 percent fair, 6 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSOURI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 75 percent short, 23 percent adequate, 2 percent surplus. KEY CROP: Soybeans 9 percent very poor, 30 percent poor, 52 percent fair, 9 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MONTANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 7 percent adequate, 93 percent short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 13 percent adequate, 87 percent short. KEY CROP: Spring wheat 2 percent excellent, 5 percent good, 19 percent fair, 32 percent poor, 42 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 65 percent short, 35 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 58 percent short, 42 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 58 percent good, 30 percent fair, 9 percent excellent, 3 percent poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 82 percent very short, 18 percent short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 68 percent very short, 27 percent short, 5 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Spring wheat 37 percent very poor, 43 percent poor, 16 percent fair, 4 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 62 percent short, 37 percent adequate, 1 percent surplus. KEY CROPS: Corn 31 percent very poor, 34 percent poor, 29 percent fair, 6 percent good. Soybeans 15 percent very poor, 28 percent poor, 40 percent fair, 16 percent good, 1 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 70 percent critically short, 27 percent short, 3 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 62 percent critically short, 35 percent short, 3 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 21 percent very poor, 37 percent poor, 37 percent fair, 5 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TENNESSEE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 2 percent surplus, 51 percent adequate, 39 percent short, 8 percent very short. KEY CROP: Cotton 4 percent excellent, 71 percent good, 21 percent fair, 4 percent poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WISCONSIN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 94 percent short, 6 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 12 percent good, 35 percent fair, 41 percent poor, 12 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Shipyard     08-01 0931</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Shipyard,0960</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shipyard Blues: Birthplace Of Solidarity Struggles To Survive</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GDANSK, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The shadow of unemployment hangs over the <LOCATION> Lenin </LOCATION> shipyard in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>, birthplace of the Solidarity trade union and once a showpiece of Polish industry. The trouble this time is not labor unrest, but whether the state-owned yard will keep operating in the face of mounting money problems and a government that says it is ready to begin shutting down financially ailing plants. Solidarity activists discount the possibility that the yard will shut down, but management and representatives of official worker organizations believe it is a real possiblity. A strike at the yard May 2-10, led by Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, ended without a settlement. Workers were demanding free trade unions and higher wages. During the strike, management announced that it was unable to qualify for new state subsidies or credits from the national bank, and it said the yard's future would have to be decided by the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are going on with production without a single zloty -LRB- less than a penny -RRB- in the cash box,'' the weekly newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Zycie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gospodarcze </ORGANIZATION> recently quoted shipyard director <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolwinski </PERSON> as saying. The newspaper described the yard as a `` giant on partly rotten legs.'' The shipyard is a jumbled heap of docks, aging buildings and huge cranes towering over a series of <LOCATION> Vistula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> tributaries and canals near the heart of this centuries-old <LOCATION> Baltic </LOCATION> port city. It will produce only 11 ships this year, down from the annual high of 27 that it made in the late 1970s. The number of workers, too, has dropped, with only about 5,000 involved in direct production. Ironically, says yard foreign trade manager <PERSON> Ireneusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubiczek </PERSON>, the yard could produce more ships and has customers clamoring for them. But a lack of manpower is preventing it from exploiting its physical capacity. Whether the yard makes or loses money is a debatable question because so much depends on arbitrarily set tax regulations, material costs and credit rates which fluctuate widely and are beyond the shipyard's control, said <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bukowicz </PERSON>, president of the worker's self-management council. The council's job is to help run the shipyard along with management. But in a sign of confidence, 11 hulls were launched this year in order to have work for next year, he said. Officials say the strike cost 500,000 hours of labor, which must be made up by overtime and higher productivity. Workers got pay increases June 1, but management says the increases were planned before the strike. The increases were slightly higher than the 40 percent raise the government said could be allowed in response to price increases imposed this year. Pay now averages about 50,000 zlotys -LRB- $ 111 -RRB- a month and is structured to provide incentive for harder workers, said <PERSON> Waldemar </PERSON> <PERSON> Langer </PERSON>, a leader of the yard's official trade union. Despite the improvement, the yard's main trouble is that it can not attract a sufficient work force, said <PERSON> Kubiczek </PERSON>. `` We have lost 5,000 workers from the early 1980s until now,'' he said. `` It is our own near-tragedy. We have survived the most difficult years of the crisis in shipbuilding, and now the market is reviving. And we have clients willing to place orders.'' As an example, <PERSON> Kubiczek </PERSON> cited a timber-carrying ship ordered by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The yard has been able to contract to produce only 12 of the vessels, while the Soviets need 150, he said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is by far the yard's biggest customer. A sign inside the 343-acre facility says 575 out of 881 ships produced there have been for the Soviets. With more workers, the yard could nearly double production, <PERSON> Kubiczek </PERSON> said. But instead, workers are going to smaller private companies or cooperatives where they can make more money and work indoors. As a state-owned company, said <PERSON> Kubiczek </PERSON>, the shipyard is unable to raise wages dramatically because it would be hit with a punitive tax designed to fight wage inflation. It is one example of how national economic policies have hurt the yard, he said. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s frequently changing strategies to deal with its ailing economy have taken a toll in other ways, he said. `` At least once a year, every year, we are confronted with a new set of regulations and modifications of these rules for economic reform, while our commitments extend out many years ahead. `` It makes it practically impossible to predict whether the contract we sign today, which seems to be profitable, will in fact be practical,'' he said. One of the people who does not believe the yard will close is long-time <ORGANIZATION> Gdansk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> activist <PERSON> Bogdan </PERSON> <PERSON> Borusewicz </PERSON>. `` First of all, someone has to build ships for the Russians. Secondly, nobody really knows whether the <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> shipyard is making profit or losing money, because the prices for materials and components, such as steel plating and engines, are not market prices really,'' he said. The yard has a history of worker militancy. In December 1970 protests over food prices, an unknown number of employees were fatally shot by security forces. A towering monument to them, erected outside the main gate, was one result of the August 1980 strike at the yard that catapulted Solidarity and <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> to worldwide fame. The inconclusive May strike showed that tensions persist, especially among younger workers. Indeed, a decision to close the yard would likely set off a new round of unrest. `` It is my firm belief that the workers themselves would not allow it,'' said <PERSON> Grzegorz </PERSON> <PERSON> Szrejder </PERSON>, a 27-year-old welder active in Solidarity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-US-SAfrica     08-01 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-SAfrica,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S.-Soviets meet in advance of talks on Southern Africa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet diplomats opened talks Sunday on southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and its racial conflicts in preparation for a new round of four-nation negotiations aimed at bringing peace to the region. Cuban, Angolan, South African and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegations are to resume talks here Tuesday on the future of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, a territory controlled by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s white-minority governmet. That session is scheduled to last three days and is the fifth publicly announced round since negotiations were started in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> last April. <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistant secretary of state for <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> affairs, conferred with Soviet deputy foreign minister <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamishin </PERSON> for 3 -LCB- hours Sunday at the Soviet mission. No details were given of their their talks that are set to end Monday. The four-nation conference will attempt to build on a set of principles initialed by <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> at a meeting July 13 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. That accord commits the parties to seek a timetable for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to relinquish control over <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, under a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> plan for the territory to gain its independence. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has been battling guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> for control of the territory for more than a decade. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> accuses <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s Marxist governmment of harboring and supporing the guerrillas and has frequently sent its troops into southern <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> support anti-communist guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- who have been fighting the government since they were defeated in a civil war by the Marxists after <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> won independence from <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> in November 1975. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is participating in the talks because it has more than 40,000 military personnel in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> helping the government fight the rebels. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has said it would not grant independence to <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> until the Cuban forces are withdrawn. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has administered <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, a former German territory, since the end of World War I under a mandate by the defunct League of Nations. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> repudiated that mandate and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> rejected <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions calling for indpendence and free elections in the territory. <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON> on July 20 called the agreement on principles an important step but said `` there are a great many hard and difficult compromises to be achieved.'' Previous rounds in the talks included sessions in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and a meeting of top military officers from the four sides in the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ArcticSunset     08-01 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Arctic Sunset,0146</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Sunset Harbinger Of Long Night</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BARROW, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the sun sets briefly here Tuesday for the first time in almost three months, it will herald the end of round-the-clock daylight and the onset of long winter darkness. The sun will dip below the horizon at 2:19 a.m. on <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s North Slope and will rise 30 minutes later, the first sunset since May 10, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> station here Summer in <LOCATION> Barrow </LOCATION> and the seven villages in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Slope </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Borough </LOCATION> typically is a time of non-stop outdoor activity. It is not unusual to see children on playgrounds at midnight. Three to four days after that first sunset, the nights will get dark, said the weather service's <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. When the sun sets on Nov. 19, it will not rise here until Jan. 23.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DayCarePolitics Bjt   08-01 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Day Care Politics, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis, Bush Try To Score Points on This Year's Hot Issue: Day
Care</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SECAUCUS, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With a few minutes to spare in a long campaign day, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> stopped by the Harmony Early Learning Center to shake a few hands with preschoolers. Looking to campaign on a tight preconvention budget, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a day later rode out to <ORGANIZATION> Tysons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corner </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> suburbs to do the same thing, tossing a foam ball and pushing youngsters on a tire swing. For both it was time well spent. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was rewarded with prominent photographs in newspapers and the television networks; and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> reaped similar coverage. The twin events on the presidential campaign trail last week underscored what already has become apparent to both campaigns: Child care is a hot issue in the 1988 race for the White House. It's politics dictated by demographics. The <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> says more than half of new mothers go back to work before their children are a year old. Neither party wants to find itself outmaneuvered on the issue. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic nominee, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who will become the Republican nominee in less than three weeks, have introduced competing proposals on day care. The proposals reflect their differing philosophies on government involvement, yet, importantly, both candidates support in principle some form of government initiatives to assist parents in providing care for their young children. `` We can ignore the fact that most women with small children now hold jobs, or we can work to make quality, affordable child care available to every family that needs it,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` You have to have choice, parental choice, family choice, and you have to have diversity,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The vice president's plan is basically a $ 1,000-per-child tax break for low-income parents of children 4 and under. It would cost an estimated $ 2.2 billion a year, and in its first stages would benefit only families earning less than $ 12,000 a year, according to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> domestic affairs adviser <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Steelman </PERSON>. Eventually families earning up to $ 20,000 would benefit. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan generally would exclude the middle-class families that pay $ 100 a week or so to put a child in the centers the two presidential candidates visited last week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' plan, according to his aides, largely is embodied in legislation now before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that is similar to day care assistance being provided in his own state of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. It is aimed at helping low - and moderate-income families afford child care, and would reserve 75 percent of its money for that aid States could use the rest to encourage developing and upgrading centers through grants. It would establish standards for care, and states would have to match a portion of the federal money. `` It is n't just that day care is n't affordable, it's that it is n't available,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Rideout </PERSON>. The legislation would cost an estimated $ 2.5 billion. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has stopped short of committing himself to paying that full amount, instead saying that would be only a goal. `` Until I walk into the office and take a good hard look at the books ... it's impossible to put an exact dollar figure on it,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides fault the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan because it provides money with the filing of tax returns, not when money is spent paying day care bills. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also objects to permitting the tax credit for all who are eligible even if the family keeps the child at home, and he says <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would pile a tax break on top of his proposed cut in capital gains. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> contends, however, that offering the tax break to all families who qualify would help parents who chose to have one spouse stay at home. `` I am absolutely convinced he problem is so big and so diverse that the federal government alone can not have a bricks and mortar child care program that's going to be effective,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CampaignNotebook     08-01 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campaign Notebook,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Seeing Benefits _ and Disadvantages _ of Campaign Life</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOUISVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has drawn some large crowds in the two campaign swings he's taken since leaving <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> as the Democratic presidential nominee. Invariably, he has attracted protesters too. At virtually every stop in his campaign travels, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been confronted by demonstrators, sometimes numbering no more than a dozen, but always vocal. Most carry signs and chant slogans objecting to the right of women to have abortions. Often mixed with them are signs supporting Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, and there are occasional signs attacking <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' record in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, such as the one in <LOCATION> Sturtevant </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, last week that said: `` <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the criminal's choice, go home.'' It referred to the program, since modified, allowing prison furloughs for some convicted murderers in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. The presence of anti-abortion protesters recalls the campaign in 1984 of vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, who faced similar demonstrations at many speeches. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign staffers, many of whom are veterans of the Mondale-Ferraro effort, say they and their candidate are not bothered or surprised by the protesters. `` We expect them at every event,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' senior issues adviser who travels with the candidate The largest gathering, numbering 100 or more, confronted <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as he went to church on Sunday a week ago in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Secaucus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, last week, the dozen or so protesters positioned themselves so close behind the stage that their chants were picked up by the public address system _ and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had to walk right by them as he left. In <PERSON> Sturtevant </PERSON> a day later, a larger group chanted slogans throughout his speech, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> appeared to have been put off his stride by the distraction. Was he rattled? `` Rattled? I did n't feel rattled. Did I look rattled? I did n't feel rattled Did I look rattled? Terribly rattled? `` Let me tell you, If you went through the kind of governorship I went through in the first four years as governor of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, that's a day at the beach,'' added <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He was turned out of office after that turbulent first term, in 1978, then regained it four years later.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' Greek heritage and sometimes bland style prompted humorist <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> to pin the name `` Zorba the clerk'' on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Last week in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> found a phrase on a supporter's placard that he seemed to like better. `` Zeus on the loose,'' it said, in reference to the supreme deity of the ancient Greeks. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked that one out of the crowd as he stood on the platform beginning his speech. `` I do n't know what that means,'' he told the audience. But he said he would tell his wife <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> about it.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Since leaving <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has rarely failed to mention to audiences that 25-year-old snow blower of his. It was first displayed to the nation by cousin <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the actress, in a campaign film aired as part of the Democratic National Convention. It has become, he said, a symbol of the efficient frugality he embodies. Mentioning the snow blower sometimes seemed a bit out of place with the setting as he campaigned in 90 degree and 100 degree temperatures, such as inside the hot <LOCATION> Dorton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arena </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, on Saturday. But he did _ and noted that he not only still has the machine, he still has its owners manual.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 It may not be at the top of most voters' lists of concerns in a president, but journalists always want to know what a new president has in mind for frequency of news conferences. When asked that question in local television interviews in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, `` I would expect two, three, four times a week I would be meeting with the press, taking questions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ConventionBounce     08-01 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Convention Bounce,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Seen as Enjoying Same Convention Bounce as Dukakis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Republican National Convention should help <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cut into <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' advantage in the public opinion polls if historical trends hold up, political analysts say. Several national political pollsters said they expected <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would enjoy a surge in the polls coming out of the Democratic National Convention, and they said that would be in keeping with past post-convention poll trends. But these experts also said that because of this tendency for candidates to get a public opinion lift from all of the exposure, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should be able to use the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> extravaganza in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> Aug. 15-18 to help his standing. While <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could take some solace from such a boost, analysts noted that history often has shown these post-convention spurts to be short-lived. For the moment, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has a commanding lead. He was ahead by 17 percentage points in two polls last week, 18 points in two others. Survey results just before the July 18-22 convention had ranged from a dead heat to a slim <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> lead. But what would have been a remarkable surge any other week was routine by post-convention standards. Conventions traditionally boost the nominee by 10 or more points, mainly because of the intense positive exposure they provide. `` The bounce <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> got seems to be pretty typical of what we've seen in the past three elections,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugick </PERSON>, political poll chief for the <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. `` It would be remarkable if he did n't get a bounce.'' `` The polls are accurate. The question is, are they predictive of what will happen on election day,'' said <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickman </PERSON>, a Democratic pollster. `` There is no question that the race will tighten up.'' If getting the bounce is easy, keeping it is not. Gallup polls in recent elections showed convention surges settling as the campaigns progressed and voters began paying more attention to the issues: _ <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> went from a 17-percentage-point lead over President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> before the 1976 Democratic convention to a 33-point lead after it But within a month his lead was down to 13 points, and he won in November by just 2.1 points. _ In 1980, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went from a 3-point lead over <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> before the Republican convention to a 16-point lead after it A month later it was a tie, though <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went on to win by 9.7 percentage points. _ In 1984, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> moved up from a 14-point deficit before the convention to a 2-point deficit just after it But <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> soon made it back, and won the election by a landslide 18.2 points. With that history in mind, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pollster <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> said he viewed the bounce more as an opportunity than an accomplishment. `` The idea is to work as hard as you can to solidify what you got from the convention,'' he said. Conversely, the bounce puts pressure on the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign to counterpunch effectively at the Republican National Convention this month. If <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> can not match <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' post-convention poll bounce, `` it certainly does not augur well for an election success,'' said <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarrance </PERSON>, a Republican pollster based in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. `` If they do n't bring enough back to cancel out that bounce from the Democrats, then they're digging themselves into a deeper hole,'' Tarrance said. `` They'll have to rely on a more negative campaign,'' a risky fall strategy that could alienate voters. The Republicans' task could be tough. <PERSON> Hickman </PERSON>, the Democratic pollster, said the nominee of the party in power often gains less of a convention boost because he generally is well known and has fewer voters to persuade. <PERSON> Hickman </PERSON> also noted another historical pattern: In eight of the past 10 presidential elections, the summertime leader went on to win. `` You're better off, if you're the candidate who's made the first good impression,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FatalCarCrashes     08-01 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fatal Car Crashes,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Accidents Kill 11, Injure 7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A pickup truck in the wrong lane collided Sunday with a van in a flaming crash that left five people dead and six critically injured in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, and six were killed in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> when a car flew out of control and crashed during a drag race, police said. Police in <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said they were searching for a second car involved in the race about 5:50 p.m. on a one-way, two-lane corridor. In <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, five passengers of the van were dead at the scene, while the four other people in the van and both occupants of the pickup truck were critically injured, police said. The pickup was westbound in the eastbound lane at the time of the collision about 4:45 p.m., police said. The van was knocked backward off the road, then burst into flames, but passersby got four of the occupants out of the vehicle, officials said. The dead were identified as <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Becerra </PERSON>, 26, of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>; his daughter, <PERSON> Julia </PERSON>, no age available; <PERSON> Remundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Erma </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, no ages available; and their son, <PERSON> Hermando </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 10. Also in the van were <PERSON> Ovuula </PERSON> <PERSON> Becerra </PERSON>, 27; <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Becerra </PERSON>, 2; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Becerra </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 1; and <PERSON> Erica </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 7, police and hospital officials said. The occupants of the pickup were identified as driver <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, no age available, and <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Carapia </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Investigators believe the Chevrolet Nova that crashed in <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> went out of control and struck a utility pole, became airborne and hit a tree before landing, officers said. Two people in the car were thrown from the vehicle when it struck the tree, and the car landed on top of them, officers said. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kokomo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, said he was working on a truck parked on the street when the vehicle that crashed missed him by about 3 feet. `` The white car came skidding down the street -LRB- and -RRB- hit the stump on the right side of the road,'' said <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>. `` He took out the pole, he hit the tree, spun around, and I saw people flying.'' The ages and the identities of those killed and the status of the one person injured were not immediately available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-MichiganPrimary     08-01 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Michigan Primary,0743</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Former Michigan Congressmen Out To Defeat Riegle</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Dukakis-Blacks, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF HOLYFIELD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two former Republican congressmen, including one who says that if AIDS is n't `` the wrath of God ... it should be,'' are battling for a chance to topple liberal Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>. But neither <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> has managed to generate much enthusiasm and both are financing their campaigns largely with their own money. In contrast, <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s senior senator, has $ 4 million in campaign funds, wide backing, and a 22-year record in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as he faces Tuesday's Democratic primary unopposed. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> want to make <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>'s liberal voting record the issue, a strategy the 50-year-old <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> likes because he sees that as one of his strong points as he seeks a third six-year term. `` I think the experience that I've developed in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and some of the things we've helped accomplish _ helping the farmers -LRB- hurt by floods -RRB- two years ago, and saving <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> and saving Social Security _ these are all things where I took a leadership role and we got things done,'' he said. He also emphasizes that he's expected to become chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION>, Housing, and <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> if he is re-elected Nov. 8. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> contend <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>'s record, including a 100 percent score in a recent voting survey by the liberal public policy group Americans for Democratic Action, means his views are n't in line with those of most <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> voters. `` He's a big spender. He's voted for cutting defense and for giving up the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, and that turned out to be a big disaster,'' said <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>. `` He's been taking campaign funds from all over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Those are things I think people are going to be pretty fed up with.'' A Detroit Free Press-WXYZ-TV poll released July 18 showed that of the likely <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> voters, 55 percent had n't decided which candidate they would support in the primary. That is reflected in the financing for the two campaigns. Contributions to <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>'s campaign between April 1 and July 13 totaled $ 846. He has loaned his campaign $ 221,000. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> reported contributions of $ 39,283, and has loaned his campaign more than $ 224,000, some of which has been paid back. <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, a conservative making his fourth try for the nomination, has portrayed himself as a staunch <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Republican. Specifically, he's for preserving federal income tax cuts, a strong defense, using more federal muscle in the war on drugs, and against abortion. AIDS came to the fore after <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> mentioned it in a radio interview last week as a subject about which he and his opponent differed. `` I take a reasonable, rational, I think very responsible approach to the problems that face this nation,'' <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said. `` Mr. <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> has said that the reason people have AIDS is the wrath of God, punishment from God'' of homosexuals and drug users. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> does not think AIDS is the wrath of God,'' he said later. <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, asked about <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>'s remarks, said `` I do n't know whether it's the wrath of God, but if it is n't it should be.'' <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, 65, has been the mayor of the <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> suburb of Troy, a state senator and a congressman. He was defeated in a re-election bid in 1974 by now-Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, 44, an East Lansing homebuilder, holds more moderate views. During his term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, 1981-82, <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> supported most of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s tax cut and budget reduction policies, but often opposed the administration on social issues and cuts in aid to college students. Observers favor <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> in the primary because he has the support of most of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> regulars and moderates. The Free Press-WXYZ poll found <PERSON> Huber </PERSON> ahead of <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, 26 percent to 19 percent, but <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>'s lead was within the poll's margin of error of 8.4 percentage points, and both trailed the number undecided. This portion of the July 11-13 telephone survey was conducted among 137 people who described themselves as likely Republican primary voters. Another portion of the poll found <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> had a 51 percent to 19 percent lead over either <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> or <PERSON> Huber </PERSON>, with 30 percent of the voters undecided. That survey of 598 people who described themselves as likely primary voters had a margin of error of 4 percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0039EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-01 0928</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0967</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> says his life is missing something, despite his tremendous success. `` I feel a void. There's not a total emptiness, but I feel something's missing,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said in an interview published in this week's People magazine. `` No matter how much you accomplish, how much money you make, or how many cars or houses you have or how many people you make happy, life is n't perfect for anybody.'' Is it romance that's missing? `` I'm in a cool place right now. I do n't have someone who is my woman,'' said <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, 27. `` I have a couple of friends. That's where I'm at right now. He finds that he and another movie star, <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, face similar problems. `` When I sit back with people like <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>, we can trade stories,'' he said. `` It's like the same identical things happen: the way power isolates you, and everybody tries to get close to you, and the weight of being the patriarch in your family. It's just a bunch of stuff.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer-songwriter <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> is still making money off the <ORGANIZATION> Monkees </ORGANIZATION> hit, `` Daydream Believer,'' which he wrote two decades ago. `` It has kept me alive,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said prior to a weekend engagement here. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>'s song sold 5 million copies and became his signature tune. It also inspired a popular remake by <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> in 1980. The 49-year-old performer still tours much of the year, even though he has n't had a hit since 1979's `` Gold.'' His latest song, `` Runaway Train,'' sung by <PERSON> Rosanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON>, dwells on a relationship clearly out of control. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, a former member of the <ORGANIZATION> Kingston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trio </ORGANIZATION>, has n't had much success with new material. His last album, `` Punch the Big Guy,'' was released in November and sold only 25,000 copies. He blames it on poor promotion and marketing. There may still be another hit for him, though. `` You never know,'' he said. `` No one thought ` Daydream Believer' was going to be a hit.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON> says he is troubled by the stir his forthcoming film, `` The Last Temptation of Christ,'' is creating. An alliance of conservative church groups has objected to the movie's release, with pickets, organized phone and mail protests, demonstrations and threats of a boycott. `` This film for me is like a prayer. It is my way of worshiping,'' <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON>, whose films include `` Raging Bull'' and `` The Color of Money,'' said, according to this week's People magazine. The director told the magazine the idea of making the film touched the roots of his own spirituality and became an obsession that has dogged him throughout his career. In response to the backlash, <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON> offers his view of the movie's message: `` It's about the last battle between God and Satan, and God wins.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOCA RATON, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tennis star <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> and former ski champion <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mill </PERSON> were ending eight-year marriages when they met 19 months ago at a New Year's Eve party in <LOCATION> Aspen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. Now, they have tied the knot `` The last thing we were looking for was another romantic relationship,'' <PERSON> Mill </PERSON> said last week. `` But the old cliche is that when you're looking for love, you never find it.'' On Saturday, <PERSON> Evert </PERSON>, 33, and Mill, 35, exchanged wedding vows in a formal civil ceremony attended by 100 people. `` We're thrilled,'' <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> said. `` It was a very emotional ceremony. We were both crying.'' `` The feeling was just overwhelming,'' <PERSON> Mill </PERSON> said. Among those at the wedding were tennis players <PERSON> Martina </PERSON> <PERSON> Navratilova </PERSON>, <PERSON> Billie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Shriver </PERSON> and <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Turnbull </PERSON>, entertainer <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, body builder <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLish </PERSON> and race-car driver <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The rumpled raincoat is coming back _ not as a fashion trend, just the one worn by that tenacious detective from the 1970s series, `` <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>.'' But like most of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Falk </PERSON> is awaiting the end of the scriptwriters' strike so work can resume on six new episodes. `` I do n't know why people liked -LRB- that character -RRB- so much,'' <PERSON> Falk </PERSON> said during a recent interview at his home. `` I like people that are abstracted, that are preoccupied with something, so they're unaware what they look like,'' he said, referring to the character whose exploits endeared him to millions of TV viewers. `` Without affectation, he's genuinely absorbed by what it is that makes the elevator light go on when you push the button.'' While awaiting the resumption of production, <PERSON> Falk </PERSON> is co-starring as an amiable con man opposite <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauper </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldblum </PERSON> in the comedy movie `` Vibes,'' which opens Friday.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following is moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>COOPERSTOWN, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> slugger <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stargell </PERSON> was thinking about others when he was inducted into baseball's Hall of Fame. `` I did not get to <LOCATION> Cooperstown </LOCATION> without a network of family, coaches, teammates and teachers, you name it,'' <PERSON> Stargell </PERSON> said Sunday as he became the 200th player enshrined at the Hall of Fame. `` I accept this for all the people at the stadiums. The batboys, the groundcrew, announcers and the media.'' In 21 years with <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stargell </PERSON> hit 475 home runs, had 1,540 runs batted in, hit .282 and helped the <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> win the World Series title in 1971 and'79. In the'79 Series, <PERSON> Stargell </PERSON> hit .400 with three homers and was the Most Valuable Player. Sportscaster <PERSON> Lindsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and sports columnist <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> also were honored Sunday during induction ceremonies at the Hall of Fame.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Internment Bjt   08-01 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Internment, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese-American Internees To Get $20,000 Tax-Free Payments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE GOULD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is poised this week to give final approval to legislation providing more than $ 1 billion to Japanese-Americans who were forced from their homes and sent to internment camps during World War II. The House is expected to approve the bill on Wednesday, sending it to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is likely to sign it into law. If all goes according to that schedule, Japanese-Americans who qualify should start getting individual $ 20,000 tax-free payments in about a year. The most elderly will be given priority for the first payments. Enactment of the reparations bill will help end the nearly half-century-old controversy over how the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> treated its Japanese-American population after <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> attacked <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, on Dec. 7, 1941. About 120,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens and resident aliens of <LOCATION> Japanese </LOCATION> descent were singled out _ unlike Americans of German or Italian descent _ and sent to internment camps for the duration of the war. In addition to losing their freedom, some of the internees lost jobs and possessions and were forced to sell homes at below-market prices. In the years immediately after the war, some were reimbursed for direct losses, such as impounded property. But efforts to provide an across-the-board payment were delayed for decades. In 1980, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> authorized a federal Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians to study the issue. In December 1982 it released the results of its investigation, including a recommendation that each camp survivor be given a $ 20,000 tax-free payment, providing they agree to drop all related claims against the government. Earlier this year, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> accepted the recommendations and passed separate but slightly different bills providing for the money. The differences were reconciled, and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last week approved the compromise version without dissent. The House should do the same this week. Once approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the reparations package will go to the president for his signature. <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, deputy White House press secretary, said following <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval that, `` They have improved the bill a lot. A lot of our concerns have been taken care of.'' One of those concerns was over how many years the government would take to make the payments. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a five-year payout; the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> objected, claiming it would cost too much, too soon. As part of the compromise, the government now can take up to 10 years to make the payments, starting in about a year. The <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> proposal also authorizes payments of up to $ 12,000 for surviving members of the <PERSON> Aleut </PERSON> <PERSON> Indian </PERSON> tribes who were removed from the <LOCATION> Aleutian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> during the Japanese attack on those islands in 1942. `` It is most gratifying to me personally to see this long battle for personal justice come to an end at last,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Spark </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, sponsor of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill. The internment camps arose from a 1942 order by President <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> that said the War Department could designate military areas from which people could be excluded. Later military orders resulted in the exclusion of all people of Japanese ancestry from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, and some in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. The orders affected 77,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens and 43,000 legal and illegal resident aliens. All were taken to prison camps in the Western states. The last camp was closed in January 1946. In all, about 120,000 people of Japanese ancestry were detained in the camps, including 77,000 American citizens. An estimated 60,000 are still alive, and the bill would allow them to claim the individual $ 20,000 payments in return for waiving any further wartime claims against the government. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> already has awarded about $ 38 million in restitution payments since the passage of a 1948 Evacuation Claims law. Five years ago, however, a federal commission estimated that Japanese-Americans had suffered losses of up to $ 2 billion that had never been compensated. About 900 Aleuts were moved from their homes and forced to live in abandoned mines, canneries and camps about 2,000 miles away. Lack of medical care and adequate food contributed to disease and death, and many of their homes were destroyed or vandalized in their absence. About 450 Aleuts survive and would be eligible for the $ 12,000 payments. Another $ 20 million would benefit Aleut villages and provide for scholarships and the general welfare of the tribe.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0052EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Powell     08-01 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Powell,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Supreme Court Associate Justice Enjoying Busy Retirement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although he cited age and declining health when he retired from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> one year ago, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> shows little sign of slowing, says one associate. `` His idea of retirement is to stop working at 4 o'clock on Saturday afternoon,'' said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Merhige </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a longtime friend. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who was a <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> lawyer when he was tapped for the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1972 by then-President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, has returned to his hometown and now maintains a modest office in the same building as <PERSON> Merhige </PERSON>. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who also keeps office hours in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, has sat with appellate panels on three occasions since his retirement, and has taught at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>. This spring, he delivered commencement addresses at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, his alma mater. The only sign marking <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>'s office at the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Courthouse is a room number scratched above a door frame. And the interior of his office contains no plaques, citations or personal photographs. `` People wonder why I have such a Spartan office. I love it,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said last week. `` Very few people find me over here, which I regard as a plus.'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, who turns 81 this fall, said he has no regrets about stepping down from the nation's highest court, even though he admits missing the intellectual challenge and the close association with other justices. `` When you reach my ancient age, family is far more important than any of the less personal things that happen to one over a long lifetime,'' he said. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>, have four children and seven grandchildren. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> also describes his health as `` not vigorous.'' Since 1979, he has undergone several operations, including removal of a cancerous prostate in 1985. In June, he was hospitalized for almost a week for treatment of a blood infection. Although his cancer has been in remission, <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said his health prevents him and his wife of 52 years from extensive travel. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> also takes a modest view of his role on the court, although he was often seen during the 1980s as the moderate justice who kept the rest of the court from drifting too far in either direction. And last year, he was described by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> as a more powerful influence on the law than President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> or Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON>. `` If I got into a footnote, I'd be surprised,'' <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. After <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> retired last August, he avoided comment as <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> and <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsburg </PERSON> failed to win <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval as his successor. Eight months later, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> finally won approval. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> refuses to pinpoint blame but strongly denounced the delays in replacing him. `` The disappointment to me was that for the first time in many years, the process was prolonged to the point where it was a disservice to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> itself,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ForestFiresRdp 1stLd-Writethru a0749 08-01 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Forest Fires Rdp, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0749,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rapid City Fire Nearly Out, Fires Slow In Yellowstone</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 2 grafs to UPDATE with Rapid City fire controlled,
add Oregon to list of states. Picks up 3rd graf pvs. Inserts one
graf after 8th graf ``Elsewhere in...' with details. Subs last 2
grafs with 3 grafs to UPDATE Idaho fire and add detail on Oregon
fire.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Yellowstone National Park officials re-opened areas of the park Sunday that had been closed because of forest fires, and firefighters used hand tools to choke the last embers of a controlled fire that destroyed 15 homes at Rapid City, S.D. Crews battled at least four new blazes in two national forests in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, a wilderness fire forced evacuation of a ranger station in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, and firefighters also were at work in the forests of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Fire activity in <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> declined Sunday, said Costa Dillon, fire information officer. That allowed officials to re-open the park's south entrance north of <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, closed one week ago by the 10,100-acre Shoshone fire and the 10,600-acre Red fire. Officials also re-opened the park's <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thumb </LOCATION> area Sunday, closed Saturday when firefighters started controlled burns to remove fuels before the Shoshone fire, which jumped the road from the southern entrance, could reach the area. A controlled burn on the eastern and northeastern edge of the 11,300-acre North Fork fire, which at one point was six miles from the tourist complex at Old Faithful geyser, had worked as planned and flames headed north away from the geyser Sunday, <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. Firefighters completed a containment line around 30 percent of the fire and hoped for full containment by Wednesday, he added. Because the fire was caused by man rather than lightning, firefighters will attempt to control it. The largest fire in the park, the 68,035-acre Clover Mist, did not grow significantly during the weekend, <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. Elsewhere in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, two new fires in the <ORGANIZATION> Bighorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> kept firefighters busy, and crews in the <ORGANIZATION> Targhee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> fought two lightning-caused blazes. The largest had covered 1,260 acres on Medicine Mountain in the Big Horn. A timber fire that burned 3,840 acres in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> on the western edge of <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> over six days was declared controlled Sunday night, as was a 35-acre fire that broke out nearby Saturday. A fire is considered controlled when it is reduced to smoldering patches. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxler </PERSON>, a fire information officer, said about 584 firefighters were at the fire Sunday morning, about half the number there 24 hours earlier. The remaining firefighters worked from the fire line to the center of the burned area with hand tools and other equipment, <PERSON> Waxler </PERSON> said. `` Basically, they're doing things like extinguishing embers and turning over logs to make sure that things are out,'' she said. The Rock Creek fire in the Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness Area of southwestern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> jumped fire lines and covered about 3,000 acres Sunday, said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kendley </PERSON>, fire information officer at the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dispatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>. Although it was in a wilderness area, the fire was being fought because it was man-caused. Late Saturday, smoke from the fire could be seen in <LOCATION> Helena </LOCATION>, more than 100 miles away, he said. In northwestern <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 10 to 15 people were evacuated from a remote ranger station in the <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> Wilderness Area when the Gates fire spread to about 8,000 acres, <PERSON> Kendley </PERSON> said. `` That fire increased 2,000 to 3,000 acres in size'' on Saturday, <PERSON> Kendley </PERSON> said. `` The buildings -LRB- at the station -RRB- have been covered with fireproof tarps, a gravity-feed sprinkler system has been installed on a nearby ridge and personnel and livestock have been evacuated from the station.'' Also in the <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> blaze had grown to 15,000 acres Sunday, he said. In <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, ground crews cleared landing areas for helicopters around the 5,000-acre <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gulch </PERSON> fire so weary firefighters can be flown back and forth from the remote fire line in the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION>. The heliports cut the walk for firefighters from four miles to about a half mile. Containment was expected Monday evening, and by late Sunday a containment line had been thrown around 90 percent of the fire's 10-mile perimeter, forest officials said Firefighters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> continued work Sunday on the 3,600-acre <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> fire along the crest of the <LOCATION> Cascades </LOCATION>, about 12 miles northeast of Mount Rainier National Park, and a smaller burn in the Cascade foothills. A 75-acre fire broke out late Saturday in the <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and and a lightning storm sparked nearly 70 small fires in southern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, forest spokeswomen said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-BeachWaste Bjt   08-01 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beach Waste, Bjt,0937</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gumshoes On Garbage Zero In On Beach-Defiling Wastes</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT DVORCHAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP National Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Lt. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Rossano </PERSON>, one of 13 city sanitation cops, sifts through syringes, blood vials and other disgusting debris, hunting for the culprit who's dumping the infectious medical waste tainting beaches in five states. `` It's like the detective work on a murder case,'' <PERSON> Rossano </PERSON> said. `` We're doing interviews, surveillance, followup, just good old-fashioned police work. We trace every marked item we can.'' These gumshoes of garbage look for names, dates and places so they can zero in on the offending source. But most of the seaborne slop, carried by the whims of tides, currents and winds, either has no markings or waterlogged labels are unreadable. More than 1,000 items of medical waste, most of it syringes used to inject insulin or illegal drugs, have been bagged in an evidence trailer. Under particular scrutiny are people who were caught dumping before. `` There's reason to believe we can identify the bad actors who are illegally dumping,'' said <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sexton </PERSON>, head of the city's <ORGANIZATION> Sanitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> `` It looks like repeated dumping by a smaller user,'' said <PERSON> Marlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Gold </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> Sanitation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s enforcement team of five lawyers, 13 environmental sleuths and 10 extra officers. `` I do n't think we're looking at large hospitals. There's no indication of wholesale dumping,'' she said. `` It's just very hard to reconstruct what must have happened. It's very hard to trace this material. We're looking for people who have no regard for the way they handle waste.'' State and federal authorities are also part of the investigation. This summer's floating filth first came ashore July 6 on a <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> beach. Also contaminated are beaches in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. The refuse is mostly unmarked needles and vials, several of which tested positive for AIDS antibodies and hepatitis B virus. Other items included stained bandages, catheter bags, colostomy bags, respirator parts, prescription bottles, plastic tubing for intravenous drugs, rubber gloves and nine dead rats. Infectious medical wastes, treated like industrial trash, are supposed to be placed in red bags to alert handlers of the contents. No red bags have washed ashore. State investigators believe the rubbish may have come from several sources: illegal dumpers, runoff from city storm sewers, wind-swept garbage barges or sloppy handling of trash at city landfills. `` The evidence does not point to a single incident or a single event as a ` smoking gun,''' said R.W. <PERSON> Groneman </PERSON>, spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION>, which has 10 environmental police on the case. `` It's a big ocean,'' <PERSON> Groneman </PERSON> said. `` The midnight dumpers, the people who might deliberately dump this stuff, do n't necessarily leave calling cards or identifying marks.'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> generates 1.8 million pounds of red bag waste each week, 45 percent of which comes from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Most of it is incinerated on the spot or taken out of state for disposal. <PERSON> Groneman </PERSON> said the items scoured from hundreds of miles of beaches would fill six shopping bags. `` We're not talking about wave upon wave of red bag waste,'' he said. <PERSON> Groneman </PERSON> says that needles flushed down toilets by diabetics and junkies may have been carried out to sea during a heavy rain that overloaded the city's sewers. Other officials say beach debris may be inevitable. `` From this whole episode, we now understand that needles on the beach are part of the ecology of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> Health Commissioner. Some seemingly promising clues have washed out. A prescription bottle was traced to an upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> man, and hopeful authorities thought they could find who handled his trash. But the man said he lost his pills on a fishing trip at sea. `` You get very excited when you see something with markings on it. You figure you can trace it and get to the bottom of this thing. But there are a lot of false leads,'' said Gold. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyko </PERSON> heads a team of 13 lawyers and 25 investigators who drive along back roads trailing garbage trucks, videotaping work at garbage transfer stations and combing through litter. `` We are going to nail people for deliberate dumping,'' said <PERSON> Lyko </PERSON>, head of the state's task force on environmental protection. Ocean experts say the trash may have washed out to sea from any number of inlets, then sloshed back to a different shore. `` The tides along the <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seaboard </LOCATION> carry things in and out. Once it goes out, it mixes. You do n't know which inlet it came from,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>. `` Winds, currents, rain and tide all impact on what's moving in and out.'' In <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, authorities say they have no doubt where unwelcome litter originated. They had 75 pieces of trash, including a prescription bottle from a woman in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and a sign they believe belongs to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rhode </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> computer model of winds, currents and tides during the last 30 days indicated the garbage came from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> DiOrio </PERSON>, an aide to Gov. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> DiPrete </PERSON>. `` It is all leading us back to the same general area _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> DiOrio </PERSON>, head of the state's <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Medical Wastes. `` This is a great warning to all of us. We better be aggressive in protecting our shoreline.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880801-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-01-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-TheEiger Bjt   08-01 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Eiger, Bjt,0755</SECOND>
<HEAD>Climber Recalls Travails of Eiger's North Face 50 Years Later</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA WATSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRINDELWALD, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
