<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Guam-Dems     04-24 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guam-Dems,170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guam To Send Uncommitted Delegation to Democratic Presidential
Convention</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AGANA, Guam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats in this <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territory decided Sunday to send an uncommitted delegation to the national convention in an attempt to have more political clout when the party selects its presidential nominee. `` The idea behind our uncommitted stance was to allow the <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> delegation to discuss Guam issues so more people could become aware of what we want,'' <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggerty </PERSON>, vice chairman of the party's delegate selection committee, said Sunday following the party's Topping the list of concerns in the territory's effort to become a commonwealth of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Party members selected six delegates, each of whom will cast -LCB- vote for a total of three votes. One member of the delegation is former territorial Gov. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>, who was unseated in 1986 after he was indicted for accepting bribes in exchange for government contracts. He was later convicted, but remains free pending appeal in federal courts. <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>'s wife, territorial Sen. <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>, also was selected as a delegate. Most of the other delegates are former members of <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>'s cabinet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SAfrica-US     04-24 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-US,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Television Denounces U.S. Media</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A program Sunday on government-run television accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> news media of `` bias, hostility and missionary zeal'' in its reporting on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The 30-minute South African <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> program said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> media focused only on violence and black-white confrontation, ignoring positive developments. The program included interviews with officials from such <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> groups as the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Hoover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>. No journalists working for American news organizations in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> appeared on the program. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> media simply are not going to give a fair shake to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rusher </PERSON>, publisher of the conservative <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> journal <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. Program narrator <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON> said many foreign television organizations `` dash into <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, shoot a documentary in frantic haste, then dash home to tell a story which in no way reflects insight into the South African situation.'' The three largest American televison networks, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, all have permanent bureaus in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` But ignorance and haste are only part of the problem,'' <PERSON> Saunders </PERSON> said. `` Outright bias, hostility and a missionary zeal to discredit South African conditions are widespread.'' The program did not cite any inaccuracies reported in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> media and mentioned only two American news organizations by name, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. It showed brief footage from black townships that appeared in the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> documentary, `` Children of Apartheid.'' The program aired in December. Minister of Home Affairs <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> called the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> program a `` blatant distortion that should be condemned with the contempt it deserves.'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and his department monitor the South African and foreign news media under the nationwide state of emergency in effect since June 1986. The restrictions prevent journalists from reporting disturbances, security force actions and most forms of protest. All of the Americans interviewed agreed that the media crackdown has reduced <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> television coverage of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` The government has been remarkably effective in pushing <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> off the -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- evening news,'' said <PERSON> Stanford </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungar </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Marcos     04-24 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Marcos,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aquino Says Marcos Not Welcome</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said Sunday she has no intention of allowing former President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return to the country. `` I just want our people to know and to reassure them that I will never do anything that will go against the interests of the Filipino people,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said during her weekly radio program `` Ask the President.'' She was responding to two women callers who said they were disappointed that she had sent emissaries early this year to meet with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has been living in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> since his regime toppled by a February 1986 revolt that swept <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power. One of the women said she was disappointed because of reports that government representatives were negotiating with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> for his possible return. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s spokesmen had earlier denied the reports. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> last week that negotiations with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s government were continuing and he was told he could return in two months to act as government adviser. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said she sent two of her relatives to meet with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> last January and February because she had heard his health was `` really deteriorating very fast'' and that he had a message for her. `` My directions to my relatives ... were very clear _ just to listen to what Mr. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> had to say,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> said. `` Never did I say that he could come back or that I wanted him to advise me and help me -LRB- find -RRB- the solutions to our problems. `` I think you also heard me say in the past that many of our problems were caused in fact by Mr. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>,'' the president added. Government officials have said Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> does not want <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return because his followers still are capable of plots to destabilize the government. Meanwhile, two gunmen fatally shot a bodyguard of the mayor of suburban <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> early Sunday outside the mayor's home, police said. Police quoted witnesses as saying the assailants shouted `` do n't interfere, we're the <ORGANIZATION> NPA </ORGANIZATION>,'' referring to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Communist rebels have been waging a 19-year insurgency. The victim, <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Abratique </PERSON>, was the second bodyguard of Mayor <PERSON> Jejomar </PERSON> <PERSON> Binay </PERSON> slain in the past week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 2ndLd-Writethru a0812 04-24 1168</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0812,1100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis, Jackson Spar Over Providing Budget Figures</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 3 grafs after 14th graf pvs bgng, `Jackson's
delegate,' to UPDATE with Guam Democrats sending uncommitted
delegates to convention; PICKS UP 16th graf pvs bgng, `Curt
Clinkscales'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Sunday he would be willing to talk with those holding <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and suggested that he would be more effective in winning their freedom that would his Democratic presidential rival, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has refused as a matter of policy to negotiate with hostage-takers. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he would be willing to talk to anyone _ including the kidnappers. `` In this world, in this ambiguous world, you must not set up preconditions that stop effectiveness,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said at a rally in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I would meet with anyone I could meet with to get the hostages out of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s remarks came in the final weekend of the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary campaign, as he and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> set aside their best-friends campaign style. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> rejected as `` absurd'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s suggestion that he offer specific budget figures for programs he favors. Both candidates sounded jobs themes as they campaigned in this industrial state. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> talked about steel industry jobs and economic development during a whistle-stop train trip through the western half of the state. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spent the night with an unemployed steelworker and his family in <LOCATION> Aliquippa </LOCATION>, preached at a local church and met with paperworkers in <LOCATION> Lock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION> before flying to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is considered a sure bet to win most of the 178 Democratic convention delegations at stake in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s best chance to make an impression would be in the non-binding preference vote that also will be part of Tuesday's ballot With 78 Republican delegates also at stake, Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should reach the 1,139 total he needs to clinch the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> presidential nomination with a majority of the delegates to the Republican National Convention in August in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. `` Vote 12 times for <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' said fliers being distributed to Democratic voters in the state's 2nd Congressional District. That appeal was not an invitation to vote fraud, but an effort to help voters understand the long and complex ballot that will confront them Tuesday. Democratic voters will elect delegates identified as supporters of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. For Republicans the task is even more difficult since the ballot will not identify the presidential preference of delegate candidates. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign was spending $ 25,000 on radio commercials that begin: `` On April 26 in the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary, one vote for <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wo n't be enough. If you want to help send <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> to the White House, you've got to vote for all the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> delegates in our area.'' The <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign also was distributing fliers explaining to voters what they must do to support the former civil rights activist. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s delegate strength is concentrated in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> where the vast majority of the state's black voters live. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is expected to win most of the delegates in other parts of the state. Meanwhile, Democrats in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> territory of <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> decided Sunday that its six delegates _ representing three votes at the national convention _ will remain uncommitted in an attempt to have more political clout. `` The idea behind our uncommitted stance was to allow the <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> delegation to discuss Guam issues so more people could become aware of what we want,'' <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggerty </PERSON>, vice chairman of the party's delegate selection committee, said Sunday following the party's The <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> delegation includes former territorial Gov. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordallo </PERSON>, who was convicted of accepting bribes in exchange for government contracts but remains free pending appeal in federal courts. While <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> battled for Democratic delegates in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, conservative Republicans were trying to influence <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of a running mate. <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinkscales </PERSON>, a conservative activist, has formed an unauthorized committee to raise money to promote former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON> as the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Salter </PERSON>, a spokesman for Mrs. <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, said, `` She believes the decision on the vice president should be solely that of Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' The former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador, a favorite of conservatives because of her hardline views on foreign policy, briefly considered getting into the presidential race, but finally decided against it. <PERSON> Clinkscales </PERSON> said he has raised $ 100,000 and collected the names of 1,400 volunteers. Through most of the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> campaign, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> avoided any criticism of each other, concentrating instead on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Their nice-guy approach was strained slightly Saturday night when they debated in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> chided <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for failing to attach price tags to his proposals. `` I'm not just for <ORGANIZATION> Head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Start </ORGANIZATION>, I'm willing to pay for Head Start,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said during the debate. `` I have put numbers together to pay for my dreams.'' After the debate, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had failed `` to answer the budget question. ... I know it's good to project for a national health care plan, which I support. But it will cost.'' `` I do n't know what he's trying to do,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Sunday when asked about the pressure from <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to come up with budget figures. `` You ca n't prepare a budget now for next year,'' he told reporters on his campaign train. `` That's absurd.'' On the hostage question, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> criticized <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' stance that terrorists should not be negotiated with. `` I've raised the point in several debates this year,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` Every time a question comes up about terrorism, Mr. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says: ` I'm against terrorism ... We should not negotiate with terrorists. In the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, never negotiate with terrorists. Be tough.''' `` I disagree with that,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> went on. `` If I could get those hostages out, I would bring them back home.'' He said making a deal with kidnappers would be no worse than dealing with the likes of Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` We say now if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> will come out of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, we'll send him to another country. That's a concession ... But the fact is, the object must be to free Americans who are held hostage in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' Nine Americans are believed held by kidnappers in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. They are: <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON>; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>; <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>; <ORGANIZATION> Edward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Austin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tracy </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Polhill </PERSON>; <PERSON> Alann </PERSON> <PERSON> Steen </PERSON> and Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spent Saturday night with 35-year-old <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Cafrelli </PERSON> and his wife and five children. After working 13 years at <ORGANIZATION> LTV </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cafrelli </PERSON> was laid off in 1985. He said he got a call Saturday asking if he'd be willing to have <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a house guest for one night. `` I was in a daze, in a dream,'' he said. The next morning, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> sat with Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON> Cafrelli </PERSON> at the kitchen table in their two-story frame house and had a breakfast scrambled eggs, bacon and sausage. Then he preached at the local Methodist church.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0005EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MissingFamily     04-24 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Family,0349</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bodies of Mother, Two Sons Found in Desert</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BARSTOW, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bodies of a missing woman and her two sons were found Saturday in a desert wash more than a week after they disappeared, but officials said there was no evidence of foul play. The bodies of <PERSON> Penny </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, 26 and her 3-month-old son, <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> were spotted at 8:45 a.m. Saturday by <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's officials in a helicopter, Deputy <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Valencia </PERSON> said. The body of 4-year-old <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> was found about eight hours later, following an intensive search in driving, wind-whipped rain with temperatures in the low 40s, <ORGANIZATION> Valencia </ORGANIZATION> said. About 70 people using aircraft, horses, 4-wheel-drive vehicles and motorcyles searched the remote desert area until they found the boy's body about a mile south of his brother and mother. `` It looks like <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> turned around and headed back towards the car,'' <ORGANIZATION> Valencia </ORGANIZATION> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and the boys were reported missing on April 13. The woman and her husband, <PERSON> John </PERSON>, had argued in the morning before she drove away with the boys, authorities said. `` We have no indication that there was a physical fight,'' <ORGANIZATION> Valencia </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> reported his wife and children were missing after Mrs. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> failed to pick up her 6-year-old daughter from school. The <LOCATION> Barstow </LOCATION> woman's car was found on April 20, stuck in soft sand on an electrical company service road about 15 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Barstow </LOCATION>. Footprints led into the desert. The woman was wearing jeans and a shirt and was barefoot when she left. The boys were in their pajamas. `` They were not dressed for the weather,'' <ORGANIZATION> Valencia </ORGANIZATION> said. `` Even if someone were dressed for it, you could n't stay out there that long.'' The mother and children, who were identified Saturday by a deputy coroner, were found about 10 miles from the car. But coroner's officials refused to comment on how long the three had been dead or what caused their deaths. Autopsies had yet to be scheduled, <ORGANIZATION> Valencia </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Weld-Corruption     04-24 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weld-Corruption,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Resigning Justice Department Official Calls For Anti-Corruption
Fight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, one of two top <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials who recently resigned, says federal laws should be revised to make it easier to charge state and local public officials with corruption and to include <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> members under all anti-corruption laws. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, who resigned March 29 as head of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s criminal division, said in the opinion section column in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday that he would not discuss the reasons for his departure after two years in the department led by embattled Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> He wrote that the nation greatly underrates public corruption as a political and economic problem in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and said that corruption is a weed that will grow fast if left unattended, so legislation at the federal level is necessary. `` I, for one, believe that the federal government must take an active role in the fight against public corruption at all levels,'' he said. At a White House meeting on Wednesday, <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> and resigning Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> painted a picture of a crippled department and an attorney general wracked by legal troubles, according to sources familiar with the half-hour meeting with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Sources said <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> told the president that, if it were up to him, he would seek an indictment against <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> who has been the subject of a lengthy investigation by an independent counsel. In the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> column, <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> said there must be a federal anti-corruption law to overcome the effects of last year's <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision which limited the ability of federal prosecutors to charge local officers with abuses of public trust. `` Another welcome step would be to apply all existing anti-corruption statutes to members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said, noting that only members of the executive branch and independent agencies are prohibited from supplementing their salaries with fees and honoraria for job-related activities. <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> said he found attractive the proposal to raise the salary of all members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to between $ 150,000 and $ 175,000 while prohibiting all honoraria. `` One big gain would be ruling out the possibility that fees or honoraria would influence a legislator's sense of priorities, let alone his or her vote,'' <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> wrote. `` Moreover, if members did not have to scramble to suport their families and two residences, they would have more time to devote to the public's business. `` Those higher salaries might also attract to the national legislature at least some able women and men who would not otherwise be able to make the sacrifice,'' he said. `` We should cleanse the system so as to attract them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PeelAcquitted 2ndLd-Writethru a0665 04-24 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peel Acquitted, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0665,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peel Acquitted in 8 Fishing Boat Killings in 1982</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS detail, background, quotes.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SUE CROSS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A boat builder was acquitted on Saturday for the second time of charges that he killed eight people aboard a fishing vessel in 1982, ending the longest and most expensive criminal case in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> history. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Peel </PERSON>, 27, broke into tears and his family cheered when the jury announced its decision in <ORGANIZATION> Juneau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. He had been charged in the killing of eight peope aboard the fishing vessel Investor, which burned near <LOCATION> Craig </LOCATION> in September 1982. `` It's terrible being an innocent man accused of a crime,'' said Peel, of <LOCATION> Bellingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> `` I just thank God it's over. Justice did work this time.'' It was Peel's second trial on eight counts of murder and one count of arson. The first ended in a hung jury in <LOCATION> Ketchikan </LOCATION> in 1986. Peel, a boat builder who once was a crew member on the Investor, was accused of killing skipper <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Coulthurst </PERSON>, his wife, <PERSON> Irene </PERSON>, two Coulthurst children and four teen-age crew members. He was not arrested until two years after the crime. Prosecutor <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, who handled both trials, told jurors the state had bungled the Investor investigation, had no motive and no physical evidence against Peel. But <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> contended the prosecution could prove its case based on witnesses who said they saw Peel near the Investor around the time of the killings and in the fishing vessel's skiff after the larger boat was found burning in a cove. Peel was working on another nearby fishing boat at the time. The state spent $ 2 million on the investigation and on Peel's first trial, which took six months The state budgeted $ 700,000 for the three-month retrial. It has been the longest and most expensive criminal case in the state's history. Jury deliberations began Wednesday evening. The jury forewoman said members of the panel had agreed not to talk to reporters. Peel had been in his parents' custody on a $ 1 million property bond since his arrest. His mother said the family will return to <LOCATION> Bellingham </LOCATION> `` as fast as we can get there.'' Defense attorney <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Weidner </PERSON> said the family is considering a lawsuit to seek restitution for the `` years of horror,'' but declined to say who might be the target of such a suit. <PERSON> Weidner </PERSON> contends if the first trial in <LOCATION> Ketchikan </LOCATION> had been handled correctly, Peel would have been acquitted there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Attacks     04-24 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Attacks,0247</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Gunmen Slain In Attack On Governor</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Armed men ambushed a car carrying a provincial governor, but security guards killed three of the attackers in a gun battle, the military said Sunday. Zambales provincial Gov. <PERSON> Amor </PERSON> <PERSON> Delos </PERSON> and his party were driving to <PERSON> Delos </PERSON>' home Saturday when they were ambushed by five gunmen outside of <LOCATION> Botolan </LOCATION> town, 80 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, a military report from <LOCATION> Zambales </LOCATION> said. The governor's bodyguards engaged the ambushers in a brief gunfight. Three attackers were killed, including a former policeman who had deserted his post in neighboring <LOCATION> Pampanga </LOCATION> province, the report said. There were no casualties in the governor's party, it said. The report gave no motive for the attack. Meanwhile, military officials said communist rebels on Saturday shot and killed two soldiers, a militiaman and their two civilian boatmen as the group was patrolling a river in the <LOCATION> Pampanga </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Macabebe </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> province, about 60 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas commandeered a bus and two jeeps Saturday and used them to attack a Philippine Constabulary patrol base near the town of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION>, 80 miles northeast of the capital. Two soldiers were wounded in the fighting and the rebels fled on foot toward nearby mountains after burning the camp and taking an unspecified number of firearms, a military report said. It mentioned no casualties n the rebel side. Communists rebels have been waging a 19-year-old insurgency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Rich     04-24 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Rich,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Silent Screen Actress Irene Rich Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, who played <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' nagging wife in several films before becoming a popular radio star with the `` Dear John'' program during World War II, died of heart failure at age 96. `` She just wore out. She was delightful and beautiful and enchanting up to the last,'' her daughter, <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, said Saturday. Miss <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> died at her Hope Ranch home on Friday. Born <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, the actress appeared in 100 films from 1918 through 1942. She performed regularly with the <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Grape </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juice </ORGANIZATION> radio variety show on CBS and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> between 1933 and 1945 and appeared more than 5,000 times in the touring playlet, `` Ask Your Wife.'' Her career began in short silent films opposite <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> and she continued with him, usually playing his nagging wife, in such talkies as `` They Had to See <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>,'' `` So This is <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'' and `` Down to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> later referred to <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> as his `` reel'' wife. During World War II, her rendition of `` Dear John'' letters on the <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>'s radio program made the term a catch-phrase for disastrous letters from home. In the 1920s and early 1930s, she was a star at <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studio </ORGANIZATION>, appearing in 21 films, including the original productions of three classics: `` Lady Windemere's Fan'' in 1925, `` <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>'s Wife'' in 1928; and `` The Champ'' in 1931 She is survived by two daughters; two grandsons; and three great-grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneDown     04-24 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Down,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed in Single-Engine Airplane Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men were killed Saturday after their homemade single-engine airplane crashed in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> about four miles south of <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vicente </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> official said. An off-duty <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fire paramedic saw the plane dive into the waters off the <LOCATION> Palos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verdes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION> about 3 p.m. and alerted the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, Petty Officer <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said. The pilot was identified as <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Reddick </PERSON>, 43, of <LOCATION> Lomita </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said. The passenger's name was being withheld until relatives could be notified. A <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter, a 41-foot patrol boat and an airplane joined in the search for the plane, which flew out of the <LOCATION> Compton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` The plane is described as a two-seater, home-built aircraft; asingle-engine <PERSON> Thorp </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> said. A <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> official said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> probably would investigate the accident because it involved a homemade aircraft. Weather did not seem to play a part in the crash, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. Weather during the search was partially cloudy with no rain, <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0413EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-NationAtRisk Bjt 1stLd-Writethru 04-24 1093</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nation At Risk, Bjt, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0527,1120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Schools Have Reformed, But Have They Improved?</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New material adds contents of report, edits thruout.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With BC-School Reform, moved in advance as b0749-750 as part of
the AP Newsfeatures budget</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five years after a searing report called `` A Nation At Risk'' warned that American education was sinking beneath `` a rising tide of mediocrity,'' Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> says, `` we are still at risk.'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> in a new report said after five years of education reform efforts and higher spending, the nation's public schools have improved only marginally, the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. `` Too many American students are not now getting the education they deserve,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> wrote in the study requested by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. He said student achievement continues unacceptably low. The administration will mark the fifth anniversary of `` A Nation At Risk'' on Tuesday at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> when <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> will give President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> his own assessment of how the schools are performing. The Bennett report said $ 56 billion more has been spent on public schools over the past five years and while there has been some progress, the improvement is `` at a disappointingly slow pace and still at excessively low levels of achievement.'' The education secretary lashed at teacher unions and other education organizations, saying their `` narrow, self-interested exercise of political power'' threatens school reform efforts. `` Whenever a worthwhile school proposal or legislative initiative is under consideration, those with a vested interest in the educational status quo will use political muscle to block reform,'' he wrote. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> added, `` And too often the anti-reformers succeed. If our schools are to improve, that power must be overcome.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> will mark the anniversary with a protest Tuesday in <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> across the street from the White House. The union president, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON>, has charged school reform is `` withering on the vine'' due to lack of federal funds. An NEA flyer promoting the rally bears the headline: `` 1983: A Nation At Risk. 1988: An Administration Asleep.'' The first wave of school reforms involved top-down efforts by states to mandate stiffer course requirements and to impose tougher licensing requirements on teachers. The stick of accountability was often coupled with the carrot of big pay increases. Teacher salaries have climbed 35 percent since 1983, from an average of $ 20,693 to roughly $ 28,000. More recently, the push has been toward bottom-up reforms aimed at giving local teachers and school administrators more freedom to chart their own path toward better schools. A 1986 Carnegie task force laid the groundwork for creating a private, non-profit <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teaching </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standards </ORGANIZATION>, but it is still several years away from figuring out how to recognize outstanding teachers. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> proposes a common academic curriculum for all students, more difficult course content and more challenging instruction in the lower grades and for minority and disadvantaged students. He also suggests changes in state rules to allow those without education degrees to become teachers and school principals. Some experts echo <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s criticism that school reforms have had little impact on the worst problems. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> of the States, 45 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> have raised graduation standards since 1980. In 1987, the average high school student had to take nearly 20 units of credit to graduate, up from 17 in 1980. But such groups as the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Teaching and the <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> have concluded school reforms have had little or no impact on urban schools. The <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, led by top business executives, said, `` Recent reform efforts have largely bypassed the problems of the educationally disadvantaged _ the 30 percent of children facing major risk of educational failure and lifelong dependency.'' The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching said last month, `` The harsh truth is that the reform movement has largely bypassed our most deeply troubled schools.'' It said such prescriptions as more homework, more testing and more requirements for graduation were `` irrelevant to many children _ largely black and Hispanic _ in our urban schools.'' <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanker </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` There's no evidence that reform is working for any of our kids, except for maybe the 20 percent who have always made it in the traditional school system.'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Honig </PERSON>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s superintendent of public instruction, offers a far more upbeat view of what has happened since `` A Nation At Risk.'' <PERSON> Honig </PERSON> said <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> students are scoring higher on the Scholastic Aptitude Test as well as state exams and thousands more are taking three years of math and science. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> students passed 41,000 College Board Advancement Placement exams last year, up 73 percent from 1984. `` It has worked for many kids in inner cities. They're taking harder courses,'' said <PERSON> Honig </PERSON> and there has has been no jump in dropout rates, as some had feared. `` I'm not saying we're anywhere near where we have to be, but we're on the right track,'' said <PERSON> Honig </PERSON>. The original `` Nation At Risk'' report was the work of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Excellence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, a panel of 18 citizens appointed by then-Secretary of Education T.H. Bell in August 1981 to address `` the widespread public perception that something is seriously remiss in our educational system.'' The commission, headed by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, called its provocative report an open letter to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people. `` The educational foundations of our society are presently being eroded by a rising ride of mediocrity that threatens our very future as a nation and a people,'' it said. `` If an unfriendly foreign power had attempted to impose on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> the mediocre educational performance that exists today, we might well have viewed it as an act of war.'' The commission recommended a longer school-year, competitive `` performance-based'' salaries for teachers, and minimum high school graduation standards of four years of English, three years each of math, science and social studies and a half-year of computer science. The commission members, but not <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, all have been invited to the White House for Tuesday's ceremony. <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, in his memoirs, `` The Thirteenth Man,'' accused <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> of neglecting school reform after the 1984 election. In a recent interview, <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> said, `` We're doing a better job of educating the top 60 to 70 percent. ... -LRB- But -RRB- we've made no progress with respect to this bottom 30-40 percent _ the dropouts, minorities. `` The big push for school reform did n't do a darn thing to solve that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0415EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-AfghanGuerrillas 1stLd-Writethru   04-24 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghan Guerrillas, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0571,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrillas Take Strategic Garrison</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 4th graf pvs, ``There was...'' with Najib confirming
capture; recasts 5th graf to conform; picks up 6th graf pvs: The
guerrillas...</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Afghanistan, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PESHAWAR, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Afghan rebels stormed and captured a strategic Soviet-Afghan garrison and opened a new, direct supply route for weapons, rebel spokesmen said Saturday. They said the garrison at <LOCATION> Barikot </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s northeast <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION> province, fell Friday at 1 p.m. after a four-month siege. Shortly before that, helicopters airlifted about five infantry and commando battalions, including a handful of Soviet advisers, from the installation, the rebels said. In <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> confirmed Sunday that guerrillas had captured the post, but he refused to call it a defeat. He characterized it as a `` change of positions of the army forces.'' The capture is a major victory for the anti-communist guerrillas fighting the Soviet-backed government. It opens a new supply route over the Pakistani border for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> and other Western weapons. The guerrillas said the operation was led by Commander <PERSON> Rahmatullah </PERSON> of the Hezb-I-Islami <LOCATION> Khalis </LOCATION> faction. <PERSON> Rahmatullah </PERSON> sent a radio message to guerrilla headquarters in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> saying the transmission was coming from inside Barikot. Before being airlifted, communist forces blew up a major ammunition dump inside the garrison, apparently to reduce the guerrilla's war booty, the spokesmen said. They said Soviet and Afghan jetfighters made high-altitude bombing raids while helicopter gunships escorted transport copters in and out of the garrison. Dozens of houses were destroyed in the air raids. One report said the garrison and a neighboring village were still being bombed Saturday afternoon. Rebel spokesman <PERSON> Qariburahman </PERSON> <PERSON> Saeed </PERSON> said Soviet-Afghan forces were trying to destroy <PERSON> Barikot </PERSON> rather than let it remain in guerrilla hands. He said 17 rebels had been killed and 16 wounded in the operation, but had no casualty figures for Soviet-Afghan troops. The attack on Barikot garrison is one of a dozen major military operations carried out by the guerrillas against the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government since the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> signed an agreement in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> April 14 to withdraw an estimated 115,000 Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. The guerrillas, who were not direct party to the accord, have vowed to continue fighting until the communist government is overthrown. The Soviets intervened in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in December 1979. Barikot lies just inside the Afghan border with northern <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. For the guerrillas, the capture of Barikot would open a major supply route from <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s border town of <LOCATION> Arando </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>'s northeastern province of <LOCATION> Nuristan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Arando </PERSON> is separated from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> Kunar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is a staging area for the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance, although <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> has pledged in the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> accord to stop serving as an arms conduit when the agreement goes into effect on May 15.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0422EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BabyMissing     04-24 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Baby Missing,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baby Reported Missing From Hospital, Feared Abducted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 4-month-old baby disappeared from The Children's Hospital of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> after a visit Saturday from a woman who said she was an aunt, police said. The woman was being sought for questioning, police Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Apeldorn </PERSON> said. `` We believe she did leave the area with the child, but we do n't have any witnesses,'' <PERSON> Apeldorn </PERSON> said Hospital officials said <PERSON> LaShae </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherry </PERSON>, the daughter of 18-year-old <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherry </PERSON>, had been at the hospital since Monday for treatment of pneumonia and diarrhea. <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor, said the woman who visited <PERSON> LaShae </PERSON> did n't seem suspicious. `` She came into the room where the child was, approached her knowingly and talked with her, played with her and ... picked her up after that and took her for a walk,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> said. The infant was described as black, 27 inches long, weighing 10 pounds, with a birthmark on her right cheek.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0448EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel-Unrest     04-24 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Unrest,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Relaxes Travel Ban In Occupied Lands</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The army on Sunday lifted a four-day ban that had barred Palestinians in occupied territories from traveling to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, a military spokesman said. It also permitted tankers to supply gas stations in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> for the first time in more than a month. Soldiers lifted a six-day curfew in more than a dozen towns and refugee camps on Sunday, permitting thousands of Arabs to reach their jobs in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, the spokesman said. But the military said curfews would be imposed for a seventh straight day on three towns in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and a refugee camp in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> in an effort to quell unrest that has followed the April 16 assassination of <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON> at his home in a <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> suburb. Underground leaders of the Palestinian uprising had called for a `` Day of Rage'' in the occupied territories Saturday to mark a week since <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>'s death. A paramilitary border policeman shot and killed a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> man Saturday who attacked him with an ax during a protest in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village of <LOCATION> Qabatiya </LOCATION>, the army said without identifying the dead man. The death brought to 172 the number of Arabs killed since the uprising began 19 weeks ago. An Israeli teen-ager and an army soldier also have been slain.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0606EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-India-Punjab     04-24 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-India-Punjab,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sikh Gunmen Kill 13; Police Emergency In Punjab</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen believed to be Sikh militants shot and killed 13 people in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> on Sunday, prompting a police alert across the northern Indian state, news reports and police said. Sunday's slayings brought the death toll blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> radicals to at least 30 since Friday. The killings also triggered tightened security measures in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, where police began checking vehicles. Several road blocks were erected in the city of six million people. `` We have reports that Sikh terrorists may try to create public disorder in the capital, hence the measure,'' said an officer at the police control center. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said that suspected Sikh militants shot and killed 13 people, including a <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> woman in six separate attacks in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state on Sunday. Among the dead were seven Sikhs and three Hindus. No other details were available. Sikh radicals, who are campaigning for an independent homeland in their rich farming state, were blamed for 12 deaths in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> on Friday. On Saturday, five more people died in Sikh radical attacks. The latest killings raised to 807 the number of deaths blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state since the start of the year. Sikh militants have been waging a guerrilla war since 1982 for more political economy or an independent homeland in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0846EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-GulfRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0695 04-24 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Gulf Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0695 ,0548</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iranian Attacker Hits, Damages Saudi Ship</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS thruout with Captain's report, missile slipping
overboard, DELETES references to machine gun fire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An Iranian gunboat rocketed a Saudi Arabian-owned tanker in the Strait of Hormuz Sunday, hours after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> warned <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to stop attacking neutral ships in the region, <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> shipping sources said. The tanker, which sustained minor damage, made for the southern port of <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION> with an unexploded rocket hanging from its punctured site. But the captain said that the missile fell overboard when the tanker docked. He reported no explosion. Gulf-based shipping executives, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the 37,011-ton Sea Trader was approached by a swarm of six gunboats as it sailed northward through the strait, gateway to the gulf. But they said only one Iranian boat took part in the attack. The tanker's Indian skipper, Capt. B.R. <PERSON> Pagarkar </PERSON>, reported that his ship was only slightly damaged with no casualties among his Indian crew, the officials said. The shipping officials quoted <PERSON> Pagarkar </PERSON> as saying he saw six speedboats heading in his direction as the tanker was entering the gulf to take on a cargo of oil at the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> port of <PERSON> Ras </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanura </PERSON>. `` Five then went in one direction, while one appeared to be heading for another tanker, and I thought we'd escaped an attack. But suddenly, it veered toward my ship,'' <PERSON> Pagarkar </PERSON> said. The Iranians demanded the Sea Trader's destination and were preparing to board, when `` suddenly, they began firing with shoulder-carried guns. They must have fired 10 to 12 rockets,'' the captain said. `` I had no fire and no injuries, and so when I saw that I did n't require assistance, I just proceeded,'' he said The tanker flies a Liberian flag but is owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Bakri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navigation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Jiddah </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> warned Saturday that further Iranian attacks on shipping `` will be very costly to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and its people.'' The raid was the first Iranian attack on a neutral merchant ship since Monday, when Iranian gunboats attacked several vessels during a series of clashes with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> last Monday. The battles began when the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships blasted two offshore Iranian oil platforms the Americans said also were used as bases for Iranian attacks on ships in the so-called `` tanker war,'' a spillover from the 7 -LCB- - year-old Iran-Iraq war The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> also disabled two Iranian frigates and sank or disabled four other armed Iranian vessels. The platforms were hit in what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> termed a `` measured response'' for damage to the guided missile frigate USS <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> when it hit an Iranian mine April 14. Ten of the frigate's crewmen were wounded by the mine blast in a channel used by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to escort U.S.-flagged commercial vessels to and from <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have disclosed that American warships in the gulf will now be allowed to go to the aid of neutral vessels under attack. Previously, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> was not permitted to intervene in raids on non-American vessels. However, spokesmen for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> said they knew of no <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intervention Sunday to help vessels under attack in the gulf.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0857EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BRF--BurningMan     04-24 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-BRF--Burning Man,0156</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Sets Himself On Fire At Macon Church</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Stands as a writethru to a0686, AM-BRF--Burning Man to UPDATE
with man dying.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who set himself on fire and walked down the aisle of a church before horrified worshippers could douse the flames died early Sunday from his burns, a hospital spokeswoman said. Authorities said they did n't know why <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boone </PERSON>, 41, soaked his clothes with gasoline and then torched himself. <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> suffered burns over his entire body except the soles of his feet, said <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> patient representative <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. <PERSON> Boone </PERSON> had been standing outside the Friendship Baptist Church before he walked into the church and set himself afire, said police Capt. <PERSON> Tommy </PERSON> <PERSON> Alston </PERSON>. `` He came down the aisle completely ablaze,'' <PERSON> Alston </PERSON> said. `` It terrified those people.'' Worshippers grabbed a fire extinguisher and doused the flames.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 0905EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Lebanon-Hostages     04-24 0416</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Lebanon-Hostages,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kidnappers Threaten To Kill Two U.S. Hostages</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pro-Iranian Shiite Moslem extremists threatened Sunday to kill two American hostages if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> launch new attacks on Iranian targets. The threat was contained in a handwritten statement signed by the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionarey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and delivered to the <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> office of a Western news agency. Revolutionary Justice holds <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, 57, of <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forge </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, 57, of <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. They are among the 22 foreign hostages held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The conservative ad-Diyar newspaper reported earlier Sunday that a deal to free three French hostages held by another <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> faction fell through when the kidnappers reneged on pledges to release them because the hijackers of a Kuwaiti airliner were still in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION>. Kuwaiti officials said when the Algerians negotiated an end to the 16-day hijack drama Wednesday the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> hijackers left the plane on condition they were given safe passage to another country. Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> statement was accompanied by a photograph of <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>, the acting comptroller at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION> who was kidnapped Sept. 12, 1986. `` Any new -LRB- <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> -RRB- aggression under any pretext or excuse will lead to the execution of spy <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> first and <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON> secondly,'' the Arabic-language statement said. Another Western news agency received a photocopy of a membership card of an unidentified Lebanese organization bearing <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>'s photograph to authenticate the statement <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON>, a writer of children's books, was kidnapped Oct. 21, 1986. `` The attacks occurring in the gulf will not go unpunished and will not be as easy as <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> assumes and defines the beginning and the end of the aggression,'' the letter said. The letter said that if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attacks continued one option would be to move `` the battle arena to inside <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, after which things will get out of control.'' It did not elaborate. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> disabled two Iranian frigates and sank or disabled four other armed Iranian vessels in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> last Monday. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said the attack was in retaliation for the mine strike on an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> frigate that left 10 crewmembers injured. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> warned Saturday that further Iranian attacks on neutral shipping `` will be very costly to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and its people.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have disclosed that American warships in the gulf will now be allowed to go to the aid of neutral vessels under attack. Previously, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> was not permitted to intervene in raids on non-American vessels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Iran-Contra-Hakim Bjt   04-24 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Contra-Hakim, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran-Contra: Conflict Between Fair Trial and National Security</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge's decision to give defendant <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> access to classified documents in the Iran-Contra case spotlights the dilemma of ensuring a fair trial while protecting the nation's secrets. Since <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> has never been granted a security clearance, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>'s recent decision made clear that fairness takes precedence over normal security rules in a criminal trial. The judge gave all four defendants access to 300,000 classified documents to prepare for trial, although anyone in the case faces stiff penalties for unauthorized disclosure of material in the documents. But <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>'s case is the best example of the problem, because his background is so different from those of the other defendants. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> all are former military men with wide experience in handling secret documents and covert operations. But <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> is a businessman of Iranian heritage, who told the Iran-Contra congressional committees, `` As a businessman, I never pretended to undertake these activities for philanthropic purposes.'' <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubino </PERSON>, director of security for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` It does present a problem whenever we ca n't do traditional background checks'' for security clearances. <PERSON> Rubino </PERSON> said he ca n't recall any previous case where such broad access to classified information was granted to someone without a clearance. Normally, he said, `` The indictment makes it inappropriate to say this person is trustworthy.'' The Iran-Contra indictment alleges a broad conspiracy to misuse a lawful presidential order allowing the secret sales of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The conspirators are accused of using money from the sales to aid the Nicaraguan Contra rebels when such assistance was banned, to generate illegal profits for private gain, and to cover up their activities. North was a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff member; his boss was former national security adviser <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>; <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> is a former <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> major general turned private businessman and <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> was <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>'s business partner. As an <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION> staffer, <PERSON> North </PERSON> generated many of the classified Iran-Contra documents that he will see in the case; so did <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, who routinely briefed the president on national security matters and therefore had vast knowledge of the nation's secrets <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, who became <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s key private sector operative, had held sensitive Pentagon jobs. He once was in charge of international security matters and reportedly helped plan an unexecuted Pentagon mission to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in 1980, when 52 Americans were held hostage at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy there. <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a former assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> who specialized in anti-terrorism prosecutions, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials `` probably are very edgy about letting <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> see it -LRB- the classified information -RRB-.'' But he added, `` The problem is, that was the choice the -LRB- independent counsel -RRB- knew about before he indicted him.'' The government has decided on occasion against bringing charges in some espionage or anti-terrorism cases so it would n't risk disclosure of classified information, <PERSON> Barcella </PERSON> said. But far worse for the government was `` graymail,'' a form of blackmail used by those threatening to expose classified information if indicted. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' answer was passage in 1980 of the Classified Information Procedures Act, which sets up rules for handling classified information in criminal trials. The law allows the judge to take swift retribution against unauthorized disclosures, by finding a violator in contempt and jailing him or her immediately. In return for the swift contempt penalty that protects the government's information, the defense is assured the access it needs to present its side. `` The act was structured to equalize the status of a defendant regardless of whether he has a security clearance,'' said <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON>, a legislative counsel of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` No one should have an advantage. What <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> intended was that a criminal defendant's ... right -LRB- to a fair trial -RRB- should not be impaired by the fact that information relating to the charges is classified.'' The act requires the defendant to notify the court and the prosecution if it plans to use classified documents in the case. The court has discretion to work out alternative procedures that could keep the documents secret, while allowing the trial to continue. For instance, there could be a government statement admitting relevant facts that the specific classified information would tend to prove. There could be a summary of the information. And if a defendant is prevented by the judge from using classified information he needs for his defense, the court has three choices: it can dismiss the indictment in whole or in part, strike certain prosecution testimony, or rule against the prosecution on any issue where the information would be relevant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GunControl Bjt   04-24 0711</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gun Control, Bjt,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Host of Factors Credited for Passage of Maryland Gun Control Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROLL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The passage of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>'s new law banning cheap handguns stems in part from an epidemic of drug-related killings, but it also owes a lot to a state senator's embarrassment at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> party. What embarrassed state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> also made him a center of attention, and that led to a meeting with a woman who is a driving force in the move for gun control legislation. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s secretary misread an invitation to a <ORGANIZATION> Gridiron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> event last year as saying white attire was required, instead of white tie, so <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> was the only one who showed up in a white tuxedo. He was approached by <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, wife of presidential press secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who was severely injured in the 1981 assassination attempt on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` It was unbelievable,'' recalled <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. `` There I was red-faced, standing 15 feet from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> comes over and tries to make me feel at ease. She told me I was the only thing adding any pizazz to the party.'' They met again a few weeks ago when Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who has become active in the fight for gun control legislation, asked for <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>'s help in pushing a bill that would outlaw the sale and manufacture in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> of cheap handguns commonly known as Saturday Night Specials `` I was impressed with her and when I was given the opportunity to help it was the least I could do for her,'' he said. The law, which Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> has promised to sign, will require a nine-member state board to draw up a list of acceptable handguns. Those not on the list would be banned in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, and violators would be liable for stiff fines, up to $ 10,000 for each illegal gun sold or manufactured. The ban wo n't go into effect until January 1990, giving the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> a chance next year to try to have it repealed. <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> officials have vowed to make such an attempt. While four other states have laws that ban cheap guns based on the melting point of a weapon's metal, the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> measure is considered by its supporters to be much broader. They hope it will be used as a model by other states. Gun control advocates also see the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> experience as a useful political primer in how to withstand the powerful NRA. `` <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> was absolutely crucial,'' said Del. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Franchot </PERSON>, one of a cadre of lawmakers who pushed the bill through the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION>. `` He just stood up for the gun-control bill and stared down the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Franchot </PERSON> said. `` We just sat back there in awe at the way <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> pushed the thing through. We would have been nowhere without the political muscle of the president.'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> acknowledged the role played by Mrs. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>'s personal lobbying, but said a more important factor was the attitude of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> itself. `` The very fact that they were opposed to -LRB- banning -RRB- guns that could go past metal detectors turned off a great many legislators,'' he explained. `` The fact that they were opposed to banning tin and plastic guns that sell for $ 29.95 whose sole purpose is to kill, that told the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> that they were n't interested in a reasonable compromise.'' Agreeing with that analysis was <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Beard </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> to Ban Handguns: `` The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, I think, just blew it. They were too arrogant.'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <PERSON> Franchot </PERSON> and <PERSON> Beard </PERSON> also agreed that the recent rash of shootings by teen-agers hooked into the drug trade in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and metropolitan <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was a crucial factor. Credit also was given to effective personal lobbying by <PERSON> Coretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, wife of slain civil rights leader <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, and other victims of violence. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lattanzio </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s director of state and local affairs, cited those and other factors for creating an `` emotional hysteria'' that made passage possible. `` It was a concerted effort by the governor, other political leadership, gun-control groups and the media that steamrolled an unfortunate law, which deludes the public into thinking it will have an impact on crime, which it wo n't,'' <PERSON> Lattanzio </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Spy     04-24 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Spy,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>Double Agent Interviewed For First Time On Soviet Television</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet spymaster <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> said in his first television interview that he has had an `` amazingly good'' life in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since he escaped from a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> prison more than 20 years ago. `` Gradually, I got to make some friends, I met my wife, I found a very interesting job with interesting and pleasant colleagues. Then my son was born, and my life took a very happy course,'' the Dutch-born <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> told Soviet television in an interview broadcast Saturday. The broadcast was monitored by the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Blake </PERSON>, a British subject, was convicted in 1962 of spying for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> while working in British intelligence. His celebrated case brought a 42-year jail term, one year for every British agent the prosecution claimed he betrayed to their deaths. The spymaster escaped from jail in 1966, and the <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said last October he was aided by two leaders of the British anti-nuclear movement. `` Being faced with such a long term of imprisonment makes a man want to do something about it,'' <PERSON> Blake </PERSON>, 65, said on the late-night Soviet television program `` Before and After Midnight.'' `` And I was very lucky in that there were some good people who sympathized with me, people inside and outside of jail, and who were ready to help me.'' <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> said he hid for a few days in an apartment near the Wormwood Scrubs Prison, moved to another apartment further away and after two months was smuggled to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> in a van. `` And that's how I go to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' he said. He said his adjustment to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was not easy. `` It was for me a different country, different traditions, and even a different society, so of course it was difficult.'' As he acquired a family and got a good job, which he did not identify, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> said, `` My life has been amazingly good, beyond all my expectations.'' News reports in 1971 said <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> was receiving first-class treatment in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, owning a car and vacationing at <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> resorts. The Soviet television announcer introduced <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> as `` an honorary member of the state security service who has been awarded the Orders of <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> and the Combat Red Banner.'' The announcer described him as an `` outstanding Soviet secret servicemen.'' After his jail escape, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> lived secretly in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> until an interview with him appeared Feb. 14, 1970, in the Soviet government newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Izvestia </ORGANIZATION>. In that interview, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> said he became a spy for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to help in `` exposing and interferring with imperialist aggression and subversion.'' Among his exploits was to betray a British spy ring in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and a tunnel there which the American <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> and British MI-6 used to monitor <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION> communications. During the 12-minute television interview, <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> spoke about his work in the Dutch resistance during World War II, his 1942 flight to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, where he joined the British secret service and his conversion to Communism after studying the works of <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Blake </PERSON> was the second British-Soviet double agent interviewed recently by Soviet television. Other broadcasts have focused on <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> `` Kim'' <PERSON> Philby </PERSON>, 76, a former <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> intelligence officer who defected to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1963.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Punjab     04-24 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Punjab,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sikh Gunmen Kill 13 People In Punjab. 30 Dead Since Friday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sikh militants fatally shot 13 people in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> on Sunday. Police went on alert across the northern Indian state and tightened security in the Indian capital. Sunday's slayings brought to at least 30 the number of people killed since Friday in violence blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> radicals and more than 800 since the first of the year. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, police checked vehicles and set up several road blocks because of the killings. `` We have reports that Sikh terrorists may try to create public disorder in the capital, hense the measure,'' said an officer at the police control center of this city of 6 million. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday's killings came in six separate attacks. Among the dead were seven Sikhs, including one woman, and three Hindus. Identities of the remaining three were not immediately known. Sikh radicals, fighting for an independent homeland in their rich farming state, were blamed for 12 deaths in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> on Friday. On Saturday five more people died in Sikh radical attacks. The latest killings raised to 807 the number of deaths blamed on <ORGANIZATION> Sikh </ORGANIZATION> militants in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> state since the start of the year. Sikh militants have been waging a guerrilla war since 1982 for more political economy or an independent homeland in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. Sikhs, whose religion was formed about 500 years ago as an alternative to <LOCATION> Hinduism </LOCATION> and Islam, claim they are discriminated against by <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s majority Hindus. Sikhs make up about 2 percent of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 800 million people but are in a majority in <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION>. Hindus account for about 80 percent of the country's population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Japan-Nuclear     04-24 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Japan-Nuclear,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands of Japanese March Against Nuclear Power Plants</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> priests rang gongs and housewives marched with their babies as thousands rallied Sunday to protest nuclear power. Police said more than 6,200 people joined the rally at a downtown park and the march through <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Ginza </LOCATION> district, but organizers estimated the crowd at 20,000. The sponsors said it was one of the largest anti-nuclear power demonstrations ever held in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> priests and nuns rang gongs. Other protesters included members of environmental, consumer and parents' groups. At the rally in downtown Hibiya Park, children staged a drama showing ways of stopping nuclear power plants. The crowd cheered when speakers denounced a recent U.S.-Japan nuclear agreement that they said will allow <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to refine and transport plutonium. Some demonstrators wore signs reading `` Protect our children'' and `` Do n't repeat Chernobyl,'' referring to the nuclear power plant accident in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> nearly two years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-VD     04-24 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-VD,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Venereal Disease Cases Increasing In China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of venereal disease cases in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has increased since the country adopted an open door policy toward foreigners, an official Chinese report said Sunday. <PERSON> Ye </PERSON> <PERSON> Ganyun </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Venereal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consultative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, gave no figures but said the number of cases was still relatively low, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said in a report published in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> newspapers. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> virtually stamped out VD in the 60s but a few cases were discovered in the early 80s and they spread rapidly in the country, <PERSON> Ye </PERSON> was quoted as saying. <PERSON> Ye </PERSON> said young Chinese are more casual toward sex than before. He said more than 70 percent of the VD cases involved men, and most of them were members of criminal gangs or prositution rings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-40th Bjt   04-24 0837</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-40th, Bjt,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab Uprising Casts Shadow Over 40th Anniversary Bash</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KARIN LAUB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Arab uprising has cast a shadow over <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s yearlong 40th anniversary bash, with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> director <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, poet <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> and tennis ace <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> among celebrities who turned down invitations. Israeli organizers hope to stem the wave of cancellations by assuring reluctant guests that the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict will be a central theme and that they are free to criticize <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Some Israelis consider the no-shows another slap in the face to a nation that throughout its short history has often found itself isolated and a target of international criticism. But others said they wo n't let it spoil the party. `` You have seen the people of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> truly rejoice, going out for picnics, going out into the streets,'' said Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s aide, <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON>, referring to last week's Independence Day celebrations `` Nobody can take that away.'' Organizers said many big names remained on the guest list, including American movie director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> and Indian-born <PERSON> Zubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON>, conductor of both the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Philharmonic orchestras. Israeli organizers had planned an impressive lineup of poetry readings, film festivals and theater performances as highlights of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 40th anniversary celebration. But in the midst of preparations, the Arab uprising erupted five months ago, and televised images of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers clubbing Arab youths and razing houses sparked an international outcry. More than 170 Arabs and two Israelis have died in the unrest. `` We are in a war, and it hurts everything, our celebration, our economy, tourism, our feelings,'' said <PERSON> Yakov </PERSON> <PERSON> Agmon </PERSON>, the chief coordinator of the anniversary festivities. <PERSON> Agmon </PERSON> suffered a major setback last week when five <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> poets organizing one of the main events, the `` International Poetry Week,'' withdrew their support and called on fellow artists to boycott the June festival. `` A government that demolishes civilian houses ... and kills youths in what can only be termed state terror is not worthy to have poets come to a government-sponsored festival,'' said <PERSON> Natan </PERSON> <PERSON> Zach </PERSON>, a founding father of modern Hebrew poetry who lives in <LOCATION> Haifa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Agmon </PERSON> initially wanted to cancel the festival, but then asked his staffers to poll the invited poets _ 80 Israelis and 35 foreigners _ to see if there was enough support to go ahead. He said he would make a decision later this month. He would not give names of poets who turned down invitations, but two of the most prominent, <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> and Soviet poet <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Yevtushenko </PERSON>, said they would not attend. <PERSON> Ginsberg </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> he initially accepted, hoping to use the festival as a `` protest for peace,'' but later withdrew in solidarity with <PERSON> Zach </PERSON>'s decision. Organizers of other festivals also said many international artists were torn about whether to attend. `` We got a lot of letters from film directors who said, ` how can we come to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and talk about movies when people get murdered?''' said <PERSON> Nili </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the weeklong <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>, scheduled for May. Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said organizers had asked 150 film schools to submit contributions, and 45 accepted while 50 of the refusals cited political reasons. To overcome such reservations, organizers decided on a 32-hour retrospective of films on the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict, which has become the centerpiece of the festival. As a result, several prestigious contributors, including the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, agreed to attend. `` They now have a feeling that they're not just coming to talk about art, but to get involved,'' Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. But others, like <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, turned down the invitation. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> did not give a reason, but Ms. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> suggested his refusal was politically motivated. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, who is Jewish, sharply criticized army policies in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> and fellow tennis star <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> pulled out of a May tennis benefit tournament for <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Shaare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zedek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` Ms. <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> decided to withdraw mainly because of the political problems,'' said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Rami </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadan </PERSON>, who canceled the tournament. Some entertainers have chosen another way. Theatre <PERSON> du </PERSON> <PERSON> Soleil </PERSON>, a Paris-based avant-garde troupe, agreed to attend this summer's <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Festival, an annual performing arts extravaganza, after telling organizers it would first publish a statement about its political views in Israeli newspapers. In the half-page ad published April 15 in the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, the group described the Arab uprising as justified, but also asserted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist in peace and security. <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> said he opposed attempts to encourage political debate to assuage the liberal conscience of VIPs. `` It is wrong to turn a national celebration into a political event,'' <PERSON> Pazner </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>. `` The <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> people want to rejoice without politics.'' He lashed out at local artists criticizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, calling them `` a small minority of pseudo-intellectuals who believe self-hatred is the answer to the problems of the Jewish people.'' Countered Zach: `` He is probably right if he means by self-hatred that we are having problems with our conscience.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Jordan-Hussein     04-24 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jordan-Hussein,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jordan's King Says Wazir Slaying May Have Been To Kill Peace
Initiative</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The assassination of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s No. 2 leader may have been aimed at scuttling <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace efforts, and a breakdown could lead to a disaster, King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said in a rare interview broadcast Sunday. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> condemned the April 16 killing in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION> of <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Wazir </PERSON>, military head of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which he said was `` more than likely'' carried out by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Israeli sources have said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was behind the attack, but the government has not confirmed it. `` I think it will probably mean that tensions in the area will grow more and conceivable it could be an action in itself which is aimed at creating the kind of reaction that would destroy the chances for progress towards peace,'' <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Sunday Today. `` Sticks and stones and tear gas -LRB- are -RRB- causing a lot of damage ... but this area has nuclear weapons within it,'' he said. `` If there is no solution, the end is an explosion, a disaster. ... I could see a disaster overtaking all of us ... sooner or later.'' Palestinian rioting in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war, and in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> taken from <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in the same conflict, has left more than 170 Arabs and two Israelis dead. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, in the interview taped Thursday, also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is not doing enough to promote peace. When asked if he trusted the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as mediator, he said: `` I have no reason to do so, so far. It's not a question of trust. It's a question of is the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> willing to ... assume the responsibilities of a superpower in its position.'' He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` has a moral right'' to push <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> toward a peace settlement. He also called on <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to rally the five-member <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which includes the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, behind a peace initiative.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880424-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-24-88 1155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Bender-Profile Bjt   04-24 0884</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bender-Profile, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese, Bender Families Tied For Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
