<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 2348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Anti-DrugProposals     06-07 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anti-Drug Proposals,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Proposal Would Withhold Federal Aid to Promote Anti-Drug War</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is considering withholding governmental benefits such as student loans and public housing assistance to people convicted of drug use, according to a published report. The <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet-level </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, headed by Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, approved the proposals in outline form at a meeting May 27, but they have not yet been presented to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Wednesday's editions, citing sources it did not identify. `` We're not trying to be Draconian _ we're not going to kick poor people out of public housing ...,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted one source as saying. `` But at the same time, we're trying to encourage'' state and local governments and colleges to adopt anti-drug programs that will have `` maximum impact.'' The proposals would seek to fight drug abuse by threatening to withhold some federal aid to state and local governments, colleges and universities and other publicly funded institutions that fail to adopt strict, federally approved anti-drug programs, the sources said. One proposal calls for state governments to refuse to issue first-time drivers' licenses to minors who have been convicted of drug use, and the federal government would enforce this by threatening to withhold federal transportation funding, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. Various federal department and agencies were directed to study the proposals and report back to <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> by Wednesday, the newspaper said. One source told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> that no objections had been raised and that the proposals probably would be presented to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> within the next few days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b p AM-Dukakis-NominationWinner     06-07 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dukakis-Nomination Winner,60</SECOND>
<HEAD>BULLETIN</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> clinched the Democratic presidential nomination on Tuesday night, assuring his victory on the first ballot at the party's national convention, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> delegate count. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor exceeded the 2,081 delegate majority as votes were being counted in the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> primary. Earlier, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked up more than 100 delegates in winning the three other final-day primaries in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> began the day about 150 delegates short and was likely to end the evening with about 2,200 delegates in the AP count. On Wednesday, he expected to pick up more delegates and the endorsements of two former rivals. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> mathematically clinched the Republican nomination in winning the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary in April.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0000EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Jackson 1stLd-Writethru a0730 06-06 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jackson, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0730,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Primary-Eve Broadcast A Disaster For Jackson</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: LEADS with 10 grafs on botched broadcast; picks up 2nd graf
pvs bgng: Jackson accused; DELETES outdated grafs 4-5 pvs; edits to
tighten</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> staged what was to have been a celebratory appeal for votes on the final night of the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> primary campaign, but the half-hour show was botched when the presidential candidate got stuck in traffic and missed half of it. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> arrived 16 minutes into the half-hour broadcast, which originated at <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> station <ORGANIZATION> KTLA </ORGANIZATION> and shown throughout the state at a cost of $ 150,000. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> fell behind schedule on campaign appearances in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> earlier in the the day, then got tied up in traffic jams trying to get to the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> airport. The show opened with rock disc jockey <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasem </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> supporter, announcing that the chair next to him was empty because <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was on his way. The first half of the show was given over to a video montage of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign appearances. <PERSON> Kasem </PERSON> filled time waiting for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> by interviewing <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s state campaign manager, producing some tortured exchanges. Then came a second video montage, featuring some of the same footage already shown. Finally, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> appeared. The candidate, appearing calm but his face glistening with perspiration, talked about the issues that he has stressed in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> _ offshore oil drilling and environmental concerns as well as devoting defense funding to peaceful application in space and science instead. He also highlighted his anti-drug message and his call for an end to gang warfare. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> told <PERSON> Kasem </PERSON> he had a `` day of big crowds, lots of excitement, but mostly of touching people's hearts.'' Earlier in the day, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, shifting the focus toward thd Democratic convention this summer, said Monday he will go to the convention mat with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> unless the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> front-runner comes around to his position on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of proceeding too `` cautiously and conservatively'' in refusing to agree with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> should be declared a terrorist nation. `` If he will not bend on that matter, we'll simply meet on the floor at <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said during a call-in radio news conference. The tough talk was the most pointed language <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has used in discussing his intentions for the convention. `` The matter needs to be resolved in the committee or in platform hearings or on the convention floor,'' he told reporters later. He indicated he will put up a fight for his platform issues but will do so within the framework of party rules, leaving unclear just how hard a bargain he will drive. `` We can resolve our differences within the context of our party and not in the streets _ and that's growth,'' he said at one point. He also said that at the convention he would `` use the rules to have fair rules'' _ a reference to his contention that the popular vote is not fairly reflected in the delegate count and so delegate-selection procedures should be changed. As for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> contends the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should subject that nation to the trade sanctions applied to other countries it has put on its terrorist list such as <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` By any definition of a terrorist state <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> qualifies,'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said the Democratic convention `` will have a tremendous impact on the priorities that the ticket will have. I'm convinced the ticket will take a strong position against apartheid and declare <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to be a terrorist state.'' As to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, he said, `` Either the governor will offer leadership on these basic issues or be wallowing in the wave of the convention taking him out to sea.'' `` It's not a question of integrity, it's a question of judgment and priorities. And the governor, like all of us, will keep expanding and keep growing,'' he said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> indicated he will push for platform planks on cutting back military spending and on shifting spending to housing, health care and other social services. Although polls have shown <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> consistently trailing <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said the state `` can produce an upset tomorrow if voters listen to their convictions rather than reports of an inevitable <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> win.'' In a philosophical vein, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he believes his candidacy has helped <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> grow in racial tolerance. `` It's clear <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has become more and more accustomed to <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as a possible next president. ... It's a matter of growth. I'm the stimulus. I'm the catalyst for that growth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Pirates     06-07 0131</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Pirates,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pirates Reappear In East China Sea</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pirates are harassing boats off the eastern seaboard of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for the first time since the Communists took over the mainland in 1949, an official newspaper reported today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said that in the past few weeks, pirates in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> off the coast of <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zhejiang </LOCATION> province and <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> province have stolen the catches of fishing boats and assaulted and kidnapped fishermen. The daily said the pirates have been armed with iron pipes, explosives and detonators. It not say how many boats were involved in pirating or indicate their origin. It did say, however, that six boats from a <LOCATION> Fujian </LOCATION> province county had been seized in the past two months for illegal possession of fish.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Chile-Cocaine     06-07 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chile-Cocaine,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Cocaine Shipment From Colombian Group Seized in Chile, Police
Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police say they foiled the first attempt of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s ` <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION>' drug barons to use <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> as a transit point to send cocaine to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The seizure of 22 pounds of pure cocaine worth $ 1.2 million on the street was the biggest cocaine bust in <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> in 14 years, police Maj. <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Rieutord </PERSON> said Monday. Two Colombians, <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, 30, and <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Marquez </PERSON>, 42, were arrested with the narcotic on Friday at a fashionable <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> hotel after arriving from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, police said. The arrests were not immediately announced because police were waiting for accomplices to pick up the drugs, but the accomplices never showed, <PERSON> Rieutord </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marquez </PERSON> admitted to belonging to the cartel named after the city where it is based and `` said they were told to use <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> as a transit point because this city was not normally used, and thus security could be less severe,'' the major said. <PERSON> Rieutord </PERSON> said cocaine traffickers had not used <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION> as a transit station for more than a decade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0136EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DonkeyExpecting     06-07 0326</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Donkey Expecting,0333</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare French Donkey Expecting Baby</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OLIVENHAIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sonnette </PERSON>, a rare French donkey who narrowly escaped a government death sentence four years ago, is expecting its first offspring. `` She looks like she swallowed a barrel. She looks like she wants to have it any minute,'' said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanderlip </PERSON>, who owns the donkey with her husband, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Vanderlip </PERSON>. The Vanderlips, both veterinarians at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Sonnette </PERSON> successfully mated with a 3-year-old of the same breed about a year ago and should deliver her first foal later this month. Sonnette is one of four donkeys the Vanderlips imported to their northern <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> farm from the <LOCATION> Poitou </LOCATION> region of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1984 and 1985. In 1984, federal agriculture inspectors almost put <PERSON> Sonnette </PERSON>, a member of an endangered species, to death because the donkey failed an equine blood test for communicable diseases. A public outcry ensued over the plans to destroy the animal, and officials changed their mind when the Vanderlips and other experts showed the test given was n't suitable for a specialized variety such as the Poitou donkey. A test designed for the rare donkey was then given to <LOCATION> Sonnette </LOCATION> and it was released from quarantine after being certified as healthy and free of disease. Since then, the <PERSON> Vanderlips </PERSON> have imported three other rare Poitou donkeys, including the father-to-be, <LOCATION> Tartarin </LOCATION>. The Vanderlips hope to establish a herd to help the save the breed from extinction. About 45 Poitou donkeys remain in existence, said Mrs. <PERSON> Vanderlip </PERSON>, who learned about the species while studying veterinary medicine in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> several years ago. <PERSON> Sonnette </PERSON> has been separated from the other donkeys and will remain alone with the foal until the baby is weaned at 4 months to 6 months of age. <PERSON> Tartarin </PERSON> also will be kept away from <LOCATION> Sonnette </LOCATION> as well as the foal because male donkeys can become agitated around small creatures and may even kill them, Mrs. <PERSON> Vanderlip </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0023EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     06-07 0939</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0975</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Zubin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON>, music director of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philharmonic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION>, confessed to some `` trepidation'' before a joint performance by his musicians and those from a Soviet orchestra. The Philharmonic and the Symphony Orchestra of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION>, led by <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Rozhdestventsky </PERSON>, will play together works by <PERSON> Berlioz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shostakovich </PERSON> on Wednesday night in <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. The Philharmonic performed last week in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>, and will give three performances, including the one by the combined group of more than 250 musicians, in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` I am standing here with some trepidation,'' <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON> said Monday at a reception on the eve of the first rehearsal with the combined ensemble. `` But whatever happens, the concert of Wednesday night, after the summit of last week, just could n't be better.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will join <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on Wednesday to address 500 foster grandparents, and will invite the 60-year-old rodent to become an honorary foster grandfather. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will address the grandparent-volunteer group at the <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> amusement park's <ORGANIZATION> Epcot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to encourage their participation in anti-drug abuse activities, the White House said Monday. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> plans to return to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on Wednesday afternoon.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Victoria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sellers </ORGANIZATION>, daughter of the late actor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sellers </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekland </PERSON>, has pleaded guilty to violating her parole by using cocaine. Ms. Sellers, 23, had been ordered to undergo periodic testing for drugs as a condition of her three-year probation in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> drug conspiracy case. She pleaded guilty in that case in March 1987 to concealing a crime. In a federal court hearing in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Monday, Ms. Sellers admitted diluting urine samples by drinking a lot of fluids, failing to appear for tests and leaving the district without probation approval, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincenberg </PERSON>. She will be sentenced June 27. `` Right now she is being tested every day, according to the probation officer,'' <PERSON> Lincenberg </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Probation Office has indicated it will recommend that the former <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> model and actress be treated at a drug rehabilitation program. Miss Sellers, a British citizen who lives in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, already has spent time in a rehabilitation program at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lincenberg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two months before her baby was due, the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was already accompanied by a new member of the family. But <PERSON> Bendicks </PERSON>, a young brown-and-white terrier acquired last weekend, stayed in the car Monday as the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> inaugurated a restored water wheel at <LOCATION> Painshill </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Surrey </LOCATION>, outside <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. After the duchess completed her second-to-last official engagement before giving birth, she allowed <PERSON> Bendicks </PERSON> to curl up in her lap on the way home. The duchess' baby will be the first for <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> and her husband, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, the second son of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. A Buckingham Palace spokesman said the duchess' official agenda will be halted tonight after a theater engagement.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WESTPORT, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talk show host <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Marlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, have upset preservationists because the couple wants to demolish a unique contemporary home on their property. Although an ordinance provides a three-month grace period for structures over 50 years old, nothing is on the books to stop the demolition of those built during the past 50 years. `` We want architecturally significant structures included in the ordinance as well,'' said <PERSON> Lucinda </PERSON> <PERSON> McWeeney </PERSON>, chairwoman of a historic survey of 400 <LOCATION> Westport </LOCATION> homes. The concrete house, built in 1963, is located on the shore at <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON>'s property. It was purchased for $ 6.8 million in March by the couple, along with 7 acres and a guest house next to their $ 3.5 million Tudor home on 3.1 acres overlooking <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Sound. The couple bought the land adjoining their property to prevent construction of a subdivision. The house is considered a landmark in modern architecture, <PERSON> McWeeney </PERSON> said, and should be preserved for that reason. `` I'm sorry that these people whom I respect would suggest that my only interest is the view,'' <PERSON> Donahue </PERSON> said. `` My main interest is the security of my family and all the children who visit my home during the summer.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> abandoned his dressing room and changed clothes in a restroom to get some privacy before the 22nd annual Music City News country music awards show. `` I did n't want to dress in front of other people's wives,'' he said Monday night, while shaving and dressing in a restroom backstage at the Grand Ole Opry House. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> shared a dressing room with other male performers. About a half-dozen people were in the restroom. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> is known for hits such as `` Country Boy'' and `` Highway 40 Blues.'' He and his wife, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, sang on the awards show. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> was named top instrumentalist at the awards show.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KIRKSVILLE, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Too many doctors hesitate to give good advice about disease prevention and promotion of good health, perhaps because they're preoccupied with high-tech medicine, <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Surgeon General <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Koop </PERSON> said. `` We seem at times to be more interested in transplanting diseased hearts and lungs than we are in teaching people not to smoke in order to prevent heart and lung disease from occuring in the first place,'' he said Monday. <PERSON> Koop </PERSON>, speaking to graduates of the <ORGANIZATION> Kirksville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Osteopathic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, said doctors are under greater pressure to slow down if not reverse the rising cost of health care _ sometimes by making judgments based on cost rather than on the basis of good medicine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0158EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-WorldClimate     06-07 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-World Climate,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Urge Action to Forestall Weather Calamities</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR MAX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rising ocean levels will flood cities and the climate will become hotter and more stormy unless governments curb gas emissions that make the Earth an ever-warming greenhouse, a group of scientists said. `` The problem here is 10 times or maybe 100 times more important and more difficult'' than the thinning ozone layer, said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meteorological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. The group Monday issued a report calling for coordinated planning to prepare coastal defenses against floods, stop deforestation, re-examine energy policies, cooperate to monitor and study emissions, and to carry out the accord to halt the depletion of the ozone layer recently signed in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>. The report said weather changes will make deserts hotter and tropical storms more severe in the next few decades. It said rising seas will threaten to flood coastal cities like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and endanger entire countries like the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON> said the scientists could not establish how the weather changes would hit specific areas, but it was clear that `` climatic problems will be part of people's lives over the next century.'' The study was a follow-up to a 1985 conference of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unions </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Villach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, which endorsed the theory that gases trap energy from the sun near the Earth's surface, warming the atmosphere in a `` greenhouse effect.'' `` We are entering a new phase. We told the world what scientists believe will be the case ... Now nations and politicians must start to think about the problems,'' said <PERSON> Bolin </PERSON>, whose pioneering work on the greenhouse effect and the ozone layer earned him this year's $ 150,000 Tyler Prize for Environmental Achievement from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> The report said the earth's average temperature will rise by at least 0.54 to 1.44 degrees Fahrenheit per decade. In the tropics and in the polar regions, the rise in temperature may reach as much as 9 degrees, the report said. The rising temperatures will melt polar ice packs in summer, raising the sea level by 8 to 60 inches over the next 50 years, the report said. At least 30 of the world's largest cities `` definitely will be affected,'' said <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaeger </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Beijer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, who wrote the report. In the last 100 years the earth's average temperature has risen nine-tenths of a degree and sea level has risen by four to 4.8 inches, she said. Even if emissions of dangerous gases were stopped immediately, temperatures and the sea level would continue to rise at that rate for another 100 years because of those gases already released in the atmosphere, she said. The report said that among the effects, tropical storms will become more frequent and hit wider areas. Patterns of rainfall, and thus farming, will change. Fish migrations will shift. Evaporation will increase, making water supplies scarcer in semi-arid zones. Trees and animals may have difficulty reproducing and may be threatened with extinction. <PERSON> Jaeger </PERSON> said more powerful storms could cause severe flooding in <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION>, threating the lives or dislocation of 50 million people. Floods could overwhelm the <LOCATION> Nile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION>, where 10 million Egyptians live. `` Roughly half of humanity lives close to the sea,'' she said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> alone will have to spend up to $ 100 billion to protect its eastern seaboard, she said. The changing climate also will have military implications as seas become ice-free along the northern coasts of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>. `` If these coastlines become navigable, fundamental security readjustments will be required,'' the report said. The report listed the `` greenhouse gases'' as carbon dioxide, methane, chlorofluorocarbons, nitrous oxide and tropospheric ozone.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-LawDean     06-07 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Law Dean,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>D.C. Law School Dean Resigns Two Months After Being Selected</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dean of the <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> has resigned two months after his selection and three months before classes are scheduled to begin, according to a published report. `` It was the most agonizing decision of my career,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> for a story in Tuesday's editions. `` My wife and family decided they really did n't want to move. It's as simple as that. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' resignation becomes effective June 15. He plans to return to a private law practice in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, where he lives with his wife, who is also an attorney, and two children. The resignation is the most recent in a series of setbacks that have plagued the fledgling law school, created amid controversy over whether the city should take over its predecessor, the failing <ORGANIZATION> Antioch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION>. Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> and the board of directors of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, which is to assume control of the school in two years, have opposed the takeover. Board chairman <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abramson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' resignation `` makes it difficult'' to continue the school's operations because <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was responsible for many of the start-up activities. The resignation also adds to the growing list of law school deans in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and around the nation who have quit recently. In May, the law school deans at <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> announced their resignations. Meanwhile, <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> named a new dean in April and new deans have assumed positions at the law schools of <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> universities in the past two years. The <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mason </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law school in suburban <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, also named a new dean in the last two years. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has reported that 86 of the nation's 174 ABA-approved law schools hired new deans in the last three years, and the average tenure has declined from six years to 3.2 years
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ToughPrincipal     06-07 0504</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tough Principal,0518</SECOND>
<HEAD>Film Crew Takes Over High School For Movie On Principal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McMAHON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PATERSON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Crews filming scenes for a movie about bat-wielding principal <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> have disrupted classes and graduation plans, but some students said the film also has generated excitement. `` They moved our classes. So what, it does n't mean they are going to stop,'' said <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sousa </PERSON>, an Eastside High junior who is an extra in the movie. `` Mostly the only reason you sit in class by now is to go over your review sheets. Books have already been collected.'' Several students and parents have complained that <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> crews filming `` Lean on Me'' forced a change in graduation sites, <LOCATION> Passaic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> schools Superintendent <PERSON> Melindo </PERSON> <PERSON> Persi </PERSON> said Monday. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who gained national attention for a get-tough approach to education that includes wielding bullhorns and baseball bats in hallways, could not be reached for comment. Calls left with his secretary Monday were not returned. As the 97-member film crew built sets, sprayed graffiti over lockers and filmed a scene with actor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON>, students hanging out after school said they saw only a positive impact from the movie. Sophomore <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, an extra waiting to be called, said students in the movie have been given plenty of time to do their homework, and tutors are available if needed. She said she hopes to parlay her movie appearance into greater roles in the future. `` I was excited because now there is a chance for us to be noticed,'' she said. Some school officials, however, were worried there are too many distractions at a time of year when important exams are held. `` My concern is just for the kids,'' said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Brightman </PERSON>, a school board member. `` I'd like them to be able to take their exams without a lot of commotion going on.'' <PERSON> Persi </PERSON> sent the <ORGANIZATION> Paterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> a letter asking how the filming of `` Lean on Me'' is affecting the school. In particular, he is asking about newspaper reports that physical education classes have been canceled to let the film crew use the gymnasium; that hallways are being blocked with film equipment; and that regular instruction rooms have been sacrificed for the movie. Producer <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>, who began filming Wednesday, said his crew's presence will have few negative academic effects. `` Sure, it's a little more crowded in the hallways,'' <PERSON> Twain </PERSON> said. `` This is the time of year when everybody starts ` short-timing' anyhow Just come over here and see the exodus at noontime.'' <PERSON> Twain </PERSON> acknowledged causing a change in graduation plans, and attributed it to the artistic preferences of director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Avildsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Avildsen </PERSON> had planned to film the ceremony but because of aesthetic concerns, persuaded the school to move the location to <LOCATION> Baurele </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION> from the original and larger site, Hinchcliffe Stadium. Two weeks ago, <PERSON> Avildsen </PERSON> decided not to film the graduation. At that point, another school had reserved the stadium for June 24, forcing Eastside to change its graduation date to June 25.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlineScorecard     06-07 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airline Scorecard,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Complaints Drop, While Airline On-Time Performance Improves</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of airline complaints to the government was the lowest in 15 months in May and air carriers also recorded their best on-time performances, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The department said Monday that its consumer affairs office received 36 percent fewer complaints from airline passengers than during the same month in 1987. For the first time since February 1987, the number of complaints dipped below the 2,000 level at 1,820. In April, the latest month for which there was on-time information available, the 14 largest airlines had 82.6 percent of their flights arriving within 15 minutes of schedule, compared with 78.8 percent in March, the department said. The April figures were the best since the department began monitoring on-time performance last September and in part reflected good weather during the month, officials said. Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> issued a statement saying that the latest on-time and consumer statistics indicate `` that our attempt to instill greater accountability into the -LRB- aviation -RRB- system seems to have made a substantial difference.'' <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> had the best performance during April with a 90.8 percent on-time arrival rate, followed by <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> at 90.3 percent. <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> reported a 91.1 percent on-time rate, but that covered only the first eight days of the month before its operations were incorporated into <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION> as a result of last year's merger. <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which has been plagued by labor tensions, had the worst on-time arrival rate among the 14 airlines, with 75.5 percent of its flights arriving within 15 minutes of schedule. <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> reported a 76.5 percent on-time mark. The airlines also misplaced fewer bags during April with 6.53 baggage complaints for every 1,000 passengers flown, compared with 7.48 reports the previous month and 11.83 reports in January. The April figures for mishandled bags were also the best since the consumer statistics began being compiled last September. The number of passengers bumped from flights because of overbooking also declined. There were 3.71 passenger for every 10,000 boardings involuntarily bumped during April, compared with 5.46 passengers during the first three months of the year, the department said. <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, both owned by <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, had the highest complaint rate in May with 11.43 complaints for every 100,000 passengers who flew on <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> and 10.34 complaints from every 100,000 people on Eastern. While the number of complaints involving <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> was more than any other airline it represented a sharp improvement over a year ago when the department received more than 21 complaints per 100,000 travelers on <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which until recently had consistently been among the airlines with high complaint rates, also showed continued improvement with only 3.22 complaints for every 100,000 passengers flown in May. <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Aloha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> had the best complaint record with less than 1 complaint for every 100,000 passengers flown. <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> had the fewest complaints among the large carriers at 1.32 per 100,000 passengers. The best arrival rate was reported at <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where 90.6 percent of the flights arrived on time during April, followed by 86.7 percent at <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> had the worst arrival record at 68.4 percent. The department tabulates on-time information for the 27 largest airports based on passenger traffic volume. The April on-time statistics are made public at the same time as the May consumer complaint statistics, although the two sets of statistics cover different months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0795 06-07 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0795,0194</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Quade; No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Virgil Oliver</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Virgil </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 72, who played the mean little kids `` Butch'' and `` Tuffy'' in early `` Our Gang'' movie shorts, died Friday. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> played the bully for about a year in 1925, earning $ 7.50 a day, before he outgrew the role. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> had two other non-speaking acting jobs in films and then decided to move on to a new career in real estate.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Edward Quade</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAGUNA HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaumberg </PERSON> <PERSON> Quade </PERSON>, a founder of the methodical problem-solving method known as `` systems analysis,'' died Saturday. He was 79. <PERSON> Quade </PERSON> joined the research organization when it was founded in 1948 and retired in 1973. His 1968 book, `` Systems Analysis and Policy Planning: Applications in Defense,'' defined systems analysis as `` a systematic approach to helping a decision-maker choose a course of action by investigating his full problem, searching out objectives and alternatives, and comparing them in the light of their consequences.'' <PERSON> Quade </PERSON>'s books applied systems analysis to military problems and later to broader public policy issues.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenitalWarts     06-07 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Genital Warts,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Approves New Wart Treatment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new treatment is available for the estimated 8 million Americans who suffer each year from genital warts. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday that it has OK'd direct injection of genetically engineered alpha interferon into the warts. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said a study of 192 patients showed they exhibited marked improvement after receiving interferon injections three times a week for up to three weeks. Of the 192, 42 percent experienced complete clearing of all their treated warts, 24 percent had a 75 percent to 99 percent reduction in the size of their treated warts and 18 percent had a 50 percent to 74 percent reduction in the size of their treated warts, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said. Previously, the most effective treatments were painful and potentially scarring removal by freezing or burning. Some types of genital warts can be treated with direct application of conventional anti-infective drugs, but this treatment often is not effective. Alpha interferon was first approved in June 1986 as a treatment for hairy cell leukemia _ a rare form of leukemia. Although the presence of genital warts is more distressing than health-threatening, some studies have suggested there could be a relationship in women between the warts and later development of cervical cancer. Adverse reactions experienced during clinical trials were mild flu-like symptoms. The drug is not recommended for use in pregnant women since animal studies have shown the treatment may cause abortions. <ORGANIZATION> Schering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kenilworth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, will market the alpha interferon treatment under the Intron-A brand name.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NancyReagan     06-07 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nancy Reagan,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Notebook: Sidelights of the Nancy-Raisa Show</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sat quietly in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Spaso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> last week, waiting for her husband to arrive for a news conference. Since President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s wife has rarely attended such events, a reporter called on her to answer a few questions. With a giggle and a grin, the first lady demurred, saying, `` I only rescue people.'' The first lady's response drew a peal of laughter from reporters _ who realized she was referring to a hectic scene several days earlier when she'd reached out to pluck a hapless reporter loose from the over-eager clutches of the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION>. In a number of ways, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first visit to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> cast her in a defender's role. Although it seemed odd for a woman who rarely goes to church, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used several events during the visit to make subtle points about religious freedom. During a visit to the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s Assumption Cathedral _ nowadays a museum _ the first lady questioned her guide and <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> about its use for religious services and the celebration of the 1,000-year anniversary of the founding of <LOCATION> Christendom </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>. She got only curt responses from the Soviet first lady, but Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> pursued the topic again several days later. Upon viewing an icon named, `` The Trinity,'' during a tour of the famed Tretyakov Gallery, she told Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> she'd arrived in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on Trinity Sunday. Again, little response. At another point, the first lady was told that before she'd come, Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> had spoken at length about the icons but failed to mention their relgious meaning. `` I do n't know how you can neglect the religious implications,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> insisted. `` I mean, they are there, when you see them.'' The first lady's propaganda points on behalf of religious freedom were accompanied by a few propaganda points on her own behalf, as well. Left smarting after her <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit encounters with the well-spoken and photogenic Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at first appeared intent on showing how to play the polite and well-mannered guest. So, it seemed, a peace pact of the magnitude of the Treaty of <LOCATION> Westphalia </LOCATION> had been reached. The two women held hands, European style, as they toured the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> cathedral on the first day of the visit. And afterwards, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s spokeswoman <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> relayed quotes from a private afternoon tea in which the two pooh-poohed the `` silly'' idea that there was any rivalry between them. But it did n't last. By Wednesday, when they toured the <ORGANIZATION> Tretyakov </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallery </ORGANIZATION>, their equally strong wills collided as they jockeyed for position in front of the cameras. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> offered reporters a `` dialogue,'' displaying her opinions of the priceless artwork, going so far as to quote Russian author <PERSON> Feodor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dostoevsky </PERSON> on their beauty and how they reflected the Russian soul. This time, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appeared ready for the assertive Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, insisting she be granted equal time. She then made her thanks known to everyone, and chatted a bit with reporters about her experiences. Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> backed away, allowing the first lady to have her say. But if body language is a barometer, judge the seating chart that evening _ when the two men sat next to each other in the front row of the Bolshoi's <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Box </ORGANIZATION> and their ladies sat on the outside _ as far apart from each other as they could be and contrary to normal practice at such events. But at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s departure, there were smiles and waves all around. Perhaps it is the last time the two women will meet and it really is n't necessary that they be friends. Given Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s newfound ability _ as her spokeswoman says _ `` to roll with the punches,'' it's clear Mrs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has discovered she must allow for the moment when a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> first lady insists she be allowed her own `` dialogue.'' And through their words and appearances, each first lady has become adept at getting a message across, not only at home, but to their counterpart's homeland as well.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WarPowers Bjt   06-07 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-War Powers, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Congressional Debate Comes Too Late on Gulf</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>'s forecast of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> policy is simple: `` Let me predict when the next great debate will occur _ when the next great tragedy occurs in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>.'' The statement by the <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> came Monday afternoon as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> again sidestepped the issue of whether to require <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to invoke the War Powers Act and defend his policy under terms of the controversial 1973 law. As Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, said, `` this is not the first time, it's not the second time, it's not even the third time. ... It's the umpteenth time'' the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> debated the issue since the May 17, 1987, attack by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> on the USS Stark killed 37 sailors. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has been unable to decide the question once and for all because it is divided both on the war powers law and on the separate question of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> policy, senators noted during Monday's debate. The War Powers Act was approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over the veto of President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who argued it was an unconstitutional restriction on his power. All succeeding presidents, including <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, have agreed with that point of view. The act requires a report from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> within 48 hours after <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel are sent into areas of `` imminent hostilities'' and, under some circumstances, requires them to be withdrawn within 60 or 90 days unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> says they can remain. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy involves reflagging 11 Kuwaiti tankers and protecting them with <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> warships in the gulf, scene of fighting in the 8-year-old Iran-Iraq war. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> is an ally of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Six weeks ago, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mantle of protection was extended to neutral ships that ask for help from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships. Monday's vote in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was a 54-31 decision to keep a resolution invoking the War Powers act off the top of the chamber's agenda Although Democrats hold a 54-46 advantage in the chamber, the issue cuts across political lines. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, summed up one view of the dilemma On one hand, he said, `` the policy of escorting, of convoying, Kuwaiti ships is not a good one, but that's the policy we're following. On the other, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said, the War Powers Act `` is an unworkable law.'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders have introduced a bill to overhaul the act by eliminating the 60-day withdrawal period. Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, disagreed that the War Powers law is unwieldy and offered a different reason for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> inaction. `` If we choose to make it work, it'll work, but we do n't have the gumption to make it work,'' he said. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> agreed. `` There seems to be the inability by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to stand up to presidents,'' he said. Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is afraid to take a stand on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policy and `` our silence is our complicity. `` If the policy appears to be a success, we can issue statements praising it, but if it appears to be out of hand, we can issue criticisms,'' he explained. The War Powers law was written in response to the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War and reflected a desire by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to take back some of the power ceded to the executive branch during <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s longest war. Senators have noted that the Constitution gives <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, not the president, the power to declare war. But the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> conflict was fought without a declaration of war and the modern reality most often features murky <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military deployments such as the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s deployment of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> for a peacekeeping mission. The latter ended shortly after 241 servicemen were killed by a terrorist truck bomb. `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will probably never again declare war,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., referring to that reality The War Powers law and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> policy are also involved in a related federal court fight. Last year, 115 legislators, frustrated at the congressional inability to act, filed suit in federal court seeking an order requiring <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to invoke the law. That challenge was turned down, but the legislators are appealing and say they will pursue their case to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> thinks the law will eventually be struck down by the nation's highest court. `` Once it hits the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, they're going to throw it out like a tub of lard, because it is unconstitutional,'' he said
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahern </PERSON> covers military issues in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BalloonRecord     06-07 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Balloon Record,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Balloonist Sets Altitude Record</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAREDO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Balloonist Per Lindstrand soared more than 10 miles to set an unofficial altitude record, but had to crawl outside his pressurized gondola at 22,000 feet and wield a pocket knife to release stubborn sandbags. Lindstrand on Monday reached 59,700 feet, easily surpassing the 55,137-foot record set in 1980, but fell short of his goal of 60,000 feet in his butane - and solar-powered `` Stratoquest'' hot-air balloon, project coordinator <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said The 12-story-high craft took off into a clear sky, but was hampered by two 200-pound sandbags that failed to release automatically. `` There was no way I could make the altitude record while carrying this sand,'' said the 39-year-old Lindstrand. `` So I had to climb out of the capsule and cut them.'' The first bag was no problem because it was near the hatch, but the second was on the other side of the craft beyond the reach of his oxygen line. `` I had to take a deep breath, run around, cut it off and run back again, all the while clinging on to the outside of the capsule,'' he said. `` That got a bit hairy. `` There were a few white knuckles when I was climbing around there,'' he said. Linstrand figures the sandbag problem cost him about 5,000 feet in potential altitude. `` It was a fairly average day, I think,'' Lindstrand said jokingly. `` We had a particular problem with the sandbags, but nothing my trusty <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> knife could n't handle.'' Last year, Lindstrand and British millionaire <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Brandson </PERSON> set another record when they became the first ever to cross the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> in a hot air balloon. The two hold balloon records for speed, 100 mph; duration, 31 hours and 41 minutes, and distance, 3,075 miles, from that flight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     06-07 0915</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farm Wives Lash Back at Critics of Pesticide Use</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Concern over the hazards of chemical pesticides has gone too far, according to members of a farm women's organization meeting in the nation's capital `` We feed our families with the food we grow; we're not going to feed them poison,'' says <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. She is here for the sixth annual <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> meeting of Women Involved in Farm Economics, an organization that brings together farm women from across the country to wrestle with agricultural issues. The group frequently has focused on the intricacies of world markets for farm commodities and federal payment programs. But pressure for congressional action on the pesticide issue prompted an environmental seminar as well this year. Many crops produced in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and overseas are sprayed with pesticides, some of which the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> has linked with cancer and other serious health problems. The two speakers at the farm women's session were representatives of industries that have been major targets of environmental criticism. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Early </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, focused on pesticides, while, <PERSON> Vickie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, a legislative analyst with a utility company, discussed the acid rain issue. Early said he doubted that regulatory legislation recently produced by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would be sent to the president's desk this year. He said so many loose ends remain to be tied up in other committees that it will be `` close to impossible to get all these things pulled together.'' `` To do all that before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> goes home and tries to get re-elected _ and they will do that earlier this year _ I just do n't think you can get it all done this year,'' he said His organization is supporting the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s bill but is opposing separate legislation cosponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., and Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn It would impose stringent standards for clean groundwater, which provides the major supply of drinking water for millions of Americans but has in some areas been found to be laced with pesticides. There may be an effort to attach the <PERSON> Leahy-Durenberger </PERSON> plan to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s blueprint for revising the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide and Rodenticide Act. After the session, a number of members of the farm women's group agreed to discuss their attitudes toward pesticides at an impromptu roundtable discussion. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, the group's president, recalled how she drove into a farmers market near her home town of <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, not long ago with a truckload of vegetables. Nearby another farmer was parked, advertising that his vegetables were organically grown _ without the use of pesticides. Customers were interested at first, she says. But that changed. `` He had on his truck `` organicially grown'' and as soon as they found the worms on his vegetables, they walked away,'' she recalled. `` They want absolutely perfect products and we have supplied them with them,'' said <PERSON> Naioma </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Sterling </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, a wheat and cattle producer. Environmentalists, she said, `` are not looking at the total, full picture'' and often have `` a biased and slanted view.'' The notion that farmers are poisoning the land with toxic chemicals is absurd, she said. `` Our families depend on it. Our futures and our childrens' futures depend on it. `` My husband really respects the chemicals and is very careful how he uses them,'' said <PERSON> Merlina </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Almira </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. She also recalled a trip to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> last year to inspect irrigation systems used in that country She saw `` beautiful vegetables'' grown there without benefit of pesticides. `` But those same vegetables would not be bought in a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> store,'' she said. The reason? Too many flaws caused by pests. The women condemned the notion that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law should attempt to eliminate all risk from the use of pesticides. Instead, they said, pesticide use should be likened to the use of certain drugs that are beneficial in treating illnesses but sometimes have side effects, or to automobiles, which are certain to mean highway fatalities but provide vital transportation. They also pointed the finger at pesticides banned here that are being used overseas on crops that are then brought into this country. `` They're being used in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and hauled across the border,'' said <PERSON> Clara </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Spivey </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, cotton and peanut grower.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Farm Belt senator clashed with administration officials after they rejected both his bill to increase the nation's commitment to agricultural research and similar recommendations from an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> task force `` You're rejecting the recommendations of your own task force,'' Sen. <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, said Monday after <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> voiced opposition to the proposals. The bill would set up an independent corporation to make research grants and provide federal funding for it. The price tag envisioned by <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> would be $ 100 million. The task force recommended $ 1 billion. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> deputy assistant secretary for science and education, made clear that the department was opposed. `` We do disagree with the amount that was involved and we do disagree with the mechanisms that were involved, and that's our privilege as it was their privilege to make those recommendations,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> already supports a sizeable, government-operated agricultural research program, and <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>'s legislation would add a new layer of bureaucracy. He also said the administration would not back research grants that could not be reviewed by the secretary of agriculture.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis-Delegates Bjt   06-07 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis-Delegates, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delegates Flock To Dukakis As He Heads Over The Top</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> closed to within 200 delegates of locking up the Democratic presidential nomination even before the first votes were counted in today's season-ending primaries, boosted by a surge of about 180 in the last week. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked up 75 of those new delegates on Monday alone, some prodded into declaring their support by his campaign staff and others attracted by the near-gravitational force that surrounds a winner. `` He's been on a roll,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brophy </PERSON>, deputy director of delegate selection for the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign. `` He's shown election success week after week after week,'' she said. `` It casts a very favorable light on <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>.'' Much of the surge came courtesy of `` super delegates,'' the party leaders and elected officials who have heavily favored <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, to the chagrin of <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor also has been converting delegates who had been pledged to the suspended candidacies of Sens. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. On Monday, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON>, a staunch supporter of <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, switched to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and brought the bulk of his state's 65-member delegation with him This came two days after <PERSON> Wilkinson </PERSON> said he would continue to support <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>. And in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> on Monday, Gov. Rose Mofford and four other `` super delegates'' moved to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> from the uncommitted ranks, where they had been since former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> dropped out of the presidential race. By its own estimates, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign has moved within striking distance of the 2,081 delegates needed to clinch the nomination. With fewer than 200 delegates to go, the campaign expects to take at least 280 of the 466 delegates at stake in today's primaries in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. The intensity of the operation to contact and win delegates has picked up as the primary season draws to a close. Delegates are told that `` the governor would appreciate it very much if they would get into the count earlier rather than later,'' Ms. <PERSON> Brophy </PERSON> said. `` The goal of all of this is to take the pressure off <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> after June 7 so he can go about the process of building a coalition for the general election,'' she said. Another incentive is the memory of 1984, when <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> finished the final round of primaries without enough delegates to lock up the nomination and spent an extra day pleading with a handful of delegates to put him over the top. Some members of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' staff, including delegate chief <PERSON> Tad </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>, worked for <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> four years ago. Of the 178 delegates moved into the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> column in the last week, roughly half were super delegates, the party leaders and politicians who automatically hold seats at the convention, and the rest were delegates picked through the primaries and caucuses who had been uncommitted or pledged to other candidates. `` I think that the advantage that we have is that we have been on the phones with these people so long and there is a real strong bond between some of these people and the campaign,'' Ms. <PERSON> Brophy </PERSON> said. By Monday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> held support from more than 321 of the 643 super delegates, while <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was backed by just 54, of whom 42 are black, according to The Associated Press delegate count. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has complained that the super delegates have disproportionately favored <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and hinted he may challenge the rules that created them. He also has indicated he may launch a convention challenge against the rules that allow some states to pick other delegates in a manner that does not reflect the results of the states' primaries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Airport-Statistics     06-07 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Airport-Statistics,120</SECOND>
<HEAD>April Figures For 27 Airports</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Airline Scorecard</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, ranked from best to worst, is a listing of 27 airports and the percentage of on-time arrivals during April, according to information provided by the airlines to the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and released Monday. The average on-time arrival percentage was 81.3. -LRB- Departure: The percentage in parentheses reflects the departure record at the airport. -RRB- The ranking covers the 27 busiest airports in passenger volume as determined by the <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Airport           On-Time (On-Time)</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>                  Arrive  (Depart)</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> 90.6 -LRB- 94.4 -RRB- <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> 86.7 -LRB- 91.0 -RRB- <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> 86.7 -LRB- 87.6 -RRB- <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> 85.9 -LRB- 89.7 -RRB- Mpls-St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> 85.7 -LRB- 90.7 -RRB- <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> 85.0 -LRB- 87.1 -RRB- <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> 84.9 -LRB- 83.4 -RRB- <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> 84.3 -LRB- 89.5 -RRB- Tampa 84.2 -LRB- 89.8 -RRB- <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> 83.6 -LRB- 89.6 -RRB- <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> 83.6 -LRB- 86.3 -RRB- <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> 82.1 -LRB- 82.6 -RRB- <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> 82.0 -LRB- 86.4 -RRB- <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 81.9 -LRB- 87.7 -RRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> 81.8 -LRB- 83.9 -RRB- <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> 81.6 -LRB- 85.4 -RRB- <LOCATION> Seattle-Tacoma </LOCATION> 80.9 -LRB- 88.0 -RRB- <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> O'Hare 80.6 -LRB- 86.1 -RRB- <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> 79.9 -LRB- 87.6 -RRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> LaGuardia </LOCATION> 79.3 -LRB- 88.1 -RRB- <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> 79.1 -LRB- 84.3 -RRB- <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> <PERSON> Intcntl </PERSON> 78.5 -LRB- 84.3 -RRB- <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Nat. 78.3 -LRB- 86.3 -RRB- <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION> 76.4 -LRB- 83.8 -RRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> 68.4 -LRB- 78.9 -RRB- <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> 67.7 -LRB- 81.1 -RRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> JFK </LOCATION> 67.6 -LRB- 80.1 -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-KennedyRemembrance Bjt   06-07 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kennedy Remembrance, Bjt,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Robert Kennedy Remembered 20 Years Later as Father, National Leader</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the dusk of a spring evening, with his family gathered before the simple cross that marks his grave, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was remembered as a father who guided his children with love and understanding and as a public figure who was `` always ready to stop and reach out to others.'' Tourists mingled with friends and aides of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> senator Monday evening at a Mass of remembrance for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who was shot by an assassin 20 years ago as he left a <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> celebration of his victory in the 1968 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> presidential primary. `` I invite you to join us in renewing the commitment that was his life, his spirit and his hope,'' said <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who was not yet 3 -LCB- years old when his father died. It was the first time the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> family had invited outsiders to take part in a memorial service. All 10 surviving children had a brief part in the service. The 11th child, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, was found dead of a drug overdose in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, in April 1984. His widow, <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, arrived on the arms of her brother-in-law, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. She did not speak at the service, but she told <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in a taped interview that her husband `` brought us all along with his enthusiasm ... his love of life ... his curiosity.'' `` He made everybody feel a part of this battle, that we're going to do better, that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> can stand for something,'' she said. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s grave _ only a few steps from the more ornate site where his brother, President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, is buried _ was unadorned for the service but an altar was set up nearby for the Mass. In front was a box with 400-500 pink Eveline roses ordered by <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. Six choirs sang and the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> band played. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> sang `` Mine Eyes Have Seen the Glory,'' as he did on the night <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was buried. The sun was setting over the cemetery as the service began and as it ended, the crowd lighted candles that had been handed to them as they entered. The flickering lights cast a soft glow as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> read a Shakespearean quotation his uncle often recited: `` When he shall die, take him and cut him out in little stars, and he will make the face of heaven so fine _ that all the world will be in love with night, and pay no worship to the garish sun.'' The youngest <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> child, daughter <PERSON> Rory </PERSON>, had not yet been born at the time of her father's death. Now 19 and a freshman at <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, she quoted from a speech her father delivered in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> in 1968: `` Let us dedicate ourselves to what the Greeks wrote so many years ago, to tame the savageness of man and make gentle the life of the world.'' `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was always ready to stop and reach out to others,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, the oldest son, who is a congressman from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. He recalled how his father, tired after a week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, would return to their seaside home in <LOCATION> Hyannisport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and make it a point to speak with each of the children about their week. `` He was deeply responsive to others, especially those who were needy and vulnerable,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, a 34-year-old son who bears his father's name, asked the crowd for a moment's prayer for a policeman who was struck and critically injured by a motorist as the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> motorcade was making its way to the service. <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhe </PERSON>, 31, a fund-raiser for the <ORGANIZATION> RFK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, quoted from a speech that the former senator gave during the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> primary campaign in 1968 a week before he was assassinated. `` Perhaps this world will always be a world in which children suffer,'' she recited. `` But we can reduce the number of suffering children and if you do n't help us, who will?'' The other <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> children who took part in the mass were <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON>, 36, who heads a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> youth corps program and was an unsuccessful candidate for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>, 35; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 34, who teaches environmental law at <ORGANIZATION> Pace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, 30, who heads <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, 28, who runs <ORGANIZATION> RFK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON>, 24, who works for the family-owned Merchandise mart in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON>, 23, a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, 21, a sophomore at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> Rory </PERSON>, 19, a freshman at <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. The gathering included some important names from the <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> era, such as <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Sorensen </PERSON>, a top aide and biographer to both <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> brothers; <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice appointed by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and former Olympic decathlon champion <PERSON> Rafer </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> who was with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> when he was shot. Neither <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> nor her daughter, <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlossberg </PERSON>, attended the service. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was shot by <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> and mortally wounded shortly after midnight on June 5, 1968, after he had addressed a crowd of supporters gathered in the Ambassador Hotel to celebrate his election victory of the day before. The senator, then 42, died the next day. The Jordanian-born assassin, who said he did not know what drove him to the deed, still is in prison.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0219EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-SenateBudgetRollCall     06-07 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Senate Budget Roll Call,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Budget</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 58-29 roll call Monday by which the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 1.1 trillion federal budget for fiscal 1989. Voting yes were 37 Democrats and 21 Republicans. Voting no were 8 Democrats and 21 Republicans. A yes vote is a vote to approve the budget. xxx denotes senators not voting. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION>, R-Colo., no; <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., no; <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., xxx; <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, R-Mo., no; <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn., yes; <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, R-Miss., no; <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., xxx; <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., yes; Dodd, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., yes; <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., no; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash., yes; <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., xxx; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, D-Ky., yes; <PERSON> Fowler </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn., yes; <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Harkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Iowa </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., yes; <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, R-Nev., no; <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., no; <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., yes; <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Hollings </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, R-Neb., xxx; <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON>, R-Kan., yes; <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis., no; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., yes; <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., yes; <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., yes; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., no; <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Matsunaga </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> McConnell </PERSON>, R-Ky., no; <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>, D-Mont., yes; <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Mikulski </PERSON>, D-Md., yes; <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, xxx; <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., yes; <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., yes; <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Pressler </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.D. </LOCATION>, no; <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., no; <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., yes; <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, D-Nev., no; <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., yes; <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, R-Del., no; <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, yes; <LOCATION> Sanford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, yes; <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., yes; <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn., yes; <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON>, D-Ala., yes; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., yes; <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION>., xxx; <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., yes; <LOCATION> Stafford </LOCATION>, R-Vt., yes
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-07 0396</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0413</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First name ``Gordhan'' in 6th graf of 1st item is cq.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two dozen contestants tried their charms on <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, but a 4-year-old boy was the only one able to spark the interest of the 5-foot-long boa constrictor. `` I can make a sound like a snake,'' <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> <PERSON> Anglin </PERSON> said as he looked into the serpent's eyes. `` I can. Listen. Ssssssssssssss.'' <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> slithered with interest. Cole backed away. The boy was declared the winner of the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> Zoo's snake-charming contest because he was the only one able to coax <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> into moving He won a certificate worth $ 40 at a restaurant. Others tried to tempt the snake from her wooden perch Sunday, but <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> turned them down cold. <PERSON> Gordhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Patel </PERSON>, a 51-year-old hospital worker who successfully sweet-talked <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> last year, was n't able to repeat the feat. Perhaps it was because <PERSON> Patel </PERSON> used the same line: `` You like pizza? Spaghetti? Oh, you like the birds _ chicken.'' <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON>, 11, tried to make <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> flinch. `` Look out, there's a truck,'' <PERSON> Nicky </PERSON> said. When that did n't work, he tried, `` How about a fat, juicy rat?'' Each competitor was allowed one minute to stand before <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, and try to coax it into motion. Three judges gauged audience and serpent reaction. The contest was part of the zoo's `` Snakes of the Metroplex'' weekend, an exhibit of snakes indigenous to the region. Boa constrictors like <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, however, in the wild live in Central and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The event presents the good side of snakes, which have been slapped with a bad reputation `` since <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> and Eve,'' said zoo spokeswoman <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Furber </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DUNKIRK, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A physics professor set a world record in a corker of an event. <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Medicus </PERSON> on Sunday opened a bottle of champagne to launch a cork 177 feet and 9 inches, beating the mark set last year of more than 68 feet at <LOCATION> Kensington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s Oval Cricket Grounds. A land surveyor used laser equipment to measure the shot, and a wine expert testified that the bottles of champagne used were undoctored. <ORGANIZATION> Medicus </ORGANIZATION>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Rensselear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Troy </ORGANIZATION>, plans to send the results to the Guiness Book of World Records. The victory was especially sweet for <ORGANIZATION> Medicus </ORGANIZATION>, whose much-heralded attempt to break the record at the <ORGANIZATION> Saratoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grounds </ORGANIZATION> last year literally fizzled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880607-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 5thLd-Writethru a0440 06-07 0988</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0440,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Nears Nomination; Jackson Prods Him on South Africa</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 7th graf pvs with Jackson-Dukakis meeting</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
