<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-NancyReagan-Astrology     08-15 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nancy Reagan-Astrology,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady: Trauma of Shooting Led to Astrologer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First Lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Monday she consulted an astrologer on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s travel schedule because she was `` obsessed with his safety'' after he was shot in March 1981. It was `` a terrible trauma'' when her husband was shot, `` and you're in shock much longer than you know you're in shock,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in a CBS News interview. `` And you reach out anywhere for, for comfort.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was first reported to have consulted an astrologer on her husband's schedule in a book by former White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>. The White House later confirmed it. Interviewed during CBS' coverage of the Republican National Convention, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told anchorman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> that some months after the attack on her husband she heard about a woman who had said she would have warned against his public appearance that day. `` And I said, ` Oh, gee, did she really?' And I was so obsessed with his safety, that anytime he went out of the house, I think my heart stopped,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` So all I would do would, would be to ask her, ` Is, is this a, would he be all right? Is it better for him to go to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on Wednesday or Tuesday?'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a RetiredU.S.News&amp;WorldReportChiefDeadAt81     08-15 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>Retired U.S. News &amp; World Report Chief Dead At 81</SECOND>
<DATELINE>BETHESDA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON>, a retired president, board chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report, died Sunday of cardiopulmonary arrest at a nursing home in this <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> suburb. He was 81. Sweet came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1946 and joined the old <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Report </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> as its circulation manager. Two years later, when World Report merged with <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, he became circulation director of the new publication. Sweet later headed the advertising and the research and promotion departments before becoming executive vice president and publisher in 1951. He was named president of the magazine in 1958 and was promoted to board chairman and chief executive officer in 1973. He stepped down as CEO in 1981 and as board chairman the following year. During his years with the magazine, it grew from a circulation of 250,000 and revenue of $ 3.4 million to a circulation of more than 2 million and advertising revenue of more than $ 70 million a year. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>; one son, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Altos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>; and one daughter, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Ternes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-CVN-Reagan-Balloon     08-15 0093</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN-Reagan-Balloon,100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Cracks Joke as Balloon Pops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was in the midst of his speech to the Republican National Convention Monday night when a balloon popped. `` Missed me,'' he said quickly and went on without a pause. That's become one of his favorite retorts to such sounds. A few moments later, in a series of statements that he began with `` facts are stubborn things,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> misspoke. `` Facts are stupid things,'' he said and, just as quickly as before, corrected himself to say `` facts are stubborn things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MiracleService 2ndLd-Writethru a0823 08-15 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miracle Service, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0823,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands Gather at Church Where Four Claim to Hear Messages from
Mary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs grafs 8-9 bgng `To some' with 4 grafs to UPDATE with
quotes from priest, add explanation. Subs 15th graf pvs `The
reported' to CORRECT that only two in Yugoslavia claim to still see
apparitions. Subs final graf to restore first reference.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WENDY E. LANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LUBBOCK, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Worshipers screamed and lifted their hands toward the sky as a ray of light burst through the clouds Monday evening during an outdoor Mass where thousands came expecting a miracle. Shortly after the 6 p.m. Mass began at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Neumann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, throngs of pilgrims stood and applauded as many spectators pointed skyward, crying that they saw <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> and calling it a miracle. `` I saw the sun pulsating a lot and saw <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> about 10 times,'' said <PERSON> Mamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fertitta </PERSON>. `` Then I saw <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> above and the doves below.'' A dozen priests standing on a rooftop altar and 600 Eucharist ministers turned their backs to the crowd to look at the sky and wave. After minutes of silence, St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Neumann </PERSON> pastor Monsignor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> began to sing `` Amazing Grace.'' People in the audience whipped out cameras to photograph the clouds and light. `` I saw baby <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> for an instant in the sky,'' said <PERSON> Koreth </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargahese </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> estimated the crowd for the service at about 12,000 people. To some in the crowd the shape they saw in the sky was the miracle they had been hoping for. Their shouts alerted others. Some then reported seeing the same apparation and others did not. `` I'm positive other people saw things and they took photographs,'' said Father <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, a Benedictine monk from <LOCATION> Pecos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. `` I did n't see anything, but some of the other priests on the altar did,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>, a deacon of the <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION> parish. Monday was the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> feast of the ascension of the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> into heaven. The crowds were drawn to the charismatic parish in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> by national attention given to three parishioners' reports that they received messages from the <PERSON> Virgin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> this spring, including tidings of miracles on the feast day Earlier Monday, parish members and priests laid hands on the pilgrims and said prayers for the scores of handicapped people present. Hundreds of people in wheelchairs and walkers settled on the grassy hillside beneath a 60-foot-long altar built atop the church office. `` I heard that <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>'s crown was spinning on the statue inside the church last night, so I believe anything can happen,'' said <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> as she stepped off a bus with 43 other Catholics from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Parish officials did not confirm the rumor about the crown. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said he did not know whether attendance would reach the 20,000 people he said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> told him would come. `` It does n't matter how many are here. Some beautiful spirtual things are going on.'' The reported messages at the church came after <PERSON> James </PERSON> and several parishioners returned from <LOCATION> Medugorje </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, where six youths claimed they began seeing apparitions of <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> in 1981 and two say they still see them daily. One group skeptical of the reports said the trip and the beginning of the messages was too coincidental to be believable. `` While we are certainly open to any verifiable paranormal events, so far the only amazing thing that has happened here is the fact that thousands of people would flock here from all over, against common sense, on the unverified claims of one man,'' said <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Madison </PERSON>, spokesman for West Texans to Promote Rational Thought, a group that investigates claims of paranormal behavior. The three parishioners say <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> and God speak to them during Monday night recitations of the rosary. The trio write the `` messages'' in notebooks and read them aloud after the service. `` I feel her love, her joy, her sorrow and that's what I write down,'' said one of the three, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Constancion </PERSON>, a former hospital therapist who quit her job to devote more time to prayer and church work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-TaxWar Bjt   08-15 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Tax War, Bjt,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Raids And Confiscations Against Delinquent Taxpayers</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RAMALLAH, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 75 Israeli troops broke into <PERSON> Yakub </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeitoon </PERSON>'s home one recent morning, stayed about a half hour and took two cars, two television sets, a stereo, a vacuum cleaner and an electric drill. <PERSON> Zeitoon </PERSON> was the target of a `` tax sweep,'' the latest method used by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s military government in the occupied territories to crack down on Palestinians who refuse to pay taxes. The eight-month-old <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> rebellion has largely moved from daily violent protests to a determined battle of wits and wills, with Arabs striving for independence and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seeking to maintain its administrative hold on the territories. That struggle for control is epitomized in the tax war. For the moment, the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> appear to be winning. Israeli roundups of cars and electronics have had limited success in convincing Palestinians to pay personal or sales taxes. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> officials acknowledge about a 50 percent drop in tax collection in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zeitoon </PERSON> himself still refuses to pay. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has filed a complaint with the army, arguing that some methods used to try to convince Palestinians to pay taxes, such as confiscating identity cards, are illegal. Army officials deny the charges of illegality and say the Palestinians will suffer in the long run for their protest. `` We are going to have to cut services'' to the occupied lands, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> this month. For their part, <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> contend that in 20 years of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation, they have never gotten back in services as much as they paid in cash to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` For 20 years we lived like chickens, laying eggs that the Israelis took,'' <PERSON> Zeitoon </PERSON> said in an interview. `` We're tired of being treated like animals. Now we want our pride.'' The Palestinians' contention is supported by Israeli researcher <PERSON> Meron </PERSON> <PERSON> Benvenisti </PERSON>, who publishes annual studies of the occupied territories funded by the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> and Rockefeller Foundations. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> collected $ 80 million in direct and indirect taxes from the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> in 1987 and returned $ 30 million to the occupied lands and southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, keeping $ 50 million for Israeli coffers, <PERSON> Benvenisti </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The tax war has intensified since King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> began cutting ties with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, which he lost to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war. <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> stopped salaries for 21,000 Palestinians and abandoned a five-year, $ 1.3 billion development plan, leaving an administrative void. But even as early as January, underground leaders of the Palestinian uprising called on Arabs to stop paying taxes to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, and many complied. Palestinians who paid taxes often were identified by graffitti scrawled on neighborhood walls or on Arab radio broadcasts, and their shops or homes were sometimes set afire or vandalized. In <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION>, about 70 percent of the 2,000 to 2,500 merchants have stopped paying taxes, according to <LOCATION> Zeitoon </LOCATION>, even though many have lost more in confiscations by the Israelis than they would have had to pay in taxes. <PERSON> Zeitoon </PERSON> said he owes the Israeli military government about $ 20,000, but the goods confiscated from him were worth about $ 75,000. <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Rawan </PERSON>, who owned a stone-cutting factory before the uprising began in December, said he stopped paying business-related taxes in January and owes the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> military administration about $ 750. When he refused to pay, they confiscated his $ 7,500 car, he said. But <PERSON> Rawan </PERSON>, 36, has another problem. Since January he has lived on the run, sleeping in the homes of friends, because he says soldiers told his wife he would be arrested if they could catch him. `` When I know the Israelis have a holiday, I try to sneak home and see my wife and two children,'' <PERSON> Rawan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in the home of a relative. `` During the week, I try to meet them at different places.'' <PERSON> Rawan </PERSON>'s factory has been closed down. He now earns small sums as a handyman and receives money monthly from a relative in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rawan </PERSON> thinks the underground leaders called for a ban on tax payments before they thoroughly thought about how seriously this would hurt Palestinians. But he says he will nevertheless obey the directive. `` We will give up what they ask us,'' he said. `` I have sacrified, yes. But compared to some _ the dead, the imprisoned _ it is little. When I think of them, how can I pay my taxes?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BouncingChecks     08-15 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bouncing Checks,0112</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Rubber Checks A Year and You're Out</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beginning today, anyone who in a year writes three checks that bounce in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> will not be allowed to have a bank account for six months. <PERSON> Jaafar </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, Governor of <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Negara </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, told reporters that just too many people have been issuing dud checks. Currently, anyone issuing bad checks is fined 100 ringgits -LRB- $ 37 -RRB- per check. `` In a recent survey, the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banks </ORGANIZATION> In <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> discovered that every month about 30,000 checks turn up that are n't worth the paper they are printed on, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in an editorial today
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DoubleEagleAnniversary     08-15 1018</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Double Eagle Anniversary,1055</SECOND>
<HEAD>Balloonist Recounts Historic Flight On 10th Anniversary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ARNOLD STAPLETON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBUQUERQUE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a cramped gondola dangling beneath an 11-story helium balloon, with clouds obstructing any view below, the disembodied voice of the radar operator seemed scarcely to be believed. `` You have crossed the coast of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>,'' the voice told three American balloonists on that still-dark early morning 10 years ago. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> asked if the message was indeed that which had eluded others for 105 years. Silence. Then, crisply, `` Sir, my radar is never wrong.'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, along with <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maxie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, whooped with joy. Sunburned and weary after five days aloft, the businessmen-adventurers had made the first trans-Atlantic crossing in a balloon. The three landed their black-and-silver Double Eagle II later that day, Aug. 17, 1978, in a wheat field west of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Today, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> is the only one of the three still alive. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> was killed in 1983 at age 48 when his balloon crashed in a West German forest during a race. <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON>, then 53, died in 1985 when his twin-engine airplane crashed shortly after takeoff in <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, now 40 and a commercial airline pilot in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, said he has no specific plans to celebrate Wednesday's anniversary. But he said his thoughts often drifted back to that summer 10 years ago. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> recalled that after the initial jubilation, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> went to sleep while he and <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON> looked down through the clearing clouds on the lights of <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The silent 112-foot balloon 15,000 feet up caught sounds that drifted skyward. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON> could hear dogs barking and trains rumbling along tracks nearly 3 miles below. `` Tears came to my eyes,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said. `` I put my arm around <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> _ he'd always been somewhat like a father to me. I had n't felt that close to another human being for as long as I can remember.'' The men began the flight six days earlier when the Double Eagle II lifted up from <LOCATION> Presque </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Isle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and headed toward <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> more than 3,000 miles away. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> says the flight was not without problems, including a clash of personalities. `` <PERSON> Maxie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> later stated that he wished he could have flown the flight by himself,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know what <PERSON> Ben </PERSON>'s feelings were, but I wanted someone to share this with I did n't want to be <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON>. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said conflicts arose when <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON> both began making key decisions. `` Any aircraft can only have one captain, and we had two: <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maxie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>,'' he said. But <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said conflicts were overshadowed by the hardships of the flight in the 12-by-6-foot living space crowded with TV cameras and navigational equipment. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>'s hang glider dangled beneath the gondola and 5,500 pounds of sand and lead for ballast hung over the sides in bags. `` There were many times the flight was in question,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> recalled. `` But how close it came to failure at each moment was interpreted different by each of us.'' They lost altitude rapidly at one point when ice chunks crusted the top of the balloon. They jettisoned valuable ballast. When they dropped to 4,000 feet the ice melted. Later in the flight they dumped more ballast, including an expensive navigation system that had failed on the second day. They tossed oxygen bottles, anything they could. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said that at one point, a bit delirious from the altitude, he chucked a $ 4,000 radio _ and only later noticed a jar of peanut butter that weighed as much. Plans were for <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> to fly the glider down once they made it to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. But 400 miles from <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, it came down to a choice of dropping the glider, their last oxygen and food, or a propane tank for a heater to battle <PERSON> Abruzzo </PERSON>'s frostbite. The glider went. Radios also failed during the flight, and the men had to communicate by ham radio. `` The first guy I talked to would n't talk because I did n't have a license,'' said <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>. `` And he did n't believe I was in a balloon over the middle of the ocean.'' Finally, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> reached an old man confined to a wheelchair in a home for the elderly somewhere in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` His call sign was ` G4JY.' I do n't think I'll ever forget that,'' he said. `` He talked to me until the last day of the flight. He was like the Good Shepherd.'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said the rough times were offset by the excitement. A high point, he said, came over <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> when a jumbo jet relayed a message from the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>. The museum had asked to display the gondola and balloon in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and Space Museum that houses the Apollo 11 moonship, <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON>'s Spirit of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> brothers' plane. In the final few hours the men believed they would make it to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON> had landed 51 years before after the first solo trans-Atlantic airplane flight. But over <LOCATION> Evreux </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, they realized they could not go on. The last of the ballast was gone, save for a bottle of champagne. They were 60 miles west of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, 3,107 miles and 137 hours from <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> where the helium-packed balloon had taken off. The swiftly draining balloon envelope carcass and its gondola settled gently to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> as cheering spectators abandoned their cars along a nearby highway and rushed to the balloon. Hundreds tried to take a piece of history. `` It's hard to chew rubberized cloth,'' <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> said. `` People were trying to tear little shreds off, but I think they were probably losing their teeth more than damaging the balloon.'' The French press dubbed them the `` new Lindberghs.'' But <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> says the only time he thought about <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON> was when the adventurers drew straws that evening to see which would sleep in <PERSON> Lindbergh </PERSON>'s bed at the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> ambassador's residence in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and his wife won. `` And I ended up on the floor after 30 minutes because I could n't sleep,'' he said. `` The bed was like a banana. The springs were shot.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Temple     08-15 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Temple,0833</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Stir Arab Protest With Plans To Open Tunnel Near Sacred
Site</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli officials have stirred Arab protests with plans to dig an opening that will allow tourists to walk along the entire western wall of the ancient Jewish Temple, which was destroyed by the Romans in A.D. 70. Caretakers of the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> mosque complex, built on the 36-acre plateau that once held the temple, fear any digging will serve as a pretext to start excavations under the Islamic holy site. Palestinians in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> rioted in July, forcing <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> workers to halt digging an entrance in a narrow side street off the <LOCATION> Via </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dolorosa </LOCATION>, where tradition says <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> carried the cross to his crucifixion. Israeli officials say they will press ahead with the project once tensions subside. The controversy illustrates the deep suspicions and acute sensitivities that surround the site which is holy to the world's three major monotheistic religions `` Our desire to open the tunnel is purely cultural and touristic,'' <PERSON> Dany </PERSON> <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON>, chief archaeologist of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, told reporters during a recent tour. Part of the 350-yard tunnel, which follows the temple's western wall for most of its route, was the main commercial thoroughfare in the days of King <PERSON> Herod </PERSON>. Folded pieces of paper with the prayers of modern Jewish visitors who walked in the tunnel can been seen in the cracks between the huge, smooth stones which have remained in place since <PERSON> Herod </PERSON> rebuilt the temple in the first century B.C. It was first destroyed by <ORGANIZATION> Babylonians </ORGANIZATION> in 586 B.C. <PERSON> Herod </PERSON>'s second temple lasted until the <ORGANIZATION> Romans </ORGANIZATION> sacked it in 70. Testifying to the greatness of Islamic architecture are vaulted chambers built by the <ORGANIZATION> Mamelukes </ORGANIZATION> in the 13th century to support a bridge linking the <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aqsa </ORGANIZATION> complex with the city. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> was built in 536. The tunnel, excavated after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> in the 1967 <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> war, can not be opened for tourists unless an exit is built, <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON> said. Moslem officials say they do not believe <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> intentions are innocent, and underground leaflets call for <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> to be on their guard to prevent attempts to excavate under the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> complex. <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> Tahboub </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moslem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said Moslems feared the tunnel would be used to burrow under the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> complex. In 1981, Israeli militants dug a 25-yard shaft before Moslem guards stopped them. `` The purpose of the -LRB- tunnel opening -RRB- is political, to make the supporters of -LRB- Israeli -RRB- religious parties happy before the -LRB- Nov. 1 -RRB- elections,'' said <PERSON> Tahboub </PERSON>. `` Their ultimate target is to take all of the area.'' <PERSON> Gershon </PERSON> <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON>, head of a group of militant Jewish nationalists called the <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Faithful </ORGANIZATION>, agreed that the tunnel was the front line in a battle for control of the holy site. <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON> said if Moslems were able to stop the tunnel they would try to expand their influence to other areas. The group met earlier in August with right-wing Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> to press demands to open the tunnel immediately. <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Yossi </PERSON> <PERSON> Achimier </PERSON> said the premier saw <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> `` primarily as a Jewish city'' and supported Jewish rights to the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION>. But he said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s `` first priority for <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> was calm and coexistence'' and nothing would be done to stir up the situation. <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON> said any further attempts to dig beneath the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> would be unlikely because two shafts leading from the tunnel under the <ORGANIZATION> Al </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aqsa </ORGANIZATION> complex are blocked by huge stones. <PERSON> Bahat </PERSON> defended earlier excavations, saying they helped improve health standards. He said the underground chambers had been used as sewers before 1967 and that seepage had leaked into the city's water supply But <PERSON> Adnan </PERSON> <PERSON> Husseini </PERSON>, chief engineer of the Moslem trust fund that administers <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON>, said Israeli excavation caused the ground to shift, resulting in serious damage to modern houses and to Islamic buildings of the 13th, 14th and 15th centuries. `` From the time digging started cracks began to appear in buildings over the tunnel,'' said <PERSON> Husseini </PERSON>. `` This important <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> tunnel comes at the expense of our important Moslem buildings.'' To Jews, the <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> is the holiest of all sites, the site of the temple that held the tablets on which <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> wrote the Ten Commandments. To Moslems, it is the <PERSON> Haram </PERSON> <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharif </PERSON>, or Noble Enclosure in Arabic, where the Prophet <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> ascended to heaven to receive the word of God from the Angel <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> is the holiest Islamic site after the <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> cities of <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Medina </PERSON>. To Christians, the temple was the site where <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> threw out the money changers. Christian Crusaders based themselves at the temple as well, converting <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON> into a church for the Knights Templar.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0009EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-Comeback     08-15 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Comeback,0872</SECOND>
<HEAD>UN: An Old Idea Whose Time Has Come Again</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of being scorned as ineffective and anti-American, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> is making a comeback as a potent instrument of international peacemaking, an old idea whose time has come again. Blue-helmeted <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping troops are peering through binoculars from the beaches of <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> to the mountains of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. About 350 soon will monitor a cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war, and they are likely to be deployed in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> under emerging peace pacts. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> owes its revitalized role to the superpowers' improved relations and their interest in redirecting resources from regional conflict to economic development If the organization is on a roll, it is because the superpowers have decided the time has come to exploit it. Recent mediation between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, leading to a planned cease-fire Aug. 20 in their 8-year-old war, has been the major accomplishment of Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. It followed a U.N.-brokered settlement in April between <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, providing for the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> after nearly nine years. The Afghan settlement was the culmination of years of patient diplomacy. When the Soviet leadership decided to cut its losses and withdraw, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> was there. A force of 50 unarmed <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observers is monitoring the withdrawal, which is to be completed by Feb. 15. `` As rarely before, we can see the organization's potential for peace, its utility as a trusted good officer,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said last week. `` Its peacemaking and peacekeeping can yet bring hope to those afflicted by endless violence.'' The momentum is building. A major <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> role is forseen in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops are separating Greek and Turkish communities on the divided island, and in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> to end the Vietnamese occupation. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops are also expected to monitor a troop withdrawal from <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, occupied by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in defiance of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions, and a transition to independence in the territory. For years, massive <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> work in refugee aid, family planning, economic and agricultural development, childhood innoculation, teacher training and other areas was overlooked as the world focused on the organization's inability to end conflicts. Suddenly, years of diplomacy seem to be bearing fruit. For all the fanfare, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> is desperately short on funds. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the first of the superpowers to rediscover the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> as a tool of foreign policy, is now paying its back dues and peacekeeping arrears. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> now hails the organization as a forum for `` new political thinking.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, by contrast, is the biggest <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> debtor. It has been withholding about $ 467 million in regular budget payments over several years and about $ 70 million in peacekeeping dues. For years, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> denounced the organization as an intrusion upon its sovereign right to act unilaterally and said it did n't like leftist <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> politics. It charged the body with squandering funds on Third World causes and refused to pay until reforms were promised. Now, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> praises <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> accomplishments in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. But the money is not forthcoming. `` Now we face a new irony,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said. `` At the very time when the pursuit of peace quickens its pace throughout the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, bankruptcy threatens to close the organization.'' If the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other debtor nations do not come up with funds soon, the organization could close this fall. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, successor to the League of Nations, was created in 1945 as an organization of peace-loving states repelled by World War II. Its aim was to maintain peace and security and work for social progress. One of the organization's most enduring problems in the last 40 years has been the search for a resolution of the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. Each time the region has been threatened by war, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has sent impartial observers or peacekeeping forces. It has launched five peace-keeping operations since <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was created in 1948, during which time six wars have broken out. The first <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> observer operation in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> was the U.N. Truce Supervision Organization. Created in the 1948 Arab-Israeli war to supervise a truce, <ORGANIZATION> UNTSO </ORGANIZATION> has remained to monitor armistice agreements between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and its neighbors. Another <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> success in the region was the creation in 1956 of its first peacekeeping force, the U.N. <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, when Israeli, British and French forces moved into <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. The force was essential in bringing about a cease-fire and the withdrawal of invading forces. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> troops sent to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> in 1964 maintained peace before and after the Turkish invasion of 1974. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> operation in the <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION> from 1960 to 1964 helped restore peace but it was criticized for partisanship during a provincial secession and the intervention of Belgian troops.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> is The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' chief correspondent at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and a former bureau chief in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-SexLies     08-15 0495</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Sex Lies,0510</SECOND>
<HEAD>One-Third Of Young Men Have Lied To Have Sex, Study Finds</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Asking about a sexual partner's health or sexual history is not a reliable means of avoiding AIDS because many people lie to have sex, a researcher says. One-third of sexually experienced male college students and 10 percent of women admitted in a study that they have told a lie of some sort to get someone to sleep with them, the researcher said. `` Asking partners about risk factors is probably not a very good strategy for reducing the risk of AIDS,'' said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, associate professor in the psychology department of <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Northridge </LOCATION>. She described results of her survey Saturday at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON> said she began the study after noticing that many women were asking sex partners about past behavor that carries a risk of AIDS infection as a way to reassure themselves about having sex with the man. People can get infected with the virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome by having sex with an infected person or using an infected needle or contaminated blood products. Questioning partners about their drug use and sexual history is not an effective substitute for taking precautions such as using condoms, she said. The study focused on 422 unmarried, sexually experienced college students at two <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> campuses. Ages ranged from 18 to 25 with an average of 19. Forty-six percent were men. Thirty-five percent of men admitted to telling a lie to have sex. In addition, 47 percent of men and 60 percent of women reported that somebody had lied to them in order to have sex. The study did not specify what the respondents had lied about. Other questions asked what the person would do if honesty threatened the chance to have sex or to maintain a desired dating relationship. Asked if they would falsely claim to have taken a blood test to detect exposure to the AIDS virus, and claim the result was negative, 20 percent of men and 4 percent of women said yes. Forty-seven percent of men and 42 percent of women said they would report having had fewer sexual partners than they really did. Still, 52 percent of the women said they ask sex partners about sexual and drug histories, and 23 percent ask if partners had taken an AIDS test. `` If you ask somebody if they have risk factors and they say yes, you can be reasonably assured they're not lying,'' <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON> said. `` But if they say no, you're not really any further along than not asking.'' <PERSON> June </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinisch </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Kinsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in Sex, Gender and Reproduction, said the results make sense. `` In the dating situation, you ca n't believe and act upon information that comes from the partner,'' she said. `` You have to take care of yourself.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LittleLoungers     08-15 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Little Loungers,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Company Thinking Small With Furniture For Little People</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HIALEAH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Barty </PERSON> was delighted as he settled his 3-foot-9 frame into the blue and white chair. His feet touched the ground. `` How can you put a price on the smile that came across his face?'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Sunburst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Outdoor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Furniture </ORGANIZATION>, which is beginning production on one of the first specially designed lines for dwarfs, midgets and other adults of small stature. `` To be able to sit in a chair with your feet touching the ground is something average-size people do n't even think about,'' <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON> said. `` For little people, it's an uncommon thrill.'' <PERSON> Barty </PERSON>, a consultant on the project, said the Sunburst outdoor furniture designs are among the first of any kind of furniture produced specifically for `` little people,'' as he terms anyone afflicted by the nearly 200 different forms of dwarfism. `` We are a minority that is really a minority,'' said the 63-year-old actor in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, where he is filming a movie. `` We are mostly handicapped by physical barriers we face. Clothes have to be cut down; light switches are too high.'' `` I ca n't tell you how wonderful it felt like to sit in a chair with your feet on the ground and your back in the proper place,'' added <PERSON> Barty </PERSON>, who has championed the little people's cause since the late 1950s. Sunburst, which supplies outdoor furniture to resorts and hotels around the world, began thinking small last year with a line of children's furniture for <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION>. Company founder and president <PERSON> R.W </PERSON>. <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON>, who had built a scaled-down bar and stool set for a dwarf couple three years ago, thought the children's furniture might be adapted for the nation's 1.5 million little people A letter was sent in March to <PERSON> Barty </PERSON> at his Foundation For Little People office in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Barty </PERSON> quickly responded and arranged a visit to the Sunburst production center in <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION> shortly after the release of `` Willow,'' in which he plays a high priest `` But he immediately showed us that furniture for little people and children are very different,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON>, arranging three chairs side by side. The children's chair was smaller but in the same proportions as the adult version. The little people's model was modified with a low seat and elevated armrests to accommodate their shorter limbs and torsos. `` It was a real learning experience for us,'' <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON> said. `` You just ca n't put a little person in children's furniture. It does n't work and they are not comfortable. They have their own special dimensions.'' Sunburst, a division of <ORGANIZATION> MetalTech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, unveiled the Rainbow Collection in July at a convention in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, attended by about 600 little people. <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON> took about 80 furniture orders. Many had special requests, such as an extra narrow seat for a woman with a rare, acute form of dwarfism. The profit for Sunburst in the venture is also small, he said. `` To be candid, a big manufacturer would not touch this project,'' <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON> said. `` It's not smart business. It's not a big-volume-type deal. But this company has been fortunate, and we'd like to give something back and not just think about the dollars involved. Sunburst, which had sales of about $ 5 million last year, scored a success in 1964 with the patent of an aluminum umbrella designed to withstand harsh weather and high winds. The umbrellas are used in most fast-food franchises and many hotels worldwide, <PERSON> Buzzella </PERSON> said. `` I know they're never going to make money on making furniture for little people,'' <PERSON> Barty </PERSON> said. `` That's what makes it so special. They have gone beyond money and done something for people who have become accustomed to being ignored.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LAMayoralRace     08-15 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-LA Mayoral Race,0630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leaked Memos Derail Councilman's Challenge To Mayor Bradley</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE V. BIGELOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaked campaign strategy memos laced with coarse remarks threaten to ignite racial tensions in the early stages of a mayoral campaign that pits a Jewish city councilman against black incumbent <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. The memos were prepared by a consulting firm associated with 39-year-old City Councilman <PERSON> Zev </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON>, who is seeking to become the city's first Jewish mayor and poses by many accounts the first real challenge to <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> in a decade. Both are Democrats; the race is nonpartisan. The documents by veteran strategists <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Agostino </PERSON>, whose firm is known as BAD Campaigns, berate <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON> about his grim demeanor, mock <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s intelligence, refer to environmentalists as `` tree huggers'' and slow-growth advocates as `` crazed homeowners.'' The strategists urge <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON>, who represents a chunk of the city's largely affluent and liberal west side, to skip <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> meetings and focus his energies on fund-raising efforts among Jewish contributors. `` What we do know is that Jewish wealth in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> is endless,'' said one of the memos, which were leaked anonymously. Elsewhere, the advisers wrote: `` The reason why BAD thinks you can beat <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> is: You've got 50 IQ points on him -LRB- and that's no compliment -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> and <PERSON> D'Agostino </PERSON>, after the memos' release last week, announced their `` regrets that our private, irreverent attempts at humor might have caused embarrassment or offense.'' <PERSON> Yaroslavsky </PERSON> quickly divorced himself from the consultants, saying, `` I do not agree with many of their ideas and I find many of their statements to be insulting, insensitive and not reflective of my views.'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridley-Thomas </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, said the memos' contents `` come perilously close to being blatant racist remarks. `` At the absolute minimum they're highly insensitive,'' he said. He said the memos threaten to inflame black resentment over a perceived lack of Jewish support during <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s failed 1986 campaign for governor, and over tensions that emerged between Jews and blacks during <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s Democratic presidential bid earlier this year. The mayor, who at age 70 is seeking an unprecedented fifth term as mayor of the nation's second-largest city, denounced the memos as unprincipled and potentially racially divisive. `` Talking about the relative intelligence of candidates is of no consequence,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. `` I think I've demonstrated over the years my intelligence and my ability to handle the public's problems. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> has become politically vulnerable because of his protracted tenure of 16 years and position on environmental issues. He has switched from opposition to approval of a proposed onshore drilling project near <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palisades </LOCATION>, an exclusive canyon enclave overlooking the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. Despite its name, BAD Campaigns is a highly regarded firm. `` <PERSON> D'Agostino </PERSON> and <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> are extremely well-respected as very capable and talented and winning consultants,'' said former Republican <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Bobbi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON>. <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> found his advice amusing when <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> submitted similar pointed comments during <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s unsuccessful 1969 mayoral campaign and in 1973, when he was elected the first black mayor of a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city. `` When it's excerpted, it becomes a bit embarrassing,'' <PERSON> Berman </PERSON> said of the memos. `` We do n't mean to offend anybody. We had no intention of offending the mayor on the IQ.'' <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON>, summing up the controversy, said, `` I think what's happened is that the voters have been given a glimpse into what politics is really like. Political consultants in general `` tend to see themselves as the movers and shakers and the candidate as the vehicle,'' she said. `` So they often will seem somewhat arrogant and paternal to this woeful candidate.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Marcos     08-15 0746</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marcos,0768</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos' Home Province Still Backs Him</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT H. REID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAOAG, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In his northern <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> stronghold, <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> remains a pervasive, respected figure more than two years after a Manila-based uprising toppled his 20-year authoritarian regime. `` I tell you that if he ran again, he would win hands down here,'' said <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Benemerito </PERSON>, mayor of the town of <LOCATION> Pagudpud </LOCATION> in the province of <LOCATION> Ilocos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norte </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was born in 1917. `` You know, we Ilocanos are very clannish.'' In most of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> years are associated with massive corruption, economic mismanagement and oppression. President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where he fled after the February 1986 uprising that propelled her to power. But in his native province, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> still enjoys widespread respect among his fellow Ilocanos. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> rewarded the province, which has a population of about 440,000, with roads and development projects. Ilocanos are strongly represented within the armed forces, although precise figures are not available. Rep. <PERSON> Roque </PERSON> <PERSON> Ablan </PERSON>, a pro-Marcos congressman, says allegations of massive corruption and embezzlement of up to $ 10 billion have not significantly dented support for the ousted leader. `` In spite of all the accusations and charges, we still look up to Mr. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Ablan </PERSON> said. `` We would like to see him come home, which is the right of every Filipino.'' The spirit of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> looms over this province, about 250 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Rural bus stops and walls of buildings in <LOCATION> Laoag </LOCATION>, the provincial capital, still bear graffiti such as `` No To Cory'' or `` Marcos Once More,'' his slogan in the fraud-tainted 1986 election. Most provincial and municipal officials elected in regional balloting in January are members of or have been aligned with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, which has virtually disintegrated elsewhere in the country. In the town hall of <LOCATION> Batac </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> family ancestral home, pictures of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, hang on the walls of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> office. There is no picture of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. `` People here still respect Mr. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Ruben </PERSON> <PERSON> Abaya </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic priest in <LOCATION> Batac </LOCATION>. `` They would like to see him come home, although not necessarily as president. They respect him for his intelligence.'' Pro-Marcos politicians insist they are no longer anxious for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return as president but as a private citizen. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> claimed he won the 1986 election against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> and left <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> only after having himself sworn into office. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> loyalists were linked to at least three major attempts to topple the Aquino government. `` In all our conversations with Mr. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, he always told us to cooperate with the Aquino government and join hands to fight the communists,'' <PERSON> Ablan </PERSON> said. But not every Ilocano is a dedicated <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> loyalist. Communist rebels have made strong inroads in <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> since 1981, and by military estimates there may be as many as 500 Ilocanos in the communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. Pro-Marcos sympathies were whipped up three months ago when supporters of the former president spread reports he would come home for the funeral of his mother, <PERSON> Josefa </PERSON>, who died May 4. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> refused to allow him to return, and the mother is still unburied. Still, rumors persist that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> will return soon. The province's association with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has not been a handicap under the new administration. Provincial Gov. <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Farinas </PERSON> said the Aquino government has not discriminated against <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> in the allocation of state funds. But the <ORGANIZATION> Laoag </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION>, which once received charter flights from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, has been closed to foreign traffic since September 1986 to prevent <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> from slipping into the counry. Airport manager <PERSON> Numeriano </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramones </PERSON> said only three flights a week come in from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Security guards doze on the tables next to X-ray machines, and goats, cattle and stray dogs wander over the tarmac. Residents of a nearby village have erected a makeshift basketball court at the southeastern end of the tarmac. The closing of the <LOCATION> Laoag </LOCATION> airport to international traffic has severely curtailed business at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ilocandia </LOCATION>, a 196-room resort built to host the wedding reception of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' daughter <PERSON> Irene </PERSON>. It was hoped the resort and its casino would attract high rollers from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and Filipino immigrant families from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wishing to vacation in their homeland. Last week, the hotel had only three guests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Corruption     08-15 0929</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Corruption,0961</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Opens Corruption Reporting Center</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The phone has been ringing off the hook with calls from ordinary citizens at the Embezzlement and <ORGANIZATION> Bribery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reporting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> ever since it opened in the east district of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The office is a sign of the times in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, as the government tries to control corruption all over the country. `` The response of the people has been excellent,'' said a frazzled <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuhua </PERSON>, the 35-year-old station head, a week after the center opened July 29. `` They are very curious and have many complaints.'' Housed in a cramped 19th century mud-and-mortar dwelling, capped with the traditional sweeping eaves of a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> home, the center is in a <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> alley, next to a butcher shop. `` We wanted the people to be at home,'' <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> said. `` If we stuck it on the fifth floor of a government building, no one would come see us.'' The station is manned six days a week for eight hours a day and is equipped with a telephone answering service for after-hours calls. In all, the station is responsible for about 6,000 government employees serving 1.5 million people. All reports are taken in secret to protect the callers and all investigations are handled by the reporting station. `` Too much corruption is investigated in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> by the corrupt bureau itself,'' said <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Songching </PERSON>, the 50-year-old director of the east district's investigative wing. `` But this reporting station will do its own work. We are eager to see results.'' Similar corruption reporting centers are opening all over the country and the government says that by September every province will one. In addition, a telephone corruption hotline opened in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in early August, ready to take calls from across the nation. <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> said such devices are necessary if <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is going to reform its government. `` In the past the government always policed itself,'' he explained. `` Now we've got to have the support of the masses. We ca n't clean up the government alone.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has always tolerated a certain level of official dishonesty. `` Guanxi,'' or connections, are the grease upon which the wheels of society run. But lately corruption has been getting out of hand. `` I am shocked at the change in my country,'' said <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Poming </PERSON>, who returned in July after eight years in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Corruption is everywhere. School teachers force their students to buy breakfast from them to make more money. Students steal tests and sell them for a profit.'' `` Corruption and inflation, that's all we Chinese are talking about,'' said <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuanshang </PERSON>, a bookstore owner in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. `` We are worried that all the dirt will stop the reforms.'' The reforms, pushed for the last decade by national leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, have helped to double <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s gross national product in five years to $ 295 billion in 1987. But, by creating a two-track pricing system of low state-set prices and higher free market prices, the reforms have created vast opportunities for illegal deals. In late July, 75 state-run businesses in the industrial city of <LOCATION> Wuhan </LOCATION> were exposed for making illegal profits off peasants. The firms bought state goods at fixed low prices and sold them to farmers at large profits. The reselling scheme has become so bad in the cigarette and liquor market that on July 28 the government raised the price of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s best brands by as much as 790 percent. The official press said the move was made to crush a black market that has gained a monopoly on high-quality cigarettes and spirit sales. In battling corruption, the government's policies have been unclear _ lax in one city, harsh in the next and creative somewhere else. In <LOCATION> Shenyang </LOCATION>, a northern city, the city government recently imposed a tax on banquets, cars and firecrackers, three items that officials often use public funds to buy. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Yonghang </PERSON>, 35, who had been working for several years at the state-owned <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, was executed July 25 for taking bribes in exchange for color television sets, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. In all, he received bribes worth 120,000 yuan -LRB- $ 32,400 -RRB-, which amounts to 125 years of the average urban salary. Still, because of `` guanxi,'' a great percentage of official corruption continues. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leading paper, the People's Daily -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Renmin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ribao </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, recently told of <PERSON> Gu </PERSON> <PERSON> Chengju </PERSON>, a forestry official in <LOCATION> Hunan </LOCATION> province who stole 300,000 yuan -LRB- $ 81,000 -RRB- in state funds to build an office building and a high-class guest house. Almost two years after his case was exposed, <PERSON> Gu </PERSON> has yet to be brought to justice. The reason is that <PERSON> Gu </PERSON> has been greasing the hands of local officials who were supposed to investigate him, the paper said. `` This feudalistic practice of officials shielding one another must end,'' it said in a strong editorial. Some Western analysts, notably <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> expert with the <ORGANIZATION> Asia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, view the growing corruption as a sign that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is becoming more democratic. `` During the Cultural Revolution the dirt and sleaze was just as widespread but it was being perpetrated by only a few individuals,'' <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> said. `` Now, at least, you have a situation where more people are being allowed to participate. That is not necessarily bad.'' <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuhuan </PERSON> and his colleagues at the Embezzlement and Bribery Reporting Station in east <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> do not agree. `` When a rat crosses the street the people run to beat it,'' <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> said, citing a popular proverb. `` To me, corruption is the rat and I must kill it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CVN--Parties 2ndLd-Writethru a0784 08-15 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CVN--Parties, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0784,630</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Updates throughout with Elephant Romp, editing to trim.</NOTE>
<HEAD>Delegates Let Good Times Roll in Party City of New Orleans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT CHARTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans paid $ 100 a piece for Sunday night snacks with a zoo elephant as their rollicking pre-convention weekend wound down. The Very Important Pachyderm at the `` Elephant Romp Welcome'' at <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoo </ORGANIZATION> was <PERSON> Ellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON>, who drew adoring attention from the herd of 3,600 partiers. `` It's a wonderful elephant, obviously Republican,'' said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Milke </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> delegate and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> city councilwoman. <PERSON> Ellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON>'s handler, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Holston </PERSON>, said the 1,200-pound elephant was named the convention's official mascot, and had a full schedule of national television appearances for the entire week. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> city councilman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Early </PERSON>, who took credit for the zoo party idea, said the goal was to stuff a 3-week <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> experience into three hours. `` A philosophy of this party, I think, would be that in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, we believe that throwing a party, hosting a party, really is an art. It really is a science,'' said Early, a Democrat. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> chef <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Prudhomme </PERSON> stirred chicken etoufee under one of four air-conditioned zoo tents, and <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>'s, which claims to dispense more alcohol than any bar in the world, prepared 2,000 potent Hurricanes in 15-ounce paper cups. `` This is the official drink, and we want the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> to try it,'' said <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>'s spokesman <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> Sunday was filled with dancing and Dixieland from the French Quarter to private homes in the fashionable Garden District. Jazz musicians had plenty of work. At the <ORGANIZATION> Sheraton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION>, a three-piece group entertained incoming guests, while another combo imparted Dixieland flavor to a congressional brunch. Across the street at the <ORGANIZATION> Marriott </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> sponsored a $ 20,000-plus feast featuring 1,000 pounds of seafood flown in for the occasion, and exotic treats like moose and reindeer sausage. Seafood flown into a city known for its seafood? `` That's your kind of seafood, not necessarily our kind,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> GOP chairman. `` But I do n't think there's a better party town in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> than <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. Some delegates got a head start on the festivities Saturday night with a rollicking river boat race, <LOCATION> Mardi </LOCATION> Gras-style parade and samplings of turtle soup au sherry. At the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>' Convention Center, delegates tasted the city's finest cooking and danced behind a fast-marching city high school band and miniature <PERSON> Mardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gras </PERSON> floats. The floats carried costumed party-goers who pitched plastic beads and doubloons touting the carnival's sponsor, The <ORGANIZATION> Times-Picayune </ORGANIZATION> newspaper. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, an alternate delegate from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> who has attended three conventions, scoffed at decorum and danced in the parade. `` This is the greatest party ever,'' said <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, swaying in a navy blazer and purple beads. White-uniformed servers from Commander's Palace ladled 138 gallons of turtle soup au sherry into white styrofoam bowls. At the 105-year-old restaurant, an appetizer portion runs $ 4.50. On a night of freebies, there were very few leftovers. `` The food's a big hit, and so's the parade,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Moses </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>'s supervisor. `` One nice thing about <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. It opens you up and brings you back to a childhood state. Folks start out saying about the dancing that it's really stupid. But five minutes later, they are out there chasing the band.'' Jefferson Parish Sheriff <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, a Democrat, watched the Republicans eat, drink and dance, then said with laughter, `` We'll party with them now, and then we'll slug it out this November.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-15 0975</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1014</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Athol </PERSON> <PERSON> Fugard </PERSON>, who's appearing in the off-Broadway production of his play, `` The Road to <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>,'' is heading down a new road _ an appearance on the soap opera `` One Life to Live.'' The South African playwright is to appear in the <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> soap Aug. 23 to Sept. 1. He'll portray a `` crusty old ex-sea captain'' who uses a wheelchair and lives in an abandoned lighthouse with his `` slightly strange, psychotic daughter,'' producer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rauch </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item is moving on the sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MANHATTAN BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A championship tennis match between <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gabriela </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON> was marred when someone threw a glass container of yellow paint onto the court. The container shattered about 15 feet from <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON>, who was down double match point at 15-40 at Sunday's $ 300,000 <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Slims </ORGANIZATION> contest. After a 15-minute delay to clean the court, <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON> won the next two points to go to deuce. <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON> hit a running forehand into the net, then <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> won the match when the 18-year-old from <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> netted a backhand. <PERSON> Evert </PERSON> won $ 60,000 and <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON> $ 24,000. `` I was scared,'' <PERSON> Sabatini </PERSON> said. `` I think maybe there's crazy people out there. It was difficult to go out again and play and I was down two match points.'' `` This was shocking,'' said <PERSON> Evert </PERSON>. `` I did n't even know what it was. I was more worried that if they did n't get it up it would get sticky and the match would be postponed. I just wanted to get it over with.'' Tournament promoter <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said police were investigating.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Having theater stars like <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Tandy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hume </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronyn </PERSON> as parents was n't exactly an open invitation to success on the stage, daughter <PERSON> Tandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronyn </PERSON> says. `` The first important reviewer to appraise my work gave me a bad notice,'' Ms. <PERSON> Cronyn </PERSON> said in in intwerview published Sunday in The Star-Ledger of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>. `` The part had only six lines and I was one of a group, but this eminent critic of a leading magazine took the trouble to single me out for a slam. He never would have noticed me except for my name. And I did n't choose it either.'' Ms. <PERSON> Cronyn </PERSON> has advanced beyond that role to play a Jewish girl in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> who has survived a concentration camp in an off-Broadway production of `` A <PERSON> Shayna </PERSON> <PERSON> Maidel </PERSON>'' -LRB- A Pretty Girl -RRB-. `` I thought, ` How can a WASP like me succeed as that Polish girl?''' Ms. <PERSON> Tandy </PERSON> said. `` But then I was so taken with the play, I started acting it in my mind and said, ` Why not.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PALM SPRINGS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> is trying to drum up more business for his city. The pop singer-restaurateur arrived in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> on Sunday in an attempt to sell the benefits of the desert city at a convention of trade associations. <PERSON> Bono </PERSON>'s first big publicity trip was to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> last month, where he met with Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, appeared on television and radio shows and attended another convention.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> says endorsements of beer of soft drinks are not for him and The News. `` No, we're not going to do anything like that in the future,'' the 38-year-old singer said. `` I'm from the'60s when it used to be ` us' against ` them.' ... `` If someone does it and donates the money to a worthy cause, I think that's OK. But I think when you're doing very well and you do n't need the money and you endorse a product that you're not really into ... as far as the artist, I lose them.'' <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and The News, who sold a combined 15 million albums with their last two hit LPs `` Sports'' and `` Fore!,'' are on a world tour to support their new album `` Small World.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' life and work are based on rock and shock. Fifteen years ago he started the heavy metal group KISS, which became known as much for its wild makeup and antics as its music. Now, he's managing <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON>'s recording career and has started his own record label. `` My life is based on shock. I find the idea so interesting,'' <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> said recently. `` All of that has a lot in common with my working with <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON>. Great work should shock you.'' <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> recently took on the role of manager for Miss <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON>, whose album on Epic is due out this year. KISS, which has released 23 albums, is beginning the European version of the `` Monsters of Rock'' tour. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> said KISS will be joining such rock heavies as <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, Guns and Roses and Halloween. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> turned down a role in the new <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> film, `` License Revoked,'' with <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalton </PERSON>, to go on the tour. At the same time, the 36-year-old entertainer is busy working with his newly formed record label, <ORGANIZATION> Simmons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, which is distributed by <ORGANIZATION> MCA </ORGANIZATION>. He said he founded the company because he has a good ear for picking new acts and got tired of others telling him his discoveries could n't cut it. `` I'll never listen to anyone else again,'' he said. `` Maybe I know something they do n't.'' In September, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION> will become the first group to release an album on the label. He is also expecting his first child with girlfriend <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>, a former Playmate of the Year. He said he feels `` numb'' about the whole thing. KISS will release a greatest hits album called `` Smashes Thrashes and Hits,'' by next summer. The album will include two new songs, `` Let's put the X in Sex'' and `` Rock Hard.'' `` Rock' n' roll should be sexy and fun _ with a strong backbeat,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--Reagan-Campaign Bjt   08-15 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Reagan-Campaign, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Makes Unprecedented Effort For Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a unique, farewell political role, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is taking the offensive as he campaigns for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s Republican ticket. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is center stage tonight for the address that will be the true keynote of the Republican National Convention. It also will be his grand finale, at his fourth convention as a dominant <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> figure. But it's only the start of his planned campaign. No modern president has conducted a parting campaign to match the one <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has promised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the Republicans. He expects to appear at least twice a week in behalf of the ticket and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> fund-raising efforts from Labor Day to Election Day. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s tone so far has been tough, sometimes contrasting with the reassuring style that became typical of his personal campaigning over the past dozen years. Not since <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> has a departing president been in a position to campaign for his party's nominee to succeed to the office. <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> served two full terms, and left office as a popular figure. But Vice President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, the Republican nominee in 1960, did not seek extensive campaigning from <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. Popularity is not transferable, of course. And there can be a down side for a vice president who relies heavily on the campaign favors of the president to whom he has been understudy. The vice president has to make his own imprint on the minds of voters, and he has a relatively brief time to do it. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his managers believe they can make the breakthrough beginning in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, aided, not inhibited, by an active <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> campaign. `` He'll be a great surrogate,'' said campaign manager <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>. He said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be especially helpful to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ticket in <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belt </LOCATION> states and in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Furthermore, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> may be able to help turn on and turn out conservatives, who never have counted the vice president as one of their heroes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> have carefully designed roles in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, so that the departing president wo n't overshadow the arriving nominee. The twain will meet once, on Tuesday, as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrives for the convention and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> for a vacation at his ranch near <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. From that point, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is supposed to have the starring role The tandem campaign began in the buildup to the convention, in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke to the administration's political appointees, the president telling them that the voters wo n't gamble the future on `` a blind date'' with the Democrats. In his weekly radio address on Saturday, the president said the Democrats are all talk, while `` we deliver.'' Then, in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> arrival preview of his convention address, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> hammered the Democrats, with periodic plugs for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He denounced the `` narrow agenda of the liberal elites and special interest groups,'' said the Democrats do n't want the voters to find out what they intend to do and called their <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention the biggest masquerade since <PERSON> Mardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gras </PERSON>. In all of that, he pressed a theme designed by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, the argument that Democrats are hiding from specifics and from comparison of their offerings with those of the Republicans. `` The stealth candidacy has to come out from under cover,'' said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` It's time to talk issues, to use the dreaded ` L' word, to say the policies of our opposition are liberal, liberal, liberal.'' That ` L' word is going to echo through the Superdome convention hall all week long. It is part of an attack strategy campaign the Republicans intend to make central to their campaign.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>, executive editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been covering presidential campaigns since 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador-Refugees 3rdLd-Writethru a0402 08-15 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Refugees, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0402,0870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Refugees Stranded at El Salvador's Border Released and Cross
Frontier</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with U.N. official's comments
confirming radio report. Picks up 6th graf pvs, ``They had ...''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL POY, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 1,200 Salvadoran refugees returned from <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to their homeland Sunday after being delayed at the border in a dispute over <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> church people accompanying them, a radio report said. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> High Commissioner for Refugees said by telephone that the refugees and more than 150 vehicles were allowed to enter <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> at 5:30 p.m. -LRB- 7:30 p.m. EDT -RRB- after the 15 church workers agreed to stay in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. Salvadoran government officials say many refugees sympathize with leftist guerrillas, and have accused church workers of similar leanings. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> said the refugees were on their way to hometowns in northern <LOCATION> Chalatenango </LOCATION> province. There was no immediate comment from the Salvadoran government. Members of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> church organization that had aided the refugees could not be reached for comment. Late Saturday, the convoy of 36 buses and 116 trucks carrying the refugees and their belongings were halted in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> about 500 yards from the border. They had left the <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> refugee camp 30 miles to the north under an accord worked out among the refugees, the Salvadoran government and the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> organization, which is overseeing the repatriation. Some of the Salvadorans spent up to eight years in the <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> camp. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Mendiluce </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> agency's Central American director, said the presence of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> church workers _ members of the <ORGANIZATION> Going </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> organization _ was not contemplated in the accord. Earlier Sunday, Interior Minister <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Belloso </PERSON> <PERSON> Funes </PERSON> told reporters at the border that his government `` welcomes with open arms'' the Salvadoran refugees. `` But the so-called internationalists among them are using our brothers for strictly political ends. They -LRB- the foreigners -RRB- are coming here to break our laws, and I have orders from the highest level that they not be permitted entry,'' he said. <PERSON> Amadeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, a returning refugee, had said the group was insisting the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> church workers be allowed to enter. He said the refugees were determined to wait in their mile-long convoy until their demand was met. But the 1,230 refugees, including hundreds of infants and children, had little food and appeared unprepared to spend days waiting on the road. Two pregnant women among the refugees were expected to give birth in coming days. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Vitale </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic priest from <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and spokesman for the Going Home delegation, blamed the Salvadoran government for the dispute. `` This is part of the <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> government's continuing efforts to obstruct the refugees' return,'' he said, adding that all members of his delegation had visas for <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Going Home is an interfaith organization supporting Salvadoran refugees. It participated last October in the first big repatriation of Salvadoran refugees from <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. The return of refugees is a highly charged issue in this small Central American country torn by nearly nine years of civil war. The armed forces consider the three Salvadoran refugee camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> part of the rear guard of leftist guerrillas fighting the U.S.-supported government. About 4,300 refugees returned last year and about 15,000 Salvadoran refugees remain in the camps. The Salvadoran government is concerned about their political sympathies and the burden they may place on an economy devastated by war, and so it is reluctant to collaborate with that project. But a regional peace accord signed last August underscored the right of refugees to return home, and the government eventually cooperated with the return. `` The terrorists use <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> as a refuge, to recover from wounds and to rest. The people there generally sympathize with the subversives. Their return could be detrimental to us militarily,'' army Col. <PERSON> Ciro </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Roque </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> at the border Saturday. He is commander of the 4th Brigade in charge of the northern frontier province of <LOCATION> Chalatenango </LOCATION>. But he also said that `` as a Salvadoran, I recognize that every Salvadoran has a right to be in his country, and should be here.'' The refugees intend to return to three towns in <LOCATION> Chalatenango </LOCATION> from which they fled in the early 1980s. <PERSON> Sofia </PERSON> <PERSON> Enriquez </PERSON>, who left her town of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ranchos </LOCATION> in 1982, stood beside a bus and held her infant daughter while another daughter clutched her skirt. Both girls were born in <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION>. Asked why she left, she said: `` We were persecuted. They were killing people just for the fun of it.'' Most of the 65,000 people killed in the war have been civilians. Human rights groups blame security forces and rightist death squads for most of the tens of thousands of political murders in the early 1980s. Such killings dropped off dramatically after 1983. Ms. <PERSON> Enriquez </PERSON>, 25, said she hoped for a better life in her own country. But asked how she planned to manage as a single mother with two children, no home and no job, she said: `` Who knows.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-CVN--Bush-Weaknesses     08-15 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CVN--Bush-Weaknesses,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Delegates Identify Bush Shortcomings As Well As Strengths</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Republicans who are about to nominate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for president see some 200 shortcomings in the candidate. They say he's too liberal or too conservative, too nice or too honest, too rich or too loyal. A few uttered the word `` wimp'' but others defended <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> against such a label. `` He's a lousy campaigner,'' carped <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> lawyer whose favorite candidate, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, lost out to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the race for the nomination. `` He has n't been elected to a major office for quite a few years, and I'm a little worried about that, I guess,'' <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Warkenthien </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> said of the man who was elected vice president in 1980 and 1984. <PERSON> Proctor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Warkenthien </PERSON> were among 1,215 delegates to the Republican National Convention who responded to an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey. In all, 2,277 delegates will attend the convention which opens today in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. When asked to identify <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s major strengths and weaknesses, delegates' responses fell into 228 categories on his weaknesses and 127 on his strengths. Sixty-three percent of the delegates said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s experience in government, especially his work in foreign policy, would be his greatest asset in the fall election. `` In all the years that I have been attending national conventions, there has not been a single aspirant who has the congressional, executive and leadership experience'' of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hering </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, who has been attending conventions since 1964. In addition to serving as vice president, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been director of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s biggest problem, according to those who are about to nominate him for president, is his image and speaking style. Nearly 32 percent of the delegates cited these as the obstacles he needs to overcome in his race for the White House. Many said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had been unfairly labeled as a `` wimp'' and blamed the news media for pinning that on him. `` He is perceived as being weak _ the wimp factor _ a <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> character,'' said <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillot </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a delegate from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. `` It is n't weakness, it's decency, integrity, but people see it as weakness and it could cost him the election.'' <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> delegate <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sexton </PERSON> was direct: `` They do n't put wimps in as head of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>. The delegates see being vice president as both a blessing and a curse, allowing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to be a part of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's successes but also forcing him to take the heat for its failures while keeping his opinions to himself `` He's the vice president, which is a weak office. Someone said it ai n't worth a cup of warm spit and he has proven how true that is,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, a delegate from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` He will end up apologizing for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on civil rights issues, ethics issues, economic issues,'' <PERSON> Clement </PERSON> said. `` He's got a lot of baggage.'' While there was no shortage of criticism, almost all of the delegates also had nice things to say about their nominee. `` When he tells you something, you can believe him,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Steen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. `` His greatest strength is the fact that he's been part of an administration that has seen the country come from the brink of disaster to a very solid, stable situation in about every aspect,'' said <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Munro </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. `` I do n't think he would have been made head of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> if he was n't intelligent,'' said <PERSON> Marguerite </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>. And finally there was a piece of advice. `` If he can appear as the All-American Boy Scout, that'll be his strength,'' said <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> delegate <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>, who was impeached and removed from office as the state's governor in April.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880815-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-15-88 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Letterman     08-15 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Letterman,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Butter Sculpture To Melt On Letterman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
