<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hijack 1stLd-Writethru   04-15 0935</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijack, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0693,0962</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hostages Plea For Their Lives, Beg Kuwait To Give In To Demands</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 7th graf ``One hostage...'' with 22 grafs to UPDATE with
one of hijackers believed to be suspect in 1985 TWA hijacking.
Pickup 8th graf pvs ``The Boeing...''</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ALG1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GOLDSMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two hostage passengers on a hijacked <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> jet pleaded for their lives via radio Friday and urged the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> government to give in to the demands of the Shiite Moslem gunmen. Algerian mediators shuttled between the booby-trapped jet and <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> officials on Friday, the 11th day of the crisis. The masked gunmen who commandeered the jumbo jet on a flight from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> on April 5 want <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> to release 17 terrorists convicted of bombing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and French embassies in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> in 1982. `` In the name of God the merciful, I greet my family and my friends and I ask the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> authorities to free the 17 prisoners held in <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> prisons,'' said <PERSON> Soleiman </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Soleiman </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Mashari </PERSON>, one hostage, in a message to the control tower. `` In the event of refusal, they are going to kill us.'' In a second message, a man identifying himself as <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Ajem </PERSON> said: `` I am one of the hostages from the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION>. I greet my family, large and small and I ask the Kuwaiti authorities to free the prisoners in the prisons. Without that, the kidnappers have decided to kill us.'' An estimated 31 passengers and four crew members were being held in grim conditions by eight hijackers, armed with guns and grenades. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration official speaking on condition of anonymity said a man wanted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the 1985 hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> jetliner was believed to be one of the gunmen on the Kuwaiti plane. The official said the man, <PERSON> Hasan </PERSON> <PERSON> Izz-Al-Din </PERSON>, was named in a 1987 federal indictment charging him and three others with conspiracy to commit air piracy, murder and assault in the hijacking in which 39 Americans were held hostage and a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sailor was killed. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747, which had 112 passengers aboard when it began its journey, was diverted to <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, then to <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. Fifty-seven passengers were released in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and another 13 in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. Two passengers were killed in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. The air pirates have threatened to kill the remaining hostages and blow up the plane if their demands are not met. Algerian officials expressed disappointment Friday that negotiations at the airport had not achieved better results. Negotiations began Wednesday, shortly after the plane arrived from <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>. Western sources in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> said it was believed that parallel, high-level negotiations were also taking place between <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> acting as an intermediary. A report by the official <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> news agency Friday said the hijackers appeared to be divided over the negotiations, and it seemed that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was directing the hard-line faction. Some of the hijackers believed to have boarded in <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION> had in recent hours become `` more extremist and obstinate,'' said the agency KUNA, without citing any sources. State-owned <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> radio reported that <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Sad </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Abdallah </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON> on Friday telephoned Algerian Premier <PERSON> Abdelhamid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brahimi </PERSON> to discuss `` the intensification of efforts being exerted to bring about the release of the passengers.'' The radio report, monitored in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, gave no details. On Thursday, the hijackers released <PERSON> Djuma </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdallah </PERSON> <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON>, 70, a diabetic who was in urgent need of an insulin injection. Before his release, he had been examined on board the plane by an Algerian doctor who told the hijackers <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> was in danger of dying if he did not receive treatment. After <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> was freed, the gunmen issued a statement saying, `` We are not highway bandits.'' However, the hijackers repeated their demand and said they would carry out executions `` even if the price we have to pay is very high.'' A <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> official, who insisted on anonymity, said <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> reported that all of the hostages had their wrists handcuffed behind their backs. They were not allowed to speak or move from their seats in the mid-section of the plane except to be escorted to the toilets by one of the gunmen, who kept a pistol pointed at the hostage's back. <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> said the hostages were completely ignorant of the negotiations. He said there were eight hijackers and that passengers were grouped in seat rows 22 to 36, located directly above the fuel tanks. A <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> official who demanded anonymity said <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> told the <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> delegation that four bombs were attached to the four doors in the midsection of the plane. Among the hostages are three members of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>'s royal family and at least four crew members. Algerian officials on Thursday privately expressed optimism that their separate negotiations with the Shiite Moslem hijackers and a <LOCATION> Kuwaiti </LOCATION> delegation would lead to the release of the last two women on board, cousins of the emir of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. There was widespread disappointment when only <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> was freed. <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> said the hostage treated most roughly was the <PERSON> Fadel </PERSON> <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON> <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON>, 33, cousin of the emir of <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, regarded as the hijackers' trump card. <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON> suffered from a severe nervous disorder even before he boarded the plane in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, and the experience of the hijack `` seems to have put him over the brink,'' <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Chatti </PERSON> said <PERSON> Al-Sabah </PERSON> had continuous violent shakes, was unable to speak and cries continuously. The hijackers brought a microphone to him and tried to force him to make a statement, but he was unable to do so.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 2332EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Hijack-Suspect 1stLd-Writethru   04-15 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hijack-Suspect, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0725,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Imad Mughniyeh Pegged As Mastermind Of Kuwait Airways Hijacking</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with one hijacker wanted in
United States in 1985 TWA hijacking. Pickup 3rd graf pvs ``Western
intelligence...''</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The alleged mastermind behind the hijacking of <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> Flight 422 is a longtime fugitive from justice linked to two earlier hijacks. <PERSON> Imad </PERSON> <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>, 36, is one of four suspects wanted by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in the hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> airliner on June 14, 1985, by Shiite Moslem extremists. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver was killed and 39 Americans were held hostage for 17 days before being freed after Syrian intervention. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration official said another man wanted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> hijacking was believed to be a hijacker on the Kuwaiti plane. The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the man, <PERSON> Hasan </PERSON> <PERSON> Izz-Al-Din </PERSON>, was named in a 1987 federal indictment charging him and three others with conspiracy to commit air piracy, murder and assault in the hijacking. Western intelligence agencies also believe <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> was involved in the December 1984 hijacking of a Kuwaiti airliner to <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> that left two Americans dead. Iranian security forces stormed the plane after five days. The hijackers disappeared and <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> has issued no word about them. Western sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> is the leader of a clan, one of several in the <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> of eastern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> that control the drug trade in there. He also is chief of security for the pro-Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God, in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> is considered by Western and Lebanese intelligence agencies to be the umbrella organization for groups holding foreigners hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>'s cousin and brother-in-law is one of the three Shiites among the 17 imprisoned in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> who have been sentenced to death. Western observers have said it is this family connection that has fueled <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>'s mission to free the 17 terrorists. The Kuwaitis have identified the condemned man as <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Saab </PERSON>, but his real name is <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Badreddin </PERSON>. He entered <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> on a forged Iraqi passport, Western intelligence authorities said. Ever since <PERSON> Badreddin </PERSON> was arrested in <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> has tried to free him. <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> dropped out of sight in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> several weeks ago, according to well-informed sources who asked not to be identified. One of <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>'s factions is the Islamic Jihad, or Islamic Holy War, the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> group holding foreigners hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. It has said it would free the Americans they hold if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> frees the 17 terrorists. <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> has refused and the hijacking of the Kuwaiti airliner, which was taken first to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, then to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> and finally to <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>, has not changed that stance. At one point during talks in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> negotiators said the hijackers offered to release half their hostages if <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> freed the three among the 17 who had been sentenced to death. <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>'s cousin is among the three. The Cypriots, acting on Kuwaiti advice, rejected the offer. But it underlined <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON>'s suspected role in the hijacking. Western intelligence sources believe that <PERSON> Mughniyeh </PERSON> joined the hijacked Kuwaiti airliner in <LOCATION> Mashhad </LOCATION>, northeastern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, when it landed there after it was seized during a flight from <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 3dLd-Writethru a0831 04-15 0883</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 3d Ld-Writethru, a0831,0905</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panama Protests U.S. Blocking Of Highway</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS 4th graf that Nevglovski has been a Marine for 24
years, stead 24 years old.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By REID G. MILLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> sent a formal protest to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> on Friday alleging <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> violations of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s sovereignty during a firefight involving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines this week. The protest said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops closed a <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> highway just outside the capital for three hours Tuesday night after fighting broke out between `` soldiers of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and an unknown group.'' At a news conference called by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military, Marine 1st Sgt. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> said Friday that his company became engaged in a gunfight Tuesday night at a fuel depot with uniformed men `` who were using us as training aids.'' `` They were highly professional,'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON>, who has served for 24 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, told the news conference at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Southern Command's headquarters. `` They were good. They were trying to provoke us.'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lejeune </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, said the intruders wore black uniforms and carried sophisticated night - vision equipment, but declined to speculate on whether they were members of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> In the protest sent to <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Abadia </PERSON> called the highway closing a `` flagrant violation of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s sovereignty'' by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops. According to earlier reports, the highway was closed after about 100 Marines exchanged fire with what they described as 40 to 50 uniformed intruders at the fuel dump near <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, a few miles west of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> said it consulted with the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> before closing the highway for `` security reasons.'' Col. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Sconyers </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>'s chief spokesman, said <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> was presented at the news conference Friday to answer reporters' questions because of skeptical reports in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and ridicule in the Panamanian press, which is largely controlled by the government. <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> told of two separate firefights Tuesday night, and said that during one eight Marines and a sailor were surrounded by a group of intruders about half a mile from the sergeant's position. No casualties were reported Tuesday, but a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> was shot and fatally wounded by fellow Marines in an incident Monday. <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said the fatal shooting occurred as the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> tried to encircle eight intruders wearing black uniforms and moving in military fashion. The Defense Forces are commanded by Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who is under federal indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has imposed economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in an effort to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who dominates the civilian government, to resign. <PERSON> Sconyers </PERSON> said a full investigation into the actions Monday and Tuesday was under way. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> maintains about 10,000 military personnel in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> as a permanent force to defend the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. About 1,300 additional <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers and Marines were sent to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> last week to increase security. The Panamanian government has described the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Marines as inexperienced troops who were `` shooting at swaying palm trees.'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON>'s account of Tuesday's incidents left unanswered the questions of who were the intruders and why in more than two hours of sporadic gunfire were there apparently no injuries on either side. He was asked to assess the intruders' motives and the sergeant replied: `` They were basically using us as training aides, to see how they can get around and how they ca n't get around, to see how they can get detected and how they ca n't get detected.'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> raised a new question when he said <PERSON> Marines </PERSON> did not chase the intruders into the surrounding jungle because a month or so earlier `` two <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> MPs chased an intruder into the jungle and one was hacked to death with a machete and the other was cut up pretty bad.'' No such incident had been announced and after the news conference military spokesmen said <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> had repeated a rumor that had no basis in fact. And while <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said he had a group of about 42 intruders almost constantly in view with a night-vision device, `` I did n't see a weapon on them I ca n't say why. We could see them clearly.'' He said of the shooting: `` We received the first three rounds and our -LRB- return fire -RRB- lasted about 15 minutes. What I could identify was three or four -LRB- muzzle -RRB- flashes coming from a certain area.'' `` At that time I immediately went to my machine gunner and tapped him on the shoulder and told him to return fire,'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said. `` He returned fire, approximately 10 or 15 rounds, and I tapped him again and told him to cease fire.'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said another Marine opened fire at the same time with a second machine gun, but `` none of the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> used their weapons or pistols because the word had n't been given to open fire.'' <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said that while he and about 90 other Marines were engaged with more than 40 intruders, another group of nine <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> servicemen were surrounded by `` about 10 other intruders'' on a hill half a mile away. The two groups were in radio contact, <PERSON> Nevglovski </PERSON> said, and at least three 80mm mortar rounds were fired at the intruders' positions
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FourSlain 3rdLd-Writethru a0843 04-15 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Four Slain, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0843,0795</SECOND>
<BYLINE>URGENT</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Four Found Stabbed To Death in Mobile Home; Ex-Boyfriend Arrested</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with suspect identified as a
former boyfriend of one of the victims; PICKS UP 18th graf pvs,
`The victims' ...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos SA2,3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID SEDENO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A boy and his three teen-age sisters were found mutilated in their home and stabbed so hard with steak knives that the blades broke, and a former boyfriend of one victim was arrested, police said. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Narvaiz </PERSON>, 20, was taken into custody after being treated at a hospital for a stab wound to his thigh and a cut on the hand. He was charged with four counts of capital murder, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Grego </PERSON>, court officer for Magistrate <PERSON> Quon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lew </PERSON>. <PERSON> Narvaiz </PERSON> was taken back to <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> after a late-night hearing and will be transferred to <ORGANIZATION> Bexar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jail </ORGANIZATION> on $ 4.05 million bail, <PERSON> Grego </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Narvaiz </PERSON> had broken up with 17-year-old <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> in the past three weeks and had been named in two complaints filed by the teen-ager's father, one alleging a terroristic threat, said homicide Lt. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>. `` He had been trying to get back with her and since he was unable to, we figure this is what prompted him to break into the house and commit these murders,'' <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> said. Miss <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> was found slain along with her sisters, <PERSON> Jenniffer </PERSON>, 19, and <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>, 14, and brother <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON>, 13, in their mobile home early Friday. `` We figure he either surprised them in their sleep or there's a possibility that more than one person was involved, which would have kept them from running out or anything like that. We ca n't tell for sure,'' said <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> said a girl called the 911 emergency number about 3:27 a.m. and said `` one of my sister's boyfriends is beating us up and has killed my sister.'' Police were able to trace the call and found the bodies at 3:55 a.m., <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> said. Police said at least five steak knives were used in the slayings and that more could have been carried off from the five-bedroom mobile home. `` It's unbelievable. All of them were savagely stabbed. There are knives broken off in their necks,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a 28-year member of the department. `` It's a slaughterhouse.'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Mireles </PERSON>, who lives across from the trailer park, said there have been numerous robberies there and that she heard a commotion early Friday, and thought she heard gunshots. `` I heard a lot of screams,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Mireles </PERSON> said. `` They were screaming, ` Help' and they were crying and screaming and I told my husband and he said, ` No, let's not get involved.''' `` He thought they would shoot at anybody who went out to see what was going on,'' she said. The 10-acre park in a quiet neighborhood has a full-patrol security system, plus a swimming pool and well-equipped recreation center, said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Byers </PERSON>, a supervisor for Mobile Home Park. He described residents as middle-class. `` These people have been screened,'' he said. The victims' parents, <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> and <PERSON> Becky </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, are separated. Mrs. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> was living with the children but was not home at the time of the attack, police said. Police Lt. <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinson </PERSON> said officers were unable to determine if the girls had been sexually assaulted. The bodies were so mutilated that police first reported that four girls had been killed. But Mrs. <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> later confirmed that one was a boy. She collapsed after identifying them, police said. At one point, the victims' father struck a television cameraman and four officers restrained him from striking a second one. `` Get those cameras out of here. This is not a carnival!'' <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Janice </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>, a friend of the girls, said the family moved in about a month ago and were known for throwing parties for neighborhood friends. `` They loved to have fun. They just wanted some attention,'' Ms. <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> said. `` They just wanted friends.'' <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON>, 20, said she had worked with <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> at a grocery store until Miss <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> resigned about four months ago. `` She would n't talk, but she asked me about married life and said she was wanting to move in with her boyfriend,'' Ms. <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> said. `` They were always breaking up but she said she loved him. `` She said that he hit her and that he also broke into her other house but that she still wanted to marry him.'' <PERSON> Darrell </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynt </PERSON>, principal of <ORGANIZATION> McCollum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> withdrew from school last November as a sophomore, and <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> dropped out of school in 1985 as a junior.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-FinanceMinisters 2ndLd-Writethru a0811 04-15 1089</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Finance Ministers, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0811,1050</SECOND>
<HEAD>US, Allies Try To Put Best Face On Dollar's Tumble</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: INSERTS 1 graf after 9th graf pvs bgng, `In Europe' to UPDATE
with dollar opening lower but then stabilizing in Tokyo early
Friday</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dollar plunged on world currency markets Thursday in reaction to bad news on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit despite a massive coordinated effort on the part of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its economic allies to halt the slide. The dollar's steep dive served served as an ominous reminder to the world's economic powers that their best-laid plans to steady the global economy can be quickly disrupted by events. Just as it had done several times last year, the weakness in the dollar quickly spread to other financial markets, sending interest rates up sharply and pushing the Dow Jones Industrial Average down by more than 100 points, its second three-digit loss this year. The market turmoil came only a day after the world's seven major industrial countries had issued a glowing communique bragging about their ability to hold the dollar stable for the past four months. Finance ministers and central bank presidents of the seven nations _ the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britian </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> _ reaffirmed on Wednesday their commitment to keep the dollar stable. They pledged to back up the commitment with coordinated intervention, the process by which governments dump other currencies in exchange for dollars as a way of supporting the greenback. Participants in the day-long Wednesday meeting said they had not been told in advance by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> that the February trade deficit would be an unexpectedly large $ 13.8 billion, triggering the need for intervention. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is briefed a day in advance on government economic reports. The finance ministers professed satisfaction with the way their cooridnation effort had worked Thursday, but the dollar still closed sharply lower against other currencies. In <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, the dollar fell to 123.60 yen, breaking through a 125-yen barrier which has been considered the lower level for the greenback over the past four months. In <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Friday, the dollar opened a sharp 1.7 percent lower against the yen but stabilized later at that level on reports of heavy dollar-buying by the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION>. While the global recession which some predicted following last October's market collapse has not materialized, the turmoil Thursday served as an chilling reminder of the continued fragility of world economy. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and finance ministers from other countries tried to put the best face on the dollar's tumble Thursday, contending that the speed with which the countries intervened to support the dollar showed that the drive for international cooperation was working. Currency traders reported that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the central banks of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> were among those intervening to brake the dollar's fall. `` I think what you see today is a very good example of international cooperation because there has been concerted intervention in support of the dollar involving a very large number of countries,'' <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, the British chancellor of the exchequer, said in a briefing for reporters. The surge in the trade deficit and the dollar's tumble were among the items discussed by the world finance leaders as they continued their talks Thursday. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, the prime architect of the three-year effort to manage the level of the dollar, was grim-faced when he arrived for the meetings, held at the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. He brushed past reporters without answering any questions, but later his office released a text of comments he made during the closed-door session in which he played down the significance of February's widening of the trade deficit and stressed the resolve of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its allies to keep the value of the dollar stable. `` Monthly trade figures are by their nature erratic. What is important is that we are continuing along the general path of reduced imbalances,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has made progress in reducing its huge federal budget deficits, something other countries have long urged. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> singled out <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for praise in efforts to stimulate their domestic economies as a way of keeping the global economy growing. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s comments were echoed by other finance ministers, who also dismissed the February jump in the deficit as an aberration. But the swift drop in the dollar's value raised questions of how successful countries will be over the long term in keeping the dollar at its present levels. Many economists have forecast that the dollar will eventually have to decline more to solve <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s trade problems In their Dec. 22 accord, the countries pledged to keep the dollar stable around current levels. While the governments have never been specific about just what those levels were, speculation has put the lower limit for the dollar at 125 yen. After it fell below that level Thursday, West German Finance Minister <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoltenberg </PERSON>, was asked whether the countries would have to accept a new level for the dollar. `` That is a very good question, a thousand-dollar question,'' he answered. The dollar turmoil also raised the possibility that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> would be forced to tighten interest rates further in this country to defend the dollar. Higher <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interest rates, while slowing the American economy, are seen as a positive for the greenback because foreign investors are able to earn more on their dollar-denominated investments. <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Poehl </PERSON>, head of the West German central bank, sidestepped questions about whether the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> should tighten up during a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>. With <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> looking on, <PERSON> Poehl </PERSON> said, `` I do n't want to comment on <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> monetary and fiscal policies.'' He said he believed that his country had done its part to stimulate world growth by lowering <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> interest rates. `` As far as -LRB- our -RRB- monetary policy is concerned, we could n't have done more. We have the lowest interest rates in the world ... and it would be irresponsible to pursue more expansionary monetary policies,'' <PERSON> Poehl </PERSON> said. It was a heated dispute between <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and the West Germans last year over interest rates which has been cited as one of the contributing factors to Oct. 19 stock market plunge. Since that time, world finance leaders have gone out of their way to stress harmony and coordinated efforts to keep the global economy from toppling into another recession.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-JaiAlaiStrike     04-15 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jai Alai Strike,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Players Strike In Connecticut, Rhode Island and Florida</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANNE McGRATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jai </PERSON> alai players went on strike in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> on Thursday to protest what they say are unfair working conditions and harassment since organizing a union earlier this year. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Aries </PERSON>, a lawyer for the 500-member <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Players </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the strike affected frontons in <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION>, and many of the 10 frontons in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Frontons are buildings that house courts where the handball-like game is played before spectators who bet on the matches. People who answered the telephones in <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> said the frontons were n't open because players were n't working. There was no answer at the <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> facility. In <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, two frontons in <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> canceled performances Thursday. Frontons in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, remained open using non-striking and substitute players. Officials at all frontons in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> except <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said they expected to be open Friday. The others are in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Carbone </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> fronton </LOCATION>, said management signed about six players Thursday night and expected to have between 15 and 20 players ready for Friday's program There are about 550 jai alai players in the three states, <PERSON> Aries </PERSON> said. He said about 90 percent of them have joined the association. <PERSON> Aries </PERSON> said that members of the association have been forbidden from wearing the union's insignia and that at least five players have been told their contracts will be terminated. `` The players were unable to tolerate the continuing harassment and intimidation that has followed their organizing into an association,'' <PERSON> Aries </PERSON> said. `` They had put up with a lot during the course of their regular employment ... with contracts that allowed fronton owners to dominate them.'' The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> has conducted hearings in <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on the association's request that federal officials oversee union authorization votes at the 14 frontons in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aries </PERSON> said there have been no decisions from the <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NLRB </ORGANIZATION> offices, and the hearings are continuing in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-15 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0993</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The `` Rat Pack'' tour has become `` The Ultimate Event,'' as <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> joined forces with <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> for an 18-concert, 12-city <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour. <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> had begun a recent singing tour with rat-pack buddy <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> had to drop out after six concerts when an old kidney problem flared up. `` We miss <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> and we love him _ he's like a brother to me and <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> said Thursday. `` <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> is the greatest female performer of our time. She is a great lady and it is always a privilege to share a stage with her.'' The tour, dubbed `` The Ultimate Event,'' will debut at <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>'s Summit Arena on Sept. 17 and end at the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Theater on Oct. 16, said <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, vice president of entertainment, marketing and publicity for <ORGANIZATION> Burson-Marsteller </ORGANIZATION> `` <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> has been a good friend for many years and my admiration for her is limitless,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. `` Let me tell you, this will be a fall to remember.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. ALBANS, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Being a princess is not all it's cracked up to be, says Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, who added that she enjoys an occasional shopping trip to a supermarket, local workers reported <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, the wife of Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, the heir to the British throne, was in this city 19 miles outside <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to open a big new shopping mall Thursday and told workers she enjoys buying tea-time treats for her young sons, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON>. `` We spoke to her about it not being an easy life. She said it was not all that it's made out to be,'' said pet shop manager <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Straton </PERSON>. But, `` She said she'd rather not say anything about that.'' The royal family is the constant object of attention of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s racy tabloids. Earlier this year, rumors abounded that <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' and <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>'s marriage was troubled.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WINTER PARK, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Connally </PERSON>, who filed for personal bankruptcy earlier this year, has been hired to help a designer of all-plastic weapons try to sell sell its technology to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military. <ORGANIZATION> Redeye </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> has developed a process that could be used for weapons ranging from hand guns to howitzers, the company's chief operating officer, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Floren </PERSON>, said Thursday. `` Based upon my understanding of this technology, it represents an opportunity to revolutionize conventional armaments and defense systems,'' said <PERSON> Connally </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary, during a meeting in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> with company officials. The terms of the contract were not disclosed. Plastic weapons have been criticized as a boon to terrorists but <PERSON> Floren </PERSON> said the new weapons will be detectable to airport security systems, and that the main use for the technology was in larger weapons. <PERSON> Connally </PERSON>, a victim of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' oil and real estate slump, had his personal property auctioned off in January after filing for bankruptcy.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> `` The Greek'' <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION>, fired as a CBS sports commentator earlier this year, says he's been `` hiding'' in a posh hotel since then. To add to his troubles, he's back in the hospital for chest pains. The 70-year-old oddsmaker was in good condition and undergoing tests and observation, <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Saporito </PERSON> said Thursday. <ORGANIZATION> Snyder </ORGANIZATION>, dismissed from `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Today'' in January because of his controversial remarks about black athletes, said he woke up in his hotel room here Wednesday with chest pains. `` I do n't take any chances, the sooner they can do something for you the better,'' he said from his hospital bed. `` They -LRB- doctors -RRB- are just looking to see what they find.'' <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> was hospitalized last July at <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, where examinations disclosed that an artery to his heart was blocked, and again shortly after his firing. Afterward, <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> took up residence alone at the posh, oceanfront Alexander Hotel on <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. `` I've been hiding there for 2 -LCB- months and then this had to happen,'' said <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, adding that he did n't feel `` too good right now.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SECAUCUS, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the ultra-conservative talk-show host known for his confrontational style with guests, has been cleared of charges that he assaulted a gay rights activist during a program. Judge <PERSON> Emil </PERSON> <PERSON> DelBaglivo </PERSON> found <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> innocent of assaulting <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Humm </PERSON>, a 34-year-old spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lesbian </ORGANIZATION> and Gay Rights. <PERSON> DelBaglivo </PERSON> watched a videotape of the show and listened to testimony during a 4 -LCB- - hour trial Wednesday before issuing his decision The tape shows <PERSON> Humm </PERSON> raising his right arm during an angry exchange between the two. <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> abruptly struck <PERSON> Humm </PERSON>'s arm away, and in doing so, grazed <PERSON> Humm </PERSON>'s face. The 55-year-old <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> flashed his familiar toothy grin to the crowd after the verdict and said, `` I am very pleased.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>, a writer of historical novels, has been selected to write the long-awaited sequel to `` Gone With the Wind,'' according to Life magazine. The magazine's May issue reports that <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>, 54, was selected from a dozen finalists two years ago by the <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which is handling the project for the family of GWTW author <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON>, the author of `` <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>,'' `` New Orleans Legacy'' and two other historical novels, has written an outline and two chapters of the sequel, which will be shown to publishers on Monday. The auction for hardcover rights could fetch as much as $ 6 million, with most of the profits going to <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s two nephews, the magazine said. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who was killed in 1949 by a drunken driver, refused to write a sequel to her 1936 novel, saying the story of <PERSON> Rhett </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, <PERSON> Scarlett </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hara </PERSON> and the Civil War reached its `` natural and proper ending.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BlindArrest     04-15 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blind Arrest,0573</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activists Hit Airlines On Blind Seating</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Airlines are deliberately discriminating against blind people by forcing them to switch seats under the guise of safety while lacking a uniform seating policy, blind activists contend. Their complaint follows the second arrest in as many weeks involving the seating of blind people on airlines. In the latst incident, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON>, director of governmental affairs for the National Federation of the <PERSON> Blind </PERSON>, who is blind, was taken into custody Thursday at <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> after he refused to leave his seat in an emergency exit row on a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight bound from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> attorneys later withdrew the complaint alleging criminal trespass, pending a review of the case, and <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON> was released, said <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Police Sgt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> DeGraff </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON>, 41, who was on his way to a conference in <LOCATION> Boise </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, says <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> knew he was blind when they assigned him the seat and ordered him to move to harass him. `` I'm not a safety hazard to anybody. So I do n't believe that there's a basis for requiring me to move,'' he said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> O'Hare </LOCATION> late Thursday. `` I did n't like being singled out that way.'' `` Mr. <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON> was adamant in his refusal to leave or to change seats, and <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> susbequently canceled the flight,'' the sergeant said. The DC-8 with 200 passengers was scheduled to leave at 3 p.m. CDT. Passengers were put on a later flight which left at 4:26 p.m., said <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s policy is not to seat blind people in emergency exit row seats because `` they're normally not manned by crew members. If there were a fire in the wing area, -LRB- the blind person -RRB- might be unable to assess the situation. `` Also, if we had to evacuate the plane ... it could slow the evacuation,'' <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said, adding that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says plane evacuations must take no longer than 90 seconds. `` I do n't know the mechanics of how he got that seat,'' <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> said. `` Once we realized what had happened, we attempted to relocate him to conform to our policies. In a similar incident, a blind attorney from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was arrested March 31 on a <ORGANIZATION> Midway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight at the <LOCATION> Washington-National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> after she refused to move from a smoking section seat into an exit area seat, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Reihing </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Baltimore-based federation. `` It is becoming clear to us that the pattern is deliberate. Our leaders, some who move with canes ... are being assigned those seats and being forced to move from them. It is a clear attempt to be be harassed,'' she said. `` Some airlines say we ca n't sit in exit rows. Some say we have to sit in exit rows,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Benson </PERSON>, president of the federation's Illinois chapter. `` We regard it as blatantly discriminatory.'' <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON> denied the allegation, saying, `` They're after the publicity.'' <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON>, meantime, planned to fly to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> today on another airline. `` I do n't believe in going along with violating a law,'' he said. `` I was n't causing a delay. I feel sad that <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> caused a delay for other passengers and me. I feel about as sad about that as other passengers. `` How do I get justice?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AlcoholBan     04-15 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Alcohol Ban,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Rally Against Alcohol Ban</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 500 <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> students, some carrying beer cans and liquor bottles, held a Bring Your Own Booze rally on campus Thursday night to protest a ban on alcohol at outdoor events. About 200 of the students marched to the home of Chancellor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON>, who imposed the ban last week. No arrests were reported. The chancellor was out of town. Students sang `` Give booze a chance'' to the tune of `` Give Peace a Chance.'' `` This could definitely get out of hand but everyone here is a responsible drinker,'' said student <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON>, 19. <PERSON> Deirdre </PERSON> <PERSON> Ling </PERSON>, vice chancellor for university relations and development, stood outside <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON>'s house. `` As long as it's a peaceful demonstration, students have the right to express their opinion,'' she said. Students began defying the ban en masse Wednesday when nearly 1,000 marched on the administration building. `` Students who are of legal age have the right to drink responsibly at public events,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, president of the campus <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, which sponsored the Wednesday rally with other student organizations. He said students were particularly annoyed because <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> failed to consult with a student-faculty committee on campus drinking before issuing the ban. The chancellor contended alcohol played a large role in several racial incidents on campus, including a fracas involving hundreds of students after the 1986 World Series and an attack on two blacks by five whites in February.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TurnpikeExplosives 1stLd-Writethru a0874ResortsInternationalHotelCasinoities.
04-15 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Turnpike Explosives, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0874,0606</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspected Japanese Red Army Terrorist Held On Federal Charges</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 6th graf pvs, `Superior Court ...' and 9th graf pvs,
`McGinley said ...' to CORRECT judge's name to DiGisi sted DeGisi
and suspect's name to Kikumura sted Kikimura.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BOB McMAHON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HACKENSACK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suspected member of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s terrorist <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> charged with possessing three homemade bombs was turned over Thursday to federal authorities trying to determine what he planned to do with the explosives. The 35-year-old suspect, who was identified by officials in his native <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> through fingerprints as <PERSON> Yu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON>, is listed by the <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> as a suspected member of the left-wing <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said they had not yet established ties between <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> and any group. `` We have a lot of unanswered questions that we have to answer,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGinley </PERSON>, agent in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> was arrested Tuesday at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turnpike </LOCATION> service area in <LOCATION> Ridgefield </LOCATION> after a state trooper found three bombs in his car, officials said. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> DiGisi </PERSON> released Kikumura to federal agents without setting bail Thursday. <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> was taken to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> jail to be held for a hearing Friday before a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> magistrate in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>. In a complaint filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, authorities charged <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> with possessing a fraudulent visa and unregistered firearms. If convicted, he faces up to $ 260,000 in fines and up to 15 years in prison. State and federal officials heading a terrorist task force said Thursday they have little information about <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> and what he planned to do with the bombs. <PERSON> McGinley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> had not spoken to federal officials since being taken into custody. According to Japanese authorities, <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> was acquitted in a Japanese court in 1986 of charges of possessing dynamite in his luggage at an airport in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, which deported him. The Japanese news agency <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> reported that <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON>'s arrest Tuesday had raised suspicions the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> might be planning attacks during the summit of leaders of advanced industrial nations June 19 in <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which advocates `` simultaneous world revolution'' and is believed to have members allied with pro-Palestinian groups in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, has been linked to a bloody attack on <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Lod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in 1972 that killed 26 people and the hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> plane in 1977. The group has been largely inactive in the 1980s, but <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> officials have expressed concern it might revive its terrorist activities at the Olympics in September. State police Superintendent Col. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> <PERSON> Pagano </PERSON> said the terrorist task force decided to investigate because of the sophisticated nature of the bombs. `` These are the first devices of this type that we have come across,'' <PERSON> Pagano </PERSON> said. Neither federal or state officials would elaborate. According to the federal complaint, police said the bombs consisted of three 18-inch steel cylinders. There was a total of 15 pounds of black powder in the car, officials said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Alito </PERSON> said authorities have learned <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> acquired an international driver's license in the name of <PERSON> Masatoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kishizona </PERSON> on Jan. 20. <PERSON> Kishizono </PERSON> is a 36-year-old employee of a hospital in <LOCATION> Kyoto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, who had reported his passport missing, police said. On Feb. 29, <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON>, using a fraudulent passport bearing <PERSON> Kishizona </PERSON>'s name, applied for a visa to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alito </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Kikumura </PERSON> entered the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on March 8.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Drugs 4thLd-Writethru a0873 04-15 0900</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Drugs, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0873,860</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Senate Votes Aid Sanctions On Mexico</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: SUBS 8th graf pvs bgng, `During more,' with 4 grafs to UPDATE
with Mexican foreign ministry reax</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted overwhelmingly Thursday to slap aid and trade sanctions on <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> for failing to do enough in the war on drugs, ignoring a plea from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and warnings that sanctions would do more harm than good. The move, on a 63 to 27 vote, came after backers of the legislation said it would shock <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> into doing more to combat the growing drug flow coming across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' southwestern border. Earlier, the lawmakers had voted voted 54 to 40 against taking the same action against the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. Similar bills were pending in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but the measures were given little chance of being finally enacted into law because of remaining procedural hurdles in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and a threat that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would veto any such measure to reach his desk. Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif., sponsor of the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> resolution, conceded that point, but said passage in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would `` send a message to the government of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'' and added, `` We are compelled to face reality. Opponents of the anti-drug sanctions protested that both <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, while they can be faulted for shortcomings, are making good-faith efforts to halt the flow of drugs through their countries into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. And <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in a letter to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders, had argued that imposition of sanctions against <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> because would `` adversely affect every aspect'' of U.S.-Mexican relations. The Mexican <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> released a statement Thursday night rejecting the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote as `` foreign interference.'' `` It is a profound conviction rooted in our history and in our laws that it only falls to one's own people to define without foreign interference their institutions and that at all time only they have the inalienable right to conduct their destiny,'' the statement said. In addition, the statement said, `` No one has the right to impose from abroad conduct, ideas, political or economic systems on other peoples.'' During more than five hours of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> debate, several lawmakers suggested that backers of the sanctions were jeopardizing bilateral relations in response to election-year political pressure. `` It's a great opportunity to show them we're tough, show them who's boss, and that we're against drugs,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, R-R. But he noted that the <LOCATION> Bahamian </LOCATION> government has won praise from drug authorities for its cooperation. Penalizing the islands `` just does n't make much sense,'' he said. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, noted that <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is the third largest customer for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports and that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gets 14 percent of its petroleum imports from its southern neighbor. `` This is likely to have a serious negative impact'' on that relationship, he said. Under a 1986 law, countries identified as production or transit points for illegal drugs must lose half their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid unless the president certifies that they are `` fully cooperating'' with the war on drugs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made such a certification on March 1 for 17 of the 24 countries on the drug-trafficking list, including the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. After that certification, several lawmakers in both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> began efforts to undo it. `` The purpose of this resolution is not to bash <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, but to defend the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, sponsor of the <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> resolution along with Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, R-N. But one colleague suggested that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has little room to criticize its southern neighbor. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, R-Ariz., noted that marijuana is one of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s largest cash crops and that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> streets are unsafe because of drug-related crime `` I wonder if we should n't decertify those states'' and cut off federal aid, <PERSON> McCain </PERSON> asked. While neither the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> nor <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> receives substantial <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic aid, losing the administration's drug certification could lead to loss of other benefits, including lucrative sugar-import quotas, airline landing rights and trade preferences. Of particular concern to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> was a requirement that if certification is lost, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representatives to international development banks must vote against future loans to the affected country. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a weighted vote on the banks, but not a majority. Loans from the banks have been crucial to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, which is laboring under a mammoth foreign debt. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> had sent private diplomatic signals that if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> persists in publicly embarrassing it through resolutions of non-cooperation, it is likely to evict <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug agents and wage the anti-narcotics fight without outside aid, according to congressional and diplomatic sources. In other action, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved, on a voice vote, a non-binding resolution to place <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> on the list of drug producing and transit countries, subjecting it to greater scrutiny and to possible similar sanctions next year. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in his letter, said the impact of the legislation `` would almost certainly be an increase in the flow of drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had said earlier that the administration was aware of congressional concerns about the international drug trafficking problem. But he said that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s advisers were prepared to recommend that he veto any legislation imposing sanctions on <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> He said it was necessary to `` keep in mind the broader national security interests of our two countries and other interests such as trade, immigration and so forth.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush-KidsBrite     04-15 0220</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Kids Brite,210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Upstaged by Giggling Toddlers Chanting `Jesse Jackson'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A visit by Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to a government day care center turned into a pint-sized political rally when about a dozen toddlers began chanting `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'' over and over. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s name was mentioned when a reporter shouted out a question about the Democratic contender while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was winding up his visit Thursday to a day care center at the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Upon hearing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s name, one child after another began repeating it. Soon, the entire class of about a dozen pre-schoolers was chanting `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'' in unison. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> grinned, then the Republican nominee-to-be responded: `` I'm not going to get into the Democratic side of the equation, particularly in a day care center. The kids were not about to let <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> off easy. `` Are you the president?'' one asked him. `` No, I'm the vice president,'' he said. `` Are you <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>?'' another asked. `` Yes, I'm <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' came the answer. He was asked if he saw the president. Yes, just that morning. `` Did you see the Easter bunny?'' he was asked. Yes, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, at the recent White House Easter egg hunt. One child asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> if they should be afraid of him. `` I've got 10 grandchildren,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I would n't hurt a flea.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OPEC-Texas Bjt   04-15 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OPEC-Texas, Bjt,910</SECOND>
<HEAD>Texas Talking with OPEC About Possible Cooperation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> is talking with the folks who brought you the oil embargoes of the 1970s, looking for ways to cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> cartel in a bid to revive its struggling oil industry. By itself, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> is still the seventh largest producer in the world, but its oil, real estate and banking industries have been devastated since a 1986 oil price collapse. Texans `` can not continue to bury our heads in the sand and hope everything is going to be OK,'' says <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Hance </PERSON>, one of the three members of the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which regulates oil production in the state. <PERSON> Hance </PERSON> met earlier this month with <PERSON> Rilwanu </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukman </PERSON>, the president of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Countries </ORGANIZATION>, and discussed the possibility that his state and the cartel would cooperate. More contacts are planned. <PERSON> Hance </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Harte-Hanks </ORGANIZATION> newspapers on Tuesday that cutting <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> production to hold up prices `` is one of the things that has to be considered. It would be one of the items we would discuss'' at <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>'s April 23 meeting in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. `` We can do it to prevent waste,'' he said in an interview Thursday from <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. From the 1930s to the early 1970s, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> played the role that <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> can play today _ acting as the world's swing producer, whose production stabilizes the price of oil. The commission, by controlling the amount of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oil produced, thus had a significant degree of control over prices. That influence dissipated with the rise of the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> cartel and since 1972, the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> commission has allowed wells in the state to produce at 100 percent of capacity. <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> demonstrated its clout in 1973, when 11 Arab member nations, angered over the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict, slapped the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with an oil embargo that produced gasoline lines all over the country. <PERSON> Hance </PERSON> said that in the discussions with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>, `` we are not trying to seek an alliance or cartel. We just want input. ... Our goal is one of stability.'' But <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> head <PERSON> Lukman </PERSON>, who is <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s oil minister, told <PERSON> AP-Dow </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> last week after meeting with <PERSON> Hance </PERSON> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, `` Exchanging information is n't going to do the trick, is it?'' Last week, <PERSON> Hance </PERSON> said he had discussed a more effective output monitoring system for <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>, which has been plagued for several years by member cheating. That point struck <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON>, oil specialist in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Lobel </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Novins </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Lamont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Flug </PERSON>. Noting that the commission for four decades had effective control over oil prices, <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON> said, `` I do n't want <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> going over there and showing them how it's done.'' <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON> said cooperation with the cartel by the commission would be `` probably illegal'' under antitrust laws, but that was disputed by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON>, a former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s antitrust division who is now a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> The economic harm resulting from higher prices and reduced output `` is precisely the evil that the antitrust laws are aimed against,'' said <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON>, but he added that it is `` fairly standard doctrine'' that the laws apply only to private action, not action by states. States also can file antitrust suits, and eight did so recently against insurance companies. One of the attorneys general involved, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, was asked about the chances of a suit against <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> should it cut production in concert with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. His spokeswoman, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Connell </PERSON>, replied, `` <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> price-fixing has cost <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consumers billions, maybe trillions of dollars, and we would n't want to see a state of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> participating.'' But she said <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>' office `` would want to know more about <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> law'' before commenting on any legal challenges. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheehan </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> antitrust division, declined to comment. But a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said: `` You can imagine what the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration thinks about it. It's a cartel that does not operate in <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. interests.'' On the record, <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Elmets </PERSON>, press aide to Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON>, said, `` It's the department's belief and the government's policy that assistance to <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> in its effort to manipulate the price of oil is not the correct approach.'' <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> had 201,000 oil wells, a third of the national total, at the end of 1986 _ down 8,000 wells from the year before. The state's 2.3 million barrels a day in 1986, the most recent year for which state-by-state statistics are available, was more than a quarter of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> crude production totaling 8.6 million barrels. Current <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> production is about 8.2 million barrels, and most analysts believe <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' production is more than 2 million barrels. Several analysts pooh-poohed <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' chances of achieving anything by talking with <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's a joke,'' said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothschild </PERSON>, assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> Citizen-Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>, a group which advocates `` pro-consumer'' positions. He noted that <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> has had trouble controlling prices in recent years. `` Since 1981, this organization has been a crumbling, disorganized, battling group of countries,'' he said. `` When they agree on action, it never works out. Within a month it's back to normal _ price discounting.'' <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Safer </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Futures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consulting firm, said a plausible <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> production cut to help <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> might be 70,000 barrels a day. But he said another 70,000 barrels a day `` would show up pretty quick on world oil markets, I guarantee it'' _ perhaps even provided by other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> producing states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxTime Bjt   04-15 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Time, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tax Deadline Today but `Tax Freedom' Still 20 Days Away</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first return-filing season under the broadest <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> income tax overhaul in history closes out at midnight. But the average American will have to work 20 more days to keep federal, state and local tax collectors at bay for another year. `` Tax Freedom Day'' will come May 5, the latest date since the <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> began counting a half-century ago. If the government took every penny you earned until your share of the total tax burden were paid, the foundation reckons, you would have to work the first 126 days of 1988 just to meet those obligations. Thirty years ago, Tax Freedom Day fell on April 10. Several million Americans did n't have time to fret about such fanciful calculations. They were working up to the eleventh hour on their 1987 returns, and many were sure to be standing in line in front of mail drops as the midnight filing deadline approached. Any return not postmarked by midnight _ and carrying the correct postage _ could be subject to a late filing penalty. The <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> cautioned taxpayers not to ignore the deadline, even if they ca n't afford to pay all the taxes they owe. Although failure to pay on time can result in one penalty, failure to file can bring an additional one. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> estimated that about 6.2 million couples and individuals would apply for an automatic four-month extension of the filing deadline by mailing Form 4868 with a check for their estimated taxes. That is up about 20 percent from last year _ due in large part to all the tax-law changes that must be reflected on returns being filed this year. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' 1986 overhaul of the tax law changed more than 2,700 provisions and led the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> to create 48 new forms. But the typical individual was unaffected by the great majority of those changes and has to use few if any of the new forms. Nevertheless, taxpayers have been sufficiently confused about the new law to telephone more than 17 million questions to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> and to order record numbers of explanatory publications from the agency. The new law reduced tax rates significantly and nearly doubled the personal exemption to $ 1,900. But it reduced or eliminated a number of deductions and exemptions, including those for sales taxes, medical expenses, moving, consumer interest and <ORGANIZATION> Individual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounts </ORGANIZATION>. One of the biggest sources of confusion was the requirement that every employee file a revised W-4 form so that the amount of tax withheld could be adjusted to mirror the new law. Many workers found the new form so complex that the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> had to revise it again. Eventually the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> announced it would not penalize any worker for failing to pay enough tax in advance on 1987 wages. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> itself is having trouble keeping up with the new law. As recently as Thursday, it was issuing advice to taxpayers on how they might avoid penalties that were caused by getting the wrong answer to a tax question from an <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> telephone `` assistor.'' About 28 of every 100 callers are getting wrong answers, the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> concedes. Economists for the <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> say benefits of the across-the-board tax cut enacted in 1981 have been wiped out by tax increases voted in 1982, 1983, 1984 and 1987. `` Like the <LOCATION> Cheshire </LOCATION> Cat in ` Alice in Wonderland,' nothing remains but the smile,'' the foundation said. Tax Freedom Day calculations by the <ORGANIZATION> Tax </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> research organization, assume that individuals pay all taxes _ including those collected from corporations. The economists simply divide all federal, state and local tax collections among taxpayers and assume that every penny earned each year goes to government until tax obligations are satisfied. Last year, Tax Freedom Day was May 4; this year's May 5 date is two days later because 1988 is a leap year. If taxes were viewed on the basis of an eight-hour work day, the foundation said, the average taxpayer would have to work 1 hour and 50 minutes a day to pay federal taxes, and another 55 minutes for state and local taxes. That's two minutes longer for federal taxes than in 1987 but the same as last year for state and local taxes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese-RealEstate Bjt   04-15 0972</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese-Real Estate, Bjt,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meese Grand Jury Hears Testimony From Real Estate Magnate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL J. SNIFFEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>and</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writers</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal grand jury is weighing testimony from a wealthy couple who won a $ 50 million lease for <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> offices after arranging to pay a $ 40,000 salary for Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON>. Independent Counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> on Thursday personally supervised the questioning of <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Sondra </PERSON>, before the grand jury, something he does only when major witnesses are summoned. <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> spent about three hours before the grand jury; his wife was there only an hour. She left at the grand jury's normal quitting time, indicating she might be called back. The Benders were accompanied by their attorney, <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Glanzer </PERSON>. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> is investigating whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> violated federal law through any conflict between his personal financial dealings and his government job. Although <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> said April 1 he did not have evidence to indict <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> in cases involving telephone stock and a <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> oil pipeline, Thursday's appearance by the Benders underscored the prosecutor's other announcement at that time: that he still had some cases to pursue. Meanwhile, trustees of the <ORGANIZATION> Multiple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sclerosis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that they never voted on the plan to hire <PERSON> Ursula </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> at $ 40,000 a year with money donated by the <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> family foundation. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday that a partnership headed by <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> won a $ 50 million lease on <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> offices after the <ORGANIZATION> Bender </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> put up the money to pay Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s salary at the MS society. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to attend a drug conference, was asked by a reporter about the matter but declined to comment. During a later stop at an Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Nationalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> center in <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, he turned aside several questions about the lease arrangement, saying `` that's not on the subject of immigration.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Thursday that he knew nothing about the lease but that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` still has full confidence in <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>.'' MS officials have said the <ORGANIZATION> Bender </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, of which <PERSON> Sondra </PERSON> is president, donated the money in October 1985 to give Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, previously a volunteer, the salary for three years. Mrs. <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> are MS trustees. Several MS trustees said they did not learn of that arrangement until newspaper accounts appeared in the last two weeks. Others, however, said the board had been advised earlier. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, wife of Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, D-Minn., said she first learned about Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s salary when her husband read a newspaper account Mrs. <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, a trustee, said the issue of Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s job was never discussed in any board meeting that she attended. Another trustee, <PERSON> Remmel </PERSON> <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON>, gave a different version. `` I guess you might say it was reported to the board,'' said <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON>. `` I can not say that a proposal was put before the board, discussed pro and con and then a vote was taken, but we were informed that this had been proposed. `` I was pleased,'' <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> said. `` I was told the Benders had this foundation and they could make a contribution to MS or pay for someone's salary or designate for a specific purpose. We were delighted to know she -LRB- Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> -RRB- would be a full-time employee because she's a worker.'' The board meets quarterly and not all the trustees attend each meeting. Another longtime trustee, who spoke on condition she not be identified, said, `` I was shocked ... I was aghast when I saw it'' in a newspaper. She said she never missed a board meeting, but had no idea Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was being paid as MS development director. Attorney <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Barkley </PERSON>, also a trustee, said, `` I do n't recall a discussion at a board meeting'' about the plan to hire Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>. He said, `` It is not normal to earmark a grant for the salary of a specific person. That's a little unusual.'' But he added, `` It's not necessarily something the board would get into to vote on or ratify. MS society attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bierbower </PERSON> said the arrangement was brought up in October 1985 at a special meeting to discuss expansion of Operation Job Match, a program to help MS victims find work. Mrs. <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> was at the session, he said. <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> has subpoenaed records of Mrs. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s job at the society and is known to be interested in a $ 50 million lease renewal won by the <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> partnership in May 1987. Most of the offices in the lease were occupied by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which had complained about the building's maintenance, size, location and security. The Bender partnership sold the building 13 days after the lease renewal, earning a $ 22.6 million profit on a two-year investment. The lease was crucial to the sale, the new owner said. The <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> partnership had bought the building in March 1985 for nearly twice its assessed value at a time when the government wanted to move more than a third of its offices elsewhere. Three months after the <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> partnership purchased the building, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration disclosed publicly that it had decided to retain the building. An attorney for the Meeses, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rocap </PERSON>, denies any wrongdoing on their part in the transactions, but acknowledges that the Benders and <PERSON> Meeses </PERSON> know each other. The Benders refuse to discuss the matter publicly. A key government official said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> played no role in the real estate decision. Other <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> buildings have done business with the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Government documents show that <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON> and his two brothers, <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>, as a partnership, signed a lease in June 1985 to give the government more space in a downtown office building, One <LOCATION> McPherson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, where it has leased several floors since 1971. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> occupies part of one floor there.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WritersStrike     04-15 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Writers Strike,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Striking Scriptwriters Grant Two Exceptions</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Striking TV and film scriptwriters have agreed to go back to work under interim contracts at only two of the several independent producers that asked for relief from the walkout, the union said Thursday. East Coast members of the striking <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Thursday to consider the request for relief and take an informal vote; <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> members met Wednesday. Vote totals were not released. <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> leaders had recommended against separate contracts because `` it could lead to divisiveness and destruction of morale among members,'' <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said in a statement announcing the outcome of the vote. However, <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said, the <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> membership approved two exceptions: The `` New Smothers Brothers Comedy Hour'' and <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reitman </PERSON> Productions, which has produced such film hits as `` Animal House'' and `` Ghostbusters.'' The exceptions were granted because of unspecified legal considerations and because negotiations with the two producers `` were more advanced,'' <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> said. It was not known how many scriptwriters would be affected by the decision to enter into separate contracts with the two production companies. <PERSON> Rhoden </PERSON> could not immediately be reached for comment. An unspecified number of independent producers had asked the union for separate agreements that would allow them to resume work. Some 9,000 union writers went on strike March 7 over creative control and residuals from reruns and foreign distribution. The walkout shortened the season for many prime-time shows and stalled the start of some series. There have been no formal negotiations since March 10. <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, a spokesman for TV and film producers, said the producers had no comment on the guild's decision not to seek side deals with independent producers other than the two exceptions. He held out little hope for Monday's negotiating session. `` There has been no change in our position,'' <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> said. `` Unless this new meeting carries a lantern with it, we see no light at the end of the tunnel.'' On Thursday, about 300 union supporters rallied outside the <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> building, where Paramount has offices. Among those appearing were writer and director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON> and writers <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinoy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> <PERSON> Foote </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880415-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-15-88 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Gore'sFrustration Bjt   04-15 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gore's Frustration, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gore Struggles Against Odds In Last Days Before Primary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
