<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Spain-Shootout     11-01 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spain-Shootout,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Policemen Die in Shootout</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VILANOVA I LA GELTRU, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two policemen were killed Tuesday in a shootout with a fugitive bank robber on a restaurant terrace in this <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coastal town, police said. The fugitive, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, was seriously injured. Police said firing began when four policemen moved in to arrest <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, described as the brains behind a notorious bank holdup and hostage-taking in <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION> in 1981. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> had been imprisoned since 1983 serving a 25-year sentence for his role in the <ORGANIZATION> Banco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> holdup and was let out on furlough Sept. 29. He failed to return when his leave was up Oct. 5. Police said <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was having lunch with a woman, a man and two children when police approached to check his identity. They said he shot and killed one officer outright and fatally wounded the other. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> and eight other men held up the bank and held 263 people hostage inside for two days before special police teams took the building by storm, killing one of the robbers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PershingBurn     11-01 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pershing Burn,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Grants Army Emissions Permit For Pershing Motor Destruction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JULIA RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday granted the Army an air pollution emission permit to burn Pershing II missile motors at its Pueblo depot to comply with an arms reduction treaty. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> had been seeking the state permit since February, because the missiles must be destroyed under terms of the Intermediate Nuclear Forces treaty signed by leaders of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The permit imposes some restrictions on the method, frequency and wind conditions for missile destruction at the depot in southern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Clouse </PERSON> of the department's Air Pollution Control Division. It also requires emissions monitoring for the three years the permit will be in effect, beginning on the first day of missile destruction. `` Under these conditions, there will be no adverse impact to <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION> residents or to the residents east of the site,'' said <PERSON> Clouse </PERSON>. Gov. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Romer </PERSON> praised the department for allowing the burn `` while, at the same time, protecting our environment and the health of our citizens.'' `` I wanted <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> to help get rid of these missiles so that this country could fulfill its treaty obligation,'' <PERSON> Romer </PERSON> said. `` However, I wanted it to be done safely, and we have worked that out with the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Army.'' Slated for destruction at the depot are 234 Pershing II Stage I motors, each of which contains 7,940 pounds of propellant, and 223 Pershing II Stage 2 motors, each of which contains 4,940 pounds of propellant, state officials said. The rest of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s original stockpile of 849 Pershing II missiles will be destroyed at a site in <LOCATION> Marshall </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officials said. `` We're very pleased. We're grateful to the citizens and the state of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> for the confidence they have placed in us. And rest assured, we do n't take that confidence lightly,'' said <PERSON> Pueblo </PERSON> depot spokesman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kenitzer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kenitzer </PERSON> said depot officials will travel to <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> in the next few days to pick up the permit, and the depot will send the health department a check later this week for about $ 25,000 for research and administrative costs. He said the Army will select a date to begin the missile burns and, under treaty terms, will give the Soviets 30 days' notice. Some state lawmakers had been concerned that if the state denied the permit, jobs at the facility might be in jeopardy. <PERSON> Kenitzer </PERSON> did n't know immediately whether the depot might hire more people as a result of the permit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2334EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 5thLd-Writethru a0821 11-01 1071</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0821,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Campaigns Like President-Elect; Dukakis Seeks Blue-Collar
Votes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: To UPDATE with Washington Post editorial, SUB two grafs for
22nd pvs, The Massachusetts..., and EDIT to tighten.
^By DAVID ESPO</NOTE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaigned like a president-to-be Tuesday, saying he hoped for a meeting with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> soon after moving into the Oval Office. Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said `` Made in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' was the only label he cared about as he bid for union support. The polls one week before Election Day showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a solid leader, and the contrast in campaign styles between the front-runner and the underdog could n't have been plainer. The vice president struck an above-the-fray pose in a speech at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Notre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dame </ORGANIZATION>, saying he wanted to meet <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> for a `` serious and direct examination'' of superpower relations. The GOP presidential nominee also pledged to appoint `` moderate persons of conservative views'' to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was in the political trenches, blending his appeal for blue collar support with an attack on alleged Republican influence peddling. `` As president, I'm not going to stand up for the sharp operators, I'm going to stand up for the lathe operators and machine operators,'' he said. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign also unveiled a new one-minute ad centering on the theme `` The Rich Get Richer'' and claiming <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' tax proposals would be fairer to the middle class. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' aides said their private polls pointed to a race that was narrowing. Privately, some Democrats expressed doubts, while <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said its survey of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a leader by seven points in the nation's biggest state. A CBS News poll released Tuesday showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holding a 12-point lead over <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 53-41 percent. The survey of 1,065 probable voters was conducted Saturday through Monday and had a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had an even larger lead in an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News-Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> poll, 55-42, which the network said was the largest lead in its polling since Labor Day. The survey of 1,099 likely voters Wednesday through Monday had a margin of error of close to four percentage points in either direction. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, expressed irritation with <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> campaign managers after they abruptly switched his schedule to cancel a trip to South Bend, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. _ the same city <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was visiting. Democratic vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> climbed into the cockpit of an F-16 fighter for the benefit of television cameras as he renewed his campaign to persuade Texans that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would be strong on defense. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> campaigned for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and other Republicans, ripping into <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for describing himself as a liberal in the mold of <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no `` <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and he's no FDR,'' the outgoing president said _ and then depicted this year's <ORGANIZATION> Democatic </ORGANIZATION> candidate as a man pursuing the `` Carter-Mondale liberal agenda. Transition planners were on a schedule that could n't wait for the election. Stationery bearing the politically correct letterhead `` Office of the President-elect'' was on order to suit either <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> behaved like a man who thought he'd be using the stationery. In his speech at <LOCATION> Notre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dame </LOCATION>, he said `` much progress has been made'' in superpower relations during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years and added it was important for him and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to `` size each other up correctly.'' He said he would ask his secretary of state to `` make it clear that I am prepared to meet with General Secretary <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at the earliest time that would serve the interests of world peace.'' `` My purpose in such a meeting would not be to achieve any grand breakthrough but to engage in a serious and direct examination of where we are and how we can best go forward toward further arms reductions, a decrease in regional tensions and further adherence to human rights and thus toward a surer peace,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could n't resist a few sharp digs at <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, saying now was no time for `` total inexperience'' in diplomacy and adding that his Democratic rival would name `` doctrinaire liberals'' to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. In a campaign matter that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> jumped on instantly, a top <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> fund-raiser denounced as `` rotten'' a report implying that he was trying to use his position to land a public relations contract for his firm with the government of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is not related to the vice president, said he had told his partner <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Govan </PERSON> to `` forget it'' when it came to <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>, but his partner had ignored the admonition and had written the nation's new president using <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s name <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> referred to the reports as he campaigned his way across the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, saying the country has had a `` bellyful of allowing representatives of foreign governments easy access to the White House.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' first event of the day was in <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, a steel-producing region hard hit by recession. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> likes to talk about labels, a reference to the way the vice president attempts to make him seem a liberal out of touch with the mainstream. `` You know what label I'm intereted in? ` Made in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>' is the label I'm interested in.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday said it would endorse neither <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for president, saying neither candidate `` has established a claim to the office that we find compelling.'' `` This has been a terrible campaign, a national disappointment,'' the newspaper said. With only a week to go, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' schedule seemed stretched almost beyond endurance. He arranged four appearances in as many states _ then was flying to the bedside of his wife <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON>, who was hospitalized with a viral infection in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. His marathon was brightened in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, where he was serenaded with a chorus of `` Happy Birthday'' two days before his 55th and presented with a new snow blower. That was a joking reference to the 25-year-old model that he keeps in his garage in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also took another crack at answering a question that many advisers felt he handled poorly in last month's televised debate, the issue of whether he would favor the death penalty if his wife were raped and murdered. `` I think I would have that kind of emotion,'' he told <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, the newsman who asked the same question during the debate. `` On the other hand, this is not a country where we glorify vengeance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0779 11-01 0314</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0779,0318</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Uhlenbeck; A separate moved for AMs on Uhlenbeck as
a0804.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Merle Balch</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNTAIN VIEW, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> Balch </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> veteran pilot who inaugurated jet service across the north <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> for 30 years, died Thusday after a stroke. He was 76. In 1934, <PERSON> Balch </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> as an aviation cadet. He trained as a pilot at <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> and learned to pilot flying boats. In 1937, <PERSON> Balch </PERSON> left the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> to join <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> flying the <ORGANIZATION> Clippers </ORGANIZATION> out of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> tourists spots. He made the 1958 flight in a Douglas DC-7 but got no credit in the record books because the plane carried no paying passengers, only members of the press. Instead, credit for the pioneering passenger flight went two weeks later to then <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. In his 35 years as captain and assistant chief pilot with <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Balch </PERSON> logged nearly 25,000 hours in the air.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Uhlenbeck</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Uhlenbeck </PERSON>, a major figure in theoretical physics and a professor emeritus at <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, died Monday at age 87. <PERSON> Uhlenbeck </PERSON> was best known as the co-discoverer, with the late <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goudsmit </PERSON>, of the phenomenon of electron spin. This discovery that electrons spin proved to be a cornerstone of basic atomic theory. He and <ORGANIZATION> Goudsmit </ORGANIZATION> made their landmark discovery about electron spin as graduate students there. <PERSON> Uhlenbeck </PERSON> joined <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, formerly the <ORGANIZATION> Rockefeller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, in 1961 to help establish its theoretical physics faculty. He became a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> in 1955. <PERSON> Uhlenbeck </PERSON> received the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's highest science award, in 1977, the same year the Dutch government made him Commander of the Order of Orange-Nassau, the highest non-military award it gives to foreigners
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CocaineSuit 1stLd-Writethru a0748 11-01 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cocaine Suit, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0748,0360</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Files $5 Million Suit Against Convicted Smuggler</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to add seizure, quote from prosecutor;
Picks up 3rd graf pvs: `Essentially, this; Adds background graf on
pvs record</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state seized more than $ 5 million in businesses and property belonging to a convicted cocaine smuggler Tuesday in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s largest civil racketeering confiscation. The seizures were made as prosecutors filed suit to collect $ 5 million in drug profits the state claims the <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, man funneled into a string of businesses in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and elsewhere. `` This is really a big lick for us,'' said statewide prosecutor <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonacci </PERSON>. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Brothers </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 51, was jailed last week after a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> jury found him guilty of piloting two planeloads of cocaine from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION> in 1986. `` Essentially, this is an action against property in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> derived from a pattern of racketeering,'' said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Zelman </PERSON>, an assistant statewide prosecutor. <PERSON> Zelman </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> sent the cash to a <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> banker named <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellul </PERSON>, who transferred the money back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to be invested. According to the lawsuit filed in <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, property involved in the money-laundering scheme ranged from a <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> corporation to ranches in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and a 42-foot boat at a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pierce </LOCATION> marina. <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>' assets also included two airplanes, one of which was seized and sold by Costa Rican authorities and the other, a Beechcraft Baron, which was seized by the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Zelman </PERSON> said. `` It all adds up to over $ 5 million,'' the prosecutor said. `` These are corporate entities that were funded by the proceeds of racketeering.'' <PERSON> Brothers </PERSON> claimed in his trial that he got involved with a ring of drug smugglers while trying to hide assets, including an airplane, from his wife, whom he was divorcing. She testified against him at the trial and is now seeking a divorce settlement. The previous state record for seized drug assets in a civil case was $ 2 million in property taken last September from convicted drug smuggler <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LottoDispute     11-01 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lotto Dispute,0201</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Rejects Injunction In Lotto Suit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STUART, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge Tuesday denied a request by the ex-husband of a state lottery winner to block payment of the first installment of the $ 31.5 million jackpot claimed by the woman and her sister. Martin County Judge <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> said there was no legal precedent to warrant <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Snipes </PERSON>' claim that he deserves a share of the prize because he purchased the tickets and encouraged the <LOCATION> Indiantown </LOCATION> women to play the Lotto game. The first of 20 $ 1.57 million annual installments for <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Snipes </PERSON> and her sister <PERSON> Maxine </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> is scheduled to be wired to the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indiantown </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. The women won the state's third-largest Lotto prize on Oct. 22 <PERSON> Snipes </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Coutant </PERSON>, said the suit was filed Friday after he broke off negotiations to get a `` fair division'' of the jackpot. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrell </PERSON>, attorney for the two sisters and Ms. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s husband <PERSON> William </PERSON>, said the sisters had offered <PERSON> Snipes </PERSON> $ 1 million to settle his claim for part of the prize He added that they have no legal obligation to the <LOCATION> Indiantown </LOCATION> man. The Snipeses ended their two-year marriage in 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NewlywedConviction     11-01 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newlywed Conviction,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>ROTC Recommends Student Who Disappeared Serve Four Years In Army</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ROTC commander recommended Tuesday that a former college student who disappeared with his new wife for four months last spring should serve four years in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> as an enlisted man because he violated his contract. The recommendation that <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, 23, serve in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> was made by Brig. Gen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Musselman </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Officers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> regional headquarters in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Knox </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky </LOCATION>. It now goes to Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>, at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, who will make the final decision, said Capt. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, an ROTC spokesman at <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Knox </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's not punishment, nor is it the final decision,'' <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> said Tuesday night. `` This is all administrative procedure. It was never intended as punishment.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Swansons </ORGANIZATION>' disappearance last April drew national attention as authorities in several states searched for them for four months. They surfaced in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, saying they had vanished to seek `` perfect love.'' <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> said he would abide by the <ORGANIZATION> ROTC </ORGANIZATION> decision and if he must serve in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, `` I'm going to be up front about it ... I'm going to serve proudly.'' <PERSON> Musselman </PERSON>'s recommendation differs from one offered by a three-member Army panel that reviewed <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>'s case in August. The panel found that <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> had violated his ROTC contract when he and his wife, <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON>, disappeared April 2 before he had completed his military and academic obligations. But it recommended that he be expelled from the ROTC program. The panel also recommended <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> pay back more than $ 16,000 he received through the ROTC program for college tuition and other education expenses. He had been scheduled to graduate from <ORGANIZATION> Wheaton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> last May. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> said the contract is standard procedure for all candidates when they enter the advanced <ORGANIZATION> ROTC </ORGANIZATION> program in their final two years of college. The contract contains a provision stating that any breech of its terms can result in the cadet having to repay an ROTC scholarship, fulfill the contract as an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officer or serve a term of enlistment, <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> explained. <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON> `` knew the options going into it as does every cadet,'' <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> said. He said he did not know how long it would take for <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>, commander general of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ROTC </ORGANIZATION> command, to make a decision.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ShipHandling     11-01 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ship Handling,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Officers Train In Ship Models</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEAN McNAIR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ensign </PERSON> <PERSON> Deron </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> confidently barked out orders as the helmsman guided a sleek gray <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ship between red and green markers that dotted the smooth waters. Looking toward the bow, he directed the helmsmen to turn the rudder to the right. `` See your red buoy up here?'' asked the helmsman, Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>. As the ship passed within inches of the red marker, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> called out another order, then looked over the side and said under his breath, `` We did n't touch, did we?'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> had missed the marker, but it would n't have mattered if he had hit it. He and other young officers were the crew on a 36-foot fiberglass model of a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> supply ship gliding across <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION> at the Little Creek Amphibious Base. The officers were participating in a popular <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> course on ship handling that uses scale models of everything from a fast frigate to an aircraft carrier. Ship handling is a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> skill that attracts little attention unless something goes awry. The commander of the carrier <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> lost his job because the ship collided with an anchored Spanish collier in <LOCATION> Hampton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roads </LOCATION> harbor Aug. 29. And the captain of the tank landing ship <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> was relieved of his command because the ship ran aground during a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> exercise off the coast of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> on Sept. 12. The junior officers who take the one-week ship handling course are a long way from commanding a ship. But with other officers they share responsibility for navigating their ships into piers and anchorages and away from other vessels. The more than 400 officers who take the course each year have been assigned to a ship for at least six months. Most young <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officers get little experience aboard ship, however, because so many officers share the ship-handling duties, said <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON>, who oversees ship-handling training at the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amphibious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. In his 16 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said, he has maneuvered a ship to the dock only twice. `` Here in one week a guy can make 15 pier approaches,'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said as he showed off a 40-by-40-foot water tank where the students practice with remote-controlled ship models. `` Ships have gotten very expensive. You just ca n't afford to let everybody come in and try to take them alongside because if you do have a collision there's going to be a lot of damage,'' he said. The course allows the young officers to make mistakes with few consequences, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said. `` Here the captain's not watching,'' he said. `` It's not going to show up on their fitness reports.'' The course begins with the tank, a shallow blue body of water marked with an island, a bridge, a canal and several piers. A small fan provides the wind. With remote-control boxes, the students guide 3-foot models of frigates, destroyers and amphibious assault ships alongside the piers and under the bridge. In the afternoon, they head for the lake to practice in the 43-foot model of a Nimitz-class carrier and five other ships that cost an average of $ 74,000. With a crew of three or four, the ships powered by electric motors glide between the piers, moorings and channel markers set up in the lake. `` It builds confidence,'' <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Saratoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, said after his turn at navigating. `` You can experiment more.'' Giving orders to the person whose hands are on the wheel teaches responsibility, the students said. `` We learn the basics and when we actually do get to do it, it's a lot more realistic,'' said Lt. j.g <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Kordyjak </PERSON>, 25, of <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> `` We have an idea of the theory behind it.'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said the model ships probably have endured a few fender-benders since they were put in use in the 1970s. Since <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> and other instructors steer the ships, they can simply ignore students' orders if the vessel is about to crash into the dock. But do the students ever get to take a turn at steering? `` Let them have fun? No,'' <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> said with a grin as he turned the wheel of his miniature supply ship.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Afghanistan Bjt   11-01 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Afghanistan, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Soviet Missiles in Kabul Seen as Threatening Pakistan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The arrival of at least two new Soviet missiles in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> has raised <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> concern about <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s security and whether there will be a delay in the second stage of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> The SS-1 Scud rockets were displayed in the Afghan capital after Undersecretary of State <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> complained to Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubinin </PERSON> on Monday about sending long-range TU26 Backfire bombers into combat there for the first time. The Soviets are backing the Afghan government against U.S.-armed rebels in a war that has raged for nearly nine years. On Aug. 15, the Soviets completed the pullout of more than half the 100,000 troops that had fought alongside the pro-Moscow government. The remaining troops must depart by Feb. 15 under an agreement signed in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> last spring. The Soviets hinted recently that the second stage would begin Nov. 15. But a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official, who spoke Tuesday on condition of anonymity, said that might be delayed. He also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would see to it that the rebels had an `` adequate'' arsenal, although missiles to match the Scuds probably would not be provided through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. Two Scud-B missiles, which have the range of about 175 miles, were displayed in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, the official said. It was not clear whether the Soviets delivered more of them, which are mobile and can reach the Pakistani frontier as well as vast areas of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. `` It's clearly intended to intimidate <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>,'' the official said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> weapons to the guerrillas are delivered through <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, which also has given sanctuary to millions of Afghan refugees. The Afghan news agency, in a dispatch Tuesday, accused <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> of instigating attacks by `` extremist'' guerrillas on population centers and demilitarized areas. `` This is why a new kind of weapon, mainly long-range missiles with a great destructive power, was adopted for service by the Afghan army,'' the Afghan general staff said. `` The missiles will be used to stop the criminal activities of the extremist group,'' the dispatch added, without referring specifically to the Scud-B. <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerasimov </PERSON>, the spokesman for the Soviet foreign ministry, said at a news conference last month in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s support for the rebels could have `` unpredictable'' consequences `` We do n't want to be specific,'' he said. But he left open the possibility that the withdrawal of Soviet troops might be suspended. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> cautioned <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Tuesday that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was determined to protect <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>. `` If the purpose of these latest military developments is to threaten <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> knows that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> enjoys our full support in this situation,'' he said. The version of the Scud the Soviets are believed to have provided to the Afghan forces is a mobile rocket, 37 feet long, 34 inches in diameter, and weighing 14,000 pounds. The Scud has a simple guidance system, uses liquid fuel, and can be equipped with either a nuclear or high-explosive conventional warhead. `` This action,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, `` calls into question the Soviets' stated desire to achieve a genuine political settlement in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and their undertakings to us not to engage in offensive actions This display is only the latest attempt by the Soviets to prop up a desperate regime which lacks legitimacy among the Afghan people and clearly demonstrates that the regime is incapable of defending itself.'' In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, accompanying President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on a political speaking tour, issued this formal statement: `` We are concerned about the display of SS-1 missiles in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> and the deployment of Soviet MiGs and Backfire bombers. These actions call into question the Soviets' stated desire to achieve a genuine settlement in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. `` This display of military hardware will only increase tensions in the region. Our support for <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> remains unshakeable.'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> welcomed, meanwhile, the visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of <PERSON> Burhanuddin </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabbani </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla group. He called Monday in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> for elections to create a new government after Soviet troops withdraw. `` Our position is that we can support any proposal for a political solution which reflects the will of the Afghan people and meets their aspirations for self-determination,'' <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rabbani </PERSON> will be in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> next week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     11-01 0405</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Halloween' Sequel Haunts Top Box Office Spot</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIC LEYVA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Halloween 4, The Return of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>'' spooked the competition for the second straight week and pulled in $ 4.1 million at the box office the weekend before Halloween. In second place with more than $ 3 million in weekend ticket receipts was `` The Accused.'' `` Alien Nation'' was in third place with $ 1.8 million, followed by `` Gorillas In The Mist,'' which drew $ 1.6 million and moved up a slot to fourth. `` Punchline'' dropped one place to fifth with $ 1.5 million. `` Feds,'' starring <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> DeMornay </PERSON> in a comedy about aspiring female <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, made its debut in sixth place with $ 1.4 million. `` Mystic Pizza,'' a comedy dealing with the lives and loves of three pizza waitresses in a small <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> town, delivered seventh place again with a $ 1.3 million slice of weekend receipts. `` Bat 21,'' starring <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackman </PERSON> as an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officer shot down over hostile territory during the Vietnam War, was in eighth place with $ 1 million. `` Without A Clue,'' a <PERSON> Sherlock </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> spoof starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsley </PERSON>, came in ninth with about $ 920,000, and `` Crossing Delancey,'' starring <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> in a lighthearted romantic drama, finished 10th with about $ 820,000. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Halloween 4, The Return of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>,'' Galaxy, $ 4.1 million, 1,692 screens, $ 2,432 per screen, $ 12.9 million, two weeks. 2. `` The Accused,'' Paramount, $ 3 million, 930 screens, $ 3,232 per screen, $ 14.2 million, three weeks. 3. `` Alien Nation,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 1.8 million, 1,420 screens, $ 1,256 per screen, $ 20.3 million, four weeks. 4. `` Gorillas In The Mist,'' Universal, $ 1.6 million, 1,054 screens, $ 1,475 per screen, $ 17.9 million, six weeks. 5. `` Punchline,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 917 screens, $ 1,669 per screen, $ 15.6 million, five weeks. 6. `` Feds,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.4 million, 849 screens, $ 1,635 per screen, 1.4 million, one week. 7. `` Mystic Pizza,'' <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON>, $ 1.3 million, 386 screens, $ 3,432 per sceen, $ 2.9 million, two weeks. 8. `` Bat 21,'' Tri-Star, $ 1 million, 516 screens, $ 1,984 per screen, $ 2.3 million, two weeks. 9. `` Without A Clue,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 917,894, 280 screens, $ 3,278 per screen, $ 2.5 million, two weeks. 10. `` Crossing Delancey,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 819,553, 304 screens, $ 2,695 per screen, $ 11.3 million, nine weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TMIHearing     10-31 0448</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-TMI Hearing,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activist, TMI Attorney Face Off Over Contaminated Water</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LANCASTER, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Representatives of the <LOCATION> Three </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nuclear plant told federal officials Monday that allowing 2.3 million gallons of contaminated water to evaporate would pose no health threat, but an activist argued for storing the water at the site. The statements came before the <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Licensing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which will help decide what to do with the water contaminated by the March 1979 accident at <ORGANIZATION> TMI </ORGANIZATION> Unit 2 and the continuing cleanup. A battery of lawyers representing the plant owner, <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, faced <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Skolnick </PERSON>, the lone representative of the citizen groups <ORGANIZATION> Three </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alert </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Susquehanna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> B </PERSON>. Block, chairman of the board, repeatedly reproached <PERSON> Skolnick </PERSON>, saying she was failing to prove her alternative was better than the <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> proposal. In his opening statement, attorney <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> told the board <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> wants to evaporate the water and bury the residue off site as commercial low-level waste at a cost of $ 4.1 million. `` The intervenors' alternative would cost at least $ 2.1 million for the pre-processing of the water, $ 9.1 million for the tanks they suggest, plus the unknown costs of ultimate disposal of the water,'' <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> also argued evaporation would pose no health risk in the <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION> area. He said a conservative estimate of the average exposure to someone living within a 50-mile radius is 0.005 millirems of radiation, compared with about 300 millirems per year that people receive from natural sources. <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear has argued that storing the water in tanks at the plant would be dangerous because during an accident, the entire load would flow into the nearby <LOCATION> Susquehanna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, which feeds into the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Piccioni </PERSON>, a senior staff scientist at <ORGANIZATION> Accord </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, disputed the GPU Nuclear scenerio. <PERSON> Piccioni </PERSON>, testifying as <PERSON> Skolnick </PERSON>'s expert witness, said that `` there appears to be an overstatement by the licensee'' regarding the amount of contamination that would be released. Questioned during a break, <PERSON> Piccioni </PERSON> said the levels of contamination suggested by <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear would not be reached if the activists' recommendations were followed. `` First, they assume that the water is not treated, which they plan on doing anyway,'' he said. `` Second, they assume all 2.3 million gallons would go into the river, and three, they assume people will eat shellfish from the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> after the release, which would account for a majority of the dose.'' <PERSON> Piccioni </PERSON> acknowledged the alternative would cost more than <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION>'s plan. `` But I do n't have an easy time associating dollar costs with cancer risks,'' he said. The four-day hearing continues Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     11-01 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shuttle Atlantis Set For Move To Launch Pad</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Space shuttle Atlantis will be moved to the launch pad early Wednesday for a late November liftoff with a secret military payload. The four-mile, six-hour trip to Launch Pad 39B was scheduled to start at 12:01 a.m., with the shuttle perched upright on the broad back of a giant tracked transporter called a crawler. The move was delayed two days after a three-inch wire was discovered Saturday pinned beneath a nut and washer that are part of structure that attaches the shuttle to its external fuel tank. Before the nut could be loosened to get at the wire, <ORGANIZATION> Atlantis </ORGANIZATION> had to be partially decoupled from the tank, to which it was attached last week. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adminstration </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, said the wire was removed Monday and engineers did not determine how it became lodged under the washer. At the pad, <ORGANIZATION> Atlantis </ORGANIZATION> will be readied for a launch in the last week in November. A date will be set Nov. 10 following a flight readiness review. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> said Monday the launch would occur between 6:32 a.m. and 9:32 a.m. EST. Much of the flight will be cloaked in secrecy because of the classified payload, believed to be an intelligence-gathering satellite. A five-man crew of military officers will fly the mission.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SacredGround     11-01 0377</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sacred Ground,0386</SECOND>
<HEAD>Landfill Ruled Out At Sacred Indian Burial Ground and Recreation
Area</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS J. SHEERAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>INDEPENDENCE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state environmental agency has blocked a nine-year attempt by an excavating company to establish a landfill on land believed to be a sacred Indian burial ground. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shank </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, went to the <ORGANIZATION> Cuyahoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> between <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> on Monday to announce his rejection of the landfill application. `` We won! The council fires will be burning tonight all over the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, a social worker at <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, who has worked to preserve the remaining 25 percent of the burial ground undisturbed by shale mining The council fires, similar to the `` smoke signals'' that Indians used to communicate, `` mean we have succeeded to keep from polluting the burial grounds,'' <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> said his decision, while affecting the burial site and the 33,000-acre recreation area, was based primarily on environmental risks to underground water resources. He said the geology of the landfill site, a 200-foot shale quarry in this <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> suburb, was inappropriate for dumping trash because of the risk of contamination of underground water resources. The company wanted permission to dump up to 2,750 tons a day. In addition, <PERSON> Shank </PERSON> said, `` This decision is based, in part, on my continued belief that a landfill has no business being placed in or near a park or recognized recreation area such as this one in the <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>.'' The recreation area, which follows a 22-mile stretch along the <LOCATION> Cuyahoga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, attracts more than 6 million people a year. <ORGANIZATION> Boyas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Excavating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> had applied to operate a 31-acre landfill on private land within the park boundary for up to 20 years. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Gavin </PERSON>, an attorney for Boyas Excavating, said the company would probably appeal <ORGANIZATION> Shank </ORGANIZATION>'s decision because of the expense incurred in its nine-year battle to gain approval of the landfill. <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON>, 60, a member of the Choctaw Indian tribe of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, has visited the burial ground once or twice weekly for several years. He hopes to rebury bones found at the site in 1984 if Indians gain control of the land.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fed-InterestRates     11-01 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fed-Interest Rates,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stabilizing Interest Rates Forecast</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates have been falling in recent weeks, but many economists believe they will stabilize around current levels for the rest of the year and climb early next year. While the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> is not likely to take any action to drive rates higher for the rest of 1988, these analysts said the central bank will be forced into a series of rate hikes beginning next year to fight renewed inflationary pressures. The Federal Open Market Committee, led by <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, was meeting behind closed doors today to review how the economy has been performing and map monetary policy for the next two months. Analysts said they expected no dramatic change in course from this session, especially given the fact that the presidential election is just one week away. `` Right now there is no overwhelming need to change monetary policy and they certainly are n't going to stick their neck out one week before an election,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyss </PERSON>, chief financial economist with <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, forecasting firm. Various economic reports are suggesting that the economy slowed in the second half of the year. Last week, the government said the broadest measure of the economy, the gross national product, grew at a modest 2.2 percent annual rate during the summer, the slowest pace in almost two years. Many economists believe this slowdown is good because it will relieve the pressure on tight labor markets and factories already operating at peak capacity. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> began a series of credit-tightening steps late last March which culminated in August with a one-half percentage point increase in its discount rate, the interest it charges to make bank loans. Analysts give these changes part of the credit for slowing economic growth although some critics contend the central bank overreacted and has increased the chances of a recession next year. `` Economic growth has slowed to far below its potential,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahn </PERSON>, chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` It is time for the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> to reverse its mistaken interest-rate policy and lower the discount rate before slowing investment derails the 71-month-old economic expansion.'' While economic growth has slowed, many economists argue that it is not at all certain that inflationary pressures have abated. They predicted the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> would take a wait-and-see attitude, ready to react more quickly to signs of inflation than to fears of a recession. The performance of consumer prices, especially energy and food prices, and renewed downward pressure on the dollar will contribute to higher inflation next year, many economists said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, head of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> forecasting firm, said the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> will probably delay further increases in interest rates, however, partly out of fears that it could be accused of manipulating the presidential election. `` I think the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> would consider it extremely poor form to tighten right after the election. People would say they knew they had to tighten but they just held off until -LRB- <PERSON> George </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> got elected,'' he said. Mortgage rates have been falling in recent weeks, reflecting an easing of inflation fears on financial markets because of the various reports showing slower growth in the second half. Fixed-rate mortgages stood at 10.22 percent at the end of last week, according to a survey by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, down from 10.42 percent at the end of September. Reflecting this decline, the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday that it was lowering its maximum interest rate for federally backed <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> home loan mortgages by one-half percentage point to 10 percent, effective Tuesday. But <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasko </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said he would not be surprised to see fixed-rate mortgages hit 11 percent by next spring, driven higher by borrowing demands on the part of the federal government and other factors. `` The economy is working at almost full capacity, there are some pressures on wages,'' he said. `` While these pressures are less ominous than they were two months ago, we are still forecasting higher interest rates.'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> predicted that fixed-rate mortgages could hit 11.5 percent next year. The official minutes of today's meeting will not be released until after the next <ORGANIZATION> FOMC </ORGANIZATION> meeting, scheduled for Dec. 13-14. On Friday, the central bank will release the minutes of the last policy session, held on Sept. 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Property-Cities     11-01 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Property-Cities,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Says LA, Washington, Boston Are Best Real Estate Markets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new survey of real estate investment prospects in major cities says there are fewer `` best'' markets this year, although <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> remain the most favorable. It said the worst real estate markets are <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. The report released Monday said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was dropped from the list of `` most bullish'' property markets because it is `` just too expensive'' to live there. Even <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, while remaining on the list of top prospects, were said to face possible future problems due to their fast-rising housing costs. `` Fewer and fewer people can afford to live in or near those centers, and that will take its toll on economic expansion,'' the report said. But <ORGANIZATION> Real </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said that despite its current problems, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is `` a premier market that will return to favor as its inherent strengths prevail.'' The company said its survey was based on interviews with 90 real estate investors, lenders and developers around the country. It said there are fewer `` best'' markets than in the past and that `` no city or region offers good prospects across the board.'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was called a prime investment prospect despite regulatory barriers. `` LA's pluses _ economic diversity, job growth, climate, quality of life, and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rim </LOCATION> access _ outweigh traffic congestion, smog, ridiculously high housing prices, and regulatory hurdles,'' said the report, `` Emerging Trends in Real Estate, 1989.'' Growth restriction, it says, `` is one of the things that attracts investors to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and to the other top-ranked areas. Developers complain, often bitterly, of the hassles, expense and risk, but they are increasingly resigned to them and willing to accept the responsibilities in return for unsurpass development opportunities, less competition, and upside profits.'' The report put <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> under `` places to be avoided.'' Also included in this category were <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>. `` Any meaningful turnaround is still a year or so off in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> and two to three years in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>,'' the report said. `` <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, a much smaller market, needs a year-or-two respite. When it does come back, it wo n't be to the level of the early'80s.'' Here is what the report said of other cities as real estate investment opportunities: <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>: `` Overbuilt in every property type. Speculative S & amp; L-financed land deals, apartments and office space are in seriously long supply. The <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> economy is slow and steady -LRB- resort pizazz notwithstanding -RRB- and needs three years to rebuild enough momentum to justify new starts.'' <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>: `` share the distinction of receiving about as many positive votes as negatives.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-US-Hostages Bjt   11-01 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Hostages, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Disputes Hostage's Statement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> disputes hostage <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s videotaped statement that the administration bargained with terrorists, but says he still does n't know what happened in the Iran-Contra affair. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> commented Monday on the videotape of <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> that was released in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> by pro-Iranian Shiite Moslem kidnappers. `` I do n't think that was <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> speaking,'' the president said after a bill-signing ceremony in a hotel ballroom. `` I think he had a script that was given to him.'' `` When I was given a script, I always read the lines,'' the former movie actor said to laughter in the room sprinkled with film luminaries. Hollywood executives and such stars as <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Cyd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Charisse </ORGANIZATION> had come to watch <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> sign a copyright bill affecting the entertainment industry. Reporters, however, zeroed in on <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s taped statements that the administration thwarted efforts for the release of the hostages and that Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had bargained with terrorists during the Iran-Contra affair and the 1985 hijacking of a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> airliner on a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> flight. `` There's never been any interference, nor have we ever been negotiating any more than we would with any other kind of kidnapper on a ransom type of basis,'' the president said. Asked specifically whether <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, now the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate for president, was involved in the <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> talks, the president said, `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> has been a part of everything that we've accomplished ... but in a constructive way, and that's why he's my choice in the coming election.'' When asked if this meant <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was involved in all his decisions on the Iran-Contra affair `` which wound up in a scandal,'' the president replied: `` Well, there was no scandal. That scandal ... I'm afraid has been artificially created by a media that I can not understand ...'' The president completed the sentence by saying that his administration sought to find out the facts `` the minute the news broke and the operation was exposed.'' `` And I am still asking, after 10 months of a congressional investigation _ I still do n't know who delivered the weapons and where the money came from,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, asked during an interview with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> anchor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> about <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s statement, said: `` I had no role that you are aware of or are not aware of, absolutely. So I do n't know what he's, what that refers to.'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 41, the chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, was kidnapped by the <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jihad </LOCATION> on March 16, 1985. He is the longest-held of the 14 foreign hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Nine are Americans. Copies of the 2-minute, 35-second tape were delivered to two Western news agencies in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> four days after <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> marked his fourth birthday in captivity. `` I have been very close to being released several times over the past three years, but each time it seems that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government uses its influence to stop any agreement and I do n't understand this,'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said on the tape `` I am not asking <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to deal with terrorists, although Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did so in the Iran-Contra affair and <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> hijacking,'' he said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said `` any information'' <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> has must come from his captors. `` You have to recognize that no hostage is taking something upon himself,'' he said. `` They're telling him what to do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JFK-Mob     11-01 0847</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-JFK-Mob,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Book, TV Special Reignite Debate Over JFK Assassination</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new book and a TV report are reviving the emotional debate over the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> assassination and whether reputed <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> mob chieftain <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> conspired to kill the president. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kwitny </PERSON>, a former investigative reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>, hosts an hour-long public television special that concludes there was a mob conspiracy to kill <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The TV report points to evidence that both <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> assassin <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>'s killer, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>, had connections to <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON>'s crime syndicate. The show airs tonight on <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> public television and elsewhere later in the month. It recounts a potpourri of evidence presented over the years by <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> authors, theorists and investigators, plus some new evidence unearthed by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a cousin of <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> and author of a new book on Marcello and the JFK slaying. <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON>, who was a prime target of then-Attorney General <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and was temporarily deported by <LOCATION> RFK </LOCATION>, was mentioned by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assassinations </ORGANIZATION> as a possible conspiracy suspect in the <LOCATION> JFK </LOCATION> assassination. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel concluded that <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was probably the victim of a conspiracy, breaking sharply with the <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The commission, appointed by <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and headed by then-Chief Justice <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, concluded that there was no conspiracy, and two commission counsels who appear on The Kwitny Report reject the mob conspiracy theory as nonsense. Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., who served as a commission counsel, said evidence presented by the theorists are `` snatches of a little fact here and there which really add up to nothing. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> turned over every stone and found no conspiracy,'' <PERSON> Specter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Belin </PERSON>, the panel's chief counsel, scoffed at the notion that <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>, who gunned down <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> in a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police station, was a mob assassin. `` Mafia hitmen do not go ahead and kill their targets when they're surrounded by police, when they're sure to be apprehended and face life in prison and possible death,'' he said. <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> reportedly hated the <PERSON> Kennedys </PERSON> for the 1961 deportation. A Las Vegas private investigator told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee that <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> indicated to him a year before the slaying that he wanted to kill the president. `` You cut off the head, the tail dies,'' <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Becker </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> as saying. The tail allegedly was a reference to <LOCATION> RFK </LOCATION>. The evidence presented by mob conspiracy theorists include that <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>'s uncle, who helped raise him, worked for the <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> organization, and reports that <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> at least several times met <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrie </PERSON>, who was <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON>'s personal pilot. A new piece of evidence uncovered by <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> in his book, titled `` Mafia Kingfish,'' is an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report quoting a <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> businessman who said shortly after the assassination that he remembered seeing <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> earlier that year accepting cash from a man later identified as a top Marcello lieutenant. The author said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> never followed up on that lead. Ruby, according to one <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report, was not just a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> nightclub owner and a small-time operator but an important player in narcotics trafficking in the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> area, which would have fallen under <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON>'s turf. And the mob conspiracy theorists point to reports that <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> went to visit <PERSON> Santos </PERSON> <PERSON> Traficante </PERSON> when the reputed <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> mob boss was imprisoned in <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. `` Clearly, <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON>'s ties to the Mafia were n't just marginal as the <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> suggested. He was exactly the sort of person to be assigned to an important and risky mission. And he was not the sort of person who would have suddenly shot <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> in sorrow for the <PERSON> Kennedys </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Kwitny </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kwitny </PERSON> points to several eyewitness reports that place Ruby outside the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> police station long before he shot <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> said he just happened on the police station and killed <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON> spontaneously, hoping to spare the president's widow the pain of coming back to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and testifying at <PERSON> Oswald </PERSON>'s trial. <PERSON> Belin </PERSON> dismissed the reports of those who say they saw Ruby earlier. `` Whenever you have a witness to an accident, to any sudden emergency, you're going to get different stories,'' he said. <PERSON> Kwitny </PERSON> also argues that the late Teamsters boss <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON> was involved with <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> in the alleged conspiracy, noting <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON>'s hatred of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> for his dogged investigations of union corruption <PERSON> Kwitny </PERSON> also quoted <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON>'s son as saying his father had known <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> since 1939, and law enforcement officials said <PERSON> Hoffa </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marcello </PERSON> were close. The Kennedy assassination, 25 years ago this Nov. 22, has triggered a never-ending flow of conspiracy theories, ranging from mob retribution to a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> scheme to a plot by <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>. Last week, a British television program claimed three French gangsters killed <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> on a contract from American mob figures. Some, including the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> assassinations committee, believe there was a second gunman standing on the grassy knoll as the president's motorcade rode through <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>' <LOCATION> Dealey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaza </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has stood by the <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> findings and closed its investigation into the slaying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-01 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commodity Prices Stabilize</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New figures from the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> show that farm commodity prices, on the average, have held steady the last two months after peaking during the summer drought. Even so, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s preliminary figures released Monday showed that October prices still averaged 13 percent more than they did a year ago. The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said prices rose from September to October for oranges, milk, lettuce and corn but were offset by lower prices for tomatoes, apples, eggs and soybeans. Meanwhile, prices paid by farmers to meet expenses _ a figure computed only every three months _ rose 1.2 percent from July and averaged 5.5 percent more than a year ago. Farmers paid more for feeder cattle and calves than they did in July, but feed and fuels were lower, the report said. Prices received by farmers for some major commodities are based on mid-month averages and then are revised the following month when additional information is available. The revised figures showed the leveling off actually began in September when the price index held steady at its August average. The preliminary reading for October continued at the August-September level. Prices of raw farm commodities began rising in May as the drought worsened and continued climbing in June, July and August, an increase of about 11 percent from last April. After holding steady during most of last winter, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> index rose 3.1 percent from April to May, followed by June, 2.2 percent; July 2.9 percent; and August 2.1 percent. The drought and searing heat during the spring and summer cut 1988 harvest prospects sharply and triggered the midyear price rise. Total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain production is expected to be down 31 percent from last year's harvest. Despite the leveling of the overall price index, some commodity prices were higher in October. Wheat, for example, rose an additional 14 cents per bushel to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm price average of $ 3.89 per bushel, the most since it was $ 3.95 in May 1981. Prices of livestock and livestock products as a group were unchanged from September, although dairy products gained 3.1 percent during the month and the index for poultry and eggs declined 5 percent. Compared with October 1987, the index was up 4.1 percent. The department's all-crops price index for October, although unchanged from September, was up 27 percent from a year earlier. Prices of feed grain and hay as a group rose 1.5 percent from September and averaged 62 percent more than in October 1987. Prices of commercial vegetables were down 5 percent from September but were still 8.2 percent more than a year ago. Although the projections are subject to change, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> economists say that net cash income of farmers may be in the range of $ 55 billion to $ 60 billion this year, compared with the record level of $ 57.1 billion in 1987. That is the difference between cash receipts and cash expenses during the calendar year. Department economists are holding to an earlier prediction that consumer food prices will rise 3 percent to 5 percent this year, compared with a 4.2 percent average increase in 1987. Before the drought took hold, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> was predicting a 1988 food price hike of 2 percent to 4 percent. Some <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> officials also have predicted that the drought may add 2 percentage points to food prices in 1989, above the expected increase in inflation, currently forecast at around 4 percent. That could mean a 1989 food prices increase in the range of 6 percent to 7 percent. The report said: _ Cattle averaged $ 67.90 per 100 pounds of live weight nationally, up from $ 67.20 in September and $ 62.90 reported for October 1987 Those are averages for all types of cattle sold as beef. _ Hogs averaged $ 39.40 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 40.70 in September and $ 48.90 a year earlier _ Corn, at $ 2.71 a bushel, was up from $ 2.60 in September and the average of $ 1.55 per bushel a year earlier _ Wheat prices at the farm, according to preliminary figures, averaged $ 3.89 per bushel, compared with $ 3.75 in September and $ 2.62 a year earlier _ Rice averaged $ 7.15 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 6.82 in September and $ 5.88 a year earlier _ Soybeans were $ 7.71 per bushel, compared with $ 7.94 in September and $ 5.04 a year earlier _ Upland cotton was reported at 50 cents per pound, compared with 51.8 in September and 65.1 cents in October 1987 _ Eggs were 58.7 cents per dozen, compared with 63.8 cents in September and 50.2 cents a year earlier _ Milk was $ 12.80 per 100 pounds, compared with $ 12.40 in September and $ 12.90 a year earlier _ Broilers were 37.5 cents per pound, live weight, compared with 39.2 cents in September and 25.1 cents a year ago
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeltaCrash     11-01 0827</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Delta Crash,810</SECOND>
<HEAD>Documents Suggest Pilot Waited Too Long To Apply Full Power</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot of a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> flight that crashed last August near <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> waited at least 20 seconds after a stall warning before he applied full power, according to documents. The documents made public Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> pointed to no specific cause for the Aug. 31 crash in which 14 of the 108 people aboard Flight 1141 were killed. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> investigation is not expected to be completed for a number of weeks. According to a transcript of the cockpit voice recorder tape on Flight 1141, an unusual `` snap'' was heard seconds after liftoff, followed almost immediately by a vibration of the control column _ a warning of an impending stall. A normal procedure for dealing with an impending stall close to the ground such as in a takeoff would be to apply full power and attempt to fly out of the problem, according to aviation experts. But the transcript showed that Capt. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 48, a veteran <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> pilot, did not call for `` full power'' until nearly 23 seconds after the first sign of trouble and nearly 20 seconds after the so-called `` stickshaker'' stall warning. The call to full power came as the aircraft was about to crash and eight seconds after <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> could be heard on the tape saying, `` We're not gon na make it,'' according to the transcript. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a 23-year veteran at <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> with 17,000 hours of flying including 6,500 in a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727, later told investigators, `` In retrospect, I should have pushed up full power immediately.'' A summary of the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> interview of <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> from his hospital bed was included among the documents made public Monday without further comment by safety board officials. The documents provided no apparent clear evidence as to specifically what caused Flight 1141 not to gain proper lift as it departed the <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> airport. The flight was bound for <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>. The investigation continues to focus on the possibility that the flight crew failed to set the plane's flaps properly, inhibiting the aircraft's lift. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> previously had said that the wing flaps were found in a retracted position in the wreckage as was the cockpit lever controlling the flaps. But the cockpit tape transcript shows, as also has been previously disclosed, that co-pilot <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> specifically acknowledged during a pre-takeoff check that the flaps were in the proper 15 degree extension _ contradicting evidence in the wreckage. But that does not necessarily mean the flaps actually were in that position, sources close to the investigation have said. Among the documents released Monday were the results of a sophisticated sound analysis of the tape to determine whether there were any background sounds to indicate flaps being extended. The tests concluded that after an examination of the entire tape from Flight 1141 no noise pattern could be found to match the pattern of flaps actually being set on a test <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 aircraft. Two `` click'' sounds heard on the tape did not match the pattern of an actual setting of flaps on the test plane, the document said. <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> has told investigators he recalls nothing after the plane departed from the gate. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> has said he does not know whether the flaps were set properly, although he recalled <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> making the acknowledgment. A third man in the cockpit, flight engineer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Judd </PERSON>, 31, said he believes that <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> set the flaps to their proper setting, but does not recall actually seeing the flap lever in that position. According to the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> documents, a takeoff alarm that should have sounded if the flaps were not properly set, was inspected 20 days before the accident and replaced because the horn was `` weak and intermittent.'' A new alarm was installed. Meanwhile, the cockpit tape, which began shortly before the aircraft pushed back from the gate, revealed that Flight 1141 had nearly a 30-minute wait before getting takeoff clearance, during which much of the time the flight crew _ sometimes with a flight attendant taking part _ engaged in casual conversation, including a lengthy exchange about the large number of birds at the <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> airport. At one point, the transcript refers to nearly eight minutes of `` nonpertinent conversation'' _ omitted from the transcript _ with a senior flight attendant. The exchange is cut short when <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> asks <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> about requiring to change frequencies to contact a second ground controller as the plane moved from the east to the west side of the airport. `` Yeah, I'm sorry. I'm sitting here talking to the flight attendant,'' apologized <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>. <PERSON> Judd </PERSON>, the flight engineer, later told investigators that when the plane was third in line for takeoff, he announced the plane would be taking off soon `` in part because of his concern about the flight attendant's continued presence in the cockpit,'' one <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> document said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Campaign-JFK Bjt   11-01 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Campaign-JFK, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>JFK's Legacy Echoing on the Campaign Trail in the Closing Days</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In Republican as well as Democratic accents, the name and the policies of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> are echoing in the waning days of the campaign for the White House. And to hear the Republican ticket tell it, Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> claims that on such issues as taxes and defense, he has more in common with JFK than <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> does. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been invoking the <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> political legacy all campaign long. On Sunday, after shrinking from the liberal label all season, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> declared that he is one, and said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> was, too. `` Yes, I am a liberal in the tradition of <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said. That's not the Kennedy legacy <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> cites. `` How much the national <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has changed since the days of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` How far it has moved from those policies of lower taxes and a stronger defense.'' A <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign commercial recalls the narrow 1960 victory that put <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> in the White House. `` My friends, they won that election by a margin of 112,000 votes out of nearly 70 million cast,'' he says. `` And remember what a difference <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> made in the lives of millions and millions of people.'' The Kennedy issue first was unleashed by Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee and unlikely enforcer of claims on the JFK legacy. In debate with Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> dismissed his rival's claim to congressional experience matching <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s with a stinging: `` Senator, you're no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s brother, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, was gentler and kinder to <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said that while they disagree on issues, he thinks the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator was treated unfairly in news accounts that questioned his record and abilities. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> used <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s belittling line Monday to dispute <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' claim to the venerable liberal tradition of <LOCATION> Roosevelt </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> `` I did n't know <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and I did n't serve with <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is no <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told a crowd in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. When he chose <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he was reassembling a <ORGANIZATION> Boston-Austin </ORGANIZATION> partnership that would win the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> did in 1960. He says that was `` a strong ticket, one of our best tickets,'' and that he and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> are out to match it. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has taken to reciting lines from <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> speeches, notably on a 1963 tax cut proposal. In <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, last Thursday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' election would mean higher taxes, smothering economic growth, and that it would then become virtually impossible to cut the budget deficit `` The reason for this was perhaps best explained by a previous Democratic president, none other than <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, back in 1962. ` It is a paradoxical truth that tax rates are too high today and tax revenues are too low, and the soundest way to raise the revenues in the long run is to cut the rates now,''' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said quoting the late president. In <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, insisting that his proposal for a reduction in the tax on capital gains would spur the economy and create new jobs, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> endorsed just such a plan. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has denounced the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> proposal as a tax break for the rich. In <LOCATION> Waterbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recalled a memorable <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> campaign rally shortly before his 1960 victory, when thousands of people waited long into a rainy night to see the young candidate from <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. `` If we succeed here, then the cause of freedom is strengthened,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> told them. `` It's important to remember how President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> went about strengthening the cause of freedom,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` He signed one of the most important tax cuts in our history. He rapidly rebuilt <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s national defense. And from that position of strength he was able to negotiate a test ban treaty with the Soviets.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> did not live to sign the tax cut he proposed. President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> signed it into law on Feb. 26, 1964. There's sometimes a Kennedy flavor in <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' campaign speeches, more often in the six weeks or so since <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sorensen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s friend, aide and speechwriter, began traveling with the Democratic nominee. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> tells people that `` we can do better,'' promises to `` get this country moving again,'' sometimes speaks of conquering new frontiers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     11-01 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court to Rule in Secrecy Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> will referee a dispute over congressional access to national security information, the latest conflict over checks and balances between the legislative and executive branches. The justices announced Monday they will consider reviving legislation limiting presidential authority to withhold classified information. A decision is expected by July. Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who had breast cancer surgery 10 days ago at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, was back on the bench as she and her fellow justices returned from a two-week recess to hear arguments and issue orders. <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, 58, has said the cancer was detected in an early stage and the prognosis is for a full recovery. The national security case involving classified information, a sticking point for years between <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and various presidents, stems from a 1983 directive by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The directive requires federal officials, before they are allowed access to classified information, to sign an agreement they will not disclose the information. The directive also created a standard form for officials to sign, promising they never will divulge classified or `` classifiable'' information without written permission from proper authorities. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said the president is seeking to abridge free-speech rights of federal employees and `` punish whistleblowers for making disclosures that embarrass their superiors.'' Opponents of the presidential directive also said the secrecy agreement federal employees must sign would bar them for life from revealing information to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> which lawmakers are entitled to receive. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> enacted legislation prohibiting use of funds during the 1987-88 fiscal year to implement the standard forms <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had authorized. A similar provision was attached to the spending bill for the current fiscal year. A federal judge declared the legislation unconstitutional last May because he said it tramples on presidential foreign-policy powers. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, representing members of the nation's diplomatic corps, and senators and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members from both political parties appealed to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to reinstate the law. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> announced last week that he was pocket-vetoing another measure intended to give new protection to federal employees who expose government fraud and abuse. That measure is not tied directly to the case acted on by the court Monday. In other action, the court: _ Heard arguments in a case involving a woman denied partnership in a leading <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> accounting firm The case centers on how difficult it should be for employers to disprove charges of sexual stereotyping. _ Killed a lawsuit against the government stemming from the World War II mass detention of Japanese-Americans in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prison camps The action bars a suit for property losses by veterans of the internment camps, but legislation was enacted this year that permits each detainee to receive $ 20,000. _ Agreed in a case from <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to decide whether states must continue to provide lawyers for indigent death row inmates after they have lost their initial round of appeals _ Ruled, 7-2, that police in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> did not violate the rights of a man suspected of drunken driving when they failed to read him <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> warnings after he was stopped for questioning _ Let stand an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> law that bans the possession of child pornography _ Allowed public school officials in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to ban leaflets and school yearbook advertisements that promoted a student-run, lunch-hour Bible study group
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881101-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-01-88 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietDeficit Bjt   11-01 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Deficit, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts Say Soviet Budget Gap Is Relatively Bigger Than US Deficit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
