<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 2322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths     05-23 0276</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths,0289</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: AMs separates moved as a0662 on Schoenbrun and as a0580 on
Grandi.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>David Schoenbrun</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenbrun </PERSON>, 73, a war correspondent who was recruited for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON>, died Monday of heart failure. He was 73. <PERSON> Schoenbrun </PERSON> was introduced to <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON> by Gen. <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> at the end of World War II. <PERSON> Schoenbrun </PERSON> had gone to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in 1941 with the <ORGANIZATION> War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> as an editor. He joined the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in 1943 and covered the invasion of southern <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 1944. <PERSON> Murrow </PERSON> hired <PERSON> Schoenbrun </PERSON> as <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> correspondent. He was <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> bureau chief from 1947 until 1961. <PERSON> Schoenbrun </PERSON> later served in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, as <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' main political correspondent.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Dino Grandi</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dino </PERSON> <PERSON> Grandi </PERSON>, who lost out to <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> in a 1921 bid for leadership of the <ORGANIZATION> Fascist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and helped depose the dictator in 1943, died Saturday at age 92. <PERSON> Grandi </PERSON> fought in World War I and joined the fascist squads that terrorized the Italian countryside. He failed to win the leadership of the fascists at a national congress in 1921 but successfully made a bid for a seat in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. He participated in the October 1922 march on <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> that led to <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>'s installation as head of government. <PERSON> Grandi </PERSON> served as undersecretary of the interior in 1924 and was foreign minister from 1929 to 1934.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Edward Adamek</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA CLARITA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Adamek </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> stunt man and rodeo cowboy, died Friday of cancer at the age of 77. <PERSON> Adamek </PERSON> worked in the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> movie `` <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobo </LOCATION>'' and the TV series `` Gunsmoke.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-ArmsControlPlay     05-23 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Arms Control Play,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Gets Special Showing of Broadway Show on Arms Control</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Arms Treaty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The producers of a Broadway play about arms control negotiations brought their performance to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday night, where it was viewed by an appreciative audience that included the secretary of state and two men involved in such talks. `` It bore no resemblance to reality, that's what made it so good,'' said Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> after viewing `` A Walk in the Woods.'' `` It was a good characterization and a lot of laughs,'' he said. The play, starring <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Waterston </PERSON> as the American negotiator and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosky </PERSON> as his Soviet counterpart, was performed in the Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> auditorium, across the street from the Capitol. A dozen senators, having just finished a day of debate about the U.S.-Soviet medium-range arms control treaty, were among the 250 people who attended the play, along with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON> <PERSON> Glitman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON> was the American who formed the basis of <PERSON> Waterston </PERSON>'s character, while <PERSON> Glitman </PERSON> was the chief <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiator on the medium-range missile treaty <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glitman </PERSON> agreed with <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>. `` It did n't bear any relationship to anything we talked about,'' said <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON>. `` It's a dramatization, and while it's good, it's not like reality,'' said <PERSON> Glitman </PERSON>. The play, a black comedy, is based on <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON>'s 1982 private talk with <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> Kvitsinsky </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nitze </PERSON>'s Soviet counterpart. That discussion produced an agreement between the two men on the framework for a medium-range missile treaty, but the plan was later rejected by both governments. Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he thought the production `` dramatizes the human side of what is too often a faceless bureaucracy.'' <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> was one of the hosts for the play, which was performed by <PERSON> Waterston </PERSON> and <PERSON> Prosky </PERSON> on their day off.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 2334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ObieAwards     05-23 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obie Awards,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>Off-Broadway Honored By Village Voice</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Playwright <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON>, actor <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Reeve </PERSON> and director <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brook </PERSON> were among 24 people recognized Monday night for their contribution to Off and Off-Off Broadway theater at the 33rd annual Village Voice Obie awards ceremony. <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON> was honored with an Obie for sustained achievement as a playwright. Sharing the award for best new play were <PERSON> Caryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> for `` Serious Money'' and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> Fornes </PERSON> for `` Abingdon Square.'' The playwrights' awards included $ 1,000 in cash grants from the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartenieff </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> <PERSON> Blossom </PERSON> won Obies for sustained excellence in performance. <PERSON> Reeve </PERSON> was honored for his courageous work on behalf of Chilean artists. Actress <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogosian </PERSON> presided over the awards ceremony at the Ritz in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>. Receiving Obies in the performance category were: <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bazzell </PERSON> for `` The Signal Season of Dummy Hoy;'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> for `` <ORGANIZATION> Frankie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> in the <PERSON> Claire </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Lune </PERSON>;'' <PERSON> Yvonne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryceland </PERSON> for `` The Road to <LOCATION> Mecca </LOCATION>;'' <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Garber </PERSON> for `` Wenceslas Square;'' and <PERSON> Erland </PERSON> <PERSON> Josephson </PERSON> for `` The Cherry Orchard.'' Also, <PERSON> Gordana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rashovich </PERSON> for `` A <PERSON> Shayna </PERSON> <PERSON> Maidel </PERSON>;'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Seitz </PERSON> for `` Abingdon Square;'' <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> for `` Dress Suits to Hire;'' <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> for `` The Three Lives of <PERSON> Lucie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabrol </PERSON>;'' and <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> for `` American Notes.'' Obies in the director category went to <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogart </PERSON> for `` No Plays No Poetry ...;'' <PERSON> Brook </PERSON> for `` The Mahabharata;'' and <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Taymor </PERSON> for `` <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Darien </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchmuller </PERSON> was honored for sustained excellence in stage design; <PERSON> Huck </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> for sustained excellence in scenic design; and B.H. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> for sustained excellence in combat choreography. <PERSON> Elliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldenthal </PERSON> won an Obie for his music in `` <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Darien </PERSON>.'' Also honored were the <ORGANIZATION> CSC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Repertory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> and the Theatre for a New Audience, which received $ 5,000 cash grants from the newspaper for achieving artistic excellence while working with severe budget limitations. Village Voice critics judged the 1988 Obies for Off and Off-Off Broadway. Guest judges were <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> of the Non-Traditional Casting Project, and <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Malina </PERSON>, founder and artistic director of the Living Theatre.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 2339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BoxOffice 1stLd-Writethru a0715 05-23 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Box Office, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0715,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>Good First Week Tally for `Willow,' Reel Test Next Week</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 24th graf, `8. ``Salsa ... to CORRECT revenue for the
film to $1.13 million, sted $1.14 million.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JEFF WILSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The medieval fantasy `` Willow,'' a $ 55 million gamble in an often-disastrous film genre, found an audience and box office figures Monday show moviemaker <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> apparently has another hit on his hands. `` Willow,'' released early to avoid first-week competition from certain blockbusters `` Crocodile Dundee II'' and `` Rambo III,'' was the nation's top-grossing film in its debut weekend with an $ 8.3 million take. <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> said he was buoyed by the figures and was confident `` Willow'' could maintain its box office appeal despite the two sure-fire sequels that will flood 2,000 screens each on Wednesday. `` Willow'' surpassed the opening weekend business of `` Raiders of the Lost Ark'' -LRB- $ 8.26 million in June 1981 -RRB- and `` Top Gun'' -LRB- $ 8.19 million in May 1986 -RRB-, <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> said. In addition to high expectations from `` Star Wars'' creator <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> and `` Cocoon'' director <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, `` Willow'' has received interest because of the amount of money it cost to make the film over a two-year period. It also comes after two expensive <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> flops _ `` Labyrinth'' and `` Howard the Duck.'' One `` Willow'' critic recently called it `` <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> the Duck.'' <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, who monitors box office trends for <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Variety </ORGANIZATION>, noted that only five motion pictures in history have ever done $ 8 million-plus during May's traditional pre-Memorial Day holiday movie slump. Other Top 10 films pulled in considerably less during the weekend. Last week's top performer, `` Friday the 13th Part VII - The New Blood,'' took in $ 3.43 million to place second in the latest sweepstakes. It made almost as much as `` Willow'' in its debut with an $ 8.2 million take on 1,796 screens. In third was `` Colors'' with $ 2.9 million, followed by `` Beetlejuice'' with $ 2.7 million and `` Shakedown'' in fifth with $ 1.2 million. In `` Willow,'' the main character lives in a village of little people and finds a baby floating in the river, but it's a special baby who will threaten the throne of the evil Queen <PERSON> Bavmorda </PERSON>. The queen orders her warriors to find and kill the baby and the story revolves around the perilous trek to a castle sanctuary. `` Willow,'' which opened Friday at 1,024 theaters nationwide with little enthusiasm from reviewers, is the latest effort from <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>, whose `` Star Wars'' and `` Indiana Jones'' films have grossed $ 1 billion. <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> reviewer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kehr </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON>: `` In ` Willow,' the Force has left him. He's imitating himself and he's moping while he does it. Daily Variety termed the film `` a medieval mishmash'' but predicted `` kids will probably love it.'' The Hollywood Reporter praised the production values but complained the storyline `` never really kicks into overdrive.'' Here are the top films for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross, number of weeks in release, and estimated production costs when available. 1. `` Willow,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 8.31 million, 1,024 screens, $ 8,106 per screen, $ 8.3 million, one week, n-a. 2. `` Friday the 13th Part VII - The New Blood,'' Paramount, $ 3.43 million, 1,796 screens, $ 1,912 per screen, $ 13.24 million, two weeks, n-a. 3. `` Colors,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.94 million, 1,388 screens, $ 2,122 per screen, $ 34.4 million, six weeks, $ 12 million. 4. `` Beetlejuice,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.72 million, 1,546 screens, $ 1,764 per screen, $ 58,8 million, eight weeks, $ 20 million. 5. `` Shakedown,'' Universal, $ 1.22 million, 938 screens, $ 1,703 per screen, $ 8.12 million, three weeks, n-a. 6. `` Moonstruck,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.17 million, 771 screens, $ 1,525 per screen, $ 73.97 million, 23 weeks, $ 17 million. 7. `` Above The Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.14 million, 715 screens, $ 1,604 per screen, $ 17.45 million, seven weeks, $ 14 million. 8. `` Salsa,'' Cannon, $ 1.13 million, 757 screens, $ 1,510 per screen, $ 6.79 million, three weeks, n-a. 9. `` <LOCATION> Biloxi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blues </LOCATION>,'' Universal, $ 1.12 million, 876 screens, $ 1,282 per screen, $ 39.3 million, nine weeks, $ 16 million. 10. `` The Last Emperor,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 930,729, 792 screens, $ 1,175 per screen, $ 40.29 million, 27 weeks, $ 25 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-MissUniverse 2ndLd-Writethru a0778 05-23 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss Universe, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0778,0621</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thai Student Crowned Miss Universe</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 5 grafs to UPDATE with California schools the
winner attended. Picks up 5th graf pvs, ``Organizers of ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SHIRLEY LAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LINKOU, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 19-year-old student from <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> who studied in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was crowned Miss Universe of 1988 in a flashy competition on this <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> island Tuesday morning. <PERSON> Porntip </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakhirunkanok </PERSON>, a black-haired <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> resident, won $ 250,000 in cash and prizes, including a sports car and mink coat. She wiped away tears of joy and joined her hands together in a Thai sign of thanks after winning. The first runner-up was <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Yunjung </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang </PERSON>. She was followed by Miss <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Amanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivares </PERSON>; Miss <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mizuho </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakaguchi </PERSON>; and Miss <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeung </PERSON>. Sixty-six women had competed. Among the 10 semi-finalists was Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Nakhirunkanok </PERSON>, who weighs 114 pounds and stands 5 feet 8 inches tall, was educated at <ORGANIZATION> Pasadena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> UCLA </ORGANIZATION> in southern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. She said during the program that she owed her English-speaking ability to <LOCATION> Big </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bird </LOCATION> on the `` Sesame Street'' children's program. Organizers of the 37th Miss Universe pageant estimated 600 million people in 57 countries watched the televised competition for a successor to the 1987 Miss Universe, <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolocco </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>. The program was filmed at 9 a.m. Tuesday -LRB- 9 p.m. EDT Monday -RRB- from a 9,000-seat sports stadium in a <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> suburb so <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> viewers could watch during prime time Monday evening. The schedule forced the local audience to don tuxedos and evening attire at an hour more appropriate for reading the morning newspaper over a bowl of cereal. The live broadcast seen in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> was briefly interrupted with a bulletin for a civil defense emergency exercise in the central island. Missing from this year's festivities was long-time host <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON>, who resigned after last year's competition in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> to protest the use of furs. He was replaced by television personality <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thicke </PERSON>. Beauty pageants were banned in 1964 by <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s leaders, who viewed the competitions as an extravagance for a poor nation and were dismayed by reports that a Miss <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> winner performed strip dances in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. The island has since emerged as one of <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s most prosperous countries, and authorities lifted the ban last year to clear the way for a domestic airline to sponsor the Miss Universe pageant. There is lingering opposition from a few groups, including retired soldiers who view beauty contests as an insult to mothers. But the telecast generally was seen in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> as an opportunity to present the island to a worldwide audience as the Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the official name of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> seldom used internationally because most countries recognize the rival communist Chinese government in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Organizers pledged to refer to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> as the Republic of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during the telecast and promised the two-hour program would have about 30 minutes of videotapes taken during recent weeks of the contestants at scenic spots in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. The Miss Universe pageant generated much interest in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> but was pushed into the background Friday when the island's most violent anti-government protest in recent years broke out in <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>. The 18-hour street battle between protesters and police left more than 200 people injured. Nearly 100 demonstrators were detained. Prizes for the 1988 Miss Universe include $ 76,000 in cash, a Maserati convertible automobile, and a mink coat and mink jacket. The 11 judges include <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeana </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeager </PERSON>, who made history with their round-the-world flight aboard the Voyager two years ago, and <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruttan </PERSON> of the television series `` <LOCATION> L.A </LOCATION>. Law.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WasteKiln 2Takes   05-23 0893</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Waste Kiln, 2 Takes,0916</SECOND>
<HEAD>Incinerator Or Recycler? Company Makes Product From Hazardous
Waste</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN McGILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MORGAN CITY, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> is making money and enemies at both ends of the 275-foot-long contraption he runs near this town of oil men and shrimp boats. His hazardous waste kiln at <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Processors </ORGANIZATION> _ big as a football field with a smokestack 140 feet high _ is a high-profile presence on the flat southern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> horizon. It's also a target of two groups that want to shut it down: some local residents who suspect it's dangerous and business competitors who accuse the company of skirting environmental regulations. Marine Shale, which employs about 240 people, denies the claims and insists that it cooperates fully with regulators. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as well as <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, the debate centers on whether <PERSON> Kent </PERSON>'s contraption is an incinerator, which must meet one set of regulations, or a recycling plant, required to meet others. Kent charges $ 200 to $ 300 per 50-gallon drum to take in hazardous wastes from the companies that make them, ranging from glues to various petroleum by-products, but excluding PCBs, dioxins, asbestos, explosives, mercury compounds or disease-carrying materials. He receives 720 tons a day. He heats the waste to about 2,500 degrees Fahrenheit for 2 -LCB- hours while running it through a whirling kiln that looks like an elongated cement mixer. He sells the resulting aggregate as material for road beds and parking lots. He has about 10 customers so far. If <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION>'s claims about its process and product are found valid by state and federal officials examining the company's operations, it could render competitors' incinerators obsolete while revolutionizing the way a growing national hazardous waste disposal problem is handled It could also be very lucrative for Marine Shale. Company attorney and vice president <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Eldredge </PERSON> says a patent is being sought for part of the process and licensing arrangements will follow. <PERSON> Eldredge </PERSON> likes to say that incinerators create hazardous waste for storage in landfills, while <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> eliminates it in the creation of a product. At <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION>, next to <PERSON> Bayou </PERSON> <PERSON> Boeuf </PERSON>, conveyors lift piles of various materials _ some sludgy, some solid and some that serve as their own fuel _ into a huge rotating cylinder. Cameras at both ends monitor the inside of the kiln, which looks like <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION>'s vision of hell, red hot with glowing embers and tumbling debris. A computer keeps tabs on temperature, gases and pressure, shutting down the operation if anything goes awry, according to <PERSON> Eldredge </PERSON>. Earlier this year <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> gave members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> clear plastic letter openers containing a small amount of the aggregate in the handle. The public relations gimmick prompted <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fortuna </PERSON>, lobbyist for a trade group representing competitors, to write to the lawmakers and urge them to contact the Capitol's safety engineer `` to arrange for the transportation of this material to a permitted facility for proper disposal. `` Sure, we did it,'' acknowledged <PERSON> Fortuna </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Hazardous </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. He contends the Marine Shale product is dangerous. <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> says envy motivates the Treatment Council. He's charging less than half what his competitors do to take in hazardous waste, and then turns it into a product that sells for $ 1 a ton. `` It makes them sad,'' he says sardonically. The <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> has joined South Louisianians Against Pollution, or SLAP, to fight Marine Shale. <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Herman </PERSON>, head of SLAP, says she opposes <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> because she believes, admittedly without evidence, that the company may be a factor in the area's unsually high cancer rate. `` Personally, I think they're contributing to it,'' she said. SLAP and <PERSON> Fortuna </PERSON>'s group have threatened a federal suit to try to halt <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION>'s operations. The battle has spread to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, D-La., attacked the company in April in a subcommittee hearing, suggesting that laws might be needed to close loopholes that allow <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> to operate without an incinerator permit <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> suggested that <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON> was acting on behalf of his friend <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Broadhurst </PERSON>, whose law firm has represented <ORGANIZATION> Rollins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Treatment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> member. <PERSON> Broadhurst </PERSON> is the attorney and lobbyist who accompanied former presidential candidate <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> on the ship `` Monkey Business'' with <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>. <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> labeled <PERSON> Kent </PERSON>'s suggestion ridiculous. The 140-foot emissions stack at <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> puts out a steady plume of vapor, which the company says is clean. Water used to `` scrub'' the gases of particles that might pollute the air is re-used in the process, he said. Emissions pass through a `` bag house,'' where, according to <PERSON> Eldredge </PERSON>, they are filtered through more than a thousand bags, resembling vacuum cleaner bags, before release into the air. <PERSON> Eldredge </PERSON> stressed that none of the water from the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION> process is discharged into the bayou. He cited state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quality </ORGANIZATION> records showing that traditional incinerators, such as the one run by <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, contaminate `` scrub'' water that must be treated before it is discharged into the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, a source of drinking water for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and other communities. About 1,750 companies that generate hazardous materials in 42 states ship them to <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shale </ORGANIZATION>, according to spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> August </PERSON>. The materials are tested to ensure that they can be safely put in Marine Shale's kiln, he said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BridgeWalk     05-23 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bridge Walk,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>65,000 Stroll Across Chesakpeake Bridge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANDY POINT, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A record 65,000 people walked across the 4.3 mile eastbound span of the <LOCATION> Chesapeake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>. Stollers were met Sunday on the west side by Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, who kicked off his One Million Marylanders bay clean-up campaign, an attempt to get residents to practice water conservation and change household disposal habits. The Bay Bridge Walk, which began at 9 a.m. and was completed by 5:30 p.m., drew 15,000 more people this year than last year's record, in part because Sunday was one of the first warm weekend days in what has been a rainy, cool spring The first annual walk was in 1975. `` I'm out here every year because it's here,'' said <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>'s resident <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Chesley </PERSON> `` Why you walk across a bridge is the same reason you climb a mountain _ because it's there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LiveFromMoscow     05-23 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Live From Moscow,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan Tour de Force _ Will it Play on Vremya?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN WOLMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 We have a pretty good idea what remarkable images Americans will see during the upcoming <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit: <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> toasted in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, embracing dissidents and <ORGANIZATION> Bolsheviks </ORGANIZATION>, chatting with <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> monks, talking shop with Russian filmmakers. Not to mention <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> at the Monument to the Defenders in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>. To capture this presidential tour de force, there will be more American TV technicians in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> than spies and diplomats combined. What with the eight-hour time difference, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> appearances will be beamed back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in plenty of time for morning newscasts. Breakfast at <LOCATION> Wimbledon </LOCATION>? This will be breakfast at the Hall of Facets. But what about the Soviet people? What will Gostelradio, the Soviet radio-and-television monopoly, show of the summit? <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the refuseniks lead off Vremya -LRB- the evening news -RRB-? Already, Soviet TV has taped a interview with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for broadcast on Friday. But it was a simple `` talking head'' session, 30 minutes of question-and-answer _ with none of the adventure or significance of next week's <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> tours around <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. American experts believe Soviet television will broadcast excerpts from the president's address at <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hills </ORGANIZATION>, as well as ceremonial exchanges between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in the Kremlin. If there are agreements to be signed, the klieg lights will be set up in <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON>'s Hall. And surely there will be footage from the Bolshoi, where the <ORGANIZATION> Gorbachevs </ORGANIZATION> host the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> for a 90-minute ballet sampler. But will Soviet officials air highlights from the <LOCATION> Danilov </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monastery </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will discuss religious freedom with monks who work restoring Orthodox icons? How much will be broadcast from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s dialogue on artistic freedom with Soviet intellectuals at the Union of Writers club? And what of the first lady's visit to <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> _ will she be shown touring the Hermitage, much as <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was shown on American TV touring the Smithsonian galleries? Just what images will Glasnost permit? Will Soviet television let <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> be <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>? ` It'll be very interesting to see what they show on television the week before the summit,'' former Ambassador <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON> said last week, wondering whether <PERSON> Gostelradio </PERSON> will `` show the bum on the grate.'' Soviet TV loves to broadcast pictures of hapless vagabonds reduced to sleeping on the heat grates near the White House; it's a sad and pathetic side of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> dream and many viewers of Soviet TV probably have come to believe it's an accurate snapshot of life in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. But certainly something is afoot on the Gostelradio side of Glasnost. Just last week, Soviet TV viewers got a glance of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> performance, a glimpse of a Visa card and a sales pitch for the quality of <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> TVs. Never mind that you ca n't get a <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> TV in the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION>. Commercials for <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Visa </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> were aired last week in the midst of a five-part Soviet series on life in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Estimated audience: 120 million people. `` I expect we might get some angry letters from people saying, ` Why are you advertising <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> TVs when we ca n't buy any?''' TV personality <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> said at a news conference announcing his series. To hear him tell it, the decision to air the commercials was less Glasnost than Perestroika -LRB- the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> campaign for economic reform -RRB-. `` We on our part can make some money out of this, which in our day and age when we are becoming economically self-supportive and self-sufficient, also makes sense,'' <PERSON> Posner </PERSON> said. Reports in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said the Soviet broadcast agency Gostelradio received $ 10,000 for each 30-second ad. Profit motive. That's the American way.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolman </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant bureau chief in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Afghanistan Bjt   05-23 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Afghanistan, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Afghanistan Pullout Saves Gorbachev From Reagan Lecture</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet decision to withdraw troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is more than a life-saving step. It has rescued <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> from another `` leave-the-Afghans-alone'' lecture from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. As the leaders prepare for their fourth summit, in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> May 29-June 2, the first <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> units have come home to <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION> and the Soviets seem determined to meet a February 1989 deadline for the removal of all 115,000 troops. The erasure of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> as the topmost regional issue at the summit will give <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> more time to push <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> toward settlements in other global hot spots _ <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. At least for now, `` there has been a resolution, or at least the formula for resolving the Afghan issue,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON>, undersecretary of state for political affairs and head of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team preparing for the summit discussion of regional issues. `` At the summit there just is n't that much more to say to them, except perhaps, ` thanks' and ` keep up the good work,''' said another <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, speaking on condition of anonymity. This official, and <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> as well, suggested, however, that Afghan issues could re-emerge as a summit topic because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> are still actively engaged in the settlement process as the Soviets wind down their eight-year war. `` In terms of military arrangements, one of our biggest concerns is that they take out whatever minefields they have sown over the past eight years,'' the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said. `` This is an issue of safety for civilians coming back to their villages.'' Earlier this year, before the Soviets signed a pledge to withdraw their troops, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> beseeched <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to take the further step of ceasing military assistance to the government headed by Afghan leader <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>. In return, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> said it would stop giving military support to the mujahadeen, the anti-Soviet resistance fighters, matching Soviet restraint with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> restraint. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> rejected the proposal and on May 14, the Soviet military commander in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> announced he would leave behind up to $ 1 billion in arms and installations for use by the Afghan army. `` That does n't strike me as a demonstration of tremendous restraint,'' <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> said. He reiterated the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> determination to keep helping the guerrillas and said, bluntly, `` we'll have practical ways of accomplishing that purpose.'' Asked if <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> might seek <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s help in getting the resistance to let the Russian troops retreat home without being harried by attacks, <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON> said the Soviets would do better by seeking `` local arrangements'' with mujahadeen leaders. Though these issues remain, the fundamental decision to withdraw and evidence last week that the agreement is being carried out, removed an irritant that has nagged U.S.-Soviet relations since December 1979, when <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> forces entered what had been a civil war. President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> protested the invasion by keeping the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic team home from the 1980 <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> games and he embargoed grain sales to the Soviets. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> resumed the grain deals, but he made clear that better U.S.-Soviet relations hinged to a large extent on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s willingness to pull its troops home from the Afghan conflict Indeed, before his met <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in 1985, in <LOCATION> Reykjavik </LOCATION> in 1986 and in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1987, he devoted speeches to the issue and signaled his intention to berate the Soviet leader about <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> when they met. For example, in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> eight days before the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` It's time for them to pack up, pull out and go home. It's time that they set a date certain for the complete withdrawal of all Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said it appeared that even the Soviets were writing off the current regime in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` The Soviets pride themselves on recognizing objective reality. Well, it's time for them to bite the bullet.'' By contrast, two weeks before the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit, the White House found itself praising Soviet actions, calling the pullout `` a welcome first step.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON> covers the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DefiantNewspaper     05-23 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defiant Newspaper,0793</SECOND>
<HEAD>South African Newspaper Fights Threat Of Closure</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the government threatened to close The Weekly Mail, the newspaper responded in typically irreverent fashion: it printed a rat-faced caricature of the government minister who issued the warning. Since its birth in 1985, The Weekly Mail has been a combative government opponent, winning staunch friends and making plenty of enemies, but never losing its sense of humor. Its aggressive reporting and sassy political commentary have earned it the nickname `` The Weekly Wail,'' and many consider it the best-written newspaper in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The newspaper has a circulation of only 22,000, and most of the readers are well-off white liberals. Its prominent backers range from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., to the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which places a full-page ad in each issue supporting press freedom or urging political reform `` Three years ago, we felt the tradition of aggressive, critical newspapers was being lost,'' said co-editor <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Harber </PERSON>. `` Our role has been to pursue in-depth coverage of the townships and politics and take a more strident stance against censorship.'' The government repeatedly has attacked The Weekly Mail as part of the `` alternative media'' that `` fans revolution'' and promotes outlawed organizations such as the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the largest guerrilla group fighting <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s white-led government. Home Affairs Minister <PERSON> Stoffel </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> has complained about numerous articles in The Weekly Mail, issued two official warnings against the newspaper and threatened to close it for three months. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> already has suspended two newspapers aimed at <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s black majority _ New Nation and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. The Weekly Mail is one of five more papers that have received warnings. `` <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> warned us ... that our wailing threatens public safety,'' The Weekly Mail said in an editorial on its front page. `` We deny the charge. Our newspaper kicks at consciences and tears down barriers. It does not throw bombs.'' `` Do n't let us go quietly. Carry on reading us. Carry on subscribing. Make a fuss. Wail, dammit,'' the editorial said. Despite threats of closure, the newspaper continues to pursue controversial stories critical of the government and its system of apartheid, which prohibits blacks from having a voice in national affairs. Recent articles have challenged government casualty figures for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> fighting the Marxist government in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s civil war; suggested South African agents were behind the killings of <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> officials abroad; examined the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in a report from the group's headquarters in <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>; and provided a detailed account of a black activist who allegedly was kidnapped and assaulted by the army. `` We've managed to put issues on the agenda that were n't being covered by the larger papers,'' said <PERSON> Harber </PERSON>. While the newspaper focuses on serious political issues, it regularly finds room for lighter matters. It is the only South African newspaper to run the American comic strip Doonesbury, and it has lively culture and sports sections, often written with an acid wit. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boxing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> junior-lightweight champion who must fight abroad to have his bouts officially sanctioned, is described by the paper as <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s `` only diplomat with clout.'' After a white South African sprinter ran 100 meters in 10.06 seconds, newspapers and the state-run television network checked the record books and proclaimed him the `` world's fourth fastest white man.'' A Weekly Mail columnist responded: `` My next sporting goal is to become the seventh-fastest, gray-bearded, pink-freckled, left-eyed, sexagenarian, tanned-but-white hurdler over four meters ... Glory beckons.'' When a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> field hockey team competed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as a `` mystery team'' to avoid criticism for boycott-busting, other newspapers protected its anonymity. But The Weekly Mail's staffer attended a game and reported that knowledgable fans were preoccupied with the weather, repeatedly saying, `` Chilly.'' Business Day, the country's leading financial daily, describes <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weekly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mail </ORGANIZATION>'s political coverage as `` stylish, sophisticated, frequently clever, and aimed at an elite market.'' The weekly paper posed no threat to public safety because it is aimed at the `` gentlest, least violent, most anxious, guilt-ridden, sweetly intentioned middle class,'' a Business Day editorial said. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> -RRB- and his advisers have neither the general education, nor the wit, to distinguish between revolution and radical chic,'' it added. <PERSON> Harber </PERSON> says staff morale remains high, although it is unclear what will happen to the newspaper if it is closed for three months. `` We've always figured that we would probably be shut down at some point,'' said <PERSON> Harber </PERSON>. `` It's tough working under these kind of conditions, but it's something we've had to get used to.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OpenEnrollment Bjt   05-23 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Open Enrollment, Bjt,0764</SECOND>
<HEAD>Open Enrollment Puts Students, Parents On Honor System</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA WILKINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new state law allowing students to choose their schools will improve education, proponents say. But some educators fear the plan could hurt smaller schools and bring unhealthy competition. `` We realize there may be some poor choice-making in the free market, but the challenge is to educate parents in how to make sound choices,'' says <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, assistant state education commissioner. The measure gives <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> the nation's broadest open enrollment plan, <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> said. Schools may refuse students only if the transfer would interfere with desegregation ratios in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, or if the school is too crowded. State funding, about $ 3,000 per youngster, follows the student to the new district. Previously, parents had to pay tuition to the new district. Gov. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> signed the measure into law May 6. It takes effect in the 1989-90 school year in larger districts and applies statewide in 1990-91. State education officials hope schools will improve their programs in the competition to attract students. A 1986 National Governors' Association project recommended open enrollment as a way to boost school quality. `` I have mixed feelings,'' said <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, an assistant to the superintendent of the 89-student Humboldt-St. <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> school district, one of the state's smallest `` If they're put on the honor system, are they going to transfer for the right reasons?'' A champion debate coach worries about students transferring for non-academic reasons. `` For some students, those activities are a very important part of what they're about,'' said <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, whose teams have won three state titles in six years and one national title. But <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> says he sees the value of such plans. `` If the concept is to allow parents and students some choice, you have to recognize that's important for them,'' <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> said. Students could transfer to schools where their chances of making an athletic team might be better or to join friends, but it's debatable whether those are poor reasons to switch, <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> said `` It's just who gets to judge,'' she said. `` The people who get to make the decisions are the parents and the students. If the Education Department thinks it's a frivolous reason, it does n't matter. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> of <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, who lives on the border between two districts, took advantage of a forerunner of the law and sent her two children to a different district so they could be with their friends. `` They just love going to school. If they -LRB- children -RRB- are n't happy being at a school, they are n't happy doing anything there,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Frisch </PERSON> said The <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> opposes allowing students to transfer for non-academic reasons. `` I do n't think students should be permitted to exchange districts for athletic reasons or for some personality reasons. It seems to me that really could cause some chaos or problems,'' said Executive Director <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, whose association represents 435 districts. The <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, which represents 20,000 teachers, has not taken a position. `` There's a possibility that small districts could end up losing students,'' said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON>, federation president. `` They may have to look at cooperative ventures with other districts or consolidation.'' <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> began open enrollment on a voluntary basis this school year, with 137 students in 95 districts choosing to participate. Under the voluntary program, districts had the option of accepting transfers from outside their districts. For the 1988-89 school year, 435 students in 153 districts applied, said <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Zastrow </PERSON>, director of support services for the <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> department </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> officials have applauded <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>'s efforts. `` The overwhelming majority will not make decisions like these for frivolous reasons,'' said <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearlstein </PERSON>, spokesman for the department's <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> and Improvement. `` Indeed, most students will not change school districts. But choice is valuable even when people decide to stay where they are.'' <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> said he hopes the new law will prompt more schools to offer debate programs, but worries about the effect of transfers on his own program. `` If we had even four students transfer into our school and they were good, that would lock up all positions so kids from <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> would not have a shot,'' <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> said. On the other hand, <PERSON> Keillor </PERSON> said, `` If open enrollment provides a marketplace for education, then, shoot, that's going to get more schools looking at adding this program.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SovietNewThinking     05-23 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet New Thinking,0806</SECOND>
<HEAD>`New Thinking' Changes Image More Than Content Of Foreign Policy</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On Madison Avenue, it would be called an image make-over. In the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, the shifts and realignments in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> foreign policy over the past three years have been labeled `` new thinking.'' The change in appearance of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> diplomacy has boosted <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s standing in the world and improved the atmosphere at international meetings. Stony-faced officials have been replaced by smiling, congenial diplomats, such as Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> foreign affairs secretary <PERSON> Anatoly </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobrynin </PERSON>. A more active schedule of foreign visits has distinguished <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s tenure, and Soviet officials have emulated their leader's more open approach by giving news conferences and social events at home and during trips abroad. The smoother style has done much to break down the wall of mystery that has surrounded the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since the 1917 Bolshevik Revolution that gave birth to the world's first socialist state. But in <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s rebuilding of relations with countries in regions as diverse as the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, many of the pieces of <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> foreign policy have fallen into familiar places. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> coined the `` new thinking'' phrase in speeches during his first months as party general secretary, calling on his nation's policy-makers to take a fresh look at Soviet relations and activity around the world. The foreign policy mosaic evident three years after <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> assumed power shows some advances, broadened influence _ and stagnation. The most dramatic achievements have been the start of Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, agreed to after eight years of fighting and five years of negotiation, and the signing last Dec. 8 of an agreement with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to eliminate medium-range nuclear missiles, the first treaty to scrap an entire class of nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and other senior Soviets have claimed the INF agreement was a result of Kremlin flexibility and perseverance toward fulfilling their goal of a nuclear-free world by the year 2000, a disarmament plan set out in a speech by the leader in January 1986. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, on the other hand, attributes it to the White House policy of dealing with the Soviets `` from a position of strength.'' Despite the rhetoric and conflicting claims of responsibility, the movement on arms control has encouraged observers to believe that `` new thinking'' has moved from idea to action in some instances, although the outcome remains mixed and at times contradictory. Relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have surpassed the detente era of the 1970s, when the superpowers' policy of mutual tolerance produced a short-lived warm spot in the postwar chill. Peace, friendship and educational exchange groups arrive daily to build bridges between Soviet and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizens. But the leaders continue to regard each other as adversaries. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and other major European powers have shared in the warmth of better ties between the superpowers and progress toward nuclear arms control. Yet the societies of East and West retain sharp differences, including their definitions of personal freedom and fundamental human rights. While Soviet soldiers are leaving the war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s support for <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> remains a point of contention between the superpowers. It also suggests that the <ORGANIZATION> Kremlin </ORGANIZATION>'s historic practice of spreading socialist revolution remains a goal. The Kremlin's reforms have spread in part to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where the Soviet bloc, to some degree, have been able to choose their own course of development. With that comes more responsibility for their own economic performance and less reliance on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for support. Soviet influence have seen the least change in the troubled <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> region, where the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict still draws a sharp line between the superpowers. And neither has succeeded in defusing the Iran-Iraq war. The <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> has given its relations with <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> a lower public profile and tried to gain some influence with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in hopes of resolving the 8-year-old Gulf War. However, the Soviets still have no diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and is viewed as too closely aligned with some Arab countries to broker a peace accord in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The Kremlin has continued to make restoration of diplomatic ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> contingent on the Jewish state's departure from Arab territories occupied after the 1967 Mideast War. However, an exchange of visits by consular delegations was permitted last year and a sharp rise in Jewish emigration from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> have to some degree improved the <LOCATION> Soviet-Israeli </LOCATION> relationship.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> has reported from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Soviet foreign affairs and other issues since 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NoPhones     05-23 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-No Phones,0834</SECOND>
<HEAD>Businesses, Residents Learn To Cope With Limited Phone Service</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ED WHITE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HINSDALE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Duntley </PERSON> has traded in his ties and starched shirts. Casual dress will do these days, when instead of calling customers from his comfortable office, he stands in line to make his pitch on a pay phone. `` It's like fighting with one arm tied behind your back,'' said <PERSON> Duntley </PERSON>, 55, as he scanned a legal pad filled with names of potential buyers around the country for <ORGANIZATION> Ameristate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 7,500 steel-cutting equipment. `` Actually, it's like throwing your money down the drain.'' `` It'' is the hassle created by the Great Phone Outage. It began May 8, when a fire damaged virtually all the vital hardware at an <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> switching station. At first, the outage seemed only a minor inconvenience for customers in a handful of Du Page County communities about 30 miles west of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. But as <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> crews examined the smoldering cables and water-damaged electronics, the picture became much clearer _ and very bleak. Phones for 35,000 customers were dead indefinitely, silencing the simple crosstown call or the long-distance business deal. Limited local service has since been restored, but calls outside the immediate area are hit or miss. To offset the lack of phone service, towns increased police patrols. For several days, public employees also sat in vehicles on street corners watching for crime or fire or medical emergencies. There have been no reports of any law enforcement or fire problems linked to the outage, however. <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> crews are working around the clock to replace the wrecked equipment, but the job may take until June. `` It's total confusion. It's been a disaster,'' said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Schramm </PERSON>, an officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Hinsdale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION>, with 16,700 residents, is one of the largest communities affected, but there is little industry here. With its cozy, colonial-style downtown shops and century-old homes, the village is a soothing retreat from the hectic pace of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. But to the south in <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Burr </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Willowbrook </LOCATION>, industrial parks sprawl along Interstate 55. Some of the country's biggest corporate names are here, including <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which employs 1,500 people at its headquarters `` Calls to downtown <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> have been tricky,'' said <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Lana </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ehrsam </PERSON> `` If one finally gets through, we might pass the phone around. Despite the fire we are able to keep operating. We were never totally without anything. `` We've been using a lot of resources,'' she added, `` Faxing and Telexing all over.'' `` It's driving me crazy,'' said <PERSON> Dirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>, a salesman for <ORGANIZATION> Outdoor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Headquarters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Willowbrook </LOCATION>. `` At first I thought it was funny, you know, ` Hey the phones do n't work.' Now I guess it's pretty serious. `` I still run my regular route to stores that want hunting and fishing stuff, but I really ca n't tell what they might need if I do n't have a phone,'' Tweed said. `` Heck, I ca n't even call my boss in <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>.'' He said he spends much of his time reading magazines and talking to two secretaries. `` How are we coping? This is how we're coping,'' says <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Riendeau </PERSON>, chewing a candy bar with her legs up on the desk. `` If this keeps up, I'll be a raving lunatic. We've looked at the files and already rearranged what we rearranged last week. What else is there?'' Among the hardest hit are 24,000 florists nationwide that belong to <ORGANIZATION> FTD </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the flower delivery network. About half are hooked to a computer system in Downers Grove designed to relay an order across the country in a snap. But the line to the FTD computer network flows through the <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION> station. `` We've been absolutely crippled,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON>, director of operations for <ORGANIZATION> FTD </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary <ORGANIZATION> Floral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, who has the task of trying to find an alternative system. `` The flower business has not stopped _ people can still call and order. But instead of using the computer network, florists have to look up florists in other cities and call them one by one. That hurts.'' The switching station, meanwhile, has come to resemble a traveling circus. Big mess tents are erected for the dozens of laborers assigned to get the site back in order, and <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> executives call the shots from a row of trailers. Customers line up at a bank of portable pay phones trucked in by the utility. `` It's been a disaster, but it's folksy,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ging </PERSON>, a local psychotherapist, referring to the small talk between people waiting to use the phones. `` There are pluses as well as minuses,'' she said. `` One plus is people have to be resourceful. Most people do n't know how strong they are, how they can get along. ... I'm impressed with how well people have been coping.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Gorbachev Bjt   05-23 0787</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev, Bjt,0813</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Says Long-Range Missile Treaty Could Be Signed By
January</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said a U.S.-Soviet treaty reducing long-range nuclear weapons could be signed by January but that he will not set aside disputes over the `` Star Wars'' program to reach such an accord. The Soviet leader also said his policy of `` glasnost,'' or openness, includes freedom of speech, but he condemned a leading dissident as a `` parasite'' and accused him of `` sponging on the democratic process.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s comments came in a pre-summit interview with two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> news organizations. The Soviet news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday ran a partial transcript of the interview with <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>. Radio <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s English-language foreign service also carried a report about it as its lead item on Sunday. Soviet television's widely watched evening news program `` Vremya'' mentioned as its lead item that the interview had been published in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and would appear in today's Soviet newspapers The 90-minute discussion, in which <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also proposed a joint U.S.-Soviet trip to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>, covered a wide range of foreign and domestic issues. The interview, conducted in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> on Wednesday, produced a startling Biblical reference by the head of the officially atheistic state. When asked about how far glasnost should go and about criticism of dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>, the 57-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader said: `` <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> alone knew answers to all questions and knew how to feed 20,000 Jews with five loaves of bread. We do n't possess that skill, we have no ready prescription to solve all our problems quickly.'' The interview was conducted 11 days before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s arrival in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for a five-day summit with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> It will be their fourth meeting. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> transcript included much of the interview, it deleted a reference to <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, the Kremlin's No. 2 man. It also left out a reference to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, considered more conservative than the Soviet leader, reportedly wants to slow <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s policy of `` perestroika,'' or restructuring, of the Soviet economy and society. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> acknowledged a lively debate between the two but said `` to present these discussions _ which are a normal part of the democratic process _ as division within the leadership would be a great mistake itself.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> expressed optimism that a superpower agreement to cut strategic, or long-range, nuclear weapons will be completed by the time <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leaves office in January. `` We want to have that signed,'' he said. If the agreement `` comes to be drafted under the present <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration, I see no reason why President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and I should not sign it. I would certainly welcome that,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> added. However, he cautioned that he has no plans to set aside disputes to hasten an agreement. `` If we sign with one hand a treaty reducing strategic offensive forces in one area and at the same time launch an arms race in space or at sea, what would be the point? That would be senseless,'' he said. He reiterated his opposition to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s `` Star Wars'' missile defense program, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION>, saying the leader who promotes an escalation of the arms race in space `` is committing a crime against the people _ his own people, and others.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet officials have said they do n't believe the long-range nuclear weapons treaty will be completed by the end of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s term. Another treaty to ban short - and medium-range nuclear weapons is being debated by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he will ask <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at the summit to approve a joint Soviet-U.S. unmanned flight to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. `` Why should n't we work together? We have great experience, you have great experience _ let us cooperate to master the cosmos, to fulfill big programs,'' he said. On domestic affairs, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was asked whether glasnost includes freedom of speech. `` While freedom of speech is indispensable for glasnost, we see glasnost as a broader phenomenon,'' he said. Glasnost is `` the right of every citizen to openly say what he or she thinks about all social and political questions,'' he added. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> was asked later whether freedom of speech applies to dissidents such as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> journalist <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>, who was jailed for a week earlier this month. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said Soviets think of <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> `` as some kind of alien phenomenon in our society sponging on the democratic process.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> went on to call <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON> a `` parasite.'' It was a rare reference by a Soviet leader to a dissident. <PERSON> Grigoryants </PERSON>, editor of the dissident magazine Glasnost, said the computer and printer used to produce the journal were confiscated when he was arrested. In a telephone interview on Sunday, he called <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s comments about him `` very unpleasant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DistrictFight     05-23 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-District Fight,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>Something Happened on the Way to a Political Dynasty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MITCH WEISS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOWLING GREEN, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For years, Rep. <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> groomed his son to replace him when he retired from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. But another well-known <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Republican had a different idea about who will go to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. After the elder <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> announced in January he would not seek re-election, it seemed only natural that <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> would declare his candidacy for <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>'s 5th District. But the Lattas did n't count on a challenge from within. The challenge came from Republican <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>, who had irritated the Lattas just enough to prompt murmurs of a feud. <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> was the highest ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> legislator in the state and candidate for his party's nomination for governor in 1986. Official vote totals from the May 3 congressional primary show <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> by 41 votes of more than 63,000 cast in a three-way race. But a recount is automatic because of the slim margin _ 28,680 to 28,639 _ and even the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION> says the race is too close to call. `` I do n't think it divided the Republicans because I ran a positive race,'' <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>, 49, said last week. `` I said before the primary race that I would support the eventual nominee. I expect they would do the same.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> has refused to concede, but the 32-year-old corporate attorney from Bowling Green said he will support <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> if <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> is the nominee. `` As a Republican for my entire life, you support Republicans,'' he said. Hoping to pick up the pieces is Democrat <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, a 51-year-old <LOCATION> Sandusky </LOCATION> attorney making his second run for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> believes the departure of the elder <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> will end <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> domination in the Bowling Green district, which now boasts more registered Democrats than Republicans. `` Nobody believed I could beat <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> in 1986, and they were right. It was like running against an institution,'' <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> said. `` There's no doubt that he has the contacts in the district from 30 years of service, but I'm not sure the same can be said for any of the Republicans this time.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Wood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> may be chasing moonbeams. `` I think -LRB- the GOP primary -RRB- had the potential to be a real nasty kind of thing, but basically I think the candidates did a good job of talking about themselves rather than each other,'' he said. `` I think it makes it easier to put together a campaign in the fall for the winner. ... I just do n't see people flocking to vote for <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> said a rift occurred between <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> and <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> in 1982, when the Legislature was redrawing congressional district lines. At the time, <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> _ a position he still holds. <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> was trying to redraw the 9th Congressional District, a traditional Democratic stronghold that includes <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, so it would be more favorable for <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, a Republican elected in 1980. To accomplish that, <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> wanted to take away one county and part of another from <LOCATION> Latta </LOCATION>'s district and place it in the 9th District, <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> said. He also wanted to move <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>'s district east. <PERSON> Latta </PERSON> opposed <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>'s plan, <PERSON> Marsh </PERSON> said. Eventually, <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>'s district moved a bit east and lost parts of Wood and <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION> counties. The 9th District gained a part of a Democratic stronghold. The result: <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> lost in 1982, and the 9th District, under Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Marcy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaptur </PERSON> is once again Democratic territory. Later, <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON> found himself shut out of some GOP functions in northwestern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. For example, he discovered he was an outsider during President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s visit to Bowling Green in 1984. `` They have a dais in a hall and have 50 people up there _ <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>'s neighbors are up there _ but the president of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is sitting out in the crowd,'' said one Republican official, who spoke on the condition his name not be used. The elder <PERSON> Latta </PERSON>, 67, son of a barber, is serving his 15th term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He is senior Republican member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a veteran member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmCredit Bjt   05-23 0684</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Credit, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>FmHA's New Loanmaking Policies To Allow For Debt Restructuring</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New regulations to reshape the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s loan policies will cost $ 8.7 billion and push as many as 64,800 farmers into liquidation or foreclosure, the agency says. The <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>, an agency of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, is scheduled to open the proposed changes to public comment this week. A summary of the agency's proposal was made available to The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, a lobbyist and lawyer for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said she had not had an opportunity to study the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>'s proposal in detail but indicated that the figures cited by the agency appeared to be in line with estimates `` If they had used the authority that they had gotten in the 1985 farm -LRB- law -RRB- to restructure this debt, we would n't be in a situation now where it was too late for 64,800 people,'' she said. The FmHA is often called the government's farm lender of last resort because loans are made only to those who can not qualify at banks or other commercial sources. Overall, the agency's farm loan portfolio totals around $ 26 billion to 250,000 borrowers. With loan delinquencies rising, <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> was directed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in last year's Agricultural Credit Act to rewrite many of its regulations so that borrowers would be given a greater opportunity to restructure or spread out payments and still hold onto their land. In many cases, debts far beyond the ability of farmers to repay would be `` written down'' to manageable levels or forgiven entirely. Many other regulatory changes also were ordered by the new law. Basically, the write-down would reduce a farmer's <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> debt to the level of his assets, depending upon his ability to operate with enough cash flow thereafter to repay the new loan balance. The proposed regulations are scheduled for publication this week in the Federal Register, the government's official rulemaking document, and will be open for public comment for 30 days. In its summary, the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> said about 118,000 borrowers `` were delinquent or in some other default status in early 1988.'' Those included 16,000 borrowers who have been `` accelerated'' by the agency, a process that leads to forced liquidation or foreclosure for hopeless cases. But the agency estimated that about 37,000 of the 118,000 delinquents `` will be able to resolve repayment problems through normal servicing procedures'' such as the rescheduling of loan installments and other alternatives. `` The remaining 81,000 borrowers would be eligible for consideration of restructuring with write-down of debt,'' the report said. `` Based on an earlier survey of borrowers eligible to restructuring with write-down of debt, an estimated 20 percent -LRB- 16,200 -RRB- of the 81,000 borrowers are able to show repayment on remaining debt and qualify for the write-down.'' It added: `` About two-thirds of the borrowers are unable to show repayment ability on remaining debt and would be rejected for write-down. The remaining potential write-down borrowers would not be considered for write-down because their debt was less than the estimated recovery value.'' The report included a brief profile of borrowers in the survey who qualified for <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> debt write-down: _ A large proportion of their total debt was with FmHA _ The <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> loans were `` greatly under-secured'' or there was no net value in the security for <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION>, which mean that a large percentage, or all, of their FmHA debt would be subject to write-down _ A substantial portion of the borrower's income was from off-farm jobs Costs of writing down FmHA debt for the estimated 16,200 qualified borrowers were estimated at a net of $ 2.1 billion. The agency said that its federal budget authority `` may be dramatically affected by the revised servicing procedures as loan losses will tend to be recognized up front'' as the write-downs are incurred instead of after the liquidation and delayed settlement of the debts. `` Requested reimbursement -LRB- of agency funding -RRB- for losses may be increased from about $ 1 billion in fiscal year 1989 to a substantial share of the total estimated write-down and loan losses of $ 8.7 billion in fiscal year 1990,'' the <ORGANIZATION> FmHA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoldingTrial Bjt   05-23 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bolding Trial, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nursing Group Watches Trial Of Nurse Accused Of Potassium Overdose</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD KEIL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UPPER MARLBORO, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The verdict in the trial of a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> nurse accused of killing hospital patients with a common substance used for a variety of medical procedures will influence how all nurses go about their jobs, a spokeswoman for a nurses organization says. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON>, formerly a nurse at the Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> about 20 miles east of the nation's capital, is accused of killing three of her intensive care patients by injecting them with lethal doses of potassium and attempting to murder two others the same way. Potassium is found naturally in the body, but in large amounts can cause cardiac arrest. A guilty verdict would likely have a `` chilling effect'' on health care officials who routinely prescribe and administer common medicines like sodium bicarbonate and insulin, which can be fatal if used in large quantities, said <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Grimaldi </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nurses </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. Such a verdict `` would make it more difficult for people to carry on in an already stressful environment,'' she said. `` We usually see cases where people are accused of murder by turning off machines or poisoning, not the use of an organic compound,'' she said. The 180,000-member association represents registered nurses. Autopsies on the three victims all revealed inexplicably high levels of potassium. But no official cause of death was ever listed in any of the cases and no one witnessed <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> doing anything wrong. If <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> is convicted of murder, the case could have ramifications for the nation's health care industry, according to defense attorney <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>. `` If this case went unchallenged, there would be paranoia throughout the medical industry,'' <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> said. `` This case is a medical and legal nightmare.'' What makes the case so important is that potassium, an electrolyte found in the body, is also used for a variety of common medical purposes in hospitals, <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> said. Assistant State's Attorney <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Creech </PERSON> has called <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> `` a killer angel.'' He is basing his case on a study by the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> that indicates more of <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON>'s patients died of cardiac arrest than did those of any other nurse at the hospital On the first day of trial in Prince <PERSON> George </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last Wednesday, defense attorneys scoffed at the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> report, and said the prosecution's case is based on the flimsiest of circumstantial evidence. On Thursday, <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON>'s attorneys got the pathologist for the intensive care unit of the hospital where the nurse worked to say that potassium levels normally begin to rise as soon as a patient dies. Dr. <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Matei </PERSON> said that once the heart stops _ and oxygen ceases to flow in the bloodstream _ tissues and cells begin to break down, releasing stored-up potassium. `` It's a normal process,'' <PERSON> Matei </PERSON> told the court. Cardiopulmonary resuscitation, in which a strenuous chest massage is used in efforts to restart the heart, also causes tissue breakdown, <PERSON> Matei </PERSON> testified. In addition, kidney failure contributes to high potassium rates because the bloodstream, which caries potassium, is not purified, <PERSON> Matei </PERSON> added. CPR was attempted on all three patients <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> is accused of killing, and at least one had kidney problems, hospital records indicate. `` We say it's impossible to tell whether potassium caused the heart attacks, or whether the heart attacks resulted in high levels of potassium,'' <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> said. `` This whole case is about doubt.'' The investigation of <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> runs from January 1984 to March 1985, but <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON> introduced into the court record documents indicating high potassium levels for patients at the hospital during a 10-year period that encompasses the Bolding probe. <PERSON> Creech </PERSON> has relied on hospital records in an attempt to establish that <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> was present when the patients died, but hospital officials testified under cross examination that many others also had access to the alleged victims. None of <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON>'s former colleagues who have testified so far have questioned the nurse's work ethic or job performance. <PERSON> Bolding </PERSON> was indicted after a grand jury heard testimony last year on the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> study. The non-jury trial is expected to last up to eight weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-23 0771</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poultry And Pork Consumption Grows With Meat Consumption</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The world's biggest meat eaters are curbing their appetites for beef and looking for second helpings of poultry and pork. Per capita meat consumption in the major producing countries _ usually the richest _ grew about 11 percent over the last decade, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report. But the gains were n't across the board. `` For instance, most of the increase came from poultry and pork, while beef declined,'' the report said. `` Consumption of lamb, mutton and goat stagnated worldwide.'' In 1975-77, Americans averaged about 127 pounds of beef and veal, 59 pounds of pork, 2 pounds of lamb, mutton and goat, and 51 pounds of poultry. By 1985-87, per capita consumption was: beef and veal, 106 pounds; pork, 63; lamb, mutton and goat, 2; and poultry, 73. Those are carcass weight equivalents before being divided and trimmed into retail cuts. Even in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, the biggest meat-eater of all, per capita beef consumption dropped to 174 pounds from 187 a decade earlier. Declines also occurred for lamb, mutton and goat meat, and poultry, each down 1 pound. However, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, which has been striving to upgrade diets, boosted beef consumption to 62 pounds per capita from 52 pounds in 1975-77, while pork increased to 48 pounds from 43. Lamb, mutton and goat held steady at 3 pounds, but poultry consumption jumped to 23 pounds from 14 pounds previously. The report was included by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in the agency's quarterly <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> issued last week. Analysts noted that per capita meat consumption is affected by many factors, including local and world economies, religion, social customs and even climate. `` Most meat is produced and consumed in high-income countries,'' the report said. `` However, new technologies, like improved refrigeration and transportation, in developing countries have opened the door for meat imports and improved the distribution of such products.'' On the other hand, religion sometimes restricts the kinds of meats that are acceptable in certain countries. Moslems and Jews shun pork, and Hindus avoid all meat. Pork is the predominant meat in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, especially <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, as well as in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and other Asian nations. In <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, alone, where about a third of the world's pork is produced, consumption rose to about 35 pounds from 18 pounds during the decade, the report said. Poultry consumption has gained the most, reflecting the relatively brief time span and less feed required to produce a pound of poultry meat, compared with other grain-fed livestock. `` Beef consumption predominates in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, where an abundance of forage is available for ruminant livestock production,'' the report said. `` Ruminants like cattle, sheep and goats can be raised without any grain, but this requires reliable sources of cheap forage.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite sharp differences over agricultural policy and subsidies, the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> remains the leading market for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm products. In calendar 1987, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, exports of farm products to the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> were worth $ 6.8 billion, up by more than 3 percent from 1986. Although sales to the European bloc _ and farm exports generally, for that matter _ have not recovered to their record levels of the early 1980s, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts say further growth can be expected. But <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> leaders frostily reject a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal made in negotiations under auspices of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade to phase out all trade-distorting farm subsidies by the end of the century. <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Clercq </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>'s top trade official, said in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> last week at a meeting of trade ministers that the trade bloc would never agree to the elimination of such subsidies, although it favors unspecified reductions. According to a recent analysis by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm exports to the EEC this year could rise by an additional 5 percent because of `` attractive <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prices, favorable exchange rates and continued economic growth'' in the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> countries.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dispatch from an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> trade official in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> says West Germans are eating more rice these days. `` Rice, noodles and additional vegetable consumption are replacing the traditional potato as the No. 1 German food item,'' says <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural counselor. `` Rice millers are confident that this trend will continue into 1988.'' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>'s comments were reported in the June issue of Foreign Agriculture magazine. Competitive prices for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> rice pushed shipments up sharply last year and primarily replaced rice from <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880523-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-23-88 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--HongKong-Synagogue     05-23 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hong Kong-Synagogue,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rabbi Approves Demolition Of Hong Kong Synagogue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
