<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Mexico-Economy     12-12 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mexico-Economy,0263</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salinas Extends Anti-Inflation Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> said Monday night he will extend a year-old inflation-fighting program through the first half of 1989, institute a gradual peso devaluation and allow an 8 percent pay increase for workers. The increase will be the workers' first in nine months. In a Monday night ceremony with business and labor leaders, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> also gave the program a new name: the Economic Growth and Stability Pact. Former President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrid </PERSON> implemented the plan, then known as the Economic Solidarity Pact, in December 1987 as inflation reached a record annual rate of 159.2 percent. Inflation reached 48.6 percent for the first 11 months of 1988, according to the central bank. The central features of the plan included freezes enacted Feb. 29 on the peso currency exchange rate and on prices for government-regulated goods and services. The government also froze the daily minimum wage, which in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mexico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> amounted to about $ 3.70. On Jan. 1, the government will begin adjusting the peso-dollar exchange rate by an average of one peso per day through July 31, 1989, the statement said. It said the controlled devaluation will occur `` at a rhythm that continues to make possible for those making their investments in pesos a better yield than that obtained using other currencies.'' The measure will be implemented `` without abandoning the objective of stabilizing the exchange rate during the year,'' the statement added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Argentina-Military     12-12 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentina-Military,0282</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers To Get 20 Percent Pay Raise This Month, Plus Bonus</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The armed forces will receive pay raises of 20 percent in December with a $ 100 bonus, an official report said Monday. Soldiers who mounted a four-day uprising this month had demanded raises. The government's news agency, <ORGANIZATION> Telam </ORGANIZATION>, cited `` reliable sources'' for its report of the raises. It gave no details in its two-paragraph story. The military uprising broke out at a base on the outskirts of the capital on Dec. 1 and moved to another base nearby before the mutineers agreed to return to their units. The revolt left three people dead. Civilian President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> denied reports at the time that he was forced to make concessions in exchange for the surrender of the rebellious troops. Soldiers have complained that they _ like other public employees _ have lost significant purchasing power as raises failed to keep pace with increases in the cost of living. The military received a 30 percent raise in July and 12 percent in October. The cost of living rose by 26 percent in July and 9 percent in October. The latest raise would be well ahead of inflation, which last month increased by 6 percent. The government has tried to control military salaries partly in an effort to harness inflation. In addition, the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has blocked the 1988 budget because it wants more federal funds for the provinces. The military share of the total budget has shrunk to about 2 percent of gross domestic product from about 4 percent during military dictatorships of 1976-83.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 2341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Texas-Executions 2ndLd-Writethru a0795 12-12 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Texas-Executions, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0795,0582</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Grants State In One of Two Scheduled Executions Early
Tuesday</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 7 grafs to UPDATE with Supreme Court issuing stay;
other execution still on. Picks up 6th graf pvs, `Hawkins, 65,...'.
It is scheduled for after 1 a.m. EST, but could go hours later;
leads will be expedited. Abbe is cq in 8h graf.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL L. GRACZYK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTSVILLE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A convict dubbed the `` traveling rapist'' received a stay of execution late Monday for the rape-murder of a 19-year-old woman, but a second man was still slated to be put to death by injection early Tuesday for the killing of a restaurateur. The high court granted an application for a stay of execution for <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> late Monday, hours after turning down a similar request from <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, whose execution was still scheduled for after midnight. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Arberg </PERSON> said the application was filed at 9:30 p.m. EST and the order sparing <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> was entered at 10:25 p.m. with Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> and Justice <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> dissenting. He was sentenced to death for the 1976 rape-slaying of a 19-year-old woman. Earlier Monday, the nation's high court voted 7-2 to refuse the appeal filed by lawyers for <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, 39, a native of <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, who was convicted of killing a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> restaurant owner during a robbery. Since the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 allowed capital punishment to resume, no state has executed two inmates in a single day, although two inmates, and in one case three, have been executed on the same day in separate states. Before Tuesday's scheduled executions, 28 inmates, including two this year, had been put to death by <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> prison officials since 1976. The tally is the highest of any state. Before the issuance of a stay, the two were to be executed in the same death chamber, with <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> scheduled first. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, 45, faced injection for the rape and stabbing death of <PERSON> Abbe </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> of <PERSON> Borger </PERSON>, who was killed after <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> entered her apparently unlocked home. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>' case Monday went to the 5th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> after a federal district judge in <LOCATION> Lubbock </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Halbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON>, reversed a stay he issued Friday. State attorneys had appealed his action. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> also has a second death sentence for the abduction and slaying of a 12-year-old Amarillo girl. He has been dubbed the `` traveling rapist'' after admitting to some 40 rapes, prosecutors said. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>, bypassed lower federal courts and had appealed directly to the high court. <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, a former electrician, was sentenced for the shooting death of <PERSON> Kosmas </PERSON> <PERSON> Prittis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Prittis </PERSON>, 33, a Greek immigrant, was robbed of more than $ 2,300 and fatally shot in the head while he and his family were closing their restaurant. Last January, <PERSON> Landry </PERSON> came within three hours of execution before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> issued a stay. In appeals for each inmate, defense attorneys cited a case pending before the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> involving <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> death row inmate <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Penry </PERSON>. That case challenges the legality of executing mentally retarded inmates. `` This man is n't retarded,'' assistant attorney general <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>. `` I do n't think that's going to fly with the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Landry </PERSON>, an 11th-grade dropout, has a lengthy criminal record, including arrests for sexual assault and abuse of a juvenile, assault, family neglect and petty larceny.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CubanExiles     12-12 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cuban Exiles,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>More Than 200 Cubans Arrive In Miami; Had Been Stranded In Other
Countries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 200 Cubans came to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> over the weekend as part of a program to reunite Cuban-Americans with relatives who left <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> but have been stranded in other countries. About 190 Cubans arrived Saturday and an additional 20 arrived Sunday on flights from <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. Some 370 more Cubans were expected to arrive Tuesday and Thursday on flights sponsored by the Cuban <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. The refugees were greeted with cheers as they arrived. `` I'm elated,'' said <PERSON> Gilfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Landa </PERSON>, 21, as he hugged his brothers, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 19, and <PERSON> Yoeidy </PERSON>, 14. The two brothers had just arrived to join <PERSON> Gilfredo </PERSON>, who arrived in 1980 during the Mariel boatlift. `` They're going to learn English,'' he said. Since the foundation program began Sept. 11, 805 former Cubans have arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. Under the guidelines of the program, relatives or friends of the refugees promise to pay travel costs and provide financial support for two years. Foundation chairman <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Mas </PERSON> <PERSON> Canosa </PERSON> said there will be more flights from <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and possibly <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>. The foundation can bring up to 1,500 refugees into the country this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--SAfrica-Exhumation     12-12 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--SAfrica-Exhumation,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plan To Exhume 3,600 Bodies Draws Protests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE TOWN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Parliament member says his constituents are outraged by a government plan to exhume and re-bury the remains of more than 3,600 people to make way for a new traffic interchange. `` It's wrong, immoral and unchristian,'' said <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON>, who represents the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Bontheuwel </LOCATION> in the mixed-race chamber of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Major newspapers on Sunday carried a list of all the dead people whose graves in <LOCATION> Maitland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cemetery </LOCATION> will be affected by the construction project. `` Existing memorials will be suitably re-erected, and a Garden of Remembrance established for the re-burial of the remains of those who at present do not have any memorials,'' said a notice accompanying the list. <PERSON> McKenzie </PERSON> was quoted by the nationally circulated <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> as saying those buried in the cemetery were mostly mixed-race people but also included white immigrants from <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and elsewhere.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Japan-Airport     12-12 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Japan-Airport,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Flights Delayed After Break-In At Airport Control Room</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than a dozen flights were delayed at <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> when a man broke into a control room and disconnected hundreds of fuses from the air traffic control system, police said today. The incident cut communications between airport controllers and flights using the airport for about 40 minutes on Sunday, said a local police official who spoke on condition of anonymity. Six departures and 11 arrivals were delayed for up to half an hour. Police arrested a 26-year-old man they described only as a professional golfer. The official said the man may have entered the closely guarded communications control center when employees were at lunch. Police using a duplicate key entered and overpowered the man, who shouted that he was acting `` at the guidance of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>,'' the official said. His identity was withheld pending investigation of his mental health.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AdvancedPlacement     12-12 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Advanced Placement,0436</SECOND>
<HEAD>Number of Minorities Taking Advanced Placement Exams Doubles in
Five Years</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-School Discipline, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE MITGANG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than twice the number of minority high school students took advancement placement exams in 1988 than five years ago, led by a surge among Hispanics and Asian-Americans, the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> reported. The board's annual survey of advanced placement tests, which high school students take to qualify for credit or placement in upper-level college courses, also found that <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> had by far the most black and Hispanic test-takers who scored qualifying grades. In all, 288,372 students took 419,101 advanced placement exams in 1988. The program, sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, offers 27 college-level examinations in 16 subjects. Nearly 52,000 minority students nationwide took the exams in 1988, compared with 39,517 in 1987, and 142 percent more than the 21,501 who took it five years ago, the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. Forty-nine thousand of those students scored high enough to qualify for college credit. The tests are scored on a scale of 1-5, with colleges usually requiring at least a 3 to qualify for credit. Minority students made up nearly 20 percent of all advanced placement test-takers in 1988, compared with 18.4 percent in 1987 and 14.7 percent in 1984. `` By using AP to raise the expectations of minority students and helping them achieve higher goals ... schools are bringing more minorities into professional and graduate schools,'' said board president <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. The number of Asian-American students taking the exams was 27,396, up from 21,101 in 1987 and 140 percent greater than the 11,413 in 1984. The number of Hispanics taking the test grew 156 percent over five years: from 5,200 to 13,322; the number of blacks grew by 135 percent, from 4,448 to 10,448. The number of whites taking the tests totaled 210,582, up 27 percent from 165,924 in 1987, and 80 percent higher than the 117,302 in 1984. Some 8,247 schools offered the exams in 1988, 470 more than last year. <ORGANIZATION> Plano </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, near <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, with a student body of 2,600, had the largest number of advanced placement candidates of any school _ 490 _ and the largest number of tests taken _ 887, according to the report. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> led the nation with 5,125 black and Hispanic test-takers last year. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> was second with 2,526, followed by <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with 2,439. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> is a nonprofit organization representing 2,600 colleges and other educational groups.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TVCulture     12-12 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--TV Culture,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Culture Minister So Many U.S. Shows On French TV Is Humiliating</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Culture Minister <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> says he's sometimes humiliated when he ca n't find anything to watch on the six French television channels but programs imported from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, in a television interview on Sunday, called on the station chiefs to make their programming `` more French, more European.'' `` I am sometimes humiliated by the fact that at certain times there's nothing to watch but American series,'' he said. `` This is unacceptable. I say to the channel managers: Do your job, serve French culture.'' While <PERSON> Lang </PERSON> was speaking on the state-owned FR3 channel Sunday afternoon, French viewers had the choice of turning to other stations to watch such U.S.-made programs as `` Magnum P.I.,'' `` The Incredible Hulk,'' or `` Max Headroom.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Quake-Relief     12-12 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quake-Relief,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agencies Involved In Soviet Quake Aid</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet-Quake</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some addresses of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> groups collecting relief for Armenian earthquake victims: <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disaster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relief </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> P.O </ORGANIZATION>. Box 37243 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20013. -LRB- 800 -RRB- 453-9000. -LRB- money only -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relief </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> 80 <LOCATION> Bigelow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ave. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Watertown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. 02172 -LRB- 617 -RRB- 926-3801. -LRB- collecting money, tents, blankets, sleeping bags, warm clothing -RRB- Armenian Earthquake Relief Fund -LRB- Armenian Assembly of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> -RRB- St. Vartan Armenian Cathedral 630 Second Avenue <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 10016 or Armenian General Benevolent Union 535 Saddle River Rd. <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> 07662 -LRB- money only -RRB- The Armenian Relief -LRB- also under auspices of Armenian Assembly of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> -RRB- St. Illuminator's <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Apostolic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> 221 E. 27th <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 10016 -LRB- money only -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> 10 West 17th Street <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> 10011 -LRB- 212 -RRB- 242-7757 -LRB- money only -RRB- World Vision Box 0 <LOCATION> Passadena </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> 91109 1-800-4-HUNGER -LRB- money for medicine -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Armenian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Missionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> 140 <LOCATION> Forest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paramus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> 07652 -LRB- 201 -RRB- 265-2607
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Botha-Mandela     12-12 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Botha-Mandela,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mandela Overshadows Botha's Efforts To Ease Pressure</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> is campaigning doggedly to improve <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s image overseas, but he faces constant reminders that success will be limited until he comes to terms with <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. Among those conveying that message in recent days were <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s best-known novelist, black and white corporate executives, and two leading <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senators who were rebuffed curtly when they asked <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> if they could meet the jailed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leader. Even the government's recent decision to transfer <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> to a prison farm staff house, complete with swimming pool and patio, seemed to underscore the special stature of the 70-year-old black nationalist. `` They are showing that he is the major kingpin in the constitutional future of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Dalling </PERSON>, parliament member from the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Perhaps the most dramatic evidence of the influence wielded over <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> came in court testimony last week on behalf of 11 black activists about to be sentenced for treason and terrorism in the same courthouse where <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> received a life sentence for sabotage in 1964. Most of the 11 treason defendants were affiliated to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a nationwide anti-apartheid coalition which the trial judge said had collaborated with the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>. The defense lawyers, instead of repudiating the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>, summoned several of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most respected opposition figures to speak about their support for and understanding of the outlawed guerrilla movement. <PERSON> Nadine </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordimer </PERSON>, the country's foremost novelist, said she considered <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> her leader and blamed her fellow whites for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s political violence. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Motsuenyane </PERSON>, a black bank chairman, said of <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>: `` Unquestionably, he is my hero.'' Similar statements came from a university administrator and the leader of a black homeland. In a subsequent magazine interview, a prominent Afrikaner business leader, <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON>, said he wanted to meet <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> `` man to man'' to discuss a peaceful political settlement. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> has declined to spell out his plans for <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> as he presses ahead with an unprecedented campaign to ease international pressure on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. In the past few weeks, he has commuted the widely denounced death sentences of a group of blacks known as the <ORGANIZATION> Sharpeville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Six </ORGANIZATION>, freed two elderly black political prisoners and endorsed a tentative peace plan that could end South African rule over <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. All these steps, as well as <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s transfer, have been welcomed in Western capitals. But always, the pressure to deal politically with <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> resumes. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> also is under fire for continued repression of dissidents at home while he tries to impress power brokers abroad. Even a seemingly benevolent gesture, the recent release of detained black newspaper editor <PERSON> Zwelakhe </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, had a harsh edge to it. <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, like several other freed detainees, was prohibited from returning to his job, restricted to the area around his home and barred from anti-government political activity. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Senators <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, at the close of a one-week fact-finding trip, acknowledged Saturday that <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> had taken some positive steps but said they came away with a feeling of pessimism. `` If those who are working for real change are foreclosed from using non-violent political methods, it is our great fear that they will be forced to turn to methods that will undoubtedly lead to violence and tragedy,'' the two Democrats said. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, `` deeply disappointed us by wanting to talk only about the past, not trying to engage and assess and share ideas about the future.'' Even if <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> were released, opposition leaders say the gesture would mean little unless he and other prominent black militants, young and old, are allowed to engage freely in politics and to work for a one-person, one-vote system. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> says he is not willing to even discuss such a system, and there is no sign that <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>'s release would mean an easing of restrictions on opposition activity.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Crary </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> news editor in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> and has been reporting from East and <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-RainMan     12-12 0381</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Rain Man,0392</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dustin Hoffman Joins Film Role Model For Preview</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY P. KISSEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HUNTINGTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An autistic man who served as a model for <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>'s latest movie character watched the premiere of `` Rain Man'' with the actor three rows behind him. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, 28, was one of three autistic people <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> studied to prepare for the role of <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, an idiot savant who inherits $ 3 million from his father's estate but has no concept of money. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, director <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON> and producer <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> to help raise funds for the <ORGANIZATION> Autism </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which is run by <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON>. About 1,500 people attended Sunday's benefit at the ornate Keith-Albee Theater. The center said it expected to get $ 30,000 to $ 35,000. `` It's not something that's happened to us before, coming to a town which has a family in it which was the inspiration for our film,'' <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> told the 600 people attending a dinner following the premiere. `` It's just a very moving experience for myself and my wife, and <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> and his wife, and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> and his wife. `` We just made a film that's going to play for, you know, a month or two, or whatever, in cities in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and around the world and be put out on -LRB- video -RRB- cassette and put on shelves and seen once. `` You people have <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> in your community for the rest of your lives, and I would take that any day of the week, and I think that's a really important thing because he is a very special person who shines through this ... magic he has. Autism is an affliction in which the brain does n't process information correctly. Some autistics are self-abusive and lack social skills but excel in music, math and art. Generally, though, autism is misunderstood, said Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. `` I had people say, ` Is n't it nice your little boy knows how to draw,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> gave the movie credit for advancing knowledge of autism, telling <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, `` You have done with one film what we have been trying to do in our field for 25 years.'' <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> said, however, `` If we do one-tenth of what Mrs. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> has done, we will have made a little advance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0058EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--CanalettoCanvas     12-12 0113</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Canaletto Canvas,0116</SECOND>
<HEAD>Venetian Painting Sells for Record Amount</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VENICE, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A painting by <PERSON> Canaletto </PERSON> has been sold for 1.4 billion lire -LRB- $ 1.01 million -RRB-, a record amount for a Venetian artist's work, the Italian news service <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported. The work, called `` The Bull Hunt in St. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Piazza </PERSON>,'' was sold at an auction Sunday in <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Giovannelli </PERSON> Palace. <PERSON> Canaletto </PERSON>, whose real name was <ORGANIZATION> Giovanni </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antonio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION>, lived from 1697 to 1768 and won fame for his precisely painted views of <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and the English countryside. The previous record was not disclosed. <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> has a long artistic tradition and has produced such painters as <PERSON> Titian </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paolo </PERSON> <PERSON> Veneziano </PERSON> and <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellini </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NorthernIreland     12-12 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Northern Ireland,0708</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protestant Schoolgirl Crosses The Sectarian Divide</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EDITH M. LEDERER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Patton </PERSON>, a 16-year-old Protestant, had never met a Roman Catholic until she went to a memorial service for the victims of an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> bombing and ended up holding hands with two nuns. That moment at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Anne </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cathedral </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, when the minister asked everyone in the overflowing congregation to join hands and pray, marked a turning point in <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON>'s life. She had been crying for the 11 people killed in <LOCATION> Enniskillen </LOCATION> on Nov. 8, 1987 and was so wrapped up in the service she did n't realize she had picked up the hands of two nuns who were sitting beside her. `` I went home and I thought, ` I'm just really fed up that I have to hate this woman because she's wearing a nun's habit, I have to hate this fellow because he's a Catholic.' It just went over and over in my mind, you know, what am I going to do?,'' she said. `` I'd never met any Catholics, never, never. ... My mom and dad are very good, they really are. They did n't keep me away from Catholics. It's just where I lived there were n't any,'' she said. In <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, with its history of sectarian animosities, it is common for youngsters, and even adults, never to have met someone of another religion. Many of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s 1 million Protestants and 600,000 Catholics live in neighborhoods segregated along religious lines, and all but 1,000 of the province's 350,000 children attend schools that are almost entirely Protestant or Catholic. <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> is studying for college entrance exams at mainly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grosvenor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in east <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. After the <LOCATION> Enniskillen </LOCATION> memorial service, she decided to try to arrange an exchange with a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> high school. `` I never thought it would be anything big, just a small meeting,'' <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> said. `` I was a very quiet person ... but something inside of me said, ` I think you should really advertise this,' and before I knew what I was saying, I asked ... if I could -LRB- address -RRB- the school assembly. `` Well, I went and did that assembly, and they clapped and they clapped and I was just shocked. I did n't think anybody felt the same way I did. And there were hundreds of them. ... They said this is the right thing we're doing.'' The first exchange late last year was with a group of <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> students from two schools, Our Lady of Mercy and <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>'s. As the Grosvenor students waited for the Catholics to arrive, <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> said, `` they were literally trying to think what these Catholics were going to look like. Are they going to talk funny and what are their names going to be like? `` Because we'd never met, we just had these ideas about the other side, and then when we came together, we just realized they were just like us.'' Over the past year, the students have exchanged further visits. Friendships have grown outside school, with frequent visits to local discos, restaurants and the movies, and shared stays at a government-sponsored camp. The Grosvenor girls have also participated in a play, `` Bridges of Celebration,'' with boys from <ORGANIZATION> Corpus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> secondary school in west <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, an Irish <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> stronghold. It filled the Opera House in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> and will be performed again in <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> in February. Recalling the first rehearsal, on neutral ground at <ORGANIZATION> Queen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Leanne </PERSON> said: `` When they first walked in ... they just sat down and stared at you I said, ` Oh dear, what's this going to be like?' But then we got to know them and we realized they were great.'' She has no illusions that her activities will change the country. `` No way. I'm never going to become a Catholic and none of them are ever going to become a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> just because they've met,'' she said. `` But just the fact that we are meeting and becoming friends ... it is harder to hate someone if you know them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-NATO     12-12 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-NATO,0911</SECOND>
<HEAD>West Germans Becoming Impatient with Foreign Military Presence</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 West Germans are showing sharp impatience with foreign <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> troops on their soil as their perception grows of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as a nation of peace. The top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military commander in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> calls it `` wishful thinking.'' On Nov. 22, a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> armored unit scrapped plans to enter a northern town during maneuvers because the townspeople were fed up with the noise and property damage created by war games. Three months earlier, a court blocked <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> plans to station 36 helicopters outside <LOCATION> Wiesbaden </LOCATION>. The ruling came amid intense local opposition to the noise caused by American aircraft and forces already in the area. American troops and other forces of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> have been guarding this frontline nation since the end of World War II. In maneuvers designed to keep the alliance's forces at peak readiness, <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> tanks rumble across West German farms and as jet aircraft swoop in on low passes. But West German politicians say they are facing what has become a widespread public perception that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the Soviet president, is a messenger of peace, and an accompanying attitude that perhaps the hair-trigger military readiness and the resulting inconveniences can finally be lessened. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announced Wednesday before the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> that he will reduce Soviet forces by 500,000 troops, including removing 50,000 soldiers and six tank divisions from Eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> by 1991. West German unease about foreign troops within its borders has increased this year amid a rash of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> jet crashes. On Thursday a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fighter jet slammed into <LOCATION> Remscheid </LOCATION>, killing the pilot and five people on the ground. Seventy people were killed in a fiery air show disaster Aug. 28 at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ramstein </LOCATION>, when Italian stunt planes collided. `` There is a deep-seated longing for peace. People find the idea of lowering the military posture very attractive,'' <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON>, a federal lawmaker in Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> says <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is a committed <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> partner and that <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s government sees the foreign troops in his country as still necessary for the security of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON> adds that domestic political pressure for a serious reduction in low-level <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> jet flights, fewer maneuvers that damage property, and other demands can not be ignored. <PERSON> Karsten </PERSON> <PERSON> Voigt </PERSON>, a lawmaker with the left-leaning opposition Social Democrats, agreed. `` It is increasingly difficult for politicians of all political colors to defend defensive needs against regional and national pressures,'' <PERSON> Voigt </PERSON> said at the Nov. 13-18 <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION> congress of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, an independent body of lawmakers from the 16 <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> nations. The Social Democrats have taken a harder stance than the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, maintaining that <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s overall defense strategy is outdated and needs to be reworked. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officials and conservative <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> politicians in recent months have been aggressively trying to counteract West European perceptions of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as a peacemaker. `` We must not get a distorted idea of what is really happening,'' Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>, supreme Allied commander in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, recently told reporters. `` Wishful thinking is causing the West to get deeper into a situation in which support for deterrence may be seriously threatened.'' A new West German unease about foreign troops on their soil has become especially apparent during the debate in <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> over `` burden-sharing.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials charge that <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> is not shouldering its fair share of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s financial burden and are asking <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and other countries to spend more for defense. The accusation is a sensitive one in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where about 400,000 foreign <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> troops, including 250,000 Americans, are based. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> himself has suggested that his countrymen already endure enough inconvenience because of <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> troops on their soil. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and other West German officials suggest the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should not be looking just at dollars and cents when weighing each <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> nation's contribution to the alliance. The West Germans say other factors should be assessed as well, such as foreign tanks tearing up farmland and fears among the population caused by low-level flights by military jets. `` There are 5,000 military exercises in this densely populated country each year,'' said <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON>, the Christian Democrat lawmaker. `` There's no piece of real estate where you have a greater concentration of soldiers and weapons _ including nuclear weapons. `` The Americans should understand these burdens. We want them to stay here, but they must realize this is a political burden.'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Enders </PERSON>, a political scientist at the <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politics </ORGANIZATION>, said a recent survey indicated that about 80 percent of West Germans backs <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, but he added that a `` resurgence of neutralism'' within <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> could grow with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in power in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. An poll this past summer indicated that 71 percent of West Germans had a favorable opinion of <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, compared with only 41 percent for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s government assures its transatlantic allies that it is not convinced the threat from the East has vanished, and that <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is committed to keeping <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> strong. <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON>: `` We're right next door to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, so we know full well why that is important.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JailedMoms     12-12 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jailed Moms,0591</SECOND>
<HEAD>Community Jailhouse For Pregnant Inmates Seeks To Preserve Mom-Baby
Bond</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new kind of state prison _ for pregnant inmates only _ opens today in an effort to keep new mothers and their babies together. Although a few other prison systems in the country make efforts to allow mothers to remain for a time with their infants, the <ORGANIZATION> Neil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> J. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> section will offer features unavailable elsewhere. Separating women and babies at birth causes `` a serious rupture in mother-infant bonding,'' said <PERSON> Lyla </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>, co-director of Social Justice for Women, a private, non-profit advocacy group for women prison inmates. The group will run the $ 550,000 program under a contract with the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correction </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's a historic step for the state and the country, to show respect for the mother and infant bond,'' Ms. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said last week. Currently, inmates in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> are separated from their children and returned to their cells within days of giving birth. Inmates of the 15-bed facility will be confined to the building but have access to counselors, drug rehabilitation, help in readjusting to society and medical care during pregnancy and after. The first resident, expected to be admitted in January, will find an atmosphere more like a halfway house than a jail. Guards will wear civilian clothes. Only women eligible for early release will be considered for admission, and it is expected that they will complete their sentences at the house. `` Three years ago, <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION> decided some immediate action was needed,'' Ms. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said. `` We had been working with women at -LRB- the state prison at -RRB- <LOCATION> Framingham </LOCATION>. We saw the numbers of pregnant women growing.'' About 50 pregnant women go through the state prison system every year; there were 17 prison births in 1986, the last year for which figures were available. The average sentence for women convicted in this state is four months, usually for drug-related crimes and prostitution, correction officials said. Since 1980 the number of women imprisoned in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> has risen 239 percent, an increase Ms. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> attributed to the general trend nationwide toward incarcerating people and away from sexism. Early in this century women routinely kept their babies with them in prison until people began to worry about the stigma attached to anyone who claimed a prison as their birthplace. More recently, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> started allowing babies born in prison to stay with their mothers until their first birthday, said <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON>, deputy superintendent for services at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> prison at <LOCATION> Bedford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. `` The bonding that results is very positive, both for mother and child, the way the babies develop and mature,'' <PERSON> Perlman </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. In <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, qualified pregnant inmates receive a 60-day furlough 30 days before they are due to give birth so that delivery can occur outside prison. But most women imprisoned in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, like those in other states, must return to their cells 40 to 72 hours after giving birth. Prison officials around the country said they knew of no such community-based program and said the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> program sounded like a good idea. `` I see when the women come in here that one of the hardest things is being separated from their children,'' said <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON>, associate warden of prisons at the federal minimum-security prison for women in <LOCATION> Alderson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BowenInterview     12-12 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bowen Interview,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bowen: Bush Has Hands Full with Medicare Spending Spiral</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration will have its hands full trying to cap Medicare's spending spiral without cutting into the quality of health care the program provides to 32 million Americans, says outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Otis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>. `` One the reasons it's going to be tougher is because of the massive new numbers of old people that we have coming along,'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said. With overall Medicare costs growing at about twice the rate of inflation, <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said the $ 100 billion program is a natural place to look for savings. `` At the same time we have to walk a very tight line and make sure we are not reducing the quality of care and access to care,'' he said in an interview. `` It is my judgment that we're getting close to that level now and we have to be very cautious about going too deep.'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> declined to discuss specifics of the final budget the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration will submit next month, but department sources have acknowledged agreeing to about $ 6 billion in net reductions in projected Medicare outlays, mostly by holding down payments to doctors and hospitals. The physician portion of <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> _ Part B _ is growing about 15 percent a year and Democrats and Republicans alike in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have said it will undergo close scrutiny in budget deliberations. Beyond the cuts he has agreed to for the next budget, <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said, `` We are getting close to the time where further ratcheting down could cause some deterioration in the quality of care and perhaps even access to care.'' <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, who will be 71 in February and plans to retire in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, noted that projections call for the number of people over the age of 100 to increase from 25,000 to 100,000 over the next decade. Not only will they tend to require more medical attention, but many also will used up savings and `` might become a bigger burden'' on public assistance, he said. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>, a former two-term governor of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> who said running that state was easier than running the huge <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> department, said his greatest accomplishment was getting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to back a catastrophic-illness insurance addition to <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> in the most sweeping expansion of the program since its birth two decades ago. `` Getting the president's approval over the objections of so many in the Cabinet, that was the tough part,'' said <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON>. `` Once the president gave his approval, then it became a lot easier to try to contain the number of additions <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> wanted to add to it.'' On the other hand, <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said he is disappointed he has been unable to get states to move more quickly to solve medical malpractice insurance problems which he said are threatening access to health care in some regions. He said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration should be ready to introduce federal legislation to override the states on the issue unless they move quickly. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said he was not suggesting such a step during the coming year, `` but certainly within four years'' unless the states act. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said there is a remaining need for special emphasis on AIDS `` because of the emotional response of the people. People are scared to death.'' `` I hesitate to single it out as a disease to be treated differently from others, but I think as yet it does need to have a little extra special treatment,'' he said. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said he has not been consulted by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition officials for a recommendation on who should succeed him. But he said he hopes the incoming president will not view the appointment as minor. `` When you're talking about a kinder and gentler <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, you're talking about <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said of the huge agency that has a larger budget than the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> and embraces such programs as Social Security, <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and welfare The department also includes the sprawling <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> umbrella that covers such well-known agencies as the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> and the Centers for Disease Control. <PERSON> Bowen </PERSON> said he hopes <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will give the new <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> secretary authority to pick the heads of those major agencies. `` I think loyalty is one of the most important attributes of somebody who is working for you and the appointing authority sort of draws that loyalty,'' he said. `` I think you can get a lot more accomplished and better serve the public if you have a team rather than somebody who you never knew and never worked with. Maybe you would n't develop the confidence in them you should.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DisplacedWorkers Bjt   12-12 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Displaced Workers, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nearly 10 Million Lost Jobs Due to Plant Closings, Layoffs Last
Five Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 10 million Americans lost their jobs due to plant closings or layoffs from 1983 to 1988 despite the longest peacetime economic expansion in the nation's history, the government reports. Of 9.7 million displaced workers during the period, 4.7 million were so-called `` tenured'' workers who had held their jobs for three years or more, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> says in the latest of its biennial reports on worker displacement. That was a slight decline from earlier BLS studies of overlapping five-year periods _ 1979-84 and 1981-86 _ which both had shown that 5.1 million tenured workers lost their jobs during the respective periods. But each of those periods also included the severe recession of 1981-82. As a result, government and private economists say the new figures show a persisting displacement problem. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mishel </PERSON>, an economist for the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank, called the decline in job displacement after the recession years `` surprisingly small.'' The <ORGANIZATION> BLS </ORGANIZATION> began conducting the displacement surveys in 1984 at the request of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. The latest report was released over the weekend. While the 1984 and 1986 surveys showed 50 percent of the displaced workers coming out of factories, only 40 percent of the tenured workers losing their jobs in 1983-88 had been employed in manufacturing. In conjunction, the distribution of the layoffs has shifted somewhat from blue-collar occupations such as machine operators, laborers and repairmen during the recession periods to white-collar management and sales occupations from 1983 to 1988. `` This was the lean-and-mean era, when companies went after middle-level managers and other white-collar workers,'' said <PERSON> Mishel </PERSON>. `` But a lot of it, especially in retail trade, is also somewhat related to these leveraged buyouts. It's probably the better-paid retail workers who lost their jobs.'' One thing that has n't changed is the percentage of workers who were given some kind of advance notice before losing their jobs. In all three surveys, roughly six of every 10 displaced workers had been told in advance to `` expect a layoff.'' But only two of every 10 in the latest survey said they had received a written notice of their impending dismissals _ a trend bound to change in view of a new law requiring 60 days written notice of plant closings and large layoffs beginning in 1989. Of the 4.7 million tenured workers who lost their jobs from 1983 to the end of 1987, 71 percent or approximately 3.2 million of them had new jobs as of January last year and 14 percent of them said they were looking for work. That compares favorably with re-employment rates of 67 percent and 60 percent and unemployment rates of 18 percent and 25 percent in the respective 1986 and 1984 surveys. Of those re-employed full-time, 56 percent reported making as much or more money in their new jobs while 44 percent reported making less _ in current dollars unadjusted for inflation. About 28 percent reported that their earnings had increased by 20 percent or more in their new jobs. Taking inflation into account, analysts said, that represents the workers who definitely are better off in their new jobs than they were in their old ones. But a slightly larger group, 30 percent, reported suffering an income loss of at least 20 percent from their old jobs. `` That's much deeper than in the previous surveys,'' said <PERSON> Mishel </PERSON>. `` It confirms a continuing trend of high-paid workers having no alternative but to shift to the poorer-paying jobs being created by this recovery.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TransitionSpending Bjt   12-12 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Transition Spending, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Transition Less Sweeping Than Reagan's</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Setting up the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration _ the task of some 300 people who toil in offices above a drugstore _ is being underwritten by the taxpayers to the tune of about $ 3.5 million. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s paid transition staff has grown to 149 at last count, with about the same number of volunteers, officials say. The highest paid are top advisers <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeder </PERSON>, both of whom are being paid at an annual rate of $ 71,377. After the transition, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will become secretary of state. To meet the payroll as well as pay for copying, research, telephones, rent, supplies and the like, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> receives a total of $ 3.5 million in public money. The money is allocated under the Presidential Transition Act of 1964. The amount was increased this year from the $ 2 million that was allowed when President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office eight years ago. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> operation, housed in three floors of an office building across the street from the hotel where <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was shot and wounded in 1981, is far more spare than the mini-bureaucracy of more than 1,000 people who worked for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s transition in 1980. And unlike <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is not supplementing his transition allowance with private donations. `` We just wanted to work within the money appropriated by the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and not make this become a big, fat, bloated operation,'' said transition spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>. `` This is not going to be a fast-growing bureaucracy. At this point close to $ 800,000 has not been allocated by us to our budget, which does indicate that we could return a sizeable chunk of money to the federal <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>.'' Volunteers are being used in clerical positions and the work days for transition officials stretch into late-night hours that have provoked some grumbling about the need for more staff. <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontaine </PERSON>, comptroller of the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which is responsible for overseeing transition spending, called it a `` very lean'' operation. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s transition staff can be smaller because, as a member of the same party and administration already in power, he will not be making the sweeping changes that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made when he took over from <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. `` This is what we call a friendly takeover,'' said <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON>. The amount <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> finally spent on his transition was never known, because he was not required to disclose the amount of private contributions his team collected, said <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> public affairs specialist <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Guiheen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ended up not actually spending all the public money, and returned some $ 250,000 of the $ 2 million to the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION> records. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year enacted a disclosure requirement for any private money raised by the transition operations. <PERSON> Prosperi </PERSON> said that just over a third of the transition budget is going into payroll. Salary schedules for the transition workers are set according to <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> scales, with the average salary at $ 35,137, according to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition officials. A status report to the <ORGANIZATION> GSA </ORGANIZATION>, detailing expenditures through the end of November, showed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had run up bills of more than $ 1 million in payroll and benefits for employees, many of whom went onto the transition payroll straight from the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. Rent and utilities came to almost $ 100,000, while printing and reproduction had cost $ 27,000. The transition had bills of $ 11,000 for supplies and had spent almost $ 149,000 on `` other services.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DanceBan     12-12 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dance Ban,0515</SECOND>
<HEAD>After First Dance, School Board Still Wants Ban</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA BRYSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PURDY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first dance in this 100-year-old Ozark town's high school is just a memory, but the students who thought it was `` a blast'' may not get an encore. The school board is appealing a court ruling that its policy against school dances is unconstitional. A federal appeals court allowed Saturday night's dance while the matter is considered. Officials restricted the dance to <ORGANIZATION> Purdy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>'s 161 students, saying they wanted to avoid any chance of trouble. Among those barred were reporters and photographers, and even an alumnus who was the lead plaintiff in the federal lawsuit that brought dancing to <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> <PERSON> High </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON>, a 1987 graduate, got only as close as the basketball game that preceded the homecoming dance. `` It's OK, though _ I won,'' <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> said as he watched the game and greeted old friends. `` It's still worth it. The idea was to allow <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> students to have a dance, and we did that.'' <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON>, a business school student, and 20 other <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> students and parents sued in 1986 to overturn the school board's written policy banning dancing. Longtime residents in this town of 900 say <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> has never been without a ban on social dancing in the schools. Some have said they associate dancing with drinking, drugs and illicit sex. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> ruled this summer that the school board's ban promoted the values of those who oppose dancing for religious reasons. The board appealed <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>'s order that they stop enforcing the ban, but the 8th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> is not expected to rule in the case before next year. The dance ban evoked comparisons to the hit movie `` Footloose'' about a similar ban in a fictional town. Although barred from dancing at school, <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> students have held dances at the community center or in neighboring towns. But they said that was inconvenient and unfair. <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Buxton </PERSON>, superintendent of the <PERSON> Purdy </PERSON> school system, said about 85 students attended Saturday night's dance. He said it went smoothly, but he refused to comment on whether other dances could be expected. Student council president <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said board members attended the dance. But the board members, who sat on the sidelines during the dance talking among themselves, apparently did not cramp students' style. `` It was a blast, we had a great time,'' Miss <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> said. `` It was really fun, everybody's dancing,'' said <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON>, a senior who left the dance early. But Miss Francisco, 17, added that the dance had caused controversy and bitterness in the southwestern <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> town. `` I do n't think it was worth all that,'' she said. Miss <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, appearing tired but happy after a day that included a college entrance exam and the history-making dance, said early Sunday that she was n't ready to plan another dance. `` I'm still thinking about cleanup for this one,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-12 0875</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eggnog Sales Bring Cheer to Dairy Farmers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The traditional eggnog season is in full swing and every cup that's raised should bring cheer to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s dairy farmers, says an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> economist. Most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dairy production is consumed as Grade A milk, cheese, butter and non-fat dry milk. But dairy economist <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> says several frequently overlooked products `` lie in the shadows'' of the big-volume items. These include eggnog, fluid cream, yogurt, cottage cheese and canned milk, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. Collectively, they use the equivalent of about 11 billion pounds of milk each year and have a farm value of about $ 1 billion. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, in a report and a telephone interview, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commercial use of milk in 1987 was a record of about 136 billion pounds and that this year's consumption probably will edge still higher. Although <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said he had no breakdown showing how much eggnog counted in the group of lesser items, sales figures indicate that eggnog has grown in popularity, more than doubling between 1970 and 1987. `` Some growth in eggnog sales has come from use outside the holiday season,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. At one time, milk processors started selling eggnog just before Thanksgiving and quit in late December. Today, he said, some eggnog processors begin selling for Halloween and continue through the holidays. Sales are sometimes resumed for a brief Easter season. But it will take more than merriment around the holiday eggnog bowl to keep pace with American dairy farmers. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s recent outlook conference that milk production this year is expected to rise 2 percent to another record level of around 145 billion pounds. Production declined slightly in 1987 to 142.5 billion pounds from the record in 1986 of 143.5 billion pounds. `` The new record was reached because of an increase of almost 3 percent in milk per cow,'' he said. The number of cows in production this year was estimated at 10.2 million, down 1 percent from 1987 and the fewest on record. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said there are a lot of variables ahead for 1989, including feed costs and other factors. Even so, total milk output next year `` may be about the same'' as in 1988, while commercial use may be up 1 percent to 3 percent. Another factor in the dairy business has been the increase in use of fluid cream, with sales rising by three-fourths between 1970 and 1987, he said. Whipping cream more than doubled, while half-and-half and light cream showed similar gains. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> added that `` yogurt has received a great deal of attention'' because of its popularity among weight watchers and other consumers. Last year, he said, yogurt sales were up sixfold from 1970, but he added that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> yogurt market was tiny before the introduction of sweetened, fruit-flavored brands. `` Lost in the excitement about yogurt's rapid growth is the realization that yogurt remains a minor use of milk,'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. `` Growth in yogurt sales since 1970 has contributed considerably less to farm milk demand than have increases in fluid cream use.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> rank well behind <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and some of the other giant importers of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural products, but the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says they show good potential for growth. The market includes 57 million inhabitants, about 77 percent of whom live in urban areas on a total land mass of 150,000 square miles, or about the size of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. Collectively <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> make up the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>. Admission to the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> in 1973 gave the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> increased exposure to `` Euro-continental'' food brands, the department's <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said in a recent trade report. `` Nonetheless, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> possesses a strong food production capability as well as a taste for traditional food items, although the latter is changing along with consumer lifestyles,'' the report said. `` Seafood, meat, dairy and grain products produced or processed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> remain popular while <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and Asian food items perform well within certain market segments.'' The report noted a number of economic characteristics that make the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> attractive to exporting countries. Between 1983 and 1986, for example, per capita disposable income grew by 19.5 percent. Total national spending on food rose by 12 percent during the same period. `` Growth in food-related spending appears consistent with the general direction of the <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION> economy,'' the report said. Last year, it said, agricultural imports totaled $ 18.5 billion, with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market share at 6 percent, or about $ 1.1 billion. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imports of agricultural products from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> were valued at $ 367 million last year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Boutwell </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperatives </ORGANIZATION>, has been named leader of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural trade and development mission to two African countries next year. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> mission, which will include at least half a dozen other members, will visit <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Ivory </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, probably in February, although officials said the exact dates have to be negotiated. Similar missions were carried out this year to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> as part of a program to boost farm trade with designated countries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-QuayleDifferences     12-12 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Quayle Differences,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Likely to Push Harder Line in Private</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is likely to push for more conservative arms-control stances during backstage negotiations, but he no doubt will toe the administration line in public, national security analysts say. `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s certainly been more conservative than <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, but this is going to be a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, not a <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> administration,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON>, a national security analyst with the non-profit, conservative <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON>, director of the liberal Council for a Livable World, agreed. `` I think that to the extent there's any disagreement between the two, it will be <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> making the accommodation, not <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' he said. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a Republican from <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, was one of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s most conservative members on national security issues during his eight years in the chamber. For example, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> voiced a series of questions and criticisms earlier this year about the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty negotiated by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> strongly supported the pact, which was ratified by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who eventually voted for the pact, said in a 1987 interview that `` I have a lot of questions -LRB- about the INF treaty -RRB-, and I do n't believe in the long run, quite frankly, contrary to the popular perception, that this is going to be a big political plus for this administration.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also has voiced skepticism about <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration efforts to negotiate a U.S.-Soviet Strategic Arms Reduction Talk treaty providing deep reductions in the long-range arsenals of each nation. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has supported those efforts and pledged to work toward a START pact after he replaces <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Jan. 20. In a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing last Feb. 3 on the INF pact, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, `` If in fact we do not get a START agreement, it is not going to be the end of the world. As a matter of fact, it might give us some time to see how the INF agreement is going to be implemented.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in his first debate with Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, said, `` We've achieved an arms control agreement -LRB- INF -RRB- that our critics thought was never possible. And I want to build on it _ I want to see us finalize the START agreement.'' Both <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> have said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should be negotiating to reduce conventional weapons in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where the Soviets have a large numerical advantage. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbrunner </PERSON>, director of foreign policy studies for the liberal <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s influence is likely to be limited when the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration begins drafting arms control positions. `` <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has been a classic hardliner on arms control, but I do n't think many people imagine that he's going to have a very great weight in deliberations,'' <PERSON> Steinbrunner </PERSON> said. `` The speculation really focuses on how <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s own plans evolve.'' `` Quayle and other members of the right wing would have slowed up or strung out the INF treaty if they had the votes, but they showed they did n't have the votes,'' <PERSON> Steinbrunner </PERSON> said. `` The right wing has limited appeal. It's very vociferous, it's very intense, but in fact it's not in line with most people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Garthoff </PERSON>, who helped negotiate the SALT I and Anti-Ballistic Missile treaties, agreed that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is likely to have only limited influence. `` Quayle wo n't differ publicly, but he may be a voice for the conservatives within the inner councils of the administration. I do n't expect that he'll have a large influence, but his opinion may be sought by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to understand what the conservatives are thinking,'' <PERSON> Garthoff </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hackett </PERSON> concurred that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is likely to seek to influence administration positions. `` Certainly <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will support the administration in public, despite what it does, but I presume he will have some influence in the in-house meetings that lead up to the public positions,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BaseClosings     12-12 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Base Closings,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Base-Closing Panel Will Meet Year-End Deadline, Chairman Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A presidential commission studying the nation's more than 3,800 military installations is closing in on its goal of determining which ones should be shut down Former Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> Republican who is co-chairman of the 12-member panel, says it will meet its year-end deadline of recommending which bases should be closed. But <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said a final list has yet to be prepared by the commission, which will report to <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON>. `` People keep asking about a list and wanting to know how many bases, but we do n't have a goal in terms of numbers,'' he said. `` We have n't made any final decisions yet.'' The commission is an attempt to untie a congressional knot that has blocked the Pentagon from closing any bases since 1977. Legislators, loathe to lose the jobs that bases provide, have erected a long and complicated series of barriers to individual closings. `` Closing bases is tough for any congressman,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` You're talking lost jobs and that means unhappy voters. This is near and dear to all our hearts.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said he does n't know how many bases will be on the final list, but <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> predicted `` the figure will likely be 20 to 25 bases, perhaps a few more.'' <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, who said he has purposefully remained aloof from the panel's work, estimated that annual savings will be about $ 2 billion. Besides evaluating data from the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the commission is also listening to petitions from congressmen and their constituents. Last week, Rep. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> English, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., delivered more than 13,000 letters from Enid, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, urging the panel not to close <ORGANIZATION> Vance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> Earlier, legislators from northeastern states ranging from <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> had written the panel, urging that <ORGANIZATION> Sunbelt </ORGANIZATION> states suffer the most reductions because they said those states had the most bases. After the <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>' panel finishes its work, <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> will have until Jan. 15 _ five days before he leaves office _ to accept or reject the entire list. He ca n't make any other changes. If <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> approves the list as expected, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> could only block the closures if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> each pass a disapproval resolution. That resolution could be vetoed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meaning it would effectively take a two-thirds vote in each chamber to block the shutdowns. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> explained that his panel is using a complicated set of criteria to make its decisions. First, installations are being grouped by military mission; for example, all Army depots, all <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter bases, all <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> ports for surface ships. Then bases in a particular category will be evaluated for five factors _ mission suitability, including geographical location and ease of deployment; physical facilities in place; the quality of those facilities; quality of life for personnel, such as housing; and community support. Bases at the bottom of each `` mission'' list will be considered for closure, partly by determining if other, higher-ranking bases can become `` receiving'' facilities. Next, cost evaluations will be done, environmental factors such as hazardous waste problems will be considered, and the impact of the lost jobs will be weighed. `` It's an extremely complicated process,'' said <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>. `` We have a huge amount of information to evaluate and judgments to make.'' The Pentagon and the services have n't offered any lists. `` What we have done is asked the services for information, a tremendous amount of information,'' he said. `` We're checking that information by sending staff members and commission members out to the bases in some instances, talking to base commanders and local people.'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> insists politics is n't an issue. `` This the most non-partisan committee I've ever been associated with. Believe me, that's the truth.'' `` We do n't look at our charge as having anything to do with politics. We have n't looked at whose district a base is located in,'' he said. `` Obviously, everybody else in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> approaches it from the perspective of politics, but we have n't.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TeacherSurvey     12-12 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Teacher Survey,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teachers Frustrated By Lack of Support from Parents, Social
Problems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than half of the nation's teachers say they see evidence of child abuse, poor nutrition and parental neglect in their classrooms, according to a national study. `` Teachers repeatedly made the point that in the push for better schools they can not do the job alone, and yet there is a growing trend to expect schools to do what families, communities and churches have been unable to accomplish,'' said <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Teaching. The foundation's survey of 22,000 teachers found a sense of frustration among teachers, both at `` the lack of support they receive from parents'' and from a feeling of `` powerlessness in teaching,'' he said. `` Large majorities of teachers find poverty, poor health, undernourishment and neglect to be problems at their schools,'' he said. Teachers from every state were canvassed in twin surveys conducted by mail in the spring and fall of 1987. The findings were released Sunday. Among them: _ 90 percent said lack of parental support was a problem at their schools _ 89 percent said there were abused or neglected children at their schools _ 69 percent said poor health was a problem for their students _ 68 percent said some children were undernourished Teachers in the survey described their students `` as ` emotionally needy' and ` starved for attention and affection,''' <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the report underscores the need for parental involvement. `` I wish I could sit down with every parent in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and emphasize how important they are to their children's education,'' Ms. <PERSON> Futrell </PERSON> said. `` Parents are a child's first _ and potentially the most influential _ teachers.'' The average public school teacher earned $ 28,031 in 1987-88, according to figures from the NEA. Forty-nine percent of the teachers in the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> survey said their pay was worse than they expected; 41 percent said it was about what they expected, and 10 percent said it was better. The average teacher surveyed had 16 years experience. The average teacher faced 79 students on a typical day, with elementary teachers working with 60 different pupils and secondary teachers 114. The typical class size was 23. Sixty-two percent of the teachers said their most typical class was about the right size; 36 percent felt it was too large, and 1 percent said it was too small -LRB- The figures do not add up to 100 percent because of rounding -RRB-. Only 7 percent of the teachers surveyed said they planned to quit the profession as soon as they could. Fifty-six percent planned to teach until they retire; 21 percent said they probably would continue teaching; 10 percent were undecided about their career plans, and 6 percent said they may take time off from teaching. The <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, published earlier `` Condition of Teaching'' reports in 1983 and 1985. It said the overall margin of error on the unusually large survey was only plus or minus 1 percentage point.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0319EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChemicalSpill     12-12 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Chemical Spill,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hundreds Return Home After Chemical Spill</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FONTANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chemical spill forced about 1,500 residents to flee their homes for three hours, authorities said. A 55-gallon drum of the insecticide mercapto spilled at <ORGANIZATION> PIE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trucking </ORGANIZATION> company late Saturday, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> fire dispatcher <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Emery </PERSON> said. Authorities could not say how the spill occurred. Residents of a section of this city 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> were evacuated as a precaution for about three hours, Ms. <PERSON> Emery </PERSON> said. Several people who complained of throat irritation and burning around the mouth were treated at the scene, said Fire Capt. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Easton </PERSON>. Mercapto can be deadly if ingested or harmful if it comes into direct skin contact, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Tibet-Foreigners Bjt   12-12 0681</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tibet-Foreigners, Bjt,0701</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreigners Tell of Panicked Flight From Clash in Tibet</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreigners caught in a clash between <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police and nationalists in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s capital told of diving behind vendors' tables and running down narrow alleys as troops open fire without warning. `` People were falling and screaming. I saw people carrying wounded Tibetans on their backs, running into their houses and trying to find some place to hide,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, a sociology professor at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newfoundland </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Johns </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. He said he dashed up a street to dodge police bullets and tear gas. `` It seemed like an eternity I was running up that street,'' he said in a telephone interview Sunday with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. The clash broke out Saturday in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> when 30 Tibetans, identified by the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> as <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks and nuns, marched into a market with the banned <LOCATION> Tibetan </LOCATION> flag to commemorate the 40th anniversary of the U.N. Declaration on Human Rights. The protesters, dressed in street clothes and face masks, demanded an end to 38 years of <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> communist rule over the Himalayan Mountain region. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> said Sunday that a <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monk was killed and 13 people were wounded when police fired at demonstrators. <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON> said the monk had been carrying <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>'s banned flag. Police `` appeared, marching in a tight formation. They fanned out in an arc, some very close to the monks,'' said <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>. He and the other foreign witnesses said the police then opened fire without warning. The nationally televised evening news said police `` were forced to fire'' when `` some troublemakers refused to heed a warning and threw stones and bottles at police.'' `` The soldiers were running after us. They came so close,'' said <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> Meindersma </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, who was shot in the left arm. `` They started shooting, and we started running. I ran for my life,'' said another witness, an English woman who spoke on condition of anonymity. One traveler, speaking on condition of anonymity, said a Tibetan who went to a hospital to give blood for the wounded saw four bodies. The foreigners, who spoke by telephone from their hotels, said authorities imposed tight security in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> and searched foreigners' hotel rooms on Sunday Ms. <PERSON> Meindersma </PERSON> said after she was wounded, she tried to hide `` but they came after me so I ran again.'' `` There was no looking back, it was just running, running. I heard the bullets skimming past my head: shoo, shoo. My only thought was, ` I have to hide.' I ran into a Tibetan courtyard. There were many people there in panic. I said, ` I'm wounded,' and I fainted.'' A British man who spoke on condition of anonymity said he ran in a different direction and found himself in a narrow alley with about 50 Tibetans. `` The police fired tear gas at both ends of the alley,'' he said. `` I thought I was going to die of suffocation.'' After 10 minutes, he said the gas subsided, and the group escaped. `` Some Tibetans took me to a small temple where I saw the dead body of the monk who had been shot in the head,'' he said. `` There was a crowd of Tibetans weeping.'' At the scene of the shooting, he said, a tear-gas canister lay near a pool of blood. `` Within half an hour after the demonstration, Tibetans began laying white scarves near the pool of blood and the canister,'' he said. Tibetan Buddhists drape gauzy, white scarves over the statues of deities in their temples as a gesture of greeting and respect. Saturday's was the third bloody confrontation in <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> between authorities and anti-Chinese protesters since October 1987. At least 38 people were killed in the earlier clashes, and hundreds were arrested. The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> government, which claims <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> has been part of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> since the 13th century, moved troops into the remote region in 1950. <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> was then ruled by a <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> theocracy headed by the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, who fled to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> when the Chinese put down a 1959 uprising.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881212-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-12-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MitchellinMaine Bjt   12-12 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mitchell in Maine, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0425 to restore dropped matter</HEAD>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Mitchell Will Need Maine Repertoire as Senate
Chief</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WATERVILLE, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
