<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0000EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NewsChoppers     11-28 0987</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-News Choppers,1015</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilot-Reporters, Authorities Fight For Space Over News Sites</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By FELIX GUTIERREZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A helicopter flying in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> last summer only wanted to shoot film for NBC News, but a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> destroyer almost blew it out of the sky when the crew failed to respond to repeated warnings. News helicopters around the world are becoming more aggressive in their quest for the best pictures. Pilots and officials now are taking steps to avoid disaster, to strike a balance between the First Amendment and public safety. Following last May's $ 7-million <LOCATION> Redondo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> pier fire near <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, news pilot <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Tur </PERSON> was criticized for fanning smoke and flames, endangering firefighters, and hampering radio communications with noise. `` We can be a pain,'' acknowledged Tur, who is currently appealing a 180-day license suspension for an unrelated infraction. But he denied he hovered too close, and said that was n't the real reason for his problems. `` People sometimes do n't want publicity. But if the media did n't tell you, who would?'' More news choppers are buzzing the skies above big news events, from earthquakes to chemical spills. Often, it's the only way television crews or newspaper photographers can grab pictures of a distant sea rescue or landslide before deadline. Not too long ago, only the three major television stations in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> used helicopters, said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreesman </PERSON>, whose <ORGANIZATION> Helitac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> currently flies for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and other news organizations. Nowadays, photographers from such publications as the National Enquirer spend hours each week airborne. `` We ask -LRB- the news helicopters -RRB- to back off and most of them are pretty polite about it,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> of the police Air Support Division. `` Others are pretty persistent. They want to keep taking their pictures and at times it becomes an annoyance.'' These days, teamwork among helicopters begins to play a more important role _ and that's not the most common trait in such a competitive business. `` There's no problem in and around a major event when pilots communicate,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettee </PERSON>, who flies for <ORGANIZATION> KNBC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. `` The only problem is when somebody does something unexpected.'' <PERSON> Pettee </PERSON> said experienced news pilots can shoot a chemical spill without stirring up toxic gas, stay far enough away from a hostage situation to avoid exciting a gunman, and cooperate with other pilots on the scene. Sometimes they even help officials by tracking fires or flying out victims, he said. Complaints were common before the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> limited flights around disasters in 1985, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Joann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sloan </PERSON> said. The restrictions allow local officials to ask the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to declare fires, crashes and other incidents off-limits to aircraft for safety reasons. News aircraft are permitted only if they file a flight plan, fly above rescue aircraft, obey on-site authorities, and follow other rules. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> fire and law enforcement officials said they coordinate coverage with news helicopters as they show up on the scene. `` I think the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> thinks they have things under control,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Sloan </PERSON>. `` We have n't had any disasters occur with these -LRB- news -RRB- helicopters that I know of anytime recently.'' But last December <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, then-Chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, cited helicopter problems in asking the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> to tighten controls around disaster sites. <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> cited six incidents since 1974 where news helicopters worsened hazards or hampered rescue efforts. These included stirring up fumes and dust around spills of hazardous materials, a fatal crash over a chemical fire, and distracting ground rescue crews. `` These incidents illustrate how non-rescue aircraft can interfere with rescue and clean-up activities and endanger the lives and health of the occupants of the aircraft, the victims of the accident, and the emergency response personnel responding to the fire or hazardous materials incident,'' <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> wrote. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> McArtor </PERSON> declined to issue new rules in March, but he pledged the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> would impose a 180-day license suspension for pilots ignoring flight restrictions. Tur knows all about such suspensions. The pilot, whose company sells videotape to several television stations, ran into trouble with federal officials in March 1987 over the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> jet fighter crash that killed <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, son of entertainer <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> honored a request by search officials to issue flight restrictions around the crash site in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, according to testimony at a suspension hearing last September. Tur was warned away from the area by an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> colonel on the scene. But he flew by to shoot late afternoon pictures of searchers combing the steep, brush-filled mountainside for debris and bodies. Other news crews were escorted over the scene at a higher altitude. Tur contended that flights were restricted only to avoid publicity. `` Never can a local, state, or federal agency prevent news media representatives from flying into an area because public relations does n't want the story told,'' he said. But Col. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cross </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officer at the site, testified news helicopters posed a safety threat. He said <PERSON> Tur </PERSON>'s noisy flight `` significantly disrupted my coordination efforts'' by distracting searchers, and jeopardized their safety Like Tur, the late <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Galanis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> KUSA-TV </ORGANIZATION>, who was head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, felt the <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> crash site was restricted merely to curb publicity. `` I think it's obvious if it was not <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s son there would not have been a -LRB- restriction -RRB- in effect,'' <PERSON> Galanis </PERSON> said in an interview a few weeks before his own death in a helicopter crash. <PERSON> Galanis </PERSON> and cameraman <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hostetler </PERSON> were returning from covering a plane crash Oct. 19 when their helicopter became entangled in a utility cable and crashed southwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. Both men were killed. Blocking or limiting media helicopters, <PERSON> Galanis </PERSON> said in the interview, `` prevents the public from seeing events that they're entitled to see under the First Amendment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-JapanorNippon     11-29 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan or Nippon,0704</SECOND>
<HEAD>Is It Japan Or Nippon? Even Japanese Differ</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARI YAMAGUCHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In Japanese this country is called Nippon or sometimes <ORGANIZATION> Nihon </ORGANIZATION>, and therein lies a seed of debate. `` Why is our country called <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>? Its ` official' name is <PERSON> Nippon </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Kazuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> wrote in a letter published in September by the <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>, provoking a minor flood of other readers' letters. The 26-year-old student from <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> argued that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> should `` unanimously use Nippon'' as its own name on the international level _ on athletes' uniforms when they compete abroad, for instance. One of the editors of <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION>'s letters section thought the flurry of response and comment was slightly alarming _ a possible sign of nationalistic feelings at a time when Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was gravely ill. `` It is a bit scary that people are interested in such a issue especially under the current situation, when the emperor's illness has been affecting the country,'' he said, asking that he not be named But the editor thought it was good for the letters columns to be used to debate the issue. `` I guess it would be easier if we could choose one -LRB- name -RRB-, but we can not decide which should be legitimate,'' he said. Not everybody is sensitive about the country's name, or worried that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is getting nationalistic. A foreign relations specialist and conservative writer, <PERSON> Hideaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kase </PERSON>, said, `` I think it's fine to have a few different names. There seems to be no problem using either <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> or Nippon. ... It has nothing to do with nationalism.'' A Foreign Ministry official said there are no rules on how to name countries in other languages, and he noted that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is spelled <PERSON> Japon </PERSON> in Spanish and pronounced like `` hapon.'' But what should Japanese athletes wear on their uniforms for international competition? No one but the Chinese would be able to recognize <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s name written in the Chinese characters, which <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> borrowed to make a writing system centuries ago, so it has to be written in the Roman alphabet, called romaji in Japanese. <PERSON> Kayoko </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amateur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sports </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said the organization provides uniforms emblazoned `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'' for international athletic events. `` For major international events, we use <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> as the country's official name, because English is the most common language,'' she said But there's no firm rule, and some teams also go with <PERSON> Nippon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Masaaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Obana </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Volleyball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said the national volleyball team has both <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Nippon </ORGANIZATION> uniforms but players wear Nippon more often in international contests. `` Either way, they're our country's names. We do n't think we should be using only one of the two,'' <PERSON> Obana </PERSON> said. After <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>'s letter was published, the volleyball association received many inquiries asking which name is official, because Japanese volleyball players wore their Nippon uniforms at the summer Olympics games in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> editor said the newspaper, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s second-largest circulation daily, received about 10 letters on the issues. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Blahitka </PERSON> from <PERSON> Yamaguchi </PERSON> prefecture in southwestern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> wrote that she was against using Nippon because many languages as well as Japanese translate foreign countries' names into their own tongue, and English-speaking countries are no exception. `` For example, <PERSON> Bundesrepublik </PERSON> <PERSON> Deutschland </PERSON> is the Federal Republic of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> or colloquially <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in English, and ` <PERSON> Nishi </PERSON> <PERSON> Doitsu </PERSON>' in Japanese,'' she said. Teacher <PERSON> Tatsuya </PERSON> <PERSON> Akizuki </PERSON>, 36, wrote: `` It is a huge task to change the way a country's name or person's name, which has already become fixed in our daily lives, is pronounced.'' `` If Japanese are told to accurately pronounce country names and names of people in the languages of the respective countries, we would be in trouble,'' he added. The origin of the name <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is not certain, but researchers say it probably came from the Malayan `` Japung'' or the Chinese `` Riben,'' meaning roughly land of the rising sun. Historians say the Japanese called their country <ORGANIZATION> Yamato </ORGANIZATION> in its early history, and they began using Nippon around the seventh century. Nippon and <ORGANIZATION> Nihon </ORGANIZATION> are used interchangeably as the country's name
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0307EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HolidayBabies     11-29 0130</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Holiday Babies,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Couple Has Third Holiday Baby</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDIANOLA, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some people celebrate April Fool's Day by playing pranks, <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>'s Day with a toast to the Irish and Thanksgiving Day with a turkey. <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> has celebrated all three by having babies. Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> gave birth to <PERSON> Jason </PERSON>, 9 pounds, 1 ounce, on Thanksgiving Day in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. Mother and baby were doing fine. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> is the third holiday baby for Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> and her 33 year-old husband, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>. Their oldest child, <PERSON> Amanda </PERSON>, arrived on April Fool's Day 1982, and their second child, <PERSON> Jacquelyn </PERSON>, was born in St. Patrick's Day 1984. Mrs. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> attributes the birthdays to luck. `` All this has made me really happy,'' she said Monday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LitterbugBuster     11-29 0244</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Litterbug Buster,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Columnist Fights Litterbugs; Gets Six Stitches</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newspaper columnist's beef about litterbugs got him into trouble on the city streets he's trying to keep clean. A few weeks ago, The <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON> wrote a column criticizing litterbugs and criticizing himself for not standing up to them. He swore, in print, that next time he saw a litterbug, he would say something. He got his opportunity Saturday, along with six stitches for his effort. <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON>, in his column Monday, wrote he and his wife were driving in the city when they saw four teen-agers throw two large beverage containers out of a car with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> license plates. <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON> got out of his car, picked up the containers and gave them back to the driver, saying, `` Do me a favor, pal, take these back to <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> with you.'' About a block later, while both cars were stuck in traffic, three teen-agers from the other car ran up to <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON>'s. When <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON> got out, he said, one `` whacked'' him from behind before they fled. <PERSON> DeLeon </PERSON> said he received six stitches about an inch below his right eye, where his glasses dug into his cheekbone when he was hit. He wrote that the doctor in the emergency room congratulated him for `` doing what she has often wanted to do but has been afraid to do for reasons that were as clear as the face in front of her.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Algeria     11-29 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Algeria,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bendjedid Reinforces His Authority For Further Reforms</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFFREY ULBRICH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Chadli </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendjedid </PERSON>, promising to usher in a new era of liberal reforms, solidified his power during a meeting of the nation's only party and virtually assured himself of another five years in office. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> wrapped up its two-day congress late Monday night by electing a new, 155-member <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which then designated Bendjedid as its secretary-general. The head of the party automatically becomes sole candidate in the presidential elections, which the <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> set for Dec. 22. Bendjedid thus will win a third five-year term as head of this one-party socialist state. But Bendjedid now must confront the growing economic and social problems that exploded into bloody riots in early October. Official reports said 176 died in the protests, but unofficial estimates put the death toll at 500. `` I need your help because the mission is difficult, the task is long and the problems are great,'' Bendjedid told the 5,078 congress delegates in his closing speech. `` The renewal of your confidence is a support for the political reform proposals, of which a part already have been applied and others are going to be. I promise to do my best to implement your political program.'' Many Algerians, however, were hoping that the congress would approve a multiparty political system. <PERSON> Bendjedid </PERSON> said during the congress that such a move was possible in the future, but he contended it could harm national unity at the present time. It was not know at the end of the congress what form <ORGANIZATION> Bendjedid </ORGANIZATION>'s reforms would take The October riots were staged by Algerians upset with high unemployment, rising prices and a shortage of housing. The protests prompted Bendjedid to promise a more liberal political system and less central control. Bendjedid has been trying for the past two years to institute reforms, particularly breaking the grip of the party on the day-to-day running of the country. That effort was accelerated by the violence in October. He told the congress that a package of reforms would be presented to Parliament soon, but did not detail what they would contain. <PERSON> Abdelhamid </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehri </PERSON>, the No. 2 man in the party, said that although a multiparty system had been rejected for the immediate future, free candidacies for some elected offices would be allowed. That means non-party members may run for local assemblies and the national <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. The new <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> was comprised almost equally of delegates elected from local cells; from government and party functionaries; and from union and professional organizations. That appeared to bring in the new blood <PERSON> Bendjedid </PERSON> was seeking and end the domination of party militants that characterized the outgoing committee. After the October riots, the government quickly held a referendum to win approval of the first phase of reforms. Those consisted mainly of changes to the constitution. Among those changes was according new power to the premier and making him directly responsible to the Parliament rather than the president. Shortly after the Nov. 3 referendum, <ORGANIZATION> Bendjedid </ORGANIZATION> appointed a new premier, <PERSON> Kasdi </PERSON> <PERSON> Merbah </PERSON>, and a government made up largely of technicians rather than professional party militants. <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>'s debt is estimated at $ 23 billion. The nation also has faced a dramatic fall in the price of oil _ the country's main export _ during the past two years, and an unemployment rate of 22 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DisfiguredSoldier     11-29 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Disfigured Soldier,0655</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maimed Soldier Appeals To Countrymen For Consideration</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONI RABIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young reserve soldier whose face was burned and mutilated by a firebomb went on television to ask fellow Israelis to show some understanding and stop staring at him. <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Navon </PERSON>, a 25-year-old university student, was doing his required duty in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> last June when Palestinians hurled a firebomb at his jeep. His face was disfigured and all his fingers had to be amputated. He decided to appear on an Israeli TV talk show Monday night, he said, because his countrymen react so cruelly when they encounter victims like himself in public. `` All the stares lock on you,'' he said. `` Sometimes it's helplessness, or even fear ... People just have no tact and they shout things, like, ` Look at this weirdo, look at this creature!' `` As though we are not living in a country where people should know about this phenomenom. It happens a lot and I'm not the only one; there are a lot like me.'' <PERSON> Navon </PERSON>'s entire face is covered with burns and scar tissue. His ears were burned off. His fingerless hands are still wrapped in bandages. He appeared on TV with his girlfriend, <PERSON> Miri </PERSON> <PERSON> Amiel </PERSON>. They began dating about six months before he was hurt, and Ms. <PERSON> Amiel </PERSON> said they were closer now than ever. `` Before, we were like any couple, going out together, studying together, having fun. ... Now we have to deal with all these things together,'' she said. `` Of course, <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> has to deal with it more than I, but I am a partner in everything.'' They met at college, where he was taking a preparatory course before studying for a degree. <PERSON> Amiel </PERSON> said she, too, is pained by the public's reaction. `` It's very sad for me ... to see all the stares, and hope that <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> does n't notice,'' she said. Tragedy struck <PERSON> Navon </PERSON> at 11 p.m. on June 14, the last day of his unit's 24-day tour of duty in the occupied areas. His jeep entered <LOCATION> Beit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Umar </LOCATION> village for one last patrol before returning to base for a farewell party. `` I did n't want to do the extra round because it was late,'' he said. `` I felt a ... strange feeling. ... After a moment or two I felt the Molotov cocktail. All of me was burning. ... I could n't open the door to get out of the jeep. Since then, <PERSON> Navon </PERSON> has undergone more than a dozen operations and skin transplants. He said he began crying when he realized what he looked like and `` my brother and my girlfriend ... also started crying. ... A few minutes later I said, O.K., guys, calm down, everything will be all right, this is n't going to break me.'' The television showed a photograph of <PERSON> Navon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Amiel </PERSON>, taken before the attack and portraying a handsome young man in army uniform. `` I was always a pretty realistic and rational type,'' <PERSON> Navon </PERSON> said. `` This new situation is not simple and not easy ... but it wo n't help to complain or ask why I look like this.'' He said he was appealing to Israeli society to be kinder to burn victims not for himself but because other burn victims were more sensitive than he. At least 10 people have suffered serious burns in firebomb attacks in the past year _ a frequent weapon in the yearlong <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> uprising that has killed more than 300 Palestinians and 11 Israelis. <PERSON> Navon </PERSON> said he harbors no desire for revenge and no feelings of hatred toward the Palestinians who attacked him. He said Palestinian insurrectionists have `` a struggle of their own, and the way they're doing it, with violence, they wo n't accomplish anything They must sit and talk this problem out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FoamFreeAmherst     11-29 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Foam Free Amherst,0329</SECOND>
<HEAD>Town Meeting Backs Off Ban On Plastic Food Containers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A town meeting Monday endorsed the idea of reducing the use of polystyrene coffee cups and other plastic food containers but backed down from a complete ban on the non-recyclable materials. A group called <ORGANIZATION> Foam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> sponsored the proposal to ban the sale of plastic foam food containers in the town of 35,000 people, home to <ORGANIZATION> Amherst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> and the University of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. Townspeople voted instead on a substitute motion calling on the town to `` endorse the goals of reducing the use of non-recyclable plastics,'' educate vendors and users about cutting back, and encourage use of alternatives. There was no discussion of the original motion at town meeting. But <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutcheson </PERSON>, who sponsored the substitute measure, said Foam Free Amherst supported the replacement. The motion passed by voice vote. The aim of the original proposal was to discourage the use of plastics because they take up considerable space in the town dump and create gases that deplete the earth's ozone layer when manufactured and burned, according to sponsor <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Polystyrene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Packaging </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, defended the plastic by saying that researchers have found fast-food packaging takes up only one-quarter of 1 percent of landfills in weight and volume. Moreover, <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> DeCampos </PERSON> said, the polystyrene industry has voluntarily agreed to stop using chlorofluoromethane in the manufacture of plastic cups by January out of concern for the earth's ozone layer. <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> was one of several communities across the nation to take a closer look at polystyrene cups and consider bans that DeCampos called `` a quick fix to the solid waste issue.'' Bans already are in effect in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, N.Y. In <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has issued an executive order effective July 1989 banning state agencies from purchasing plastic foam food packaging.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     11-29 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a city where image is everything, city planners are prescribing a face lift. They're recommending `` designer'' sidewalks, flower planters and novel street lamps to counter fears that cracked sidewalks and traffic-clogged streets will send shoppers elsewhere. `` It's a critical step forward in giving a face lift to a city which is in desperate need to maintain its beauty and attractiveness and keep its kind of garden-spot-of-the-world atmosphere,'' Mayor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanenbaum </PERSON> said. The entire revitalization plan for the 30-block business district could run $ 80 million. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said it would study the proposal. Plans include $ 2 million for flower planters, $ 715,000 for sprinklers, $ 10.4 million for scored concrete sidewalks with granite bands, $ 3.3 million for street lamps, $ 1 million to widen sidewalks on Rodeo Drive and <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Way </LOCATION>, $ 1.5 million for pedestrian gateways and $ 1 million to landscape the middle of <LOCATION> Wilshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION>. `` Are we slipping? Not a bit,'' said <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Shurz </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> president. `` But to maintain our present position of total excellence we have to keep our guard up. That's what, basically, the city is very concerned about. Maintaining the image.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stumped for a Christmas present for the person who has everything? How about a bridge. The state <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has honest-to-goodness historic bridges available to anyone who will give them good homes and will haul them away. But seriously, who would want a bridge? Cities, counties, park and recreation districts, land developers _ anyone who wants to preserve some road history and save some of the enormous cost of building a new trestle is interested in the bridges, said <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON>, staff historian for the department. Bridges in the 3-year-old `` Adopt-A-Bridge'' program are scheduled for replacement because they are deteriorating or impractical for modern traffic. Eighteen bridges, most made of steel trusses, are eligible for the program, <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> said. But so far only three have reached some stage of being moved mainly because of the difficulties in relocating them. Moving expenses vary. For example, to disassemble and relocate all four, 185-foot-long spans of the Fifth Street Bridge in Grand Junction is estimated to cost between $ 360,000 and $ 480,000. For a single span: $ 120,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DangerousFuel     11-29 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dangerous Fuel,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Service Station Mistakenly Sells Gasoline-Tainted Kerosene</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police used loudspeakers and flyers Monday to warn residents about a dangerous mixture of gas and kerosene that mistakenly was sold for use in space heaters. The fuel could cause fire or explosion if used in heating devices, Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> said. `` We've got squad cars going up and down streets in two police districts using their public address systems to warn people, and officers are handing out flyers to people on the street,'' <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> said. `` We're also getting very good cooperation from radio and television stations,'' he said. On Saturday, a fuel company delivered gas to a <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> service station, but mistakenly poured 1,640 gallons into a kerosene tank, <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> said. `` They did n't discover the error until early Monday,'' the lieutenant said, `` but they estimate that there were about 4,100 gallons of kerosene in the tank. `` That would make the mix about three-to-one,'' <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> said. `` The owner estimates they sold from 730 to 800 gallons of the kerosene before learning that there was gasoline in it.'' By late Monday night, consumers had returned at least 200 gallons to the station, and only one minor fire had been linked to the mixture, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrucialChoice Bjt   11-29 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crucial Choice, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tokyo Envoy Rivals Cabinet Slot in Importance</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GENE KRAMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least one of the 100-odd American ambassadors that President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must select could rank in importance with many of the Cabinet choices now drawing most of the nation's attention. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must select the successor to former <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leader <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON>, retiring after a record 11 years as ambassador to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The job is important simply because <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has become so important to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in the late 20th Century. Together the two countries account for 40 to 50 percent of world economic output. They have one of the world's most complex, emotionally-charged and changing relationships. <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> calls the U.S.-Japanese relationship the most important in the world and says that during his tenure in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> it has changed from that of uncle-nephew to brother-brother. Complicating the love-hate feelings often felt between the countries are deep cultural and language differences and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s new world importance. In only four decades, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has transformed itself from a humble, defeated <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> enemy to a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> protege and loyal ally, an economic superpower and rival, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> creditor, landlord and occasional critic. During the election campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took positions on issues such as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s military and foreign aid role and trade. To demands that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> increase military spending and relieve some of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense burden, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ a bomber pilot against <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in World War II _ noted that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> neighbors still remember the war and `` remain very sensitive to the issue of Japanese rearmament.'' He suggested that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> rapidly boost its share of global economic aid, a category in which it is about to surpass the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But that, too, could create other conflicts, because <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is already becoming a rival to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dominance of such international institutions as the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. On trade, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to take President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s general line of seeking to brake protectionist efforts to restrict Japanese imports into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> while encouraging sharpened <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> competitiveness. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, the Japanese prime minister from 1982-87, developed a first-name relationship unprecedented in the two countries' history. Their personal connection helped the nations weather a rough period marked by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure against Japanese domestic barriers, alleged unfair trade practices and insular thinking inappropriate for a country grown rich by exporting. <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>'s successor, said during a White House visit that he also had gotten on a first-name basis with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president. <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> news reports say he hopes to visit <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> early in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> presidency to cultivate the same kind of relations. After 14 years as <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democratic leader, <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> was sent to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> by Democratic President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>. In 1981 <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> asked him to stay in the increasingly important post. Announcing his retirement, <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> said he felt he could leave `` with our heads high.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, accounting for $ 57 billion of a global deficit of $ 170 billion in 1987, is finally narrowing, he said, as a result of hard-bargained market-openings, the costlier yen and cheaper dollar and efforts by <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> to boost Japanese domestic consumption and imports. But new flareups can be expected between two countries that have such different backgrounds but are now so economically interdependent. Pressure from the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies to shoulder more defense costs promises to affect U.S.-Japanese relations. Members ask why the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with all its deficit problems should spend 6 percent of gross national product on defense, while <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> devotes just 1 percent of its wealth to the same purpose. But <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials dispute the idea that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> enjoys a `` free ride,'' arguing that it provides the bulk of the destroyers and combat jets in <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, that its military budget of $ 30 billion a year is already higher than that of any other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally, and that its contribution of $ 45,000 to the annual upkeep of each of the 55,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel based in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the most generous in the world. Tension also continues over an issue raised by presidential contender <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and other Democrats, the `` buying up of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' in the form of Japanese investments in prime <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> real estate and factories. Defenders such as <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> ask why nobody complains about <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s $ 75 billion worth of direct investment in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, compared to Japanese investments of $ 33 billion. Names mentioned as early candidates for the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> post include <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Armacost </PERSON>, undersecretary of state for political affairs, who has served in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigur </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for East Asian and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> affairs; and <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> governor instrumental in bringing Japanese factories to his state. Economic relations between <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> `` are so large and so crucial to both countries that unless we manage them intelligently, we could be facing a crisis of enormous dimensions,'' says <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> programs at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, a Washington-based private research organization. `` If the Japanese did n't buy our <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bonds, our debt would be simply unmanageable,'' <PERSON> Weinstein </PERSON> says. `` No other country is in that position.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> covers international affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-29 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Ink in Farm Trade More Than Doubles</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm exports soared to a six-year peak of 147.5 million metric tons in the year that ended Sept. 30, and black ink in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural trade doubled to more than $ 14 billion, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was again the top customer of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> farmer, as it has been for more than two decades, according to figures released Monday. American farm exports climbed from $ 27.87 billion in fiscal 1987 to $ 35.2 billion this past fiscal year, a gain of 26 percent, while imports of farm products were up 2 percent to a record $ 21 billion, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was thus left with a net agricultural trade surplus of $ 14.2 billion for fiscal 1988, compared with $ 7.22 billion a year earlier. Volume of exports climbed 14 percent from the 129.2 million metric tons posted in fiscal 1987, with wheat accounting for two-thirds of the increase, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said. A metric ton is equivalent to about 2,205 pounds. Exports of wheat increased from 28.2 million metric tons in 1987 to 40.5 million tons in the last fiscal year. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> together purchased a total of 14.6 million tons, or 36 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat shipments in fiscal 1988. Combined imports by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> totaled 4.95 million metric tons of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> wheat in 1987, or 18 percent of all shipments. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> imported 27.8 million metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agricultural goods. Other leading purchasers were: the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, 25.5 million metric tons; the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, 15.9 million metric tons; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, 8 million; and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, 7.3 million. Besides wheat, substantial gains were posted by corn, grain sorghum, feeds and fodders and vegetable oils. Among products not measured on the basis of metric tons, the biggest gains were in baby chicks, live animals, fruit juices, wines and malt beverages. The increases were moderated, however, by weakened foreign demand for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soybeans, soybean meal and rice. All of the nation's leading foreign markets for farm goods grew in fiscal 1988 except that of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, whose imports dropped nearly 1.1 million metric tons. The decrease mainly reflected fewer purchases of soybean and soybean meal. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> were among the five fastest-growing markets for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> agriculture, joining <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. American high-value exports such as livestock and horticultural products climbed to a record $ 16.4 billion in 1988, a gain of $ 2.7 billion or 19 percent over the 1987 level. It also represented a $ 1.1 billion gain over the previous peak, reached in 1981. Shipments of bulk commodities such as grains zoomed 33 percent from 1987 to a total of $ 18.8 billion. The level topped $ 25 billion in 1984 before immense crop surpluses and stiffer foreign competition battered prices and sent <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> agriculture into the doldrums. Expanded purchases of wheat and corn were the main reason for the increase, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said. It said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> were the leading markets for wheat and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, while the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> were tops for corn. Agricultural imports of $ 21 billion were some $ 250 million or 2 percent above the 1987 level and about $ 100 million over the 1986 mark of $ 20.9 billion, the previous record high. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said the increase was not limited to any single commodity group but instead reflected modest increases in nearly all major competitive items. Top suppliers were: the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.12 billion; <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, $ 2.37 billion; <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, $ 1.9 billion; <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, $ 1.9 billion and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, $ 1.15 billion. Products reflecting increases were vegetable oil, live cattle, beef and veal, wines and malt beverages and nursery products. Imports of sugar, pork, fur, coffee and spices all dropped.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Bearings     11-29 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Bearings,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Opts Against Limitation on Bearing Imports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The domestic bearing industry is operating at or near 100 percent capacity, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration said in declining to limit imports of the friction-reducing components from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The decision, announced Monday, follows a joint study by the Commerce and <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> departments. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had found separately in July that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bearing manufacturers would not be able to meet `` all national security requirements in the event of a major conventional war.'' But President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in August tentatively ruled out limits until the joint study could be completed. The administration wanted to ensure that the domestic bearing industry would be sufficiently healthy to meet production needs in the event of an emergency, without the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> having to rely on outside suppliers. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the joint study found that conditions in the domestic bearing industry had improved signficantly in the last several months. His statement said that it was concluded that `` administration initiatives should be adequate to bring the domestic industrial base into an acceptable posture for national security purposes.'' Commerce Secretary <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Verity </PERSON> said in a statement that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision was made `` after a thorough review of the impact of bearing imports on national security.'' `` While recognizing the critical importance of bearings to defense preparedness, other administration initiatives already under way _ coupled with significantly improved economic conditions for the industry _ make me confident that this is the right decision,'' he said. The decision against moving to curb imports of bearings was based on these conclusions of the government investigators: _ Current demand for bearings in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is at its highest level in recent years, particularly as bearing-consuming industries such as automobiles, aerospace and off-road equipment experience heavy sales increases _ The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bearing industry has benefited from substantial increases in domestic demand and is operating at or near 100 percent of capacity _ The industry has attracted `` significant investment'' from both domestic - and foreign-owned _ A change in <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> acquisition guidelines last August, which now require the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> to use only domestic industries for the purchase of bearings for defense-related equipment This could provide the domestic industry with an estimated $ 40 million to $ 50 million in additional revenue for domestic suppliers. In a separate and unrelated action, the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it was `` aggressively pursuing'' an investigation of alleged unfair trade practices by foreign suppliers of anti-friction bearings. `` Our preliminary findings indicate dumping margins in the 20 to 80 percent range,'' <ORGANIZATION> Verity </ORGANIZATION> said. `` If the final results of this investigation verify these margins, the duties imposed could contribute to leveling the playing field for this important industry.'' He said that a final determination on the issue of dumping of bearings by foreign competitors in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market will be due Jan. 9, and a decision will be made 45 days later on what kind of actions to take. Dumping is the selling of a product in a foreign market at a price lower than the domestic price.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fitzwater     11-29 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fitzwater,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veteran Public Affairs Official Remains On White House Job</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, signed on for another hitch as <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, says President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` will have new ways of dealing with the press'' that may include more informal meetings with reporters. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, 46, has been President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief spokesman since February 1987 and was Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s press secretary for two years before that. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, making his first appearance in the White House press briefing room since his election Nov. 8, announced Monday that he is retaining <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. It is the first time the press secretary of an outgoing president has been named permanently to the job in a new administration, although <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinger </PERSON> served President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> for an interim after President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s assassination. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> declined to say how frequently <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would hold presidential news conferences, saying: `` The vice president has been holding press conferences at the rate of one every five hours for the last few weeks, so we'll have to see how that works out. `` The new president, I'm sure, will have new ways of dealing with the press. I'm sure there will be all kinds of interviews and press conferences and meetings.'' When a reporter observed that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> seems more comfortable than <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in freewheeling give-and-take with reporters, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` I would agree with you that the president-elect is comfortable with the press, he does operate informally quite effectively.'' `` So I would suspect you might see a lot more informal _,'' the spokesman said, at which point his response was cut off by a reporter's question as to what he would recommend in the way of news conferences. `` I wo n't talk about all the things I've recommended and not recommended, but we'll just have to wait and see,'' he said. `` I think there should be as much contact with the press as possible and it should be as regular as possible,'' the spokesman said. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> is a veteran public affairs official whose federal career began in 1972 when he was a speechwriter for Secretary of Transportation <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Volpe </PERSON>. Before that, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had worked for newspapers in his native <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. `` I think he's the best,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` He represents the old and the new. He represents the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and he also represents the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. ... This is continuity in the best sense.'' When asked if he would hold more frequent news conferences than <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the president-elect said, `` I ` m going to lean heavily on <LOCATION> Marlin </LOCATION> for advice on this.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>'s present title is assistant to the president for press relations. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that in the new administration <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> will be press secretary, a title held now by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, who was wounded in the 1981 assassination attempt on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. When asked whether <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> would have a role in the new administration, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, `` I know the vice president is very interested in <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and concerned about his well-being'' and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his advisers `` have some ideas of things they would like him to do.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> would remain <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s press secretary through the transition, and he would take over on Jan. 20. Ms. <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> has said she plans to leave government. After <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> left the briefing room, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> opened his presentation with a few words of gratitude to the president-elect and president. Then a reporter asked him, `` Well, will you keep avoiding briefings and will you promise to hold more news conferences?'' `` A two-minute honeymoon,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` Amazing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GrainDeal     11-29 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grain Deal,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>US-Soviet Grain Agreement Extended for 27 Months</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration hailed the new U.S.-Soviet grain agreement as providing a steady market for American farm products, but a congressman from <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s wheat belt said the deal sold growers short. The plan `` stabilizes grain trade between our two countries by ensuring a secure source of supply for Soviet grain imports and secure market for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain exports,'' said a statement from <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmer </PERSON>, chief of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> delegation to the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> meetings. Under a 27-month extension of the long-term agreement between the two nations, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is promising to buy at the equivalent of at least 9 million metric tons annually of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grain. A metric ton equals about 2,205 pounds. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet negotiators signed the extension in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on Monday, breathing new life into a five-year plan that helped to turn the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> into one of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farmer's best customers. That agreement had expired Sept. 30. `` The extension will continue to stabilize grain trade between the two countries, benefiting American farmers,'' Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said in a statement. The agreement calls for the Soviets to buy at least 4 million metric tons each of wheat and corn annually as well as 1 million metric tons of additional wheat, corn, soybeans and soybean meal, or any combination of those commodities. The Soviets also are allowed to purchase up to 3 million metric tons of additional wheat and corn annually without further discussions. Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s subcommittee on wheat, soybeans and feed grains, said the pact has `` done nothing more than maintain the current agreement. `` This was an historic opportunity with one of our most important grain clients and all we can say is we did n't lose any ground,'' he said. `` That simply is n't good enough.'' `` This administration has driven down the price of grain in order to export more, but they do n't seem to be able to close the deal,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the Soviets bought 9.05 million tons of wheat, 5.18 million tons of corn, 830,700 tons of soybeans and 1.3 million tons of soybean meal for delivery in the fifth and final year of the current agreement. The Soviets purchased <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat for the final year and a half of the old agreement at federally subsidized prices under the government's Export Enhancement Program, designed to offset competition from the European Community and other suppliers. Under the 1985 program, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> pays private exporters in kind out of stocks held by the government-owned <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> to ship the grain at highly attractive prices. There are no dollar estimates for these sales. A provision of the old plan carried over into the new version allows the Soviets to count one ton of soybeans or soybean meal as two tons and thus round out their purchase obligation by buying 500,000 tons of those commodities rather than a million tons of wheat or corn. `` In general our impression is favorable,'' <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON> said. `` It's a continuation of what we had before, which worked fairly well.'' <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION>, said his members were pleased with the agreement but had hoped that the amounts would have been a bit larger. In any case, he said, the plan was likely to have less effect on prices than will lingering problems caused by the drought. He said markets mainly would be relieved to get some assurance of continued Soviet demand. `` It's like a security blanket for some people,'' <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SenateLeader-Profiles     11-29 1012</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Leader-Profiles,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidates for Leadership of U.S. Senate</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Following are profiles of the three candidates in today's
election of the next Senate majority leader:
^With PM-Senate Leader Bjt</NOTE>
<HEAD>GEORGE M. MITCHELL: Made His Name in Iran-Contra Hearings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> eight years ago as an appointee who had never won election to public office. But the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Democrat has since proven himself a popular vote-getter, a thoughtful lawmaker and a telegenic party spokesman. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, a former federal judge, won praise for his incisive questioning of witnesses before the Iran-Contra investigating panel last year. He also hushed the hearing room with a statement as dramatic as the emotional testimony of Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. `` Although he's regularly asked to do so, God does not take sides in <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> politics,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> lectured the Marine. `` And in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, disagreement with the policies of the government is not evidence of lack of patriotism.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s Iran-Contra performance solidified his status as a potential majority leader. He was first mentioned for the job in 1986 when, as the hard-working head of the Democrats' senatorial campaign committee, he led his party back to control of the chamber. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, 55, had less legislative experience than his two opponents for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority leader and was perceived as more liberal. As chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s environmental protection subcommittee, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> led a losing fight this year for an anti-pollution bill designed to reduce acid rain, smog and airborne toxic chemicals. His powerful opponents included the current <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority leader, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> also chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s health panel and has proposed a major long-term health care initiative. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> was appointed to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1980 to succeed <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Muskie </PERSON>, whom he had served as an executive assistant two decades earlier. He won election in 1982 with 61 percent of the vote and garnered 81 percent this year. The son of a utility company laborer and a Lebanese immigrant mother who worked the midnight shift at a woolen mill for 27 years, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Bowdoin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, spent two years as an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> intelligence officer and worked as an insurance claims adjuster while attending night classes at <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law school. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> lost a 1974 bid to become governor of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. He was appointed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for the state in 1977 and two years later was named to a new federal judgeship in <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>By Jill Lawrence</HEAD>
<HEAD>DANIEL K. INOUYE: A Deep-Voiced Presence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, the most senior of three candidates for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority leader, is known for his solemn, deep-voiced presence which commands attention whether during a floor debate or at a hearing. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, who has been a senator since 1962, earned national prominence first as keynote speaker at the Democratic National Convention in 1968, then gained added respect as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watergate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> in 1973. But the gloss was dulled somewhat last year when <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> was criticized for not keeping a firm enough handle on hearings before the Iran-Contra investigating panel he helped chair. In that post and as former <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman and a senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> has prided himself on being able to work closely with Republicans. But he also has been a party loyalist, backing President <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s Vietnam War policy and defending Sen. <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, in 1981 against expulsion in the Abscam case. His colleagues made him secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, the No. 3 party leadership position, leading many to rank him a year ago as the top prospect to succeed <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> as majority leader. But in recent months, <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>'s chances seemed to fade as some _ particularly newer senators _ searched for a less ponderous figure to represent their numbers on television. Last year, <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> was embarrassed after it was revealed that he had slipped into a money bill $ 8 million for a school in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> for North African Jews. He later was forced to rescind the provision. In recent years, his voting record has tended toward the liberal side: he has favored gun control, sanctions against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and limits on political action committee contributions to candidates. He has opposed the Star Wars defense system and aid to the Nicaraguan Contras.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>By Jim Drinkard</HEAD>
<HEAD>J. BENNETT JOHNSTON: Cagey in the Senate's Back Rooms</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> is an accomplished power broker with a reputation of knowing how to swing legislative deals while protecting his own interests. The Louisianan is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and of the energy and water development appropriations subcommittee, posts from which he watches out for his state and its energy industry. That was seen by some observers as a possible disadvantage in his race for majority leader, since the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> already is led by another oil and gas advocate, Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. While known for an easygoing, quotable style, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> is quick to master details of legislation, has a strong grasp of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> procedure and is considered a cagey backroom deal-maker. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> was more conservative than either of his two rivals for majority leader. During his second term, he was a leading opponent of court-ordered busing to desegregate schools. But he now casts himself as a centrist. He dramatically came out against President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nomination of conservative <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> last year, supported a bill aimed at reducing pollution that causes global warming, and fought <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s efforts to finance the Star Wars missile defense system. In the majority leader's race, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> sold himself as the candidate most likely to appeal to <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and thus as the best standard-bearer for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. He picked up endorsements from two of the party's stars, Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Now 56, <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> entered the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1973 after a nine-year career in the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> state legislature.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>By Alan Fram</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Environment-Farm     11-29 0493</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Environment-Farm,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Environmental Concerns to Influence Farm Bills</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmental concerns are likely to influence the next comprehensive farm bill and threaten some farmers' incomes unless agricultural interests adopt reforms on their own, a researcher says Farmers must `` modify programs, or agriculture must be prepared to face environmental legislation,'' says <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichelderfer </PERSON>, coauthor of a paper released Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> and Agricultural Policy. The center is part of the environmental research organization Resources for the Future. The study noted that 37 states have passed or are considering legislation aimed at agricultural contamination of water. Agriculture is already the largest source of some pollution, such as nutrients reaching waterways. Pesticides have been found, for example, in 40 percent of the wells in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. The paper surveyed existing research documenting environmental harm from farming as practiced today with massive government involvement in restricting acreage, supporting farm income and controlling supply. Growing environmental concern could mean modification of farm subsidy programs or new environmental controls that could reduce the income of some farmers, the study said. `` The net effect of the current combination of farm program instruments include the following: More acreage is retained in the agricultural sector than would be the case in the absence of farm programs, but less acreage is cultivated and agricultural chemical use rates and crop yields per acre are higher,'' the study said. Ending all price support programs while keeping current conservation requirements would `` increase the number of acres planted to crops, but would result in environmentally beneficial relocation and mix of production activities, with less intensive and less damaging use of agricultural chemicals on expanded acreage,'' it said. However, `` farm income would decline, agricultural exports would fall and rural communities and agribusiness interests would suffer.'' <PERSON> Reichelderfer </PERSON> said the environmental benefits `` probably -LRB- would -RRB- not'' outweigh the costs. Nonetheless, `` polls have shown what I consider a rather dramatic increase in public concern about agricultural sources of pollution, particularly contamination of drinking water sources,'' she said. `` You're probably going to see even more participation by the environmental community'' in shaping the next farm bill, tentatively on the congressional agenda for 1990, said the study's other author, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Phipps </PERSON>. Environmentalists were influential in adding the `` sodbuster'' and `` swampbuster'' provisions to the 1985 bill, forbidding subsidies to farmers who convert grasslands and swamps to crops, and in fashioning the conservation reserve, aimed at retiring 45 million acres of erodible land from production through rent payments to farmers who convert it to grassland or forest for 10 years. The paper discussed in detail three possible modifications to current programs: removing the link between production and income support that current commodity-oriented price supports provide; gradually ending all price supports; and expansion of the conservation reserve. Other possibilities mentioned were taxes on pesticides, subsidies to encourage so-called `` low input'' farming or low-chemical `` integrated pest management,'' and more research on alternatives to chemical-dependent farming.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-29 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON> says working with veteran actors such as <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> is a learning experience. `` What you get from great actors like <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> is where to focus your energies and what to worry about and what not to worry about,'' <PERSON> Cruise </PERSON> said. `` Because as a young actor, you're worried about everything.'' Cruise, 26, starred with <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> in `` The Color of Money,'' and with <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> in the to-be-released `` Rain Man.'' In `` Rain Man,'' the 51-year-old <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> plays an autistic man with remarkable powers of memory and a $ 3 million inheritance. Cruise plays his brother, who wants the money. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, known as a hard-working perfectionist on a movie set, says Cruise is equally driven. `` He's a demon. He gets up early, he works out, he goes home early, he studies, he works out again at night. ... And he always wanted to rehearse,'' <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> said in December's Gentlemen's Quarterly
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge dismissed <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'s libel suit against a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> woman who filed a paternity suit against the comedian. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON> threw out <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'s lawsuit Monday for lack of personal jurisdiction. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> last year sued <PERSON> Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>, alleging libel, invasion of privacy, copyright infringement and unjust enrichment, over a live stage production `` Oh Jackie Oh,'' on which they collaborated. Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON>'s paternity lawsuit in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is pending. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, declined comment on Monday's ruling, saying he had not yet seen it There was no answer at the <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> offices of Ms. <PERSON> Reiter </PERSON>'s lawyers when called for comment Monday evening.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tahnee </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> says it was difficult growing up as the child of a sex symbol, but she does n't fault her mother, <PERSON> Raquel </PERSON>. `` She's a hard worker. She's always taken care of herself. My mother has never, never, never been supported by anyone,'' the 26-year-old <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said. `` So I had it in my mind that I had to do it myself. I have this pride.'' The younger <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> insists she won her part in the 1985 film, `` Cocoon,'' on merit, not because of her mother. <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> also appears in the recently released `` Cocoon: The Return.'' `` They said I never paid my dues,'' <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> said in an interview in December's Gentlemen's Quarterly. `` It's like what I was doing did n't count. Like I cheated. But the point is not the advantages I had but what I'm doing with them.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Duke and Duchess of York picked the historic <ORGANIZATION> Chapel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> James </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION> for the Dec. 20 christening of their infant daughter, Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON>. The chapel was the site of the wedding of Queen <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> and Prince <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> in 1840 and where royal christenings occasionally have taken place. Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, fifth in line to the throne and the fifth grandchild of Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, will wear the royal family's christening robe of <LOCATION> Honiton </LOCATION> lace and will be baptized at the silver gilt Lily Font, Buckingham Palace said Monday. Princess <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON>, born Aug. 8, is the first child of Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, the queen's second son, and the former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>. The royal couple chose <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Habgood </PERSON>, the archbishop of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and second-ranking prelate in the Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, to christen their daughter.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doubleday has acquired the English publishing rights to 14 books by <PERSON> Naguib </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahfouz </PERSON>, the Egyptian writer who won the 1988 Nobel Prize in literature, and to a book on architecture by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON>, a Doubleday editor, and <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Vitale </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Bantam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doubleday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, who lived in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> for many years, acquired the rights to <PERSON> Mahfouz </PERSON>'s works from <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cairo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, the publishing house said. It was not immediately known how much Doubleday paid to acquire the English rights to the works by <PERSON> Mahfouz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>. The publishing house could not be reached after office hours Monday for comment. <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON> said last week that the company will publish 14 books by the 77-year-old <PERSON> Mahfouz </PERSON>, the first writer in the Arabic language to win the Nobel Prize in literature. It will publish a collection of his short stories and 13 of his novels, four of which have never been published in English. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>' book, `` A Vision of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>: A Personal View of Architecture,'' is based on his recent television documentary, which sharply criticized modern architecture in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The British publishing rights were acquired by <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON> <LOCATION> U.K. </LOCATION>, a division of <ORGANIZATION> Transworld </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     11-29 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 29,318.30 points, up 334.98 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CrashVictims     11-29 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crash Victims,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Offers Help Pour In for Young Suvivors Of Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VALLEY CITY, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Callers from around the country have offered money, stuffed animals and other help for three young children who survived a car-train crash that killed their parents and three siblings, officials said. Two funds also were opened for 6-year-old <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, his brother <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON>, 4, and sister <PERSON> Melinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON>, 5. Their parents, <PERSON> Arlynn </PERSON>, 41, and <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 29, died last week when a freight train smashed into their car at a fog-covered railroad crossing five miles west of <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Also killed were the children's brother <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, 9, and two sisters, 15-month-old <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> and 6-week-old <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>. `` I have gotten calls from all over the country,'' said <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Pederson </PERSON>, a nursing supervisor at <LOCATION> Mercy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> remained hospitalized Monday in good condition. <PERSON> Melinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> remained in critical condition Monday in <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fargo </LOCATION> Family members said she has had at least three operations for severe head injuries and has a badly broken arm. In addition to the telephone inquiries, the two funds started for the children have raised about $ 900. <ORGANIZATION> Mercy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> employees contributed about $ 200 to buy <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> savings bonds for the children, said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoltz </PERSON>, a hospital supervisor. Another $ 700 has come into a separate trust at <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, spokesman <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. The Nelson boys' hospital room also is filled with gifts, <PERSON> Stoltz </PERSON> said. `` They have seven or eight stuffed animals apiece, balloons and toys ... lots of toys,'' she said. `` About the only thing they're running out of is batteries. The two boys were released from the hospital briefly Saturday for the family's funeral in <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, authorities said. The boys remain hospitalized only because arrangements about who they will live with have not been decided, <PERSON> Barb </PERSON> <PERSON> Roeber </PERSON>, patient services director, said Monday. The children's maternal grandmother, <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunze </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, is their guardian and has been making medical decisions for them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Picasso Bjt   11-29 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Picasso, Bjt,0662</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Department Store Buys Picasso's `Acrobat And Young
Harlequin'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Japanese department store said today that it bought <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>'s `` Acrobat and Young Harlequin'' for a record $ 38.46 million and plans to sell the Rose Period masterpiece to a buyer in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The pink-and-rose painting of two circus performers sold Monday for the highest price ever paid at auction for a work of art created in this century. It also was the third most expensive work of art ever auctioned. It is surpassed only by two late 19th century paintings by <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON> sold in 1987, `` Irises'' at $ 53.9 million and `` Sunflowers'' at $ 41.3 million. <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Mitsukoshi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Store </ORGANIZATION>, said in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> that its representative <PERSON> Akio </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishino </PERSON> bought the <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON> painting at the <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s auction in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on behalf of the store. `` We bought the painting expecting to sell it to a private buyer here in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON> said. But he said the store, which is a major importer of art into <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, had not decided on specific plans for displaying or selling the painting. <PERSON> Nishino </PERSON> left the crowded saleroom after buying the painting and slumped in a chair in a private room for 20 minutes. He did n't speak to reporters but wore a big smile. A director said the man was emotionally exhausted. `` We offered him a glass of champagne but he did n't like it and had <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> instead,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrey </PERSON>, spokesman for the auction house. `` The buyer told me he had bought a most wonderful masterpiece. He did n't question the price _ he was very excited.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s imports of art and curios have ballooned in recent years as increasingly affluent Japanese turn to collecting as a form of investment. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Yasuda </ORGANIZATION> Fire and <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> bought <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>'s `` Sunflowers'' when it was sold at <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in March 1987 Dealers estimate that at least 30 percent of worldwide art sales are to Japanese buyers, often large corporations that buy for tax-free investment purposes. <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON> painted `` Acrobat and Young Harlequin'' in 1905 in his <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> attic studio at 13 rue Ravignon using gouache, an opaque watercolor easier to handle than oil paint. After being shown in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> in 1905, it found its way into a German museum and was confiscated by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> in 1937 as an example of decadent art. They sold it at auction in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> to a Belgian collector, and it had been in private hands since. Bidding on Monday opened at $ 9.2 million, and the painting sold in 3 -LCB- minutes. The selling price topped the previous record for a 20th century painting, $ 24.75 million paid for <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>'s `` Maternity'' Nov. 14 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Auctioneer <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Allsopp </PERSON> said the price was not exorbitant. `` By any standard, <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON> was the towering figure of art in this century. This picture was from his Rose Period, which is usually considered his best, and it's the last great work of that series likely to come on the market,'' <PERSON> Allsopp </PERSON> said. `` In the 27 years I've been here, it has gripped more people and people with a greater variety of tastes than any previous picture. It has had practically no detractors _ even among those who do n't like <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>. A picture by the French Impressionist <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Monet </PERSON>, `` The Railroad Bridge at <LOCATION> Argenteuil </LOCATION>,'' sold for $ 12.55 million, also joining the list of the 10 most expensive works of art sold at auction. In June 28, another <ORGANIZATION> Monet </ORGANIZATION> painting, `` In the Field,'' sold at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> for $ 24.90 million. Monday's auction of 60 works by 40 artists brought $ 102.01 million, a record for an Impressionist and modern art sale in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Individual records were set for works by <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauguin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Giacometti </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Klee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Signac </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Paintings-Top10     11-29 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Paintings-Top 10,0222</SECOND>
<HEAD>10 Most Expensive Paintings Sold At Christie's And Sotheby's</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Picasso</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Following is a current list of the top 10 prices paid for paintings at the world's two major auction houses, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s and <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s: 1. `` Irises'' by <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>; $ 53.90 million, sold by <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Nov. 11, 1987. 2. `` Sunflowers'' by <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>; $ 41.3 million, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, March 31, 1987. 3. `` Acrobat and Young Harlequin'' by <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>; $ 38.46 million -LRB- record for a 20th-century work -RRB-, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, Nov. 28, 1988. 4. `` Maternity'' by <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>; $ 24.75 million, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Nov. 14, 1988. 5. `` In the Field'' by <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Monet </PERSON>; $ 24.90 million, sold by <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, June 28, 1988. 6. `` The Trinquetalle Bridge'' by <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>; $ 20.24 million, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, June 29, 1987. 7. `` False Start'' by <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>; $ 17.05 million -LRB- record for a living artist -RRB-, sold by <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Nov. 10, 1988. 8. `` Bird Cage'' by <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>, $ 15.4 million, sold by <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, Nov. 10, 1988. 9. `` Portrait of <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravoux </PERSON>'' by <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Gogh </PERSON>; $ 13.75 million, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, May 11, 1988. 10. `` The Railroad Bridge at <LOCATION> Argenteuil </LOCATION>,'' by <ORGANIZATION> Monet </ORGANIZATION>, $ 12.55 million, sold by <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, Nov. 28. 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Guatemala-Massacre     11-29 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guatemala-Massacre,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Says 21 Bodies Found Over Weekend Were Tortured, Strangled</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALFONSO ANZUETO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY, Guatemala (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty peasants and a civilian liaison officer were tortured and burned before they were strangled by leftist guerrillas last week, an army spokesman said. The guerrillas' coalition denied that rebels were responsible and blamed the army for the massacre. The victims, found Saturday night in common graves near <LOCATION> Chimaltenango </LOCATION>, about 50 miles west of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, were tortured before they were killed, army spokesman Col. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> said on Monday. He denied a report that the victims were members of a death squad and repeated government claims that guerrillas were responsible. The government said on Sunday that guerrillas killed <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON> <PERSON> Callejas </PERSON>, a civilian who worked with the military in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aguacate </LOCATION> town and who disappeared last Wednesday. It said the guerrillas then massacred 20 friends and relatives who organized a search party Friday and went looking for him. In a statement distributed in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guatemala </ORGANIZATION>, a guerrilla umbrella organization, called the government charges `` totally and absolutely false'' and said the army was trying to cover up involvement in the killings. Troops found the bodies, the government said. One officer was reported wounded in a skirmish with rebels before the bodies were discovered. The army and government blamed the killings on guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arms </ORGANIZATION>, which, with the <ORGANIZATION> Rebel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Guerrilla </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> of the Poor, form the coalition battling the U.S.-backed government. <PERSON> Isaacs </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> said the victims `` did n't have bullet wounds ... but suffered torture and finally were strangled to death. Some had burns on the hands and -LRB- their bodies -RRB- were partially burned.'' He said the remains were taken Monday to the <LOCATION> Chimaltenango </LOCATION> army base for identification and would be turned over to family members. The victims included at least 12 relatives of <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON> <PERSON> Callejas </PERSON>, the government said. <PERSON> Guerra </PERSON> <PERSON> Callejas </PERSON> and other civilians contracted by the military often wield considerable power in rural Guatemalan communities. Some have been accused of involvement in human rights abuses. The 20 peasants killed lived in the hamlet of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Andres </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iztapa </LOCATION>. Mayor <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> on Monday declared a three-day period of mourning.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881129-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-29-88 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Salvador     11-29 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Claim 266 Government Casualties</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
