<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0432EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--LaundrySlots     03-01 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Laundry Slots,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Slots Banned In Laundries</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Slot machines line the walls of supermarkets and bars in this gaming resort, but they do n't belong in doughnut shops or laundries, officials decided. <ORGANIZATION> Clark </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioners </ORGANIZATION> voted Monday to prohibit new slot machine licenses for machines in laundries, bakeries, doughnut shops, fast-food restaurants, movie theaters and professional offices. Existing licenses are not affected. Several owners of self-service laundries said they depend on slot machine revenue to cover the high cost of doing business, with the slots generating about 25 percent of revenues. Other laundry owners stressed that customers need something to do to keep occupied while their clothes spin and tumble. Commissioners said it is too hard to regulate the machines if they are allowed to continue to proliferate in different businesses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 4thLd-Writethru a0888 03-01 0980</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 4th Ld - Writethru, a0888,1008</SECOND>
<HEAD>Violence in Second Day of General Strike</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New grafs 1-20 UPDATE with Zuniga beaten, freed, other
details. Pick up 15th graf pvs: Journalists saw ... with deletions
to trim and conform</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Plainclothes police stormed a building housing an opposition party office and its radio station Tuesday, setting off a rock-throwing protest by foes of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s military rule. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, leader and presidential candidate of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, was beaten and arrested. <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, owner of Radio 10-FM, was released hours later. The plainclothes police and later a riot squad fired dozens of shots into the air to disperse the crowd outside the building. The brawl occurred as an anti-Noriega strike called by the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crusade </ORGANIZATION> entered its second day and appeared to be picking up support. Witnesses, who spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of reprisals, said plainclothes police with shotguns and pistols rushed into the Popular Action building on <ORGANIZATION> Via </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espana </ORGANIZATION>, smashing furniture and equipment inside the radio station. Radio 10-FM was under censorship orders to play only music, but had been broadcasting news supporting the strike. An angry crowd gathered outside the building and started throwing rocks at the officers. An unidentified radio station employee was slightly injured. Leaders of the Civil Crusade, a coalition of 180 business, professional, labor, student and political groups, told a news conference Tuesday night the strike shut down 85 percent of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economic activity. They said 90 percent of industry and construction were paralyzed. They conceded that transportation was down by only 10 percent, but said retail commerce was 40 percent of normal. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Lastra </PERSON>, a Crusade leader and a strike organizer, said `` this demonstrates the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people's repudiation of the dictatorship of Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and the fervent desire for complete democracy. The government, through some of the news media it controls, has been calling the strike `` a complete failure,'' alleging business and transportation were functioning normally. The young security men at the radio station, dressed in jeans and T-shirts, outnumbered the protesters and broke up the demonstration after 40 minutes. The demonstrators were banging pots and pans in the streets and distributing leaflets. At least four men were punched, kicked and beaten with rubber truncheons during the melee as they were arrested and shoved into police vehicles. Two women were among those arrested on Via <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, an upper middle-class neighborhood. They were not beaten, but one was slapped on the buttocks as she was hustled into a car. At first only about 15 demonstrators from the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> were involved at the radio station building, but the crowd swelled to about 150 when residents came out on balconies or sidewalks to join in beating pans. Many people bolted for cover, however, when security agents came to screeching stops in 4-wheel-drive Toyotas. The agents jumped out and began shooting. Some residents returned to balconies from time to time, shouting `` Murderers!'' and `` Cowards!'' <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, leader of Popular Action, was beaten and shoved into a vehicle. The car was blocked by another vehicle and <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON>, a white-haired man of about 60, fled down the street with his torn shirt fluttering and security men in pursuit. Bystanders created interference and <PERSON> Zuniga </PERSON> dived into a car that sped away, but he was caught later. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, ousted as president last week by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, remained in hiding Tuesday. He predicted serious economic trouble. <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s successor, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of `` lies and defamation'' about <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, the 17,000-member military and police organization commanded by <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the real power behind the civilian government. Journalists saw at least three people wounded by birdshot fired by either the plainclothes agents or soldiers who arrived later. One man was bleeding from the head, but did not seem to be seriously injured. Calm was reported elsewhere in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. By midafternoon, the strike had drastically thinned traffic and the crowds on the streets. Strike leaders said 12 Panamanian-owned banks were closed. Most international banks opened, but did comparatively little business. Only one employee and five guards occupied the main area of the large <ORGANIZATION> Chase </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> branch. The scenes were similar at <ORGANIZATION> Citibank </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION>. Some international institutions shut down, including the Bank of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s replacement, inaugurated a new session of the <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> with an anti-American speech. The assembly, which <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> controls, dismissed <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> last Friday. `` <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has been the victim of the most violent and terrible campaign of lies and defamation that any leader has ever received,'' <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> said. He accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and opponents of the government of `` the clear political intention of bringing ill repute on the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> Defense Forces.'' He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` wants to asphyxiate the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people economically.'' <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been `` a traditional enemy'' of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` They send to our country destabilizing agents who try to sow chaos in a nation that let its entrails be opened to serve the world,'' he said in a reference to the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. Panamanian officials have claimed protests at home and the indictment of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> on drug charges in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> are the work of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> conservatives who oppose the 1977 treaties under which the canal is to be turned over to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on Dec. 31, 1999. In a videotape of <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> distributed by his associates, the former president pledged to remain in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and continue resistance to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. He said the crisis would make it impossible for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to get new loans from abroad and described the country as `` totally bankrupt.'' <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> predicted the lack of credit would force the government to raise taxes, which he said `` will increase unemployment and social unrest.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     03-01 0692</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Accepts First Drug Testing Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mandatory drug testing in the workplace will be studied for the first time by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in a case that involves government workers but could have an impact on private businesses as well. The justices on Monday agreed to decide whether the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, in the interest of fighting drug smuggling, may force those applying for or holding drug-enforcement jobs to be tested. The court will hear arguments in the case next fall, with a decision on the constitutionality of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration program not expected until 1989. The court also may be called upon soon to study drug and alcohol testing for federal railway workers. A federal appeals court in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> ruled on Feb. 11 that the railway testing program is unconstitutional and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration said it will appeal that ruling to the high court. <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> said the high court's action on testing of government workers could influence private employers, depending on how broad the court ruling is. `` The big question is whether the court is going to determine this on a narrow, fact basis or will it attempt to articulate broad principles'' involving workers' reasonable expecations of privacy, he said. He said a narrow ruling relying on the special security needs of the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> would limit the impact in part because `` most -LRB- private -RRB- employers have shied away from random, generalized testing.'' But a sweeping endorsement of testing by the court could change that. The case before the justices is limited to whether public officials violate constitutional rights by testing those who are not suspected of using drugs. The outcome will affect tests conducted by federal, state or local governments but not by industry. Under the law, governments may not violate any rights protected by the Constitution, but private individuals or corporations have more leeway. <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> workers in sensitive jobs must provide urine samples in restroom stalls as a person overseeing the procedure waits outside the stall. The tests are conducted by an independent company hired by the service. Administration lawyers said the tests are needed to prevent agents who used drugs from being bribed or blackmailed. They said any sacrifice of personal privacy is outweighed by the need to stop drug smuggling. Government lawyers said the tests are particularly important now because the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> plans to recruit some 3,000 new employees, including many in the 18-25 age range in which use of illegal drugs is most prevalent. The Customs Service adopted the test procedure under an executive order President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> signed in 1986. The procedure is being challenged by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which said subjecting workers to the test is a humiliating invasion of privacy. The union welcomed the high court's intervention. Union President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobias </PERSON> said the court's ruling will clear up `` a legal and moral morass ... and, we hope, destroy <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s plans for wholesale testing of the federal work force.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, with 30,000 employees, has adopted random testing for its workers. The program covers those in safety-related jobs such as air traffic controllers, <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> pilots and workers with high-rated security clearance. The Customs Service tests, which are not administered randomly, were upheld by the New Orleans-based 5th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. The appeals court said the tests may be considered searches but do not intrude unnecessarily on the privacy rights of workers. In other actions Monday, the court: _ Agreed to decide whether states may bar a man from trying to prove he fathered the child of a woman married to someone else The `` reverse paternity'' case challenges a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> law, similar to those in many other states, that always considers the woman's husband the father _ Asked the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, in a case from <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, whether it thinks high-stakes bingo games run by Indian tribes are subject to state sales taxes _ Said it will decide whether employees of a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> intelligence agency are entitled to administrative hearings when the government fires them as security risks
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-KennedyRe-Election     03-01 0299</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kennedy Re-Election,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kennedy Raises $1.32 Million While GOP Still Searches For A
Candidate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Republicans searched for a candidate for what many believe is a hopeless situation, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> raised $ 1.32 million in preparation for his re-election bid. <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> reports show the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat has $ 1.01 million in his campaign account after spending $ 457,640 during 1987. He raised $ 826,790 in the last six months of 1987 alone. `` We will have a strong candidate,'' promised <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON>, executive director of the state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, in a recent interview. `` As of now, discussions are still going on.'' But it is no secret that the state's few big-name Republicans, including party chief <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamie </PERSON>, have no desire to put on a quixotic campaign against <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who is seeking his sixth term. One potential candidate is <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Carhart </PERSON>, a program analyst at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s strategic defense office who is considering a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> run. His family is from the <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> area. <PERSON> Carhart </PERSON> said in a recent interview he would decide in several weeks whether to run. <PERSON> Carhart </PERSON>, 44, is a graduate of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. He has been a platoon leader in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, an analyst at the <ORGANIZATION> Rand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the editor of a tax journal, author of a book about <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, an attorney and a leading activist against the controversial Vietnam Memorial in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Carhart </PERSON> has little experience in politics and is a virtual unknown in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> strategists are quietly working to get a better-known candidate to run against <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. The senator's year-end <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> report showed he received most of his 1987 campaign contributions _ $ 1.06 million _ from individual contributors. The remaining $ 263,000 came from political action committees.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-CentralAmerica     03-01 0532</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Central America,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan May Sign Bill Providing Only Humanitarian Aid To Contras</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Lead prospects uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is indicating he would sign a bill giving only humanitarian aid to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s rebels if it preserves his option of seeking military funds in the future. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the American Legion convention that `` preventing the consolidation of a pro-Soviet regime on the American mainland is a crucial test of national security.'' On the eve of today's scheduled <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> consideration of a humanitarian aid package, he seemed resigned to the fact there will be no immediate vote for military aid. `` Some say they're willing to support some type of humanitarian aid, but are doing everything they can do disband the freedom fighters,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` But there's nothing humanitarian about asking people to go up against Soviet attack helicopters armed only with boots and bandages.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used the American Legion address to remind <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of his intentions as he prepared to leave for the summit with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> partners in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. He is concerned about possible showdown votes on <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> aid, first in the Rules Committee and later in the week on the House floor. The committee is weighing a $ 30.5 million Contra aid bill, sponsored by Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., and other Democrats, which would provide no military assistance A rival Republican bill would be in much the same form as the $ 36.2 million piece of legislation that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had sought earlier this year, except there would be no money contained in the bill for a military escrow account. In an attempt to win enactment of the $ 36.2 million measure in early February, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> he would consult with leading lawmakers before releasing the $ 3.6 million in an escrow fund for military use. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> defeated the bill by eight votes. It was passed in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, but the vote was only symbolic. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>'s authority to carry out airlifts of supplies to the rebels expired at midnight. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> did not mention this Monday. But he did say that `` whatever package emerges from the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must include a provision for expedited procedures that would allow us to request official military aid to the freedom fighters should the peace process break down.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that since the $ 36.2 million Contra aid package was defeated, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> have been ambivalent about promised reforms, causing <PERSON> Cardinal </PERSON> <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo to suspend peace talks he has been mediating. `` Unless the freedom fighters remain a viable force, the peace process will remain what it was before _ an empty charade, dragging endlessly and fruitlessly on while the Soviets continue the military buildup on the American mainland,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told his audience that if all assistance is stopped, the rebels `` will be picked off one by one'' by the leftist Sandinista regime in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. `` Are we going to cut them off now and leave them defenseless against the <PERSON> Sandinistas </PERSON>? If we do, who will ever trust in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> again? How can we remain a world power if we gain a reputation for pulling the plug on the people that placed their trust in us?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OfficerStrength     03-01 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Officer Strength,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>World's Soldiers Holding up Lots of Brass</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> may be upset about the number of officers in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military, but the armed forces of some of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s closest allies are much more top-heavy, a survey has found. Of 11 nations surveyed by a military journal, only two had a lower ratio of admirals and generals to active-duty personnel than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Moreover, the No. 1 country among those surveyed _ <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ has built a military force whose ratio of generals and admirals to active-duty forces is more than three times that of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The survey was conducted by the monthly magazine `` Armed Forces Journal'' and the results summarized in its March issue, published today. The magazine said it contacted the defense ministries directly or else turned to foreign embassies in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for the information needed to make a comparison of active-duty forces. <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> possesses easily the leanest of the military establishments surveyed, with just 5 generals leading an active-duty force of 54,700, the survey found. That translates to just 0.9 generals per 10,000 active-duty personnel, the magazine reported. The next eight countries fall into a range that runs from 4 generals and admirals per 10,000 active-duty personnel to about 9 generals per 10,000. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is in this group with a ratio of 4.9 generals and admirals for every 10,000 active-duty personnel. The final two countries _ <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ are in a class by themselves, the magazine reported. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has 476 generals and admirals to lead its 320,000 men and women on active duty, or a ratio of 14.9 per 10,000, while <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> has 141 generals and admirals for 87,254 active-duty personnel, or a ratio of 16.2 per 10,000. At the other end of the scale, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> followed <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> with 199 generals and admirals for its 495,000 on active duty, or a ratio of 4.0 generals and admirals per 10,000 troops. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has slightly more than 2.1 million men and women under arms. As of November, when the information was compiled, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had authorized 1,073 slots for generals and admirals and 1,057 of those jobs were filled. Either number produces the same ratio of roughly 4.9 per 10,000. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, complaining about what it calls `` grade creep,'' imposed the cap of 1,073 active-duty slots for generals and admirals in 1981. Lawmakers have refused ever since to raise it despite repeated Pentagon entreaties. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> also ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in its fiscal 1987 budget to begin reducing the number of lower-ranking officers in the military. The Pentagon is under orders to reduce its officer corps of colonels and captains by 6 percent by fiscal 1990 _ or more than 18,000 job slots. Before the cutting began, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> had more than 308,700 officers on active duty, or roughly one officer for every 5.9 enlisted personnel. By next September, that number must fall to 302,620, with additional cuts to follow.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ContraMoney     03-01 0549</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Contra Money,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>IRS Rules Allowed Contras To Bypass Paperwork For New Foundation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Contra rebels, looking for a tax-exempt organization to carry out fund raising, used a legal shortcut to take over a foundation begun by political conservatives to promote understanding of `` governmental systems.'' By reconstituting an existing foundation, the Contras avoided the time nd lengthy application process generally entailed in applying to the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for tax-exempt status. What now goes by the name of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> was originally the <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Davis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> records. The Contra foundation has not filed its first tax return yet because the changeover occurred just last fall. The Lodge foundation stated in its application for tax-exempt status in 1982 that its purpose would be to `` foster, develop and promote, among people of the world, in a nonpartisan basis, a greater understanding and awareness of comparative governmental systems, international policies and the relationships between sovereign states.'' The late <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Lodge </PERSON> was a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> governor and congressman, and ambassador to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>. The grandson of Sen. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabot </PERSON> <PERSON> Lodge </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, he was an ardent anti-communist and chaired <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1980 presidential campaign in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. He died in 1985 at age 82. He was also a mentor to conservative political consultant <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Stone set up the Lodge foundation in 1982 to host forums and publish educational materials. `` It was set up as a hardline anti-communist'' organization, but the foundation never really got off the ground and published only one monograph by former <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> Ambassador <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. Last fall, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> learned from his wife that the rebels needed a foundation to collect money for their cause. It so happens that <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> has a direct mail fund-raising business and the Contras are one of her clients. `` She had something to do with it,'' <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said of the idea to turn his foundation over to the Contras. `` She made the argument it was consistent with the original purposes of the foundation.'' So last October, Stone and two business partners, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Manafort </PERSON>, whom <ORGANIZATION> Stone </ORGANIZATION> had installed as original board members, met and voted themselves off the board. They turned the organization over to newly elected board members <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Palazio </PERSON>, the Contras' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> spokesman, and two <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> officials, <PERSON> Leonardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Somarriba </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeledon </PERSON>. Now the foundation is the principal conduit for funds the Contras are raising privately. The rebels have placed increasing emphasis on these efforts in the wake of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' recent rejection of new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. The Contras say the money they are raising from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens is for humanitarian aid only. Raising money for weapons is not a tax-exempt function, and <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> backers ran afoul of that law in last year's Iran-Contra scandal. The <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> permits changes in purpose and makeup of a foundation as long as the new group is still within the guidelines of tax-exempt purposes, said <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadely </PERSON>. The Contra foundation in December received $ 140,000 from the fund created in memory of the late CIA Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> officials said the money was for a rehabilitation hospital for their wounded and maimed soldiers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OMB-CreditCards     03-01 0499</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-OMB-Credit Cards,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government, $150 Billion In Red, To Become World's Largest Charge
Card User</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government still prints money on paper for all debts public and private, but the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration says it will gladly take plastic. The Office of Management and Budget on Monday announced a new progam to increase dramatically the government's use of credit cards _ both for buying and selling. Not only will the government start accepting credit cards from the public for such items as passports and payments on college loans, but the <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> said it also hopes to develop a plan under which government officials and purchasing agents will use cards. `` Eventually, the Office of Management and Budget will be able to require that all purchases made -LRB- by the government -RRB- under $ 2,500 be by credit card,'' the <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> said in President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s `` management'' report on the federal government In fact, the report itself can be purchased by mail with VISA or <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION>, for $ 6.50. -LRB- The president's fiscal 1989 budget costs $ 18 -RRB-. Budget Director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news briefing he did have a few qualms about use of credit cards as an alternative to legal tender _ for a goverment that was $ 150 billion in the red last year. But, he added, by allowing citizens to repay their government debts with credit cards, `` We're collecting some of this -LRB- debt -RRB- rather than just letting it ride.'' Under the expanded program, the government is expected to process 130 million credit-card transactions annually by 1991, or $ 6.5 billion worth, said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, deputy <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> director. `` It will make us the largest credit card user in the world,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, however, that the cards wo n't be accepted for tax payments _ at least not yet. That would require seeking legislation from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, something the administration is n't now prepared to do. However, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said the subject is being explored with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The government for some time has accepted credit cards for specified items, including publications of the Government Printing Office. More recently, the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has accepted credit cards for duty collection at most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airports and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Mint is now accepting them for coin sales. The management report also said that the government is studying, for possible future use, a system under which `` smart cards'' would be issued by the government to people who receive Social Security and other payments and benefits. `` These cards -LRB- would -RRB- have embedded on them information about the cardholder that can be accessed electronically. Potentially -LRB- the -RRB- cards could make available funds for food stamps, social security payments, or grants and control their use electronically through central computers.'' And what's to keep the government from running up large interest payments on its past-due credit card accounts, just like it has with the national debt? `` We're not going to pay -LRB- interest -RRB- because we're not going to let them go beyond 30 days,'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Macy's-Federated 1stLd-Writethru a0410 03-01 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Macy's-Federated, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0410,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Macy's Proposes Merger With Federated Department Store Chain</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS last graf with 6 grafs to add more background on two
companies, efforts to reach Macy's for comment, other detail. No
pickup. A version moved on financial wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> R.H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has proposed a $ 6.6 billion merger with <ORGANIZATION> Federated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, topping a rival $ 6.1 billion offer from Toronto-based <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> said late Monday night. The $ 73.80-a-share offer from <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> was disclosed as <PERSON> Federated </PERSON>'s board considered a $ 68 a share negotiated offer from <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> for all of <PERSON> Federated </PERSON>'s 89.6 million common shares outstanding. The board took no action on the <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> bid but directed its management, and advisers to investigate <PERSON> Macy </PERSON>'s proposals, to negotiate a definitive agreement and submit both negotiated agreements to the board as soon as possible, the company stated. Officials of <PERSON> Federated </PERSON>, the nation's largest operator of department stores including such well-known retailers as <ORGANIZATION> Bloomingdale </ORGANIZATION>'s, <ORGANIZATION> Filene </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>'s, did not know when the board would get the proposals, according to spokeswoman <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanger </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION>'s would make a cash tender offer for approximately 80 percent of <PERSON> Federated </PERSON>'s outstanding shares at $ 73.80 per share, <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> said. The board of directors of the merged company, which would be renamed <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> - <ORGANIZATION> Federated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, would include significant representation from the existing <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> board, <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> operates more than 650 department stores, specialty stores, mass merchandising stores and supermarkets in 36 states. Annual sales exceeded $ 11 billion in 1987. <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, which was taken private in a $ 3.6 billion management leveraged buyout in 1986, operates 100 department stores and recently opened three specialty clothing stores. Its annual sales were $ 5.21 billion in the fiscal year that ended last Aug. 1. <ORGANIZATION> Macy </ORGANIZATION>'s offices in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> were closed when <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> announced the proposal late Monday, and a spokesman could not be reached for comment. <PERSON> Federated </PERSON> had announced earlier that its board was considering a third-party proposal that was competitive to <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION>'s offer. A <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman declined earlier Monday to comment on the last-minute bid, although <ORGANIZATION> Campeau </ORGANIZATION> repeatedly has stated it wanted the opportunity to meet competing offers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Soviet-Arms Bjt   03-01 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Arms, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Hold to Optimistic Timetable for START Treaty</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Write</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet officials are optimistic about a strategic arms accord being reached before a summit this summer despite President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s remark last week that not enough time is left. The Soviets hope major disagreements in the Strategic Arms Reduction Talks can be settled at a March 22-23 meeting in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> between Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and his Soviet counterpart <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. `` We remain optimistic,'' said a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> diplomat who has been involved in the negotiations in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on long-range weapons. He spoke only on condition of anonymity. `` We are near the finishing line,'' he said, and `` there is still plenty of time'' before <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> meet. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> ordered their aides to draft, before that March meeting, agreements on three areas: verifying compliance, dismantling weapons, and exchanging data on the arsenals. `` These three drafts constitute the bulk of the work to be done'' on the treaty, although several major points of disagreement remain, the Soviet official said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in an interview published last Friday by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, said he did not think it possible to reach an accord before the summit, which is expected in late May or early June. `` We're not at this moment anticipating that it would be ready for signature then,' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. But he said the deal was possible before he leaves office next January. The proposed treaty would cut strategic nuclear arsenals by 35 percent to 50 percent, setting a limit of 6,000 on the overall number of warheads with ranges of more than 3,400 miles. The Soviets are balking at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demand to limit the number of warheads on land-based missiles to 3,300 and the number of warheads aboard so-called heavy missiles to 1,650, according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. And the Soviets want to set a limit on numbers of sea-launched cruise missiles, above the 6,000 warhead ceiling. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have objected to such a limit, in part because it would be difficult to verify. The Soviet official repeated a remark by <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> that technology exists to detect nuclear weapons aboard naval vessels, a statement that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts question. `` Such things as sublimits need to be worked out at the highest political levels,'' such as the Shultz-Shevardnadze meeting in March, the official said. `` The bulk of the work, the technical details, is in the three drafts and needs to be worked out at the expert level'' before the tough political decisions, he said. The official also said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> might drop its objections to tests in space of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Star Wars missile defense system if some limits could be negotiated beforehand. He said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> would countenance some space tests as long as both sides agreed they did not violate the 1972 Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty. The diplomat noted that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> agreed at the December summit in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to abide by the ABM treaty. But the joint communique issued at summit did not address U.S.-Soviet disagreement on the extent to which the treaty restricted space tests of weapons such as lasers and other devices that were not in use when the ABM pact was signed. The Soviets are seeking a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> response to their proposal to set limits on tests for various Star Wars components such as lasers, the official said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators have rejected such limits, saying that compliance would be impossible to verify in space.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-At-A-Glance     03-01 0350</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-At-A-Glance,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-AIDS Commission</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, is the latest on AIDS.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WHAT IT IS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 AIDS, or acquired immune deficiency syndrome, is a contagious disease that destroys the body's immune system. It is incurable and usually fatal. Death comes from infections or cancers that the body can not fight.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WHAT CAUSES IT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 AIDS is caused by the human immunodeficiency virus, or HIV, and is spread through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, transfusion of infected blood or blood products, or from an infected birthing mother to her baby.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WHO GETS IT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Chief victims of AIDS have been homosexual men and intravenous drug abusers. Health officials estimate that heterosexual contact is responsible for 4 percent of cases and that between 1 million and 1.5 million Americans have been exposed to the virus.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HOW IT'S DETECTED</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Screening for AIDS is conducted by testing blood for the presence of antibodies to the AIDS virus. The test tells only if a person has been exposed to the virus. A person with a positive test has a 20 percent to 30 percent chance of developing AIDS over a five-year period, according to the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HOW MANY HAVE IT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 As of Feb. 22, AIDS had been diagnosed in 54,233 Americans, of whom more than half, or 30,355, have died since June 1, 1981, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. No one is known to have recovered from AIDS.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>POSSIBLE TREATMENTS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Numerous types of medicines against the AIDS virus are now being studied. They are in three categories: antivirals that combat the virus; anti-infectives that treat the opportunistic infections and malignancies that occur with AIDS; and immune modulators that strengthen the immune system. An antiviral, AZT -LRB- for azidothymidine -RRB-, has received <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> approval and early results show it is effective in halting progress of the AIDS virus. At least 16 other antivirals are in some stage of development and testing. Scientists also are searching for a vaccine against the virus, but this research is in early stages.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CorpsAircraft     03-01 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corps Aircraft,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Corps Of Engineers Loses Control Of Its Executive Aircraft</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID GOELLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A congressional critic of federal officials' flying in style on taxpayer-supplied executive aircraft says he's unhappy with an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> move to clip the wings of the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., expressed his displeasure Monday after the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> told him the corps had been been stripped of day-to-day control of three aircraft that have been called wasteful by <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and congressional auditors <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON>, who stepped down Friday as undersecretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, said he ordered the executive aircraft placed in a central pool, forcing the corps brass to compete against other <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> commanders for their use. `` The pooled operation, we anticipate, will yield economies,'' <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON> told <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>'s Government Operations subcommittee on environment, energy and natural resources. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Elvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Heiberg </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, the three-star chief of engineers, told the hearing that `` I concur with the decision made by my boss. ... We'll have to compete.'' Last summer, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the corps had been using the aircraft not for emergencies such as floods but for routine and ceremonial matters, many of them overseas trips on which leaders were accompanied improperly by spouses. <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON> said that before they can use any of the aircraft, <PERSON> Heiberg </PERSON> and other corps leaders will have to get flight-by-flight permission from the director of <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> staff in the Pentagon. <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said he was displeased because the director of staff has been responsible for authorizing travel by corps spouses, who <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> regulations say must have an `` unquestionable official'' role in a government-financed trip. `` Unless he does a better job than he has done with spouse travel, this is n't going to be much of a safeguard,'' <PERSON> Synar </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Heiberg </PERSON> and other corps officials have defended their use of the aircraft on grounds that they are more efficient than commercial flights. <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON>'s action partially settled an in-Army fight between the corps and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> auditors, who said last year that tax dollars could be saved by selling the planes and having corps officials use commercial or charter flights. <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON> said the Army would decide later this year whether to sell the aircraft, including Castle I, the 14-passenger jet that has been used to ferry key members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on trips to visit water projects around the nation. Before the aircraft can be sold, however, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> will have to repeal a law forbidding such a sale. The prohibition was quietly enacted in December at the behest of one of those flyers, Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, D-Ala., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee that handles corps funding <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said he disagreed with the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> auditors and with similar findings made over the years by the congressional <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. `` All three planes are needed,'' <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON> said. `` They do their best work when there's floods and emergencies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cox-Judgeship     03-01 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cox-Judgeship,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Judgeship Nominee Questioned About Racial Sensitivity</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>'s handling of the 1985 vote fraud trial of three <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> civil rights activists has come under fire during a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> hearing on his nomination to the 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, told the panel Monday that <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> displayed `` an intolerance toward and a failure to respect'' a black lawyer involved in the trial and issued rulings that raised questions about his sensitivity to racial issues. <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON>' testimony marked the second time that the vote fraud trial has been used as the basis for opposing one of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s judicial nominees. The trial, which civil rights groups charged was part of an effort by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to intimidate black voters in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, ended in innocent verdicts for all three activists. It then became the focal point of a 1986 campaign by civil rights groups against <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nomination of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney Jefferson B. Sessions III to a federal judgeship in south <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. Sessions, who was prosecutor at the vote fraud trial, was rejected by the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, marking the first time that one of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s judicial nominees has been voted down in committee. While the Sessions nomination drew opposition from a host of civil rights groups, <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON> was the only witness Monday who testified in opposition to <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION>. The committee did not vote on the nomination, but Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., who presided at the hearing, predicted that <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> would win <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation within a month <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON> criticized <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>'s decision during the 1985 trial to bring criminal contempt of court charges against <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lawyer who represented one of the activists. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> had ruled that <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>'s questioning of a witness violated his order barring defense attorneys from raising the issue of selective prosecution. That contempt ruling later was reversed by the 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON>, who represented <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that `` there was absolutely no foundation'' for the contempt charge. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> acknowledged Monday that the appeals court had `` fairly concluded'' that he had been wrong to cite <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> for contempt. `` They educated me on the law of criminal contempt,'' he said. <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON> also charged that <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> had shown a lack of racial sensivitity by refusing to delay the trial for two weeks so the jury could be selected from a jury pool drawn from the <LOCATION> Selma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, area, which had a much larger percentage of blacks than did the jury pool drawn from the Mobile, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, area. <PERSON> Cox </PERSON> declined during the hearing to respond specifically to <PERSON> Stavis </PERSON>' testimony about the jury selection issue. But he told reporters afterwards that racial considerations played no part in his handling of the case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Brazil-Sanctions     03-01 0419</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brazil-Sanctions,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Cites Progress, Puts Off Sanctions Against Brazil</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration says it wo n't go forward with $ 105 million in retaliatory sanctions against <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> at this time, citing `` some progress'' in relaxing trade barriers against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> computer software sales. The administration earlier this year announced that it would slap the duties on a variety of Brazilian products to protest the restrictions. However, since then there has been a thaw in U.S.-Brazilian relations, both on the trade and Third World debt front. A new software law in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, which calls for a new set of regulations governing imports of foreign-made computer programs and other software, helped prompt the administration decision to delay its sanctions. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, citing `` recent progress,'' in the dispute, said in a statement on Monday: `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will delay sanctions against <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> pending review of the implementing regulations for <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s new software law. `` Subsequent to that, we will review our options and consider what actions, if any, to take.'' The list of specific Brazilian exports to be targeted had never been released, even though a preliminary list included Brazilian-made shoes, aircraft, automobiles and electronics equipment. The issue of access of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> computer software companies to markets in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> `` will remain a high priority for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` Recent Brazilian actions, and discussions with representatives of the government of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, demonstrate progress on this issue,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` Some of our immediate concerns have now been met.'' The new Brazilian law will regulate commercial sales of all software, both domestic and foreign. It calls for new regulations to be issued by April 19. `` As a result, we feel it would be inappropriate and counterproductive to proceed with our previously announced plans to retaliate,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` That proposed action will be placed on hold until we have a chance to evaluate <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s response on the software regulations.'' Adding to the atmosphere of eased relations between <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and its key trading partners has been <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s participation in negotiations on a loan restructuring package. Key portions of that pact were reached over the weekend as <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s largest debtor nation, agreed to make a $ 700 million interest payment to make it current for all of 1988 and the last quarter of 1987. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> has n't repaid any principal on its $ 114 billion foreign debt since 1983. In February 1987, it decreed a moratorium on interest payments but late last year agreed to resume them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-01 0856</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0889</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RADNOR, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A throat operation could n't stop <PERSON> Katharine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> from making the upcoming TV film `` <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansing </PERSON> Slept Here,'' but it was n't an easy decision. <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> said her problem became evident when she showed up for the first script reading last fall in <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. She opened her mouth and `` no voice. Total hoarse. Just a rasp,'' she wrote in the March 5 issue of TV Guide. `` I was thinking: Do it _ do n't do it. ... If I ca n't talk, then there is no movie _ that's a lot of people out of work.'' She identified herself as her doctor's <PERSON> Aunt </PERSON> <PERSON> Nora </PERSON> when she checked into <ORGANIZATION> Vancouver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, but `` everyone immediately recognized me, and they were trying not to show it.'' A day later, she found out the growth was n't cancerous. It was `` just one of those growths that the human body throws out to torment us,'' <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CRESTED BUTTE, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 He may not have been known as `` Carter the Magnificent'' during his presidency's trying times, but <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> assumed the title temporarily during a fund-raising event here. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> donned a turban and pretended to divine the contents of sealed envelopes Monday as he imitated `` Carnac the Magnificent,'' the character created by talk-show host <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>. The former president was at the <ORGANIZATION> Crested </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Butte </ORGANIZATION> ski resort briefly to help raise money for handicapped skiers. He planned to be back in <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, today to meet with Democratic presidential hopeful <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> is joining a law firm headed by former Secretary of State <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> as a Washington-based specialist in international law and finance. The announcement was made Monday by the 275-lawyer firm of <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>, whose headquarters is in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The firm said <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> will not engage in any work involving the federal government, defense contracts or any other matters connected with the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> served as secretary of health, education and welfare and as budget director during the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration. He was senior vice president and general counsel of <ORGANIZATION> Bechtel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> from 1975 until 1980, and became secretary of defense in 1981. He resigned from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Cabinet late last year.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SCRANTON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several months ago, Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright and actor <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> looked at his 80-year-old father and realized theater could benefit from the energy and experience of the elderly. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> then decided to start a theater group for senior citizens in this former coal mecca. `` We're talking about the vitality of senior citizens, the intelligence, the talent that's lying dormant because there has n't been an opportunity to express themselves,'' he said Rehearsals began last week for the group's first play, `` It's a Sin to Tell a Lie,'' written by <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who played a priest in the movie `` The Exorcist.'' `` Senior citizens' theater should be as viable and as energetic as children's theater, but nobody has senior citizens' theater,'' said <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, winner of a 1973 Pulitzer Prize for `` That Championship Season.'' The one-act play is scheduled to open April 9 at the <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION> Public Theater and will tour nursing homes in northeastern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, offering senior citizens free admission, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MONTEZUMA, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet film crew is making a documentary to honor the 90th birthday of industrialist <PERSON> Armand </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, who has been dealing with Soviet leaders since <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>. The crew from <LOCATION> Gosteleradio </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s government television company, accompanied Hammer to northeastern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to visit the college he funded here, the <ORGANIZATION> Armand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hammer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> of the American West. The crew spent a couple of hours filming at the college Monday before heading on to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, who is chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Occidental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gosteleradio </PERSON> requested the one-hour film be made in honor of Hammer's birthday May 21 The documentary is slated to be broadcast the night of May 21 on Soviet television. Hammer first went to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in the 1920s as a physician to battle a typhus epidemic. He decided the Soviets needed a trade representative more than they needed his medical skills.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> was put on probation for six months by a judge who told him to `` stay out of trouble.'' <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, 31, was sentenced Monday for a Dec. 3 incident in which he went to a woman's apartment at 2:30 a.m., pounded on the door and demanded to be let in. The woman instead called police. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> was charged with attempted assault, resisting arrest and other lesser charges after he allegedly took a swing at one of the officers. The major charges were dropped in January, and <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> agreed to plead guilty to harassment, which is punishable by up to 15 days in jail. Judge <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> told the actor that if he stayed out of trouble during the next six months his record for the current offense will be sealed. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> starred in the movies `` King of the Gypsies,'' `` The Pope of <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>'' and `` Star 80.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryBills     03-01 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Bills,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>T-Bills Mixed In Latest Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates on short-term <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> securities were mixed in the latest auction with three-month bills dropping to the lowest level since November while rates on six-month bills edged up. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sold $ 6.4 billion in three-month bills Monday at an average discount rate of 5.62 percent, down from 5.64 percent last week. Another $ 6.4 billion was sold in six-month bills at an average discount rate of 5.86 percent, up from 5.83 percent last week. The rates on three-month bills were the lowest since 5.49 percent on Nov. 30 while the six-month bills were the highest since they averaged 6.03 percent on Feb. 16. The new discount rates understate the actual return to investors _ 5.78 percent for three-month bills with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,857.90 and 6.12 percent for a six-month bill selling for $ 9,703.70. In a separate report, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said the average yield for one-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bills, the most popular index for making changes in adjustable rate mortgages, dropped to 6.63 percent last week, down from 6.70 percent the previous week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitolMice Bjt   03-01 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capitol Mice, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Capitol Mice Foil Cat, Startle Ambassador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The cat came to stay but the Capitol mice played anyway _ around an ambassador's feet. House Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., has a mouse problem He shares it with other members of the Democratic leadership who occupy offices in the oldest part of the Capitol, the part that survived after the British burned the building in 1814. The mice call it home but <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders and their staffs call it disturbing. So traps were set and baited with cheese. The mice ignored then. Then <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> called in reinforcements. He brought his cat to work, a feline with a proven reputation as a champion mouser. The cat moved in with the <ORGANIZATION> Foleys </ORGANIZATION> a dozen years ago while they were on vacation in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. Since the cat had chosen them, and not they the cat, they gave the animal an appropriate name _ `` <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> the Lodger.'' <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> was brought in to lodge for awhile in <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s office suite on the first floor of the Capitol, sharing quarters not only with the mice but with <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s dog, <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>, who accompanies the majority leader to work on a daily basis. Expectations ran high for <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>. But the results were poor. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> the Lodger bagged no mice. The mouser's failure was underscored on Monday during a meeting in an adjoining office used by Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., the chief deputy Democratic leader <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> was conferring over coffee with <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinast </PERSON>, the Polish ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Suddenly a mouse darted out from behind a small chest. It ran across the carpet and disappeared under the conference table, literally at the startled ambassador's feet. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership is looking for a new weapon in its war against mice.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s sergeant at arms _ <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Giugni </PERSON> _ became an instant celebrity last week when he followed orders and arrested Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore. <PERSON> Giugni </PERSON>'s posse had <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON> carried onto the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor to constitute a quorum so consideration could continue of a controversial campaign financing act, then besieged by a filibuster It was not the first time a senate sergeant of arms has been the focus of attention by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the press. On Feb. 7, 1935, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted to fire Sergeant at Arms <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s offense: The 72-year-old former journalist had written a magazine article entitled `` Over the Hill to Demagoguery'' which he had thought would be published after he left office. But the publication date was moved up and when the article appeared it began with these words: `` Contrary, perhaps, to the popular belief, there are not many crooks in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>; that is out and out grafters, or those who are willing to be such. `` There are not many senators or representatives who sell their votes for money, and it is pretty well known who those few are. `` But there are many demagogues.'' Senate Republican leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, who recounted the incident on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor recently, said the article probably would have been ignored had it been written by a journalist. `` But for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s sergeant at arms it was an entirely different matter,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` So the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted him out of office, less than a month before his term would have ended.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 It does n't take much time. And it does n't cost much money. And it makes somebody somewhere happy. So <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> over the decades has busily subdivided the calendar into days, weeks, months and even years in honor of some historic figure, event, cause, profession or industry or thing. It was in that spirit early last month that Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., offered a resolution designating the week of Oct. 30 through Nov. 5 as <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jukebox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Week </ORGANIZATION> `` As a rich chronicler of music, culture and technology, the jukebox is without peer,'' <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> informed the House. `` It has brought great joy and memories to generations of Americans. Its popularity is unequaled in the eyes of young and old alike.'' Besides, he said, the juke box is on the advent of its centennial. The very first juke box, a wax cylinder Edison phonograph fitted with a coin slot, was installed in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Palais </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Royale </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Saloon </LOCATION> in 1889. Just the thing, the <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON> resolution said, to be observed `` with appropriate programs, ceremonies and activities.'' But if juke boxes bore, perhaps doll houses are the ticket. Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, wants to designate the week of October 9 as National Dollhouse Week. After all, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> contended, `` about 10 percent of our population has some involvement with dollhouse and miniature collecting.'' The source of that statistic, he disclosed, is the <ORGANIZATION> Miniatures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     03-01 0029</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0029</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Close Higher In Japan</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 25,435.90 points, up 193.09 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Senate-Afghanistan     03-01 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate-Afghanistan,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Resolution Says No Aid Cutoff Until Soviets Completely Out</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> is hinting he may delay <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> consideration of the new U.S.-Soviet nuclear arms reduction treaty if the White House ends <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to insurgents in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> before a complete and final Soviet troop withdrawal. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, commented shortly before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 77-0 on Monday to adopt a resolution urging the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> not to cut off, suspend or reduce military aid to the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance `` until it is absolutely clear that the Soviets have terminated their military occupation The non-binding resolution also urged formation of an interim government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> acceptable to the Afghan resistance. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said the resolution is intended to `` send a clear message'' to the administration that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> wants no part of any U.S.-Soviet agreement in which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the Afghan resistance is ended merely on <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s promise to withdraw its troops, not on their actual removal. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> and Sens. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, took strong exception to congressional testimony last week in which <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, an assistant deputy secretary of <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would be prepared, `` if completely satisfied with the overall agreement, to prohibit <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military assistance to the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance.'' <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> also testified last week: `` We will continue our assistance ... until that support is no longer needed. But the question of when to cut off aid is one that should be left to the president.'' <PERSON> Symms </PERSON> said <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>'s testimony leads many to fear a `` superpower deal ... that will allow the Soviets to gain politically what they could not gain on the battlefield.'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said, `` I'd like to know what's in these agreements before I call up the INF -LRB- Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces -RRB- treaty,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. `` I do n't want the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> kept in the dark,'' he added. The INF treaty, which calls for the elimination of medium-range nuclear missiles from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, is under examination by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and two other <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panels. It could reach the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor for action by the end of March or early April. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> supports <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ratification of the treaty without reservations that would force its renegotiation. He said last week that includes a reservation linking implementation of the pact to complete Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScienceEducation     03-01 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Science Education,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>International Study Shows American Students Far Behind</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Students in most other countries are far better educated in science than are American students, according to an international study that one <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said emphasizes `` the troubled state of science education in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' In a report released Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students at three different grade levels all scored well behind those from most other nations, with some American 14-year-olds scoring at the level of the `` scientifically illiterate.'' `` For a technologically advanced country, it would appear that -LRB- in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> -RRB- a re-examination of how science is presented and studied is required,'' said the study, which was conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evaluation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Achievement </ORGANIZATION>, an association of research centers. <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, said of the study: `` These findings emphasize again the troubled state of science education in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. ... <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future as a world technological and economic leader and the quality of life we enjoy depend on confronting the real problems in science education with vigor, determination and a sense of urgency.'' The study was conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evaluation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Achievement </ORGANIZATION>, an association of research centers. Early findings, which compared the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> only with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, and with partial findings from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, were reported by The Associated Press in September. The comparative study was based on tests administered to 204,308 students at 7,581 schools in 24 countries between 1983 and 1986. The tests were given at three academic levels: near the end of primary grades, at about age 10; at grades eight and nine, about age 14; and in the final year of high school. Among 10-year-olds, students in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION> scored around 15.4 out of 24 possible correct answers. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> students scored just below the middle of the scale at 13.2. Among 14-year-olds, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> scored at the top, while Americans ranked third from last with a mean score of 16.5 out of 30 possible correct answers. The lowest-scoring quarter of this age group, the report said, `` were scientifically illiterate'' with their test scores `` at chance level.'' Tests for the high school seniors were given only to those specializing in science subjects. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> scored highest, with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> students receiving among the lowest marks. In an analysis of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> results, the report said: `` The achievement of advanced science students in biology, chemistry and physics is low. The biology results are especially low.'' The study said that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, along with <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, has `` many poor scoring schools and it would seem likely that the school authorities would have grounds for concern.'' Secretary of Education <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, responding to a report of the study, said it supports an assessment on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> education that his department released last week. `` Now comes this international report card showing that compared to students in other countries, American elementary and high school students are not just in a ` dead stall,' they're doing even worse,'' <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said. `` They're in reverse and going downhill.'' The international study also compared the difference in science achievement based on gender. In grades five and nine, boys scored higher than girls in all countries. For grade 12, boys outperformed girls in biology, chemistry and physics, except in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, where girls had top marks in biology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GlassMerger     03-01 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Glass Merger,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Owens-Illinois Acquires Most Of Brockway At $60 A Share</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES HANNAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> has acquired virtually all outstanding shares of <ORGANIZATION> Brockway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> stock to the tune of about $ 740 million and is on the verge of creating the nation's largest glass container company, offcials say. Monday's move followed a decision by the government against appealing a court decision in favor of the merger. <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said the company bought 12,337,630 shares of common <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON> stock, 98.7 percent of the outstanding shares. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said the actual merger will likely occur in a couple of weeks, at which time the remaining shares will be purchased. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanigan </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, said the merger will make the combined operations and the glass container industry `` significantly more competitive with can, plastic and other materials in the worldwide packaging business.'' <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ticknor </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, declined to specify why the agency decided against appealing a decision by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> that, in effect, paving the way for the merger. However, Ms. <PERSON> Ticknor </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> has scheduled administrative hearings on potential anticompetitive effects of the merger. And she said <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> could be ordered to divest itself of <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON> holdings if the agency determines that the merger violates antitrust laws. The <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, based <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> proposed to buy <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, last September for $ 60 a share. The merger will make the combined company the nation's largest manufacturer of glass containers, which are used in packaging foods and beverages. The largest producer of glass containers has been <ORGANIZATION> Anchor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Glass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Container </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Owens-Illinois </ORGANIZATION> officials have said the only weapon the glass container industry has against plastics and metal packaging producers is competitive pricing and the merger with <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON> is designed to increase productivity and lower costs. The <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION> had attempted in court to block the merger, saying it might violate antitrust laws by substantially reducing competition and creating the conditions for price discrimination. However, last month <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Hens </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> denied the <ORGANIZATION> FTC </ORGANIZATION>'s request for a preliminary injunction on the basis that the agency had failed to prove the deal would harm competition. And last Friday, the appeals court sided with Judge <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, saying that the agency had failed to make its case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Jackson'sVotes     03-01 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jackson's Votes,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jackson Showing in Maine Seen as Breakthrough</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s surprise second-place finish in the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Democraatic caucuses was a `` breakthrough,'' proving conclusively that he has broadened his appeal, his backers say. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> reaped 28 percent of the vote in the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> contest on Sunday, on the heels of respectable showings in three other states which, like <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, all have voting age black populations of 1 percent or less. The <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> results came after he spent just $ 13,000 in the state and campaigned there only two days. The well-funded winner, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, is well known to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> voters as governor of nearby <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, and he captured 42 percent. `` It shows that we can get votes in any part of the country,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Monday in <LOCATION> Pembroke </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> `` It shows we have the broadest base ... and our campaign has the strongest appeal.'' `` The <ORGANIZATION> Rainbow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> is coming alive,'' he added, invoking the name he has given to his target constituency of all minority groups and the economically oppressed. Political consultant <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, an informal <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> adviser, called <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> `` the most significant breakthrough state for him so far.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON>, a top political strategist for <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s 1984 presidential bid, said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s performance is `` a sign of a growing movement among non-black supporters of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, and for people to try to ignore it, they're making a great mistake.'' In <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> finished fourth out of seven contenders. In <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> he was second with 20 percent in last week's caucuses. In <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 28 percent contrasted to the 1 percent that he got when he ran in 1984. Campaign manager <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said he knew his candidate would do well in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and the goal was to come in second. But <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s margin, well above the single-digit results of the other Democrats, was better than he had anticipated He credited it to organizing by students and dedicated volunteers _ the campaign had only two paid staff people in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. `` It was basically, totally indigenous and independent,'' he said of the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> organization. `` They did things on their own.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s core support came out of the university communities in <LOCATION> Orono </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, and striking paper workers in <PERSON> Jay </PERSON>, he said. He carried <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> and another of the state's largest cities, <LOCATION> Bangor </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> bought $ 10,000 worth of TV ads in the days before the caucuses, and $ 2,000 on radio. The 10-second TV spots showed the winning <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal in the 1980 Olypic hockey game against the Soviets, with an announcer saying as <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s picture appeared: `` Just like in the Olympics, one man can make a difference.'' <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON>, who called <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> `` one of the best hidden political stories of the year,'' commented also, `` People do n't want to buy the notion that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has got a message that people listen to and that has begun to rise above his blackness ... Somebody in this party has to to recognize that this is a significant guy in the party.'' Political analyst <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, however, questioned whether <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s white votes are really the downtrodden whom he has targeted. He cited exit polls from <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> showing a good portion of his votes came from upscale, well-educated liberals, `` the radical chic.'' But he also noted that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has a strong message that appeals to many Democrats. `` There is no other candidate in the race who really stands for the old politics ... what I would call Democratic fundamentalism,'' as espoused by the late Sen. <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Gov <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>. <PERSON> Beckel </PERSON> said people `` consistently underestimate'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` He's the most charismatic candidate in the field. He's got a message that's concise, that does not change from place to place.'' <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Democratic chairman <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Barton </PERSON> said timing was a key for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s successful appearance at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Orono </LOCATION> on Feb. 11, just after <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s caucuses and just before the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, was `` just the right time ... when <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> Democrats were starting to lock in,'' he said. <PERSON> Barton </PERSON> said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> probably also picked up about 5 percentage points from people who defected from the flagging campaigns of <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mecham-Coverage     03-01 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mecham-Coverage,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Statewide Audiences Have Radio, TV Coverage Available</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Mecham-Impeachment, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Public television stations are offering gavel-to-gavel coverage of Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s impeachment trial, and several radio stations are covering portions of the proceedings. Public stations KUAT-TV in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> and KAET-TV in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> started providing full live coverage when the trial began Monday. <ORGANIZATION> KFYI </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> news and talk radio station, put together a telephone network to feed continuous live coverage to stations in <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yuma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bullhead </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havasu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Prescott </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, Window Rock and <PERSON> Payson </PERSON>. Some of the stations were carrying only part of the proceedings, however. None of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s commercial television stations carried gavel-to-gavel coverage, but many chipped in to set up pool coverage with the public stations, in which all participants are entitled to broadcast parts of the live proceedings or use excerpts on later news programs. The pool costs could exceed $ 100,000, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Willi </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> KPNX-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-St.Patrick'sDay     03-01 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-St. Patrick's Day,0175</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: Retransmits a0460 to fix cycle designation</NOTE>
<HEAD>President Takes Note of St. Patrick's Day</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has issued an early St. Patrick's Day message, saying he wanted to acknowledge `` the world of debt we owe to the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> people.'' Although his message came two and a half weeks ahead of time, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Monday took note of the March 17 commemoration, saying the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> people `` have created and perpetuated a unique heritage of faith and freedom, of humor and hope, of scholarship and sanctity and sacrifice.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who is of Irish ancestry, went on to say: `` With faith and fearlessness, <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> brought Christianity to <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> a millennium and a half ago. The annals reveals the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> people's eagerness to embrace the faith and to keep it; that trait remains to this day, a tribute to the Apostle of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and to his flock in every generation. `` May <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> always cherish each other and the kinship in which we hold St. Patrick's Day.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880301-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-01-88 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Mecham'sDay Bjt   03-01 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mecham's Day, Bjt,0551</SECOND>
<HEAD>Meetings and Phone Calls, And Not Much Time For
Impeachment-Watching</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SCOTT McCARTNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
