<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BigMan     03-26 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Big Man,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weight Inspector Claims State Fired Him Because He Was Overweight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB IMRIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BISMARCK, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state weight inspector whose boss says he tipped the scales at 500 pounds himself and `` kept growing out of the uniforms'' is appealing his firing by the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wahpeton </LOCATION>, who is awaiting a hearing before the state <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday, was given five reasons in writing for being fired, including his weight, his lawyer, <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Stutsman </PERSON>, said Friday. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> was dismissed July 31 from his job in a scale house where he weighed trucks and inspected cargo. `` To say we terminated the guy because he was overweight is basically unfair,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON>, superintendent of the <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION>. `` I feel bad for the guy. We tried to work with him to improve his situation. He left us no alternative, in our opinion.'' <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>'s `` weight probably contributed to other things. ... Personal health habits would be a polite way of saying it.'' Highway Patrol policy requires employees to maintain `` appropriate health levels, weight levels and physical fitness levels'' as determined by the department's doctor, personnel officer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Anagnost </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Anagnost </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> was informed that reasons for his firing included his failure to follow the doctor's recommendations about weight loss, his appearance and grooming and his inability to wear a uniform while on duty. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> weighed 325 in 1983 and 500 pounds when he was fired, <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said. `` He kept growing out of the uniforms. We refused to keep altering them.'' <PERSON> Stutsman </PERSON> refused to discuss details of the appeal, and <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> referred all questions to his lawyer when contacted Friday. <PERSON> Stutsman </PERSON> called <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> a `` fairly good-sized man, that's for sure,'' but he said his client's weight is disputed, in part because `` they have never really had an adequate scale to weigh him on.'' <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, in his 40s, had worked for the <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> since 1977 in the agency's truck regulatory division, <PERSON> Stutsman </PERSON> said. His exact age was unavailable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TVCommercials     03-26 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TV Commercials,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Alaska Tourism Ads Poke Fun at Texas</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY PERSILY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fighting an image that <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> is cold and forsaken all year, the state tourism division is running new TV ads that get a little good-natured revenge by poking fun at its big-state rival, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Four years ago, former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said he did n't believe anyone would want to visit <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, which he called a frozen wasteland, said state tourism marketing director <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON> `` We basically took that page from history'' in making the series of six commercials, <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON> said. In the commercials, a governor visits <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> to see for himself why people come here. The governor's state is not identified, `` but you can tell he's from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON> said. `` He's sort of an LBJ look-alike.'' The governor also wears a 10-gallon hat and cowboy boots. The first commercial shows the governor visiting <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and discovering the summer weather is great. The second ad says the governor's aides are coming north to look for him because he apparently has decided he enjoys it in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> so much he stayed longer than expected. People still believe <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> endures cold, snow and ice all year, said <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON>. `` We're trying to tell travelers the truth,'' she said. July temperatures in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> average in the high 50s, with daytime temperatures often in the 60 - to 70-degree range In past ad campaigns, tourism officials have pitched the state's scenery and wildlife, <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON> said This year, `` We're basically hitting the weather head-on,'' she said. The tourism division is spending $ 2.3 million to air the commercials on network stations in 20 cities in the Lower 48. The ads started running last month and will continue through April, <PERSON> Klugherz </PERSON> said. The ads will not run in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> because it's too expensive to advertise there, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Stocks-Markets     03-26 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Stocks-Markets,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Market Finishes Worst Week of Year</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The stock market closed out its worst week so far this year, as prices fell for the second straight session. The Dow Jones average of 30 industrials dropped 44.92 points Friday to 1,978.95, finishing the week with a net loss of 108.42. That marked the average's biggest weekly decline since it dropped 143.74 points last Nov. 30-Dec. 4 After tumbling Thursday in foreign exchange, the dollar showed signs of steadying Friday. Interest rates, which had contributed to the stock market's woes by rising Thursday morning, dropped back a bit. But analysts said investors were still leery of stocks. They said Thursday's selloff dealt a significant blow to the tenuous confidence that had been building up in the market's rally since late last year. In the absence of any news to explain the market's weakness, brokers said many traders remained fearful that economic and inflationary pressures might soon reach a point where they would prompt the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> to begin tightening credit. Declining issues outnumbered advances by about 3 to 1 in the daily tally on the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, with 385 up, 1,156 down and 428 unchanged. <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> volume came to 163.17 million shares, against 184.91 million in the previous session. The <ORGANIZATION> NYSE </ORGANIZATION>'s composite index lost 2.42 to 146.58. As measured by <ORGANIZATION> Wilshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION>' index of more than 5,000 actively traded stocks, the market lost $ 39.81 billion, or 1.52 percent, in value.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Births-Deaths Bjt   03-26 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Births-Deaths, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nation Posts Record Deaths, Most Births in 23 Years</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The aging of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s population led to a national record of 2.1 million deaths last year, but births topped 3.8 million for the highest number in 23 years, the government says. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday that deaths in 1987 totaled `` 2,127,000, about 28,000 more than the previous year and the largest number ever reported for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' Deaths from heart disease, the nation's No. 1 killer, slipped slightly, but cancer claimed more victims than in the year before, the study showed. The nation's overall death rate was about the same as in 1986, at about 8.7 deaths per 1,000 people. That's because the number of fatalities increased at about the same rate as the population grew, the study noted. The study also found that marriage and divorce rates changed little, remaining at relatively low levels. Births, which had dipped somewhat in 1986, climbed 3 percent the following year to an estimated 3,829,000. `` The 1987 provisional total is the largest number reported since 1964,'' the study said. The fertility rate was 66.1 live births per 1,000 women aged 15-44, up from 64.9 in 1986. The rising number of births that have occurred in recent years has resulted from the large number of women born during the post World War II Baby Boom who have now entered their main child-bearing years. That has prompted population experts to term the recent rise in births an echo of the Baby Boom. They insist it is not, in itself, another Baby Boom, however, pointing out that birth rates have remained well below those of the 1950s and early 1960s. Subtracting deaths from births, the study reported a natural increase in population of 1,702,000 people last year, 3 percent more than in 1986. Just slightly over twice as many couples married as were divorced during the year, the annual report found. Marriages in 1987 totaled 2,421,000, 1 percent more than the year before. That represented a marriage rate of 9.9 per 1,000 population. That was the lowest rate since 1977, when it was also 9.9. Meanwhile, there were 1,157,000 divorces last year, a 1 percent decline. The divorce rate was 4.8 per 1,000 people, about the same as the year before and the lowest divorce rate since 1975. The report also looked at causes of death reported across the nation, and found a decline in heart disease fatalities, but an increase in cancer deaths between 1986 and 1987. Because it takes longer to compile the detailed figures, the cause-of-death statistics were reported for the 12-month period ending with November 1987, rather than for the calendar year. For all causes, the 1987 rate was reported at 873.0 deaths per 100,000 people, down from 873.3 in 1986. The rate for major cardiovascular diseases slipped from 401.8 per 100,000 in 1986 to 395.7 in 1987, the study said. But at the same time, the death rate for all types of cancer increased from 193.7 per 100,000 to 195.9. Among the other causes of death reported were diabetes, 15.4 per 100,000, up from 15.2; stroke, 61.0, down from 61.6; pneumonia and influenza, 28.2, down from 28.7; chronic lung disease, 31.7, up from 31.3; chronic liver disease, 10.7, down from 10.8; accidents, 38.1, down from 38.9, and suicide, 12.1, down from 12.6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryBearings     03-26 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Bearings,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon To Unveil Buy-American Regulations For Bearings</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Willson is cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will try to prop up the slumping <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bearing industry with a requirement that makers of jets, submarines and other military systems use only American-made bearings. The `` Buy-American'' regulation, due to be published Monday in the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION>, would be in place for at least three years, said Rep. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., who pushed for the rule She called it a `` tremendous victory'' for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bearing makers. The domestic industry has been severely eroded by foreign competition in recent years. Nearly 65 percent of ball bearings sold in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> come from abroad, and 40 percent of the roller bearing sales are from imports. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is a major buyer of bearings, making up nearly 19 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> buys a majority of the super-precision bearings used in jets and submarines. <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> proponents warn that the sagging domestic industry would be unable to gear up for wartime production. They point to a 1986 <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> study that said the bearing industry is critical to the nation's defense and warned that domestic manufacturers were in `` imminent danger of being unable to support national defense needs.'' `` This action is clearly needed to halt a trend that directly jeopardizes our ability to defend ourselves,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a founder of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bearing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> whose western <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> district includes several major bearing employers. `` This new policy will prevent the loss of even more business overseas and give our bearings companies the breathing room they need to regain their competitive edge,'' she said. The new regulations would cover only combat-related systems and not non-military items bought by the Pentagon such as bearings for automobiles, according to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> <PERSON> Willson </PERSON>. Military bearings make up more than half the bearings purchased by the department. About $ 40 million of the $ 350 million in military-related bearings purchased by the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> annually comes from foreign countries. And that trend has been increasing, the congresswoman said. From 1980 to 1986, she said, the number of foreign manufacturers authorized to sell bearings to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> increased from two to 12. Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said that would have climbed to 30 companies by 1990 without the new regulations. Mrs. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and other industrial-area lawmakers are supporting an industry request to the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> urging restrictions on foreign imports. The department has until July to respond to last summer's request and make a recommendation to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Since 1980, the industry has lost 15,000 jobs, a 20 percent decrease. Thirty plant closings have left about 80 companies remaining and 43,000 employees, Ms. <PERSON> Willson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Iran-Contra Bjt   03-26 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Iran-Contra, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says He Believes in Innocence of Iran-Contra Defendants</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Critics say President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> interfered with the legal process by predicting that former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aides <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> will be acquitted of charges in the Iran-Contra affair. In off-the-cuff remarks Friday, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> called the affair `` the so-called scandal'' and said he still considers North `` a hero.'' But he refused to say whether he was considering granting any pardons in the case. `` I just have to believe that they're going to be found innocent because I do n't think they were guilty of any lawbreaking or any crime,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in response to a question at a seminar sponsored by the Center for the Study of the Presidency. North and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, along with arms dealers <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, pleaded innocent Thursday to charges of conspiracy, theft and fraud in the Iran-Contra case. The case involved the sale of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and the diversion of proceeds to the Nicaraguan Contras. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s comment about the innocence or guilt of people under criminal indictment `` is highly inappropriate `` His statement could adversely and improperly influence the execution of justice,'' <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON> told reporters on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has contributed to a prejudicial climate which could make it extremely difficult to get an unbiased jury in these cases,'' he said. `` The president has made a judgment about guilt or innocence which only a jury is supposed to decide under our system of justice.'' Professor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Banzhaf </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, called <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s remarks `` highly inappropriate'' and said they could influence jurors in the case. `` Millions of people feel strongly in favor of the president and his views carry great weight. He has an awful lot of credibility,'' said <PERSON> Banzhaf </PERSON>, a consumer advocate who has been associated with liberal causes. `` This is prejudging the case.'' In 1970, defense lawyers unsuccessfully sought dismissal of murder charges against <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> after then-President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> said <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> `` was guilty directly or indirectly of eight murders without reason.'' <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> subsequently issued a statement saying he had not intended to proclaim <PERSON> Manson </PERSON> guilty, and that a person was presumed innocent until proven otherwise. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>, questioned about <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s remarks, said, `` He's a man who tells you what he thinks and that's what he thinks.'' He said the president was `` a man of rare insight and perception, just giving his perception there.'' White House chief of staff <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> described the president's remarks as `` personal views,'' and said the president's `` official position is that the system must operate. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that when he learned that proceeds from the arms sales to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> had been channeled to the Contra cause, he had top aides brief congressional leaders and appointed a commission to probe the matter. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also noted that he had sought the appointment of a special counsel to investigate the diversion. `` Now, that's the whole extent of the so-called scandal,'' he said. `` What our intent was and what happened. And you know something? After all the investigations, today I still do n't know who got that extra money or where it came from. I'm hoping to find out.'' `` But I wanted you to know that I have some definite reason for still thinking <PERSON> Ollie </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> is a hero,'' he added. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> previously had said he did not think any laws were broken in the Iran-Contra affair, but had never gone so far as to predict acquittals.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     03-26 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Green Light Given For 475,000-Ton Wheat Sale To Soviets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five private exporters have been given the green light for subsidized sales to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> of 475,000 metric tons of hard red winter wheat, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. The government's <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has approved in-kind bonuses averaging $ 21.95 a ton in value to the exporters to send the wheat to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in May, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement Friday. Under the Export Enhancement Program, approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1985, grain companies and other exporters receive government-owned crops as bonuses to spur overseas sales of American commodities. Subsidized sales of wheat to the Soviets have totaled more than 10.8 million tons since last April, officials said. And the program is playing an increasingly large role in the overall <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm export picture. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, general sales manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, identified those receiving the bonuses and the amounts of grain involved as <ORGANIZATION> Garnac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 50,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, 200,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Mitsubishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 25,000 tons; <ORGANIZATION> Artfer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 50,000 and <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dreyfus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 150,000 tons. The Soviets may still purchase an additional 525,000 tons under a 2 million ton offer made by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Jan. 29. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also made the Soviets a further 1 million-ton offer on Saturday. The two countries are preparing to negotiate a new long-term grain agreement to replace the one that expires Sept. 30. It calls for the Soviets to buy 9 million metric tons a year, of which 4 million must be wheat and 4 million corn. The remainder may be in wheat, corn, soybeans or soybean meal, with every ton of beans or meal counting as two tons of grain. Despite the agreement wheat sales to the Soviets slumped badly in 1986 but picked up against last year as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gave that country the green light for purchases under the subsidy program.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Giveaways of government surplus milk to poor people are set to resume temporarily in June after a planned suspension in May, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Just how long the distribution of nonfat dry milk under the <ORGANIZATION> Temporary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Program </ORGANIZATION> can continue beyond June remains uncertain, the department said in a statement Friday. Suspension of the nonfat dry milk and cheese distributions was announced in February amid dwindling stocks of government-owned commodities. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> inventories, however, have again climbed to the point that 8 million pounds can be distributed through local food banks in June, the department said. `` At this time, we do not know if distribution of non-fat dry milk can be continued beyond June,'' Assistant Secretary for Food and Consumer Services <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bode </PERSON> said in a statement. He said the department would `` monitor our inventories and keep states informed of availability.'' `` The same is true for cheese,'' he said. `` If we get more, we'll give it away.'' Also announced in February was a suspension of rice and honey distributions this month because of declining reserves. The actions have drawn fire from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., is holding hearings on the problem of hunger and focusing on the TEFAP He planned a grocery-bagging session at a downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> food bank on Monday to draw attention to the issue. <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> said after the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> announcement of June milk distribution that he was `` pleased that there's an additional temporary supply for the month but this does not address the long-term problem.'' More than 5 billion pounds of surplus food worth more than $ 5 billion has been distributed since 1981 when the program got under way on orders from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, the department said. Seven types of goods have been provided: cheese, butter, nonfat dry milk, honey corn meal, flour and rice.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has set a May referendum for cattle producers and cattle and beef importers on whether to continue their current $ 1 per head promotional program. The department announced Friday that anyone who produces cattle or has imported beef or beef products since Oct. 1, 1986, will be eligible to vote. A simple majority of votes will determine whether to continue the promotions, which have included television spots by actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Garner </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Cybill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>. `` Real food for real people'' has been the slogan of the commercials. The referendum will take place on May 10 in all states except <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, where the voting will be one day earlier. Extension Service offices will distribute ballots in April and absentee ballots will be available from them by mail. The program is funded by a fee of $ 1 per head on all domestic and imported cattle and an equivalent fee on beef imports. It was established under federal legislation approved in 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Nicaragua Bjt   03-26 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Nicaragua, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Expresses Doubts About Nicaragua Keeping Cease-Fire
Agreement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican conservatives in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are wary of the Nicaraguan cease-fire, with one saying the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may have to `` take some action with external forces'' if the Contra rebels quit the field. `` It's down to that,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, R-Wash. `` It's definitely a new era <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON> was among <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> conservatives attending a retreat Friday in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, meanwhile, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said that `` there is reason to have caution'' about whether <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government will keep its agreements <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s comments were his first statement in any detail on the 60-day nationwide cease-fire announced Wednesday in <LOCATION> Sapoa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, by leaders of the Sandinista government and the U.S.-backed Contra guerrilla force. `` Of course we look forward to this and hope it continues, but ... just as in some other meetings that have gone on in which I have been involved, I think that we should keep in mind that both parties must be dedicated to the things that are said and agreed to in those meetings,'' the president said. `` I think there is reason to have caution _ they have a past record that indicates that we should be,'' he added. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was questioned by reporters as he prepared to meet with President <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Balaguer </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. In a formal statement as he appeared with <PERSON> Balaguer </PERSON> in the Rose Garden after the meeting, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> commended the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> president for hosting previous Nicaraguan peace talks, mediated by Roman Catholic Cardinal <PERSON> Obando </PERSON> y Bravo. `` We both hope for democratic and peaceful solutions to the problems of the region,'' he said. `` We want to see an end to the pursuit of military solutions and to the massive Soviet armament that fuels that pursuit.'' During his daily <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news briefing earlier, presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the administration believes `` that this agreement has been reached by both sides in good faith'' but is `` skeptical of the compliance.'' `` We're very hopeful that it works,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` We want to do whatever we can to see that it works.'' The spokesman also said the administration is `` very hopeful'' that a package of humanitarian assistance to the Contras can be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' Easter recess. He said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had no intention of entering into direct discussions with the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>, as suggested by Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>. `` We've discussed that two years,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` The answer is no.'' At the <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> retreat, <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON> said that if the Contras fold their tents and it is `` back to the usual Sandinista behavior'' of totalitarian rule, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will have to `` take some action with external forces ... external, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, who has co-sponsored a plan to renew military aid to the Contras, said he expected <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the meantime to approve rapidly some new humanitarian support for the Contras with the option of adding military aid if things turn sour. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, other conservatives criticized the agreement, but appeared willing to put the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to the test and wait to see whether promised democratic reforms materialize. `` It's an agreement that's shaded on the bad side,'' said Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, said, `` A sense of euphoria is not in order ... I do n't believe I've ever heard of a leopard changing his spots.'' Sen. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said, `` The end product of what they've agreed to still leaves a Soviet puppet state in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Candidates-Schedules     03-26 0351</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Candidates-Schedules,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Candidates' Schedules</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are tentative schedules for the presidential candidates for the week beginning March 27. The information was provided by the candidates. Sunday, March 27: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dole </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Monday, March 28: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Middlebury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Waterbury </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Haven </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cedarburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> D.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Tuesday, March 29: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Osh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kosh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Appleton </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Stevens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Waukesha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Wednesday, March 30: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gore </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ Madison, <PERSON> Eau </PERSON> <PERSON> Claire </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Thursday, March 31: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Friday, April 1: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gephardt </LOCATION> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ down Saturday, April 2: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> _ open Sunday, April 3: Democrats: <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> _ <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Simon </LOCATION> _ <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republicans: <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> _ open <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Obit-Howard     03-26 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Howard,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Howard Dies Peacefully, Leaving Powerful Post Open</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McHUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, whose death at age 60 leaves open a powerful congressional post, was a widely admired lawmaker who loved a good legislative scrap almost as much as he loved golf. The 60-year-old Democrat died Friday, a day after suffering a heart attack on a suburban <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> golf course, his office said. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, influential chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, succumbed at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Center </LOCATION> here at 1:46 p.m., said aide <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Smallen </PERSON>. A Roman Catholic funeral was planned for Tuesday in <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, <PERSON> N.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>'s office said the <LOCATION> Spring </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION> lawmaker died `` of complications arising from a heart attack ... from which his heart never fully recovered.'' They did not elaborate. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, a 22-year House veteran, was stricken Thursday while playing the first hole of a morning round of golf. `` His last memory was that he was wearing Irish green and hit a great shot that landed him on the green in two,'' said his daughter <PERSON> Marie </PERSON>, who was with him at the time. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Marlene </PERSON>, and their two other daughters also were with him. Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., recalled <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>'s fondness for <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s brother, the late President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> `` The last time I saw him, last week, he asked me for another PT-109 tie clip, and we reminisced again about <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>'s 1960 campaign,'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said in a statement. House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said of Howard: `` He worked hard, played hard, loved his family, his state and his country with a burning intensity.'' Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> was one of his first friends in politics. `` He leaves a great legacy of accomplishments,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> was known among colleagues as one of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s toughest horse traders. He was an aggressive and agile lawmaker who wielded his considerable clout in an old-fashioned, behind-the-scenes way. The committee he headed since 1981 is one of the least glamorous but most powerful in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. It has jurisdiction over multibillion dollar highway and water projects, as well as the airline and trucking industries. Once in 1985, <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lawmakers mounted a plan to legalize dumping of their state's sewage off the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> coast. Suddenly, money for a much sought-after <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION> tunnel slipped to the bottom of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'s agenda. Elected in 1964, he rose to become the second most senior member of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> congressional delegation after Rep. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodino </PERSON>, the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who says he will not seek re-election. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> represented the 3rd Congressional District along <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>'s central shorefront. Rep. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, D-Calif., the ranking Democrat of the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION>, is in line to succeed <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> Any new chairman must be approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Caucus.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChambersChronology     03-26 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chambers Chronology,0391</SECOND>
<HEAD>How `Preppie Murder' Case Unfolded</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Chambers, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chronology of the <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> case: _ Sept 20 and 26, 1985 _ <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> allegedly burglarizes three apartments, stealing furs, jewelry, silver and art. _ Aug 25, 1986 _ Chambers goes to the bar <PERSON> Dorrian </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hand </ORGANIZATION> about 11:30 p.m. and runs into <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, 18, who arrives shortly after midnight. _ Aug 26, 1986 _ Chambers and <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> leave <PERSON> Dorrian </PERSON>'s for Central Park about 4:10 a.m. 6:15 a.m. _ Bicyclist finds <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s body behind Metropolitan Museum of Art; police officer spots Chambers sitting on nearby wall. 2:15 p.m. _ Police pick up Chambers at his <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> home. 9 p.m. _ Chambers admits lying to police about whether he left <PERSON> Dorrian </PERSON>'s with <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>. Provides a written statement. _ Aug 27, 1986 _ Provides videotaped statement. _ Sept 10, 1986 _ Chambers indicted on two counts of second-degree murder. _ Sept 22, 1986 _ Chambers pleads innocent. _ Sept 29, 1986 _ <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>, the trial judge, sets bail at $ 150,000. _ Oct 1, 1986 _ Chambers released on bail after bar owner <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorrian </PERSON> puts up his house as collateral. _ Oct 15, 1986 _ Chambers indicted on three burglary counts; <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> orders an additional $ 7,500 bail. _ Oct 21, 1986 _ Chambers attorney <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Litman </PERSON> asks prosecutor <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairstein </PERSON> to turn over <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s diary, saying it chronicles a kinky sex life. _ Dec 23, 1986 _ <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> diary turned over to <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION>. _ Jan 28, 1987 _ <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> refuses to turn diary over to <PERSON> Litman </PERSON>. _ April 1, 1987 _ <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Fillyaw </PERSON>, who identified Chambers as his accomplice in two Sept. 26, 1985 burglaries, pleads guilty to burglary _ Oct 16, 1987 _ Bell rules Chambers' written and video statements will be allowed at trial. _ Oct 21, 1987 _ Jury selection begins. _ Dec 18, 1987 _ Jury seated. _ Jan 4, 1988 _ Opening statements. _ March 1, 1988 _ Prosecution rests after calling 25 witnesses _ March 4, 1988 _ Jury visits Central Park site of Miss <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>'s _ March 10, 1988 _ <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> rests after calling five witnesses _ March 17, 1988 _ Deliberations begin _ March 25, 1988 _ Chambers pleads guilty to first-degree manslaughter
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IBM-Chips     03-26 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-IBM-Chips,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report IBM Offered Chip Technology to Rival</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> offered last year to sell important computer chip technology to <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in an effort to keep <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> from becoming more dependent on Japanese suppliers, a published report said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, citing a forthcoming book and sources in the industry, said <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> apparently believes the entire American electronics industry could be weakened by growing dependence on Japanese semiconductor technology. <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION>'s offer is reported in a book entitled `` Trading Places: How We Allowed <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to Take the Lead,'' written by <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Prestowitz </PERSON> and scheduled for publication in late April, The Times said. <PERSON> Prestowitz </PERSON>, formerly the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s chief trade negotiator with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, wrote that in mid-1987, <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> approached <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION>, `` its most dangerous domestic rival, and offered to transfer certain key technologies. `` At first DEC suspected a trick, then it realized the objective was to prevent <ORGANIZATION> DEC </ORGANIZATION> from falling even further into Japanese hands,'' <PERSON> Prestowitz </PERSON> wrote. His book does not elaborate on what technology was offered or whether <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> accepted the offer, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. Spokesmen for <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Digital </ORGANIZATION> would not confirm whether such talks occurred, but other industry sources who declined to be identified verified that <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> had made such an offer, the newspaper said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SalamanderStreet     03-26 0404</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salamander Street,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salamander Tunnel Fails First Test</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A lone salamander made its way through a tunnel built to prevent cars from crushing the amphibians during their annual trek across a street in this college town. `` It was an historic event. It was the first salamander to go through a tunnel all on its own,'' <LOCATION> Shutesbury </LOCATION> school teacher <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON> said Friday. But 39 other salamanders bypassed the tunnels, to the dismay of onlookers. Fifty people turned out on a drizzly Thursday night to watch the salamanders cross <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Street </PERSON> to reach a breeding pond _ a route that results in death for many of the creatures each spring. The watchers ended up barricading the street and carrying about 40 of the struggling yellow-spotted amphibians across the road. The tunnels installed for the salamanders under the street were ignored by all but the one. Shouts went up when the salamander was discovered crawling along a fence leading to one of the tunnels. The creature made it through in 5 minutes, 20 seconds, said <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON>, who lives about a mile from the street. The salamander tunnels were installed after a public outcry over the amphibians' plight. Local naturalist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> persuaded town officials to close the street last year until all the salamanders had emerged from their underground hibernation to make the nighttime trek during warm rains, which usually takes a week. The three 19-inch-high tunnels of polymer concrete were donated by ACO Polymer Products of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> and installed in November for about $ 2,000. Volunteers erected fences in January to guide the salamanders to the tunnels. The fences failed their first test, but townspeople said it was too early to tell how the experiment would fare. `` There were very few salamanders out, probably because there's not enough of a saturation rate yet to rouse the rest of the population,'' said <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON> Townspeople had different theories to explain why all but one of the salamanders bypassed the tunnels. <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON>, who also coordinated a contest for `` Salamander Crossing'' sings, said the salamanders might have been hibernating between the fence and the road. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Minear </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Selectmen </ORGANIZATION>, said the tunnels may not have been wet enough for the salamanders' liking. The town's superintendent of public works said he is in the process of hanging the crossing signs, designed by <LOCATION> Shutesbury </LOCATION> fourth-grader <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> Mackintosh </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Grossman     03-26 0238</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Grossman,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Root Canal Therapy Pioneer Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWTOWN, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Irwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON>, a pioneer in root canal therapy, has died at age 86. A professor emeritus at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON> in 1940 wrote one of the first textbooks on endodontics, or root canal therapy, the removal of diseased soft tissue from inside the tooth. `` Endodontic Practice'' is now in its 11th printing and is used worldwide, said <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON> <PERSON> Holzman </PERSON>, a university spokeswoman. <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON>, who died Thursday at home, began teaching at the dental school in 1926. `` Through his pioneering research in the field and his clinical care, endodontics got started and is where it is today,'' he said. <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON> developed methods for removing diseased pulp, the soft tissue inside the tooth, sterilizing the hollowed area and filling it with inert material to strengthen the tooth, said Dr. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON>, the school's dean. Before root canal therapy, abscessed teeth had to be extracted. <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON> was named an honorary fellow of the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surgeons </ORGANIZATION> in 1984. He retired in 1968. <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON> was born in a Ukrainian village near <LOCATION> Odessa </LOCATION> and was brought to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by his family as boy. He earned a doctorate in dental surgery from <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> in 1923 and a doctorate in medical dentistry at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rostock </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1928. Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Emma </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON>; a daughter, and a son.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets 1stLd-Writethru a0795 03-26 0200</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0795,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Prices Down</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with stock closing comments. No
pickup</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stock prices declined sharply for the third straight day in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> Saturday, following an overnight tumble on Wall Street. On the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, the Nikkei Average of 225 selected issues, which lost 154.57 points Friday, shed 305.99 more points, or 1.2 percent, during Saturday's half-day session to finish the week at 25,320.72. `` Prices were down almost across the board prompted by profit-taking selling,'' said <PERSON> Hiromi </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoneyama </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Wako </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>. He said investors sidestepped the market, following the second straight tumble on Wall Street, and before the close of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 1987 fiscal year, which ends on March 31 <PERSON> Yoneyama </PERSON>, however, added investors appeared to be optimistic about the prospects for the new fiscal year. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Friday, the Dow Jones average of 30 industrials fell 44.92 points to 1,978.95 at the close of the market's worst week this year. On the first section in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> trading, major losers included large-capital issues, such as steels, heavy electricals and shipbuildings. A light 400 million shares were traded during the session. The foreign exchange market is closed on Saturdays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-DearAbby     03-26 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Dear Abby,0141</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Dear Abby' Calls on Lawmakers to Ban Certain Animal Tests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Syndicated columnist <PERSON> Abigail </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON> called on state legislators to pass a bill that would ban the use of animal tests for cosmetics and household products. `` Dear Abby,'' as she is known to millions of readers of her daily advice column, said at a news conference that she is not opposed to animal testing for medical research when necessary. But `` it's not necessary for floor wax or lipstick,'' she said. Some makers of cosmetics and cleaning products told lawmakers that animal testing is necessary to ensure the safety of their products for humans. The <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> appearance is not the end of Miss <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>'s campaign `` I'm going to use my column as a platform to do this nationally,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0252EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     03-26 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Malfitano Sings her First Met `Lulu'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Malfitano </PERSON> sang the title role in <PERSON> Berg </PERSON>'s `` Lulu'' for the first time at the Metropolitan Opera on Friday night. She sang it well, leaving only the question of whether the luminous lyric quality of her soprano voice will survive a role composed with so many shrieks on top and such angular intervals. She is singing all six performances, which includes the Saturday afternoon radio broadcast of April 2. Tenor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, made his Met debut as <PERSON> Alwa </PERSON> on Friday night. `` Lulu'' is a difficult opera in which to judge voices but <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> certainly coped with the very high range of a fairly large but thankless role. <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazura </PERSON> was excellent as Dr. <PERSON> Schon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alwa </PERSON>'s father. <PERSON> Tatiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Troyanos </PERSON> was properly self-sacrificing as the Countess. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> conducted, with the orchestra sometimes at times overpowering the singers. The <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> production, from 1977, captures the decadence of the story in which everybody falls for <PERSON> Lulu </PERSON>, some to die of suicide, murder or shock. The Met performed `` Lulu'' for the first time in 1977 and performed it with the third act added, making it a four-hour evening, for the first time in 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nancy-Hockey     03-26 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nancy-Hockey,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Goes 2 For 3 In Hockey Anti-Drug Ceremony</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LANDOVER, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went two for three in goals as she wielded a hockey stick during a ceremony to thank athletes for promoting the `` Just Say No'' anti-drug campaign. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> made two goals in three shots during her appearance before a sellout crowd at the Capital Centre just after the first period of the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Flyers-Washington Capitals game Friday night. When Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was introduced, most of the sellout crowd of 18,130 stood and applauded. She was joined on the Capital Centre ice by <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, and 30 `` Just Say No'' skaters, including one dressed as the Peanuts character Snoopy. `` Athletes are very important role models for our young people,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. `` I'm very grateful for all of their help.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took a hockey stick and made three shots on <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Capitals goaltender <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Peeters </PERSON>. Two shots went in. Each of the 21 <ORGANIZATION> NHL </ORGANIZATION> teams will participate in a salute to the Just Say No Foundation at games being played this week across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EasternAirlines     03-26 0292</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern Airlines,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Denies Stay in Eastern Airlines Case</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Retransmitting a0406 to correct cycle designator.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court will hear arguments May 6 on whether to dismiss a contempt ruling against <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> for its attempt to sell its <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> shuttle. The hearing date was set Friday, when the court also refused a request by Eastern to block a set of sanctions levied against the carrier. The ruling by the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> means <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>, at least temporarily, will have to halt its efforts to sell the shuttle while it conducts a legal battle with its largest labor union. Judges <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sentelle </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silberman </PERSON> all voted to deny <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s request to drop the sanctions. On March 10, District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> found Eastern in contempt for trying to sell its shuttle for $ 225 million. Eastern, a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, proposed selling the shuttle to a new company to be created within <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> found that the proposed sale violated an order he issued last July that Eastern not change the working conditions of its 12,000 employees represented by the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. Company officials had said Eastern was in the red and needed the cash from the sale, but union leaders said the deal really was intended to weaken the labor organization. Monday, <PERSON> Pratt </PERSON> ruled that until the case was settled, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> would have to halt all efforts to gain government approval of the shuttle sale. The judge also threatened to fine the airline $ 10,000 daily for future violations. Under Friday's ruling, the sanctions will remain in place until <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s appeal of the contempt ruling is decided.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Afghan     03-26 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Afghan,280</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Halting Stingers To Afghan Rebels In Anticipation Of
Settlement</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is halting its supply of Stinger missiles to the Afghan rebels because of concern the weapons could be left to Afghan factions that could n't be controlled if <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military ties were severed, according to a published report today. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, citing diplomatic and other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources that it did not identify, also reported that the administration is rushing at least $ 300 million in other weapons to the resistance before an agreement is reached that would ban such outside assistance. Among the U.S.-purchased military equipment being rushed to the resistance are 120mm Spanish heavy mortars and modern mine-clearing weapons, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. The decision to stop supplying the anti-aircraft Stingers apparently was reached late last month in anticipation of a peace settlement in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the newspaper said. `` Certainly we would not want the war to end with a lot of them unused,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, a strong supporter of the resistance who said he did not know if a decision had been made to stop supplying the Stingers. Last month, an Afghan guerrilla commander either sold or was forced to hand over some Stingers to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. Pieces of a Stinger were found on an Iranian gunboat involved in a shooting incident with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> helicopter helping the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> escort mission in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> last October. The Afghan rebels started receiving the Stingers in mid-1986 and they reportedly have gotten more than 1,000 of them, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said. A withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> was a major topic discussed during this past week's visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> of Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Cubic-FalseTests     03-26 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cubic-False Tests,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Cubic Workers Accused Of Falsifying Mine Detector Tests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <ORGANIZATION> Cubic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> employees were charged Friday with falsifying test results on hand-held mine detectors produced for the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. In announcing the indictment, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> also said that the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego-based </LOCATION> defense contractor had agreed to pay the government $ 7.25 million to settle a civil suit stemming from the allegations. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON>, 55, of <LOCATION> Tullahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fink </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, pleaded innocent in federal court Friday to conspiracy to defraud the government, making false statements and submitting false claims for payment. Each of the 24 counts in the indictment carries a maximum penalty of five years in prison and a $ 10,000 fine. Cubic held a $ 9 million Army contract to produce and retrofit more than 8,500 detectors designed to locate mines in arid soil. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the devices were never used in combat by American forces. <PERSON> Fink </PERSON> was the senior associate engineer on the technical staff, while <PERSON> Bauder </PERSON> was the program manager for Cubic Defense Systems on the contract signed in 1981. Before full-scale production could begin, Cubic had to demonstrate that it could mass produce mine-detectors that worked as effectively as earlier prototypes, the indictment said. The indictment alleged that the test results were falsified so that the mine detectors appeared to function better than they really did. As a result of the false information, the indictment said, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> gave approval for full-scale production but terminated the contract in 1984 because of equipment faults. In the civil suit, prosecutors alleged Cubic knowingly presented false claims for payment because some company officials were aware that the detectors had failed the tests. Under an agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, Cubic company will remain a government contractor. `` Since the events leading to the indictment, Cubic has taken the necessary steps to avoid a recurrence of similar conduct,'' <PERSON> Nunez </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Panama Bjt   03-26 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama, Bjt,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Can't Pay His Troops, Essentials In Shorter Supply</HEAD>
<BYLINE>LaserPhoto PAN1
^By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has failed for the first time to pay the 15,000 troops supporting him as <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economic crisis deepens and the opposition promises more confrontation. Also Friday, the civilian government that acts for <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> threatened to revoke stores' licenses unless they stop observing a week-long general strike and open to sell such essentials as food, medicine and gasoline. The strike has shut down more than 90 percent of the nation's commerce Cash and food are in short supply. The opposition, meanwhile, said it was planning massive street anti-Noriega demonstrations for Monday that appeared likely to trigger a confrontation with troops loyal to the general. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, under indictment in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on drug trafficking charges, once again claimed the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, in a desire to hold on to the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, is behind his country's troubles `` A man is not the problem,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said of himself on Friday. `` The problem is <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s canal and the presence of a foreign army in our territory.'' In an attempt to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> into exile, the White House has had Panamanian deposits in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks frozen and payments for use of the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> withheld. The former canal zone is headquarters to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military's <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> Under a 1977 treaty, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will cede control of the canal by the year 2000. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> denied any connections with drug-trafficking pilots whose testimony led to his indictments last month, and joked about reports he wields a $ 200 million fortune: `` Bring it to me, bring it to me and I'll pay off <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s foreign debt.'' He implied force might be used to make the nation's banks re-open. On Thursday, they refused to hand over an estimated $ 70 million in their vaults so the government could pay the army on Friday, pensioners Monday, and 130,000 public employees over the next week. Banks have refused to open, partly to support the general strike and partly because they fear a panic run on their deposits. `` Those who understand such things consider it necessary to open the banks,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said. Opposition leaders said they hoped <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s soldiers would stop supporting him now that they have joined the 2.5 million Panamanians who have gone without pay for up to a month. But the anti-Noriega umbrella group, The National Civic Crusade, suffered a surprising blow Friday when <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> Archbishop <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> failed to issue an expected statement strongly condemning <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and supporting Monday's planned demonstration. <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, who had met with <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> on Thursday, would only say on Friday that he planned to meet with again with the general, who heads <PERSON> Panamana </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, ended a two-day fact-finding trip Friday saying he was `` still hopeful that at some time the Church will be able to make a statement that will bring a happier remedy than we have seen so far.'' <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, D-Pa., issued a statement saying `` there is absolute unanimity that Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> should go, and that his departure is only a function of time. That sentiment was echoed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 92-0 to demand that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> increase economic sanctions to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> out. In the former canal zone, wives of the mostly American ship pilots who guide vessels through the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> _ and could shut the waterway down if they went on strike _ demonstrated in front of the joint U.S.-Panamanian commission that runs the canal. They complained they were being harassed by Panamanian troops who set up roadblocks at intersections across <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, questioning motorists and searching their cars. `` We feel like we are hostages within the political crisis because we feel unsafe going into town,'' said <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsson </PERSON>, wife of a canal pilot. The problem was apparently resolved later Friday, but the <ORGANIZATION> Panama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and the commission refused to say what arrangements were made.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     03-26 0674</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>New POW Medal Ready To Be Issued</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new medal being issued to honor American prisoners of war features an eagle surrounded by barbed wire and bayonet points and includes the inscription, `` For Honorable Service While a Prisoner of War.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday it was ready to begin issuing the new military medals, which <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> authorized two years ago. About 142,200 individuals or their families will be eligible for the awards, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. The medals can be awarded posthumously to legal next-of-kin. The phone number for requesting an application form is 800-873-3768. Personal letters requesting award of the medal or more information should be sent to one of these three addresses: _ For former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> prisoners of war: <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, Attn: DARP-PAS-EAW, 9700 Page Blvd., <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. 63132-5200. _ For former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> prisoners of war: <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liaison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, 9700 Page Blvd., <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION> 63132-5199. _ For former <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> prisoners of war: <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Branch </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, 9700 Page Blvd., <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION> 63132-5199.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Fiscal Survey Finds Most States Sound But Close To Financial Edge</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new `` Fiscal Survey of the States'' finds that most states tightened their budget belts last year and are reluctant to start major new programs this year because of uncertainty about the economy. The report from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, says most states are in sound financial shape, although states such as <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> are facing tough financial times because of their reliance on the troubled energy industry. Most states, however, are close to the financial edge, according to the report released Friday. It found that the majority of states will end the year with only small budget balances. Those balances are expected to fall to 1.5 percent of total expenditures at the end of next fiscal year, the lowest level since the recession of 1983, when it was 1.3 percent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Military Exercise To Take Place Atlantic, Gulf, Caribbean</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon says this year's `` Ocean Venture'' exercise will take place in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> as well as at selected bases in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. More than 40,000 servicemen are expected to participate in the exercise, which begins on April 1 and extends through April 22, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. `` Ocean Venture exercises are held every two years and are designed to demonstrate the joint forces capability of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> to rapidly project military power,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. The exercise will include aircraft carrier operations; airborne, amphibious and infantry assaults; live-fire exercises, and port security, harbor defense and combat search and rescue drills, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Senators Urge Caution On Giving Submarine Secrets to Canada</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two senators say the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should be cautious about allowing the sale to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> of highly secret <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> submarine technology. Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, D-Neb., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> strategic weapons subcommittee, said Friday that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear-powered sub technology had only been transferred once in the past, to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, and he questioned whether <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> has `` the money and the enormous infrastructure'' needed to safely operate the subs Any accidents aboard Canadian subs which involve <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technology would raise fears about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> subs and could hamper the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s operation, he said in a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>. R-Va., said, `` before we approve this decision, we need to know how <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> proposes to fund this program, how <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> proposes to insure that the standard of nuclear safety will be at least as high as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the British. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> is considering building vessels which are updated versions of the British Trafalgar-class subs or the French Rubis-class subs. The Trafalgars use <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technology, which means the information could not be supplied to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> by the British unless the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> approves, both <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0314EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Panama-Life     03-26 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Panama-Life,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panamanians Selling Bootleg Beer &amp; Stealing To Eat</HEAD>
<BYLINE>With PM-Panama, Bjt
^By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> and his wife <PERSON> Donilda </PERSON>, teachers at government high schools who have n't been paid since mid-month, are selling bootleg beer to feed themselves and their three children. They eat only twice a day. Even so, they are luckier than one neighbor in the poor <LOCATION> Villa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guadalupe </LOCATION> neighborhood in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miguelito </LOCATION> hills on the outskirts of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, who had sent her children out to steal. As the opposition exerts pressure to oust strongman Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and cash grows increasingly scarce, many Panamanians are relying on donated food to stay alive. Families have sent their children to stay with relatives in the countryside, where fresh milk and produce is at least more readily available than in the capital. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON>, who insisted on not being further identified for fear of reprisal, said several stores in his neighborhood, mostly owned by Panamanians of Chinese descent, have been robbed during the past couple of weeks. `` People are not stealing money, they are stealing food,'' he said. `` This woman the other day told her kids to go in that store and grab some milk. When the owner came chasing after them, she faced him with a big stick and told him her kids had to eat and she would kill him if he tried to stop them.'' `` What do we tell the kids we are teaching?'' <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> asked. `` We have suffered years of bad government in this country,'' he said of 20 years under military rule. `` I am not very political, but things must change ... <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s departure would be the beginning of the political solution.'' The general, who heads the 15,000-strong <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and is <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto ruler, is under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment on charges of trafficking in Colombian cocaine. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, seeking to force him out, has frozen virtually all <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s funds in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks, including <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> tolls, the country's main source of revenue. Since the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar is <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s currency, the cash shortage became doubly acute. Most of the country's 118 banks have been closed for three weeks, some for longer. There have been street demonstrations, some of them violent, and a general strike has paralyzed the nation since Monday. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has dug in his heels and refuses to leave. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> and his wife, together normally net $ 170 a month after deductions for taxes and payments on a government-financed mortgage on their three-bedroom concrete block home. Each got their last paycheck _ for $ 75 _ on March 15. It was the last time the government paid employees, and many did n't get anything. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> used to make about $ 40 more a month refereeing soccer matches. But the games have n't been played since the crisis began. There is no money. A strong, wiry man with a mustache and a tiny tuft of beard on his chin, <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> held his restless 4-year-old son <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON>, trying to quiet him. `` We make adjustments, we survive,'' he said. That morning, <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> and his family had oatmeal, some cheese and bread for breakfast. <PERSON> Donilda </PERSON> was planning to cook some fish and rice for lunch. But there would be `` some tea and bread only in the evening,'' she said. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> said he had n't paid his light and water bills. With the schools closed until further notice, <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> spends his time doing odd jobs around the house, training his 12-year-old daughter <LOCATION> Zulia </LOCATION> and other kids in the neighborhood in track and field. And he digs into his savings, buying American bootleg beer and cigarettes which he resells, making about $ 4 profit on each case of beer. `` A lot of people are doing that. People will always buy beer,'' he explained, sweating in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s tropical heat. A few blocks away, several hundred people stood in line outside the <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redeemer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which has been donating bags of food and running a soup kitchen for the destitute.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Mexico-Centam     03-26 0412</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Centam,0421</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Mexican President Criticizes U.S. Central American Policy As
^With US-Nicaragua, Bjt
^By JAVIER PICHARDINI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CANCUN, Mexico (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> strongly criticized the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration for stressing might over diplomacy in its Central American policy _ at a high cost in death and destruction. `` We oppose the justification for acts of intervention or economic coercion'' in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, he said Friday during a state dinner for visiting President <PERSON> Vinicio </PERSON> <PERSON> Cerezo </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. `` The protection of our security is n't associated with strategic projects of doubtful standing,'' he added in comments clearly aimed at the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration though not mentioning the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by name. De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Cerezo </ORGANIZATION> held two rounds of private talks Friday in this <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> resort on the <LOCATION> Yucatan </LOCATION> peninsula. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s own interests in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> are jeopardized by instability in the region, de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> declared in the rare attack on his country's northern neighbor. `` <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> perceives the overflow of the Central American conflict as a risk affecting its legitimate interests and provoking disorder and instability that threaten our institutions,'' he said. De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> referred to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> financing of the Contra rebels who have been fighting <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Sandinista government for six years and the dispatch of 3,200 American troops to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> on March 17 after an alleged incursion by Nicaraguan troops chasing Contra fighters. Military sources in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> say the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops are going home Monday, now that a <LOCATION> Sandinsta-Contra </LOCATION> truce is holding with the two sides' agreement Wednesday to cease hostilities and seek to forge a lasting peace. De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> also criticized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade and economic sanctions against <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> that are aimed at forcing the ouster of that country's military strongman, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` Stubbornness in imposing military options over diplomatic efforts is producing a conflict whose high costs in death and destruction we can neither tolerate nor view with indifference,'' the president said. De la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> first voiced criticism of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in the region Monday, when he said `` it is not with the movement of troops, nor with the financing of subversion from whatever origin that the problems of the area which is vital to the interests of the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> people are resolved.'' Conflicts in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> stems from economic and social causes, he said, declaring that his nation would search for solutions that `` guarantee the legitimate interests'' of the region. <ORGANIZATION> Cerezo </ORGANIZATION> and de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> were scheduled to conclude their talks today.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CelestialShower 1stLd-Writethru a0450 03-26 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Celestial Shower, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0450,0449</SECOND>
<HEAD>Flaming Object Lights Up Skies Over Texas</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Eds: UPDATES throughout with <ORGANIZATION> NORAD </ORGANIZATION> spokesman saying object launched from <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, eyewitness descriptions. No pickup.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Flaming Object Lights Up Skies Over Texas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet space debris bigger than a railroad boxcar re-entered the atmosphere in a brilliant atmospheric fireworks display Friday night that triggered phone calls from curious skywatchers in three states, officials said. `` I saw a meteorite once that was pretty spectacular, but this one just blew that away. This was the most amazing celestial event I've ever seen,'' said <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Farr </PERSON>, 33, of Round Rock, who watched from his front yard. `` It was part of a package that was sent up a couple of days ago from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'' said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Ivan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinnell </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> NORAD </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Colo </PERSON>. The object, which was `` larger than a railroad boxcar,'' re-entered the atmosphere around 10:50 p.m. CST, <PERSON> Pinnell </PERSON> said. The chances of it causing any damage on the ground were highly improbable, he said. `` When an object like that re-enters, it breaks up in the atmosphere, and you have these smaller pieces and sometimes you have quite a show,'' <PERSON> Pinnell </PERSON> said. The re-entry was seen in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NORAD </ORGANIZATION> had been tracking the object by satellite, he said. `` We knew this was going to re-enter, but exactly where was hard to predict, as far as the exact time and location,'' he said. Most of the phone calls about the fiery re-entry came from the <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> areas, but the object was seen as far away as <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Pinnell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hecke </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> meteorologist who operates a weather station from his home in <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION>, 30 miles south of <LOCATION> Waco </LOCATION>, said the object looked like a meteorite to him. `` It was closer and larger than anything I've ever seen anything before, and I've been real active watching the skies since 1963,'' <PERSON> Hecke </PERSON> said. He said he called a number of radio stations after the sighting and said it had been seen in <LOCATION> Lawton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>. Cars along Interstate 35 pulled off the road to watch the fireworks, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribble </PERSON>, a newsman for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> who was driving on the interstate when he saw the re-entry He said it looked like the sparks caused by a car whose muffler has come loose and is dragging along the roadway. `` It just kept growing, like a sparkler,'' said <PERSON> Farr </PERSON>, a 33-year-old technical writer for <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Instruments </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. `` It went across the entire sky.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880326-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-26-88 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LowcountryBaskets Bjt   03-26 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lowcountry Baskets, Bjt,0542</SECOND>
<HEAD>Condos Threaten Ancient Craft As Sweetgrass Disappears</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
