<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-VPWimps     07-15 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-VP Wimps,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fight Wimpdom, Abolish Vice Presidency, Professor Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MADISON, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The vice presidency converts respectable politicians into champagne-sipping wimps and ought to be abolished, a political scientist says. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hubert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> were examples of vigorous congressmen who became victims of a job that has little authority. <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON>, an associate director of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Robert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> M. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Follette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, also said the office is outmoded because the founding fathers conceived of the vice presidency as an advisory post Yet presidents today have plenty of advisers, he said. Worst of all, <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON> said, is the effect the vice presidency has on the people who hold the office. `` The vice presidency turns a vigorous, robust individual into a wimp,'' he said. `` After a few years as vice president, even a previously vigorous and creative political leader turns into a wishy-washy, mealy-mouthed sycophant.'' `` Vice presidents have always been wimps. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> were all wimpy vice presidents,'' he said. `` In order to do the job as vice president, they must play the role of a meek and humble servant, a presidential loyalist, a defender of the president's position,'' he said. The country could easily turn to the secretary of state or the speaker of the House of Representatives for a successor if a president were to die in office, he said. The secretary of state also could perform many of the vice president's functions, he said. `` The secretary of state can sip champagne at diplomatic parties and look somber and dignified at state funerals,'' <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON> said. `` The vice president is eminently dispensable.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0257EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EmbassyGunman     07-15 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Embassy Gunman,0509</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest Lebanese Gunman After Standoff At Libyan Embassy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police ended a nearly 12-hour standoff with an armed Lebanese man barricaded in the Libyan Embassy by rushing in and grabbing the gunman after he had fallen asleep, officials said. No shots were fired in the incident Thursday, and a handful of Libyan embassy employees who had been trapped on the top floors were not injured, police said. Police identified the man as <PERSON> El-Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON>, 22, and said he had escaped from a prison in <LOCATION> Goettingen </LOCATION> on July 8 along with a <LOCATION> Turkish </LOCATION> accomplice who has since been recaptured. <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> was serving a three-year prison term for assault, police said. For nearly 12 hours police negotiated with <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON>, who pulled out a pistol inside the embassy's first-floor reception room after he was denied a visa for <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. Embassy employees were able to flee the building quickly or run to the upper floors, leaving <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> by himself, police said. `` He had become very weak since his escape and looked exhausted during the negotiations,'' said <PERSON> Ulrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>, head of the <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> police team that captured <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>'s team was able to watch <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> by making use of a video camera that is a normal part of embassy security. At about 9:15 p.m., police noticed <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> had fallen asleep and they rushed him, <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON> said. `` Finally, he just fell asleep from exhaustion,'' said <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>. `` He did not offer us any resistance.'' Police said they did not know where <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> got the pistol. <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> was taken to a local hospital for examination, officials said. A team of police officers negotiated with the gunman for almost 12 hours by telephone as well as through a metal-barred door at the entrance to the structure. `` He demanded that he not be returned to prison. He said he wanted to go to <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> because the Libyans always help the Lebanese,'' said <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>. Police spokesman <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Classen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. But he said <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> police did not know how long <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> had lived in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, whether he had any relatives in this country or know any other details about the man other than his prison record. <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> had been at the prison in <LOCATION> Goettingen </LOCATION> for about 18 months, <PERSON> Classen </PERSON> said. Shortly after the standoff began, heavily armed police officers wearing combat gear climbed through a second-story window into the embassy, known as the <ORGANIZATION> Libyan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. Those officers guarded access to the upper floors of the five-story building in case <PERSON> Edelbi </PERSON> tried to take hostages from among the employees on the higher floors, <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bukhries </PERSON>, head of the embassy, had given police permission to enter the building, <PERSON> Classen </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bukhries </PERSON> was able to escape through a side door shortly after the standoff began. Police sealed off the area after embassy employees signaled an alarm shortly before 10 a.m.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gorbachev-Tour     07-15 0309</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev-Tour,0322</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev's Poland Tour: A Reporter's Notebook</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland-Gorbachev, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> made his way around <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> this week, he fell further and further behind schedule, leaving thousands of people who had been invited to see him waiting for hours _ sometimes in vain. The Soviet leader arrived in the western port city of <LOCATION> Sczcecin </LOCATION> on Wednesday already an hour behind schedule, and by the time he reached his first scheduled event, a speech at a shipyard, he was two hours late. Polish authorities, anxious to ensure all went smoothly for their Soviet visitor, had seated the workers nearly two hours ahead of time. So when <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> finally arrived, the 3,000 people in the audience were squirming after sitting practically silent on backless wooden benches for four hours. Organizers of the trip kept adding events to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s schedule, including a visit to a private farm on his way to the airport to return to <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> It was nearly midnight when the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief arrived back in the capital, just about four hours late. The delay forced cancellation of a special chamber music concert that had been arranged for <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Raisa </PERSON>, in a palace on the outskirts of the capital. Although most of the unannounced stops had been arranged in advance, with state-run television often set up to record the events, Polish government spokesman <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON> attributed the delays to what he called <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s extraordinary popularity among the Polish people. Never before, he said, had a visitor drawn such crowds or generated so much `` spontaneous joy.'' But at all those events reporters were permitted to witness, the crowds were screened in advance, and Polish security often checked peoples' invitations against their identification cards before permitting them within sight of the Soviet leader.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Cosmetics     07-15 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cosmetics,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Few Controls On Ingredients, FDA Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans have indicated they would like to see more federal regulation of the $ 17 billion-a-year cosmetic industry, which currently lacks stringent controls, an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> says. <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eiermann </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>'s division of cosmetic technology, said people are often surprised to learn that cosmetics, which usually contain chemicals, have so few federal guidelines. <PERSON> Eiermann </PERSON> made his comments in a telephone interview Thursday after a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee heard testimony about the potential danger of some of the chemicals in cosmetics. Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore., chairman of the small business panel, said some of the chemicals in cosmetics can cause cancer, birth defects, central nervous disorders, skin and eye irritations and allergic reactions <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON> promised to have additional hearings in the fall to weigh whether <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should take action to enforce additional testing and labeling of cosmetics. About 8,000 chemicals are used in cosmetics and perfume. He said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> does not have the authority to test cosmetics for safety before they are sold, and can not require manufacturers to provide test data on a product's safety. The only actions <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> can take are to seize contaminated products and to ask manufacturers to change their advertising claims, he said. Retail products sold to consumers must be labeled as to contents, but that regulation does not apply to products sold to business establishments, such as hair styling salons. <PERSON> Eiermann </PERSON> said it is <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' responsibility to decide whether Americans want cosmetics to be subject to the same standards applied to food and drugs. But he said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> did a food survey in the 1970s and included questions about cosmetics. `` There is a preponderance of the population ... they think the products should be regulated,'' he said. Results of the study were never published because they were part of the broader survey, he said. The Cosmetic, Toiletry and <ORGANIZATION> Fragrance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a group that represents the industry, said cosmetic companies are committed to safety. `` Because of this commitment, personal care products are among the safest of any consumer products and are used confidently by millions of persons on a daily basis,'' it said in a statement The industry has a program of self-regulation that involves testing ingredients, the statement said. <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON>, vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should pass legislation requiring that all cosmetic products contain ingredient labels. Secondly, she said, more studies need to be done to determine the long-term effects on people who use the chemicals. Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cone </PERSON>, chief of the occupational health clinic at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to take steps to warn consumers and beauticians about any possible health hazards in cosmetics. He suggested that products contain detailed labels that clearly spell out the nature of any chemicals in the cosmetics and explain possible health hazards. Moreover, the government should collect better information about the chemicals and their effects and remove any that are deemed dangerous, <PERSON> Cone </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Anti-ApartheidMarch     07-15 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Anti-Apartheid March,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>NAACP Delegates March on South African Embassy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CRISPIN Y. CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 1,000 <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> members, some carrying a casket to symbolize the burial of apartheid, prayed and demonstrated before the South African Embassy to protest that nation's system of racial discrimination. Raising their fists and chanting `` let our people go,'' the demonstrators lifted the gray casket before the embassy entrance, as <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> executive director <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON> led the crowd Thursday in a series of prayers that `` hearts might be changed.'' Hooks prayed that `` those white folk in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, that call themselves Christians, may start acting like <PERSON> Christians </PERSON> and recognize that they are their brother's keeper ... that we are all one blood.'' `` We come here today in the spirit of <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> ... to say that we wo n't be satisfied until the walls of segregation, apartheid and oppression are brought low in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Guess </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> communications director. `` We come today praying that our own pharaoh, who sits at 1600 <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, will hear these voices -LRB- and realize that -RRB- we can not exist in this world, half slave and half free,'' Guess prayed, referring to the White House address. Hooks then pointed to the casket and pronounced sentence on the policies of apartheid, segregation, hatred, racial discrmination, unjust treatment and inequality. He led the crowd in the closing words over the coffin, saying, `` dust to dust, ashes to ashes _ apartheid you'll never rise again!'' The coffin was placed in a white hearse as the demonstrators sang `` Oh, Freedom,'' a song from the civil rights movement. The half-hour march was the culmination of South Africa Day at the 79th annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People. There were no arrests. In the morning sessions, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., and <PERSON> Randall </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> TransAfrica </ORGANIZATION>, a lobby group for the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, urged the delegates to support legislation to impose stronger economic sanctions on the African nation
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Peru-Violence     07-15 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peru-Violence ,0359</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT SEAVEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's largest private television stations began limiting coverage of guerrilla violence in a bid to encourage peace, and the government prolonged a state of emergency to combat the rebels. Also Thursday, Maoist rebels from the group known as Shining Path shot to death the city administrator of <LOCATION> Chincha </LOCATION>, 120 miles south of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, police said. Television coverage of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s eight-year rebel insurgency had become a battle ground among stations in ratings wars, with some channels dedicating up to 15 minutes a night to violent footage. `` The accord of a minute'' was agreed to by <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> channels 2, 4, 5 and 9 _ most of the city's stations. It calls for the time alloted to local news reports of violence held to 60 seconds per broadcast. Channel 5 press director <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> said the goal of the self-imposed pact was to contribute to national pacification. President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> prolonged a state of emergency for two months in the coastal capital of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> and parts of six other states in the <LOCATION> Andes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle. The announcement was made in a decree in the official gazette <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peruano </LOCATION>. Police said three Shining Path guerrilla gunmen killed administrator <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Casas </PERSON>, a member of <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s center-left <ORGANIZATION> Aprista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, near his <LOCATION> Chincha </LOCATION> home and escaped before authorities arrived. The official was leaving home for work. The assassination was carried out like dozens of others by the rebel band against government and party officials. But most of the more than 10,000 people slain during the insurgency have been highland peasants caught in the fighting between guerrillas and government forces. The state of emergency was first imposed in highland <LOCATION> Ayacucho </LOCATION> two years after the Shining Path, inspired by the late <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Zedong </PERSON>, launched its insurgency there in 1980 to topple <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s elected government and install Marxist rule. A state of emergency suspends citizens' rights to meet publicly and travel freely, while permitting government forces to conduct searches without warrants and hold suspects for long periods before filing charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0317EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TaxBill     07-15 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tax Bill,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tax Bill Gives Breaks to Mail Carriers, Pistachio Growers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pistachio growers, mail carriers and freelance writers are in for tax breaks under a bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Some farmers, moonlighters and pipe smokers will help pick up the tab. After a month of off-and-on work behind closed doors, the committee on Thursday voted 33-3 for a package providing $ 7.1 billion in specialized tax relief over the next three years. Because of budget restrictions the bill also carries the tax increases to pay for the cuts. The bill originally was designed solely to correct hundreds of errors that showed up in the landmark tax overhaul enacted in 1986. But since this is the only tax bill with a chance of passing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this year, committee members ended up adding numerous amendments extending some expiring tax benefits and dozens of others providing relief to specialized groups of taxpayers. For example, the bill would allow an 80 percent tax deduction for contributions to college athletic scholarship funds when such `` gifts'' guarantee a fan the privilege of buying a game ticket. Because the bill would raise other taxes on some people, there is enough controversy associated with it to make enactment far less than certain. For one thing, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration opposes some of the increases. Too, there is some doubt that Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, will interrupt his vice presidential campaign to handle a bill that raises taxes on anybody. Some of the dozens of provisions in the bill would: _ Allow rural mail carriers to deduct 33.75 cents for each mile a personal car is driven on a mail route; most people are allowed just 22.5 cents a mile for business-related mileage _ Give certain producers of pistachio nuts a break on how they account for production costs _ Exempt freelance writers, artists and photographers from a new requirement that they deduct expenses of an endeavor only after it starts producing income _ Impose a tax of $ 2.67 per pound of pipe tobacco; that is equivalent to the existing 16-cent-a-pack tax on cigarettes _ Tighten depreciation provisions for single-purpose farm structures, such as poultry houses, and farm machinery _ Prohibit any person with a home-based business -LRB- including moonlighters -RRB- from deducting any part of the base monthly telephone charge as a business expense _ Renew at a reduced level the tax exclusion for employer-provided educational assistance Only $ 1,500 of such aid per year could avoid tax, down from $ 5,250. _ Extend several expiring provisions, including credits for research and experimentation and for owners of low-income rental housing and a tax exemption for bonds used to help lower-income families buy their first home _ Relieve farmers from a 1987 requirement that they pay tax on off-road diesel fuel and then apply for a refund _ Allow owners of mutual fund shares to deduct certain fund expenses without regard to the usual 2 percent floor under miscellaneous deductions _ Remove some tax benefits from single-premium life insurance policies _ Raise taxes on various corporations, including those that own parts of other corporations and defense contractors _ Assure that fellowships created to honor the memory of Challenger astronaut <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON> are tax-free so long as the recipient teacher uses the money for academic improvement _ Permit operators of offshore or <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> oil rigs and of some commercial vessels -LRB- but not luxury liners -RRB- to deduct the full cost of meals provided to employees; most business may deduct only 80 percent _ Allow a surviving spouse to defer taxation on certain profits from the sale of a principal home, just as though the spouse had not died Present law denies such a break if a spouse dies after a home is sold and before a new one is built.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ArgentineFreed     07-15 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Argentine Freed,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Argentine Court Frees Former Economy Minister</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's top court dropped illegal arrest and extortion charges against the most prominent civilian in a former military government. But the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday also upheld the same charges against former President Gen. <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Videla </PERSON> and former Interior Minister Gen. <PERSON> Albano </PERSON> <PERSON> Harguindeguy </PERSON>. Thursday's decision freed former Economy Minister <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoz </PERSON>. The court gave no reason for its action. All three had been charged in the case of two Argentine businessmen who said they were victimized by the government leaders in 1976. The former economy minister, jailed with <PERSON> Harguindeguy </PERSON> in this capital since April 27, drove off from prison Thursday without comment. <PERSON> Videla </PERSON> already is serving a life sentence in connection with his conviction for human rights violations during the military's 1976-83 rule over <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NomineeRejection     07-15 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nominee Rejection,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Gives up Bid to Confirm Reagan Judicial Nominee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans say they'll `` make no effort'' to wage a floor fight for <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>, a conservative appellate court nominee whose writings were cited as too extreme to win Democratic backing. In a vote that had similarities to the rejection last year of <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>, the Democratic-led <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> voted 8-6 along party lines Thursday to recommend <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejection of <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>. The professor of constitutional law at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diego </ORGANIZATION> was President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s nominee for the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, covering nine Western states. Like <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>, <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> wrote often on the law, and _ like <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> _ his views often were contrary to precedents set by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, especially on civil rights and civil liberties. But while senators decided a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee deserved a full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote, even <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>'s supporters said no such effort would be made for him. Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, whose motion to report the nomination without recommendation failed on a 7-7 tie, said afterwards that Republicans `` will make no effort to take it to the floor. It's obvious that it's over.'' Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, R-Utah and another <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> supporter, agreed that there would be no floor fight. Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>. first voted for rejection, but then sided with the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> no-recommendation motion Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., who offered the motion to reject <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>, criticized the nominee's almost total lack of experience before federal courts _ he had one case three decades ago _ and said the nominee practiced `` judicial activism in the extreme. Sen. <PERSON> Arlen </PERSON> <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, R-Pa., agreed that <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>'s writings were `` extreme'' but voted for him anyway, arguing a law professor should have freedom to write what he chooses <PERSON> Specter </PERSON>, who opposed <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>, said he would be more concerned about <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>'s views if he were a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee. An appellate court candidate would have no choice but to follow <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> rulings, he said _ a point <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> made in two confirmation hearings. <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> wrote that prayer in schools could be constitutional, although the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has said otherwise. He contended that equal weight should be given to property rights and human rights. He said framers of the 14th Amendment, which guarantees basic freedoms, never intended its scope to be as broad as that defined by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> also disagreed with the high court's reasoning in its 1954 decision outlawing school segregation, although he agreed with the result. The landmark ruling, <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON> said, should have been based on the right of black students to travel to the schools of their choice. His critics said this would have left students at the schoolhouse door, without guaranteeing a seat inside. <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>, 63, was only the second judicial nominee to be rejected by the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> since the Democrats regained control in January 1987. <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> was the first. Although the two men disagreed on some areas of the law, both wrote often from their positions as law school scholars. <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> went on to become a federal appellate judge, although he resigned after his defeat for the high court. <PERSON> Siegan </PERSON>, after a state court practice, went on to become a professor. His lack of federal court experience was cited by Democrats opposing him. `` He has n't handled a case since I was 12 years old _ 36 years ago,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt. The 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> has jurisdiction over <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guam </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mariana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TradeBill     07-15 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trade Bill,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen: Campaign Won't Lure Me Away from Trade Battle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is promising to keep up his push for trade legislation even though he expects to spend considerable time on the vice presidential campaign trail. `` I'll be taking some of my time to work on that trade bill here in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' the Texan said Thursday at a meeting of his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He said he had `` talked to Governor <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on that'' and received approval to keep working on the trade measure. The measure was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday and sent to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where there could be floor action before mid-August. The decision by <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to tap <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate heightens prospects for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval of the legislation, in the view of some Democrats. In related action, a legislative blueprint for implementing the U.S.-Canadian free trade agreement won approval Thursday from the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The plan also cleared the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Tariffs between the two nations would be phased out over the next 10 years under the agreement. Under special procedures reserved for international trade pacts, the administration will now introduce implementing legislation that follows closely the blueprint drawn up by the two committees. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guarantees in turn that the legislation gets speeded up consideration, with amendments ruled out. Administration officials promised the <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that the legislation would not include subsidies for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> uranium industry, which had been delaying action by the two committees. Both <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, D-Ill., balked at the uranium subsidy plan Other squabbles also were settled and officials said the path appeared clear for approval of the agreement and the bill. `` We've set an example for the entire world on what can be accomplished with free trade,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said. `` This is a historic moment.'' <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON> issued a statement saying the lawmakers had `` reached agreement among ourselves and with the administration on the details of the implementing legislation.'' `` I believe that this consultative process has developed a sound, well crafted implementing bill, which balances all interests,'' he said. `` It fully carries out our obligations under the agreement but also protects the legitimate intrerests of those few industries concerned about possible adverse effects on their current business dealings,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Soviet-Inspections     07-15 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Soviet-Inspections,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>No Violations So Far, Head Of American Team Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet teams monitoring compliance with the new medium-range missile treaty have found no violations of the pact so far, says Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, head of the American inspection contingent. `` There have been no difficulties,'' <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> told reporters at the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday. <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, the chief of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> On-Site </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, headed a team on the first round of American on-site visits to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> at the beginning of this month, and was expected to begin the second <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> round over the weekend. Four Soviet teams of 10 people arrived Thursday evening aboard a special Ilyushin-62 at <LOCATION> Dulles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> and were to begin their second round of inspections today or Saturday. The sites the Soviets were expected to visit were a <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> plant near <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; the <ORGANIZATION> Redstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arsenal </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Huntsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>; and possibily the <ORGANIZATION> Longhorn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Depot </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Marshall </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Although <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet inspectors were a little wary at first, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, the process has gone smoothly since President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> exchanged articles of ratification in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on June 1 and the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty went into effect. During a 60-day period of `` baseline inspections,'' the Soviets are visiting 30 sites in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> and his team are inspecting 133 sites in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, to determine the accuracy of data exchanged by the two sides. Under the treaty, which calls for elimination of all superpower missiles with ranges of 340 miles to 3,000 miles over about three years, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is to destroy about 6,000 items, consisting of missiles and related components, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is to destroy 2,000 items, <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> said. With inspections about 25 percent complete, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, `` the count has been exactly on.'' `` Inspectors tend to be congenitally suspicious, which is probably a healthy attitude,'' he said. `` Both sides are wary that the other will be concealing or hiding items. That has not been the case on either side.'' The on-site inspectors are confined to strictly defined areas and do not have the right to roam through woods or caves looking for hidden missiles. `` There are other sources that hopefully will give us the confidence there is not something'' in areas inspectors can not visit, said <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, alluding to satellites which take photographs and collect electronic intelligence. `` It is too early in the life of this treaty to be philosophic or to make grand pronouncements,'' he added. But <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON>, who has served twice as military attache in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and once in <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, said `` there are some dramatic differences in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> from when I was there, leaving for the last time in 1983, and the relationship I had with the Group of Soviet Forces in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> from'83 to'86.'' <PERSON> Lajoie </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in 1985 when <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> soldiers fatally shot Maj. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> while the soldier visited <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, and `` clearly there was a considerable tension in our relationship. All of that is gone now.'' The Soviets, under severe pressure from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, apologized last month for shooting <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Unchurched Bjt   07-15 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unchurched, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gap Grows Between Religious `Believers and Belongers'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The number of Americans who believe in the divinity of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> has increased in the last decade, but a smaller percentage belong to organized churches, according to a new Gallup Poll. `` The churches of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> have made no headway in narrowing the gap between religious belief and church involvement, between believers and belongers,'' said the polling organization's co-chairman, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallup </PERSON>, in previewing the survey results Thursday The nationwide survey, called `` The Unchurched American,'' found that 84 percent of those surveyed believe <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> is either God or the son of God, compared with 78 percent in a similar 1978 Gallup Poll. The number of survey respondents declaring they were `` committed to Jesus Christ'' increased from 60 percent to 66 percent. Forty-four percent of respondents were classified as `` unchurched'' because they have not attended regular services in six months, compared with 40 percent of those polled a decade ago. The survey projects that 61 million American adults did not belong to any church in 1978, with the number increasing to 78 million today. While churchgoers tend to have stronger beliefs than those who do not attend, the survey found considerable `` faith'' among the unchurched, <PERSON> Gallup </PERSON> said at a news conference. The poll showed that 72 percent of those who do not attend church believe in Christ, 77 percent believe in God, 63 percent believe the Bible is inspired, 58 percent believe in an afterlife and 25 percent say they have had a `` religious experience.'' The $ 163,000 study, based on in-person interviews with 2,556 adults, was conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, for 22 major religious organizations and is to be distributed at a National Festival of Evangelism in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Aug. 4-7. Gallup said the poll has a margin of error of plus or minus 3 percentage points, making the 10-year change in results on church participation and religious belief statistically significant. `` One might maintain that churches have done well to keep slippage at a minimum in view of the continued high mobility among Americans during the last decade, the distractions of modern life, and the apparent growing appeal of cults and non-traditional religious movements,'' Gallup said. The percentage of all respondents who said they believe that most churches are too concerned with organizational rather than spiritual issues has grown from 51 percent in 1978 to 59 percent in the new survey. And, 41 percent said they believe churches are not concerned enough about social justice, compared to 35 percent in the previous survey. Gallup said the survey found more criticism of churches from those who attend than those who do not, but he did not give details. Complete survey results are to be released at the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> convention. There was no significant change over the 10-year period in the view held by more than three-fourths of those surveyed that a person can be a good Christian or Jew without attending a church or synagogue. In both surveys, about 80 percent also said they believe that a person `` should arrive at his or her religious beliefs independent of any church or synagogue.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>, executive director of the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> conference, said the survey results showed little differences in opinions between Protestants and Catholics. He said it was not possible to break down the results by denominations because the individual samplings were not large enough. He said religious leaders have yet to analyze the survey results but they seem to indicate that while church membership has sagged, Americans are `` deeply religious and the churches have a tremendous opportunity to reach out.'' `` Many times we churches are only concerned about our needs and become self-centered and ingrown,'' <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> said. The poll interviewed more blacks and Hispanics than the percentages existing in the general population in order to find if there were any significant differences in responses by race, <PERSON> Gallup </PERSON> said. It found no relationship between race and church status or religious values, he said, but more black respondents said they had `` real religious experiences,'' believed more strongly in personal freedom, and were critical of churches for inadequate commitment to social justice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SurveyofSurveys Bjt   07-15 0698</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Survey of Surveys, Bjt,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sighs of Relief by Delegates and Nation as Surveys Come to an End</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The political survey season is coming mercifully to an end for the 6,438 Democratic and Republican convention delegates who have had to endure 1,001 questions from the news media. And so, too, for the rest of us who've suffered the cumulative results. Is there a collective national amen? The delegates, chosen by their fellow party members to pick candidates for president and vice president, were telephoned, polled, interviewed, prodded, bothered, analyzed, classified, categorized, pigeonholed, sorted, shuffled and mostly picked clean for their opinions by newspapers, wire services, radio and television. Then they were dissected by age, sex, race, voting record, ethnicity, religion, region, income, education, height, weight and pet ownership. As in, tall, red-haired female college graduates who own <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Danes </LOCATION> can be counted for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Or, perhaps, the other way around. It was a Herculean task, draining considerable media talent, for there are 4,161 delegates to next week's <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> and 2,277 to next month's <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> bash in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. The survey effort, which started with the selection of the first <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Republican delegates in January, cries out for a summing up. What made you hate surveys? How many calls did you get? How much time did you spend on them? Whose survey did you like best, whose least and what was the dumbest question you were asked, present company excepted? `` I think questions about my race, religion and sex would be illegal if the government asked them,'' said Republican delegate <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, the top aide to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> governor <PERSON> Arch </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>. `` If we in government asked those questions they would be considered insulting or suspect.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> handled survey questions for his boss, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>. `` Surveys have ranged from one paragraph to what look like <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> grand inquisitions,'' was his answer to the survey of surveys. The longest, he said, was the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times which spread its 132 questions over 16 pages and `` you virtually need a Ph.D. and two weeks time to answer that survey.'' <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> was asked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' strongest point. `` His record as governor.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' weakest point? `` His record as governor,'' said <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON>. Of such stuff are trends discerned. `` There must be at least 50 surveys,'' said <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, attorney <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Pajcic </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> delegate. `` It seems to me there is more inefficiency in the media than there is in government.'' Some people do exaggerate. `` There were too many surveys,'' groused <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> state Democratic party vice chairman. `` You get some that are 15 and 20 minutes long. That's crazy.'' <PERSON> Bernice </PERSON> <PERSON> Covilli </PERSON>, 61, of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Frankfort </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, was bothered by the 20 or so interviewers who would n't accept her insistence on being uncommitted. `` Who's your choice? Who's your choice?'' she mimicked. <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> Representative <PERSON> Monique </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> delegate, was irritated by the `` what-if'' questions about vice presidential possibilities. `` Finally, I just told one guy: Put down <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> every time you get to that question.'' Delegate <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Canino </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat who works for the state welfare department, was reluctant to answer questions. Then she was n't crazy about question No. 1, her age. Then she wanted to know if the questions had been cleared by the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Then she hung up. Congressman <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, accustomed to interviews, was willing to answer questions until he found out it was a survey. `` I'm not doing any of these,'' he said and hung up. Some delegates, it must be said, were flattered by the attention and said things like `` Thank you for asking my opinion.'' The survey of surveys failed to ask whether it was their first interview or the 15th. As for the dumbest question, there were several candidates. `` How much money I plan to spend in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a super delegate from <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. `` What was it in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> that I wanted to see more than anything before I left,'' said <PERSON> Monique </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, the indomitable <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> delegate. Her reply: `` I told them, ` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as the vice president or the president.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Carter'sRehabililtiation Bjt   07-15 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Carter's Rehabililtiation, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Man From Plains Dons the Title of Elder Statesman</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE P. HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight years after <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> left the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in defeat and despair, his long political exile is coming to an end here in his native <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. No longer is he shunned by the Democratic establishment or scorned as the hapless leader who turned over the keys of the White House to Republican <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. With the Democratic convention threatened by discord, <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> turned to <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> to mediate his high-profile differences with <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` He has earned respect of all of us,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> explained. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said he wants <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> to play `` a real role'' in settling the differences. `` He understands the equation,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> will deliver an opening-night speech before the Democratic convention on Monday. He is hosting receptions for the media, former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> members and other dignitaries. And, the Carter Presidential Center will be the site for many convention-related activities, such as forums on domestic and foreign policy issues. At long last, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> is an undisputed elder statesman of the party. Democratic chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said Americans have changed their opinion about <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> after `` eight years of three-by-five cards and hands-off government'' under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` People understand the sincerity and the seriousness of purpose and the enlightment of values and views that President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> brought to his administration,'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said. `` And I think he will be greeted and welcomed at the Democratic convention as he should be _ just as a president whose roots were planted and nutured here in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> but who made a great contribution to values around the globe,'' <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said. Those must be sweet words to <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, particularly since they come from a man who wanted to see Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., not <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, as the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee for president in 1980 It has n't been easy for <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> since <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> turned him out of office in 1980, humiliating him with a 44-state sweep. Even after losing the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> remained a favorite target of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and Republicans, blamed for the sagging economy and ridiculed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for talking about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s `` malaise.'' For a long while, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was remembered as the president who left American hostages in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, the leader who authorized a rescue attempt that ended in failure in the desert. He presided over a nation that waited in long lines for gasoline and had to pay double-digit interest rates for loans. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has had his setbacks, too: 242 servicemen killed in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, Americans held hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, record budget deficits, the Iran-Contra scandal and, most recently, the picture of an American warship shooting down a civilian airliner over the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, killing 290 people. Perhaps these events have softened the Republican-promoted image of <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> as inept. On the campaign trail, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, certain to be the Republican presidential nominee, is likely to pass over <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and talk about `` <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> Democrats.'' A relationship with <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> has proven not to be a political liability, as evidenced by the election successes of former administration members such as <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s secretary of transportation, <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, who won a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, and <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador who now is mayor of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Though <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s name is not frequently invoked by <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, all of the Democrats who ran for president _ <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> included _ made a pilgrimage to <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> to pay respects this year. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s success is in marked contrast to that of another former president, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. Fourteen years after <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> resigned in disgrace, he still avoids the Republican presidential conventions and plays only a backstage role in offering occasional advice to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Blacks-Jackson     07-15 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blacks-Jackson,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Leaders Urge Dukakis To Quickly Move To Mend Rift With
Jackson</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Black leaders say it is urgent that Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> heal his rift with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, the man he defeated, and they predict next week's party convention could be `` on the wild and ragged side.'' `` There has to be a real healing process set in motion,'' said <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooks </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, adding that he would try to play a role in reconciling the two sides in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` I'm concerned that the black community not feel that in snubbing Mr. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has snubbed them,'' Hooks said. `` Up to now the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> campaign has been healthy for the Democratic party, and I see no reason why it should n't continue to be healthy,'' said <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>. Black members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> planned a series of meetings for this weekend and early next week aimed at reconciling the party's split factions. Sessions were being set first with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to develop a unified strategy, then with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or his top aide, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>. `` Clearly the way <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was dealt with, on a personal basis, looms as a monumental issue,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` It speaks to how black people are perceived in this election He is the personification of the hopes of millions of people. Whether Mr. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> understands that or not is something that remains to be seen.'' <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON> said the snub gives the appearance that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is courting conservatives who have been fickle to the Democratic party and taking for granted the black voters who have been its most loyal supporters. Several black leaders said they expect the path to reconciliation to be rocky, and Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill., vowed to stage several protests, including a Monday march from the grave of slain civil rights leader Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> to the Omni convention center `` I think there's going to be a lot of confusion down in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, a lot of pain down there,'' <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON> said. Added Hooks: `` It will be a little on the wild and ragged side. But we'll leave there together.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and his supporters were stung by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' selection of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> for the vice presidential spot on the Democratic ticket, and the hurt was compounded when <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> first learned about the choice from reporters rather than directly from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> telephoned <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Wednesday to try to mend the damage, and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said Thursday he had asked former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> to mediate between the two camps. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> also said he got an apology from a top <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aide but no apology from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He said he was n't seeking one, though. The lawmakers said their concerns extended beyond the personal tiff to the appearance that issues of concern to blacks were being given short shrift. `` We are trying to salvage this,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Mervyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION>, acknowledging that there is a wide range of intensity about the matter among the 23 black House members who make up the caucus. `` We are practical politicians.'' Some caucus members said they recognized the danger to their political standing if <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> appears to be going to the convention purely as a spoiler, and <PERSON> Young </PERSON> hinted that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> should be ready to compromise. `` This party has elected <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as its nominee,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` His primary responsibility is to bring victory. He ca n't do anything for <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> or for me or the cities unless he wins election.'' The black caucus was working through Rep. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON>, D-Mass., to set up meetings with the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> camp, and <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON> said he expected there to be a lengthy meeting, perhaps on Tuesday `` I think it would be a very wise idea on the part of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> people,'' <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON> said. `` They can talk at length about problems, about issues. And if they want, they can talk about the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> thing. ... I would like very much if we could have a nice, good, normal, united convention.'' <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON> said the members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> `` play a very key role. We need them with us. I think most of them want this settled.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Drought     07-15 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Drought,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says ``We Can Help To Ease The Pain''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, back from a look at what he called the `` worst natural disaster since the Dust Bowl,'' is sending a team headed by Secretary of Agriculture <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> on a tour of 11 drought-stricken states from <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> inspected corn and soybean fields in southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> on Thursday and appealed to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to focus its attention on drought relief, putting aside partisanship and efforts to rewrite the overall farm laws. `` Politics must stop at the parched field's edge,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, paraphrasing a traditional foreign policy slogan that partisanship should stop at the water's edge. The president spoke at a luncheon in <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION> after inspecting crop damage at the <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quoin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> grounds and the nearby farm of <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Krone </PERSON> near <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> `` We should keep our eye on the ball,'' he told the luncheon audience. `` Drought relief should be just that, drought relief.'' Both in <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION> and at the fair grounds, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> urged the lawmakers to avoid amendments not relevant to the drought crisis. `` What I saw was not a pretty sight,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said after walking through the shriveled fields and viewing them from a helicopter. `` We ca n't make it rain but we can help to ease the pain, and that's what the federal government will do,'' he told state agriculture officials and farmers gathered at the fair grounds. `` From <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, and right here in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, farmers face the worst natural disaster since the Dust Bowl of the 1930s,'' the president said. On Air Force One flying back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> said he and his task force plan to visit 11 states, beginning next Tuesday. He listed <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. He said he would be accompanied by representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> and several other agencies. Meanwhile in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> approved a $ 5.5 billion drought relief bill after adopting 10 amendments. The corresponding committee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is considering a similar bill. <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> told reporters that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill appeared to be `` pretty close to the package we've been talking about.'' In <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spoke at a luncheon sponsored by <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WOC </ORGANIZATION> and the local chamber of commerce after taking part in 65th anniversary observances of the station, where he began his entertainment career as an announcer in the 1930s. In an interview with <ORGANIZATION> WOC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said he is waiting for the farm relief bill. `` I will sign it the minute it is delivered to me,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0214EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Democrats-Analysis Bjt   07-15 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats-Analysis, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>This Dispute _ Any Dispute _ Serves Jackson's Purposes</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nobody really expected <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to go gently into the campaign to win the White House for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. And <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s grievances against the Democrat who defeated him were inevitable. For <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, it's too soon to have them settled. Without his complaints _ notably <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' failure to give him advance word that Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> would be the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee _ there would be nothing but symbolism to keep the campaign going. And <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has gone far beyond symbolism in his second campaign for the presidency. In defeat, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has risen higher in the realm of presidential politics than any black man before him. He is not ready to end his campaign quite yet. So as his convention cavalcade rolls from <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> on a final campaign bus tour, he is demanding a clear and influential role in the campaign and in the councils of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says he'll have one. `` I want <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> to be deeply involved in the campaign as a party leader,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said. `` I hope and expect that he will be.'' Neither has defined the precise nature of the role or the deep involvement. Precision is difficult if not impossible anyhow. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> says he is not satisfied. `` We are prepared to deliberate and debate Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday,'' he said, accounting for all the business sessions of the Democratic National Convention. Lacking the vice presidential slights _ he is n't it and he was n't told of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would have had to find other issues for debate, or lapse into silence, which is not his way. Now he's even involving innocent bystanders, as in the suggestion that former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> mediate his differences with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> declined to comment on that notion. The eventual settlement will be the drama of the Democratic National Convention opening Monday, with all its decisions made in advance. Debate is one thing; delegates are another. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has more than 2,500 to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s 1,150. Any time delegates vote, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is in control. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s claim that the floor will be `` wide open'' on a vice presidential nomination simply is n't so, on any item of business. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> needs to claim his victory and enforce his decisions without alienating the <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> forces, doubly difficult and also crucial, because he is dealing with a black leader and a predominantly black constituency. `` Presently, I do not know the proposed strategy to win,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on Thursday. `` At this point, my constituency has no place on the team.'' That constituency can not be turned on and off at will, not even by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s command. This time the unity show that is the traditional convention finale will have to be built on a base more substantive than handshakes and victory waves. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s supporters are echoing and escalating the complaint that he heard from <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on the <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> choice only after it had been made public. `` It speaks to the way black people are perceived in this election,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` Whether Mr. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> understands that or not is something that remains to be seen. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he was sorry he had n't been able to contact everybody in advance, and noted that he had not reached <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, either. He has talked with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> by telephone at least twice since announcing the <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> selection. The nominee-in-waiting is trying to be conciliatory without appearing to surrender control of the convention and the party he now leads. He needs <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s help _ and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> needs a continuing role in the 1988 campaign. This is, after all, only the preliminary. The real prize will be awarded on Nov. 8, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> versus Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The real test of whatever reconciliation <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> reach wo n't come in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. It will come in the campaign months that follow.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 __ EDITOR'S NOTE _ <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mears </PERSON>, executive editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has covered national politics for 25 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis     07-15 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Turns Attention To State Budget Crunch</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Lead prospects uncertain.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State budget problems are dogging <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in the days before he travels to the Democratic National Convention to receive his party's presidential nomination. While most of his headquarters campaign staff made a wholesale move to the convention site in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> on Thursday, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spent most of the day in a search for ways to deal with deficits in budgets for the current and past fiscal years. The governor and his fellow Democrats who dominate the state legislature were determined to resolve the budget problems before <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> heads for <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> on Sunday and deny Republicans an opportunity to attack the Democratic candidate's claim to be an efficient manager. `` The <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> express is rolling,'' <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said during the legislative budget debate. `` You Democrats want out of here. You do n't -LRB- care -RRB- what happens to the budget.'' Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who has clinched the Republican presidential nomination, already has attacked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for approving more than $ 100 million in new taxes as part of a budget-balancing plan. While <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was trying to clear his desk of state problems, he also was confronted by threats to his goal of a party convention that will reflect party unity. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, saying `` I simply want respect and responsibility,'' suggested that former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> step in and mediate differences between the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> camps. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON>, asked about <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s call for mediation, said only that the two sides had been talking throughout the campaign and would keep doing so. In <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> confirmed that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> had spoken with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> by telephone, but would not comment on whether he would get involved in any mediation effort. Both <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and his aides minimized the prospect that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s displeasure over the handling of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' selection of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate would endanger party unity But as he left <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> on a bus caravan for <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> refused to rule out the possibility of a convention challenge to the choice of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. Later, however, after his caravan arrived in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said, `` We hope in the next three or four days that matters will be resolved.'' And <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, asked during a CBS interview if he expected a display of unity in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> that would include <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, said `` I expect that you will.'' `` Democratic conventions seldom begin on a note of unity,'' said senior <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign aide <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>. `` But in recent years they have ended on one.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, as he has done in the past, took a tough line toward <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s complaints about his vice presidential selection process. `` Obviously in a contest like this somebody wins and somebody loses and I'm the guy who's won and it's my job to go out and pick a running mate,'' he said in the CBS interview. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> complained that he was n't notified in advance of the selection of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and learned of it from a reporter. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokesman, said the nominee-to-be called <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> on Wednesday. `` The governor obviously made it clear that it was his own intention for the Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and all of the candidates to hear the news from no one else but the governor,'' he said. <PERSON> Gearan </PERSON> declined to say whether the governor had apologized. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> termed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' gesture an `` important call and a good start'' toward healing relations, but made it clear he expects there will be a number of conversations between the two men in the days ahead. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' only public foray outside the statehouse on Thursday was a visit to two state troppers recovering from gunshot wounds suffered in a drug raid. Outside <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, using a police cruiser as a table, signed legislation toughening sentences for people convicted of possession of cocaine. `` We're serious about a war on drugs in this state,'' said the governor, sounding a familiar campaign theme.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bush     07-15 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Politics Played No Part In Bush's UN Appearance, Aides Insist</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is satisfied with his appearance before the <ORGANIZATION> UN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on the accidental <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> downing of an Iranian airliner in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, but aides are reluctant to say whether he will reap political advantage. But while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his supporters insist that political considerations did not figure in his Thursday appearance, the assignment did provide the vice president with a high-profile forum. `` Any time you can go and speak forcefully about bringing peace to this part of the world, it's worth doing,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> chief of staff <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>. `` He did n't do it for political reasons. I do not believe it will be harmful politically.'' After an angry 1 -LCB- - hour denunciation of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by Iranian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali-Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> for `` barbaric acts,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the world organization the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> felt grief for the loss of innocent lives that `` transcends political differences and boundaries. But he also condemned <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for allowing a civilian airliner carrying 290 people `` to proceed on a path over a warship engaged in battle'' and said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> must share responsibility for the tragedy. Coming days before Democrats convene in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to install <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as their presidential nominee, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s appearance gave him high visibility in an area that he is presenting as one of his strong suits: foreign policy. Still, it was the first time that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had been selected to address the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in his 7 -LCB- years as vice president, even though he served there as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador under President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in the early 1970s. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had decided to give him the assignment `` to put some real emphasis on the policy of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by elevating the level of representation.'' `` There's so much at stake, I'm not sure people have a heart for talking about how it helps him politically,'' said campaign press secretary <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>. `` This was serious business, it was n't politics. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> more subdued in his <ORGANIZATION> UN </ORGANIZATION> presentation than he has been in recent public appearances when he characterized the July 3 disaster as `` just an unhappy incident'' while telling audiences that `` life goes on.'' Departing from his prepared text, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> turned to face <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> across the semi-circular council table. Speaking in a calm voice, the vice president said: `` Of course we feel badly about it, of course we have compassion. Of course we care.'' Aides said that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s presentation was written by three or four White House speechwriters, with most of the ideas for its wording coming from him. The text was coordinated with both the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> delivered it, the aides said. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, his chief of staff, would not confirm speculation that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself had proposed the assignment to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, saying only that he and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had worked out the arrangements. <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> told reporters on <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> II after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s appearance that the vice president `` feels very good about'' the way his 20-minute address to the world forum came across. It was <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s last scheduled public appearance until next Wednesday, when he begins a six-day campaign swing. He has no public events planned for today, and on Saturday he leaves for a 4 -LCB- - day fishing trip at a remote, undisclosed location in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> with <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a close friend and adviser <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday also gave his first public reaction to the naming by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as former rival Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate, beyond a cryptic `` that's interesting'' on the day of the announcement. He called the selection of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> `` an unusual choice'' but told reporters aboard <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Two he did not think it would hurt him politically, even in his adopted state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> defeated <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in a 1970 Senate race. Asked if the selection would make him campaign harder for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' 29 electoral votes, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I do n't know I certainly wo n't lighten up. `` I plan to spend a lot of time in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> anyway. I am certainly not going to take <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> for granted and I will win <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.'' `` The race is going to be determined, as I said in 1980 and as I said in 1984, by the top of the ticket. That's what will determine it in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and elsewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0339EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Bentsen     07-15 0552</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bentsen,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bentsen Predicts Tough Fight In Texas</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is predicting that he and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> will triumph over Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> this fall in the vice president's adopted home state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. But he's not claiming it will be easy. `` I think it will be close. I think it will be tough, but I think we'll win it,'' the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator said Thursday. `` Vamos a ver,'' he said _ Spanish for `` We're going to see.'' One new poll suggested that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' choice of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate went down well with Texans. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> pulled even with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the state after picking <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday night. Its poll of 580 registered voters on Tuesday and Wednesday found 48 percent supporting <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> to 44 percent for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. With a margin of error of four percentage points, that is statistically a dead hea. Polls that were taken before <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> had found a big <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lead in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> deferred to his new political partner on Thursday on the matter of mending the rift with <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who had lobbied for the vice presidential nomination. `` I know he -LRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> -RRB- has a high regard for Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. I assume he'll have a meeting with <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said in a session with reporters from his home state. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> said he believed he was chosen as <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate because of his legislative experience `` which exposes you to so many facets of this country of ours,'' his proven ability to work with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and his exposure through the years to various heads of state. A senator since 1970, <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is being opposed in his re-election bid this year by Rep. <PERSON> Beau </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>, a Republican who has been fighting an uphill battle in the race. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> is legally allowed to run for both races under a law passed in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> that allowed <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> to run for vice president with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> as well as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> could remove his name from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ballot before Sept. 6, but the Democrats could not replace him. <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON> says <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s dual candidacy is unethical. If <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> wins both elections, he would have to choose one post or the other. If he gave up his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat, as expected, Republican Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clements </PERSON> would name an interim senator and then call a special election to pick someone to complete the six-year term. Already, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> politicians were moving to stake out a possible candidacy in the event of such a special election. Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hobby </PERSON> said he would `` certainly seriously consider'' running if such a special election takes place. State Agriculture Commissioner <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hightower </PERSON> also said he'd consider a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race. <PERSON> Hightower </PERSON> already had been looking at a 1990 race against Republican Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>. Among other Democrats looking to enter the fray are former Gov. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> and Reps. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. Attorney General <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattox </PERSON> also has expressed interest. On the Republican side, Reps. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> have shown interest. The 1961 special election to replace <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> drew more than 70 candidates. Republican <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> won.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0749EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drought-Diversion     07-15 0480</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Diversion,480</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Army Engineers Reject Diversion of Great Lakes Water to
Mississippi</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> says it turned down a request for emergency diversion of Great Lakes water to the drought-depleted <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> because the action would do little to help shipping. The decision was based on analysis of water flow and economic considerations, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Page </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant secretary for civil works, after testifying Thursday before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> merchant marine subcommittee. `` It was not politically motivated,'' Page said. Illinois Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> and other officials whose states have an economic stake in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> asked last month for an increase in water flow from the lakes to the river from 3,000 cubic feet per second to 10,000 cubic feet per second. They asked that the increased flow continue for 100 days. The officials said increasing the flow would enable barge traffic to resume movement down the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. The river's level has fallen because of the drought, and some 3,000 barges were reported stranded as a result. Barge shippers have estimated losses as a result of the stalled shipping at up to $ 60 million. But Page said increasing the outflow to 10,000 cubic feet per second would not do much to help <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> navigation, and shoals would continue to impede the flow of goods. `` We will still have flow'' on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'' through the summer, he said. `` We see in the foreseeable future based on our forecast we do n't need -LRB- increased diversion -RRB- at all.'' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Vonnahme </PERSON>, director of water resources for the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, said the agency had no problems with the decision. `` If they feel the waters would n't do any good, then we certainly would n't want to take them out of the lake,'' he said. Great Lakes state senators praised the decision. The corps' position `` gives us more ammunition in the continuing struggle to prevent any diversion,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Democrat. `` I have maintained that we should explore alternatives to diversion, such as lightening the loads on barges or utilizing truck or rail for transporting goods.'' Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Democrat, said `` this decision will let us protect our water, conserve it, and use it in the proper ways in the future.'' The governors of four Great Lakes states opposed the diversion, and only <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> supported it among the leaders of the eight states surrounding the lakes. Canadian officials also protested the proposed diversion. Supporters of diversion argued the increased flow out of the lakes would have a minuscule impact on the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lakes </LOCATION> but would have great benefits downriver. Opponents argued that the lakes water was needed in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION>, increasing diversion would set an unacceptable precedent, and the federal government could not increase diversion without the concurrence of all eight governors of Great Lakes states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880715-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-15-88 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Drought     07-15 0696</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Drought,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Expected to Sign Disaster Bill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
