<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     04-29 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan Stocks Rise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 27,509.54 points, up 75.42 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u v AM-JetBlast Advisory   04-29 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jet Blast, Advisory,0050</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Eds: A briefing by officials of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which earlier had been scheduled for 10 p.m. EDT, has been rescheduled for 2 a.m. EDT. A lead to AM-Jet Blast with developments from the briefing will be expedited. The AP
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 2346EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-OriolesNewspage     04-29 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Orioles Newspage,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Orioles Snap Losing Streak at 21</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> snapped their record-breaking losing streak at 21 games Friday night, beating the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION> 9-0 for their first win of the season. The <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> did it in style, allowing only four hits and letting only one runner get past first base. Three cases of champagne were on ice and waiting for the <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> in their clubhouse afterward, the reward for the worst start in major league history. <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> established the longest losing streak in American League history with Thursday's defeat in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>. They stopped short of the major league mark of 23 consecutive losses by the <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phillies </ORGANIZATION> in 1961. The old record for the worst start in major league history was held by both the 1904 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Senators and the 1920 <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tigers </ORGANIZATION>, who lost their first 13 games. A crowd of 14,059 sat quietly in 56-degree temperature as <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> stopped its march of misery.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Shuttle-Vandenberg     04-29 0383</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle-Vandenberg,0394</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle in Mothballs at Vandenberg, But Unmanned Launches
Planned</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VANDENBERG AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials announced plans Thursday to increase unmanned launches at this coastal base, after reaffirming a decision to put its space shuttle facilities in mothballs. Col. <PERSON> Sebastian </PERSON> <PERSON> Colitore </PERSON> said at the 25th Annual Space Congress convention Thursday in <LOCATION> Cocoa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, that the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> would build one new launch pad and modify another at the base to launch the Titan 4 missile. His statement came a day after Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromer </PERSON>, chief of the Space and Missile Test Organization at <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION>, reaffirmed a February announcement that the $ 3.5 billion shuttle launch facility at <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION> was being placed in mothballs because of federal budget cuts. <ORGANIZATION> Cromer </ORGANIZATION> said the move would save the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> $ 40 million in 1989. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> plans to use the shuttle pad to launch other, unmanned missles, Maj. Sgt. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Zielsdorf </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION> spokesman, said Thursday. The Titan 4, the military's workhorse missile, carries huge, shuttle-sized payloads and satellites into orbit. The first planned launch of the Titan 4, which is 20 feet taller than the shuttle at 204 feet, is set for February 1990, <PERSON> Colitore </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> also will modify another launch pad for old Titan 2 intercontinental missiles that are being refurbished into space boosters, said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Callaway </PERSON>, project manager. The first launch of the Titan 2 is set for July 1 at <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION>, he said. <PERSON> Colitore </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> would increase its unmanned launches at <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION>, 150 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast. The <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION> shuttle site has been regularly maintained at a cost of $ 50 million a year since the space shuttle Challenger exploded during launch in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> in January 1986, killing the seven people aboard. It was to be the next site of a shuttle launch in July 1986. But after the Challenger disaster, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> moved the launch back to 1992. Now launches have been indefinitely postponed at <LOCATION> Vandenberg </LOCATION>, although an August shuttle launch is planned at <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Even if <PERSON> Vandenberg </PERSON>'s vast shuttle complex, which includes a launch pad, buildings and runway, were to be reactivated, it would take at least four years for it to be functional, <PERSON> Zielsdorf </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BuildingFall     04-29 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Building Fall,0128</SECOND>
<HEAD>Falls Trying to Reach Girlfriend's Window</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ROCHELLE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man who could not get his girlfriend to answer the doorbell tried to lower himself to their apartment window from the roof but fell nearly six stories when he lost his grip on a rope, police said Thursday. A friend who was assisting the stunt, told police he heard <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Strange </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rochelle </LOCATION> mutter an expletive, then felt the rope go slack. Strange was in serious condition with multiple injuries Thursday after the fall. Strange asked a friend to help him get into the couple's apartment Wednesday night by lowering him on a rope from the roof of the six story building, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rochelle </LOCATION> police spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanley </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FloridaLottery 1stLd-Writethru a0784 04-29 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Florida Lottery, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0784,0499</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cash 3, Lotto Games Start Amid Confusion</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with four grafs to UPDATE with results of first
drawing; picks up 2nd graf pvs, `Sales of the ...' SUBS 6th graf
with two grafs, `Lottery Secretary ...' to UPDATE with first-day
sales; picks up 7th graf pvs, `Thirty-five percent ...'
^By ED BIRK</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> lottery's first computerized numbers game produced 859 winners Friday night, and that did n't include the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petersburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, which published a photo of a winning ticket hours before the contest. A photograph at the top of the front page of Friday morning's paper showed the numbers 8-0-6, which proved to be the winning combination in the first Cash 3 contest The photo showed a sample ticket sent to the paper a month ago. `` This was entirely coincidental,'' City Editor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> said. `` It does n't seem like that should need to be said, but we've gotten so many calls. The Cash 3 winners will split a total payout of $ 94,090. Sales of the Lotto and Cash 3 tickets began when Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Brantley </PERSON> purchased two Cash 3 betting slips. But the kickoff was delayed several minutes when a computer terminal at the new lottery headquarters refused to issue <PERSON> Brantley </PERSON>'s tickets because the terminal's password had not been entered correctly. Across the state, 3,142 retailers were supposed to be hooked into a central computer to begin dispensing the 50-cent Cash 3 and $ 1 Lotto tickets. Several reported their machines were not working or said they could not get through on a hotline set up by <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which is operating the on-line computer system. By 7:30 p.m., $ 616,543 had been wagered on Cash 3 and $ 345,377 on the Lotto game. `` Most on-line games start out slow and then grow,'' lottery Secretary <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> said. She predicted combined Lotto and Cash 3 sales would surpass $ 10 million in the first eight days of sales, and $ 1 billion in the first year. Thirty-five percent of all lottery revenue is earmarked for public education. Twenty-eight states, including <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> have legalized lotteries. Law enforcement officials hope the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> games will help undermine illegal numbers rackets. `` Some of the people down here have been playing illegal numbers since they were teen-agers,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Norflett </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> vice squad. `` But if they can find a way to play the same amount, win the same amount and do it legally, I'm reasonably sure a lot of them will switch over and play the legal game or start playing both.'' Cash 3 offers daily top prizes of $ 500. Players pick numbers from 000 to 999. In the Lotto game, players pick six numbers from 1 to 49. The first winning number will be drawn May 7 when the jackpot will be at least $ 2 million, but could reach $ 4 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Tickets     04-29 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tickets,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Wins Ticket Battle, But War Could Continue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARLENE AIG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNT KISCO, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Helga </PERSON> <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON> is 83 years old, does n't do a lot of driving and gets very few parking tickets. Well, she gets a lot of tickets, actually, but she should n't. Mrs. <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, had a license plate stolen from her 1975 <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Duster </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> two years ago. By the end of the next day, she had reported the theft to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> police and received new plates from the Department of Motor Vehicles. That was not the end of it. Mrs. <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON> has gotten notices from the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Violations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> about 169 unpaid tickets totaling $ 9,299, including interest and penalties. She tried to explain, but the notices kept coming. A default judgment had been issued, they said. We can take your property and bank accounts, they said. `` I was living in a nightmare,'' she said. Finally through the help of state Sen. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodhue </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON> was given a letter here on Thursday from the parking bureau clearing her of the tickets and saying she did n't owe <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> a cent _ for now. `` We solved this, but there is something wrong with the system,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Goodhue </PERSON> said Thursday. She and <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Breen </PERSON>, an administrative supervisor for the <ORGANIZATION> PVB </ORGANIZATION> said that as long as someone is still out there with her license plate, the computers say it's her car violating the parking laws And she'll still get dunning notices. `` There is nothing in the system to trip it if someone has reported the car stolen or the plates stolen,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Goodhue </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON> had so much trouble because she had lost the police receipt showing she had reported her car stolen. That infuriates Mrs. <PERSON> Goodhue </PERSON>. `` There should be a system to double check against stolen license plates and stolen cars,'' she said. `` You can have two cars out there with the same plate and the wrong person getting dunned. These things should n't be allowed to continue happening. PVB computers should talk to DMV computers.'' <PERSON> Breen </PERSON> admitted that there was no mechanical system that would notify PVB that a ticket was given to a stolen car or plate. The burden of proof was on the victim, as it were, to show that the vehicle on the ticket is n't theirs or was n't where the ticket said it was, he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Huitt </PERSON>, now driving a 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Escort </ORGANIZATION>, says she will frame her `` $ 10,000 letter.'' <PERSON> Breen </PERSON> said she should also hope police find the car with her license plate and destroy that plate so her nightmare can end for good.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0300EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-HolyCity     04-29 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Holy City,0812</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jews, Arabs Vow Never To Leave Holy Ancient City</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Palestinian Moslems respond to a prayer call from a minaret and head for a mosque in the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. A few hundred yards away, ultra-Orthodox Jews dressed in black bow again and again before a stone wall. Arabs and Israelis, enemies but neighbors inside the walls of ancient <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, pass without speaking. Israeli riot police stand guard on rooftops and in alleys, where anti-Israeli graffiti are scrawled on some walls. <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> is a city both Jews and Moslem passionately claim _ and, reluctantly, share. For the Jews, it is, as the Old Testament's Psalms say, `` <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, my highest joy.'' For the Moslems, it is `` Al Quds,'' or `` The Holy.'' Its name means `` city of peace,'' but it is at the heart of the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. If Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is able to persuade the two sides to sit at a negotiating table, the issue of this city's future is likely to be a major stumbling block Initially settled about 2,500 years before the birth of Christ, <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> has been beseiged and conquered 37 times by foreign forces, including the Romans, the Crusaders and the Arab general <PERSON> Saladin </PERSON>. Today, walled ancient <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> covers a crowded square mile of narrow cobblestone streets, broad courtyards hidden behind locked doors, and a colorful Arab market often shuttered by strikes in the 5-month-old Palestinian uprising against Israeli rule. Nowhere in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> are Jewish-Arab differences more strongly felt than in the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Hundreds of Palestinian worshipers and <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops converge each Friday for Moslem prayers at the city's two holiest mosques, the Dome of the Rock and <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Aqsa </PERSON>, where angry Arab protests often erupt. Tear gas thrown to quell the demonstrations sometimes disturbs Jewish prayers at the adjoining Western Wall, the last remnant of the second Jewish temple destroyed by the Romans in A.D. 70 and <ORGANIZATION> Judaism </ORGANIZATION>'s holiest shrine. It is here that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seeks to break the back of the uprising by forcing merchants who supply the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> to obey Israeli rule instead of <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> orders. Fourteen Arab merchants face up to two years in jail for opening shops during PLO-ordained hours in violation of army orders. As the city grows increasingly tense, however, most of the 17,000 Moslems and 2,000 Jews who live inside ancient <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> say they grow more determined in their commitment to stay. `` The <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> tastes of history. In every stone there is a book,'' said Palestinian poet <PERSON> Fawzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakri </PERSON>, born within <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>'s walls 42 years ago `` I do n't live in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> _ it lives in me,'' he said. `` I can never leave.'' For Israeli <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who has lived here five years, the soul of the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is in its Western Wall, also known as the Wailing Wall. `` The wall offers solace to so many Jewish people. You see them day after day, talking to God,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 44, a native of <LOCATION> Greenbelt </LOCATION>, Md. `` But the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is more than a shrine. It is my home,'' she said. `` If I am threatened, I will turn into a she-bear.'' The <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> was held by <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> for the first 19 years of Israeli history, until Jewish troops overran it in the 1967 war. Then <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> proclaimed the city its capital, a decision that Arabs refuse to recognize. Palestinians in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> still recall <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s conquest with bitterness. <PERSON> Mahmud </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sneineh </PERSON>, 52, said he was forced to leave his apartment after the war when Israelis bought the building where he lived. He moved to <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> but was soon drawn back to <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, even though he could afford only two rooms for his family of six. `` Nothing can match the <LOCATION> Old </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` We will stay here and die here, which will surely happen because blood will be shed over this city.'' Israeli poet <PERSON> Yehuda </PERSON> <PERSON> Amichai </PERSON> sees the problem in dark terms. In his book `` Poems of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>,'' he writes: `` <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> stone is the only stone that can Feel pain. It has a network of nerves. From time to time <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> crowds into Mass protests like the tower of Babel. And afterward the city disperses, muttering Prayers of complaint and sporadic screams from churches And synagogues and loud-moaning mosques. Each to his own place.'' Palestinian poet <PERSON> Bakri </PERSON> knows <PERSON> Amichai </PERSON>'s poetry and appreciates that others love this city as he does. But he supports the Arab revolt. `` My only fear,'' <PERSON> Bakri </PERSON> said, fingering worry beads, `` is that the uprising brings this city closer to more calamity.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0302EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GulfArchaeology     04-29 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf Archaeology,0884</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ancient Past Of Persian Gulf Uncovered By Excavators</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA SMILEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The roughly chiseled features and downcast eyes are all that remain as reminders of the little girl who lived here more than 2,000 years ago. Nearby, looking down at her in the excavation, stood another little girl, this one from the modern village that had been built atop the ancient <LOCATION> Saar </LOCATION> burial mounds where the chiseled stone was found in February. The village girl's hair was cut short, like that of the girl in stone; they could have been sisters had they not been born 20 centuries apart. The `` little girl tombstone'' is one of five identified as belonging to the Tylos culture that existed on this island in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> around the time of Christ. The thousands of ancient graves on <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, 30 miles long an 10 miles across at its widest point, once gave rise to a theory that it was used as a regional burying ground. However, the Danish archaeologist <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Frolich </PERSON>, among others, says, `` There is no existing evidence that requires us to assume that the dead were anything other than inhabitants of <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> island.'' Over the years, many of these burial sites have been obliterated by population and urban growth, a process that continues. The Saar mounds are being excavated under pressure from developers who own the property and are impatient to have it cleared. `` Our problem is that the construction of new buildings is coming very quickly,'' said <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> <PERSON> Sowaileh </PERSON>, the superintendent of archaeology. `` <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> would like to build houses, houses. And everywhere you dig in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, you will find some evidence of the prehistoric or ancient past. `` So we ca n't preserve all the mounds, but we try to do our best to preserve as many as we can.'' At this site, known as the `` baby grave,'' 85 graves radiate from the center of a giant burial mound, with the most recent at the outer edges. Thirty-five jars containing skeletal remains of infants were also found here, giving the site its name. <PERSON> Sowaileh </PERSON> said some burial jars, pottery and skeletal remains probably will be removed and exhibited in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>'s new national museum. Ancient writings suggest <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> may have been the Garden of Eden described in the Old Testament. The Sumerians of what is now southern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> knew the island as <PERSON> Dilmun </PERSON>, during the Bronze Age, some 4,500 years ago. Succeeding cultures built atop earlier ones, making this a rich area for archaeologists. Although most of the Saar mounds, a few miles west of <LOCATION> Manama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>'s main city, are older, this particular site dates from the Greco-Roman period, 200 B.C.-200 A.D., when the island was called Tylos. For centuries, <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, which is near the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>'s western shore, has been a stopping-off place for traders, merchants, pirates and armies on the move. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> the Great never reached <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> during 13 years of conquering the world as he knew it, but some of his generals did. Along with skeletal remains, the contents of other graves escaped pillage over the years. One family mound has yielded a trove of about 1,000 items _ necklaces, glazed pottery and glassware, some in relatively good condition. The mounds are rounded cones, enclosing burial chambers or grave complexes. From afar, they resemble giant anthills. Up close, they are distinguished from natural formations by their even appearance. Some rise to about six feet, others are at ground level. At this site, the chambers are generally below ground, cut into bedrock. <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> still has about 100,000 known burial mounds. In 1880, a British officer-explorer, <PERSON> E.L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Durand </PERSON>, wrote in his journal: `` Mighty mounds, bare of vegetation, tower above the palm groves. Mass upon mass, mound upon mound, they stretch on in endless chains all round the slope that falls from the cliffs to the sea.'' The 30 Tylos mounds, of which the family site is one, could prove important in the study of the Tylos civilization. <PERSON> Sowaileh </PERSON> said it shows, for example, that people of that time made glazed pottery. `` We also notice a change in burial customs from this period,'' he said. `` People are buried clothed, their positions are changed, so they are placed on their backs, and put into some kind of coffin. We did n't see these things before the Greeks came to <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>.'' He said the discovery of more than 300 silver Greek coins, some bearing the likeness of <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Great </PERSON>, indicate that ancient Tylos, like modern <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, was a flourishing trade center. Sowaileh, surveying the gravesite as he spoke, said the craftsmanship of such artifacts as the `` little girl tombstone'' is local. `` There are other tombstones, very similar to this one, that have inscriptions in Greek, and must have been made for the <LOCATION> Greek </LOCATION> people living here at the time. But they do n't have the facial representation like this one,'' he said of the little girl in stone. The little girl from the village had wandered off by now to rejoin her playmates digging in dirt piled near the mound. Her past is only now being discovered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0637EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Town     04-29 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Town,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Site Of Strike Was Built As Model Socialist Town</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The southern Polish mill town of <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> where thousands of steelworkers went on strike this week for higher pay was built in the 1950s to be a model socialist community. With a population of 220,000 people, <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> _ the name means <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mill </ORGANIZATION> _ dates from a Polish government resolution passed in 1949 by the communist government, then entering its Stalinist period. The government's aim was to build a huge steel plant next to the ancient Polish capital of <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, then a stronghold of the Roman Catholic intelligentsia class that resisted the communist takeover of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Peasants from around <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> were brought to <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> with promises of a better life. They were to build the town and the steel plant and then work in the factory. The building of the town was celebrated in popular songs of the period and portrayed in many Polish films, including <PERSON> Andrzej </PERSON> <PERSON> Wajda </PERSON>'s `` Man of Marble,'' about a model socialist worker who becomes disillusioned with the system. Today <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> is a drab working-class district which, like the rest of <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>, suffers from heavy pollution from the plant. The plant's 32,000 workers mostly live in the community. At first <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION> was a separate town, but it was incorporated as <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>'s largest district in 1951. Besides the steel plant named after <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>, the town features a huge monument to the first Soviet leader. The monument was damaged in a 1979 dynamite attack, but later was restored by authorities. Until 1977, the town had no church in keeping with its model-socialist image. But <LOCATION> Krakow </LOCATION>'s then-archbishop, Cardinal <PERSON> Karol </PERSON> <PERSON> Wojtyla </PERSON>, now Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, worked relentlessly on government authorities for permission to build one. On May 15, 1977, he succeeded and consecrated the ultramodern Church of the Holy Ark, a local landmark and today one of at least five churches in <LOCATION> Nowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Huta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Iran-War Bjt   04-29 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-War, Bjt,0843</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Rethinks War Strategy After Double Defeat</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s twin defeats by the Iraqis on the <ORGANIZATION> Faw </ORGANIZATION> peninsula and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> have undermined its strategy that a war of attrition would eventually exhaust <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, military analysts say. `` Time is no longer on our side,'' <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s powerful <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> speaker and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, admitted in a <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> Radio interview last week `` That's very indicative that maybe the so-called pragmatists in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> are now going to get the upper hand. The Iranians have had a lot of sense knocked into them in the last few weeks,'' said <PERSON> Hans-Heino </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> specialist with the London-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s defeats on land and sea last week were their most serious in several years and analysts believe <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> needs a spectacular operation to regain the initiative in the 7 -LCB- - year-old gulf war <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Faw </ORGANIZATION> peninsula, captured by the Iranians in February 1986, was considered a `` strategic boon,'' but not vital. An <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> force led by units of the elite Presidential Guards seized the peninsula April 16-18. `` Its loss has had a major psychological impact,'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s loss of two frigates and a missile boat sunk or disabled by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> on April 18 _ in the first serious clash between the <LOCATION> Iranians </LOCATION> and Americans _ is considered more important because those warships can not be replaced. Already, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s navy suffers a lack of spare parts and missiles, and most of its major surface ships, including two U.S.-built destroyers, are believed non-operational. `` The Iranians are having to rethink their whole strategy,'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` They've lost the initiative in many ways and they'll have to do something to get it back. The pressure is on them to pull off something spectacular.'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> and other Western analysts said an escalation in the Iraqis' use of outlawed chemical weapons in recent weeks and a seven-week missile bombardment of Iranian cities has also taken its toll on Iranian morale. A sustained bombing campaign by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s superior air force has damaged <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s already battered economy. Prime targets have been oil refineries and installations and power plants. Sources in the petroleum industry, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the bombing has cut <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s refining capacity by about a third. Oil exports, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s economic lifeblood, have been disrupted by <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> air raids on tankers in the gulf. A drop in demand for oil and increasingly shaky prices on the world market have eroded oil revenue on which the Iranians depend to pay for their war effort. The Middle East Economic Survey, a respected oil industry weekly newsletter published in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, reports that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has imported about 3 million barrels of refined petroleum products, such as kerosene and aviation gas, in recent weeks. `` This unprecedented sudden import of gas oil could be due to damage inflicted on Iranian refineries because of the war,'' the newsletter says. Diplomats recently in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> reported that almost two-thirds of the country's factories have been shut down by shortages of raw materials and spare parts. Others are operating at half their normal capacity or less. Only factories producing weapons, ammunition and other war-related items are working at full tilt, they said. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is also increasingly isolated diplomatically. <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s decision on Tuesday to sever its long-touchy relations with <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, citing `` terrorism and subversion,'' was another blow. `` I'm sure other Arab states in the gulf will follow,'' <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON> said. `` Despite the war, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> relies on countries like the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> for trade and if that's affected it could have very serious repercussions.'' Since April 18, Iranian leaders, including <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON>, have been calling on their countrymen to mobilize, vowing revenge against <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> states and `` reactionary states'' like <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>. `` We are prepared to conduct military operations on several fronts,'' <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> declared. But the Iranians failed to launch their big winter offensive this year, triggering speculation that despite boasts of having trained 5 million men and women <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> is having recruiting problems. Lt. Gen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Crist </PERSON>, the Marine officer who commands <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in the region, testifed before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> recently that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was not capable of launching a major offensive in the foreseeable future because of manpower and materiel problems. Although the Iranians outnumber the Iraqis three-to-one in population, <PERSON> Crist </PERSON> said `` the fact is that the Iraqis right now have more men under arms than the Iranians do.'' But despite the problems, the analysts do not believe the Iranians are likely give up what Islamic patriarch <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> considers a crusade to crush his long-time adversary, President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, is <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> news editor for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0019EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BusWreck     04-29 0099</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bus Wreck,0102</SECOND>
<HEAD>Van Goes Over 100-Foot Cliff, One Dead, Four Critically Hurt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ESTACADA, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A van carrying forest workers went over a 100-foot cliff Thursday, killing one person and critically injuring at least four, authorities said. The accident occurred on a <LOCATION> Cascade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> highway near <LOCATION> Bagby </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, about 30 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, as the van carried at least 13 tree planters home from work, said sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> Stillman </PERSON> Three National Guard helicopters were sent to assist with the rescue, said <PERSON> Karole </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescue squadron in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-High-TechCarts     04-29 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-High-Tech Carts,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grocery Cart Enters The Video Age</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES J. GANS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The grocery cart of the future is here _ a high-tech, video-equipped gadget that can say hello and offer games, shopping tips, sports scores and _ here's the catch _ on-the-spot advertising to the consumer. `` We're expecting it to make shopping more fun, less of a hassle and more efficient for consumers,'' said <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, director for marketing communications at <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which developed the cart. The Chicago-based marketing-research company spent two years inventing the <ORGANIZATION> VideOcart </ORGANIZATION>, with a liquid-crystal-display video screen mounted near the kiddie seat to entertain, inform and offer a few words from the sponsors. Shoppers using <ORGANIZATION> IRI </ORGANIZATION>'s VideOcarts will be able to call up store maps, reserve numbers at the deli counter, find out which checkout line is shortest, play tic tac toe or trivia games to pass the time in line, and get the time, weather forecast or sports scores. The carts would be provided free to the supermarkets, with costs paid by advertisers whose commercials could be transmitted nationally by satellite to local supermarkets. The high-tech carts are to be test-marketed this fall in three stores, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said _ one in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> area, the others in cities not yet chosen. If the test-marketing goes well, <ORGANIZATION> IRI </ORGANIZATION> plans to introduce the carts in major-city grocery stores in July 1989 and go national in 1991 with carts in 10,000 supermarkets. The video screens will be especially encased to make them `` kid-proof, grape-juice-proof, shock and water resistant,'' with an alarm system to prevent theft, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. Ads will make up about 15 percent of the programming. The rest will be entertainment and information services. <ORGANIZATION> IRI </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Malec </PERSON>, who developed the cart introduced in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week, called it `` the most important new advertising and promotion medium since television.'' Using sensors in the aisles, an ad for coffee or soda pop can be automatically triggered when the cart reaches the area where those products are shelved. The use of in-store advertising _ signs attached to shopping carts, sales pitches on store sound systems and the like _ has burgeoned in recent years, with spending growing 14 percent a year over the past decade to an estimated $ 12.6 billion last year, according to industry estimates. <ORGANIZATION> VideOcart </ORGANIZATION> offers the advantage of packaging the ads with entertainment, said <PERSON> Malec </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> IRI </ORGANIZATION> plans to invest $ 200 million over the next three years in developing the system, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said. One food-company official expressed interest in the carts, but said he would want to see the test-market results before making a commitment. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Frahler </PERSON>, retail trade promotion manager for the <LOCATION> Deerfield </LOCATION>, Ill.-based Kitchens of <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, a major frozen baked-goods producer, suggested there might be some confusion as shoppers get used to wheeling and viewing. `` There is probably going to be some bumping into each other,'' said <PERSON> Frahler </PERSON>, who viewed the cart in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. But he said `` the concept is fascinating and it seems to be well thought out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0643EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PhoneyGimmick     04-29 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Phoney Gimmick,0395</SECOND>
<HEAD>Would-be Yuppies Can Have Status Without the Static</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Yuppies who ca n't afford to have it all are calling on a new accessory to tone up their image _ a fake cellular phone that's a dead ringer for the must-have gadget. `` We are a status-driven city _ there's no doubt about it,'' said <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Neu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> high-tech accessory store. The Cellular Phoney is a realistic copy of the devices that have become standard fixtures in the BMWs and Mercedes of big-city dealmakers. At $ 15.95 for the handset and a fake, stick-on antenna, the fake phones live up to the advertising slogan of `` status without the static,'' Ms. <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> said. She said she has sold hundreds of the fake phones in the last year, although she did not have an exact count. At Art Explosion, another <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> store offering the <ORGANIZATION> Cellular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phoneys </ORGANIZATION>, business is brisk whenever a new shipment arrives, said salesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornmesser </PERSON>. The Cellular Phoneys are made by Faux -LRB- that's French for `` false'' -RRB- Systems in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Altos </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. An estimated 40,000 phones have been sold, many in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, another hub of freeway fashion But the items do well wherever the real phones are popular, retailers said. At three Art Explosion outlets in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, several hundred have been sold since the Christmas season, said <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Widlus </PERSON>, spokeswoman at the company's headquarters in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Other fake models also are on the market, including just the antenna. Although many people are buying the <ORGANIZATION> Cellular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phoneys </ORGANIZATION> as gag gifts, some find the gadgets ring true, Ms. <PERSON> Stein </PERSON> said. `` It's so incredibly real-looking that you have to begin to wonder how many people driving around out there with an antenna on the back of their car actually have a phony,'' she said. `` Everybody is hungering for high technology across the board but because of cost prohibitions, not everybody can have them,'' she said. Some novelty store owners said they are n't so sure the phones will do as well in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> as in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Said </PERSON> <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, owner of Palmer Sales of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>: `` Can you see a Texan driving down the road, talking into a play phone on his way to bankruptcy court?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0323EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HorseradishCapital     04-29 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Horseradish Capital,0464</SECOND>
<HEAD>Horseradish Hot Crop For Illinois Farmers</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT LEE ZIMMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLLINSVILLE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The horseradish, touted through the years for its ability to spice up everything from romance to steak, grows nowhere quite so well as in the nation's `` horseradish capital.'' Now the proud farmers just across the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> who still cultivate the ugly, pungent root that their ancestors brought from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in the 19th century have decided it's time to celebrate its success So they're sponsoring the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horseradish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> Saturday in <LOCATION> Collinsville </LOCATION>, complete with contests to see who can eat the most horseradishes or throw their roots the farthest. So rich is the soil, so perfect the climate, so experienced the farmers that this little section of southwestern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> produces about 60 percent of the nation's horseradish supply. `` It's a lot of work but it's family tradition,'' said <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, 31, a fourth generation horseradish grower. `` It's what we know how to do, and we enjoy it.'' The festival Saturday is co-sponsored by the growers and <ORGANIZATION> WRYT </ORGANIZATION> radio. `` We'll have a horseradish root-throwing contest, spoon races carrying horseradish, and a horseradish eating contest _ if we can find someone willing to participate,'' said <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheffel </PERSON>, general manager of <ORGANIZATION> WRYT </ORGANIZATION> radio. Centuries ago, claims were made that the white root that can grow up to a foot long would stimulate the appetite, relieve colic, rid children of worms and serve as an aphrodisiac. Now, it's more likely to be served with prime rib. Though actually a member of the mustard family, the Germans called it a sea radish _ `` meerrettich.'' Many of today's plants are from the original European root cuttings. `` It's like immortality,'' said plant geneticist <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Juvik </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>, perhaps the only place horseradish research is conducted. Growers say the best horseradish burns their tongues and makes their eyes water _ and they love it. `` When you smash it with your teeth, there is a chemical reaction and that makes the heat,'' said <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>. `` It gets real hot.'' Most of their crop is bought by companies that grind up the roots and bottle them as traditional horseradish sauce. Besides volatile prices there are other problems for the growers. Horseradishes have to be lifted from the soil by hand and stripped of secondary roots; weeds have to be cultivated manually since herbicide companies do not want to develop chemicals for a low-volume crop; and machinery has to be built by the farmers. `` You do n't call <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Deere </PERSON> and say you want to buy a horseradish picker,'' said <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, who harvests from 5,000 to 10,000 pounds per acre.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SchoolAccident 5thLd-Writethru a0873 04-29 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Accident, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0873,0626</SECOND>
<HEAD>Auto Crashes into School Building;
^Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with four in critical
condition, age of motorist, comment from police. PICKS UP 6th graf
pvs, `I was ...'; SUBS 13th graf pvs, `Two 7-year-old ...' to
conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARIO FOX</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A car careened across a playground and plowed into a crowd of children and adults about to leave an elementary school Thursday, killing a 4-year-old girl and a woman and injuring eight others, officials said. At least four of the injured were in critical condition. `` I called for 10 ambulances,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowe </PERSON>, principal at <ORGANIZATION> Cyrus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> H. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McCormick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` I told them there were bodies all over the playground.'' The motorist, <PERSON> Isabel </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>, 37, was charged late Thursday with leaving the scene of an accident and negligent driving, said Officer <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickens </PERSON>. She was freed after posting $ 100 bail and her driver's license, he said. `` Our opinion is that she was driving too fast for conditions,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>. He did n't know exactly how fast she was traveling but said Mrs. <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>, who suffered a bloody nose, was going over the 20 mph limit. Witnesses said the car crashed through a chain-link fence and careened across the playground before running up a short flight of stairs to where the crowd was gathered in an entryway at the school. `` I was standing outside the school picking up my son when I turned my head and saw the car coming towards the door,'' said <PERSON> Marcella </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, 30, whose children, ages 8 and 5, attend the school. `` I just screamed and picked up my son with my hands and ran away. The car missed us by a yard and a half.'' `` There were mothers screaming, looking for their children,'' said <PERSON> Araceli </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON>, whose niece lives with her and attends the school. `` Almost every child that was on the floor had their mother next to them.'' The principal said the car pinned a child and an adult beneath it. `` Myself and a couple of the teachers and a janitor picked the car up and freed the bodies so they would n't be further crushed,'' he said. The driver walked from the scene, the car still wedged in the entryway, witnesses said. Patrolman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielman </PERSON> said police picked up the woman in the neighborhood minutes after the accident. <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuentes </PERSON>, a student at <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, said the car belonged to his family and that his mother apparently had come to the school to pick him up. `` I got on my bus. I just saw my car, I do n't know where my mother is,'' he said. A 4-year-old girl and a woman died at <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> hospitals, spokeswomen said. In critical condition in <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> were a 7-year-old boy and a 10-year-old girl, both with head injuries, and two children, ages 6 and 9, with leg fractures. A 7-year-old boy with head injuries was in fair condition. A 29-year-old parent was hit by the car and thrown into air but escaped serious injury, said <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sinai </LOCATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Dianne </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Two children, ages 6 and 5, were taken to the hospital; one had head and neck injuries and was expected to be released, and the other had bumps and bruises and was in good condition, Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. `` The car smashed into the entrance where the kids were coming out,'' said <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Cepak </PERSON>, 78, who lives nearby. Third-grade teacher <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said he saw a youngster trying to calm one of the injured women. `` A child was stroking her hair and telling her everything would be all right,'' <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0645EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HungryMigrants     04-29 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hungry Migrants,0816</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Farmers Charging Migrants High Fees To Fill Out Workers'
Forms</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Friday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM C. CRUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CORNELIUS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of destitute migrant workers are being victimized by farmers who charge them as much as $ 400 each to prepare false immigration papers, authorities say. As many as 25,000 migrants dependent on social service agencies for food and shelter are in the state, unemployed and waiting for <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>'s strawberry harvest, the country's second largest after <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s, to begin about June 1. Under the nation's new immigration law, most migrants who picked crops in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for at least 90 days in 1985-86 may qualify as permanent resident aliens and continue to legally enter the country to work in future years. Some farmers are preparing fraudulent documents for migrants who otherwise would not qualify under the law, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Beebe </PERSON>, the district director of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>. Others demand excessive fees to prepare the documents the migrants must present to federal authorities to fulfill the law's requirements, he said `` The <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is aware of unscrupulous employers ... who are finding new ways to exploit workers,'' <PERSON> Beebe </PERSON> said. He emphasized, however, that the majority of strawberry growers treat pickers fairly. <PERSON> Beebe </PERSON> declined to comment on what steps his agency is taking to deal with the dishonest farmers and their allies, including printers who can prodcuce false rent receipts and other documents. The agricultural workers have until Nov. 30 to file the papers. After that, employers who hire illegal migrant workers will face stiff penalties. The migrants must pay $ 185 each to apply for amnesty under the new law. Fees for physical examinations, pictures and other required documents push the cost to near $ 300. <PERSON> Strawberry </PERSON> farmer <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Krahmer </PERSON> said he has heard of growers charging as much as $ 400 additional to prepare the paperwork. Another grower, who asked not to be identified, said he's heard some farmers are charging $ 250. <PERSON> Krahmer </PERSON> estimated that as many as one-fourth of the migrants are being charged more than $ 25 to help defray the costs involved. He said he charges $ 20 to process paperwork for migrants seeking documentation at his Lloy-Dene Farms near <LOCATION> Cornelius </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Unger </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strawberry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, said he knows of no grower charging more than $ 25. `` The ones I know of charge nothing or a nominal fee,'' he said. <PERSON> Krahmer </PERSON> said labor contractors, brokers who sign up and deliver the pickers to growers, are promising the papers to attract workers. Last year, the strawberry crop was harvested early and 20 percent of the crop was left in the fields because not enough workers were in the state. Many pickers say they were told they must turn in their documentation by May 4, the deadline for aliens who are n't involved in agricultural work. Hundreds of migrant pickers, confused by the heavily publicized May deadline, are rushing to <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> offices around the state. The result this year has been an influx of migrants, nearly all men and teen-age boys, weeks before the crop is ready to be picked. Typical of these is 14-year-old <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON>, who is broke, on his own and a long way from his home. Speaking in Spanish, the teen-ager from <LOCATION> Ensenada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, said he has never picked strawberries in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> before, but that a `` friend'' told him growers would sign the papers he needs to keep returning here to work. The Rev. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zegar </PERSON>, of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alexander </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Cornelius </PERSON>, said he believes contractors have drawn migrants to <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> early by falsely promising to arrange their immigration papers. The workers stay in labor camps without money, food and other essentials, he said, waiting for the strawberries to ripen while social service agencies struggle to meet their needs. `` I do n't think anybody has the right to put people into a situation where they have to beg for food and essentials,'' <PERSON> Zegar </PERSON> said. At Centro Cultural, the community center in <LOCATION> Cornelius </LOCATION>, migrants watch Spanish-language television in the lobby and wait for dinner, served Monday through Thursday at 3 p.m. Each day, Centro Cultural serves an average of more than 200 free meals of beans, potatoes and tortillas to the migrants. The <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is meeting the needs of thousands of other migrants, distributing tons of beans, potatoes, rice and flour. The uncertainty over the workforce has led many growers in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> to abandon planting strawberries; plantings for next year are down 75 percent. Plantings are up in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the largest strawberry producer, which has a resident picker population and is n't reliant on foreign labor. Last year, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> produced a bumper crop of 94 million pounds which sold for a record $ 31.5 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-D'OylyCarte     04-29 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-D'Oyly Carte,0548</SECOND>
<HEAD>Original Gilbert And Sullivan Company Reborn</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SUNDERLAND, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> D'Oyly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carte </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> was launched on the stage, performing the comic <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> operas that made the founding company famous for 107 years. The new company opened a 10-day run Thursday at the Empire Theater in the northeast <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> industrial town of <LOCATION> Sunderland </LOCATION> with a preview of `` Iolanthe,'' which drew five minutes of applause. `` The Yeomen of the Guard'' will follow next Wednesday. `` I thought it went splendidly and I hope to see us touring the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> before very long,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Condon </PERSON>, the company's general manager. The critics will be at tonight's gala relaunch. `` The red-hot night is Friday,'' said theater manager <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Angus </PERSON>. `` My experience teaches me that you have to have a warm-up preview to get everything right. If you go in cold, the chances always are that it will go wrong.'' Fans of librettist Sir <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and composer Sir <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said the production style was a big improvement on the original company's last years, when it was condemned as `` old and tired'' by the state-funded Arts Council. The company folded in 1982 for lack of money when it was refused a subsidy. The `` Iolanthe'' plot _ ludicrous like all the <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> works _ mocks the law and the unelected <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, as well as the English fancy for putting on robes, wigs, coronets and velvet knee breeches, by involving the Lord <PERSON> Chancellor </PERSON> and his fellow peers with the Fairy Queen and her followers. `` The pure Englishness _ not even Britishness _ of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> makes their work difficult for a foreigner like me,'' said the only American in the 103-member company, New York-born <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Emlyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who sings tenor and baritone. `` Some of the <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> rhymes can only be understood by English people. The operettas have been translated, though I can hardly believe it,'' he said. Canadian soprano <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Halifax </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nova </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION>, said the only problems she encountered were with the fairy wings. `` Some did n't arrive, some would n't stand straight and some fell off,'' she said. `` I felt the long history of the company was a bit of pressure on us to do well,'' Miss <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> added. The new company has an office in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> but no home. <PERSON> Angus </PERSON> has offered his ornate theater, completed in 1907, as a permanent touring base. <PERSON> Condon </PERSON> said the two operas for the relaunch have meant an investment of about $ 1.3 million. The company was reborn on a bequest from the estate of the founder's granddaughter, <PERSON> Dame </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridget </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Oyly </PERSON> <PERSON> Carte </PERSON>, who died in 1985, plus commercial sponsorship and donations from supporters worldwide. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Oyly </PERSON> <PERSON> Carte </PERSON>, a Victorian impresario, started the company in 1875 to stage the operettas and built <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Savoy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> and Savoy Theater from the proceeds. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> collaborated on 14 works over 25 years, including `` The <ORGANIZATION> Pirates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Penzance </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` The Mikado'' and `` H.M.S. Pinafore.'' Other companies, professional and amateur, perform the Savoy Operas, as the works are known. But the <ORGANIZATION> D'Oyly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carte </ORGANIZATION> company is the only one devoted entirely to them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-29 0987</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1028</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` 60 Minutes'' newswoman <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> plans to marry for the first time today, to film director <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> said. The match is the culmination of a six-month romance. The location of the wedding was not disclosed by the network Thursday. <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, 56, a former comedian who went on to direct the films `` The Graduate'' and `` Silkwood'' and the plays `` The Odd Couple'' and `` The Real Thing,'' has been married twice before. It will be the first marriage for Miss <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, a 42-year-old former aide to President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Demi </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> says she and `` Moonlighting'' star <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> decided to get married last fall on a whimsy spurred by a `` romantic'' boxing match. Now, she says, <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> spends his evenings watching video of their soon-to-arrive child's ultrasound image. `` We watch it all the time _ you can see its little legs moving,'' said <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, the star of the new film `` The Seventh Sign.'' <PERSON> Willis </PERSON> has already nicknamed the baby King, she told <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> for its May 16 issue. <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, who developed a reputation for partying prior to his marriage, was n't `` tamed'' by <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> after their walk down the aisle, she said. `` From the day I met him, I never saw this wild man, this person who was like going crazy, pounding booze back or hanging from the ceiling,'' she said. `` He was clear and focused.'' However, she confessed, the couple's <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> wedding last November was on the spur of the moment. `` We were there for a boxing match and did n't plan on getting married. And I guess the boxing match was just so romantic we could n't help ourselves,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON>, premier of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, has made an unusual `` personal confession'' for a Communist leader: He is `` a very sincere admirer of <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON>, preparing for a visit to <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> next week, said of the staunchly anti-Communist Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>: `` Although I have never met her personally, I read her statements, and writings on her, analyzing the rational economic decisions she has taken to upgrade the British economy.'' <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON>, who came to power last summer to effect an austerity program to grapple with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s own economic crisis, will be the first Hungarian premier to visit <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> since World War II.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese-American writer <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> <PERSON> Lord </PERSON>'s novel `` Spring Moon,'' which depicts the life of a woman during the turmoil and revolution of 20th century <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, will finally be published in this country next month. Mrs. Lord, wife of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Lord </PERSON>, published the book in 1981. The novel was a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bestseller for 37 weeks, and has been translated into 18 languages, including Chinese, but has not appeared in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The Chinese version was translated by Vice Minister of Culture <PERSON> Ying </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruocheng </PERSON> and his late wife <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Shiliang </PERSON>, the overseas edition of the People's Daily -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Renmin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ribao </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- said Thursday. <PERSON> Ying </PERSON> is also a well-known actor who starred as the prison warden in <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON>'s Academy Award-winning movie `` The Last Emperor.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> filmmakers in 1986 agreed to produce a movie based on the book, but filming has yet to begin.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Black and Hispanic teens will get their shot at the spotlight Saturday in auditions for six spots in a movie about <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the tough-guy principal at <ORGANIZATION> Eastside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paterson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> `` We're looking for real inner-city kids who would like to act,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Avildsen </PERSON>, directing the film for <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> `` I have n't been able to find in the mainstream of actors kids who have the same street sound that I need.'' <PERSON> Avildsen </PERSON> said he expected hundreds of teen-agers to audition for `` Lean on Me,'' scheduled for a December release. All the parts are for youths aged between 15 and 18 years old.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DERBY, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Faulkner </PERSON>, who retired from his job in 1934 because of ill-health, has celebrated his 107th birthday. <PERSON> Faulkner </PERSON> took early retirement from his job as a laborer at a pipe factory at age 53 in 1934 because of breathing problems. `` I can laugh about it now but I did n't at the time,'' he told reporters at his old-age home in northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> during the celebration Thursday. A non-drinking, non-smoking bachelor, <PERSON> Faulkner </PERSON> ascribed his longevity to leading `` what you would call a quiet, contented life.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GRESHAM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jazz vocalist <PERSON> Ella </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> will headline the seventh annual <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Gresham </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, a jazz star for five decades, was forced by illness to bow out of the 1986 festival just days before her scheduled appearance. The Mount Hood date on Aug. 7 is one of the few she will make this year. Also on this year's bill are <ORGANIZATION> Modern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jazz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quartet </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Stan </PERSON> <PERSON> Getz </PERSON> <PERSON> Quartet </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> Transfer. The weekend festival annually draws about 10,000 people to the stadium at <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, about 17 miles east of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AIKEN, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wife of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> has asked that assault charges she filed against the soul music star be dropped, prosecutors said. <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON> <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> filed the request Thursday seeking dismissal of the charges, including assault with intent to kill and aggravated assault and battery. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 54, was charged April 5 in connection with alleged attacks on his 38-year-old wife. Mrs. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> has filed for divorce, though the couple reportedly has reconciled in recent weeks. Second Circuit Solicitor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harte </PERSON> said he retains judgment over whether the charges against <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> will be dropped, adding he will make that decision in four to six weeks. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, one of the legends of soul music, is known for such hits as `` I Feel Good,'' `` Papa's Got A Brand New Bag'' and `` Living In <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Shultz'sWoes Bjt   04-29 0645</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shultz's Woes, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Little Headway In Middle East Or On Soviet Front</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Instead of slowing down, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is stepping on the gas. But the determined secretary of state has little to show for his vigorous diplomatic efforts in these final months of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. He had hoped to open <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> peace talks this Sunday, in the first stage of an ambitious <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> program aimed at providing some measure of self-rule to the 1.5 million Palestinian Arabs who live on the Israeli-held <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and in <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. But despite two trips to the area, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was unable to persuade <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> or King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> to accept his proposal. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> says he will keep trying, and will try to find the time to make another personal appeal to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> leaders. But he seems less optimistic than ever before. On the Soviet front, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is making arrangements for President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> May 29-June 2 for a fourth and probably final summit meeting with General Secretary <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The centerpiece was supposed to be a treaty to halve the Soviet and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arsenals of strategic nuclear weapons. But with only a month left, the two sides are still far apart on such issues as the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Strategic Defense Initiative and how to monitor the reduction of mobile missiles and other weapons that are relatively easy to conceal. Even the treaty signed at last year's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> summit to scrap intermediate-range nuclear missiles is still awaiting <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> will try again May 11-12 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON>. But he appears to be lowering his sights to a summit that would be mostly an exchange of views between <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> instead of a historic event. Analysts differ on whether <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s decision to withdraw some 115,000 Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> is a victory for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy or a decision taken by <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for its own reasons. But on other regional fronts there is little opportunity for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration to claim credit. The Soviets are resisting a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plea that they help impose a worldwide arms embargo on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. And they decline to accept a benign role in a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace conference. `` I did n't achieve any breakthrough,'' <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> admitted Thursday to a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> appropriations subcommittee about his talks last week in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Taking the long view, he reminded the senators how cool the U.S.-Soviet relationship was in 1985, before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took over. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>'s human rights pleas now get a respectful hearing, and even some action. Jewish emigration hit a 15-month high last month. Giving the subject `` the pride of place'' on his agenda, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> opened his talks with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> with human rights and kept at it for two hours. In the past, the Soviets mostly listened impassively to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pleas. Now American and Soviet lawyers and psychiatrists are holding meetings to discuss the situation. Otherwise, though, even the climate is worsening. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> took sharp exception last week to a speech by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> accusing the Soviets of aggression and other bad behavior. He complained the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was `` sermonizing'' as well as attributing any improvement in relations to a policy of strength. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> tried to minimize the criticism. He said there was a `` rhythm'' to U.S.-Soviet relations that had both moments of progress and of discord. Other State Department officials were privately critical of the tough rhetoric in <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speech. They said it had not been submitted to the department for review before delivery. Ever loyal, though, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Thursday that `` we must call it as we see it.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> staff, accompanied <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> on his trips to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDSBill Bjt   04-29 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS Bill, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate-Passed AIDS Bill Would Provide $1.1 Billion</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passage of a billion-dollar AIDS research and education bill shows that the government has finally `` declared war on the virus and not on the victims,'' supporters say. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 87-4 for the $ 1.1 billion bill Thursday night after agreeing unanimously to require AIDS tests on people convicted of state or federal crimes related to sex or intravenous drug use. The focus now shifts to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where a bill covering research on AIDS is committee but measures addressing other portions of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> legislation have not be introduced. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill authorizes $ 665 million for state and federal AIDS education programs, increased hiring at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, a new home health care program for AIDS victims and special efforts to help high-risk minorities and intravenous drug abusers. A committee aide said open-ended research money would bring total annual spending to about $ 1.1 billion. `` Finally, we have declared war on the virus and not on the victims in our battle against AIDS,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., who as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> spearheaded support for the bill <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Basile </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, the national political action committee for the gay and lesbian community, said he was `` delighted'' with bill, which he said `` for the first time establishes a national policy on AIDS.'' During frequently bitter debate, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected or weakened a number of amendments proposed by conservatives, several of them by Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, R-N. The most controversial was <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>' attempt to renew an expiring 1987 ban on federal money for educational materials that allegedly promote or encourage homosexual activity. The ban passed 94-2 last year, but some senators said it has hampered public health efforts to reach the gay community. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>' drive was fueled by a gay-oriented AIDS education videotape he viewed with several senators on Wednesday. `` I thought that I had seen everything until I saw this video,'' said the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> Republican. `` There's something wrong when federal tax dollars are used for this garbage.'' But the bill's Republican co-sponsor, Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, told his <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> colleague that he ought to consider public health concerns and not just moral ones. `` We have to tell homosexuals more than simply to become heterosexuals,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> agreed to the <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> amendment, but the victory was brief. Lawmakers also voted for a Kennedy amendment that said nothing in the bill should prevent the dissemination of accurate information to people at risk _ effectively superseding the <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> provision. The debate provoked a number of outbursts. At one point Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, tried to get a quick vote on a provision but Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., would n't `` What the hell could be more important than 1.5 million people who are going to die?'' <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> exploded. `` I suggest we should just stick to this business and just do it or not do it and go home.'' Homosexuals and intravenous drug users have been the chief victims of AIDS, or acquired immune deficiency syndrome, a fatal disease spread through blood, blood products or semen. As of April 21, AIDS had been diagnosed in about 59,500 Americans, more than half of whom have died. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> was frustrated in several attempts to win an outright ban on federal money for programs in which drug addicts exchange shared and possibly AIDS-contaminated needles for clean ones. The final version says federal money could not be used for clean-needle programs unless the surgeon general concludes they help stop drug addiction or the spread of AIDS. A disgusted <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> said `` it's just a matter of time'' before federal dollars flow toward the programs. Under the testing amendment sponsored by Sen. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Okla </LOCATION>., AIDS tests would be mandatory for those convicted of sex or drug crimes carrying a penalty of at least a year in prison Results would be confidential but could be disclosed to prison wardens or victims of sex crimes. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration announced last year it would test new immigrants and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> later put its stamp of approval on the policy. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> tests all 2.1 million men and women on active military duty as well as all recruit applicants and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said last October that it would test some federal prisoners. Senators voting against the AIDS bill were <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, R-Colo.; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wyo </LOCATION> Not voting were Sens. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del.; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash.; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>; <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stennis </PERSON>, D-Miss; <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Symms </PERSON> Despite the bill's approval, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said it only the first step toward a national AIDS policy that also must address sensitive testing and discrimination questions. `` The total effort has to include testing, confidentiality and anti-discrimination provisions,'' he said. `` We begin work on those tomorrow.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FishDebts Bjt   04-29 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fish Debts, Bjt,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Catch of the Day: Accounts Receivable</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AU1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY HARKAVY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the bustling and often chaotic seafood industry, <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> casts a widening net for what might be the most prized catch of all: Buyers who refuse to pay up. <PERSON> Workman </PERSON>'s work has taken him on predawn visits to ramshackle back offices in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s tough Fulton Fish Market, where prudent debt collectors seldom venture in an industry notorious for its proliferation of deadbeats. Bullhorn in hand, <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> has brazenly entered crowded seafood restaurants at the height of the lunch hour to announce to patrons that the fish on their plates may not have been paid for. `` It's the No. 1 problem in the industry,'' says the former debt collector and sales representative for <ORGANIZATION> Dun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bradstreet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, who has carved out a fast-growing and profitable new business, <ORGANIZATION> Debt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. `` Fish is in such demand, it's so popular, that it's not hard to sell. It's certainly not hard to sell a <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> lobster. The hard part is to get paid for it.'' Part of the problem is that seafood is a perishable commodity whose value is at its highest when it hits the dock and then diminishes rapidly. `` To get the most for their product before the value drops they have to move it very quickly _ and that means they take unusual risks,'' <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> explained. `` They'll sell to people knowing there's maybe only a 50-50 chance they'll get paid, as opposed to a 100 percent chance that the fish will spoil and become a non-saleable item.'' Because sellers are reluctant to communicate with each other for fear of losing a competitive edge, unscrupulous restaurateurs and wholesalers have been known to switch from supplier to supplier in order to avoid ever having to pay their accounts due, <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> says. To combat such practices, Debt Management semimonthly publishes SeaScan, a continuously updated list of hundreds of seafood markets, restaurants, wholesalers, brokers and distributors who are in arrears on their debts. The publication, about 50 pages long, consists of yellow pages with the names of buyers whose payments are at least 30 days past due; red pages listing buyers whose accounts have been referred to the company for collection; and white pages, tagged the `` rubber sheet,'' which lists buyers whose checks have bounced. `` Yellow is slow, red has stopped,'' <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> explains. `` Everyone who has stopped paying his bills slowed down first.'' SeaScan is distributed to his company's more than 200 clients, ranging from salmon harvesters in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shetland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> to catfish producers in the <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> to shrimp importers on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. A seller who purchases the SeaScan report and becomes a Debt Management client can refer past due accounts to <PERSON> Workman </PERSON>'s company, which receives a percentage of the overdue receivables it collects in addition to a $ 2,500 a year membership fee. The 33-year-old <LOCATION> Nyack </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, native, who began the business three years ago in his home, today has 17 employees and subsidiary offices in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. He says his clients are among the largest in the industry, accounting for nearly half the dollar volume of seafood sold in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market. <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> has n't emerged unscathed from deadbeat raids. He recalls the time three fish cutters grabbed him by the jacket at a seafood wholesaler's in <LOCATION> Pompano </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and tossed him unceremoniously onto the sidewalk. But while inside the establishment, <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> had spotted some boxes bearing the name of one of his major clients. He immediately telephoned the client and apprised him of the situation; the client, in turn, called the wholesaler and threatened to cut off future shipments if he did n't pay the debt. Waiting for <PERSON> Workman </PERSON> when he returned was an apology and a check for $ 15,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JunkBonds Bjt   04-29 0715</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Junk Bonds, Bjt,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Say Drexel Tolerated Employee Sweetheart Deals</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressional investigators are portraying <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lambert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> as a greedy firm that elbowed its own clients aside so top employees could profit on hot new issues of high-yield, high-risk `` junk'' bonds. But <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> chief executive <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, in 6 -LCB- hours of testimony Thursday before the investigations subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, steadfastly defended the firm's practice of permitting employees to form private partnerships to compete with other investors for bonds underwritten by <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION>. Under questioning from Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of both the committee and subcommittee, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> acknowledged `` the perception of a conflict is troublesome. Still, he said <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> not only condones the partnerships, but believes they benefit corporate bond issuers by making more money available to buy the bonds. However, documents released by the subcommittee showed that on several occasions <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees purchased bonds from much-sought issues for their own accounts at the same time the firm's public customers were being turned away. In the case of <ORGANIZATION> Texstyrene </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, manufacturer of styrofoam products, partnerships owned by <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees purchased $ 12 million of an initial $ 50 million offering in February 1986, according to the subcommittee. Public customers were allowed to buy only some of the bonds they wanted, and within 17 days <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees made more than $ 900,000 profits by selling the bonds back to <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION>, subcommittee documents indicate. In another case, the subcommittee said, <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees purchased $ 235 million of a $ 2.5 billion issue in the April 1986 leveraged buyout of <ORGANIZATION> Beatrice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cos. </ORGANIZATION>, a diversified food and consumer products company. Again, other customers were denied the chance to purchase as many bonds as they had initially ordered. And less than three months later, the employees made a $ 2.8 million profit by selling $ 61.4 million of the bonds, the subcommittee said. `` Any way you slice it, the people on the outside are n't getting the same deal as the people on the inside,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, D-Ore. Rep. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION>, in effect, `` elbowed aside'' its own customers and `` cut to the head of the line. He said a telephone survey of five top competitors of <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION>, whom he declined to identify, showed that none would permit similar practices. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> said it is quite common that investors will want to buy more bonds than are available and said <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> used the same criteria for deciding how many bonds employees could purchase as it did for its other customers. He said purchases by <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees are closely monitored for propriety by the firm's compliance department. However, Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on committee, said the purchases for `` insider accounts'' appear to violate the regulations of the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dealers </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> argued that the rules applied only to sales of stock because bond prices are not subject to manipulation in the same way as are prices of new stock issues. Lent said high-quality, investment-grade bonds are exempt from the rules, but not the risky bonds of the type <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> issued. The subcommittee released a list of 35 so-called `` insider accounts'' owned by employees including <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Milken </PERSON>, chief of <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION>'s junk bond trading unit in <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and relatives of <PERSON> Milken </PERSON>. Also listed as having participated in the partnerships are <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, a former investment banker now serving a prison term for securities law violations, and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, who also has pleaded guilty to violations of securities laws. Both are former <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> employees and have cooperated in government probes of Wall Street corruption. <PERSON> Milken </PERSON>, in a subcommittee appearance Wednesday, cited his constitutional protection against self-incrimination in refusing to answer questions. He confirmed that he has been under investigation for 18 months by a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> federal grand jury that is reported to be probing insider trading. Both <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Milken </PERSON> have denied any wrongdoing. <PERSON> Milken </PERSON> pioneered use of junk bonds to allow companies without a track record of earnings to get financing based on whether they had sufficient cash flow to pay off their debts. The bonds pay higher interest rates than those of established companies and are considered riskier investments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880429-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-29-88 0327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Amnesty Bjt   04-29 0655</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amnesty, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Vote Scuttles Immigration Amnesty Extension</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
