<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 2331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DentalGasDeaths     08-08 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dental Gas Deaths,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Found Dead In Storage Room From Apparent Asphyxiation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CEDAR CITY, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two young men and two young women who apparently were inhaling laughing gas to get high were found dead Monday in a storeroom of a building housing a dental clinic, authorities said. The bodies were found shortly before noon in a small room near an empty tank of nitrous oxide, a gas used by dentists as an anesthetic, <LOCATION> Iron </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> prosecutor <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>. `` It's believed that they were inhaling the gas,'' he said. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said there was no sign of forced entry. He identified the victims as <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregerson </PERSON>, 18, and <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, 19, both of <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherie </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 20, of Fillmore; and <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Probert </PERSON>, 20, of Scipio. The bodies were sent to the state medical examiner's office for a determination of the cause of death, but <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said preliminary investigation shows they were asphyxiated. `` It's just a tragic accident and our hearts go out to the families,'' he said. `` We've never had injuries or deaths due to nitrous oxide. It's common throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for people to try to gain access to that to try to get high.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Iran-Border     08-08 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-Border,0356</SECOND>
<HEAD>Territorial Disputes Jeopardize Iran-Iraq Truce Talks</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-UN-Gulf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HANNS NEUERBOURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEHRAN, Iran (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Territorial conflicts that brought about the war between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> eight years ago will jeopardize the truce that both countries have accepted, an Iranian specialist in international law said Monday. A 1975 border treaty could be the solution and for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> there `` should be no questions,'' said <PERSON> Alireza </PERSON> <PERSON> Deyihim </PERSON>, deputy dean of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s diplomatic academy that is affiliated with the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. He said in an interview that both countries had accepted the 1975 pact and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> `` clearly violated international law'' when it abrogated the treaty unilaterally in 1979. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in September 1980 after a series of border skirmishes. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> agreed Monday to accept the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>'s call for a cease-fire. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolution 598 also states that both <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> and Iranian forces should withdraw `` to the internationally recognized borders without delay'' after the cease-fire is in place. <PERSON> Deyihim </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> believes that phrase means the forces should withdraw to the borders agreed upon in the 1975 treaty between <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s government of <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlevi </PERSON> that was overthrown in 1979 in the revolt led by <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>. `` Both countries have ratified this treaty and announced ratification to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Deyihim </PERSON> said. `` That treaty settled all problems including the border in the <LOCATION> Shatt-al-Arab </LOCATION>,'' the 120-mile waterway that flows into the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and forms the southern border between the warring neighbors. <PERSON> Deyihim </PERSON>, who entered <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s foreign service 17 years ago and was involved in the 1975 treaty negotiations, said if <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> had wanted to renegotiate parts of the agreement it could have used the complaints procedure that is part of the pact. He claimed <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> had removed many of about 570 markers set to delineate the 730-mile border after the 1975 treaty. `` They removed them ... and even pulled out trees'' that marked the border, he said. `` We hope that this -LRB- border issue -RRB- does not cause a delay in implementing the cease-fire.'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0001EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-AIDSDrug     08-08 0917</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-AIDS Drug,0942</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trickle of Americans Seek Possible Anti-AIDS Drug In Japan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s doors are hesitantly open to a trickle of Americans seeking an experimental anti-AIDS drug that has not been approved for use in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The drug, dextran sulfate, was developed in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> in the 1960s and has been used to treat arteriosclerosis and high cholesterol. Within the last year, however, Japanese and American researchers have shown in the test tube that the compound is a potent agent against infection by HIV, which causes the fatal acquired immune deficiency syndrome. Now researchers are trying to determine whether dextran sulfate is effective when given to AIDS patients and whether they can take large doses over a long period. The drug's potential has received wide publicity, and some American AIDS sufferers or their friends have sought the drug in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` A year ago I started receiving calls from <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> guys who asked if dextran sulfate was available,'' said <PERSON> Manabu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON>, manager at the American Pharmacy in central <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` I had no idea it could be used against AIDS.'' Now, <PERSON> Yamamoto </PERSON> says, two or three Americans come in every month seeking dextran sulfate. The American Pharmacy is one of three pharmacies in the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> area that were authorized two months ago to sell the compound under tight control _ but without a doctor's prescription _ by the <ORGANIZATION> Phamarceutical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, one of about a dozen makers of dextran sulfate in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> `` We talked it over with the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, and decided for humanitarian reasons it would be sold to <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> tourists,'' said <PERSON> Kowa </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Kazuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Endo </PERSON>. <PERSON> Endo </PERSON> said the company limited over-the-counter sales to three pharmacies because if dextran sulfate were widely available, it would be difficult to give proper warnings to purchasers. `` There could be damage, and we as a pharmaceutical company are quite worried about this,'' he said. A buyer at the American Pharmacy must sign a form in English stating how many tablets were purchased, that they were for personal use, that the drug is approved in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for treatment of high cholesterol at a dosage of 450-900 milligrams a day, and that it affects blood coagulation and should not be used by hemophiliacs. A separate page includes information on adverse reactions, such as skin eruptions, anorexia and diarrhea. The dosages being considered for AIDS therapy are much higher than routine use in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. `` We do n't have any information on this drug in such high dosage,'' <PERSON> Endo </PERSON> said, adding that if a patient takes a high dosage, `` the risks might be higher.'' He declined to name all three pharmacies permitted to sell the drug, though he said their names were well-known to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francicso </LOCATION> AIDS sufferers. He said <PERSON> Kowa </PERSON> was concerned that people that people with irrational fears of AIDS might experiment with dangerously high doses. The three pharmacies reportedly have anywhere from two to 30 customers per month. The company also worries that buyers might start a black market business exporting the drug, which sells at the American Pharmacy for $ 272 for 1,000 300-milligram tablets. <PERSON> Kowa </PERSON> is not doing AIDS research with dextran sulfate. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s leader in that area is a 70-year-old chemical firm, <ORGANIZATION> Ueno </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemicals </ORGANIZATION>, which has no medicines currently on the market Ueno is worried that its research, backed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>, may be harmed by personal imports by American AIDS sufferers. `` From a humane point of view, we will not do anything'' to stop the drug's sale to Americans, said Dr. <PERSON> Ryuji </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueno </PERSON>, director of the department of medicine at his family's company. `` We are just a little disappointed, though.'' At stake for the company is the possibility of a lucrative <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market if the drug is proved effective. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> recently reaffirmed its policy of letting AIDS patients import drugs for their personal use even if they have not been approved. But the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> last week ordered inspectors to block imports of dextran sulfate from <ORGANIZATION> Polydex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmaceuticals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, saying the Canadian company was promoting its unproven drug in violation of federal rules. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has approved clinical tests of <PERSON> Ueno </PERSON>'s dextran sulfate compound but approval for use of the drug in AIDS therapy still is a long way off, <PERSON> Ueno </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from his laboratory near <LOCATION> Osaka </LOCATION>. So far, he said, the drug has been tested for side effects on patients at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> General </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. The current phase of tests, which began July 7, involves giving patients increasingly higher doses to see whether the drug is effective against HIV and to determine its side effects, <PERSON> Ueno </PERSON> said. The research is being done at nine AIDS-treatment centers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and will take six months. <PERSON> Ueno </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> had granted his compound `` open drug status,'' meaning authorities will help fund research and give the drug a protected market for seven years if it is successful. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has had only 80 AIDS cases, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION>, so few that the drug could not be tested on patients. AIDS is most often transmitted through sexual contact. Other means of transmission include transfusions of tainted blood or blood products, and the sharing of contaminated hypodermic needles or syringes by drug abusers. AIDS can also be passed from mother to child at or before birth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-HaitiPriest     08-08 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti Priest,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>Expelled Canadian priest said he feared for his life</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON>, a Roman Catholic priest deported from <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> after he criticized the military government, said in an interview Sunday he told his superiors last week that `` something could happen to me.'' `` I told them that if they heard I'd received a bullet in my head, do n't be surprised,'' <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> said in the telephone interview. The priest, a native of <LOCATION> Cornwall </LOCATION>, Ont., arrived in <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> Saturday on a flight from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> He was asked why be believed he could be the target of killers and said `` the system is becoming much more repressive and anything is possible.'' <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> said he was expelled because he spoke out against injustice and encouraged the poor to organize politically. He acknowledged he had refused a military demand to provide a list of parish members who attended one of his recent religious services. He said the troopers who seized him Friday did not have a warrant for his arrest and did not know his name. `` All they knew was that I was the -LRB- parish -RRB- priest and therefore wicked,'' he said. <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> gave this account of his expulsion: Several soldiers entered his parish in <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Goave </LOCATION>, 30 miles southeast of the capital of <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>, and drove him to a prison where he was not allowed to call the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. The soldiers took him to the airport where he was placed aboard a commercial jetliner, and when he tried to resist they struck him with their rifles and threw him face down on the aisle. It was a New York-bound flight and after spending the night in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> he flew to <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION>. A Haitian radio station said the government accused <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> of making `` insulting public declarations which are liable to disturb the social and political order established in the country.'' A statement by the Canadian government said it was `` deeply distressed and unhappy at the cavalier way that Father <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> was deported and -LRB- we -RRB- will be expressing our dissatisfaction to the Haitian authorities.'' <PERSON> Poirier </PERSON> was seized the same day that <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s leader, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, was touring the Grand Goave region. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said at that time that <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s problems should be solved by Haitians, not foreigners. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, the armed forces commander, ousted civilian President <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> in June and sent him into exile. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> headed a three-man junta that had ruled <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> for two years after dictator <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> fled the country during violent protests in February 1986. <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> now lives in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0004EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Fires     08-08 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Fires,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Forest Fires In China Kill 69 In First Half of 1988</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forest fires killed 69 people and injured 116 in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during the first half of the year, but the deaths represented a sharp drop from the same period a year ago, a newspaper reported today. An official of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prevention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Headquarters </ORGANIZATION> attributed the improved record to more rain in the north and stepped-up efforts to upgrade the nation's fire-fighting capabilities, the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said. The number of deaths declined 48 percent over the same period last year, the unidentified official was quoted as saying. The official said there were 9,700 forest fires during the first half of the year, 33 percent fewer than for the same period of 1987; and that 120,694 acres of forest were burned through June, down 85 percent, the paper reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0006EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Zoo     08-08 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Zoo,0370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Price Hikes Afflict Beijing Zoo Residents, Too</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Elephants at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Zoo have forgotten the taste of bananas and tigers are now rarely thrown a live chicken. Hard times have befallen their keepers. The official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said today that the 3,000 animals, birds and fish at <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s largest zoo have come across lean days because of inadequate funding and sharp rises in food prices. With the quadrupling of banana prices in recent years, elephants have been put on a diet of nutritious but less palatable carrots, zoo officials said. Tigers now get just two meals a day, down from three, and are fasting one day a week, zoo officials said, explaining that the big cats are used to eating irregularly in the wild. In addition, tigers, lions and other carnivores that used to have a twice-weekly treat of a live chicken or rabbit now feast on such delicacies only when they are sick or weak. The report said the zoo had to give away its most popular seal because it could n't afford the annual expense of up to $ 13,500 in fish. `` We do n't want to adopt these cruel measures, but as our budget is tightened, there seems to be no other way around,'' the report quoted <PERSON> Jiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Hongtao </PERSON>, office director of the zoo, as saying. The daily said expenses at the zoo have shot up from $ 1.1 million in 1984 to $ 1.9 million last year. The state last year provided $ 810,000, and the zoo had to make up the rest by introducing video games, bumper cars and other sources of recreation. Admission to the zoo costs less than a nickel. The zoo's chief accountant, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Qingchuan </PERSON>, said expenses may double next year because of swiftly rising food costs. Consumer prices rose 19 percent in June compared to the same month in 1987, while prices of some food items have nearly doubled in the past year with the elimination of some government price controls. The zoo opened in 1908 and is home to rare animals such as the giant panda and the golden monkey. It is one of the capital's main tourist attractions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Poll-CivilRights Bjt   08-08 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll-Civil Rights, Bjt,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll: Equality Closer But Society Still Racist</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GARY LANGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans believe the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has moved toward racial equality during the past quarter century, but a majority say society remains racist overall, a <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll has found. Twenty-five years after the Rev. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> declared his dream of equal opportunity, more than eight in 10 respondents in the poll said the goal is closer and seven in 10 said it is attainable. But while 54 percent said blacks and other minorities have the same opportunities as whites in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, a sizable 42 percent of all respondents, including 69 percent of blacks, disagreed. There were other measures of concern over inequality found by the national survey of 1,223 adults. Among them: _ Respondents were evenly divided on whether minorities receive equal treatment in the nation's criminal justice system, and three in 10 said minorities are denied justice because of their race _ Of those who said racial equality can be achieved, four in 10 said it would not occur within their lifetimes _ Majorities in all education, income and ideological groups, and all but the oldest age group, said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society is racist overall Fifty-three percent of whites agreed, as did 68 percent of blacks. In all, 55 percent said society is racist, 37 percent said not and the rest had no opinion. It was a quarter century ago, in August 1963, that <PERSON> King </PERSON> delivered his celebrated `` I have a dream'' speech to 200,000 demonstrators in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, establishing civil rights at the forefront of the nation's social agenda. `` I have a dream that one day on the red hills of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> sons of former slaves and sons of former slave owners will be able to sit down together at the table of brotherhood,'' <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. `` I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin, but by the content of their character.'' The Civil Rights Act became law a year later, prompting sweeping changes in the then-segregated South. But many Americans in the poll, particularly the better-educated, indicated that the advances are not complete. Among respondents with postgraduate degrees, only 28 percent said blacks and other minorities have the same opportunities as whites now. By contrast, 65 percent of those with only high school diplomas said there is equality. On the question of the criminal justice system, 46 percent of whites said minorities received equal treatment, but 40 percent said not, and nearly 15 percent did n't know. Sixty-one percent of blacks said minorities did not receive equal treatment in the criminal justice system. Even with the perceptions of inequality, the poll found divided opinion among blacks and solid opposition among whites to the practice of giving minorities preference in hiring and college admissions to address past inequalities. Forty-eight percent of blacks were in favor and 44 percent were opposed to preferential treatment in hiring, and they split 44-47 on preference in college admissions. More than 80 percent of whites opposed both. Despite their sense of racism and discrimination in society, 94 percent of the blacks said they had close friends who are white. A smaller share of whites, 67 percent, said they had close friends who are black. The Media General-AP poll consisted of telephone interviews June 22-July 2 with a randomly selected sample of adults across the nation, and had a margin of error of plus or minus 3 percentage points. <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a communications company based in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, publishes the Richmond Times-Dispatch, the Richmond News Leader, the Tampa -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION> -RRB-. Tribune and the <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, and operates TV stations <ORGANIZATION> WXFL </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, WCBD in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> WJKS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PollMethod     08-08 0527</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poll Method,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Poll-Civil Rights, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General-Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> poll on civil rights was based on telephone interviews June 22-July 2 with 1,223 adults in the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Phone numbers were selected randomly by computer and interviews were conducted with the adult at each household who had the most recent birthday. The results were weighted to adjust for variations in the sample. The poll has a 3-point margin of error, meaning that if every adult American were asked the same questions, the results theoretically would be within 3 points of the poll's results, 19 times out of 20. The error margin is larger for subgroups _ 9 points, for example, for blacks, who made up 11 percent of the adjusted sample, their share of the adult population. There are other sources of potential error in polls, including the wording and order of questions. These are the questions and responses in this poll; because of rounding, some totals may exceed 100: 1. Overall, do you think blacks and other minorities have the same opportunities as whites in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or not? Yes: 54 percent. No: 42 percent. Do n't know or no answer: 4 percent. 2. In the past 25 years, do you think the country has moved closer to equal opportunity among the races, or farther away from it, or has there been no movement? Closer: 84 percent. Farther: 5 percent. No movement: 7 percent. DK-NA: 4 percent. 3. Do you think it is possible to achieve equal opportunity among the races in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, or not? Yes: 71 percent. No: 24 percent. DK-NA: 5 percent. 3a. If yes: Do you think it will happen in your lifetime, or not? Yes: 53 percent. No: 40 percent. DK-NA: 7 percent. 4. Do you think blacks and other minorities should receive preference in hiring to make up for past inequalities, or not? Yes: 15 percent. No: 79 percent. DK-NA: 6 percent. 5. Do you think blacks and other minorities should receive preference in college admissions to make up for past inequalities, or not? Yes: 18 percent. No: 76 percent. DK-NA: 5 percent. 6. Do you think blacks and other minorities receive equal treatment as whites in the criminal justice system, or not? Yes: 43 percent. No: 43 percent. DK-NA: 15 percent. 6a. If no: Do you think blacks and other minorities are denied justice because of their race, or not? Yes: 69 percent. No: 24 percent. DK-NA: 7 percent. 7. Do you think <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s campaign for the Democratic presidential nomination advanced the cause of civil rights, set back the cause of civil rights, or had no effect on it? Advanced: 51 percent. Set back: 7 percent. No effect: 33 percent. DK-NA: 9 percent. 8. Do you have any close friends who are black, or not? Among whites: Yes: 67 percent. No: 31 percent. DK-NA: 2 percent. 9. Do you have any close friends who are white, or not? Among blacks Yes: 94 percent. No: 5 percent. DK-NA: 2 percent. 10. Do you think American society overall is racist, or not? Yes: 55 percent. No: 37 percent. DK-NA: 9 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChemicalSpill     08-08 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Spill,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Derailment Causes Spill, Evacuation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIDDLETON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 50 cars of a freight train derailed Monday, causing tankers to break open and spill a flammable industrial solvent, and forcing the evacuation of about 300 people overnight, authorities said. Authorities built a dike, using booms supplied by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, to keep the pool of liquid xylene from flowing into nearby <LOCATION> Beaver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Justus </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the state Environmental Protection Division. The <LOCATION> Elbert </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's department and officials with <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> estimated 57 cars in the 95-car <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> train derailed about 1:30 p.m. in this rural community. <ORGANIZATION> Elbert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> reported treating about 20 people who had breathed fumes from the liquid chemical, which is used in aviation fuel and as a solvent for resins, enamels and lacquers. None were seriously injured and all were released after `` they were washed down and looked at by a physician,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, a hospital official. `` The primary hazard is that it -LRB- xylene -RRB- is flammable. There are vapors and fumes which are mildly toxic by inhalation or ingestion,'' Ms. <PERSON> Justus </PERSON> said. The fractured tanker, which contained about 30,000 gallons of xylene, leaked its contents at a rate that grew to 3,000 gallons an hour, she said. A second tanker also was leaking the chemical, although at a much slower rate, she said. Five of the derailed cars contained xylene, she said. <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> said the train, which was headed to <LOCATION> Hamlet </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, also carried coal, pulp board, lumber, soybean meal and a number of piggybacked truck trailers. He said the train was going about 35 mph when it derailed. There was no immediate indication of what caused the derailment. Cleanup was expected to begin after daylight Tuesday. Ms. <PERSON> Justus </PERSON> said the liquid probably would be allowed to soak into the dirt field where it spilled and the contaminated soil would be dug up and taken to a hazardous waste landfill. The <ORGANIZATION> Elberton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> was set up as a clearing house for aid to the evacuees. Most found shelter at motels or at the homes of family and friends in the area, although the Rev. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Purvis </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elberton </ORGANIZATION>, said he expected some evacuees would sleep on the pews at his church. <PERSON> Middleton </PERSON> is four miles northeast of <LOCATION> Elberton </LOCATION>, in eastern <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> about midway between <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, S.C.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-08 0957</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0998</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> is savoring his part in the new movie `` Tucker: The Man and His Dream,'' saying it is one of the best roles he's had in 25 years. `` This role allowed me to act. I loved it,'' <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said in an interview published Sunday in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>, perhaps best known as master illusionist <PERSON> Rolin </PERSON>' Hand in television's `` Mission: Impossible,'' plays <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Karatz </PERSON> in <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>'s film, which opens this week. His character is an amiable businessman-hustler who advises <PERSON> Preston </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, an industrialist who tried to break into the automobile industry following World War II. Their friendship forms a subplot of the movie. `` I think of it as a love story,'' <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said, `` a very healthy love story between two men.'' `` In size and dimension, it's probably the best role I've had since ` Cleopatra,''' <PERSON> Landau </PERSON> said, referring to the 1963 movie.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, who became a star as the tiny hero of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Diff ` rent Strokes,'' says he blames his parents for his lack of maturity and a resulting reputation as a difficult, spoiled child `` I have a lot of trouble with industry people that respect my work, respect my craft, but do n't respect me because I have that shadowy reputation,'' <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Costas </PERSON> on the forthcoming <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> talk show `` Later with <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Costas </PERSON>.'' The 20-year-old actor is only 4-foot-8 because of drugs he takes to keep his body from rejecting two kidney transplants. In the three years since `` Diff ` rent Strokes'' went off the air, <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> has had just two acting `` I just hope people understand that if I'm crazy or if I'm rude or if I have a bad reputation, it's 10 percent my fault and 90 percent of those that were supposed to have been helping me and caring for me,'' he said. He said he has little contact with his parents, calling them on the phone `` once in a blue moon.'' The Costas show is slated to debut later this month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet defector <PERSON> Natalia </PERSON> <PERSON> Makarova </PERSON> says that although she has n't danced with <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>'s Kirov Ballet for 18 years, she's always had a `` spiritual contact'' with the troupe. Miss <PERSON> Makarova </PERSON>, 47, rejoined her former company Saturday during its <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> visit to dance one performance of the pas de deux from Act II of `` <LOCATION> Swan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>,'' after getting special permission from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. As she took her bow, many in the audience stood, clapping and shouting, `` Bravo!'' Miss <PERSON> Makarova </PERSON> defected in 1970 during the Kirov's last visit to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, saying she wanted greater artistic freedom and opportunity. She said in an interview before Saturday's performance that she would have liked to rejoin the Kirov, if she were younger. `` One company has been in my heart all these years, and I never lose spiritual contact with them. It is the most happy moment in my life,'' she said. `` It fulfills my own soul.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pro basketball player <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Moncrief </PERSON> told youngsters in a summer reading program that if he'd paid more attention to reading himself that day, he would n't have had a weekend encounter with the law. <PERSON> Moncrief </PERSON> said he wished he'd read his speedometer while driving to speak to the program Saturday. `` If I had read my speed, I would n't have been stopped by a state trooper'' while en route to the ceremony for about 150 participants in the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> System </ORGANIZATION>'s Summer Reading Program. <PERSON> Moncrief </PERSON>, who plays for the <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bucks </ORGANIZATION>, has an unlisted telephone number and could not be reached Sunday to elaborate on the traffic stop. An <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> dispatcher said he had no information about it.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although Arkansas Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> had a full agenda at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> meeting, one of his main objectives was living down the long speech he made at the Democratic National Convention. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> said he received a request to speak at the governors' meeting from its incoming chairman and fellow Democrat, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON>. `` Governor <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> just suggested that I begin my remarks with the words, ` in conclusion,''' <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> said Sunday, drawing applause from those gathered to hear a debate on education issues. Those two words drew a roar of applause when <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> wrapped up his speech in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to nominate <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for president. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> was allotted 15 minutes for the nationally-televised speech but spoke for more than twice that. The speech was panned as boring and too long. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> admitted as much later.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Congressman <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> is planning a homecoming to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> for the first time since his double-lung transplant and his marriage to a woman 23 years his junior. The 60-year-old Republican congressman who's running for re-election in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> this fall says he's grateful to be alive. On May 6, his lungs, devastated by years of emphysema, were replaced with a pair from an 18-year-old youth killed in a motorcycle accident in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. And on July 3, he married <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a woman he had been courting 8 -LCB- years. <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> said in an interview with The -LRB- <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- State newspaper from <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, that his illness has cost him votes because of questions about his ability to represent the district. But <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> says he's recovering well and is able to exercise 90 minutes a day. His convalescence was highlighted by a get-well note from former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and a telephone call from singer <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON>, he said. <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> and his bride are scheduled to arrive in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> tonight. He plans to attend a fund-raiser for his campaign on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-08 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0539</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINCOLN, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parishioners at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mark </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Methodist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> can simply say, `` Charge it,'' the next time the collection plate comes their way. Officers of the church's finance committee decided to accept donations via <ORGANIZATION> MasterCard </ORGANIZATION> and Visa, beginning Sunday. `` A lot of people may look at it with distaste, but they do n't have to utilize it,'' said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Ecklund </PERSON>, chairman of the church finance committee `` Some people have requested it and we're a large enough church that we can accommodate them. I think convenience is the number one advantage.'' Any of the 3,000 parishioners who make credit-card donations will get a receipt they can put in an envelope and drop in the collection plate. `` People still feel good about putting something in the collection plate,'' <PERSON> Ecklund </PERSON> said. `` I always feel awkward sitting in the pew and not putting anything in the collection plate when it is passed.'' Congregation members also can arrange to have a certain amount automatically charged to their bank account on a specified day of the month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AURORA, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She was in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, he was in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. But the distance between them did n't stop them from exchanging wedding vows. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardiner </PERSON> became husband and wife by telephone on Saturday, with a speaker phone standing in for <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> during the ceremony here. `` It was different talking to a machine instead of a live person looking me in the eye,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellim </PERSON>, who performed the ceremony. The couple met a year ago, and <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> proposed after the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> shipped him to <LOCATION> Ankara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. They decided to get married by telephone because <PERSON> Boatwright </PERSON> might not have been able to come to <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION> for six more months, said the bride, who hopes to join her husband within six weeks. About 30 people gathered at the bride's home for the ceremony, but the groom was alone. `` This is a very solemn thing for us, and I chose to be by myself,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EDWARDS, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When <ORGANIZATION> Caterpillar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> struts its stuff, it does it in a big way. The company staged a `` power parade'' Sunday, displaying $ 15 million worth of its finest earth-moving equipment in a showcase of sophisticated engineering and raw power for 10,000 customers and employees. The Peoria-based <ORGANIZATION> Caterpillar </ORGANIZATION> trotted out 76 machines _ from the largest track-type tractor in production on any assembly line, down to its smallest paving vehicle. The demonstration track built near <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> for the parade looked like a giant construction site. Scrapers used in highway construction pulled up dirt and dumped it back. Excavators dug holes, filled their buckets with dirt and then loaded empty dump trucks used in mining and construction. Graders leveled the rumpled ground and compactors rumbled along, packing the dirt down again. There were tests of strength for hydraulic-powered swing arms. Other machines did push-ups, intricate driving and even waved to the crowd in unison. But the crowd's favorite was a wheel loader that used one tooth on its massive front bucket to gently crack an egg.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Ellerbee     08-08 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Ellerbee,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ellerbee Blames Network for Not Trying to Help Anchorwoman</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> reporter <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> said she was afraid that colleague <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON> was on a suicidal course because of problems including drug use but her approaches to network management went unheeded. <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON> was killed in a car accident Oct. 26, 1983, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hope </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. The accident was not linked to drug use. Recent books about <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON> describe her as a tormented women who was well aware that she had moved up the ladder on her appealing presence and was resented by more experienced colleagues. Her career nose-dived after a disastrous newsbrief in which she appeared on the air virtually incoherent. `` At one point,'' <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> said, `` I went to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> management and said, ` You have to do something. This woman's in trouble.' An <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> vice president said to me, ` We're afraid to do anything. We're afraid she'll kill herself on our time. <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> says on the first installment of the new late-night talk show `` Later with <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Costas </PERSON>,'' to be broadcast Aug. 22, that she and her <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondents decided to try to help <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> said she, former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> colleagues met in <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON>'s office and decided <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> would get advice from his psychiatrist on how to approach <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON>. But she died in the car wreck that weekend. <PERSON> Savitch </PERSON>'s story is worth telling, <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON> said, `` as a cautionary tale'' for young women and men entering the television news field. <PERSON> Ellerbee </PERSON>, who now free-lances her commentary and hopes to have a PBS version of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Our World,'' says television news has changed little in its attitude toward women who go into the business. `` <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> is just what the business wanted,'' she said. `` Let's be candid _ what the men who run the business wanted She looked the part, and they did n't care that she was n't a very good reporter and that she was n't a very good writer. `` They just wanted what they wanted out of her, and it's a tragedy that they did n't want more. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> might have been able to give more had they expected more from the very beginning.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0131EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan-Bush Bjt   08-08 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Bush, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Reagan is Bush Surrogate with Conservatives</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A surrogate campaigner for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been trying to reassure the political right that the vice president is n't straying too far from conservative doctrine as he moves toward the center in his presidential campaign. The surrogate's name is <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Increasingly the president sprinkles his speeches with such phrases as `` Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and I'' and `` <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and me.'' He also has both praised and glossed over positions that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has taken that are at variance with his own conservative stands. In a recent speech to a group of evangelical youth, for example, he tackled the issue of day care for children. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has opposed government-subsidized child care proposals. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, however, trails in the polls among women voters and has attempted to close that `` gender gap'' with proposals including a $ 2.2 billion plan to give low-income families a $ 1,000-per-child tax credit for day care. Conservatives have generally been against this kind of thing, and it is one of a number of issues on which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been exploring new territory in a campaign that is expected to be fought out in the political center. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, speaking to the <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Evangelism, approached the matter this way: `` Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed an innovative plan, one that would strengthen the family. ... The basic idea here is that the government would simply let families keep up to $ 1,000 more of their own money. That's money the family itself can decide how to spend. Working mothers could put the money toward child care. But by giving each family this tax credit the vice president's plan would also permit thousands of mothers to choose to stay home with their children.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> suggests that even though it goes against the grain of traditional conservative thought, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s day-care program is really pro-family and amounts to a kind of tax cut _ things that conservatives like. The president also tiptoed around the differences between his position and the vice president's on abortion. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he would accept abortion if necessary to save the life of the mother or in instances of rape and incest. The president has said repeatedly he would accept the operation only if needed to save the mother's life. The way <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spelled it out to the evangelicals was: `` Many who seek abortions do so in harrowing circumstances. And just as tolerance means accepting that many in good faith hold views different from our own, it also means that no man or woman should sit in judgment on another. I believe _ and Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> believes with me _ that we must rise above bitterness and reproach to find positive answers to the tragedy of abortion.'' No mention of their differences _ just `` positive answers'' for people in `` harrowing circumstances.'' As the campaign goes on, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to stake out increasingly independent stands. `` He's talking about education, he's talking about child care, soon he is going to be talking about flexibility in defense posture, he's talking about public service,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>, a specialist in the presidency and electoral politics at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Not the usual fare for conservative rallies. So are <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s explanations part of a plan to bolster <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s conservative credentials `` I do n't know if it has been strategically laid out as such, but it makes sense,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` That is probably the single best way to use him.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DukakisDefense 1stLd-Writethru a0427 08-08 0682</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis Defense, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0427,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Making Strong Counterpunch on Defense Issue</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS editor's note at end identifying writer.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' challenge to debate <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on foreign policy and defense is the Democratic presidential nominee's confident counterattack in an area that could be either a weakness or a weapon for him. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' staff seemed taken aback by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s claim last week that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would unilaterally disarm the nation, an unusually aggressive attack at this early stage of the general election campaign. `` Shrill'' was the way <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> described it as he delivered a series of escalating responses ending in the call for a mid-September debate on the issue. It had already been clear, however, that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would strive to paint <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as inexperienced and out of step on national security matters as the vice president moved to recover from a substantial deficit in the polls. Foreign policy, defense and national security concerns are widely regarded as the weakest areas for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for a variety of reasons. It is the one area in which <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a statehouse politician, has no record. And despite his familiarity with several languages, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not a veteran traveler to foreign capitals. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for all his image problems, can point to his experience in the international arena even before his vice presidency as ambassador to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director. But <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been hammering away at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the foreign affairs missteps of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign clearly believes that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is vulnerable on the Iran-Contra affair, dealings with Panamanian strongman <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contracting scandal and other problems. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> raised that criticism to a new level on Friday while campaigning in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> when he said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does n't `` have what it takes'' to run the country. `` Anybody who sits there and does nothing while we trade arms to the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON>, and says he did n't know that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was doing drugs and running drugs -LRB- and -RRB- is a suspected murderer, and went to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> in the early'80s and commended -LRB- <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> for his commitment to democracy, in my judgment does n't have what it takes to lead this country when it comes to foreign policy,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. A day earlier, however, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had fed the impression he could misstep on military issues when he was questioned about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s charges Asked initially if he still supported a nuclear freeze, which was debated before arms reduction talks began in 1985, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> responded `` sure.'' Moments later aboard his campaign jet, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides hastily arranged a news conference and brought the candidate back to where reporters were sitting on the plane. There, when asked, he clarified his response and said that the issue had moved beyond the question of a nuclear freeze to that of arms reductions. `` The reason we were all for the freeze originally was because we wanted to stop the administration from expanding the arsenal,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. He said that had changed now that negotiations centered on reductions. `` Did I favor the freeze? Sure. I'm for reductions now. So's the administration,'' he said. `` I'm for developing certain weapons systems -LRB- and -RRB- for substantially reducing others.'' In attacking the Democratic nominee, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pointed to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' opposition to some new systems, particularly land-based nuclear weapons <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has said he does n't rule out modernization of the land-based arsenal _ that is, producing a new type of missile. Yet he opposes current options _ the MX and the smaller Midgetman. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> aides point to his support for other systems, such as the new Trident submarine-based missile and cruise missiles, and for development of the bomb-carrying Stealth aircraft. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> generally prefers to talk about his plans to beef up conventional forces, although he has not been specific on how to pay for expensive upgrades in equipment, weaponry, supplies and training. It is on conventional forces that he can be expected to focus if he gets that debate with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ EDITOR'S NOTE _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> is covering the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidential campaign for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0138EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CollisionCosts Bjt   08-08 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Collision Costs, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Big Cars Have Fewer Accident Claims</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owners of 1988 passenger vans and large sedans are likely to have fewer damage claims and lower repair bills, while those who own sports cars and some compact cars may not be as lucky, according to an insurance industry report. The study by the <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an insurance research group, examined both the frequency of insurance collision claims and the average amount of the claim for 60 new cars that had repairs paid through insurance policies during the first nine months of the 1988 model year. `` Even among cars of the same size class and body style there were large variations in results,'' the insurance group said. But it said that in general, larger cars had a better collision loss record than smaller vehicles. The average claim payment ranged from $ 800 to $ 3,500, depending on the type of vehicle. The frequency of claims ranged from six to nearly 17 per 100 vehicles, the study said. The study did not provide dollar amounts for all vehicle claims, but said the average repair bill for the 60 cars was $ 1,921. The average number of claims filed was 11.1 per 100 insured vehicles. It singled out the <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astro </ORGANIZATION> van as having the lowest average loss payment per claim, 60 percent lower than average for all passenger vehicles examined. The Jaguar XJ6 had the highest, 83 percent higher than average for all cars, while the <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> MX-6 and the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mustang </ORGANIZATION> also had average repair costs per claim that were at least 50 percent higher than average. The study said the passenger vehicles with `` substantially better than average'' results in both frequency of claims and average cost of repairs also were vans _ the <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Dodge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caravan </ORGANIZATION> _ and two large, 4-door sedans _ the <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caprice </ORGANIZATION> and the Mercury Grand Marquis. All four of these vehicles had claim frequencies and loss payments at least 30 percent below the average for all cars. The least number of claims per vehicles on the road involved the 4-door <ORGANIZATION> Cadillac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> DeVille </ORGANIZATION> which had 46 percent fewer claims than average for all cars. At the other extreme, the cars with the poorest showing in both claim frequencies and repair costs were the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mustang </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Chevrolet </PERSON> <PERSON> Camaro </PERSON>, both in the `` sports-speciality'' category, and the 2-door <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> MX-6 in the small car category. All three had claim frequencies and loss payments more than 20 percent above average. The Mustang had more than twice the average repair cost than reported for all cars _ the highest among the 60 cars _ and 32 percent more claims. The 2-door Toyota Celica had the most number of claims, 53 percent more than the average for all cars. While both the number of claims and the average cost of repairs ranged widely among vehicles of different size and design, the insurance group said they also varied significantly within groups of basically similar cars. For example, the frequency of claims among the `` small'' cars ranged from 12 percent below average for the Mercury Tracer to 53 percent above average for the Toyota Celica and 46 percent above average for the Pontiac LeMans. In the mid-size category, the frequency of claims ranged from 32 percent below average for the <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Celebrity </ORGANIZATION> to 29 percent above average for the Renault Medallion. Repair costs ranged from 21 percent below average per claim for the Celebrity to 25 percent above average for the <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cavalier </ORGANIZATION>. The study examined 60 model 1988 passenger vehicles that had collision claims filed from June 1987 through February 1988. While there are about 400 various 1988 car types, only 60 had sufficient highway exposure during the period to be included in the study, the institute said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CarList     08-08 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Car List,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Collision Costs Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the relative frequency of claims and repair cost comparisions of 1988 model cars examined by the insurance industry, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. The number in each column reflects relative claim frequencies or repair costs compared to the average -LRB- reflected by the figure 100 -RRB- for all cars examined. For claim frequency, 100 is equivalent to 11.1 claims per 100 insured vehicles; for average loss payment per claim, 100 is equivalent to $ 1,921. -LRB- Example: a claim frequency 123 would reflect 23 percent more claims than average for all vehicles listed. A claim frequency of 88 would reflect 12 percent fewer claims than average for all vehicles listed. A repair cost figure of 82 reflects a cost 18 percent lower than average, while a repair cost figure of 166 reflects a cost 66 percent higher than average. -RRB-
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Car Model       Claim Repair</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Frequency Cost
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Small Cars (2 door)@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Toyota Tercel 123 82 <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Civic 108 103 Ford Fiesta 104 114 <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> Sentra 129 91 Ford Escort 131 98 Mercury Tracer 109 118 Hyundai Excel 139 96 <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> 323 114 119 Pontiac Lemans 146 113 Toyota Celica 153 118 <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> MX-6 121 166
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Small Cars (4 door)@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Ford Escort 110 73 Mercury Tracer 88 96 <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> 323 91 102 Honda Civic 132 75 Toyota Corolla 102 110 Hyundai Excel 118 102 Pontiac Lemans 129 117
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Mid-size Cars (2-door)@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Mercury Cougar 108 89 <ORGANIZATION> Pontiac </ORGANIZATION> GrandAm 97 100 Buick Regal 103 101 <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Prelude 113 96 Oldsmobile Calaise 101 108 <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Accord 123 99 Chevrolet Baretta 118 104 Ford Thunderbird 113 121 Chevrolet Cavalier 113 125
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Mid-size Cars (4-door)@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Chevrolet Celebrity 68 79 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taurus </ORGANIZATION> 81 76 Olds. <PERSON> Cutlass </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciera </PERSON> 72 89 <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camry </ORGANIZATION> 77 91 Dodge Aries 75 96 <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reliant </ORGANIZATION> 82 91 <ORGANIZATION> Mazda </ORGANIZATION> 626 80 115 <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corsica </ORGANIZATION> 110 85 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tempo </ORGANIZATION> 87 110 <ORGANIZATION> Honda </ORGANIZATION> Accord 108 90 Renault Medallion 129 97
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Mid-Size Stationwagon@Vans@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Ford Taurus 75 93
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Mid-size Sports@Speciality@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> IV 83 113 Chevrolet Camaro 128 120 Ford Mustang 132 156
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Large Cars (4-door)@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Chevrolet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caprice </ORGANIZATION> 67 65 <ORGANIZATION> Merc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marquis </ORGANIZATION> 64 69 <ORGANIZATION> Pontiac </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bonneville </ORGANIZATION> 57 84 Olds Ninety Eight 55 95 <ORGANIZATION> Buick </ORGANIZATION> LeSabre 76 90 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Victoria </ORGANIZATION> 80 88 <ORGANIZATION> Buick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electra </ORGANIZATION> 79 97 <ORGANIZATION> Oldsmobile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> 88 78 101
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Large Stationwagons@Vans@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Chevrolet Astro Van 78 40 Plym. Grand Voyager 63 59 Dodge Caravan 66 60 <ORGANIZATION> Plymouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voyager </ORGANIZATION> 75 61 Dodge Grand Caravan 76 70 <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerostar </ORGANIZATION> 78 84
</TEXT>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
<HEAD>Large Sports@Speciality@</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Cadillac DeV'll 4dr 54 104 <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Town </ORGANIZATION> Car 77 94 <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION> XJ6 72 183 BMW 735i 89 149
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FallingSatellite     08-08 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Falling Satellite,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Officials Keeping Eye on Falling Soviet Satellite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal officials have begun contingency planning in case an out-of-control Russian satellite powered by a nuclear reactor plunges to earth inside the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. At the moment, `` we do n't anticipate at all that it will land on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' says <PERSON> Peg </PERSON> <PERSON> Malloy </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. `` But we need to have our act together to respond to any catastrophic emergency, so we're coordinating an inter-agency effort right now.'' The planning work has drawn together representatives from the <ORGANIZATION> Departments </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> in addition to the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the spokeswoman added. The various agencies are working to tailor <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION>'s general `` Federal Radiological Emergency Response Plan'' to deal with the possibility of radioactive satellite pieces being spread across the countryside, Ms. <PERSON> Malloy </PERSON> said. The agency's radiological emergency plan was originally developed in the wake of the <LOCATION> Three-Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nuclear plant disaster, she added. The concern of the planners is a nuclear-powered, ocean-surveillance satellite launched by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> last December 12 to keep track of <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> vessels. The satellite, designated by the Soviets as Cosmos 1900, began its life in space in a low circular orbit about 160 miles above the earth's surface. Soviet controllers unexpectedly lost radio contact with the craft in April and the Russian news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported May 11 that the satellite could fall to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> in August or September. Soviet officials have insisted there is no reason to fear radioactive debris from the spacecraft's re-entry. But according to <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials, the Soviets have apparently been unable to separate either the nuclear reactor or the fuel section from the rest of the satellite _ two common safeguards. That raises the possibility Cosmos 1900 could re-enter the atmosphere in one piece, meaning it might not burn up completely. That could spread harmful radioactive debris, just as <ORGANIZATION> Cosmos </ORGANIZATION> 954 did over <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in 1978. `` At the moment, it's still a one-piece satellite,'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Dugald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>, said recently. The orbit of Cosmos 1900 is continuing to decay and the spacecraft is now under constant surveillance, <PERSON> Gillies </PERSON> said. `` Re-entry is not imminent,'' he said. `` But the period for a revolution is continuing to decline and it's continuing to come in closer to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. We're keeping a close watch on it.'' While the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Space Command is not yet prepared to predict when the Russian satellite will re-enter the atmosphere, the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> said last week it thought the plunge would occur in mid-September. `` Cosmos 1900 is expected to re-enter around the middle of September, give or take four weeks,'' the agency said in a statement. `` Only a few days before the satellite re-enters can the entry location be predicted. `` Until then, experts can only say that Cosmos 1900 will re-enter somewhere between latitudes 65 degrees north and 65 degrees south'' _ meaning anywhere in the world between the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circles </LOCATION>. `` It's not coming down as fast as originally anticipated, but it's coming down,'' added Ms. <PERSON> Malloy </PERSON>. Should Cosmos 1900 fall within <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> borders, <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> will have an emergency response team ready, she said. The size and composition of the response team will depend upon a variety of factors, including whether the satellite debris is radioactive and where it lands, she said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has launched more than 30 nuclear-powered satellites over the years and in at least two cases, radioactive debris from such satellites has fallen to the Earth's surface. Besides the crash of <ORGANIZATION> Cosmos </ORGANIZATION> 954 over <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in 1978, the nuclear core of Cosmos 1402 splashed into the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> in 1983.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-TVGuideSale Bjt   08-08 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TV Guide Sale, Bjt,0609</SECOND>
<HEAD>Murdoch Agrees To Pay $3 Billion For Annenberg's Triangle
Publications</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> has agreed to buy <ORGANIZATION> Triangle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> for $ 3 billion in one of the most expensive media deals ever and one that would add TV Guide, the nation's largest-selling weekly magazine, to his empire The purchase of the privately-held company from <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> includes two other publications: the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Racing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Form </ORGANIZATION> and Seventeen magazine, <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> said Sunday. `` These publications are the most valuable and prized publishing properties in the world,'' <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> said in a statement announcing the purchase by his <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The purchase of TV Guide raises anti-trust questions because of <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s ownership of the <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartzman </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Access </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-based public interest telecommunications firm. But a spokesman for <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> said TV Guide would be run separately from <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s other holdings, which include newspapers and magazines on four continents. <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> began negotiating with the 80-year-old <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> for Triangle a month ago. `` They -LRB- the Triangle publications -RRB- have been developed brilliantly by Ambassador <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> and we plan to make them the cornerstone of a great American publishing company,'' <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON>, chairman of Triangle, said in a statement: `` I am very happy that my publications are passing to Mr. <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s company I now plan to devote the rest of my life to education and philanthropy.'' His past philanthropies include the establishment of the <ORGANIZATION> Annenberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION>, to which he has given one-third of Triangle's stock over the years. <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> and <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> were in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and would have no further comment, said <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubenstein </PERSON>. The spokesman declined to say who initiated the talks for the sale, which is contingent upon signing of a final contract. The largest media takeover was <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s $ 3.5 billion purchase of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> in 1986. <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON>, who was <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the Court of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> during the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration, took over Triangle from his father in the 1930s. He founded TV Guide in 1952 and it quickly became Triangle's flagship, earning an estimated $ 75 million per year. TV Guide has an audited circulation of more than 17 million copies. Triangle was valued at about $ 1 billion last year by Wall Street analysts. `` The three best businesses in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> are the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Racing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Form </ORGANIZATION>, TV Guide and the Wall Street Journal,'' <PERSON> Annenberg </PERSON> said in a 1987 interview, when he indicated that the three publications would be sold before 1990. <PERSON> Schwartzman </PERSON> said joint ownership of TV Guide and the Fox network could allow <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> to use the publication to favor <PERSON> Fox </PERSON> programs and stations. Such treatment could hurt small independent TV stations, for which TV Guide is an essential advertising medium, said <PERSON> Schwartzman </PERSON>. `` Any media conglomeration of this scope ought to set off warning signals at the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Schwartzman </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Rubinstein </PERSON> said, `` The TV Guide will be run totally independent of all Mr. <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s other interests.'' <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>, 58, is perhaps best known in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for his work at the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, which he purchased in 1976 and converted from one of the country's most liberal dailies to a conservative paper with screaming headlines. He sold the Post earlier this year to conform with federal regulations barring dual ownership of a television station and a newspaper in the same city. His holdings have an estimated value of $ 2.2 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-RepublicanDelegates-VP     08-08 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Republican Delegates-VP,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>GOP Delegates Aren't Choosy on Vice President Selection</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Delegates to the Republican National Convention are n't particularly choosy about a vice presidential candidate, with the largest group inclined to accept anyone <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> selects. In an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey, the `` candidate'' backed by the largest group of delegates, 39 percent, was nobody in particular. Two former presidential candidates, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, each were favored by 14 percent. Others mentioned by a smattering of delegates included <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON>, major league baseball Commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> communications director <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> and a couple of otherwise unknowns whose candidacies were advanced by relatives who happen to be delegates Of the 1,274 <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegates responding to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey, 492 said they had no particular choice for the No. 2 spot on the party's ticket That sentiment is not at all uncommon as delegates tend to defer to whatever decision their party's presidential nominee makes on the issue of a running mate. Two-thirds of the Democratic delegates did not name anyone as their choice for vice president, but when <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> picked <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> as his running mate, that decision was endorsed by acclamation at last month's convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he will not announce his running mate until Aug. 18, the final day of the Republican convention. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey did show some sentiment for a female vice presidential candidate. Polls have shown that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> lags behind <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> among female voters, and 10 percent of the delegates responding to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey said one way to overcome this would be to pick a woman as his running mate. Fourteen percent of the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> delegates scattered their support among four women: former <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> Ambassador <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, who was named by 82 delegates, former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, supported by 79 delegates, Sen. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> with 17 delegates and <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> with five delegates. <PERSON> Kassebaum </PERSON> has said she does not want to be considered for the vice presidential spot, as has <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON>, who was named as the choice of two dozen delegates. The delegates' vice presidential choices cut across lines of education, gender and political experience, with roughly the same percentages of college graduates supporting <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> as <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, for example. The survey was conducted by <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> bureaus in all 50 states, as well as <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION> and is based on responses from 56 percent of the 2,277 delegates who will attend the GOP convention.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0202EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Haid     08-08 0179</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Haid,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Hill Street Blues' Actor Rescued After Spill From Boat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MALIBU, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Haid </PERSON>, who portrayed Officer <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Renko </PERSON> on television's old `` Hill Street Blues'' and stars in the movie `` The Rescue,'' was plucked from the ocean after he took a spill off his sail boat. <PERSON> Haid </PERSON>, 40, said he was never in danger after falling from the catamaran about a mile off <LOCATION> Broad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> on Saturday afternoon. He said a couple pulled him from the water 45 minutes later. <PERSON> Haid </PERSON> said he fell into the water while trying to attach himself to a harness that allows him to lean out over the water as the wind-tipped boat rides on one pontoon. `` I was hooking on, my hook slipped and I went off the back,'' <PERSON> Haid </PERSON> said after the accident. His brother, who also was on the boat, lost sight of him, and went back to shore for help. The actor, who was wearing a wet suit and a life preserver, said he `` would have just floated ashore'' if the unidentified couple had n't come along.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MurdochHoldings     08-08 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Murdoch Holdings,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-TV Guide Sale, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the major media holdings of <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which on Sunday announced an agreement to buy <ORGANIZATION> Triangle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, publisher of TV Guide, the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Racing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Form </ORGANIZATION> and Seventeen magazine, for $ 3 billion.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEWSPAPERS</BYLINE>
<HEAD>United States</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Antonio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Britain</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The Times -LRB- <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> -RRB- The <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> -RRB- The Sun -LRB- <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> -RRB- News of the World -LRB- <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Australia</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION> -RRB- Weekly Times -LRB- <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION> -RRB- The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> -RRB- The Daily Mirror -LRB- <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> -RRB- The Australian -LRB- <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Hong Kong</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 South China Morning Post
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAGAZINES</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 New York Magazine The Star New Woman <PERSON> Elle </PERSON> -LRB- 50 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> edition -RRB- In Fashion Sportswear International
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>BROADCASTING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Twentieth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WXFT-TV </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> -RRB- WNYW-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -RRB- KTTV-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -RRB- WFLD-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -RRB- WTTG-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> -RRB- KRIV-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> -RRB- KDAF-TV -LRB- <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PUBLISHING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Row </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Sons -LRB- <LOCATION> Glasgow </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Obit-Wright     08-08 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Wright,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. District Judge J. Skelly Wright Noted For Desegregation
Rulings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, whose 38-year career as a federal judge included decisions on major cases balancing individual rights and government power, has died at age 77. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who participated in the Pentagon Papers case and wrote the decree ending de facto segregation in the nation's capital, died Saturday of cancer. He had retired last year after 25 years on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> here _ two as chief judge _ and 13 years as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District judge in his native <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, whose full name was <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in 1934 and became an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney three years later. Following military duty in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> to practice law before being named <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in 1948. The next year, at the age of 38, he was appointed to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, becoming the youngest man to hold the post at that time. After his 1960 order desegregating the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> school system drew threats against his life, President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> reassigned <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. In 1967, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s order overturned the District school system's racially separate `` tracking system'' for grouping students The `` Wright decree,'' in addressing de facto segregation, was considered one of the most significant education rulings since the 1954 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision outlawing the doctrine of `` separate but equal'' schools. In the 1971 Pentagon Papers case involving an attempt by the government on national security grounds to restrain publication of military documents by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, he dissented from the ruling of two other judges on a three-member appeals court panel. In favoring the right of the newspaper to publish, he wrote: `` To allow a government to suppress free speech simply through a system of bureaucratic classification would sell our heritage far, far too cheaply.'' Survivors include his wife, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON>, a son, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, one brother, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, and three sisters, <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruckert </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hotard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0228EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     08-08 0026</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0027</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 28,253.12 points, down 109.06 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Jordan-Palestinians Bjt   08-08 0745</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jordan-Palestinians, Bjt,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jordan Will Recognize Exile Government; PLO Working On Declaration</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HALABY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A week after abandoning any claim to the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> says he would recognize the establishment of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> government-in-exile and welcome a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>. The Jordanian monarch made the comments to reporters Sunday as draft documents calling for an independent Palestinian state circulated in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupied lands, where the uprising entered its ninth month today. By severing administrative ties with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> has challenged the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to make good on its claims to leadership in the territory that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> seized from his family's control 21 years ago. Without hesitation, <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> told foreign reporters on Sunday that he would `` immediately'' recognize a Palestinian government-in-exile. In <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on Sunday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> indicated the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had not abandoned hope <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> will play an important role in the peace process. `` <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has been and will remain a strategic anchor for peace in the region,'' the assistant secretary of state told reporters. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s -RRB- interest is in peace, and I assume his actions were taken toward that goal.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has relied heavily on <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> as a stand-in for the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> refuses to recognize. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> was scheduled to travel to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> today for talks. He said dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> is possible, but <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> told <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> contacts with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> would only lead to further violence in the occupied lands. Despite the Israeli occupation, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has maintained heavy economic and political ties with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Its dinar is the dominant currency and many Palestinians carry Jordanian passports. In the past two weeks, the king has scrapped a $ 1.3-billion development plan for the territories, laid off or retired 21,200 Jordanian employees there and shut the separate ministry for territorial affairs in his government. He said Sunday the option of reversing these measures `` does not exist.'' `` We are in a new reality of position,'' the king said in a somber tone, adding: `` <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> has no sovereignty over the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> ... both belong to the Palestinian people.'' It is not clear how <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>'s moves may affect the Palestinian uprising in the occupied lands, which has claimed the lives of at least 237 Arabs and four Israelis. But Palestinians and others have suggested <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> is trying to pressure the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to make good on its claims of <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> leadership. If the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> fails, the argument goes, <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> might be ready to step back in. Commenting on measures to be taken regarding citizenship, the king said that `` passports will all remain -LRB- with <LOCATION> Jordanian </LOCATION> citizens of Palestinian origin -RRB- until a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state is created and they can choose their own citizenship.'' <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> also denied media reports that both bridges linking <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> with the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> are to be closed down. `` Bridges are the lifeline,'' he said. `` We have no intension to close them ... nor has it -LRB- the idea -RRB- crossed our minds.'' The king said he hoped to see the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s mission in <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION> `` enjoy the diplomatic status like other missions ... like an embassy.'' He said, however, that `` we have nothing to say to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> delegation'' that is due to visit <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> later in the week, though adding `` we shall keep in touch in the future ... there are no differences between us.'' Palestinian sources in the occupied territories, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Sunday that a draft of a declaration of independence had been forwarded to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> for approval. The Israeli daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday published what it said was a draft declaration of independence signed by 152 Palestinians. The declaration called for a state based on a 1947 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> partition plan, which would encompass much of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s northern <LOCATION> Galilee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> east </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> as well as the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION>. A different draft obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> made no mention of 1947 borders, calling for a state in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> with Arab east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> as its capital. Both draft versions said <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> would be president of a government-in-exile. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> television on Saturday said one draft version of the declaration was seized by Israeli security forces during a search at the east <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> immediately after the institute's leader, <PERSON> Faisal </PERSON> <PERSON> Husseini </PERSON>, was arrested on Aug. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880808-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-88 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WritersStrike     08-08 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Writers Strike,0691</SECOND>
<HEAD>Writers Ratify Contract; Producers Gear Up to Salvage Devastated
TV Season</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
