<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0815EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Guatemala     04-23 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Guatemala,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Leader Says Guatemala Lagging On Peace Accord</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GUATEMALA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An opposition leader who was arrested when she returned from exile said Friday that <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> is lagging behind other Central American nations in seeking peace with rebels. <PERSON> Rigoberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Menchu </PERSON> and another activist were arrested Monday, then released after being held for seven hours. She returned to exile in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Friday. Despite her arrest, Ms. <PERSON> Menchu </PERSON> said she moved freely during her stay here, despite periodic death threats that she called `` normal and of not much importance.'' She said she and three other members of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guatemalan </ORGANIZATION> had discussed with Roman Catholic Archbishop <PERSON> Prespero </PERSON> <PERSON> Penados </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrio </PERSON> whether exiles can safely return to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>. `` We had great success,'' she said at the airport before departing for <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, but gave no details. Travel plans of the the other exiles, <PERSON> Rolando </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Montalvo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Rue </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, were not known. Ms. <PERSON> Menchu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON> <PERSON> Montalvo </PERSON> were arrested and charged with crimes `` against the internal security of the nation,'' but a judge subsequently dismissed the charges for lack of evidence. Speaking with reporters at the airport, Ms. <PERSON> Menchu </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> is far from meeting provisions of a Central American peace plan signed Aug. 7 by the presidents of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. `` I believe that this process still is just beginning to begin -LRB- in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> -RRB- because ... in other countries of the Central American region there have been more concrete things, there have been more realistic things than there have been in our country,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0818EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Sweden-India     04-23 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sweden-India,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radio Says Bofors Bribed Indian Family for Weapons Contract</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Swedish radio said Friday it had obtained documents supporting allegations that a family of Indian financiers received $ 13.7 million in connection with a Swedish arms sale to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. It said the documents included telex messages between the Swedish firm <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> and two <LOCATION> Swiss </LOCATION> banks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in 1986 dealing with accounts under the control of London-based members of the <PERSON> Hinduja </PERSON> family. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Hindu </ORGANIZATION> also reported the allegations. <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinduja </PERSON>, one of four brothers active in the family operations, called the information `` a complete fabrication'' in a statement to the Hindu. <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Per </PERSON> <PERSON> Mossberg </PERSON> was quoted as denying the allegations. The telex messages indicated the account holder was promised a 10 percent commission on a $ 1.4 billion Indian contract for 155mm howitzers made by <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s largest arms manufacturer, the Swedish radio said. It described the <PERSON> Hindujas </PERSON> as being close to Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. The broadcast said money from <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> passed through accounts held by the <PERSON> Hinduja </PERSON> family at the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. It claimed the deposits were transferred to <ORGANIZATION> Sangam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, a company <ORGANIZATION> Swedish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> radio </ORGANIZATION> said was owned by the <PERSON> Hinduja </PERSON> family. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government was facing allegations of corruption when it negotiated the deal with <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> in 1986 and made the condition that no middlemen be used. A Swedish investigation last June found that <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> paid up to $ 40 million to individuals, but the company legally blocked access to further information. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> committee dealing with the case adopted its final report Friday, but the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said investigators had `` drawn a blank.'' The report was not made public. It is to be presented to Parliament next Friday. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> pledged anew that the government would punish any Indian who profited from the deal illegally, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said. He was in <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION> for a two-day <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> meeting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0826EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Gulf-Pool     04-23 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gulf-Pool,0547</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Gulf Strike Was Disciplined Operation, Commander Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Gulf Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABOARD THE USS LYNDE MCCORMICK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Marines who landed on an Iranian oil platform after it was battered by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships found weapons that may have been used against American helicopters, the commander of the attack said. Capt. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who heads <ORGANIZATION> Destroyer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> 9, said the attack on the <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION> oil platform bore out <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claims that the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> facility was being used for military purposes. `` We believe that <ORGANIZATION> Sassan </ORGANIZATION> was a communications and surveillence station,'' said <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. `` We found weapons, ammunition and communications gear.'' <ORGANIZATION> Sassan </ORGANIZATION>, one of two Iranian oil rigs attacked by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces on Monday, was destroyed in an operation that began with a two-ship naval bombardment followed by a helicopter assault. It ended with an assault by <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>. demolition specialists who blew up the remaining facilities. `` We've gotten pretty beat up for our combined operations in the past ... but I thought this was just about perfect,'' <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> said during an interview on the bridge of this San Diego-based warship. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> declined to speculate on how the Iranians used <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION>, other than for surveillance of shipping, but an officer aboard this destroyer said the weapons recovered were types associated with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s armed speedboat operations in the gulf. After the shelling, the Marines who assaulted the platform found 23mm guns, primarily anti-aircraft weapons. Officers said it was most likely one of those weapons fired on two helicopters from the guided missile frigate <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> on March 5. Although the helicopters were not hit, the incident was cited by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials as one of the reasons for Operation Praying Mantis. Another reason was the mining of the frigate <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> on April 14. The 4,500-ton <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON>, a guided-missile destroyer brought into the gulf from its battle group station in the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>, and the 7,818-ton destroyer <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> fired 133 5-inch shells at the platform. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> said that at <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION>, `` the destruction was complete. It was pretty beat up by the naval gunfire, and the demolition charges made one hell of an explosion. `` It was obscured in smoke and flame. It's certainly uninhabitable at this point.'' <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>' unit gave the Iranians at <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION> a five-minute warning that they were about to be attacked. About 29 workers on the platform quickly boarded two tugboats that were tied up under the living quarters platform at <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION> and got out of the way. Some Iranians who had stayed behind fired at the <PERSON> McCormick </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> with one of three Soviet-made 23mm guns placed on the three-tiered, southernmost deck. Although the twin-barrelled weapon has a range of four miles, the rounds fell short of the ships, which were about two miles from the platform. <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON> said one of the tugboats radioed for permission to return to the platform and pick up another group of about 38 still aboard. The request was granted and a 45-minute evacuation took place while the ships held their fire. Radio traffic indicated only two Iranian casualties at <LOCATION> Sassan </LOCATION>, one dead and one wounded, but <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officers said there may have been more.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0801EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Meese-Reagan Bjt   04-23 0733</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Meese-Reagan, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says Meese Should Stay In Office, Helps Fill Key Vacancy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is moving to fill one <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> slot and Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> is appointing temporary replacements for up to a dozen others in an attempt to end the turmoil caused by the March 29 protest resignations of two key <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> aides. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Friday moved quickly to ease <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s personnel problems by nominating <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> to fill the associate attorney general's slot, the department's empty No. 3 post. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should stay in office and the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is running `` just fine,'' although two top <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> aides who quit told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Wednesday a `` deep malaise'' had `` infected'' the department and one of them said <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should be indicted. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> would replace <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Trott </PERSON>, who left the department a week ago to become a federal judge. His was not one of the protest resignations, but the vacancy has been affected by the concern with <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s leadership. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, an assistant <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> secretary, may come in to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on an acting basis late next week until he can be confirmed by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The Nos. 2 and 3 offices at the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> are virtually vacant from the top down, and the department plans to shore them up by naming perhaps nearly a dozen people in all, department spokesman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Korten </PERSON> said. The posts probably will be filled on Monday. <PERSON> Korten </PERSON> added, `` <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> absolutely has no intention of stepping down.'' An independent counsel has been examining <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s assistance to scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and a proposed $ 1 billion Iraqi oil pipeline project at the behest of longtime friend <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>. Also under investigation are <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s meetings with regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> telephone company executives at a time when he owned $ 14,000 in <ORGANIZATION> Baby </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> stock and <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>'s role in securing a $ 40,000-a-year job for <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s wife. Since the protest resignations of Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and Assistant Attorney General <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>, <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> has twice unsuccessfully tried to fill <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' post. <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> lawyer <PERSON> Arlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> rejected <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s overtures, and at least five current or former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys who have been sounded out about <PERSON> Weld </PERSON>'s job have said they were n't interested. <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON> withdrew from consideration for <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>' post Wednesday after adverse publicity about an alleged affair with his law firm's bookkeeper and other matters <PERSON> Weld </PERSON> was `` unequivocal'' at the White House meeting in telling the president that if it were up to him, he would seek an indictment of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, said an administration source who spoke on condition of anonymity. The former criminal division chief then proceeded to lay out `` an oral indictment'' of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> to the president, said the source, focusing on <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s relationship with <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wallach </PERSON> is under indictment in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> scandal. The administration source said <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> told the president that <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> had violated the standards of ethical conduct for executive branch employees spelled out in a 1965 executive order. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, according to the source, said that in other similar instances of possible impropriety, <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> lawyers would be placed on administrative leave, disciplined or dismissed. `` The president was very attentive,'' said the source, adding that `` it was clear he was hearing for the first time that not everything is well in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>.'' The ethical standards say employees should avoid any action which could create the appearance of using public office for private gain, giving preferential treatment to any organization or person or making a government decision outside official channels. Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> and White House counsel A.B. <PERSON> Culvahouse </PERSON> also attended the meeting. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> was summoned to a 40-minute meeting with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> immediately afterward. According to <PERSON> Korten </PERSON>, the president told <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> at the end of their meeting that he was `` satisfied and supportive'' of the attorney general. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> left his post officially on Friday, 3 -LCB- weeks after resigning to protest <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s continued tenure as attorney general. Independent counsel <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>, who has been conducting a criminal investigation of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> since last May 11, is expected to issue a report of <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s activites if he does n't seek an indictment of the attorney general. It is likely the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsibility </ORGANIZATION> will then examine ethical questions raised as a result of <PERSON> McKay </PERSON>'s probe and will recommend to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> whether <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> should be disciplined or fired.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0010EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     04-23 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0025</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Rise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 27,058.37 points, up 221.25 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0801EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagans-Health Bjt   04-23 0506</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagans-Health, Bjt,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Test Shows No Recurrence Of Breast Cancer For First Lady</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mammogram of <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s right breast shows no sign of cancer, the White House says. While the first lady went to <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> to have her six-month checkup following removal of her cancerous left breast, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had dental X-rays done there. The first couple flew by helicopter Friday to the suburban <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> military facility from the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, remained there for less than a half-hour, then went to Camp David for the weekend. `` The president and first lady completed their routine radiological procedures,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> physician Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutton </PERSON> said. `` The president had a series of routine dental X-rays in the dental clinic, while Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had her first post-operative mammogram,'' he said. `` The mammogram was negative. No immediate treatment of any kind is required as a result of today's procedures on the president and first lady.'' The White House had said earlier that the examinations were not prompted by any current physicial problems of either of the Reagans. The Reagans did not answer reporters' questions when they left the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or on arrival or departure from the hospital. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, however, made an `` A-OK'' thumb-and-forefinger sign, indicating things went well. The last time the 77-year-old president visited the hospital was in January, when he underwent his semi-annual checkup for colon cancer. He has had regular checkups every January and June since he underwent surgery for an intestinal malignancy in July 1985. <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s press secretary, said, `` It's wise and routine to check the other breast'' after surgery of the kind the first lady had six months ago. She said the first lady has had periodic examinations since her operation Oct. 17, 1987, but this was her first X-ray of the right breast. Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said the couple wanted to have the results of Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s exam promptly `` so they could send her off for a comfortable, worry-free weekend.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 66, had her breast removed after doctors discovered a quarter-inch cancerous lesion. She chose to undergo a modified radical mastectomy, which involves the removal of the entire breast and some lymph nodes. Mrs. <PERSON> Crispen </PERSON> said that not only was it time for the first lady's six-month checkup, but the president could use the time `` to get his dental X-rays taken, rather than usually doing it at the White House. White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> usually has a cleaning and checkup every three months at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, but that the president planned to have a `` panoramic'' X-ray done this time in order to get a full-view picture of his mouth. The White House has X-ray machines that take pictures of parts of the mouth, but does not have the larger machine that pans the entire mouth area, he said. Panoramic radiographs, or X-rays that provide an overall view of the teeth and jaws, are used to diagnose problems ranging from cavities to tumors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0800EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra Bjt   04-23 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Top Administration Officials Called To Testify Against North</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A host of current and former top government officials are listed as prosecution witnesses for the Iran-Contra conspiracy trial of Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and three co-defendants. Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and two top deputies and Attorney <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and two of his top aides are among the list of 105 witnesses submitted in a court filing Friday by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>. The list includes national security officials knowledgeable about the covert sale of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, private operatives who ran the secret supply network that armed the Nicaraguan rebels, <PERSON> Contra </PERSON> leaders and wealthy donors who contributed to their cause. No date has been set for the trial of North, former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> and two arms dealers: retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>. They are accused of conspiring to divert profits illegally from the U.S.-Iran arms sales to help the Contras during a ban on direct American military aid to the rebels. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> filed the witness list in advance of Monday's hearing called by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> to determine if prosecutors impermissibly relied on evidence derived from the compelled congressional testimony of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>. Most of the witnesses were known to <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> before <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON> received congressional immunity on April 20, 1987. The list includes deputy <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, former White House chief of staff <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, former national security adviser <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON> and assistant attorneys general <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> would be expected to testify about the November 1986 investigation they conducted that uncovered the diversion of arms-sale profits. The defense, meanwhile, indicated that it will call <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> as a witness during the hearing on the immunity question. The defense wants to show that statements he made to the grand jury were influenced by the defendants' compelled congressional testimony, according to court papers. Late Friday, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> issued an order blocking a defense attempt to subpoena nine members of <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s staff to testify at the hearing. Seven of the prospective trial witnesses are referred to only by number `` because of national security concerns,'' <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said. Their identities were given privately to the court and the defense. Other top officials on the list include Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> legal adviser <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Sofaer </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> general counsel <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sporkin </PERSON>, now a federal judge here. <PERSON> McFarlane </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty to misdemeanor charges of withholding information from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> about covert aid to the Contras, is one of several former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> officials on the list, which includes <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s former secretary <PERSON> Fawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. Contra leaders <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> and <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> Robelo </PERSON> are listed along with retired <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Maj. Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Singlaub </PERSON>, who helped raise private money for the anti-Sandinista cause. Donors <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Garwood </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Boyle </PERSON>, and <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Claggett </PERSON>, Jr. are listed along with <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON>, who owned land in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> where an airstrip was built for resupply operations. Also on the list were two conservative fund-raisers, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Spitz </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Channell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>. <PERSON> Channell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> pleaded guilty last year to conspiring illegally to use a tax-exempt foundation to help raise Contra money. The defense indicated it also wanted to call <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> deGraffenreid </PERSON> as witnesses at next week's hearing. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s office moved to disqualify the defense from calling any witnesses on the ground that the lawyers did not meet Thursday's deadline for notifying the prosecution of the grand jury witness they intended to produce at the hearing The prosecutor also argued that deGraffenreid and <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> were n't grand jury witnesses and therefore could n't testify at next week's The defense apparently wants to put <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> on the witness stand to show that testimony he gave to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, without immunity, was based on information he received from <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>, who gave closed-door testimony to the congressional committees before the public hearings began last spring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0800EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Anti-AcneDrug Bjt   04-23 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Anti-Acne Drug, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accutane Maker Will Devise New Safeguards On Use</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The maker of a popular anti-acne medication that can cause birth defects says it will try once again to devise a way to keep women from taking the prescription drug if they are pregnant or likely to become pregnant. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Friday it has convened an advisory panel next Tuesday to consider reports that more pregnant women than previously believed are taking the drug Accutane despite strict warnings that it is likely to cause birth defects. Short of an outright ban, the agency has no way to guarantee the drug will not be used by women who are pregnant or become pregnant while taking it. And there was no indication whether the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> was actively considering ordering it off the market. The New Jersey-based maker _ <ORGANIZATION> Roche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> _ issued a statement late Friday saying it will propose a new series of safeguards at the Tuesday meeting. It said it will propose tighter restrictions on use of the drug in women of childbearing potential and offer to provide `` innovative blister-packaging to ensure that female patients receive the pregnancy warning with every prescription.'' The statement did not detail what type of restrictions the company will propose for the drug in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The drug is marketed in 40 countries worldwide. The warnings accompanying the drug since its introduction in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1982 are explicit: Do n't take the drug if you are pregnant and do n't get pregnant while you are taking it. <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> McLearn </PERSON> said Friday the agency's dermatologic drugs advisory committee has been asked to review use of Accutrane because `` we're concerned that a drug is not being used as the labeling indicates.'' `` The drug has all sorts of warnings that people who are pregnant should not be using it and that the drug is only for a very severe form of acne,'' said <PERSON> McLearn </PERSON>. `` It's clear that it's being used for a larger group than that. Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, a dermatologist from <ORGANIZATION> Beth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and a member of the advisory panel, emphasized that concern about the drug does not involve any new scientific discoveries, but rather new indications that some people are ignoring long-standing warnings of those effects. He said in a telephone interview Friday that the newly raised concern flows from a study of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Medicaid figures that suggests the frequency of people getting pregnant while on Accutane may be `` much higher than anybody thought it was.'' However, <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said he has substantial questions about the accuracy of the projected pregnancy rate, since it was based on a `` very specialized population, namely people who are already on Aid to Families With Dependent Children because of prior unintended pregnancies.'' The question, he said, is not whether there is a problem, but how great the problem is for the estimated 1 million people _ a majority of them men _ who benefit from the drug. The <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> statistical projection says Accutane may have caused more than 1,000 babies to be born with birth defects in the past six years. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has received reports of 62 birth defects associated with the drug from the time it came on the market in 1982, but scientists believe that may understate the problem simply because many side effects from any drug often are unrecognized and under-reported. Accutane is specifically intended for treatment of severe cystic acne, a type that often causes severe disfiguring and deep pitting scars and sometimes can be treated only with Accutane. Since the drug was approved in 1982, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Roche </LOCATION> _ a division of <ORGANIZATION> Hoffmann-La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> _ have strengthened the warning label, made repeated mailings of special letters to doctors and pharmacists emphasizing the risks and discussed the risks twice in the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Drug Bulletin that is sent to more than 1 million health professionals. They also have distributed red warning stickers to pharmacists to be placed on each prescription bottle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ShroudofTurin Bjt   04-23 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shroud of Turin, Bjt,0495</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sample Taken For Dating of Shroud Venerated As Christ's Burial
Cloth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tiny sample has been cut from the Shroud of <LOCATION> Turin </LOCATION> for radiocarbon-dating that may determine whether the cloth existed at the time of <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s death on the cross, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> announced. The linen, which appears to bear the image of a crucified man, is venerated by some as <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s burial cloth. The operation, eagerly awaited by scientists, was carried out Thursday in <LOCATION> Turin </LOCATION> under the supervision of Cardinal <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballestrero </PERSON>, the Roman Catholic archbishop of <LOCATION> Turin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, with the collaboration of Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tite </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> said. The British Museum has agreed to guarantee the scientific validity of the carbon-dating, which is to be done independently on nuclear atom-counters at <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zurich </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>, which owns the shroud, had resisted carbon-dating on grounds it would damage the cloth, which is 14 feet, 3 inches long and 3 feet, 7 inches wide. But the development in the 1970s of an atom-counter known as an accelerator mass spectrometer made it possible to date objects with much smaller samples. The shroud, whose history is well-documented from the mid-14th century, has been kept in the Turin Cathedral since 1578. A piece of cloth measuring just 1 centimeter by 7 centimeters -LRB- four-tenths of an inch by 2.8 inches -RRB- was cut from the shroud, then cut further into three samples for the laboratories, Friday's <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> announcement said The size of the individual samples was not given, but Tite has previously said each laboratory would receive a 0.3-square-inch sample of the shroud. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> said the area of cutting was chosen to guarantee that the sample belongs to the principal body of the shroud and that the cut would cause `` the least damage possible to the cloth.'' It said the entire operation was videotaped and photographed. Each laboratory will also receive two dummy cloth samples, one carbon-dated and the other dated historically but not scientifically to see if they get consistent results for all three samples. The labs are not being told which sample is from the shroud, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> said. Tite has said the triple carbon-dating should reveal the shroud's age within a 200-year range. The results are expected to be announced by summer. The tests will not prove that the image on the cloth is <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>'s, but would indicate whether the shroud existed when <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> was crucified. The shroud bears a faint yellowish image of both the front and back of a man's body. Stains, scientifically identified as blood, can be seen around the wrists. Believers contend the image was left by a supernatural burst of energy accompanying Christ's resurrection, while skeptics claim it was painted during the Middle Ages.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-KennedyFiles     04-23 0519</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kennedy Files,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>Destroyed Files Were Duplicates, Police Said</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 2,500 photographs from the <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> assassination file were destroyed because they were unneeded duplicates that took up filing space, a police spokesman says. Commander <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Booth </PERSON>, responding to questions about the destruction disclosed earlier this week, said Friday the explanation came from a retired police officer who was very involved in the case. He declined to give the officer's name, saying, `` He has been retired for some time and is disinclined to get involved.'' But he said the man `` has an independent recollection'' of events relating to the pictures. In the aftermath of <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s assassination at the Ambassador Hotel on June 5, 1968, he said, police took photographs of every possible angle of the crime scene. `` What happened is there were many hundreds of photographs taken, thousands of photographs,'' <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> said. `` And many copies of each photograph were copied for us and for each agency involved.'' `` What were destroyed were superfluous duplicates that amounted to a lot of redundancy,'' he said. `` There was no need to keep them. Filing space was a consideration.'' The police department's voluminous file on the <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> assassination was released for the first time Tuesday, and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Archivist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> noted a certificate showing that 2,410 photographs were burned by police two months after <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>'s death Police earlier had conceded they destroyed ceiling panels and part of a door jamb from the kitchen of the Ambassador that became central to investigation of whether a second gun might have been fired at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> senator. <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sirhan </PERSON>, a Jordanian immigrant, was convicted of murdering <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and is serving a life term at <LOCATION> Soledad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION>. He has said he was the lone assassin but insists he has no memory of the actual shooting. He blames alcohol for his amnesia. In another development, the woman who told police in 1968 that she saw a girl in a polka-dot dress run from the assassination scene declared she had been badgered into recanting her original story. The newly released police files showed that <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Serrano </PERSON> withdrew her statement two weeks after the killing, saying, `` The whole thing was a lie.'' But the woman, now <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Serrano-Sewell </PERSON>, told a radio reporter Thursday that she was a victim of police harassment. She had reported seeing a girl in a polka dot dress running from the Ambassador Hotel shouting, `` We shot him. We shot him.'' When she asked who was shot, she said the woman replied, `` Senator <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>.'' But her retraction of the story led police to cancel a search for such a girl, the files showed. In an interview with <ORGANIZATION> KUOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Serrano-Sewell </PERSON> said, `` There was a lot of badgering that was going on. I was just 20 years old, and I became unglued. ... I said what they wanted me to say.'' Asked on Friday about the woman's statements, <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> said, `` Our conclusion was she did not tell the truth when she gave all that information. ... The files have to speak for themselves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0759EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-23 0938</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0977</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Names in the News</BYLINE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Deaf actress <PERSON> Marlee </PERSON> <PERSON> Matlin </PERSON> says she's unhappy with the way The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> treated her decision to speak without using sign language on the Academy Awards program. The Times' article on April 13 said some people viewed her appearance earlier this month as `` a blow not only to deaf people but also to the goal of ` total communication.''' `` I do not sign and speak simultaneously, and when I chose to sign alone -LRB- with an off-camera voice -RRB- or to speak alone, as I did on the Oscar ceremony telecast, I could have potentially ignored two major segments of the deaf community _ those who use speech and do not sign and those who sign and do not use speech,'' she wrote in a letter to the newspaper published Friday. `` Fortunately, the telecast was closed captioned ... and everyone, regardless of communication preference, had access. So what's the big fuss?'' The star of `` Children of a Lesser God'' closed her letter with a complimentary P.S.: `` But thank you for the nice picture.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, the youngest son of Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., underwent surgery to have a non-cancerous tumor removed from the top of his spine and was reported in `` very satisfactory'' condition <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 20, was admitted Monday to <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> after complaining of headaches and back pains. The operation Thursday was without complication and <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a sophomore at <ORGANIZATION> Providence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, was expected to make a complete recovery, said <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> will be a <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> delegate to the Democratic National Convention in July. Like his father, he is backing Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. He is also working on his father's re-election campaign.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ORANGEBURG, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A decision to award an honorary degree to Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> has upset some faculty members and students at predominantly black <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's not just his old past, it's his recent past. Every single civil rights bill since 1957 he has opposed. Right up to two weeks ago, when he voted against the recent civil rights bill,'' said history Professor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hine </PERSON>. The college's board of trustees decided in February to give the honorary doctorate of laws degree to the conservative <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> during graduation May 8, school President <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. Four petitions are circulating among the faculty calling for the degree not to be awarded, <PERSON> Hine </PERSON> said, and students are talking about boycotting graduation ceremonies. <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> will accept the award but will be out of the country on a classified trip with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, press secretary <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> says he may have overindulged at his 80th birthday party, but normally he's more restrained. `` I'm happy to be alive. I've had three pieces of cake but otherwise I'm looking after my health,'' <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, the star of the television shows `` Green Acres'' and `` Switch,'' was awakened by his granddaughter, <PERSON> Mia </PERSON>, who serenaded him with `` Happy Birthday, Poppy,'' said publicist <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Landau </PERSON>. The actor's daughter, <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, was with him Friday but his son, actor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, was in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> filming the feature movie `` Fistfighter.'' He called with his greetings Wednesday night. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> appeared in several episodes of `` Falcon Crest'' this season. His son also had a recurring role on the series.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> has offered a $ 10,000 reward for information leading to an arrest in the shooting of Grammy Award-winning jazz guitarist <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON>. <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> was shot in the neck April 6 outside his home in the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>. He is recuperating at an undisclosed location and is expected to recover fully from his injuries. The council motion passed unanimously Friday. Friends and associates of the musician also are collecting money for a reward. Police have been baffled by the attack, for which they have found no motive. They say it may have been an aborted robbery attempt.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The New Orleans Jazz and <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION> opened with <PERSON> Taj </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahal </PERSON> and other entertainers despite cloudy skies, blustery winds and a threat of rain. More than 600,000 people are expected for the six-day event featuring the <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Brubeck </PERSON> <PERSON> Quartet </PERSON>, bluesman B.B. King, soul singer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, clarintetist <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Fountain </PERSON> and Cajun musician <PERSON> Zachary </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON>. The biggest names on the opening-day schedule Friday were <PERSON> Taj </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahal </PERSON>, the New Yorker who sings and plays the happy side of the blues, and the Kent Jordan Quartet. Some, like B.B. King, were doing double duty, with a daytime gig at the Fair Grounds and a nighttime concert another time during the week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> XVI </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvia </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> as part of a nationwide tour to celebrate <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>'s ties to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, took in some Texas-style entertainment _ barbeque, broncos and bullriding. The queen arrived at the <ORGANIZATION> Mesquite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rodeo </ORGANIZATION> on Friday in a crimson western-style fringe dress, a giant white hat, and gold lizard skin boots. The king opted for a casual look of a checkered sports jacket and tassled loafers and hat. He also woore an engraved belt buckle the size of a fist. Before the rodeo, they ate barbecue under a yellow-striped tent. `` We had a glimpse of -LRB- rodeo -RRB- in <LOCATION> Calgary </LOCATION> the other day. It will be fun to see the difference between their revue and this one,'' the king said. A crowd of about 4,000 people cheered as the flag of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> was introduced and again when the queen and king were presented.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0806EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NewsmenDetained     04-23 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newsmen Detained,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Detained For Allegedly Entering Secure Area</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GROTON, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A reporter and a photographer from a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> newspaper were detained for about two hours Friday after the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said their rented boat entered a restricted area near a submarine shipyard. The reporter denied that the small boat had entered the restricted waters, which extend 100 feet into the <LOCATION> Thames </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> from the <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION>, where submarines including nuclear-powered Tridents are built. The boat, rented by photographer <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Badz </PERSON> and reporter <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Romaner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Jacksonville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-Union </ORGANIZATION>, was stopped and boarded after it was spotted within the restricted area, said <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON>. Also aboard the 18-to-20-foot vessel was <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Zelvin </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Groton </LOCATION> businessman who rents boats, <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON> said. `` We did n't know what we had. We did n't know if we had terrorists, criminals or what,'' said <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON> said officials were concerned because the Trident submarine <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> was being prepared for a launch Saturday. The three men denied being in the restricted zone, but were taken to <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> headquarters while their stories and identities were checked, <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON> said. The procedure took about two hours, and in the end no charges were filed, he said. `` We were n't anywhere near 100 feet, we were n't even within 200 feet,'' <PERSON> Romaner </PERSON> said. `` You ca n't even get a Trident into the camera lens from that close.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> intelligence officer was called in and confiscated the photographer's film. <PERSON> Rutkovsky </PERSON> said if no sensitive portions of the shipyard were found on the film it would be returned to the newspaper. The newsmen objected to the confiscation and the newspaper's executive editor, <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartmann </PERSON>, tried to stop the confiscation in a telephone call to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Romaner </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-L'AmbianceAnniversary Bjt   04-23 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-L'Ambiance Anniversary, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Weighing Safety Changes Year After Building Collapse
Killed 28</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The concrete and steel rubble from <LOCATION> L'Ambiance </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaza </LOCATION> has long been cleared away, but the impact of the decade's most devastating construction accident still is being felt in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Lawmakers have been pushing for changes in construction-safety laws since the partially built <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, apartment complex collapsed one year ago today, leaving 28 workers dead. Proposals have ranged from tinkering with the accident reporting requirements and stiffening criminal penalties in fatal construction accidents to creating a separate construction agency outside the often-criticized <ORGANIZATION> Occupational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. `` Obviously the price is too high in all the lives lost to ever think of it as having a silver lining,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn. `` But given that all of that ca n't be changed, I do think it can be used ... to remind people in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and remind people in <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION>'' of problems in the construction industry Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., who was a state representative when <PERSON> L'Ambiance </PERSON> collapsed, has devoted much of his time to the accident since coming to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to replace the late Rep. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> But the freshman congressman is frustrated at the slow-moving gears of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` Like most victims of crimes, you have the victims of L'Ambiance who are seeing a fairly unresponsive government, or at least a government that has responded slowly,'' <PERSON> Shays </PERSON> said in an interview this week. <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> said he is drafting legislation to increase criminal penalties for contractors convicted in fatal construction accidents. The current maximum penalty is six months in prison and a $ 10,000 fine for willful violation of <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> standards. At the request of lawmakers, <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> is reviewing whether to change its reporting standards. Under current regulations, only accidents with a death or at least five injuries have to be reported. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> critics point to an accident in <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, shortly before the L'Ambiance collapse that involved the same contractor and the same type of problem that investigators say triggered the <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> accident. But the <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> accident went unreported because only one worker was injured. <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, who labeled the current reporting requirements `` absurd,'' believes knowledge of the <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION> accident could have prevented L'Ambiance. <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> said the reporting requirement is still under review. The agency also is reviewing its regulations on the lift-slab construction method used by <PERSON> L'Ambiance </PERSON> builders that was implicated in the collapse. Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., is pushing a measure that would put the L'Ambiance fines in a special trust fund for the victims' families <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> fears the heavy fines will drive the contractors into bankruptcy, making them unable to pay damages that could be awarded in pending civil suits. Some lawmakers are embracing the idea of making a separate construction division within <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION>, while the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> wants to create a separate construction agency. Congressional supporters said, however, that they do not expect action this year. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapping </PERSON>, director of safety and health for the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Building </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said he does not hold out hope for significant changes because of L'Ambiance. `` In'78 we had the <LOCATION> Willow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> -LRB- cooling tower -RRB- accident -LRB- in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> -RRB- and we had 51 people killed there and nothing came out of that,'' Lapping said. Such criticism of <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> was reignited by the <LOCATION> Bridgeport </LOCATION> collapse, with charges that the agency has too few inspectors and relies too heavily on industry self-regulation. But <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> officials defend their policing policies. `` If <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, in its vision when it imagined what <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> would be like, wanted an inspector on every job site 24 hours a day, it would have said so,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON>. `` It made employers accountable for safety and health, knowing full well the government would n't have inspectors at every site in the country.'' <PERSON> Mikelson </PERSON> also said <ORGANIZATION> OSHA </ORGANIZATION> has made changes in recent years, including imposing heavier fines such as those at L'Ambiance and severely penalizing project contractors when they fail to properly oversee subcontractors. `` The bottom line is when employers show a strong commitment to safety and health, workers sustain far fewer injures,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     04-23 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0024</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 19; 32; 34; 36; 40.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     04-23 0081</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0087</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked this week:
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 19; 32; 34; 36; 40.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0-0-4-8.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 05; 06; 11; 15; 20.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 08; 19; 24; 29; 32; 41. Bonus: 9-7-0-6-3.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 48 Game: 12; 27; 42; 43; 44; 46. Supplementary 04.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 2-6-8-5.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 7-6-0; 6-4-4-7; 1-2-4-1-4; 0-6-9-3-6-1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0840EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--TaillightLanding     04-23 0168</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Taillight Landing,0171</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pilot Lands On Dark Road With Guidance From Car's Taillights</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALLEGAN, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> `` Butch'' <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> could n't make much of a living as a race driver by following other cars. But he may owe his life to the car whose taillights he followed before landing his disabled airplane. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> Coopersville </LOCATION>, safely landed his six-passenger Aerostar 600 about 10 p.m. Thursday on the northbound lane of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> 40 about two miles north of here. `` At night, it's very hard to pick out roads, if not impossible,'' he said. `` Basically I chased the taillights. Whoever he is he saved my life and does n't know it.'' The driver of the car had not been identified by late Friday, said Deputy <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Allegan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, the defending <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Speed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> stock car racing champion, said he was en route from <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> when the plane's right engine blew a gasket and he had to make an emergency landing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0320EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PoliticalRdp Bjt   04-23 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Political Rdp, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis, Jackson Hold Love Feast; Bush Goes Fishing</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Prenoon top possible.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EVANS WITT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> are battling gently for the Democratic presidential nomination, trading good-natured jibes about a running mate and saving their potshots for Republican Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Going into the final weekend before <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>'s primary Tuesday, the two surviving Democratic hopefuls found little to disagree about in their first head-to-head debate Friday night in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. `` Any combination on this stage against <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ... will beat the Republicans in November,'' said civil rights leader <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` The two remaining _ and I guess that makes us the leading _ candidates for the Democratic nomination are the son of immigrants from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and a black man who grew up poor in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor told the hour-long debate in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. `` I think that says everything there is to say about his country.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, his nomination victory well in hand, spent Friday fishing in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Both Democrats headed back out across <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> today, looking for votes in the Tuesday balloting with 178 delegates at stake. A second debate was scheduled tonight in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. The good humor of the debate sponsored by the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> Democratic party stood in sharp contrast to the harsh racial and religious overtones of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> primary only a week ago. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> insisted it is a close race for the Democratic nomination, but <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is firmly in the front-runner's spot with a widening lead in the national delegate battle and a substantial edge in the polls for the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> primary. Who will fill the No. 2 spot on the Democratic ticket occupied much of the debate. It has also dominated the Democratic campaign since <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> won his big <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> victory to become the odds-on favorite to win the presidential nomination at the party convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in July. `` It's a bit premature to be giving out coronation roses for the governor and taps for me,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said when asked if he would accept the No. 2 spot. `` We're now moving into the last lap of a significant race, and I'm a long-distance runner. I look forward to it.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who has denied even thinking about a running mate, then turned to <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and asked softly: `` Are you interested?'' After the audience's laughter subsided, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> smiled and replied, `` You got it, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had a curt response to a question of whether he believed polls showing <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> as the vice presidential nominee would cost Democrats the White House in the fall elections: `` No.'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> drew his share of laughter as well, in response to a question about how the Democrats could win the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> in the general election. `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on my ticket will win the South,'' the preacher-turned-politician said. The only harsh words of the day were directed at Republicans. `` First of all, the drug program of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is to have the First Lady to say ` Just say no,' the president to just cut the budget, and Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to just say and do nothing,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said during the debate. Earlier, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> fails to understand what it takes to `` build an economic future and to create good jobs.'' `` I do n't see how we are going to bring good jobs and good wages back to the industrial <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> unless we work together,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION>. `` If the vice president does n't understand that, then he should n't be running for president.'' Both men told reporters after the debate that keeping the focus on winning in the fall was the correct course. The only differences between the two in the debate were not major ones. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> praised plant-closing legislation, saying he had used a state law like the one now before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to save thousands of jobs in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said reinvesting in the nation is more important. He also pressed <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> seriously on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, suggesting that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s strong stand against terrorism should be applied to that nation and its `` state-sponsored terrorism.'' `` I would be very tough on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor replied.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0321EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ArmsTreaty     04-23 0425</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arms Treaty,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Won't Promise INF Approval Before Moscow Summit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders say they wo n't be pushed into approving the U.S.-Soviet arms control treaty to meet a White House deadline of ratifying the historic pact before President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s trip to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in late May The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> still needs to nail down answers to questions about whether the Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces treaty bans futuristic weapons as well as existing missiles, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, said Assurances by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and a top Soviet official that both superpowers agree the treaty does ban future types of weapons are n't enough, said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> `` We need to make sure, be absolutely clear,'' said <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, speaking of the issue of how the pact affects weapons such as lasers or particle beam weapons. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> told his colleagues: `` I did not set the date of the summit, I had nothing to do with it. This <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is no president's rubber stamp and this senator is no president's man. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had said Thursday that he hopes the pact is approved in time for him to take a ratification notice to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for his May 29-June 2 meeting with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, asked whether failure to ratify the pact would affect the summit, said, `` I think it would be very upsetting and it would put a strain on the summit.'' When the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> finally does vote, ratification is likely, said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>. Ratification requires 67 votes, and <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> leaders have said they believe 90 of the 100 senators will support the pact. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> said the futuristic weapons issues could be settled by an amendment to the pact. The administration has urged ratification without any amendments and will likely portray <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>'s proposal as `` a killer amendment,'' he said. But `` I do n't see this as a killer amendment.'' A so-called killer amendment is one attached to a treaty that could make it unacceptable to the parties that negotiated the agreement, and thus `` kill'' the treaty. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said the questions should be answered, but noted, `` there is an advantage to having this ratified'' before the summit begins Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, also said he supports speedy ratification so that `` we can keep this momentum toward arms control.'' The treaty would ban nuclear missiles with a range of 300 to 3,400 miles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-23 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Department Sets Up Task Force To Monitor Drought</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> secretly created a special drought task force seven weeks ago to keep track of dry weather that threatened much of the West. Officials announced Friday that the task force was set up by <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> on March 1 and had been meeting weekly in his office. No mention of the nature of the meeting was evident in his published daily schedules or in those of senior aides. But the dry weather has since prompted many reports of drought around the country since then, and there have been repeated references to it in the news media in those affected areas, said <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> director of information. So it was decided to go public about <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s task force. <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> defended the secrecy, saying: `` It was more of a review of the situation than anything else. If we had put out some big announcement, we might have looked like we were trying to pat ourselves on the back.'' <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> appointed Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> as chairman of the panel. Others include heads of <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agencies mostly closely associated with farm programs, credit and other resources that might be needed. In his statement announcing the task force, <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> said that <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> is stepping up contact with state agriculture departments in the affected areas so those can `` provide us with a constant flow of information regarding the moisture situation and preparations'' for relief. The <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> and other western states, which suffered through drought last year, appear to be the prime regions for another drought spell in 1988, with several states reporting February and March being the driest on record, he said. Conditions likely to cause problems for agricultural producers were said to prevail in parts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. Some other states are having extremely dry weather in smaller areas, raising concerns that forest fires could be severe this year. <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> said that several of the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency administrators report that their state and county offices in the dry areas have been received numerous inquiries about various federal drought assistance programs. In a related report on the outlook for western water supplies, Wilson Scaling, chief of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, said that in March, for the second month in a row, precipitation was well below normal in the West. He said parts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> reported the driest February and March combination on record. But some areas improved last month, including the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>, the western Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, the northern Cascade range, the Colorado-Wyoming border, and most parts of <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. `` <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> reported its first month of above-average precipitation in over a year,'' Scaling said. `` We are encouraged by that eading.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A quarterly report by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> shows cattle feedlot inventories in the nation's 13 leading beef states totaled 9.37 million head as of April 1, up 6 percent from a year ago and 5 percent above two years ago. Only <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> showed decreases from April 1, 1987, while cattle numbers in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> were virtually unchanged. Increases were reported for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Marketings of fed cattle for slaughter during January, February and March totaled 5.81 million head, a 1 percent increase from the same period of 1987 and also 1 percent more than in 1986, the report said Friday. The placement of new cattle and calves on feed during the first quarter of the year totaled 5.8 million head, up 2 percent from last year and 10 percent more than two years ago. Cattle feeders indicated they expect to market 5.93 million head during April, May and June, up 6 percent from second-quarter levels of last year and 2 percent more than two years ago. State feedlot cattle inventories are listed here for the 13 states, which account for about 85 percent of the nation's beef. The first number is the number of cattle, in thousands, as of April 1, and the second number is the percentage of a year earlier.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> 291 98 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 355 113 <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> 815 107 <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> 182 116 <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> 370 86 <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> 680 101 Kansas 1,490 110 <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> 320 100 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 2,000 108 <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> 305 122 <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> 290 104 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 2,095 106 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 172 125
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 _ greater
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OrganizedCrime     04-23 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Organized Crime,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigator Says Mob Organized Into `Cells' Like Terrorist Groups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An investigator who almost became the first <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent inducted into an organized crime family says he was pulled out of the mob by his <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> superiors after being ordered to kill a gangster from a rival group. `` The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> felt _ and so did I _ that this was a good time for getting out, because everybody was being killed,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON> told senators, explaining that he was given the hit assignment during a mob civil war. <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON> also told members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Permanent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> on Investigations there's a `` surprising similarity'' between the structure of organized crime families and terrorist groups. He said `` a strict need-to-know policy is enforced,'' and fellow mobsters often avoid telling each other their last names. <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON>, who spent six years working undercover with the mob, said he was scheduled to become a `` made'' member of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Bonanno </PERSON> family in December 1981 The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> abruptly ended his operation a half-year after two <PERSON> Bonanno </PERSON> factions began a civil war, he said. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> said that to this day, no agent has ever become a formal `` made'' member of the mob rather than an associate. <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON> testified from behind a screen because he has been relocated and changed his appearance. But he has told his story before, in court testimony and in a book on his six years posing as a small-time but successful jewel thief and burglar, <PERSON> Donnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brasco </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON>'s testimony in trials resulted in more than 200 indictments and more than 100 convictions of organized crime members. Explaining the workings of mob families, <PERSON> Pistone </PERSON> said: `` There is a surprising similarity which marks the inner-workings of the Mafia and contemporary terrorist organizations. `` The families are broken down into small, separate cells, commonly called crews. `` In all likelihood, a member of one crew may not even know who are the members of another crew in his own family.'' He said `` gambling is probably the most important source of income'' for traditional organized crime families. Gambling supports other mob activities, such as drug buys, payoffs, lawyer's fees, and investments into legitimate businesses, he said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Collapse     04-23 0063</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Collapse,0062</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sixteen Killed When Cinema Collapses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rural movie theater built by a local farmer collapsed with more than 100 people inside, killing 16 people and injuring 18, the official <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> said today. The daily said the accident occurred April 16 in <LOCATION> Lingbao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Henan </LOCATION> province, and that a local farmer had built the theater in February.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperconductorCenters     04-23 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superconductor Centers,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Argonne, Los Alamos, Oak Ridge Named Superconductivity Pilot
Centers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Industries trying to capitalize on superconducting technology will get help from three federal research facilities under a program announced by the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Argonne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alamos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and Oak Ridge National Laboratory in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> were designated on Friday as special pilot centers, Energy Secretary <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said. The centers, he said, will collaborate with industry on applications of the technology gleaned from basic energy research. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> last year outlined a program last year under which government and industry will work together to find commercial uses for high-temperature superconductors, which can conduct electricity without energy loss. `` Superconductors ... have great potential in such areas as electrical generation, storage and transmission, computers, communications, medical diagnostics and transportation,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. `` However, the newly discovered materials will require extensive research and development.'' All three laboratories have been active in superconductivity research and have the facilities and expertise needed to make the technology marketable, <PERSON> Herrington </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0334EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugSmuggling     04-23 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Smuggling,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yost Says Coast Guard Patrol Cuts Could Be Leading To Drug Trade
Increase</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> says severe cutbacks in air and sea drug patrols by the financially strapped agency could be leading to an increase in drug trafficking along <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coasts. `` The smugglers, when they ship, do n't send us an invoice,'' said Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` But we do have intelligence that indicates the awareness by the smugglers that the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> has cut back its patrols by ship and by air. `` I can only surmise that that influences their shipping schedules'' and that there is `` some intention of taking advantage of that,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, faced with a $ 100 million budget shortfall, earlier this year permanently shut down dozens of stations, resulting in $ 40 million in savings. To cover the remaining $ 60 million, <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> ordered a 55 percent across-the-board reduction of sea and air missions for drug interdiction and routine search-and-rescue patrols. The cutbacks have been in effect for about three months. `` Fifty-five percent of my ships are sitting alongside the dock and planes are on the runways,'' the commandant said in interviews this week with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think that's a travesty,'' he said. `` I really think the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people, having paid money for the ships and aircraft, and ... paying the salary of the young men and women who they've trained to do these jobs, to have them sitting on the runway and tied up at the dock That ought to make the taxpayer angry.'' Last month, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to transfer $ 60 million in other <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> funds, such as <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION>, mass transit and highway projects, to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> to bring the patrols back up to last year's levels. But <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has yet to act. <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said he believes he is caught in the middle of two political realities on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, and that he is coming out on the short end. `` What I see there is every member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> hates drugs and supports and loves the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, particularly members of our appropriations subcommittees,'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said. `` But they are forced to choose between drug interdiction and mass transit'' projects in their districts. `` I would guess very few of those members are saying, ` Take my money,''' he said. <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> said he sympathized with the chairmen of the transportation funding panels, Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>. `` They're both strong supporters of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, and yet they have a very difficult time taking money from their grant programs to properly fund the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said A <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> aide said the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee may take up the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s funding request this week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Markets 1stLd-Writethru a0864 04-23 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Markets, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0864,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Prices Rally In Tokyo</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with closing figures, details</NOTE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stock prices topped the 27,000-point level in an active half-day of trading Saturday, buoyed by an overnight rally on Wall Street, analysts said. On the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, the 225-issue Nikkei Stock Average, which gained 8.96 points Friday, surged by 221.25 points to close the half-day session at 27,058.37. It was the <ORGANIZATION> Nikkei </ORGANIZATION>'s second-highest close since April 14, when it was 27,111.35 Volume on the first section was a moderate 470 million shares. `` Since there were few new incentives to affect the market today, it's clear that investors had been waiting on the sidelines for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> share prices to recover,'' said an analyst with <ORGANIZATION> Nomura </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s largest brokerage. <PERSON> Yoshio </PERSON> <PERSON> Shimayama </PERSON>, a trader with <ORGANIZATION> Nikko </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION>, attributed the favorable showing to the growing Japanese economy. `` The market is looking at the state of business in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which is very favorable. ... The major recovery in share prices in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> overnight is also driving the market, and the overall mood of investors here is very strong,'' <PERSON> Shimayama </PERSON> said. Large issues such as steels and constructions were traded actively, along with electricals such as <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION>. Buy orders for <ORGANIZATION> Toshiba </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, targeted for penalty sanctions in an omnibus trade bill approved by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> Thursday, totaled more than 6.1 million shares, compared with 730,000 sell orders. `` It indicates the -LRB- positive -RRB- mood of market investors,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Nomura </ORGANIZATION> analyst said. The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> foreign exchange is closed on Saturdays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Obit-Price     04-23 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Price,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rep. Price Remembered As Advocate For Military, Servant To
Constituents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Democrat elected in the waning days of World War II who rose to second in House seniority, was remembered at his death as a loyal servant to his constituents and a strong advocate for the nation's military. Price, 83, died Friday of cancer at <LOCATION> Malcolm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grove </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. He was serving his 22nd term in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a tenure surpassed only by 24-term Rep. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, D-Mass. Price, who had announced two years ago this would be his last term in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, for 10 years chaired the chamber's <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He was ousted from that post in January 1985 by younger Democrats seeking a more vigorous watchdog on the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's military policies. During his tenure as head of the committee, Price had presided over the drive to beef up the nation's arms stockpile with the MX missile, the B-1 bomber, a nuclear aircraft carrier and a vast array of other hardware. A proposed amendment to the Pentagon budget bill pending in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> would name a new Trident missile-firing submarine for Price. He considered himself a staunch supporter of administration requests for military spending regardless of which party was in power, acknowledging the committee under his aegis was somewhat of a `` rubber stamp'' for the Pentagon. `` In many ways, it is,'' Price once said. `` I'd rather be criticized for being for something than have to alibi when we need it and we do n't have it.'' Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., who replaced Price as chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, called him `` a fair, evenhanded, thoughtful member'' with `` a quiet grace that will be missed around <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Price had suffered in recent years from arthritis and diabetes, and learned in the last month that he had pancreatic cancer, said administrative assistant <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON>. He went to the hospital early Friday complaining of pain and died in the early evening. Price, who had been a sports writer in the 1920s, grew up along the banks of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>. He came to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as an aide at the start of the New Deal and won election while serving as an enlisted man in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. He took office in 1945, as the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> was closing in on <PERSON> Adolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s bunker. <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>' two Democratic senators said Price's impact on his state and on the nation's military would continue. `` <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> was a man of the people who kept a common touch after reaching great heights. He moved from being an Army corporal to contributing in a major way to the nation's defense,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> said Price `` had absolutely no peer in service to his constituency. He was my mentor and close personal friend. My deepest sympathies are with his wife today.'' Illinois Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, a Republican, said, `` <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> dedicated his life to serving the people of southwestern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, and he became one of the most powerful people in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` The people of his district will miss Representative Price, but the evidence of his dedication is clearly visible throughout the towns and villages of that area,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. Price, himself a victim of ouster from the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> panel by younger lawmakers, first was selected to chair the panel in 1974 when junior lawmakers rebelled against Rep. <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., whom they considered too autocratic He continued to serve as chairman of the panel's research and development subcommittee even after his ouster from the committee's top position, but in his later years suffered from severe arthritis which forced him to inch his way across <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> and miss some legislative business due to hospitalization Price in 1986 survived a four-way primary battle to win his party's nomination, and defeated his <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> challenger by just 943 votes, his smallest margin of victory. In <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, Madison County Clerk <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowles </PERSON>, said Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> has five days from the death to call for a special election, which would must be held within 115 days of the governor's call. Price is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Garaldine </PERSON>, and one son, Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Colo </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880423-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-23-88 0350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WalkingHorses     04-23 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walking Horses,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Rules Designed To Prevent Trauma To Show Horses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
