<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Drought-SpiderMites     08-09 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought-Spider Mites,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spider Mites Threaten Drought-Stressed Soybean Crops</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KALAMAZOO, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drought-weary farmers who are pinning their hopes on soybeans now face another threat: tiny, hungry mites that like dry weather and can go unnoticed while destroying crops. State agriculture officials say spider mites are invading soybean fields in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and other drought-plagued <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> states. `` It's a difficult critter to fight because they're hard to see with the naked eye,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Landis </PERSON>, a field crops entomologist at <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` When a crop looks bad, it's blamed on other things _ mostly the drought. It's not until the problem becomes severe that the mites are discovered,'' <PERSON> Landis </PERSON> said Monday. The mites, which thrive in dry, hot conditions, feed on the underside of plant leaves by piercing plant cells and extracting the sap, <PERSON> Landis </PERSON> said. After a few days, the leaves bear yellow speckles and eventually turn brown or bronze. `` Entire fields can be completely lost if spider mites are not controlled and weather conditions allow them to build up populations,'' <PERSON> Landis </PERSON> said. The eight-legged pests are easily carried on the wind from field to field. `` It's just another thing you've got to fight,'' said farmer <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fulton </LOCATION>, who recently discovered mites in his soybean field. The infestation is potentially another serious blow to farmers who have lost much of their corn crop in the drought and were hoping to cut their losses with soybeans, which are bringing in higher prices. Because farmers in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> also are combating the mites, there has been a shortage of pesticides to kill the pests, <PERSON> Landis </PERSON> said. `` We are running at capacity in an attempt to meet the stepped-up demand,'' <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrick </PERSON> said of the production of one such pesticide, <ORGANIZATION> Lorsban </ORGANIZATION> 4 E. `` The demand has been so great for the product we're just running out of product.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Beryl 2ndLd-Writethru a0786 08-09 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Beryl, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0786,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beryl Moves Inland, Raises Hopes For Rain In Midwest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 7th graf `The storm's...' with one graf to UPDATE with
later position.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical storm <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> was downgraded to a tropical depression Tuesday after moving inland and weakening, leaving one person missing in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> but raising hopes that its remnants could bring rain to drought-stricken <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> farmers. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescued six people who endured two days of wind and rain on an island after high seas prevented them from returning to the mainland. There was virtually no damage in southern <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> except for some spot flooding and tree limbs blown down. Scattered damage was reported in southern <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, including downed tree limbs and scattered power outages. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, where preparations continued for next week's Republican National Convention, few problems developed from the storm `` The beneficial aspects of this tropical storm are probably much greater than any negative effects from this system _ and that's rain,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. Shortly before 5 p.m. CDT, forecasters downgraded the storm to a tropical depression as its highest sustained wind speed dropped to 35 mph; a storm is designated a tropical storm when wind speed hits 39 mph. The storm's center was just west-southwest of <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION> by 9:30 p.m., and was expected to continue moving slowly northwest, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. Seas of 7 to 10 feet were expected to drop behind the storm, forecasters said. Although the storm was not producing widespread rain, there was a danger of flooding from locally heavy storms, the weather service said. Flooding was reported in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> in low areas and along overflowing rivers and streams. About 150 people in <LOCATION> Harrison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> were forced to move to higher ground Tuesday because of river flooding, said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Rouse </PERSON>, deputy director for <ORGANIZATION> Harrison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have people on all of the rivers'' monitoring the levels. <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> storm season's second named tropical storm, still had the potential of moving back over the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, where it would gain strength from the warm water, but forecasters said that was unlikely. `` We think it's going to go on a more west track, west northwest, then turn toward the northwest up over the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> area,'' Sheets said. `` We do n't think it's going to go back out over the water so there's not much chance of it ever strengthening again.'' Thousands of workers from the marshes and offshore oil rigs were evacuated Monday as a precaution, and tourists abandoned the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> coasts. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> suspended a search Tuesday for a 15-year-old boy who fell overboard when a 24-foot fishing boat capsized near <LOCATION> Dauphin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> off the coast of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. The youth, whose name was not given, was reported missing Tuesday by a survivor found clinging to the hull of a vessel that capsized Monday in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> Sound. Searchers believe the boat was swamped by seven-foot waves. Although <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> barely bruised <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>'s coastline, 11.6 inches of rain was reported at <LOCATION> Dauphin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> for the 24-hour period ending at 7 a.m. Tuesday. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> rescued six people who went camping Sunday on <LOCATION> Petit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bois </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Pasagoula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Miss. </LOCATION>, when the forecast was for mostly sunny weather. That night, the weather turned bad and the water became too choppy to travel back to the mainland. `` We lost one of the tents,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> said. `` We patched the other with garbage bags and anything else we could find. We exhausted everything we had.'' `` We have n't slept since Sunday,'' she said after being rescued Tuesday. `` We have n't been dry since then.'' Homes were evacuated east of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION> fishing villages of <LOCATION> Hopedale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yscloskey </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Lafourche </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Parish </LOCATION>, authorities readied eight evacuation centers Monday, but seven of the centers remained closed Tuesday, the eighth was unoccupied and parish officials said they expected few problems with the storm.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     08-09 0482</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0494</SECOND>
<HEAD>Countdown Set to Begin Tonight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new countdown begins tonight for a 22-second firing of space shuttle Discovery's three main engines, a vital test that has been postponed five times because of malfunctions. If this test succeeds, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials will set a date for the first American manned space flight since the Challenger burst into flames on liftoff in January 1986. The Discovery launch date, already officially moved four times, is not likely to be before October because of all the test delays. The flight readiness firing, as it's called, is an overall workout of the main engines, computer software, ground support equipment, communications lines and the launch teams. The `` call to stations'' that begins the countdown was scheduled for 6:10 p.m. with the test set for 7:30 a.m. Wednesday. Without further problems, fueling of the shuttle's huge tank begins a half hour before midnight. The shuttle's No. 2 engine is fitted with a new `` hydrogen bleed valve'' and sensor to replace units that caused a scheduled test to be scrapped last Thursday in the split second before the start of ignition. `` The recovery from the problem on Thursday shows that the team is working smoothly and I am expecting an on-time engine firing on Wednesday morning,'' said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Kennedy Space Center Discovery's three engines will be fired with slightly different start and stop times, using only a portion of the half million gallons of fuel in the external tank. Bolts 3 feet long and 3 inches in diameter hold the shuttle to the pad while the engines generate 1.1 million pounds of thrust. The two solid fuel rocket boosters flanking the shuttle tank will not be ignited but will be subjected to the same bending movements that led to a leak in one of the joints during Challenger's liftoff. That leak allowed flame to escape and led to the shuttle's destruction and the deaths of seven astronauts. Flight readiness firings have been required in the past for new shuttles only, except for one time when a malfunction made a retest necessary. But the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is treating Discovery as an untried ship because of the long time since the last flight and the many changes since the Challenger disaster. Last Thursday's engine test was aborted in the last second when a sensor reported that a valve had not closed as it was supposed to. Engineers determined that the sensor, not the valve, was malfunctioning but decided to replace both parts. The designer of the shuttle rocket booster, meanwhile, announced Monday that the last of five full-scale test-firings for the booster will be held Aug. 18. The fifth in the series of firings of the 126-foot-long redesigned rocket will be conducted at <ORGANIZATION> Morton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thiokol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s northern <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> plant
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HanfordReach     08-09 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hanford Reach,0877</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Works To Save Last Free Stretch of Columbia River</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICHOLAS K. GERANIOS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ON THE COLUMBIA RIVER, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> rolls lazily through the desert of central <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, nourishing crops and wildlife in what otherwise would be a wasteland of sagebrush and barren hills. The river, which once roared through deep gorges, was immortalized in <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Guthrie </PERSON>'s Depression-era song `` Roll On, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` <PERSON> Green </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> fir where the waters cut through, Down her wild mountains and canyons she flew, Canadian North-west to the ocean so blue, It's roll on, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, roll on!'' But after the construction of more than a dozen dams in 51 years, the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> has rolled nearly to a standstill. For much of its 1,214 miles, the river is a series of dams and slackwater reservoirs, providing electricity, irrigation and flood control for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> claims one last free-flowing stretch _ the 55-mile Hanford Reach _ and it too is facing major development. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> is proposing a $ 180 million project to open the river to barge traffic all the way to <LOCATION> Wenatchee </LOCATION>, so that logs, wheat and apples from the state's interior can be floated to <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> ports. The plan calls for dredging part of the river and building giant lifts over three dams to allow navigation between <LOCATION> Richland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wenatchee </LOCATION>. Opponents say the dredging would forever ruin valuable fish and wildlife habitat, archaeological sites and the last vestige of natural river flow. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s congressional delegation has introduced legislation to protect the area. The reach `` is one of the only areas where spawning habitats remain undisturbed, nesting areas abound, and majestic cliffs lining the river are mirrored in its quiet, deep calm,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, R-Wash. `` We're telling them do n't go ahead with these ill-conceived plans until we know the impact on spawning and recreation, the most important use of the river,'' said Republican Rep. <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, whose district includes the area Under the bill, the Department of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> would protect the Hanford Reach for eight years until a study determines whether to permanently preserve the stretch under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act. The bill has already cleared the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> but <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> has delayed House action while negotiations continue to address concerns of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION>. That agency operates the <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION> nuclear reservation, a sprawling plutonium-production site that straddles the river. The Energy Department is worried the study could hamper Hanford operations, said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Seeley </PERSON>, a legislative aide to <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>. There lies the irony of the `` wild and scenic'' designation: as the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> flows past nine federal nuclear reactors no one would call the view pastoral. The huge, eerie reactors, technological marvels in their time, produced much of the plutonium for the nation's nuclear weapons arsenal. The slow-moving river creeps past the hulking reactors, with pumping stations, razor-wire fences and guard towers casting shadows over the water. Eight are closed permanently. The newest, the N Reactor, which was placed on `` cold standby'' earlier this year because the federal government no longer needed the plutonium, stands closest to the river, a brooding presence amid the jumping fish, herons and deer. Much of the shore is off-limits to recreational users because the federal government wanted a buffer zone around its reactors. The Hanford Reach runs from Priest Rapids Dam, south of <LOCATION> Mattawa </LOCATION>, to the reservoir of <PERSON> McNary </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON> just north of <LOCATION> Richland </LOCATION>. The biggest objections to the dredging are that the movement of a half-million cubic yards of dirt would destroy some of the last wild runs of chinook salmon, which battle their way up river to spawn. `` That's one of the few or perhaps the only remaining natural spawning area in that entire river system below Grand Coulee -LRB- dam -RRB- that salmon and steelhead can get too,'' said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, deputy director the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> has proposed building an artificial salmon spawning channel, to compensate for areas lost to dredging. But opponents say that would not work. `` Artificial spawning channels just do n't provide the quantity and quality of reproduction that the natural free-flowing river provides,'' <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> said. `` The technology has n't been that well-perfected.'' The dredging proposal has also run into stiff fiscal opposition. The cost-benefit ratio for the project currently stands at just 80 cents in benefits for every dollar spent, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sellar </PERSON>, manager of water resources for the Port of <LOCATION> Chelan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Wenatchee </LOCATION>, which has been pushing the plan since the 1950s. The port and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> are now studying the plan to try to make it economically stronger. For instance, some people feel that large quantities of apples could not be moved by barge because of the length of the trip, but others say using refrigerated containers would keep them fresh, <PERSON> Sellar </PERSON> said. The port hopes to save up to 40 percent in transportation costs compared to rail or trucking. `` One barge will move the equivalent of 50 to 60 trucks,'' <PERSON> Sellar </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DroughtConditions     08-09 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Conditions,0562</SECOND>
<HEAD>Latest Reports on Soil, Crop Conditions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Following are the latest soil and crop conditions in some of the states hardest hit by the drought, based on an <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey of Monday's weekly reports by state agricultural offices. Percentages relate to the number of reporting stations listing a particular soil or crop condition.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALABAMA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 SOIL MOISTURE: 6 percent very short, 50 percent short, 39 percent adequate, 5 percent surplus. KEY CROPS: Soybeans 15 percent poor, 35 percent fair, 38 percent good, 12 percent excellent. Cotton 11 percent very poor, 32 percent poor, 38 percent fair, 14 percent good, 5 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ILLINOIS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 88 percent short, 12 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 3 percent good, 30 percent fair, 47 percent poor, 20 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IOWA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 2 percent surplus, 37 percent adequate, 36 percent short, 25 percent critically short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 1 percent surplus, 7 percent adequate, 43 percent short, 49 percent critically short. KEY CROP: Corn 1 percent excellent, 8 percent good, 34 percent fair, 39 percent poor, 18 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KENTUCKY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 13 percent very short, 60 percent short, 27 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Tobacco 1 percent very poor, 7 percent poor, 44 percent fair, 48 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MICHIGAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 85 percent short and 15 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 2 percent excellent, 15 percent good, 35 percent fair, 28 percent poor, 20 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MINNESOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 49 percent very short, 38 percent short, 13 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 34 percent very poor, 40 percent poor, 26 percent fair.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 55 percent short, 45 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 65 percent short, 35 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 10 percent poor, 21 percent fair, 54 percent good, 15 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 73 percent very short, 24 percent short, 3 percent adequate. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 74 percent very short, 20 percent short, 6 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Wheat 37 percent very poor, 43 percent poor, 16 percent fair, 4 percent good.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 32 percent adequate, 68 percent short. KEY CROPS: Corn 8 percent good, 33 percent fair, 33 percent poor, 26 percent very poor. Soybeans 1 percent excellent, 15 percent good, 42 percent fair, 28 percent poor, 14 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 2 percent surplus, 37 percent adequate, 36 percent short, 25 percent critically short. SUBSOIL MOISTURE: 1 percent surplus, 7 percent adequate, 43 percent short, 49 percent critically short. KEY CROP: Corn 1 percent excellent, 8 percent good, 34 percent fair, 39 percent poor, 18 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TENNESSEE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 4 percent very short, 47 percent short, 48 percent adequate, 1 percent surplus. KEY CROP: Cotton 2 percent poor, 20 percent fair, 74 percent good, 4 percent excellent.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WISCONSIN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 TOPSOIL MOISTURE: 96 percent short, 4 percent adequate. KEY CROP: Corn 6 percent good, 35 percent fair, 38 percent poor, 21 percent very poor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-09 0460</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILLBURY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A distaste for turning lambs into chops has transformed a sewage treatment plant into a haven for sheep, chickens, geese, rabbits and, as their keeper puts it, `` whatever people throw over the fence.'' The creatures live on the 107-acre spread of the <ORGANIZATION> Upper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blackstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pollution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abatement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> amid tanks, pipes, pools, pumps, an incinerator and plenty of grass for grazing. <PERSON> Emil </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>, plant director, recalls that in the spring of 1978 a farmer was allowed to leave two lambs there to fatten up on the plant's grassy field. By the time the farmer returned in the fall, plant employees had grown attached to the lambs and pleaded that they be spared their fate as shish kebab. So, the sewage district board voted to buy the sheep from the farmer. Soon, more creatures arrived unannounced, apparently abandoned by their owners. `` We'd come in the morning and one day we had 12 geese,'' <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> said Monday. `` The next day we had 12 ducks, then four chickens.'' On Monday, the `` community,'' as <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> describes it, included three sheep, two dozen geese, two dozen chickens and roosters _ `` we get a lot of roosters'' _ and uncounted rabbits and pigeons. The animals drink from a fountain that carries clean water. They also have the run of two huts, and staff at the sewage plant feed them grain. Motorists stop every day to look, <ORGANIZATION> Holland </ORGANIZATION> said, and some leave with a pet. `` We give them away to anybody who asks,'' <PERSON> Holland </PERSON> said, `` as long as they're not going to eat them.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State officials wanted a big check from <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bourre </PERSON> for back taxes, and that's what they got. <PERSON> Bourre </PERSON> handed then a check measuring 7 inches by 14 inches, or more than twice the standard size. `` It's a perfectly legitimate check,'' said <PERSON> Bourre </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, resident and a opponent of a <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> law that requires him to pay <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> income taxes because he works at the <ORGANIZATION> Portsmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION>. The shipyard is on an island in the <LOCATION> Piscataqua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> between <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and is connected by a bridge to <LOCATION> Kittery </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> state Treasurer <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON> agreed that the check, printed on thick brown paper, was legal tender. <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON>'s deputy, <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stickney </PERSON>, deposited the $ 981.12 payment in a bank Monday afternoon. <PERSON> Bourre </PERSON>, 40, said Monday that a friend arranged for a printing shop to blow up a check. He said he wanted to make it 4 feet by 8 feet, but `` that's the biggest I could get made up right away.'' <PERSON> Bourre </PERSON> said he had withheld payment during a legal challenge by shipyard workers. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> refused to hear the case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0110EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Costs     08-09 1032</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Costs,1068</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least 1 Million Casualties, Billions In Cost For No Gain</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> say they will accept a cease-fire. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace plan appears to be under way and there is hope the 8-year-old war in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> will end soon. Here is a report on the human and material cost.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN MARRIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For eight years, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> sent their youth to slaughter, squandered their wealth and mortaged their futures in a war that gained nothing for either side. Children as young as 13, eagerly seeking a martyr's death, perished as sacrificial mine sweepers. Children, parents and grandparents were blown to bits or crippled by bombs, shells and missiles in the cities of both sides. Soldiers and civilians were maimed by poison warfare. In all, more than 1 million people were killed or wounded. The war cost hundreds of billions of dollars and caused measureless agony and grief. <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> secretary-general, announced Monday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> that the two enemies had agreed to end the war with a cease-fire Aug. 20 and to begin peace negotiations Aug. 25 in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. On the killing fields near the southern port of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> soldiers dug trenches and unreeled barbed wire for set-piece battles reminiscent of World War I. Men and boys died by the thousands in the mud and shallow water of the marshes. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s official news media periodically reported a `` harvest of the rotten heads.'' Foreign correspondents taken on guided tours were shown heaps of Iranian bodies on the battlefield. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> spoke of victories by its `` martyrdom-seeking'' soldiers and Revolutionary Guards. The ranks were swollen by children wearing `` Martyr'' T-shirts, pressed into the service of <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s fundamentalist Islamic government. Sometimes it seemed the young men of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> commuted to battle, so close was the front to many cities. They returned in coffins atop automobiles moving in long processions. Iranians buried their dead in the Martyrs' Cemetery outside <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, a huge graveyard whose centerpiece is a `` fountain of blood'' spewing water dyed red. By Western estimates, the set-piece battles east of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> in January 1987 killed 25,000 Iranians and 10,000 Iraqis. All the casualty figures are estimates. Neither country provided comprehensive numbers during the war, which began in September 1980 with border skirmishes followed by an Iraqi invasion across the <PERSON> Shatt </PERSON> <PERSON> al-Arab </PERSON>, the waterway that forms the southern border. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordesman </PERSON> says in his book `` The Iran-Iraq War and Western Security,'' that at least 300,000 Iranians were killed and 600,000 wounded through 1987, with corresponding for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> of 120,000 and 300,000. He says the estimates are conservative, that by some accounts the dead total 1 million and the wounded 1.7 million. By comparison, 2.9 million people were killed in the Korean war and 2.4 million in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Hundreds of billions of dollars were devoured by arms purchases, lost revenues, damaged or destroyed buildings and industrial plants. War damage extended beyond <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> insurance exchange, reported 90 ships sunk or destroyed in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and 546 attacked, with at least 300 sailors killed and 300 injured. Ninety-three ships were trapped in Iraqi waterways throughout the war, many of them written off. <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> said its underwriters paid more than $ 1 billion in ship claims and other insurers a like amount. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> started the war with foreign exchange reserves of $ 35 billion and now owes an estimated $ 60 billion. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has not borrowed but its foreign exchange reserves have declined to a few billion dollars. <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, an financial journal published in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, estimates <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> needs $ 80 billion and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> $ 30 billion to rebuild transportation, oil installations, housing, factories, schools and hospitals. Evidence of the human cost is everywhere. `` Every family has been touched by the war,'' an accountant named <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON> told an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> earlier this month. `` They've all had a son or a brother killed or maimed or taken prisoner,'' he said. `` Every family has one or more men in the army.'' Two of <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON>'s sons were in the army and a third was at home, minus a hand and a leg. Battle casualties include many children under 15 who ran into mine fields with plastic `` keys to Paradise'' around their necks. French photographer <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Lochon </PERSON> visited the front in 1984 and reported seeing the bodies of many dead children `` who were no older than 12 or 14.'' `` The skull shaved, wrapped in the red scarf of the martyrs, the key to Paradise around the neck, they were scattered around the rocky trenches or floating in the still waters,'' he said. Many other warriors shown on Iranian television appeared elderly, with white hair and grins that showed few teeth. In <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> encouraged older citizens to join the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> militia. Thousands of civilians were killed by bombs and surface-to-surface missiles that struck hospitals, schools and residential areas in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and other cities. Hundreds of missiles were fired in a round of the `` war of the cities'' earlier this year. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> reported 1,145 civilians killed and 4,000 wounded. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> did not give casualty figures, but nearly 30 children were killed when an Iranian missile hit a <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> school last year. <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> battlefield casualties have been only about one-quarter of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s, but <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has only 16 million people compared to 45 million in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and was conscious from the beginning of the need to avoid heavy losses. It resorted to chemical weapons, which are banned by the 1925 <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> Convention. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> reports say one of those weapons was mustard gas, the scourge of the World War I trenches. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> claimed 5,000 Kurds were killed and 5,000 wounded in a chemical attack on the border town of <LOCATION> Halabja </LOCATION> in March. Foreign reporters taken there saw many bodies, unmarked by wounds. <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Azizi </PERSON>, a 25-year-old student, was in <LOCATION> Halabja </LOCATION> at the time and said streets were strewn with the bodies of victims. Doctors said they suspected mustard gas killed them. `` Any door you opened, there were children, men and women, dying, dead,'' <ORGANIZATION> Azizi </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Statlers     08-09 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Statlers,0167</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wrigley Field Lights Prompt Statler Lyric Change</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Cub Lights, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turning the lights on for the first night game at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s Wrigley Field is forcing country music's Statlers quartet to change the lyrics of their 7-year-old song `` Do n't Wait On Me. The lyrics of the 1981 song contain the phrase, `` When the lights go on at <LOCATION> Wrigley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>, I'll be coming home to you.'' Although the recording, from the album `` Years Ago,'' ca n't be changed, the group will substitute the line with, `` When they put a dome on <LOCATION> Wrigley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>, I'll be coming home to you'' in performances. `` That ought to keep us ahead of them for a few years,'' The Statlers' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> said from his home in <LOCATION> Staunton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` It never crossed our minds that one day they would put lights in <LOCATION> Wrigley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Field </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, a baseball buff who wrote the song with his brother and fellow group member, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0114EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Losses     08-09 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Losses,0570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Futile War Costly to Both Sides in Terms of Revenue, Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-UN-Gulf</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NICK LUDINGTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Iran-Iraq war cost hundreds of billions of dollars in lost revenues, damaged and destroyed buildings, industrial plants, ships and military equipment. Aside from the human toll, the economic cost to the combatants, according to Israeli experts who followed the war closely, was more than $ 200 billion through 1986. Nineteen months of further devastation added to this figure. Other countries have lost as well. The <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> insurance firm, <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, reports that in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> `` tanker war'' 90 ships were sunk or destroyed and and 546 ships attacked, most of them damaged. Another 93 ships have been trapped in Iraqi waterways since the war began, many of them written off. Insurance losses paid out by <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> on ship hulls has been more than $ 1 billion. Other firms paid a similar amount, <ORGANIZATION> Lloyds </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> started the war with foreign exchange reserves of $ 35 billion and now owes foreign countries an estimated $ 60 billion. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has avoided borrowing but has run down its foreign exchange reserves to a few billion dollars. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> refused to give figures on losses, human, material or economic. The <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> economic paper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, quoting Western economic experts, says <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> needs $ 80 billion to rebuild transport facilities, oil installations, housing, factories, schools and hospitals. It said <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> needs $ 30 billion for the same task. A report by <PERSON> Kiyotaki </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsuji </PERSON> of the Japanese institute of <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> estimated that damage to oil installations alone, from bombing and shelling raids, amounted to $ 28 billion for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and $ 8 billion for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Estimates of military equipment purchases for the war, above normal pre-war expenditures vary, from $ 25 billion to $ 40 billion for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and from $ 35 billion to $ 70 billion for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Paying, feeding and treating wounded soldiers added billions more to war expenditures. Losses in oil revenues, estimated by <PERSON> Tsuji </PERSON>, are $ 23 billion for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and $ 65 billion for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Pre-war production in <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> was 3.6 million barrels a day. It fell to 1.2 million barrels a day in 1981 and gradually has been built back to 2.7 million barrels a day. Iraqi bombing raids decimated <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s refining capacity from 1.3 million barrels a day pre-war, to 400,000 barrels a day, forcing the Iranians to import petroleum products costing $ 1.5 million a year, oil experts here estimated. Iraqi raids damaged or put out of action Iranian refineries at <LOCATION> Abadan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Isfahan </LOCATION>, Shiraz, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bakhtaran </LOCATION>. The billion-dollar oil loading facility at <LOCATION> Kharg </LOCATION> island is virtually destroyed. Iranians wrecked <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s oil shipping terminal at <LOCATION> Faw </LOCATION>. Construction in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has stopped because of Iraqi bombing at a major petrochemical plant being built with Japanese help at <PERSON> Bandar </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, at the huge gas collection and treatment plant being built by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Nar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kangan </LOCATION>, and at a nuclear power plant at <LOCATION> Bushehr </LOCATION>. Early in the war <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> lost its 140,000 barrel-a-day oil refinery at <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> port was closed and two-thirds of the 1 million inhabitants of the city fled shelling attacks from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> which damaged most of the buildings. Missiles and bombs did extensive damage to civilian facilities in other major cities on both sides, including <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Royals-Duchess     08-09 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Royals-Duchess,0763</SECOND>
<HEAD>Duchess Delights Some, Worries Others</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With PM-Royals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By AUDREY WOODS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the two years since she married the queen's second son <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Duchess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> has brought both sparkle and new controversy to the royal scene Some critics find her vivacious personality and sense of fun tiresome or vulgar, her adventurous spirit verging on the reckless. But royal watchers say the 28-year-old former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> is a favorite with Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>. Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, a tall, handsome <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant, gained a playboy reputation during a colorful bachelorhood. It included a well-publicized romance with an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> actress, <PERSON> Koo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON>, who once appeared in soft-porn movies. But by the spring of 1986 <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> was clearly smitten with the red-haired Miss <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>. The public were enjoying her lively good nature and the queen was reported to be greatly relieved that <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> had found a suitable wife. They married at Westminster Abbey July 23, 1986, and became the <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> and Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Both were 26. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> was a new kind of royal bride. A sales executive with a graphic arts publishing company when she married, she had led a free and independent life that included a three-year romance with motor-racing figure <PERSON> Paddy </PERSON> <PERSON> McNally </PERSON>, a widower with two sons. Robust, athletic and outspoken, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> was far from the slim, demure and impeccably-groomed English rose that Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, wife of Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, typified. She kept working after her marriage, and although she had given up her publishing job by early 1988, she planned to do free-lance work. While <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> pursued his career as a <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> pilot, his wife learned to fly a helicopter and a plane so she could share the experience with him. The <ORGANIZATION> Yorks </ORGANIZATION> have rejected the traditional choice of an old stately home and are building a new house near <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION> _ in a neo-Tudor style that has drawn some criticism. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>'s attempts to find a fashion sense of her own led to some howling failures, each of which was dissected in the press. The media also criticized what they saw as the duchess' brash and vulgar behavior during the couple's March <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour, particularly in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Newspapers were especially critical of the duchess' quip: `` I'll see you later,'' to a man who yelled out, `` I love you'' at a dinner When <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> wore a flamboyant black-and-red gown to a black-tie dinner, <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> wrote: `` While the stars of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> dressed in discreet black and stayed in the shadows, down the stairs walloped someone who looked as if she'd just won third prize for her <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> impersonation ... at some forgotten resort.'' `` Has the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> gone too far?'' asked the Observer newspaper. As <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> grew heavily pregnant, the tabloids carried unflattering photos of her and made remarks about her weight. But the duchess's sense of humor scarcely flagged _ except in May when a newspaper carried a photo of her father, Maj. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON>, emerging from a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> massage parlor. While some newspapers called him <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> and suggested he be fired from his job as polo manager to <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, the heir to the throne, and others said the duchess was advised to avoid him in public, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> was photographed speaking to her father, worriedly. The major had become a close friend of the queen's husband, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Philip </PERSON>, through their shared interest in polo. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, born Oct. 15, 1959, has known all the queen's children since childhood. She became a close friend of <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>, who is reported to have done some matchmaking in <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>'s relationship with <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> grew up at her family's 18th-century farmhouse set in 1,200 acres of rolling <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> countryside at <PERSON> Dummer </PERSON>. She was educated at two local boarding schools, <PERSON> Daneshill </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Hurst </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lodge </LOCATION>, where she was head girl _ the school leader _ excelling at sports rather than studies. <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>'s parents divorced when she was 14, and her mother, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON>, married Argentine polo professional <PERSON> Hector </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrantes </PERSON>. They live at Trenque Laughen near <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> and travel the international polo circuit. After school, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> studied at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> James </ORGANIZATION>' secretarial college in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Then it was off to work, first at an apartment rental agency, then at a Covent Garden art gallery, a sports public relations agency and finally as a sales executive with B.C.K. Graphic Arts in fashionable <PERSON> Mayfair </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MagazineSecurity     08-09 0659</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Magazine Security,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nervous Over Business Week Scandal, Competitors Watch Their Backs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RICK GLADSTONE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Insider trading on stolen Business Week stock tip columns has alarmed the magazine's rivals, compelling some to review their own security and recheck back issues to make sure they have n't been victimized, too. `` We do n't take any pleasure in what happened to Business Week, but we're in the enviable position of bolting the barn door before the horse escapes, or at least checking the locks,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Belis </PERSON>, spokesman for Fortune, which has a biweekly circulation of 755,000. `` We're checking the locks.'' <PERSON> Belis </PERSON> said a spot check of Fortune's `` Companies to Watch'' column going back several months showed no unusual prepublication activity in any stocks mentioned. Senior editorial officials at Forbes and Money, two other widely read business magazines, also said they were reassessing protection of market-sensitive material in the aftermath of the scandal at Business Week. In addition, the printing companies used by all four magazines said they were scrutinizing security and reminding all employees that unpublished material is sacrosanct and not to leave the plant. The scandal surfaced July 21 when Business Week, the nation's largest business weekly with a circulation of nearly 1 million, disclosed evidence of possibly illegal trading on stocks featured in its `` Inside Wall Street'' column before it was available to the public A major investigation has since revealed workers in two plants run by Business Week printer R.R. <ORGANIZATION> Donnelley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> took copies the day before they were released to the public and peddled them to brokers, sometimes for as little as $ 20 each. As of the weekend, four <PERSON> Donnelley </PERSON> printers and three stock brokers, one each from <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Prudential-Bache </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Advest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, had lost their jobs. Trades in several more brokerages are under investigation for possible links to prepublished `` Inside Wall Street'' tips. Unlike newspapers, where the time gap between writing and printing sensitive material is brief, weeklies and monthlies face the problem of protecting potentially market-moving items over a period of days and weeks. The problem is compounded in mass-circulation magazines, which rely on printing plants at several locations and the honesty of hundreds of printers, couriers, truckers and postal workers who have access before subscribers do. `` There's a real limitation on our ability to place guards on every truck,'' said <PERSON> Landon </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, managing editor of Money, a monthly with a circulation of 1.8 million. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said Money sent a letter to its printer, <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Color </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Effingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, after the Business Week scandal surfaced, warning that `` the material they handle is property of Money magazine. It is their obligation to protect Money's property as it passes through their hands.'' He said a check of Money's `` Wall Street'' column and other potentially sensitive material going back at least one year found no suspicious trading. At <LOCATION> Forbes </LOCATION>, also printed by <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Color </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, deputy managing editor <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Minard </PERSON> said the 740,000-circulation weekly and its printer historically have had a firm understanding about confidentiality. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Minard </PERSON> said, `` we did reiterate to World Color that we expect the agreement we've had with them to be vigilantly observed.'' <PERSON> Minard </PERSON> said there was no effort at Forbes to recheck back issues, but he said, `` I suppose on a continuing basis, I very unofficially monitor it.'' For their part, <PERSON> Donnelley </PERSON>, World Color and <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Printing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Wauseca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, which prints Fortune, have undertaken security crackdowns. Besides dismissing employees implicated in the Business Week scandal, Chicago-based <PERSON> Donnelley </PERSON> has reminded all workers of a ban on removing any material from plants. Others have done likewise. <PERSON> Donnelley </PERSON> also has uniformed sentries at exits, plainclothes guards patrolling production lines and a policy that workers' clothing may be searched Nevertheless, spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratcliffe </PERSON> said, the company still must largely rely on employee's integrity. `` To frisk 650 people would be a bit impractical,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Angola Bjt   08-09 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Angola, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Getting Five Armies To Stop Shooting No Small
Task</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For the past 13 years, three national armies and two guerrilla insurgencies have been fighting in southwestern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Now, finally, there is hope that an end to the conflict may be within reach. The latest step in the process occurred Monday when South African Foreign Minister <PERSON> Roelof </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said a `` de facto cessation of hostilities'' is now in effect in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, the scene of direct or indirect military involvement by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The imponderables in the region are many and just keeping track of all the players is no small achievement. The Cubans have been in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> since that country's independence from <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> rule in 1975. South Africans have fought intermittently in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, worried about Marxist penetration in an area close to home. The <ORGANIZATION> Angolan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, of course, has been a major player, arrayed against both the South Africans and a U.S.-backed rebel group. Finally, in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, a black nationalist liberation movement has been fighting South African colonial control. The trick for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats, led by Assistant Secretary of State <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON>, is to devise a formula that would induce each of the five to lay down its arms. For years, progress was negligible but things began to change when <PERSON> Crocker </PERSON>, serving as peace mediator, succeeded in convening a meeting of South African, <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> and Angolan authorities in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> last May. At that meeting and in three subsequent sessions, the outlines of a settlement have come into view. Following is a brief summary of the interests of each party: <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> _ It has said for years that it would be willing to allow independence and black majority rule in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> so long as the estimated 50,000 Cubans leave <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> in a reasonable time. Continued colonial control of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> has been expensive for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the departure of the Cubans would ease its security concerns about <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> _ Its initial reason for becoming involved in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> was to protect a Marxist ally against South African military encroachment. If the South Africans promise to leave, that would remove the excuse for which the Cubans were sent to <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> in the first place. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> could withdraw its troops with its head held high, claiming that <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> was now safe from South African aggression. <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> _ It has been devastated by years of warfare. A Cuban withdrawal could make the government more vulnerable to attacks by the anti-communist guerrilla movement. On the other hand, the <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> rebels under the package deal now being negotiated would no longer receive assistance from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, whose forces would be withdrawn to within the country's national boundaries. <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> _ Known formally as the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> is the Namibian rebel group that has been fighting South African colonial rule for more than 20 years Once South Africa consents to elections for an independent government, <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> can finally lay down its arms and reintegrate into Namibian society. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ It has poured hundreds of millions of dollars into <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> in support of its ally over the years. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has been showing increasing eagerness in promoting a settlement, apparently intent on cutting costs in an area of minimal strategic concern. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ Its main interest is eliminating the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> military presence in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s inclination to send large expeditionary forces to distant lands has long been a sore point in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. For the past three years, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has been sending military aid to the <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> rebels in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>'s fate is not under discussion in the U.S.-mediated talks, which are focused exclusively on external involvement in the region. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been prodding the Angolan government to open national reconciliation talks with <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION>. A key hurdle will come later this month when the parties attempt to reach agreement on a timetable for <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> withdrawal from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. Diplomats have never been more optimistic but <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> is advising caution, insisting that the cease fire is `` the first step of a very long, arduous road'' to peace.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedda </PERSON> has covered foreign affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1968.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-GulfPeace Bjt   08-09 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Gulf Peace, Bjt,0825</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran and Iraq _ Bitterness And Rancor Succumb To A Weariness Of
War</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY4,5</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a thousand years of <LOCATION> Arab-Persian </LOCATION> hostility and eight of war, peace is a precious but chimeric commodity for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Yet after a year-long <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace effort and two weeks of delicate, for a time deadlocked negotiations, a truce _ if not a lasting peace _ is at hand. On Monday, Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> announced that the guns would fall silent on Aug. 20 and both sides would meet five days later in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> for face-to-face peace talks under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> auspices. `` I am persuaded that both nations deeply wanted peace and are committed to it,'' he said. And that opened the way. It also opens the way for improved relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, a reduced <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval presence in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> and a better atmosphere in which to seek release of foreign hostages held by pro-Iranian Shiite Moslem fundamentalists in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The occasion marks the first time in memory that a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolution has been a key to ending a conflict. Numerous resolutions pertaining to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> have gone unheeded. Resolution 598 _ the year-old <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> peace plan _ is coming to fruition. The cease-fire announcement was the second major victory for <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> since April, when <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> signed a U.N.-mediated pact providing for the withdrawal of Soviet troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. As in the case of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> plan and mechanism already was in place when the belligerents turned to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Monday's proclamation also signifies a revival of the financially ailing <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> after years of lying fallow and ineffective. Among other tasks, it is now expected to play a peacekeeping role in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. For <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, the cease-fire announcement is only the beginning of a long, problematic road. Both belligerents gave way at the bargaining table because of economic and political compulsions; their weariness of war, not their dedication to peace. Both now claim political victory and say the other side gave way. The two shattered nations have nothing to show for the conflict that has claimed up to 1 million lives. The battle lines today are much as they were in September 1980, when <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> invaded <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> after a series of border skirmishes. If anything, the bitterness is greater, and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s massive and frequent use of internationally abhorred and outlawed poison gas has increased the enmity. The cease-fire announcement is the culmination of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peace efforts that began on July 20, 1987, when the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> adopted Resolution 598, demanding an immediate cease-fire and setting out a peace plan. For a full year, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> negotiated with both sides. Last year, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> was losing the war and immediately accepted Resolution 598, which calls for a troop withdrawal, prisoner exchange, establishment of a tribunal to assess responsibility for the damage, formal peace talks and reconstruction. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, which was winning, held out. It demanded that as a precondition for peace, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> must be branded the aggressor. For a full year, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was branded the obstructor of peace for not embracing the resolution. Now, a year later, the tables are turned. After a series of battlefield setbacks, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> abruptly announced on July 18 that it was embracing Resolution 598 and urged an immediate cease-fire. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> dropped the precondition of branding <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> the aggressor. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s supreme leader, the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, said that making the choice for peace was `` worse than swallowing poison.'' The secretary-general declared he would send a cease-fire mission to both countries and summoned the foreign ministers of both nations for peace talks. But <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which was on the offensive, suddenly demanded direct talks with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> as a precondition of a cease-fire. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> said direct talks could be held only after a cease-fire, troop withdrawal and prisoner exchange. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and his Iraqi counterpart, <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON>, came to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, but U.N.-mediated negotiations deadlocked over the issue of direct talks. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> appeared to be the peacemaker, while <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> held back. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> then devised a formula under which a truce would be followed rapidly by direct talks on a comprehensive peace. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> agreed immediately. On Saturday, President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> said he would go along with direct talks after a cease-fire, dropping his objections. That was the breakthrough. `` The restoration of peace will bring to the peoples of both countries victories far greater than those of war,'' <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> said Monday.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> chief correspondent at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ExtraterrestialSearch Bjt   08-09 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Extraterrestial Search, Bjt,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Discoveries Encourage Search For Intelligent Life Beyond Earth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Astronomers searching for radio signals from intelligent life beyond the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> say circumstantial evidence is growing that humankind is not alone in the universe. Reports of the discovery of new planets and of the presence of complex organic chemicals on comets are `` encouraging'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, manager of <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s radio search for life, said Monday. Research announced at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Astronomical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>'s 20th assembly last week showed the discovery of at least 10 planet-like objects in orbit of distant stars Other studies showed that comets and cosmic dust particles contain the complex organic compounds that are thought to have been the chemical precursors of life. `` That is the circumstantial evidence that life exists elsewhere,'' <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said. `` We know now that the materials are there. It gives us a good feeling that we are on the right track.'' <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> heads a project called the Search for <ORGANIZATION> Extraterrestial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION>, or SETI, that is planning to mount an intensified search for radio signals from civilizations that may exist on planets orbiting distant stars. Programs run by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and others have listened for intelligence-directed radio signals for more than 20 years, but only a small fraction of the vast universe and the many radio frequencies that must be monitored actually have been checked. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory, which is operated by the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>, has proposed expanding the effort with sophisticated new equipment that would listen to tens of millions of channels at the same time. The equipment would be monitoried by a computer capable of identifying signals that could be sent by intelligent life. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said the new equipment would be able to look at 1,000 different stars that are thought to be similar to the Earth's sun, locations that experts believe hold the best chance for the evolution of life. There also would be `` whole sky survey'' in many radio frequencies in which every portion of the heavens would be searched systematically. Searches in the past `` have only scratched the surface,'' said <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>. The new equipment would be 10 million times more thorough than present equipment, he said, noting, `` In the first few minutes, we would be able to match all of the searches that were done before.'' But even with the new devices, the job is immense, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> SETI </ORGANIZATION> committee of the astronomical union and an astronomer at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>. `` Many people think the project should succeed in the next year or two,'' he said. `` That's probably not going to happen. The universe is so huge and the cosmic haystack so large, it will take us decades.'' But <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> added: `` The consequences of success are so great that it's worth dealing with the problems.'' The theory behind the SETI work is that because there are billions of galaxies, each with billions of stars, the odds are good that the conditions that permitted life to evolve on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> also exist elsewhere. If so, then intelligent life could have developed along the same lines as it did here on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Civilizations that are equal to or more advanced than humankind would be sending out signals, just as occurs on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. The SETI project is looking for those signals. Such signals may `` leak out'' just as they do on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said. `` The strongest sign of our existence in the universe is the accumulation of our television signals,'' he said. The second most common radio signal from <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> comes from military communications. <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said the federal budget now under consideration by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> includes a $ 6 million appropriation for the enhanced <ORGANIZATION> SETI </ORGANIZATION> equipment. He said the total project would last 10 years and cost $ 90 million. If the funding were approved, the intensified search could begin in 1992, with all of the new equipment operating by 1994.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-RoyalMagic Bjt   08-09 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Royal Magic, Bjt,0697</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fanfare For New Princess Shows Monarchy Working Its Old Magic</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She's only fifth in line to the throne, but from the hospital crowds to the headlines, the birth of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s newest princess has shown the royal family working a magic that defies even the experts. `` I ca n't think why there's such hysterical interest really,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON>, editor of <PERSON> Debrett </PERSON>'s Peerage, which chronicles <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s blue bloods. `` But it just keeps increasing ... Maybe it's because there's been a leveling out of social classes _ which is very good, but at the same time does make for rather boring reading,'' <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> said in an interview `` And these characters are supposed to be a bit bigger than life, or we're led to believe they are,'' he added. And so they seemed Tuesday. Almost all of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s dozen national newspapers splashed across their front pages the Monday night birth of the Princess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON>'s second son, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, and his wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>. Radio and television networks led bulletins repeatedly with the news, edging out the cease-fire agreement in the Iran-Iraq war. Only the Communist Morning Star and the newest upscale newspaper, the 375,000-circulation Independent, ignored or paid little attention to the birth of the queen's fifth grandchild. `` We are not much interested in minor royals, but we did record the event,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, news editor of the Independent, which gave the story three lines on page 2. `` The Independent's view is that these people do n't matter.'' It was a lonely view. Compared with the attention given to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s other major surviving monarchies _ the Spanish, the Scandinavians, the Dutch and the Belgians _ <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> erupted with royal fever. The monarchs of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> attract plenty of attention among their Scandinavian subjects, but not much elsewhere. In the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, by the time former Queen <PERSON> Juliana </PERSON>'s youngest grandchild, also <PERSON> Juliana </PERSON>, was born in October 1981, interest in royal babies had cooled. The little <PERSON> Juliana </PERSON> was the ex-queen's 13th grandchild. In <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, the birth in 1982 of a third child, Princess <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON>, to King <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvia </PERSON>, dominated the local news but did not make world headlines. Royal babies not in direct line to the throne receive scant attention. Only one newspaper in <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> mentioned the birth in <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> last month of Norwegian King Olav's second great-grandchild. In <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, pictures of King <PERSON> Baudouin </PERSON> and Queen <PERSON> Fabiola </PERSON> seldom appear in then news. The heir to the throne, <PERSON> Baudouin </PERSON>'s nephew, Prince <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, keeps even further out of the limelight. In contrast, the royal family of the tiny principality of <LOCATION> Monaco </LOCATION> has the photographers in hot pursuit, particularly Princess <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON>, daughters of <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainier </PERSON> and the late <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>. But even for them, the scrutiny palls compared to the life of the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> monarch's children and their offspring. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks-Baker </PERSON>, publishing director of <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s Peerage, attributes the publicity given <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, partly to what he says has become an international hobby _ British royal-watching _ and partly to her unusual background for a royal bride. The former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> had no title, was a commoner, had two serious romances before <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON>, and pursued her career in a graphic arts company. He believes that historians will credit the former Miss <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> with `` taking the royal family into the 21st century.'' `` From the literally thousands of letters we get _ from Americans, Germans, Japanese _ wanting information about the royal family, it's clear that royal-watching has become as much a hobby as stamp-collecting,'' said <PERSON> Brooks-Baker </PERSON>. The birth of the Princess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> received more publicity in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> than did the birth in 1947 of Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, heir to the throne, he said. `` This interest in things royal is a great snowball ... interesting and also terrifying,'' said <PERSON> Brooks-Baker </PERSON>. `` As this soap opera becomes more and more universal, one wonders where it is going to end and whether it will crush the very people it is portraying. I do n't know.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-TiltingatPlatformPlanks Bjt   08-09 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tilting at Platform Planks, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weicker Battles Republican Majority in Platform Meetings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> sat alone as he delivered an impassioned plea to a Republican Platform panel, urging his <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> brethren to stand firm against apartheid in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` The regime in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is no better than the regime in <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the'30s,'' he said. `` That regime tried to do to the Jewish people what <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is doing to the blacks.'' <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, playing a role he perfected in 1984, is practically the sole dissenter in this week's platform deliberations. After <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>'s testimony, conservative activist <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> said, `` It looks like Mr. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> is doing his usual thing: going around making a lot of noise and not getting any votes.'' Alone among prominent Republicans, <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> has taken it upon himself to push for some moderate-to-liberal platform planks, positions that are almost certain not to emerge from the draft for next week's <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> platform. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> also has prepared platform proposals calling for support of the Equal Rights Amendment and an activist approach toward the AIDS crisis. He said he plans to press for adoption of the planks in drafting sessions later this week. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> is generally unpopular among the conservative activists who dominate the Republican platform process, and when his testimony ended, several subcommittee members unburdened themselves of several polite but insistent questions about his anti-apartheid stand. `` What about your call for support for front-line states of southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, including Marxist-run <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>?'' `` What further economic sanctions ... you said, an oil embargo, if necessary?'' While <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> was tilting at windmills, witnesses who gave presentations for the Strategic Defense Initiative, a continuation of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration economic policy and support for the Nicaraguan rebels received general and positive queries that enabled them to score easy points. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Ikle </PERSON>, former undersecretary of defense, testified that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should maintain a steady growth in the defense budget, continue its support for anti-communist rebels and work toward the deployment of SDI, the missile defense system known as Star Wars. The question to Ikle: `` What would have happened if the country had adopted <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' views seven years ago?'' Answer: `` We'd be in a period of crisis, rolling out the red carpet for Soviet expansion ... and have no Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces Treaty.'' <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, the former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, testified that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s Star Wars plan is a `` strategic master stroke,'' comparable to the `` <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Purchase </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Monroe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Doctrine </LOCATION> and the Apollo space program.'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>'s comments brought smiles to the faces of the subcommittee members. There were no questions. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> drew a few murmurs in the audience when he first compared <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, citing the government's policy of strict racial segregation of blacks When a panelist sought help to understand that view, <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> said: `` <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has done by law exactly what <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> did by law,'' he responded. His anti-apartheid plank would say: `` As the historical party of individual rights, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> rejects apartheid and seeks its abolition. We believe the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a moral responsibility to impose, in concert with other nations, further economic sanctions _ including an oil embargo, if necessary _ to bring this heinous practice to an end.'' <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> agreed with his questioners that an oil embargo and other economic sanctions probably would hurt the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> financially, but pleaded with the panel's sense of humanity. If that did n't work, there was <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>'s argument that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> needed a stronger presence on the African continent, especially in the face of Marxist-led countries such as <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>. And if that failed, there was always the comparison with the Democrats, who in their platform labeled <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a terrorist state. `` It should n't be a Democratic issue,'' <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> said, noting that a Republican-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed the initial economic sanctions against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> overrode <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto And as he stood up, ready to leave the conference room, <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> _ brandishing his Republicanism _ said defiantly, `` I'm not taking a back seat to the Democrats on any issue ... especially when they have a mealy-mouth platform.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Cassata </PERSON> is an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reporter covering the 1988 campaign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0147EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan     08-09 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Prods Congress To Move Faster On Welfare Reform</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has not moved quickly enough on welfare reform and urban renewal, and he told the nation's governors they've been `` way out front'' on many social issues. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, a former two-term governor of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, used a speech to the governors Monday to tout his `` New Federalism'' policy of shifting more responsibility for social programs away from the federal government and onto the states. Many governors, especially Democrats, have complained that the states can not absorb increasing cuts in federal aid while maintaining services for their citizens. During his speech at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s meeting in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> described his effort as one giving states a `` leadership role.'' `` We have broken the federal government of its compulsion to control every breath the states take,'' he said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, facing a host of last-minute issues on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> as lawmakers draw near a recess for the Republican National Convention, was playing host to Republican congressional leaders at the White House today. In his <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> speech, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> complained that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has not acted on legislation he submitted six years ago, proposing that the most depressed areas of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s cities receive tax breaks to encourage business investment. `` Despite some minor moves last year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> still has failed to pass meaningful enterprise zone legislation,'' he said. `` Not you. Over half the states have gone forward with their own enterprise zones.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also said the states have moved more quickly to get people off welfare rolls. `` Welfare reform is another field in which you have been way out front,'' he said. `` Congress today is still debating a welfare reform package _ years after states started taking advantage of the greater flexibility we gave them.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the federal government should not `` merely let the states toss ideas into a suggestion box,'' but that it should `` honor the leadership role the states have to play.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> won compliments from Republican Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, who said the president `` was talking language we understand.'' But Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> gave a political speech designed mainly to help Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the presidential election. The governor's association has said it wants its meeting to be non-partisan. <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> said, `` I think it was as political as he could be without stepping out of line.'' Earlier, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> toured a <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Precision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> plant, telling managers and employees he resents talk about the `` Rust Belt'' in the nation's <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>. `` I get a little tired of hearing <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> and other Midwestern cities called the ` Rust Belt' when the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> is n't the ` Rust Belt.' It's the ` Boom Belt.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TurtleSoup     08-09 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Turtle Soup,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Danish Film Rouses Friends of Turtle</HEAD>
<HEAD>By CARL HARTMAN</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Friends of the endangered sea turtle are upset because a prize-winning Danish film, `` <PERSON> Babette </PERSON>'s Feast,'' has turtle soup on the menu. They are investigating a report from a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> restaurant that it got some sea turtle meat from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> for use in a dinner to promote the film. `` There's a gelatinous substance called calipee under the shell of the sea turtle that's the basis for turtle soup,'' explained <PERSON> Marydele </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, director of the Sea Turtle Rescue Fund, in a telephone interview Monday. `` Actually, the turtle you see beating its flippers in the film seems to be a loggerhead, which is a different species that does n't have the calipee,'' she said `` But both are on the endangered species list and its illegal to catch them in this country.'' The film is based on a short story by Danish writer <PERSON> Isak </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinesen </PERSON>, pen name of the late <PERSON> Baroness </PERSON> <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Blixen-Finecke </PERSON>, who also wrote `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' `` <PERSON> Babette </PERSON>'s Feast'' tells of a Frenchwoman living on the coast of <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> who spends her lottery winnings on a big dinner for the villagers who have befriended her in her long exile. The Motion Picture Academy awarded it an Oscar as the best foreign film of the year. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane-Zucker </PERSON>, who is helping promote the film for <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Classics </ORGANIZATION>, said its food consultant has worked up substitute recipes using shitake mushrooms and chopped breast of duck. About 90 restaurants have been interested in reproducing the seven-course meal, he said. Ms. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> said some restaurants are using diamondback terrapin, which is not a sea turtle but is found in estuaries and considered endangered in some places. Ms. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> says 10,000 terrapin a year are sold in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> fish markets and the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Turtle </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Tortoise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> is trying to get it put on the state's endangered list Groceries sell a `` mock turtle soup,'' which she says is made from land turtles. They are not on anyone's endangered list, but she would prefer nobody ate turtle soup at all. `` Turtles in the Soup: Recipe for Disaster'' is the title of an article written by Ms. <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON> for the August issue of `` CEE Report,'' published by the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>. Meanwhile, sea turtles were n't faring well in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, where the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved legislation to bar the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration temporarily from carrying out a plan to require shrimp fishermen to use devices to protect the reptiles. Turtles often drown when snared in shrimp nets. The bill, sent to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by voice vote, would prohibit the mandatory use of so-called turtle excluder devices before Sept. 30, a month after excluder-device regulations were slated to take effect. The delay would give <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators time to work out differences in their versions of legislation to reauthorize the Endangered Species Act. Both bills would prohibit the required use of excluder devices in inshore waters until May 1990. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill also would ban device regulations for offshore waters until next May.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0130EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ThirdWorld-Corruption     08-09 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Third World-Corruption,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Bribery Reported Helping Third World</HEAD>
<HEAD>By CARL HARTMAN</HEAD>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some bribes can help Third World countries get ahead and can make a `` positive contribution to society,'' a politics professor writes in a magazine published by an affiliate of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON>, who teaches politics at <ORGANIZATION> Saint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rensselaer </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, argues that it is useful to a country if a government charges $ 1,000 for a license to enter an occupation but an official issues one for a bribe of $ 900. `` The reduced cost facilitates entry into the field, thereby introducing an element of competition into an otherwise monopolistic situation,'' he says in an article called `` Corruption and Development.'' <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON>'s article appears in the current issue of the quarterly `` Journal of Economic Growth,'' published by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. The foundation is a research affiliate of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, a private business organization. The trade bill now awaiting President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s signature will ease the effect of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act and make it easier for executives here to defend themselves when their agents are charged with paying bribes abroad. Osterfeld does n't defend all bribes, saying that some are `` wicked.'' `` For instance, the alleged involvement of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> ` s -LRB- military ruler Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in the drug trade is a case of corruption in all of its wickedness, where society is clearly hurt,'' he says. `` However, a Peruvian street vendor's bribing of a low-level government official in order to obtain a license to sell his wares, while also a corrupt act, makes a positive contribution to society,'' he wrote. <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON> says that even if the bribe is several times the size of the license fee _ as an Indian investigating committee found was often the case _ the bribe is still useful. `` -LRB- It -RRB- not only benefits the bureaucrat, but, more importantly, insures that the licenses are allocated efficiently, since those able to offer the highest bribes are the most productive and efficient firms,'' he adds. There was disagreement from <PERSON> Lilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferro-Clerico </PERSON>, a Uruguayan who coordinates <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and Central American studies for <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. `` That's pretty far-fetched,'' she said in a telephone interview. `` I do n't think corruption is ever helpful. You have a parallel here in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> scandal _ all the bribes did was to make it more expensive for the taxpayer.'' <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON> defends what he calls `` expansive corruption,'' which he says increases chances for trade that benefits a country. `` It entails increased competition and market flexibility,'' he says. `` The result is that the quantity of goods produced expands and their quality improves. It is, in short, characterized by the expansion of the overall wealth of society. `` -LRB- It -RRB- is morally defensible since its goal is to defend one's own property as well as one's right to engage in voluntary activities. As examples of `` expansive corruption'' he suggests: _ Evading price controls or tariffs by bribes to officials to permit smuggling or black marketing _ Bribes to evade licensing restrictions or controls on immigration and emigration Bribing a judge in cases of smuggling, occupational licenses, black marketing and price controls are called `` defensive bribing'' and <LOCATION> Osterfeld </LOCATION> classifies that as expansive as well. `` Even if society becomes demoralized or disillusioned by such corruption, the effects may not be an impediment to development ...,'' he adds. He explains that the cynicism may lead to increased self-seeking that furthers development. <PERSON> Osterfeld </PERSON> concludes that `` expansive corruption'' is a response to government restrictions on economic freedom. Those concerned about it, who want economic development, should concentrate on reducing government action that tempts corruption, he says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880809-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CubsLights 3rdLd-Writethru a0750 08-09 0871</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cubs Lights, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0750,0893</SECOND>
<HEAD>Neighbors Love, Hate First Night Game at Wrigley Field</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with game rained out, arrest
total. Picks up 7th graf pvs `I think...'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto CX17</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELIZABETH SHOGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
