<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-SovietEmigres     11-10 0416</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet Emigres,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Capacity To Absorb Soviet Emigres Strained</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> has been forced to suspend at least until January the processing of applications of Soviet refugees, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. In a sense, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is a victim of its own policy. Having insisted that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> allow people to leave, the embassy now finds that the flood of about 100 applications a day is exceeding financial and quota limits. Most of the refugees are Armenians, although a few are Jews. In another category, the level of Jews allowed to leave for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is now so high there may be a slowdown in processing those who apply in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> to go to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> instead, said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> called the Soviet response to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> emigration demands a `` welcome development.'' But, he said, it meant the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> processed six times as many refugees from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in fiscal year 1988, which ended Sept. 30, as in the previous year. A total of 16,500 Soviet refugees and immigrants are permitted to enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> each year _ 4,000 directly as refugees and 12,500 via <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. Among the refugees, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, there is a backlog of 1,700 cases, causing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> immigration officials to halt further interviews at least until January. `` In view of the situation,'' the spokesman said, `` the embassy is urging applicants not to make an irrevocable commitment or to cut their ties'' to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. At present, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, 1,500 applicants have been cleared and will leave for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> once they obtain airline tickets. The second category of immigrants facing a squeeze are Jews who go to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> with permits for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and then ask for admission to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. There were 2,400 applications in October, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said, `` and at this rate it may result in delays of processing, as well.'' While most of the immigrants who exit through <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> are Jews, <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said, a small percentage are not. But all of them have exit permits as Jews for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. This year's quota is squeezed by a need to process some 1,500 who were stranded last summer in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> by an upsurge in Soviet permits. Last year, 20,421 immigrants reached the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, about 9,400 of them Jews.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Latin-Nuclear     11-10 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Latin-Nuclear,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Asks Banks To Prod Latin America To Forgo Nuclear Weapons</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An anti-nuclear group on Thursday urged three major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> banks with large loans to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> to use their influence to dissuade those two nations from developing nuclear weapons. `` In no area of the world is the issue of nuclear proliferation more uncertain than in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Stone, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientists </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 5,000 scientists seeking to end the nuclear arms race. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said he made the plea in the form of a shareholders' resolution that federation members who hold bank stock had submitted to <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Hanover </LOCATION> He said those banks have loans totalling $ 10 billion to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. The resolution urged each bank `` to commend the two countries for their declared policy of using nuclear power only for peaceful purposes'' and `` to convey to suitable Brazilian and Argentine officials its view that nuclear explosives, and a nuclear arms race, in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> would complicate the bank's ability to sustain its financial links to that region.'' Neither <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> nor <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> is believed to have nuclear weapons. But both are developing nuclear plants that when fully operational could produce nuclear weapons material, according to a statement released by the federation. Both nations have recently gone from military to civilian rule, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> in 1983 and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> in 1985, a transition which in the view of nuclear proliferation expert <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> has decreased their inclination to develop nuclear weapons. <PERSON> Spector </PERSON>, a scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, wrote in his 1987 book, `` Going Nuclear,'' that <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> are the only nations in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> `` with programs that might lead to the development of a nuclear deterrent.'' `` Since the summer of 1987, the leaders of each country have visited classified nuclear installations of the other, developments which in this field are unprecedented confidence-building steps,'' <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> said in an interview. But the political climate could change, said <PERSON> Spector </PERSON>, and the nuclear programs in the two countries `` are reaching a point where dangerous ambiguities are going to arise, creating suspicions in both countries that the other is moving to acquire nuclear weapons.'' `` What we need to do is encourage positive political steps to slow down the technological trends,'' he said. Argentinta and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> have refused to sign binding non-proliferation pledges under the 1968 Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, which has been ratified by over 130 governments. A spokesman for Manufacturers' Hanover Trust, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, said bank had loans of $ 1.4 billion to <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and $ 2 billion to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>. He said the bank had received the resolution and would respond, but had no immediate public comment. Spokesmen for <ORGANIZATION> Citicorp </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> could not immediately be reached for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths CORRECTION a1449 11-10 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, CORRECTION, a1449,0190</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: CORRECTS Mitchell's middle intial to N. sted M. in 1st graf
of
1st item.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, former attorney general who authorized the Watergate break-in and then went to prison for conspiring to cover-up the burglary, died Wednesday of a heart attack. He was 75. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, the first former attorney general to be convicted of a crime, served a 19-month prison term for his role in the Watergate cover-up. He was convicted along with President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s chief of staff H.R <PERSON> Haldeman </PERSON> and the president's domestic counselor, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ehrlichman </PERSON>, who also served 1 -LCB- years in prison. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, who was known for his credo that `` when the going gets tough, the tough get going,'' was <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s closest adviser. He was <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s law partner and mentor, then ran his 1968 and 1972 election campaigns. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> was indicted March 1, 1974, and was convicted of one count of conspiracy, obstruction of justice, two counts false statements to a grand jury and one count of perjury. He began a 2 -LCB- - to-8-year term at <ORGANIZATION> Maxwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> on June 22, 1977
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LewisCarroll     11-10 0221</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lewis Carroll,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Photographs by Author Auctioned</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A collection of photographs by 19th century children's writer and mathematician <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, most of them of a female child model, has fetched $ 55,780 at auction, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> auctioneers said. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, whose real name was <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lutwidge </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodgson </PERSON>, was an enthusiastic photographer who wrote the classic children's stories `` <PERSON> Alice </PERSON>'s Adventures in Wonderland'' and `` Through the Looking Glass.'' Most of the 61 prints and 27 negatives sold Wednesday are of a family friend, child model <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Kitchin </PERSON>, between the ages of five and 16. She was known as `` Xie'' by her family, and her godmother was Queen <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON>. One of the bidders was <PERSON> Xie </PERSON>'s great-granddaughter, <PERSON> Deryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowdy </PERSON>, a 26-year-old artist who paid $ 268 for a photograph of <PERSON> Xie </PERSON> at the age of 12 in July 1876. The collection, which had been expected to sell for about $ 80,000, came on the market after a family disagreement over ownership, said Miss Cowdyy. `` There was a huge family row about who they belonged to, so they finally went to the family's solicitors -LRB- lawyers -RRB-,'' she said. `` Because they could n't agree, it was decided to sell them and divide the money between <PERSON> Xie </PERSON>'s 16 grandchildren. It's a bit sad, really.'' The Musee D'Orsay in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> bought several photographs to add to its existing collection of <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>'s photographs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SauerkrautRecall     11-10 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sauerkraut Recall,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Claussen Recalls Sauerkraut Because Of Broken Glass</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WOODSTOCK, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Claussen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> announced Wednesday a recall of certain jars of sauerkraut because pieces of glass were found in eight containers in three states, officials said. Woodstock-based <PERSON> Claussen </PERSON> asked consumers to return all 32-ounce jars of sauerkraut labled `` Use by Feb. 18, 89'' and `` Use by Feb. 19, 89'' to the stores where they were purchased, said company spokesman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Aehl </PERSON>. <PERSON> Claussen </PERSON> produced 63,000 jars bearing the two dates. Consumers in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, found glass in three jars over the weekend, he said. There were no reports of injuries. `` We searched store supplies in those areas and discovered five other jars that had glass in the sauerkraut,'' <PERSON> Aehl </PERSON> said. `` That's when we decided to recall the product. The size of the glass fragments ranged from slivers to 1 -LCB- - inch-long pieces, he said Company officials were trying to determine how the glass got into the sauerkraut, he said, `` We believe it happened during ther manufacturing of the product. There's no evidence of tampering. It appears to be broken jars where a little glass got into the product.'' The company set up a toll-free telephone number for consumers to call if they have questions. The number is 1-800-322-1421 and people can call between 7 a.m. and 11 p.m. EST.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TaxiStrike     11-10 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Taxi Strike,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Athens Police Clash With Striking Taxi Drivers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Riot squads fired tear gas to disperse more than 1,000 taxi drivers who blocked a central city square to protest anti-pollution measures that restrict their movement. Two taxi drivers were arrested during the clashes Wednesday outside parliament in Constitution square, a police official said. The cabbies blocked traffic with more than 500 taxis, and clashes broke out when police started towing the parked yellow cabs. The city's 17,000 cabbies began a four-day strike Tuesday to protest anti-pollution measures restricting taxi circulation on weekdays in a five-square-mile zone around the city center. The restrictions work according to odd and even license plate numbers. The cabbies claim 50 percent of their fares are generated in the city center. The average taxi driver takes home about $ 400 a month. A brown colored smog, known to Athenians as the Nefos _ or cloud _ forms over the city on warm, windless days. Cars, diesel-powered taxis and the city's aging buses are blamed for most of the pollution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Casey     11-10 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Casey,0187</SECOND>
<HEAD>Co-Author of `Grease' Dies At 53</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, a lyricist and author who helped write the hit musical `` Grease,'' died after a 10-month battle with AIDS. He was 53. <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, who died Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, had battled acquired immune deficiency syndrome since February but continued composing music, said his companion, <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> was best known as a collaborator with <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in `` Grease,'' a joyous look at high school in the 1950s. The musical, which appeared on Broadway, later was the basis for a movie of the same name. `` In many ways, ` Grease' typified the energy and spirit of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> theater way before what we now refer to as the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> Theater Movement,'' said <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Zacek </PERSON>, artistic director of the Victory Gardens Theater, which included <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> on its original artistic board. A native of <LOCATION> Yonkers </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> earned a degree in fine arts at <ORGANIZATION> Syracuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and later taught in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> high schools. He came to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in the 1960s and met <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> while acting with the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Mayor-Skunk     11-10 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mayor-Skunk,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Recalled By One Vote After Skunk Controversy</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FEDERAL HEIGHTS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 81-year-old mayor of this <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> suburb has been recalled from office by a single vote in an election in which his wife was not able to vote. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON>, who had been mayor 13 years and lost Tuesday's election 896-895, was blamed for cuts to a skunk-control program The fuss started earlier this year when <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> voted to end the suburb's skunk removal program in a cost-cutting effort. Officials said it costs $ 87 per skunk to catch the animals and remove them to <LOCATION> Adams </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where they were delivered to a disposal company. <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> was blamed for cuts in the program, and although skunk removal was restored, he was made the target of the recall. City Councilman <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> won the race to replace <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> as mayor. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> was recalled from the council in 1983 and failed in the last two elections to regain his seat. <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said his wife, <PERSON> Hazel </PERSON>, was n't able to vote because she was hospitalized. `` If she could have voted, it would have been tied and I would have stayed in,'' <PERSON> Bauer </PERSON> said Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-Pres-Sum     11-10 0128</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Pres-Sum,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 16:35,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This is the final table of this type, the vote count is
complete for the day.
   
^By The Associated Press</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest nationwide election returns in the race for President with 99 percent of the nation's precincts reporting.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Dukakis 41,016,429 - 46 percent</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Has won 10 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> with 112 ev. Leads in 0 state with 0 ev.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Bush 47,946,422 - 54 percent</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Has won 40 states with 426 ev. Leads in 0 state with 0 ev.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Needed to win: 270 of the 538 electoral votes -LRB- ev -RRB- from the 50 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. Percentages may not total 100 percent because of additional candidates on the ballot in some states.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-Pres-All     11-10 1033</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Pres-All,1290</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 16:35,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This is the final table of this type, the vote count is
complete for the day</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the results of Tuesday's Presidential elections for each state.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALABAMA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 9 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 547,347 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 809,663 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ALASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 97 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 62,205 - 38 percent x-Bush, GOP 102,381 - 62 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ARIZONA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 7 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 447,272 - 39 percent x-Bush, GOP 694,379 - 61 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ARKANSAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 6 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 344,991 - 43 percent x-Bush, GOP 463,574 - 57 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CALIFORNIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 47 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 4,448,393 - 48 percent x-Bush, GOP 4,756,490 - 52 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>COLORADO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 8 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 621,093 - 46 percent x-Bush, GOP 727,633 - 54 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 8 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 674,873 - 47 percent x-Bush, GOP 747,082 - 53 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 97 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 99,479 - 43 percent x-Bush, GOP 130,581 - 57 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 153,100 - 86 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 25,732 - 14 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FLORIDA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 21 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 1,632,086 - 39 percent x-Bush, GOP 2,538,994 - 61 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>GEORGIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 12 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 715,635 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,070,089 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>HAWAII</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 192,364 - 55 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 158,625 - 45 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IDAHO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 147,420 - 37 percent x-Bush, GOP 253,467 - 63 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ILLINOIS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 24 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 2,180,657 - 49 percent x-Bush, GOP 2,298,648 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 12 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 850,851 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,280,292 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>IOWA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 8 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 667,085 - 55 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 541,540 - 45 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KANSAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 7 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 422,056 - 43 percent x-Bush, GOP 552,659 - 57 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>KENTUCKY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 9 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 579,077 - 44 percent x-Bush, GOP 731,446 - 56 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>LOUISIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 10 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 715,612 - 45 percent x-Bush, GOP 880,830 - 55 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MAINE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 240,508 - 44 percent x-Bush, GOP 304,087 - 56 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MARYLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 10 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 793,939 - 49 percent x-Bush, GOP 834,202 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 13 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 1,387,398 - 54 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 1,184,323 - 46 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MICHIGAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 20 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 1,673,496 - 46 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,969,435 - 54 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MINNESOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 10 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 1,106,975 - 54 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 958,199 - 46 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSISSIPPI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 7 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 360,892 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 551,745 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSOURI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 11 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 1,004,040 - 48 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,081,163 - 52 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MONTANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 168,120 - 47 percent x-Bush, GOP 189,598 - 53 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 5 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 254,426 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 389,394 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEVADA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 132,716 - 38 percent x-Bush, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 205,942 - 60 percent None of the Above, Oth 6,932 - 2 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW HAMPSHIRE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 162,335 - 37 percent x-Bush, GOP 279,770 - 63 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 16 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 1,275,063 - 43 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,699,634 - 57 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW MEXICO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 5 97 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 236,528 - 48 percent x-Bush, GOP 260,792 - 52 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 36 99 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 3,228,304 - 52 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 2,975,276 - 48 percent <PERSON> Marra </PERSON>, Oth 22,144 - 0 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH CAROLINA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 13 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 890,034 - 42 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,232,132 - 58 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 127,081 - 43 percent x-Bush, GOP 165,517 - 57 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 23 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 1,934,922 - 45 percent x-Bush, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 2,411,719 - 55 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OKLAHOMA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 8 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 483,373 - 42 percent x-Bush, GOP 678,244 - 58 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OREGON</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 7 99 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 575,071 - 53 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 517,731 - 47 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 25 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 2,183,928 - 49 percent x-Bush, GOP 2,291,297 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 4 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 216,668 - 56 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 169,730 - 44 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUT CAROLINA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 8 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 367,511 - 38 percent x-Bush, GOP 599,871 - 62 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 145,632 - 47 percent x-Bush, GOP 165,516 - 53 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TENNESSEE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 11 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 677,715 - 42 percent x-Bush, GOP 939,434 - 58 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TEXAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 29 99 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 2,331,286 - 44 percent x-Bush, GOP 3,014,007 - 56 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>UTAH</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 5 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 206,853 - 33 percent x-Bush, GOP 426,858 - 67 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VERMONT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 116,419 - 49 percent x-Bush, GOP 123,166 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 12 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 860,767 - 40 percent x-Bush, GOP 1,305,131 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 10 99 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 844,554 - 51 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 800,182 - 49 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 6 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 339,112 - 52 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 307,824 - 48 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WISCONSIN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 11 100 percent x-Dukakis, Dem 1,122,090 - 52 percent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, GOP 1,043,584 - 48 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WYOMING</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Electoral Vote: 3 100 percent <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, Dem 67,077 - 39 percent x-Bush, GOP 106,814 - 61 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0427EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-Senate-All     11-10 0643</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Senate-All,0779</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 16:36,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This is the final table of this type, the vote count is
complete for the day</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest returns in the races for <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>ARIZONA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-DeConcini, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 651,164 - 58 percent DeGreen, GOP 472,776 - 42 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CALIFORNIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, Dem 4,060,259 - 46 percent x-Wilson, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 4,835,014 - 54 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>CONNECTICUT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Dem Gain x-Lieberman, Dem 686,018 - 50 percent <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 675,225 - 50
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 97 percent Woo, Dem 84,806 - 38 percent x-Roth, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 140,827 - 62 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>FLORIDA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open MacKay, Dem 1,977,824 - 50 percent <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, GOP 1,982,760 - 50
</TEXT>
<HEAD>HAWAII</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Matsunaga, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 247,941 - 79 percent <PERSON> Hustace </PERSON>, GOP 66,987 - 21 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent <ORGANIZATION> Wickes </ORGANIZATION>, Dem 672,551 - 32 percent x-Lugar, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 1,411,945 - 68 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MAINE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Mitchell, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 446,520 - 81 percent <PERSON> Wyman </PERSON>, GOP 104,009 - 19 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MARYLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Sarbanes, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 953,168 - 62 percent <PERSON> Keyes </PERSON>, GOP 588,519 - 38 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MASSACHUSETTS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Kennedy, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 1,676,437 - 66 percent <PERSON> Malone </PERSON>, GOP 877,643 - 34 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MICHIGAN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Riegle, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 2,107,032 - 61 percent <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON>, GOP 1,346,103 - 39 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MINNESOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, Dem 853,004 - 41 percent x-Durenberger, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 1,171,678 - 57 percent <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, Oth 44,170 - 2 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSISSIPPI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent - Open-GOP Gain Dowdy, Dem 431,048 - 47 percent x-Lott, GOP 487,238 - 53
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSOURI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, Dem 660,099 - 32 percent x-Danforth, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 1,412,146 - 68 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MONTANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - GOP Gain <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 175,003 - 48 percent x-Burns, GOP 189,074 - 52
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEBRASKA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Dem Gain x-Kerrey, Dem 371,382 - 57 percent <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 272,449 - 42 percent Chambers, Oth 10,023 - 2
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEVADA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Dem Gain x-Bryan, Dem 175,508 - 51 percent <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 161,273 - 47 percent None of the Above, Oth 7,237 - 2
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW JERSEY</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Lautenberg, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 1,552,805 - 54 percent <PERSON> Dawkins </PERSON>, GOP 1,303,907 - 46 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW MEXICO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 97 percent x-Bingaman, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 309,819 - 63 percent Valentine, GOP 180,044 - 37 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Moynihan, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 3,891,767 - 67 percent <PERSON> McMillan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 1,828,291 - 32 percent <PERSON> Nathanson </PERSON>, Oth 63,447 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Burdick, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 171,557 - 60 percent <PERSON> Strinden </PERSON>, GOP 112,186 - 40 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>OHIO</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Metzenbaum, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 2,473,816 - 57 percent <PERSON> Voinovich </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 1,870,359 - 43 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent <PERSON> Vignola </PERSON>, Dem 1,409,790 - 33 percent x-Heinz III, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 2,892,417 - 67 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent Licht, Dem 174,498 - 46 percent x-Chafee, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 207,443 - 54 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TENNESSEE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Sasser, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 1,021,080 - 66 percent <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON>, GOP 535,067 - 34 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TEXAS</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Bentsen, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 3,120,348 - 60 percent <PERSON> Boulter </PERSON>, GOP 2,111,765 - 40 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>UTAH</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>, Dem 202,873 - 32 percent x-Hatch, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 428,001 - 68 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VERMONT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open Gray, Dem 71,511 - 31 percent x-Jeffords, GOP 162,265 - 69
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open-Dem Gain x-Robb, Dem 1,474,443 - 71 percent <PERSON> Dawkins </PERSON>, GOP 594,252 - 29
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent - <PERSON> Open </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON>, Dem 814,873 - 49 percent x-Gorton, GOP 840,017 - 51
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Byrd, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 408,693 - 65 percent <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON>, GOP 221,911 - 35 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WISCONSIN</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open x-Kohl, Dem 1,122,019 - 52 percent <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON>, GOP 1,026,942 - 48
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WYOMING</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Vinich </PERSON>, Dem 89,788 - 50 percent x-Wallop, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 91,053 - 50 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0427EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-Gov-All     11-10 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Gov-All,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 16:36,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This is the final table of this type, the vote count is
complete for the day</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the latest returns in the races for Governor.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>DELAWARE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 97 percent <PERSON> Kreshtool </PERSON>, Dem 64,312 - 29 percent x-Castle, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 158,156 - 71 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>INDIANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent - Open-Dem Gain x-Bayh, Dem 1,126,197 - 53 percent <PERSON> Mutz </PERSON>, GOP 997,210 - 47
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MISSOURI</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent <PERSON> Hearnes </PERSON>, Dem 724,734 - 35 percent x-Ashcroft, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 1,338,031 - 65 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MONTANA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open-GOP Gain Judge, Dem 168,537 - 47 percent x-Stephens, GOP 189,630 - 53
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NEW HAMPSHIRE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Open <PERSON> McEachern </PERSON>, Dem 170,884 - 39 percent x-Gregg, GOP 264,669 - 61
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH CAROLINA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, Dem 954,293 - 44 percent x-Martin, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 1,217,775 - 56 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>NORTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Sinner, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 178,073 - 60 percent <PERSON> Mallberg </PERSON>, GOP 119,387 - 40 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Sundlun </PERSON>, Dem 189,274 - 49 percent x-DiPrete, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 195,634 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>UTAH</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, Dem 247,713 - 38 percent x-Bangerter, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 259,339 - 40 percent <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, Oth 136,400 - 21 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>VERMONT</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent x-Kunin, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 134,579 - 56 percent <PERSON> Bernhardt </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 104,897 - 43 percent <PERSON> Gottlieb </PERSON>, Oth 2,800 - 1 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 99 percent x-Gardner, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 1,055,467 - 63 percent <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, GOP 628,006 - 37 percent
</TEXT>
<HEAD>WEST VIRGINIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 100 percent - Dem Gain x-Caperton, Dem 381,292 - 59 percent <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 265,444 - 41
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0500EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-House-All 1stAdd   11-10 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-House-All, 1st Add,1043</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 16:36,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This take covers California</NOTE>
<HEAD>UNDATED:</HEAD>
<HEAD>CALIFORNIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 District 1 -- 100 percent x-Bosco, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 150,714 - 69 percent <ORGANIZATION> Vanderbilt </ORGANIZATION>, GOP 67,507 - 31 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 2 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, Dem 88,702 - 40 percent x-Herger, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 133,867 - 60 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 3 -- 100 percent x-Matsui, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 175,112 - 71 percent <PERSON> Landowski </PERSON>, GOP 70,723 - 29 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 4 x-Fazio, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- Uncontested
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 5 -- 100 percent x-Pelosi, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 113,838 - 81 percent <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, GOP 26,303 - 19 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 6 -- 100 percent x-Boxer, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 160,805 - 74 percent <PERSON> Steinmetz </PERSON>, GOP 57,044 - 26 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 7 -- 100 percent x-Miller, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 158,451 - 69 percent Last, GOP 71,631 - 31 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 8 -- 100 percent x-Dellums, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 152,380 - 69 percent <PERSON> Cuddihy </PERSON>, GOP 69,412 - 31 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 9 -- 100 percent x-Stark, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 145,917 - 73 percent <ORGANIZATION> Hertz </ORGANIZATION>, GOP 53,797 - 27 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 10 -- 100 percent x-Edwards, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 132,732 - 86 percent <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, Oth 21,225 - 14 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 11 -- 100 percent x-Lantos, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 138,579 - 75 percent <PERSON> Quraishi </PERSON>, GOP 47,032 - 25 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 12 -- 100 percent - Open <PERSON> Eshoo </PERSON>, Dem 112,442 - 48 percent x-Campbell, GOP 124,151 - 52
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 13 -- 100 percent x-Mineta, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 132,802 - 69 percent <PERSON> Sommer </PERSON>, GOP 58,706 - 31 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 14 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Malberg </PERSON>, Dem 100,577 - 37 percent x-Shumway, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 167,716 - 63 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 15 -- 100 percent x-Coelho, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 111,771 - 71 percent <PERSON> Harner </PERSON>, GOP 45,479 - 29 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 16 -- 100 percent x-Panetta, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 168,506 - 79 percent <PERSON> Monteith </PERSON>, GOP 45,711 - 21 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 17 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Lavery </PERSON>, Dem 49,345 - 29 percent x-Pashayan, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 122,253 - 71 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 18 -- 100 percent x-Lehman, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 120,435 - 70 percent <PERSON> Linn </PERSON>, GOP 51,798 - 30 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 19 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, Dem 105,981 - 49 percent x-Lagomarsino, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 108,257 - 51 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 20 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, Dem 59,454 - 28 percent x-Thomas, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 155,282 - 72 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 21 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, Dem 72,059 - 30 percent x-Gallegly, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 171,073 - 70 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 22 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, Dem 58,904 - 27 percent x-Moorhead, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 155,966 - 73 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 23 -- 100 percent x-Beilenson, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 140,189 - 66 percent <PERSON> Salomon </PERSON>, GOP 72,888 - 34 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 24 -- 100 percent x-Waxman, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 106,828 - 75 percent <PERSON> Cowles </PERSON>, GOP 34,723 - 25 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 25 -- 100 percent x-Roybal, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 80,425 - 85 percent Thie, Oth 5,385 - 6 percent <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON>, Oth 8,300 - 9 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 26 -- 100 percent x-Berman, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 121,404 - 70 percent <PERSON> Broderson </PERSON>, GOP 50,821 - 30 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 27 -- 100 percent x-Levine, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 141,396 - 70 percent <PERSON> Galbraith </PERSON>, GOP 61,737 - 30 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 28 -- 100 percent x-Dixon, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 104,920 - 80 percent <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 26,944 - 20 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 29 -- 100 percent x-Hawkins, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 85,338 - 86 percent <PERSON> Franco </PERSON>, GOP 13,828 - 14 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 30 -- 100 percent x-Martinez, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 69,065 - 62 percent <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, GOP 41,558 - 38 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 31 -- 100 percent x-Dymally, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 97,518 - 74 percent May, GOP 34,435 - 26 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 32 -- 100 percent x-Anderson, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 109,068 - 69 percent <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>, GOP 47,981 - 31 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 33 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Gentry </PERSON>, Dem 55,519 - 28 percent x-Dreier, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 145,071 - 72 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 34 -- 100 percent x-Torres, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 88,103 - 64 percent <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, GOP 48,641 - 36 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 35 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Sweeney </PERSON>, Dem 69,335 - 28 percent x-Lewis, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 175,873 - 72 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 36 -- 100 percent <PERSON> x-Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 100,559 - 56 percent Stark, GOP 78,737 - 44 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 37 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON>, Dem 85,333 - 34 percent x-McCandless, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 163,698 - 66 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 38 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Yudelson </PERSON>, Dem 49,421 - 37 percent x-Dornan, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 83,063 - 63 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 39 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Marquis </PERSON>, Dem 49,895 - 24 percent x-Dannemeyer, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 161,568 - 76 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 40 -- 100 percent - <PERSON> Open </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenney </PERSON>, Dem 76,367 - 31 percent x-Cox, GOP 170,640 - 69
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 41 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Kripke </PERSON>, Dem 81,836 - 32 percent x-Lowery, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 172,831 - 68 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 42 -- 100 percent - <PERSON> Open </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimbrough </PERSON>, Dem 74,745 - 34 percent x-Rohrabacher, GOP 144,017 - 66
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 43 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Greenebaum </PERSON>, Dem 67,951 - 26 percent x-Packard, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 188,826 - 74 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 44 -- 100 percent x-Bates, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 85,315 - 62 percent <PERSON> Butterfield </PERSON>, GOP 51,646 - 38 percent
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 District 45 -- 100 percent <PERSON> Lepiscopo </PERSON>, Dem 50,414 - 25 percent x-Hunter, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 154,132 - 75 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-NewTenants     11-10 0438</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-New Tenants,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagans Welcome Next White House Occupants</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hand-in-hand, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife walked down the little path that leads from the Oval Office to the south drive to greet the next occupants of the White House. `` We'll sign over the lease later,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told reporters The long black limousine bringing Vice President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from Andrews Air Force Base stopped at the foot of the walk and the first one out was Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, the vice president-elect, who had been riding in the jump seat. Often in American history, when outgoing and incoming president meet at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the atmosphere is strained and the words stilted. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had gone all out to get his vice president elected and on Wednesday, when they gathered for the first time since the election, all was cheer. `` There he is,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> when he spotted the president. `` Thank you so much.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and their wives, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> shook hands all around and walked into the Oval Office for less than five minutes of transition talk. `` Do you like the looks of the place?'' shouted a reporter. `` Beautiful day,'' said the vice president-elect. `` Look good to you?'' `` Beautiful day.'' Later, speaking to a few hundred supporters in the Rose Garden, with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at his side, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I do n't believe there's a case in modern presidential politics of a president who's worked so hard to help someone else achieve this office and I will always be grateful.'' And <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>: `` If anyone wants to know how <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> and I feel about this moment, just read our smiles.'' He then mentioned that he figures it's only 1,188 days until the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucus. In the mellowness of the moment, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> praised the Democrats who ran against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. `` I want to congratulate both of you, as well as Governor -LRB- <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Senator -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, in taking on the great challenge, and your sense of public duty in seeing it through to the end.'' `` Each of you is better for it, and so is the country,'' said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. As for the new administration: `` You ai n't seen nothing yet.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was the last to take the microphone. `` Thank you for all you have done for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he told <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. And to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: `` Yesterday, the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people overwhelmingly placed their trust and their confidence in your leadership, and I'm delighted to be part of that team and ready to go to work and change <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and make it even greater.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Dukakis Bjt   11-10 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dukakis, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>With The Quest For The Oval Office Over, Dukakis Returns To Corner
Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was back tending to <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> duties a day after losing his bid for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, promising to be <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' `` very best governor'' and warning that the negative tone of this year's campaign set a dangerous precedent for coming races. `` I gave it my best shot,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said Wednesday after spending several hours catching up on state business. `` Almost does n't count in politics.'' He said he felt no bitterness toward <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and was ready to put the campaign behind him and complete the final two years of his term as governor. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> gave no indication whether he will run for a fourth term in 1990 or seek the presidency again in four years. `` At this point my job is clear: I'm going to be the very best governor of this commonwealth that I can be,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> told reporters. `` There's a lot to do. There are many challenges out there ahead. What happens in the future remains to be seen.'' Among those challenges will be re-establishing relations with his state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> amid growing rumbling about the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> administration's handling of a revenue shortfall that has forced <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to borrow to pay its bills. Although it is dominated by Democrats, the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> has scheduled hearings next week to look into state finances, and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> could come under fire from lawmakers unhappy that the governor was out of state for much of the past year as the problem unfolded. At the same time <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said he expected to remain a player in national <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> politics _ including having a say in the selection of a new party chairman. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wasted no time getting back to work, arriving at the office at 9:30 a.m. to applause from about 50 state workers. Later in the day he met with reporters to reflect on the campaign, which he said left President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> without a mandate and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with lasting grass-roots and fund-raising organizations despite his loss. `` I'm not a bitter person,'' a weary <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` I look forward. I'm fundamentally an optimist and somebody who believes deeply in this country and its people. `` Am I disappointed, sure I am,'' he said, laying at least part of the blame for his loss on the tone of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. `` It was a distorted campaign,'' the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor said. `` It was a campaign that distorted my record and I think did not set high standards for the kind of campaign we want for the presidency and it may well set a standard we live to regret.'' National Democratic leaders were unhappy with the insular management of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> effort, yet <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> trumpeted himself as someone who would keep a high profile within his party. `` I'll be in the thick of the fight to make sure that we respond to the real concerns of the people of this coutnry,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said. `` I personally will continue to do whatever I can, with my fellow governors, the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, with the new administration, here in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, to make sure that we respond and that we respond strongly and well to those concerns and those challenges which face the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people every day.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also had a bit of advice for future candidates. `` I think one of the lessons of the campaign is that you have to respond and you have to respond quickly,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, who largely ignored unrelenting <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> attacks _ and advisers urging him to respond _ until late in the campaign. But he had no substantive answer to the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s dilemma; while it has great success in local, state and congressional races it has had only one successful presidential candidate in the last 20 years <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also offered a few jokes before saying good-bye to the large national press corps that traveled with him. `` I believe in the redemption of souls,'' he deadpanned when asked about the appointment of <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who managed the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> so frequently criticized, as secretary of state. He drew laughter again when asked why he did n't campaign throughout the race as furiously as he did in the final three days, when he stumped virtually non-stop without sleep. `` If I had more time, you'd all be in the hospital,'' he said with a grin. `` I would n't have done that to you guys, I think too much of you.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-TheFormerFour     11-10 0466</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Former Four,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Field Of Former Presidents To Be Crowded Again</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants advice from former presidents, he is likely to have more of them to call upon than any president since <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>. For the first time since <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON> died on July 24, 1862, there are expected to be four living ex-presidents after Inauguration Day on Jan. 20. This, of course, assumes that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the three former presidents now living - <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> - survive to see <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sworn in. All of them are believed to be in good health. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is the oldest, at 77. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> are 75 and <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, 64. There have only been four times in American history when as many as four former presidents were living - during the administrations of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON> <PERSON> Polk </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>. Actually, when <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> moved into the White House in March of 1861, there were five of his predecessors still around. In addition to <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>, whom he succeeded, they were <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON>, <PERSON> Millard </PERSON> <PERSON> Fillmore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> died in January 1862, and <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON> died six months later. Five times in history there have been no former presidents alive, most recently for the last year and a half of the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration, after <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> died in January 1973. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON> of course could not call on one of his predecessors for advice, because he did n't have any. As for his successor, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> died in December 1979, midway through the <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> administration. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and his three successors, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Jefferson </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Madison </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, all survived into the administration of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' son, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> The elder <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> was the longest lived of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> presidents, dying at 91. The younger <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON> all lived into the <LOCATION> Polk </LOCATION> administration of the 1840s. <PERSON> Polk </PERSON> died at 53, shortly after leaving office, but <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>, <PERSON> Tyler </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fillmore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> all lived into and through <PERSON> Buchanan </PERSON>'s term as president Fillmore and <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, along with <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, were living when <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> took office in 1869, but all had died by the time <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> left the White House in 1877. The next time the nation was left without a living ex-president was during the last two months of the <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> administration, following the death of <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> in January 1933. <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> was the only living president throughout the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> tenure of <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. Both <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> named <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> to head commissions to reorganize the executive branch of government. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has met privately with <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> several times during his administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-House-Winners 1stAdd   11-10 0261</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-House-Winners, 1st Add,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 14:05,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This take covers California</NOTE>
<HEAD>UNDATED:</HEAD>
<HEAD>CALIFORNIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 2: <PERSON> Wally </PERSON> <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 3: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 4: <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 5: <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 6: <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 7: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 8: <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 9: <PERSON> Fortney </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 10: <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 11: <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 12: <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, GOP 13: <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 14: <PERSON> Norm </PERSON> <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 15: <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 16: <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 17: <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 18: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehman </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 19: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 20: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 21: <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 22: <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 23: <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 24: <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 25: <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 26: <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 27: <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 28: <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 29: <PERSON> Augustus </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 30: <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 31: <PERSON> Mervyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 32: <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 33: <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 34: <PERSON> Esteban </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 35: <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 36: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 37: <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 38: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 39: <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 40: <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 41: <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 42: <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 43: <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Packard </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 44: <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 45: <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0429EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Quayle     11-10 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Quayle,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Welcomes Bush Back to Washington; Starts Transition Work</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice president-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is getting ready to settle into his new job in January, while his wife apparently is mulling what to do if offered her husband's vacant <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat. As Sen. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, R-Ind., headed toward his transition headquarters near the White House Wednesday, Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> was asked by reporters if she was interested in succeeding her husband `` You'll have to ask the governor,'' she replied. `` That's an answer I'll give him. You'll be the second to know.'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has refused to say when he would officially notify <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> of his resignation from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. He has signaled several times in recent days that he would submit his resignation before <PERSON> Orr </PERSON>'s term ends in January so that the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> governor, rather than Democratic Gov.-elect <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayh </PERSON>, can appoint someone to fill the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> also said he had no specific timetable for making staff appointments and said his tour of the four-story, white-brick townhouse off <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> was aimed at `` assembling thoughts, conversing with people, nothing specific.'' `` When we have specific things, believe me, you'll be the first to know,'' the senator said, a day after he and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> scored a lopsided electoral triumph over Democrats <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> had no public events on his schedule today, and aides said he would continue to make telephone calls and contacts as he works on the transition. There has been widespread speculation that <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a licensed lawyer in addition to being a housewife, is among those under consideration to take her husband's <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat. Among other names mentioned in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Republican political circles are Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hudnut </PERSON>, and possibly Lt. Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mutz </PERSON>, who lost to <PERSON> Bayh </PERSON> on Tuesday. The Quayles have sought to minimize speculation that Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is interested in succeeding her husband. The couple have three children _ <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>, 14, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>, 12 and <PERSON> Corinne </PERSON>, 9 _ and it is believed that one obstacle to Mrs. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s taking on a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat is their concern about both parents being involved in extremely demanding jobs On Wednesday afternoon, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> rode out to <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> to greet <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the vice president's return from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, saying `` he's going to be one of the great vice presidents. You watch him closely.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> and his wife drove to the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION>, where they exchanged tributes with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` As one who came to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1980, thank you for all you have done for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` ... The American people overwhelmingly placed their trust and their confidence in your leadership, and I'm delighted to be a part of that team and am ready to go to work and change <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and make it even greater.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-House-Winners 6thAdd   11-10 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-House-Winners, 6th Add,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 14:05,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This take covers New York</NOTE>
<HEAD>UNDATED:</HEAD>
<HEAD>NEW YORK</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hochbrueckner </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 2: <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 3: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 4: <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lent </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 5: <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 6: <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 7: <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 8: <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 9: <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Manton </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 10: <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 11: Edolphus Towns, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 12: Major <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 13: <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 14: <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 15: <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 16: <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 17: <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 18: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 19: <PERSON> Eliot </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Engel </PERSON>, Dem 20: No winner declared. 21: <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Fish </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 22: <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 23: <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McNulty </PERSON>, Dem 24: <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 25: <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 26: <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 27: <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 28: <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> McHugh </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 29: <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 30: <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slaughter </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 31: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Paxon </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 32: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> LaFalce </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 33: <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 34: <PERSON> Amory </PERSON> <PERSON> Houghton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-US-House-Winners 8thAdd   11-10 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-House-Winners, 8th Add,0265</SECOND>
<HEAD>11-09-88 14:05,</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This take covers Pennsylvania through Tennessee</NOTE>
<HEAD>UNDATED:</HEAD>
<HEAD>PENNSYLVANIA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foglietta </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 2: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 3: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Borski </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 4: <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolter </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 5: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 6: <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Yatron </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 7: <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 8: <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 9: <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuster </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 10: <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 11: <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanjorski </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 12: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 13: <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 14: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Coyne </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 15: <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 16: <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 17: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gekas </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 18: <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Walgren </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 19: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodling </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 20: <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 21: <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 22: <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 23: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>RHODE ISLAND</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Machtley </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 2: <PERSON> Claudine </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUTH CAROLINA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ravenel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 2: <PERSON> Floyd </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spence </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 3: <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> <PERSON> Derrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 4: <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 5: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 6: <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>SOUTH DAKOTA</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> At-Large </PERSON> <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
<HEAD>TENNESSEE</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 1: <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 2: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> 3: <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 4: <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 5: <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 6: <PERSON> Bart </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB- 7: <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Sundquist </PERSON>, GOP -LRB- i -RRB- 8: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, Dem 9: <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, Dem -LRB- i -RRB-
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-TheTransition Bjt   11-10 1004</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Transition, Bjt,1,020</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Wastes No Time in Assembling His Presidency</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, vowing to revitalize government with `` a brand new team of people,'' has instructed key figures from his campaign to develop priorities for the crucial first 100 days of his coming administration. Even before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won the presidency, job applications were pouring into his standby transition office. The stream of resumes is expected to turn into a flood now at newly opened <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition headquarters. Just hours after claiming victory, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took the first steps Wednesday toward assembling his presidency. The president-elect, at a news conference in his adopted home of <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> before flying back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, named <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, his campaign chairman and longtime trusted adviser, to be secretary of state. It could be the most important post in a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> presidency, given the vice president's emphasis on foreign affairs and his interest in pursuing progress with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, while preparing for his diplomatic duties, also will play a major role in the transfer of power to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s vice presidential chief of staff, and campaign pollster <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Teeter </PERSON> will share authority as co-chairmen of the transition team. Mindful that the first months of an administration set the tone for relations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and foreign governments, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I will have a game plan.'' `` Part of what the transition is about is to spell out the priorities. I spelled them out -LRB- during the campaign -RRB- in broad terms, in terms of keeping the economic expansion going and in terms of world peace. But the election ended yesterday,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` We will now have -LRB- 73 -RRB- days ... to formulate a game plan, the first 100 day priorities, if you will, and they'll be specific.'' In an announcement sure to send shivers through the ranks of the 5,000 political appointees happily at work in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I will for the most part bring in a brand new team of people from across the country.'' `` And in my view that will reinvigorate the process,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. He deliberately left room for some <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> holdovers and veterans to join his administration. `` There will be ... a major turnover but some people at various levels may be asked to remain.'' On the flight back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he wanted to announce the rest of his Cabinet `` sooner rather than way late'' and would think about the possible choices during a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> vacation this weekend. It has been widely assumed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will ask Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> and Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> to stay on. All three joined the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration in recent months. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said Wednesday he had been given no indication of whether <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wanted him to remain `` nor have I sought'' any information on the question. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wanted to replace <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> with former <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> chief and deputy attorney general <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruckelshaus </PERSON> or Illinois Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said Wednesday he was n't interested Former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, an arms negotiator in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration who later advised <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign on national security matters, may be in line for secretary of Defense. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Dore </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> may keep her post as <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> secretary or get another Cabinet position, possibly <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION>, where she was undersecretary from 1984 to 1987. Others mentioned as possible nominees for the Labor post include Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridge </PERSON>, R-Pa., and <PERSON> Constance </PERSON> <PERSON> Horner </PERSON>, now director of the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Personnel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> Former Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, wife of one-time <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> rival <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, also is mentioned as a candidate for another Cabinet job. For the powerful post of budget chief, the odds on favorite is <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, a one-time senior aide in the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and later deputy secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>'s name also has been mentioned as the new White House chief of staff, although <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> are more frequently discussed for that job. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> also is a candidate to be secretary of Energy. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Burt </PERSON>, ambassador to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, is known to be interested in the job of national security adviser at the White House. <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, who served in that role for President <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, is mentioned for it again. Over the next 2 -LCB- months, power will begin to shift from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as the federal bureaucracy and foreign governments look to the incoming president for a signal of his intentions. However, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is still the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and I will not be using the transition to try to make or unduly influence decisions that are properly the president's.'' Policy matters aside, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> indicated his management style will be different from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. For example, he said he will be briefed directly every day by the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> on intelligence matters instead of relying on the White House national security adviser for an update, as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also announced that <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, his legal adviser in the vice president's office, will serve the same role in the transition and then go on to the <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> House </LOCATION> as his general counsel. <PERSON> Chase </PERSON> <PERSON> Untermeyer </PERSON>, former assistant secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> who has been a one-man transition planner for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, will be the transition's chief personnel headhunter and keep the same job in the White House come Jan. 20 <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON>, who has been the campaign secretary, will be press secretary during the transition. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not mention whether she would have that title in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and some <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> sources close to the campaign indicate someone else may get the job. Altogether, there are 5,000 political appointments, divided between presidential appointments and those made by <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretaries and agency heads. Many of the 3,000 or so presidential appointments do not really draw the attention of the chief executive and are handled by others. `` It's in the hundreds rather than the thousands that really matter,'' <PERSON> Untermeyer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CDC-LabDelay     11-10 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-CDC-Lab Delay,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Malfunctions Delay Occupancy Of $23 Million CDC Containment Lab</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Malfunctions in a ventilation system designed to contain deadly microbes will delay occupancy of a $ 23 million research building at the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> until at least next year, officials said Wednesday. The new maximum-containment laboratory, for which a ribbon-cutting ceremony was held last month, is part of <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s shift from investigating outbreaks of disease to basic research into infectious disease. An estimated 80 researchers had planned to move into the building this fall, but the move will be delayed until problems are worked out in the complex ventilation system. `` They want to be sure before they clear a system like that for people like me to crawl under a hood and begin working with a hot virus,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Fowlkes </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s retrovirus laboratory. The system is designed to keep air pressure inside the building's 12 laboratories slightly below normal atmospheric pressure so that air from the hallways always flows into the labs The intentional draft is supposed to keep microbes such as viruses from being carried out of the labs. Viruses that will be studied at the labs include those that cause AIDS and Lassa Fever, which has caused epidemics of hemorrhagic fever in <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> engineer responsible for operating the air system, said Wednesday that the problems lie somewhere in the 96 pneumatic control units whose delicate sensors and valves measure and adjust air pressure throughout the building. For unknown reasons, changes in air pressure, such as those caused by an open door, throw the gauges out of adjustment. The building originally was scheduled for completion in late 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CasablancaColorization     11-10 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Casablanca Colorization,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Directors Blanch Over Colored `Casablanca'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The latest showing of the <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogart </PERSON> movie classic `` Casablanca'' is not in black and white, and the <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> is red all over. The Hollywood industry group said Wednesday night's showing of a color-enhanced version of `` Casablanca'' on cable television's SuperStation <ORGANIZATION> TBS </ORGANIZATION> represented `` a new low point in the battle to degrade an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> art form. The 1941 classic, which also starred <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON>, was filmed in black and white. `` In total disregard for the place ` Casablanca' holds in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s cultural heritage, <ORGANIZATION> TBS </ORGANIZATION> has gone ahead with a computerized assault on one of history's greatest and most-beloved motion pictures,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Gumpel </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION>'s executive director, said in a statement. `` For those who choose to watch the broadcast, we would simply remind them that what they are seeing is not ` Casablanca,' but a computerized parody of an original and classic work,'' he said. In the past, <ORGANIZATION> TBS </ORGANIZATION>' owner, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, who also owns <ORGANIZATION> MGM </ORGANIZATION>'s film library, has experienced similar criticism but healthy ratings for its colorized versions of old movie classics. Turner has responded to such criticism in the past by saying, `` I own it, I'll do what I want with it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SenateRdp     11-10 0800</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Rdp,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Democrats Indicate Desire to Work With Bush Administration</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats, assured of improving their majority control by at least one seat, are signaling President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that they want to avoid partisan warfare with the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> when the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> convenes in January. The final margin of the Democratic grip on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from Tuesday's elections will not be clear until a cliffhanger race in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> is resolved. The margin of victory for either Republican Rep. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> or Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> will not be known until state election officials complete the formidable task of counting the estimated 100,000 absentee ballots, the last to be tallied of the four million votes cast. The vote counting was not expected to be complete until sometime today at the earliest. <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> held a slim lead before the absentee ballots were put on the counting tables, but after the first results became known, <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> had erased MacKay's advantage and had built a small lead of his own. A victory by <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> would leave Democrats with 55 of the 100 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats, up one from the 54-46 majority they held during the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. A MacKay victory would hand the Democrats a 56-44 edge. In Tuesday's balloting in 33 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races, Republicans lost seats in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>; Democratic seats were captured by Republican candidates in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Even if Democrats were to lose in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, they still would have the majority. That carries with it the chairmanship of all <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committees and the right to set the chamber's agenda. Some lawmakers indicated that does not necessarily mean trouble ahead for Republican President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he and other chairmen `` are prepared to work with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and do that straight up, no holds barred, and find whether he means what he says when he says that he expects to have a close relationship with the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the House. Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., said late Tuesday night that he believes <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will find a cooperative spirit on Capitol Hill because `` the problems are too important for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> not to work with the president. Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.M. </LOCATION>, predicted budget issues will dominate the attention of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> next year. The new president's oft-repeated opposition to higher taxes `` will be the big sticking point'' in his dealings with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Domenici </PERSON> added While most of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races were won by decisive margins, one was so close that the outcome may be challenged. In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, Republican Sen. <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallop </PERSON> won a third term by a razor-thin edge over <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> challenger <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinich </PERSON> with unofficial returns giving the incumbent a 1,310-vote edge over the Democrat. But the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commmittee </ORGANIZATION> charged irregularities in the handling of absentee ballots. Secretary of State <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Karpan </PERSON> said that after reviewing the campaign committee's allegations with 23 county clerk's offices, she had no reason to call for a recount in the contest. <PERSON> Karpan </PERSON> said state law requires a recount if the difference between the two candidates' votes is less than 1 percent of those cast for the winner. In the case of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> race, the difference would have to have been less than 911 votes. However, a candidate may request a recount if he agrees to pay for it. Recounting the votes would cost a maximum of $ 11,500, <PERSON> Karpan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Vinich </PERSON>, a state senator, said Wednesday his campaign was still considering whether to ask for a recount. In <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, liberal Republican Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, who served 18 years, conceded Wednesday night after losing by just over 10,000 votes to Democrat <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, the state attorney general. <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, in a news conference in <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>, shouldered the responsibility for his defeat and ruled out any future in politics. `` I'm a big guy. I take care of myself. I take shots, I've given shots,'' he said. `` I'm responsible for last night's results. `` I did n't lose this race by a few thousand votes,'' the former senator said. `` In my mind and in my heart, I lost it by 100,000. ... This was n't a close race. It was a clear mandate by the state of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, that matters that I stood for are not to their liking, and that matters that Mr. <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> stood for are to their liking.'' While 10 new senators were elected Tuesday, there will be 11 new faces when the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> convenes in January. Republican vice president-elect <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has indicated that he would step down before January so <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>'s GOP Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> _ not the incoming governor, Democrat <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayh </PERSON> _ can appoint a successor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0503EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ReynoldsResigns     11-10 0352</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reynolds Resigns,360</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foe of Affirmative Action Quits Top Justice Department Job</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s civil rights chief is leaving government next month, after a seven-year tenure marked by support from conservatives and condemnation from civil rights groups for his attacks on affirmative action. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, assistant attorney general in charge of the civil rights division, said Wednesday he is resigning effective Dec. 9. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> said he probably will remain in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area to practice law and is discussing job possibilities with private firms. In an interview, <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> said he felt the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's greatest achievement in the civil rights field has been `` restoring the principle of non-discrimination to its rightful pedestal.'' He said his greatest disappointment was getting word of `` our extraordinary record out to the public in the way I would have wanted.'' <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> spearheaded the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's opposition to affirmative action hiring and promotion programs and other anti-discrimination tools that had been at the heart of federal civil rights policies since the 1960s. Liberals expressed pleasure over his resignation while conservatives praised his record. `` If <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' departure is an indication of what the <ORGANIZATION> Bush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will look like, then this is a hopeful sign indeed,'' said <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Kropp </PERSON>, president of People for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION>, a civil liberties organization with 270,000 members. `` Reynolds ... will be missed by civil rights advocates about as much as environmentalists miss -LRB- former <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary -RRB- <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastland </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman under former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and now a resident scholar of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION>, called <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> `` a man dedicated to colorblind law.'' `` He deserves great credit for making often courageous attempts to advance that cause,'' <PERSON> Eastland </PERSON> said. `` In areas ranging from forced school busing to employment discrimination to voting rights, <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> has had a greater impact upon the law in this area than anyone since <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Korten </PERSON>, another former <ORGANIZATION> Meese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman who is now with the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> think tank.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881110-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-10-88 0503EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpacecraftFire     11-10 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spacecraft Fire,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Damage To Venus Spacecraft Blamed For Venus Spacecraft Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
