<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 2342EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Pell-Cuba     11-28 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pell-Cuba,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pell Claims Minor Advances in Relations With Cuba</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUG FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PROVIDENCE, R.I. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, returned Monday from a five-day visit to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> that he said may have provided a `` tiny nudge'' toward improved relations. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>'s trip included a three-hour meeting with <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who he said is eager to resume normal diplomatic relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, a Democrat, said he probably would report on the trip to Secretary of State-designate <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> when the two meet Wednesday. `` I think we may have given it a tiny nudge,'' <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> said in a telephone interview after his arrival at <ORGANIZATION> Andrews </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I think some little improvements could be made, and out of those little improvements, big improvements could follow.'' He refused to cite specifics, but when pressed said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> `` both need to pull in our horns a little bit and -LRB- the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should -RRB- tone down <PERSON> Radio </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> and not start TV Marti.'' Radio Marti aims American government-generated programming into <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Pell </ORGANIZATION> aide said that during the senator's discussion with <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> leader was very angry about plans to expand <PERSON> Radio </PERSON> <PERSON> Marti </PERSON> to a television service and claimed that was one of the major stumbling blocks to diplomatic relations. <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> said he doubted much could be done to stop the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's plans to launch the TV service. The senator said he suggested to <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> that releasing four political prisoners remaining from the revolution in which <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> came to power would be a good first step to improve relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. ` I do n't want to be too optimistic about that. I certainly did n't come back with any firm agreements,'' <PERSON> Pell </PERSON> said It was <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>'s third trip to the island and his first since 1974. He said the change in presidents in this country and <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s recent agreement to pull its troops out of the African nation of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> provide a window to improve relations. `` Peace seems to be breaking out in all parts of the world. There is no reason it can not break out in that little corner of the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-ChinaArtifact 1stLd-Writethru   11-28 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China Artifact, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0602,0463</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Claims Artifact At Sotheby's Auction Was Stolen</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with Sotheby's saying it withdrew
vessel from sale and was never on display. CORRECTS spelling of
vessel to dui, sted of dun. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ancient bronze vessel that was to be auctioned in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> had been stolen in June from a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> museum, an official report said Monday. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Interpol </ORGANIZATION> office notified its <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> counterpart Saturday of the theft, and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police met Monday with a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> official to ask the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's help in recovering it. The ritual vessel, called a dui, was to be auctioned at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said A Sotheby's spokesman in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON>, said the auction house withdrew the vessel from its Tuesday sale of `` Fine Chinese Ceramics and Works of Art'' at least two weeks ago. He said <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s was holding it pending a resolution of the dispute between the owner and the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government. <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON> said the owner had requested anonymity and that <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s withdrew the artifact after receiving a description of the missing museum piece from a representative of the Chinese government The vessel was made during <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s Warring States Period, from 475 B.C. to 221 B.C., a period of conflict among rival princes before what is now northern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was unified under the first emperor. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said the vessel and 226 other Chinese antiques have been on display at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> since Thursday, but <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON> said the vessel was not publicly displayed. The <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> report said <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> police identified the dui from a color photograph in a Sotheby's catalog, which did not identify the owner and said it was expected to sell for $ 60,000 to $ 80,000. Chinese police say the dui in the catalog is identical in shape, decoration and patina spots to one that was stolen June 4 from the Qu Yuan Museum in <LOCATION> Zigui </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> province. The thieves were never caught. The dui was excavated in the county in 1983. An expert at <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Palace Museum said craftsmen at the time the piece was made were unable to cast identical bronze pieces. Millions of dollars worth of artifacts are smuggled out of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> each year, mostly through <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. Some are stolen from museums, but most are discovered by peasants in their fields or by tomb robbers, and the sites are wrecked before archaeologists can study them. <PERSON> Weigman </PERSON> said an auction `` would actually be the worst possible place'' to dispose of a stolen object because the process _ which includes the publication of photographs and detailed descriptions of every item _ is so public.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 2348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Steinberg 1stLd-Writethru a0781 11-28 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Steinberg, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0781,0514</SECOND>
<HEAD>Witness: Steinberg Slapped Child for No Apparent Reason</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Inserts two grafs after 5th graf to UPDATE with civil lawsuit
filed by Steinberg's former companion. Picks up 6th graf pvs,
`Scannapieco, indicted....'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SAMUEL MAULL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An alleged drug dealer on Monday became the first witness in the <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> murder trial to claim to have witnessed <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> hit his illegally adopted 6-year-old girl. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON> said <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> whacked the girl for no apparent reason while she was asleep in <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON>'s arms on Oct. 23, 1987, while they were driving in a car. Demonstrating the blow, <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON> slammed the back of his hand against the bench of the trial judge, state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothwax </PERSON>. The judge, <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> and the jurors seemed startled. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, a 47-year-old disbarred lawyer, is on trial for murder in the beating of <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, whom he illegally obtained from a <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> teen-ager. He smiled and shook his head as if in disbelief at Scannapieco's dramatic gesture. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> denies that he hit the child. He says she fell unconscious after choking on food she had thrown up the night of Nov. 1, 1987, and that he caused bruises on her chest and back while trying to revive her. His former live-in lover, <PERSON> Hedda </PERSON> <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON>, who was dropped as a defendant and is scheduled to testify against <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>, also filed a $ 3 million civil lawsuit that was served Monday on <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>. The lawsuit alleges that <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> used humiliation, brainwashing, drugs, and the withholding of food to teach <PERSON> Nussbaum </PERSON> that `` she was a worthless person who could only be saved through his wisdom and special powers.'' Scannapieco, indicted on federal narcotics charges, said he and <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> were driving together because he had hired <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> to represent him at his arraignment in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION> the following morning, Oct. 24, 1987. The witness said the child was cold in the car and he allowed her to snuggle against his chest for warmth. After 10 to 15 minutes she fell asleep. `` Right after she fell asleep,'' <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON> said, `` right out of the clear blue sky, Mr. <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> took his hand and went ... -LRB- demonstrating the blow -RRB- SMASH!'' <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON> said the slap was `` enough to bring tears to your eyes,'' but `` she did n't show any reaction whatsoever'' except to open her eyes and look at <LOCATION> Steinberg </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON> said <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> told him he hit the child because she sometimes slowed her heart and her breathing, putting herself into a near coma. Earlier Monday, <PERSON> Scannapieco </PERSON>'s brother-in-law, <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Koncelik </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, testified he saw <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON> drop <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> about three feet to the ground, telling her, `` You're heavy.'' <PERSON> Koncelik </PERSON>, a supervisor in a sheet metal factory in Coxsackie, said the incident was Oct. 24, 1987, in his grassy backyard. He said <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was unhurt. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> was removed unconscious from <PERSON> Steinberg </PERSON>'s apartment in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Nov. 2, 1987. She died three days later at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincent </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> head </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> injuries </ORGANIZATION>, according to testimony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BlindDiplomats Bjt   11-28 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blind Diplomats, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Says The Blind Need Not Apply</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, after a decade of accepting foreign service job applications from blind people, has ruled that diplomacy is not a suitable profession for them. The decision was a disappointment to <PERSON> Avraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON>, who has passed five <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> entrance examinations since 1985 and has other credentials that normally would make him an ideal candidate for a diplomatic career. `` I am absolutely outraged,'' <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON> said in a telephone interview after the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> informed him that blind people no longer will be permitted to take entrance examinations in <LOCATION> Braille </LOCATION> or to use outside help. `` It is absolutely unconscionable that the rest of the government has shown itself to be able to employ blind people constructively,'' <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is still in the 19th century.'' <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, is a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> with degrees in Spanish and French and has a master's degree in business administration from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>. Born in what is now <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> 46 years ago, he has been blind since age 8. He lived for 15 years in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and six months each in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and he speaks with the elegantly phrased formulations of a man accustomed to intellectual pursuits. He has his own consulting business, helping disabled people find employment. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials agree that they had been following a contradictory policy toward the blind, allowing them to take the written and oral examinations but never accepting them as foreign service officers. The officials, insisting on anonymity, said a department task force ruled recently that blind candidates must demonstrate an ability to work with original documents `` effectively and independently.'' That meant <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON> would not be provided with any materials in <LOCATION> Braille </LOCATION> for an admissions test, that a reader would not be provided for him and he could not bring his own reader with him. <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON> had been taking _ and passing _ <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> written and oral examinations since December 1985. He said his score on his written tests had improved each time. He was informed of the rule change earlier this month shortly before he was to take another `` oral assessment'' test. The officials said the policy of rejecting blind applicants after allowing them to take admission tests was not as cynical as it might seem. They said blind applicants were routinely advised that permission for them to take admission tests did not mean that medical standards requiring `` visual acuity'' for all diplomats would be relaxed. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> view is that all foreign service officers must be `` worldwide available'' and that a blind person can not be expected to deal with the myriad demands diplomats face. One official said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has facilities for helping the blind overcome their handicap but that most foreign countries lack such accommodations. Another said that much of diplomacy involves reading the `` body language'' of foreign envoys during diplomatic discussions. Such gestures as winks and nods form part of the overall message a diplomat must assimilate, the official said. <PERSON> Rabby </PERSON> said the blind are no less able than sighted people to read other people's language, be it `` silent or verbal.'' Accepting a blind person for diplomatic service `` would be a terribly unfair thing to do to that individual,'' said another official, who cited high risk posts, such as <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, as particularly inappropriate for a sightless person. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials commented only on condition their names not be used. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Jernigan </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Blind </ORGANIZATION>, has little patience with such arguments. `` Everybody says it's wonderful what blind people can do so long as they work somewhere else,'' <PERSON> Jernigan </PERSON> said from his office in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>. He said dealing with reading material is the principal activity of diplomats and blind people are capable of handling `` mountains of paperwork.'' Beyond that, he said, the blind require no more secretarial help than sighted persons. <PERSON> Jernigan </PERSON> added that the federation is prepared to take the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to court but he hopes that course can be avoided. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gashel </PERSON>, director of government affairs for the federation, said federal law requires that all government and government-assisted programs conduct their employment practices without discrimination on the basis of handicap. The blind and other disabled persons, he said, must be provided with `` reasonable accommodation'' to help them overcome their handicap. But, he said, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> wants a general exemption from this law because of the unique circumstances under which diplomats must work. He said the last time a blind person threatened court action against the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on the basis of discrimination, the agency decided on an out of court settlement worth $ 165,000 to the complainant. His account could not be confirmed by <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MilitaryDoctors     11-28 0556</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Military Doctors,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Plans Incentives To Hold On To Military Doctors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, struggling to keep military doctors from quitting for better money elsewhere, soon will establish a hefty bonus system under which some surgeons could earn $ 112,250 a year while in uniform. Under the program, which takes effect Jan. 1, physicians with critical skills now in short supply _ such as surgeons _ can boost their salaries by up to $ 20,000 a year if they agree to re-enlist for four years. Smaller `` retention bonuses'' will be paid to physicians who re-enlist for two or three years. A surgeon who signs up for another four-year hitch under the program would see his total monetary compensation rise from roughly $ 92,250 a year to $ 112,250 a year. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> believe we have spotted a problem here in time to do something about it,'' says <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Newhall </PERSON>, the No. 2 executive in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s health affairs office. `` There are other severe non-salary problems that contribute to the loss of military physicians, but this is a key start.'' <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> authorized the new bonus program in the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>'s fiscal 1989 budget authorization and earmarked $ 30 million for the effort as long as the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> meets certain requirements The most important was a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by Nov. 15 comparing military and civilian salaries along with a plan for divvying up the money among different types of physicians. Another report focusing on military health professionals other than doctors is due by Dec. 1. <ORGANIZATION> Newhall </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> met the Nov. 15 deadline for the first report and will meet the deadline for the second. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official declined to release the first report, but a copy of the 25-page document was obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> from other sources. The report concluded that the new bonus program authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is desperately needed because the last major overhaul of military physician salaries occurred in 1980. During the intervening years, it said, inflation has totaled 35 percent and the net income of civilian doctors has climbed 47 percent. In some specialties, such as heart surgery, the difference between military and civilian pay now exceeds 100 percent. `` The result is a general loss of buying power for all military physicians, and a significant loss of competitive compensation for certain highly paid specialists,'' the report states. The report said that while losses of experienced physicians were widespread, the most critical shortages were among doctors with specialty skills. `` The lure of readily attainable, significantly higher pay is an attractive incentive for military physicians to leave the service at the completion of their obligated service,'' the report said. `` In a 12-month period commencing in 1987, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lost 76 percent of its trained specialists completing their initial training obligation.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said it would use the money authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to pay annual bonuses ranging from $ 20,000 down to $ 1,500 in exchange for re-enlistment contracts. The various medical specialties have been divided into seven groups for calculating the bonuses, based on where `` the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is suffering the worst shortages,'' the report said. The top group includes only two specialties: surgery and orthopedics. The second tier will include anesthesiology, ophthalmology, otolaryngology and urology. The third group covers radiology and obstetrics-gynecology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0010EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel-Economy Bjt   11-28 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Economy, Bjt,0809</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pressures Mount For More Free Enterprise in Israel</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN ALT POWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The near-collapse of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s largest industrial conglomerate, owned by the <ORGANIZATION> Histadrut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> federation </ORGANIZATION>, has forced a rethinking of the pioneering socialism on which the nation's economy was built. <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, with annual sales of more than $ 2 billion, controls 150 firms and employs 27,000 people making products ranging from high-technology electronics to tires, fruit juice and refrigerators. <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION> lost $ 250 million last year. In October, it defaulted on a $ 20 million loan from <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and the bank demanded its liquidation. Like the successful plan by <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION> is trying to stave off bankruptcy with a government bailout and a court-backed reorganization plan. But <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION>'s problems are symptomatic of the growing financial ills that have afflicted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s economy. Even the kibbutzim, the communal farms that were the backbone of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s pioneering ideal of sharing work and profits, are in serious financial trouble. The <ORGANIZATION> Kibbutz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> announced last week that its members were struggling to pay off $ 4 billion in debt. The economic shakes have prompted increasing calls for a more capitalistic, free enterprise system. `` The economy has suffocated,'' <PERSON> Stef </PERSON> <PERSON> Wertheimer </PERSON>, a wealthy businessman, wrote in the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s tradition of `` work as a source of employment rather than a source of profits'' has failed, <PERSON> Wertheimer </PERSON> wrote. `` The only way to save <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION> is to turn it into a private enterprise.'' Even <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON>, leader of the left-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which controls the <ORGANIZATION> Histadrut </ORGANIZATION> and founded the socialized economy, says he favors selling off some state-owned companies. The Histadrut and state-owned companies account for up to 40 percent of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s $ 35 billion gross domestic product, economic analysts say. Reducing such concentration could take years, said <PERSON> Zeev </PERSON> <PERSON> Refua </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Companies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees the state-owned firms. The authority has launched a program to `` privatize'' many state enterprises within five years. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s socialized economy began even before the state was formed in 1948. Jewish immigrants, most from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> where Marxist philosophy was taking hold, arrived early this century with the idea that collectively they could build enterprises and recycle profits to create more jobs. They started in construction, and their early cooperatives grew into <PERSON> Solel </PERSON> <PERSON> Boneh </PERSON>, now the nation's largest contracting firm. `` Histadrut did start as a trade union, but with no state it soon became apparent that it had to create employers to create jobs,'' said <PERSON> Efran </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleiman </PERSON>, an economics professor at <ORGANIZATION> Hebrew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The Histadrut, which has 2.5 million members in the nation of 4.2 million, represents 80 percent of the labor force. It employs 160,000 people in its companies. When the state was founded, extensive government involvement was needed to build roads, water systems and other infrastructure. `` It was necessary to build a country,'' <PERSON> Kleiman </PERSON> said. The first steps toward more free enterprise came in 1977, when the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> came to power and passed reforms that dismantled exchange rate controls and removed some trade barriers. But high inflation in the mid-1980s forced <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION>, with <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s backing, to reimpose financial restraints Economists argue that some of the crisis today is a result of a program that began in 1985 to stabilize the economy. The program has squeezed profits by raising interest rates and other production costs while freezing the exchange rate at 1.6 new shekels to the dollar. Most, however, acknowledge inefficiency and mismanagement. `` We feel that if there is no reason the government needs to own something, it should go,'' said <PERSON> Refua </PERSON>. The government reduced its corporate holdings this year with the sale of its <ORGANIZATION> Paz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for $ 97 million. Stock has been sold in three other companies, and a study sets out a five-year plan to sell or reduce ownership in 24 other firms. If carried through, the government will control enterprises responsible for just 15 percent of current production by state companies, <PERSON> Refua </PERSON> said. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Koor </ORGANIZATION> court reorganization plan, the conglomerate can become profitable again only with extensive pruning. It has proposed selling $ 130 million in assets and dismissing 6,000 employees through 1990. Such moves are unprecedented in a country where workers believe they have a right to a job and unemployment has been held to about 6 percent despite recent economic austerity. But Histadrut economist <PERSON> Roby </PERSON> <PERSON> Nathanson </PERSON> said it must be done. `` Even if these difficult steps are not in accordance with the historical and philosophical ideas of Histadrut, we have to try and save the healthy parts,'' <PERSON> Nathanson </PERSON> said. `` If we do n't do it, we take the risk of losing everything.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SenateLeadership     11-28 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Leadership,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Byrd, Giving Up Senate Leadership, Defends Erratic Senate Schedule</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE GOULD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the 55 Democratic senators meet Tuesday to select a new leader, one of the things they'll be looking to improve is the supposedly poor `` quality of life'' in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Do n't count on it, says the outgoing majority leader, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Addressing complaints from some senators that, under his leadership, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> met too often and too long into the night, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> responded: `` I believe first in the quality of work. We ca n't operate on a punch-the-clock basis. I did that once when I was a welder in a shipyard.'' At age 71, <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> is winding up 12 years as a leader of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Democrats, including six years as majority leader. His replacement will be elected in a secret vote by the 55 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> senators who will take their place in the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> next January. Senators being courted for their votes often tell the three candidates they want a leader who will improve the quality of life in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. By that, they mean fewer long evening sessions and erratic schedules that often keep younger men away from their families and Western state senators away from their home bases. `` A majority leader does n't have many options,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` He has the responsibility to get a legislative program in action and to meet the needs of the nation. One ca n't adjust the needs of the nation to one's comfort. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, displaying a 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> calendar, said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> met for 137 days this year. `` That's a quality of life that's not too bad. I do n't know how much one can improve on that,'' he said. The three who would try are <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. There's no predicting how the voting will go in the secret balloting. `` I think no one, candidates included, has the faintest idea who's winning,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, D-Ill., who has previously spoken of the need to improve the `` quality of life. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> is the oldest and most experienced <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> candidate. At age 64, he has served in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> since 1962, on the Watergate committee during the collapse of the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration and most recently as co-chairman of the Iran-Contra investigating committee. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, 56 and a three-term senator, has been pushing hard for the job for years and tried briefly to unseat <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> in 1986. Since Election Day, he's achieved near frequent-flyer status, making the rounds of television news shows to demonstrate his ability to speak for the party. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, 55, a former federal judge with eight years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, also is regarded as a strong candidate among those senators looking for a new spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which now has <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> at the top despite ongoing ethics investigations into his financial dealings. The balloting Tuesday will be held in a locked room in the Capitol. A simple majority is needed to win, and if no one can claim that after the first ballot, the one with the least votes drops out and the voting begins anew. Republicans also will be electing their leader Tuesday, but <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> has no opposition and is almost certain to return for his third two-year term as <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> leader.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Education     11-28 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Education,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Urged To Let States Take Lead On Education</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SEPPY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should reduce the federal role in public education and let states take the lead because `` states can best respond to the unique needs of their citizens,'' a conservative group says. The <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, in a book to be released next month, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> could increase state responsibility for education by `` removing federal oversight authority from federal money for specific programs, and instead, giving solid amounts of money to states to distribute as they see fit.'' The conservative think tank said federal strings `` need to be detached to restore parental authority and involvement to the nation's public schools.'' It recommended that parents be given a choice as to where their students go to school. `` By stimulating competition, schools will be immediately forced to improve or suffer the consequences,'' the report said. `` Vouchers and tuition tax credits empower the parent, as do state and community-sponsored open enrollment plans for public schools of choice.'' The recommendations, written by <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimberling </PERSON>, a former assistant secretary of education, are contained in a chapter of the book `` Mandate for Leadership III: Policy Strategies for the 1980s.'' The book, copies of which have been distributed to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> transition team, is the third in a series of policy guides published by the <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. The first, published after President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was elected in 1980, was considered a blueprint for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. In the chapter on education in the latest book, <PERSON> Kimberling </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> should urge <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to create tax-free savings accounts to help low-and middle-income families meet future college costs, and allow tax deductions for businesses that pay their employees' college tuition to improve <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> competitiveness Ultimately, the new savings accounts might reduce demand for direct federal student aid and `` significantly increase the pool of private savings,'' he said. <PERSON> Kimberling </PERSON> also urged the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to consolidate all federal education programs, currently spread throughout several agencies, within the Education Department and to give the education secretary `` more authority for planning and coordinating education programs throughout government.'' The secretary should use his position as the top education policymaker to `` bring to light problems and solutions for education reform,'' and use its resources to help states and communities improve education programs, he said. The book says the biggest education policy disappointment of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration `` was its failure to keep or even seriously pursue its election campaign vow to abolish the -LRB- Education -RRB- Department.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Mexico-PRI Bjt   11-28 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-PRI, Bjt,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ruling Party Grapples With Division And Opposition</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS ANGELO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Institutional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has ruled <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> for almost 60 years, is fighting to retain its grip even as its presidential candidate, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, prepares to be sworn in. To overcome public discontent, internal party divisions and newly aggressive opposition, <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> will have to strike quickly on both the economic and political fronts after he takes office Thursday. `` The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> is in a battle to modernize the country ... and itself,'' said <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Enriquez </PERSON>, the party's international communications director. The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>, as it is known for its Spanish initials, has ruled with few challenges since its founding in 1929, interlocked with the government in a system that allowed its tentacles to reach every nook and cranny of society. It turned out the vote and channeled favors, including high-level jobs, and in many places succumbed to corruption. It also brought decades of stability and expansion to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, but its power has been shaken by a continuing economic crisis that has cut the average Mexican's earning power by 50 percent since 1980. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> scraped by in the July 6 presidential election with just over 50 percent of the vote. `` In the past 48 years there has not been a transfer of the federal executive power in a political crisis like this,'' wrote <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> <PERSON> Guevara </PERSON>, leader of a reform movement within the party, in a recent front-page column in the newspaper Excelsior. Still, the party remains powerful, taking sweeping victories in municipal elections in several provinces since October. Despite accusations of fraud most of the wins are recognized as genuine. For almost 60 years the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION>'s pillars _ labor, peasants and a catchall of bureaucrats, teachers and others _ have wheeled and dealed, sharing leadership, power and the rewards of power. `` The <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> was a type of cushion between the political power and the citizens,'' said <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Trejo </PERSON>, a professor at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and a labor specialist. Election victories were taken for granted and ensured, if an opposition candidate or apathy stood in the way, by fraud and campaigns that could depend on access to state funds, vehicles and employees. With transition from a largely illiterate rural population to an urban society came a political awakening, a desire for more competitive elections and an end to corruption. In response, <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> governments gave more opportunities, including congressional seats, to the small opposition parties. Adding to the discontent was the jolt of an economic crisis brought on by the oil boom and bust. Outgoing President <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>'s six-year term has been a period of austerity for most Mexicans. On July 6, the <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> was stung with its narrowest federal election win ever, setting three firsts. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> won with a scant 50.36 percent of the vote, the first time the party got less than 70 percent of the vote. It gave up <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats, four of the 64, for the first time. And it had to settle for 260 of the 500 seats in the lower house, the first time it failed to gain a two-thirds majority needed for constitutional reforms. The opposition _ both the conservatives and the left _ charged electoral fraud and that <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' victory was n't legitimate. `` Society changed. It's not the apolitical society of 20 years ago,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrido </PERSON>, who has written one history of the party and is working on another. Many opponents were former <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> members, such as leftist presidential candidate <PERSON> Cuauhtemoc </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardenas </PERSON>, who felt they'd been dealt out of the circle of power during de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>'s conservative administration, which introduced free market economic policies and attempted to reduce government subsidies. <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>, who will be the 13th consecutive <ORGANIZATION> PRI </ORGANIZATION> president, has pledged greater democracy and changes to make the party more responsive to the needs of the people. `` Our purpose is to modernize so as to retain our majority position, and so as not to be weakened and exhausted by parliamentary coalitions, which always end up by succumbing to the rule of the minorities,'' he said in a campaign speech. Even the attempt to open up the party meets tough opposition from what are known as the party's `` dinosaurs,'' the still-powerful old guard. Labor, traditionally the sector that could be relied upon to get out the vote and maintain stability, in part in exchange for public offices, is a foundation of that old guard. Before the economic crisis, `` unions could negotiate more or less satisfactory salaries'' because they were part of the system, <PERSON> Trejo </PERSON> said. But now, he said, `` there is n't enough for more salaries or to maintain employment levels. It means there are more protests.'' More than 20 labor candidates lost in the July 6 election. Recent violent incidents, including a shootout between rival unions in the lobby of one of the city's most luxurious hotels, showed either defiance of de la <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> or loss of control by top labor bosses, analysts said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LatinDemocracy 2Takes   11-28 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Latin Democracy, 2 Takes,0786</SECOND>
<HEAD>While Democracy Spreads In South America, Social Woes Persist</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTIAGO, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the past decade, seven <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> nations pried themselves loose from the dictatorial grip of military men. The march of freedom seemed inexorable. For the 210 million people in the seven nations _ <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Suriname </LOCATION> _ the return of elected civilian government brought substantial personal freedom and the restoration of human rights. Now the bright, shining shield of democracy is becoming tarnished. Growing disenchantment is evident in several countries, mostly because of dashed expectations that an end to political repression would bring economic improvement. It has n't proved that simple. Nonetheless, democracy continues to enjoy substantial allure, spreading into the few remaining enclaves of authoritarian rule. <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>'s citizenry, rallying behind the slogan `` the joy is coming,'' voted to end Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>'s 15-year tenure as president and hold elections in December, 1989. Only tiny <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>, run by aging, authoritarian <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> since 1954, remains totally outside the <ORGANIZATION> democratic </ORGANIZATION> fold. And despite the occasional rattling of sabers, and a few dramatic but isolated and abortive barracks revolts in some countries, few observers feel a military coup is likely anywhere on the continent. `` When you have inflation of 1,000 percent a year, you obviously get unhappy people, but that does n't mean they're inviting a return to military rule,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON>, a politics professor at <ORGANIZATION> Princton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and an expert on the Latin American armed forces. `` The military does n't have a solution to these problems,'' he said in a telephone interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` In the 1960s they thought they had the answers. They do n't think they do today. `` The notion that somehow they could do it better has been disproved by their own experience.'' In most South American countries economic mismanagement or corruption by the politically inexperienced armed forces contributed to the return of civilian rule. But some of the new civilian governments have not proven much more adept at handling the continent's most urgent, and persistent, problem: grinding poverty. <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> is considered the most volatile example. The inflation rate is expected to surpass 1,000 percent, the economy is stagnant and little if any headway has been made in improving the plight of a hungry peasantry that feeds the ranks of a Maoist guerrilla organization, the Shining Path. President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> was considered one of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s new generation of charismatic leaders when he took power in 1985. But his popularity has plummeted because of what critics see as a vacillating economic policy, especially since he alienated conservative parties and businessman with a plan to nationalize foreign banks in 1987. A recent survey by a Lima-based polling firm, <ORGANIZATION> Datum </ORGANIZATION>, found that 60 percent of Peruvians do n't believe a military coup is likely before <PERSON> Garica </PERSON>'s term ends in 1990. But 28 percent do _ a sign that democracy's foundations are less than rock-solid. `` If our problems continue to degenerate and if our institutions continue demonstrating ineffectiveness, the totalitarian temptation will visit us sooner or later,'' said a Peruvian political analyst, <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasara </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> also are plagued by economic and social instability, with sky-high inflation rates and tens of thousands of workers striking daily for better pay, paralyzing many basic services such as transportation and the mail. Brazilian newspapers publish regular reports of government corruption, nepotism and waste. Retired Gen. <PERSON> Joao </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueiredo </PERSON>, the last in a series of military presidents who ruled from 1964 to 1985, told citizens to `` forget me'' when he handed over power to a civilian. Now he says he is besieged by supporters asking him to return to office. A popular bumper sticker in bustling <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> wistfully recalls military rule: `` I was happy and I did n't know it.'' President <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, another charismatic symbol of democracy's return when he assumed office in 1983, was shouted down by hecklers during a recent speech and his <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> trails the <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> in popularity as the nation prepares for elections in May. But such open expressions of dissent and dissatisfaction reflect perhaps the most attractive aspect of life under the new democracies. Freedom of expression and action has been a pledge kept by the new governments. Most labor strikes take place unchallenged and the mass media suffers few if any restrictions. The systematic arrest, torture and killing of dissidents that took place when troops kept order under military rule has been replaced by respect for basic civil and human rights.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LatinDemocracy-1stAdd     11-28 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Latin Democracy-1st Add,0593</SECOND>
<HEAD>SANTIAGO: human rights.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Participation in party politics, labor federations and other social groups both pro- and anti-government is active and broad-based across the continent. The problem, according to some analysts, is that such groups often work at cross-purposes. `` The primary problem in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s democratic reconstruction is the capacity to stabilize the political system,'' said the Chilean political scientist <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Somavia </PERSON>. `` And the capacity to stabilize the political system depends on achieving basic accords among political parties and the different social sectors.'' Until a country achieves a working, stable political system `` the possibility of a coup will remain present,'' said <PERSON> Somavia </PERSON>. He is president of a Latin American study group sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humanism </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Somavia </PERSON> cited <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> as an example of a new democracy where `` political arrangement is basically working.'' Under <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON>, who took office in 1985 and is considered one of the most widely respected new presidents, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>'s political, labor and business groups have reached a basic understanding that has provided stability and economic improvement. <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> also is often cited as a democratic success story. President <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON> has overseen an economic austerity program that slashed annual inflation from an astounding 20,000 percent to about 10 percent. The Bolivian reforms were painful and politically risky, with thousands of workers at unprofitable state-run mines laid off and new taxes imposed. But the government's predictions of stability and growth are slowly coming true and, as Bolivians prepare for new presidential elections in May, no one considers a coup even remotely possible in what traditionally has been <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most political unstable country. Not that the military has n't made its presence felt. <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON> <PERSON> Siles </PERSON> <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON>, was kidnapped by police and military officers in 1984 but freed hours later because of a vast public and official outcry. In <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, Gen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazzos </PERSON> of the air force led two short-lived revolts in 1986 before the government arrested him. A year later, his followers abducted President <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Febres </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordero </PERSON> and held him for 11 hours, freeing him only after an amnesty was granted to the rebellious <PERSON> Vargas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazzos </PERSON>. Two brief but dramatic garrison revolts in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, in 1987 and 1988, were defused when President <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> agreed to limit human rights trials of soldiers. In each crisis, it is widely accepted that the civilian governments emerged strengthened. And although military rumblings persist, experts contend there is a new, less threatening tenor. `` The saber-rattling is now related to issues that directly affect the armed forces as an institution,'' such as human rights trials and military spending, said <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON>. He said they no longer are taking public issue with general government policy, or presenting themselves in the role of national saviors as they did in the 1960s. <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> said he does not subscribe to the notion of an inevitable political cycle of military and civilian rule. `` The pendulum has stopped swinging,'' he said. According to <PERSON> Somavia </PERSON>, the military also lacks the broad-based civilian support for a takeover they enjoyed during the social turmoil that affected many <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> countries two decades ago. `` They have less social force,'' he said. `` No one is asking for a coup.'' But <PERSON> Somavia </PERSON> called the antagonistic relations between the military and civilians `` a central problem that is going to be with us for a very long time.'' Re-establishing a constructive relationship in which the armed forces fully accept civilian control `` is something you ca n't accomplish in one government.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LatinDemocracy-Glance     11-28 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Latin Democracy-Glance,0508</SECOND>
<HEAD>South America's Political Systems At A Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Latin Democracy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Political transitions in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, country by country: <LOCATION> ARGENTINA </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 31 million -RRB- _ Returned to civilian government in December 1983, when <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> assumed power from the last of four military juntas that had ruled since March 1976. New elections are planned for May, with the winner taking office in December. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> would become the first Argentine president to complete his term in more than four decades.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> BOLIVIA </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 6.5 million -RRB- _ The military stepped down in 1982, when the elected president, <PERSON> Hernan </PERSON> <PERSON> Siles </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuazo </PERSON>, took office. His term was to last four years, but widespread discontent forced early elections and <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Estenssoro </PERSON> assumed the presidency in 1985. New elections are planned for May.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> BRAZIL </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 140 million -RRB- _ Twenty one years of military rule ended in March 1985 when civilian <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> took office as president, as the successor of <PERSON> Tancredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Neves </PERSON> who had been elected by a military-appointed <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> but died hours before his scheduled inauguration. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> had been named vice president. A new, popular election is planned for November 1989.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> CHILE </LOCATION> -LRB- pop 12 million -RRB- _ In October, voters rejected a proposal to extend by eight years the presidency of Gen. <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON>, who took power in a 1973 coup. Elections to pick a civilian successor are planned for December 1989, and <PERSON> Pinochet </PERSON> would hand power over to the winner in March 1990.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> COLOMBIA </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 20.5 million -RRB- _ Since the fall of military dictator <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rojas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pinilla </PERSON> in 1957, civilian presidents have been elected every four years. The next election is scheduled for May 1990, when the term of President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> expires.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> ECUADOR </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 10.4 million -RRB- _ A decade of military control ended in July 1978 with the election of civilian <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Roldos </PERSON> as president. Two elections later, President <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Borjas </PERSON> began a five-year term in August.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PARAGUAY </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 3.5 million -RRB- _ Gen. <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> has ruled since a 1954 military coup. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> has won re-election as president every five years, but charges of vote fraud have marred the balloting. The next election is planned for 1993.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PERU </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 20 million -RRB- _ Twelve years of military rule ended in July 1980, when <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Belaunde </PERSON> was inaugurated as president. Five years later, <PERSON> Belaunde </PERSON> handed the presidency to <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, the first democratic transition in decades. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s term ends in 1990.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> URUGUAY </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 3 million -RRB- _ Civilian <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> began a five-year presidential term in March 1985, ending 12 years of military rule. New elections are scheduled for November, 1989.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> VENEZUELA </LOCATION> -LRB- pop. 19 million -RRB- _ A civilian-military rebellion in January, 1958, ended almost five decades of military dictatorships, with only a couple of short-lived democratic governments. Since then, civilian presidents have been elected every five years. The next election is scheduled for Dec. 4, to pick President <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Lusinchi </PERSON>'s successor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-USMilitary     11-28 0751</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-US Military,0770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Incidents Mar U.S. Military Reputation In Japan</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A monthlong spate of incidents involving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military forces has touched a raw nerve in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, provoking outraged newspaper editorials and a sharp protest from the government. On <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION>, the southern island where 35,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops jostle for training space with 1.2 million Japanese residents, civilians complain that houses were hit by bullets in October and two tear-gas canisters exploded at a nightclub Nov. 19. The canisters sent scores of people into the street, coughing and choking. The tear-gas incident, which <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> authorities said was under investigation, came one day after the abrupt transfer of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> skipper. His ship had embarrassed the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> command by firing practice shells that hit about 1,000 feet from a Japanese coast guard vessel. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> immediately expressed regret for the shelling, which occurred in Japanese waters near the entrance to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> on Nov. 9, but the Japanese government reacted strongly. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> lodged a protest with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, while several major newspapers published blistering editorials. The <ORGANIZATION> Mainichi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> daily called the shelling `` the result of the unbelievably slack discipline and lack of moral concepts of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.'' Said the <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>: `` It would definitely be risky if things of this sort were left as they are. Even a single miscalculation would endanger human life. Besides, it would gravely affect the ties of genuine friendship that exist between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.'' About 64,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops are in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> under a security treaty that obliges the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to help defend this country, with an added major role in security for northeast <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. The treaty also obliges <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to provide the bases and training areas needed by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces. The vast majority of the Japanese support the U.S.-Japan security treaty and the country's anti-war constitution, which give the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> a prime role in defending <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. But this country never was occupied by foreign troops until its defeat in World War II, and Japanese are sensitive to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> presence. Leftists demonstrate against visiting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ships that may be carrying nuclear arms, and the public reacts strongly when a dangerous accident involves <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces or when the bases appear to be encroaching on Japanese life. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base at <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> wants to build more than 800 apartments but faces resistance from the neighboring town of <LOCATION> Zushi </LOCATION>, which has repeatedly elected a mayor who opposes taking forest land for the military housing. On <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION>, prefectural Gov. <PERSON> Junji </PERSON> <PERSON> Nishime </PERSON> has blamed a string of troubles on `` something wanting in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military's chain of command or a decline of discipline.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commanders on the southern island are reportedly reviewing safety measures following a forest fire that occurred in a training area in October and the discovery about the same time that a residential area near a Marine Corps firing range had been hit by bullets even though firing on the range is supposed to be in the opposite direction. Two Foreign Ministry officials went to <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> on Thursday to meet with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> generals, inspect the firing ranges and talk to local officials. Ministry spokesman <PERSON> Yoshifumi </PERSON> <PERSON> Matsuda </PERSON> said the local people's attitude was a `` crucial element in the presence of the bases'' and was important to the wider issue of U.S.-Japan security relations Okinawans also have asked that some land now in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases be returned to civilian use for the growth of the island's tourist industry. About 20 percent of the island's 300,350 acres is controlled by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces. An <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> official who requested anonymity said there were numerous small annoyances like parachutists landing by accident in someone's backyard or losing equipment that plummets to the ground. `` Things may not be completely improved in a day or two, but we understand that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military is at least trying,'' the official said in a telephone interview. The Foreign Ministry commended the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for relieving Cmdr. <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michaelis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as captain of the guided missile destroyer USS Towers, which fired practice shells in Japanese waters. But the ministry spokesman said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> was still awaiting a full report from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> command said it was reviewing its investigation of the Towers incident and would not comment until the review was finished. Pending the review, <PERSON> Michaelis </PERSON> was reassigned to shore duty at the <LOCATION> Yokosuka </LOCATION> base.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DividedByWar     11-28 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Divided By War,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reality Of War: One Son A Contra, The Other Killed By A Contra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MATAGALPA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> prays for the soul of his lost son, a Sandinista army officer killed in a rebel ambush, and for the health of another, a leader in the same rebel fight to oust the leftist government. `` I pray to God he will leave the Contras,'' <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> said of his son <PERSON> Luis </PERSON>, known in the rebel ranks as <PERSON> Commandante </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` He was a good boy. But it's difficult. One son is dead and the other is away.'' The divisions in the Fley family are common in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, site of a 7-year-old civil war that has pitted brothers against brothers on the battlefield. Hundreds of thousands of people have fled, leaving behind loved ones, for reasons varying from repression to opposition to the 10-year-old leftist government. <PERSON> Fley </PERSON>, 83, and his wife, <PERSON> Teodora </PERSON>, 68, raised 14 children in <LOCATION> Matagalpa </LOCATION>, a north-central mountain city. In addition to <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON>, who was killed, and <PERSON> Luis </PERSON>, with the Contras, two are officers with the Sandinista army. <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> died last year at age 30 when rebels attacked the truck he was riding. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON>, 37, once a staunch Sandinista supporter, left <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> almost eight years ago to join the Contras. They are not alone. <PERSON> Christiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> runs the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION>, while her sister <PERSON> Claudia </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> is the Sandinista ambassador to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. Brother <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> edits the official <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, <LOCATION> Barricada </LOCATION>; their other brother, <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON>, supports the Contras. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Rosa </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasos </PERSON>, is the sister of <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> Sacasa </PERSON>, who until recently was a <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. Finance Minister <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrion </PERSON>, one of nine members of the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Directorate </ORGANIZATION>, is a nephew of <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Directorate </ORGANIZATION> member. The Fleys are deeply religious rural folk, retired farmers who typify the majority of Nicaraguans divided between the U.S.-supported Contras and the Soviet-backed <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. `` One of our sons died because of the war and another is away. We ca n't solve this,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Fley </PERSON>, sitting on a rocker in her sparsely decorated home. Mrs. <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> has n't seen her son <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> since he left in 1981. She spoke with him by telephone after <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> died last January. `` He called me to offer his condolences,'' she said. Her son <PERSON> Luis </PERSON>, interviewed in a Honduran rebel camp three months earlier, remembered that phone call well. `` My mother told me to come home, that she did n't want to see another son killed,'' the rebel commander said. `` I told her I was away from all that. I meant that I was away from the battlefield. I later found out -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> Chief -RRB- <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheelock </PERSON> told people I had left the Contras. The phone was tapped.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> said she resisted Sandinista requests that she write or phone her son to plead for his return. Her husband, his white hair tucked beneath a faded blue cap, recalled why <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> left. `` He sold coffee at a low price, so the other salesmen said he was selling to the Contras. That's a lie. They were going to kill him,'' <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> said. `` He knew it was better to leave.'' The 37-year-old rebel commander, interviewed at the Contra camp in August, said he had questioned the freedom and equality promised by the Sandinistas, and was put in prison in 1981. `` Why did they have everything and we, in the rural regions, still had nothing? I took the rifle I used to fight against <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON> and fought against the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>, `` he said. `` I'd like to go back to my country,'' he said. When told that her son had recently been seen at a rebel camp in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Fley </PERSON> gasped. `` If you see him, please tell him we are well ... old, poor, but well,'' she said. Sitting in the same small room was <PERSON> Maribel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON>, the widow of the slain <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON>. She has never met her brother-in-law. `` In the beginning, I blamed <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> personally for killing him,'' she sid. `` But I also have brothers with the Contras ... We do n't talk about it much here What can we say?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Welch     11-28 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Welch,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Editor for John Birch Society Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEEDHAM, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, who edited two publications for the ultraconservative <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Birch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, which her husband helped found, has died at age 88. Mrs. <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> died Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> Glover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Needham </LOCATION>. She was editor of the society's weekly newspapers, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> and Review of the News and was a contributing editor of the society's <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Digest </ORGANIZATION>. She was born in <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and graduated from <ORGANIZATION> Wellesely </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1922, studying at the <LOCATION> Sorbonne </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>. The society was founded in 1958 by 12 men, including her husband, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON>, who has since died. It was named after a young American missionary who was killed in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1954. The group is headquartered in <LOCATION> Belmont </LOCATION>, where the <PERSON> Welches </PERSON> lived for 40 years. The society first gained national attention when it accused then-President <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> and Secretary of State <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <PERSON> Dulles </PERSON> of being implicated in a Communist plot to take over the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government in the 1950s.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SpaceShuttle 1stLd-Writethru a0651 11-28 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Space Shuttle, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0651,0688</SECOND>
<HEAD>NASA Set To Begin Countdown For Classified Shuttle Mission</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to UPDATE with countdown start, NASA quote,
Tass news agency report on mission objective; picks up 5th graf: `As
for ...</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> began the countdown early Monday for launching the space shuttle Atlantis on Thursday with five astronauts and an intelligence-gathering satellite. The clock begin ticking at 12:01 a.m. EST as test director <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Crute </PERSON> issued the traditional `` call to stations'' that summoned more than 100 controllers to their computer consoles in the launch control center four miles from the launch pad. `` We're pressing on; the countdown has started,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Diller </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The call also was a signal for workers at the pad to begin servicing the main engines and removing work platforms from around the base of the spaceship. Because the mission is classified, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> are disclosing few details of the flight. A brief statement was issued Sunday describing the preparations completed earlier in the day with the inspection and closure of the engine compartment. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are mum on the length of the flight and what the astronauts will be doing in orbit, but the official Soviet news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday the mission's main task is to put a new generation reconnaissance satellite, codenamed Lacrosse, into near-Earth orbit. `` The satellite will conduct surveillance of the territory of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with the help of updated radar,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said in a report from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> plans to deploy in the next few years four other similar spy satellites which will play the role of an ` eye' for the new strategic bomber B-2, known as stealth,'' the Soviet agency said. As for the timing of the launch Thursday, reliable sources have said that it should take place about 7 a.m. EST if weather and other conditions are adequate. But officials will say only that launch is scheduled to occur sometime between 6:32 a.m. and 9:32 a.m. They say they will make the time public when the clock reaches the 9-minute mark. A preliminary weather forecast for Thursday was not favorable, calling for overcast sky, brisk winds and a chance of showers. Once Atlantis reaches space, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> plans only two public announcements. The first, four hours after launch, will report briefly on the condition of the spaceship. The second will be a 24-hour advance notice on when the astronauts will land at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The silence will be broken only if a serious problem develops. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> contends the secrecy makes it more difficult for Soviet satellites and spy ships prowling off <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> to monitor the flight and learn its purpose. Critics argue that such secrecy is unnecessary because the Soviets, with their intelligence capabilities, undoubtedly already know a great deal about the mission and that once <ORGANIZATION> Atlantis </ORGANIZATION>' satellite is in its own orbit, the Soviets will be able to track it precisely and know what it is doing The satellite reportedly will gather extremely sharp radar images of military targets as it follows a path that will carry it over 80 percent of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The five military astronauts who will fly the mission are scheduled to arrive here Monday from their training base in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> to make final preparations for launch. They are <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, the commander; <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, the pilot; and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullane </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>. The flight will be the 27th for the space shuttle, the third dedicated totally to the military and the second since the Challenger explosion that killed seven crew members in January 1986. Following the accident, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> held up flights for 32 months while management and hardware changes were made. Discovery and a five-man crew returned the shuttle to space with a flight that began Sept. 29.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SubwaySleepers     11-28 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Subway Sleepers,0832</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Hotels On Wheels' Brace For Homeless Surge This Winter</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By BILL STIEG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Though <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> is homeless, he knows he has a warm and dry place to sleep _ as long as he does n't mind waking up several miles away from where he laid his head down. <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>, like hundreds of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s street people, calls the city's subway system home, and officials say they expect the numbers to surge as winter sets in. `` I can always get on the subway. I usually have the fare,'' said <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON>, 78, a former mental patient who was wearing a black-knit cap, grimy pants, no shirt, a sweater and tweed coat one day last week. Bedroom slippers failed to cover his swollen feet. `` In the daytime I'm out on the bench, and at nighttime I get in the subway,'' he said, lighting a cigarette butt, which he says helps his asthma. `` In bad weather, I'll go underground.'' <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> had company that day at the 179th Street Station in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>. Another homeless man was at the other end of the platform, and at least eight already were on the E train when it rolled up to start its run to <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. As the winds get colder, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s subways are drawing ever more homeless people. The attraction: a warm, relatively safe environment, all for a dollar. Trains like the E line, whose route never goes above ground, are particularly popular because they stay warmer. For many riders, the disheveled and often unbathed passengers are not welcome on the nation's largest transit system. `` They stink. They're dirty. They can smell up a whole train,'' said passenger <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nashofer </PERSON>. Transit police walk a thin line, rousting homeless people who cause trouble but letting the others sleep. Maintenance crews find themselves cleaning the kinds of messes that subways were n't meant for. Subway passengers learn to select cars by scent. In response, the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> approved a plan last week to hire the <ORGANIZATION> Volunteers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, a social service group, to patrol subway platforms and trains. Members plan to talk to the homeless and offer them the group's shelter as an alternative to sleeping underground. But many homeless people shun shelters, saying they do n't feel safe in them. Last summer, the transit authority estimated there were 1,400 people using its trains and stations as home. Advocates for the homeless say that's far too low an estimate, and the authority admits the number will be much greater this winter. The problem is not unique to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, but mainly is an issue only in cities where buses and subways run all night. In <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, transit officials say, many homeless people, drifters and alcoholics ride buses from one end of the line to the other all night long. `` Because the homeless situation has increased in the community, I would expect public transit would get its share,'' said <PERSON> Leilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bailey </PERSON>, transit director of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>. There is no policy against riding the buses over and over as long as people pay the fares, she said. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s transit system also has no such ban. On a Manhattan-bound E train at midnight one day last week, at least 18 homeless men and one woman were sleeping. Among them was a gray-haired man with a cane and a man face down over four seats, his right foot in a cast and his crutches under the seats. An <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> man with few teeth in his mouth and few English words in his vocabulary wrapped paper napkins around a bleeding hand. `` I hit,'' he explained. Another man had his head wrapped in a black scarf, topped by a fake-fur cap and a hard hat. Three large suitcases surrounded him. `` It's like a hotel on wheels,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, a 27-year-old platform conductor. `` Eight years ago, you'd see one or two in the whole train. Now you'll see six or seven in one car,'' he said. <PERSON> Constantine </PERSON> <PERSON> Sidamon-Eristoff </PERSON>, a lawyer who is on the transit authority board of directors, said the transit police must exercise more authority over the homeless. `` If they've paid their dollar they have a right, providing they comport themselves with dignity,'' he said. `` But if they take up several seats, urinate, defecate, then they should be removed.'' But Transit Police Chief <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, noting that `` homelessness is not a crime,'' said criminals and fare-beaters take precedence among his force of 3,800. One homeless man said he had little choice but to use the transit system as his home. `` There's no other place you can stay in the winter,'' said <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 31. `` It's safer in the street than it is in the shelter. This is one of the few places where you can live in harmony. And it's clean.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Canada-Economy     11-28 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Canada-Economy,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Budget Deficit Biggest Immediate Worry In Canada</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Economists predict that Prime Minister <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>, just like President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, will have a short honeymoon unless his new government can bring down the budget deficit. Concern about the deficit is troubling forecasters in both countries despite the Canadian economists' general optimism produced by the favorable election outcome for the Canada-U.S. free trade agreement. The Canadian dollar strengthened once election uncertainty was out of the way but prices declined on the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> stock exchange for two days after the Nov. 21 balloting. `` I think it's a similar situation to what happened in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Croft </PERSON>, economist for <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, Fry, <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, said. `` The overriding concern is the budget deficit.'' The election gave the <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> its second consecutive majority government and cleared the way for final parliamentary approval of the trade agreement. The pact, already ratified by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, would eliminate most trade barriers between the two countries. The agreement's benefits, however, are expected to be most visible over the long term. Economists say a Canadian decision to back away from the agreement scheduled to start taking effect Jan. 1 would have negative repercussions, but positive impact will be less easy to spot in the short term. Business expansion in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, as in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, has lasted for six years and the debt per capita in <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> is higher than in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, raising fears of higher inflation and a possible recession. During <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>'s first term, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>'s government deficit fell from a record $ 31.8 billion in the 1984-85 fiscal year to an estimated $ 24 billion for 1988-89. Finance Minister <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> has said it will be reduced further to $ 23.7 billion next year, although economists caution it could go higher if interest rates increase more than the government planned and growth is lower. `` We're in no better shape than they are,'' <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Meagher </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION>'s research department said. He said the markets in both countries are looking for signs that there are credible plans to reduce the deficits. <PERSON> Croft </PERSON> at Burns, Fry noted that among industrialized countries only <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> exceeds <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> with a higher rate of deficit to gross domestic product. The gross domestic product is the value of the nation's annual output of goods and services, excluding returns from investments abroad. The <LOCATION> Scotia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s forecasts say real gross domestic product growth will slow from 4.0 percent last year and 4.3 percent in 1988 to 2.5 percent next year. More dramatically, it predicts business investment will drop from 8.8 percent in 1987 and a soaring 18.3 percent this year to 6.1 percent in 1989. The Ottawa-based, private <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION>, which surveys 14 economists, projected growth of 4.2 percent for 1988 slowing to 2.3 percent next year. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, the board's chief economist, said the slowing growth rate was `` due to the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canada </ORGANIZATION>'s policy of high interest rates, the longevity of the current expansion _ now at 23 quarters _ and a weaker housing industry.'' Thirteen of the 14 economists surveyed said they expected inflation and interest rates to increase next year. The board found a consensus that the slowdown will not slip into a mild recession, but <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said: `` The risk is certainly rising.'' Inflation is projected to be 4.1 percent this year and increase to 5.0 percent in 1989. The prime minister announced rapidly after his victory that <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> will stay on as finance minister. `` We know better than to spend the country into recession,'' <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> said at a <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> appearance Thursday night. `` We will maintain our commitment to gradually reduce the federal deficit... It wo n't be easy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EmptyHouses     11-28 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Empty Houses,0866</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vacant Houses `Should Be Usable' For Homeless, Advocates Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report. In 3rd graf, ``next week'' date is
Dec. 5; Catie is cq in 4th graf from end, ``In New York...''</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Emergency shelters house a growing throng of homeless Americans, but the need now, in the words of a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> study, is for `` a stable residence'' for those who have none _ in other words, permanent housing. Noting that federal funds for low-income housing have been cut by more than three-quarters since 1981, advocates say the need for lasting shelter is critical. Some see potential in unused government-owned houses and in the shells of once-sturdy buildings that stand vacant in inner cities.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Taxpayers around the nation own tens of thousands of houses standing empty. At the same time, tens of thousands of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families with nowhere to live overflow shelters and haunt the streets. Now the homeless and some of the publicly owned vacant homes are being brought together _ in a project that is housing families from the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> cold, in a clandestine effort to renovate and occupy a dwelling in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s restoration of entire tumbledown blocks. Activists, while encouraged, are pressing housing officials to do more, and a major decision could come in federal court next week. They say the government is skirting a law that pledges available space to those without homes. `` I think thousands of buildings could and should be usable,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> for the Homeless in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a city that owns, mostly through tax default, 5,000 empty apartment buildings with many times that number of apartments and has an estimated 60,000 homeless people. One of the abandoned buildings was on <LOCATION> Leggett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> in a sorry corner of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bronx </LOCATION>, a national symbol of blight. One of the homeless was <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, placed in a shabby welfare hotel room in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> a few years ago with her two sons, then 6 months and 2 -LCB- years old, after she split from their father and ended up on the street. `` I used to cry'cause I did n't want to be there,'' she says. Their hotel room was broken into, and drug dealing and fear were all around. After 18 months, she boarded a city van for <LOCATION> Leggett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, to look at an apartment in a building that had been restored. `` I was n't expecting anything like this,'' the 24-year-old woman said, talking to a reporter in her tidy, bright two-bedroom apartment, her boys playing across a room that's still mostly bare of furnishings. It was Ms. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>' day off; she's a clerk in a nearby store. Her building, whose tiled entrance foyer smelled of cleaning fluid, had been a ruin not long before. Another Bronx site still is _ but not for long. Workers there are gutting five buildings that occupy a whole block, to create 220 apartments for families like the <PERSON> Thomases </PERSON>. <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Campisi </PERSON>, construction supervisor, outgrowled the demolition equipment as he described getting started: `` You literally could n't get in for the junkies ... Crack? Vials by the garbage-pailful.'' Leading a reporter on a tour, <PERSON> Campisi </PERSON> crunched up rubble-strewn steps to the remains of what? a parlor? Its ceiling was burned through to the sky. A green upholstered sofa stood upended in a corner. The windows let in a drizzle. `` No air-conditioning needed,'' he deadpanned. Still, he and others said fixing up buildings that landlords have abandoned is often cheaper than new construction in places like <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The gutting-and-rehab job that <PERSON> Campisi </PERSON> is overseeing is to cost the city $ 15 million. How much would comparable new buildings cost? `` Maybe $ 50 million,'' he guessed. Halfway across the country, in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, the vacant, publicly owned houses being readied for the homeless look different. In <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION>, a three-bedroom ranch house that had reverted to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> when its owners failed to make payments on a federally backed loan is being readied for a family that has been on the streets. `` We're offering properties that are in good condition,'' said <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, which hopes by next spring to lease 15 houses rent-free to non-profit groups that house the homeless. Such efforts have strong support, according to a survey earlier this year by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit think tank based in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>. One thousand adults were surveyed by phone Eight in 10 favored rehabilitating old and vacant buildings for homeless Americans, who number 450,000 to 3 million, estimated by the government and advocacy groups, respectively. Sixty percent said they'd willingly pay an extra $ 120 apiece in taxes each year to expand housing efforts. `` The need for permanent housing can not be met,'' says a September report by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> for the Homeless, without an increase in the federal budget for low-income housing _ $ 7.538 billion this year, down 77 percent from 1981's budget of $ 32.2 billion.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881128-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-28-88 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EmptyHouses-1stAdd     11-28 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Empty Houses - 1st Add,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>UNDATED: for them.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
