<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 2332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Grammys 7thLd-Writethru a0968 03-02 1088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Grammys, 7th Ld - Writethru, a0968,1112</SECOND>
<HEAD>U2, Whitney Houston Headline Grammys; Good Golly, Little Richard!</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDS: INSERTS one graf after graf 8, ``Narada,'' with Springsteen
winning rock vocalist category</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY57, 59, 206</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 U2, the Irish rock group with a passion for politics, picked up two Grammys Wednesday for `` The <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>,'' their 12-million selling album, and declared, `` This is just a beginning.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> won record of the year honors for `` Graceland,'' the title track from his South African-inflected album which was the Grammy album of the year last year. But Little <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> upstaged everyone as he hijacked the nationally televised ceremony for several frantic moments, declaring that he had won the Grammy for best new artist. `` I have never received nuthin' _ y' all never gave me no Grammys, and I've been singing for years,'' declared the man who sang `` Tutti Frutti'' and `` Good Golly, Miss Molly. `` I am the architect of rock' n' roll,'' he shouted, and the crowd roared approval. After again announcing that he had, in fact, won the award, <PERSON> Little </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> revealed the Academy's choice _ <PERSON> Jody </PERSON> <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> sound-alike from the old dance band, <LOCATION> Shalamar </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>, a winner two years ago with her debut album, took honors at the 30th Annual Grammy Awards for best female pop vocalist for her effervescent single, `` I Wan na Dance with Somebody,'' from her LP, `` Whitney.'' <PERSON> Narada </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Walden </PERSON> won a Grammy for producing `` Whitney.'' <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> won a combined male and female rock vocalist category with `` Tunnel of Love.'' `` Somewhere Out There,'' a sweet ballad written by veteran songwriters <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Horner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Weil </PERSON> for the animated film `` An American Tail,'' won as song of the year. `` We wrote it for the mice,'' <PERSON> Weill </PERSON> said. Guitarist The Edge, born <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, pulled out a list as he accepted the Grammy for best rock group with vocal `` The <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>.'' He thanked luminaries such as <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dylan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jimi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendrix </PERSON>, Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, Dr. <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Westheimer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> the Cat, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and college radio stations. After `` <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Tree </PERSON>'' won as album of the year, lead singer <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> -LRB- <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hewson </PERSON> -RRB- quipped, `` It's really hard to carry the weight of the world on your shoulders.'' `` We do n't see this as a peak for U2,'' <PERSON> Bono </PERSON> said backstage. `` It's just a beginning. We've got 12 songs ready for the next album.'' U2, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobos </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> each had four nominations this year, but none threatened threatened to equal <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s eight-award sweep in the 1984 ceremony. And none had a prayer of overtaking Sir <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Solti </PERSON>, conductor of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION>, whose recording of <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s 9th Symphony won a Grammy for best orchestral recording and raised his lifetime total to 26 <ORGANIZATION> Grammys </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, the pianist who had 20 Grammys entering the ceremonies, won two more for best classical instrumental performance and best classical album for `` <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>.'' He also received the President's Special Merit Award from the Academy. `` I am so very happy the classical music still has an appreciation,'' the fiery pianist told the crowd as he accepted the special award. After he won the best album award, he simply smiled and carried it away, saying nothing. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s `` Bad'' album won an early Grammy, for best-produced non-classical recording for producers <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Swedien </PERSON> and <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Gatica </PERSON>. Ladysmith Black Mambazo, the South African vocal group featured on <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>'s `` Graceland'' album, won a Grammy for themselves for best traditional folk recording for `` <PERSON> Shaka </PERSON> <PERSON> Zulu </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>'s recording of requiems by <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Faure </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Durufle </PERSON> with the <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chorus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> won Grammys for best engineered classical recording and for producer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> group's recording of <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hindemith </PERSON>'s `` When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd'' won as best choral performance. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Zappa </PERSON>'s `` Jazz from Hell'' beat his son, <PERSON> Dweezil </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> for best rock instrumental. `` Trio'' by <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Emmylou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> and <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronstadt </PERSON> won as best country vocal duo or group performance. This year's show at Radio City Music Hall, televised by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, saluted recordings released between Oct. 1, 1986 and Sept. 30, 1987, in 73 categories. Most awards were announced before the broadcast began. The show accented the sounds of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where the <PERSON> Grammyfest </PERSON> returned after seven years in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. One of the big production numbers featured the hot Latin rhythms of <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Puente </PERSON> and <PERSON> Celia </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON>, the funky rap of Run <ORGANIZATION> DMC </ORGANIZATION> and the urban ballads of <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Joel </PERSON>. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, whose music swept up eight Grammys during a `` Thriller'' of a ceremony in 1984, was nominated for album of the year for `` Bad.'' He was also up for male pop vocal performance for the album and male rhythm' n' blues vocal performance for the title track. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Quincy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who co-produced `` Bad,'' were nominated in the producer category. <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lobos </LOCATION>, whose version of `` La Bamba'' was a bigger hit than the original adaptation of the Mexican folk tune by the late <PERSON> Ritchie </PERSON> <PERSON> Valens </PERSON>, were nominated for record of the year, song of the year and best pop performane by a duo or group with vocal. The group's `` By the Light of the Moon'' LP was nominated for best rock performance by a duo or group with vocal. `` <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>'s second album, was nominated for album of the year. She was nominated as best female pop vocalist for `` I Wan na Dance With Somebody -LRB- Who Loves Me -RRB-'' and as best rhythm' n' blues female vocalist for `` For the Love of You. Another track from the album, `` Did n't We Almost Have It All,'' was nominated as song of the year for writers <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Masser </PERSON> and <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON>. The winners were elected by ballots cast by members of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recording </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Sciences in seven chapters around the nation. The academy's 6,000 members include recording artists, songwriters, musicians, producers and technicians. There was no separate category this year for female rock vocalist. The one nominee, <PERSON> Tina </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, was included with <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Seger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Cocker </PERSON> in a category combining male and female. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> NARAS </ORGANIZATION>, said the academy has a rule that members must nominate 10 people in a category for an award to be presented. <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Battle </PERSON>, the soprano who starred on four of the five operas nominated for <ORGANIZATION> Grammys </ORGANIZATION>, ended up winning two _ the <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> Philharmonic recording of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>' `` Ariadne auf Naxos'' and her solo album, `` <LOCATION> Salzburg </LOCATION> REcital.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 2346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DartmouthUnrest 1stLd-Writethru a0872 03-02 0402</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dartmouth Unrest, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0872,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>Racial Tensions At Dartmouth Intensify With March, Rally</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with march completed. PICKS UP
6th graf pvs, `Three former ...</NOTE>
<DATELINE>HANOVER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 200 people staged a candlelight march at <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday night to protest as racist a student newspaper's criticism of a black professor. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION>'s Afro-American Society and others marched down the <ORGANIZATION> Ivy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> school's Fraternity Row without incident and held a moment of silence on the campus green in the protest aimed at the <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. The demonstration came a day after a federal judge dismissed a lawsuit filed against the school by three former students involved in a 1986 sledgehammer attack on anti-apartheid shanties. The former students wanted their college records cleared and the school barred from `` intimidating or interfering'' with The <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> and staff members of the conservative student weekly. In 1986, 12 students, mostly Review staffers, took sledgehammers to symbolic anti-apartheid shanties on the campus green. The raid, hours after a service marking the birthday of <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, sparked a semester of turmoil. Racial tensions were revived last week with the Review's stinging written attack on a black professor who once sued the newspaper for libel Four Review staffers now are charged by the school with harassing professor <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> after confronting him in his classroom over the article, which criticized a music course he teaches and his ability as a professor. Critics of the Review also plan a larger rally on Thursday. Three former Review staffers involved in the 1986 incident said the shanty attack constituted `` symbolic speech'' similar to that of the group that erected the shanties to protest <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> investments in companies doing business in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. On Tuesday, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> dismissed the lawsuit, deciding that the students failed to prove that their rights were violated. The suit was filed by <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Keene </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Polenz </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Katonah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and the company that publishes the Review. The four Review staffers now charged with harassing <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> face a college disciplinary hearing on Tuesday and possible expulsion. The staffers say are being persecuted for taking strong stands on the quality of <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> life and education, and deny that race is a factor. The <ORGANIZATION> Afro-American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> believes the Review contributes to racial problems at <LOCATION> Dartmouth </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DeltaSuit     03-02 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Delta Suit,0400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Delta Air Lines Case Against U.S. Government Begins</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>' suit blaming federal agencies for the fiery crash of a <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> jet that killed 137 people went to trial Tuesday with both sides accusing the other of negligence. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> crew played Russian roulette with the lives of their passengers,'' said <PERSON> Kathlynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Fadely </PERSON>, a government attorney, during opening arguments in the complex case. Flight 191 crashed and exploded into flames Aug. 2, 1985, as it headed toward a <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> runway during a storm. The 137 dead included the driver of a car that was hit as the plane plunged downward. Twenty-five people were injured. In his opening statement, <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said the government is to blame, arguing that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> tower and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sevice </ORGANIZATION> failed to warn the flight crew of the severity of a weather system at the airport. He said the <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> flight happened to be at the wrong place at the wrong time and air traffic control completely broke down at D-FW when the crash occured. But <PERSON> Fadely </PERSON> said the crew did n't listen to warnings from the control tower and flew into the storm system. A report by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> concluded that the crash was caused, in part, by the pilot's decision to fly into a wind shear, a violent downdraft. The trial of <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>'s claims against the government, delayed six months from its original date, seeks to determine who is to blame for the crash and may also decide how much can be recovered in damages. The decision also will determine whether the government must pay part of $ 91.2 million in claims that <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>'s insurers have paid so far in connection with the crash. In December, about 90 lawsuits filed by individuals against <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> were parceled out from federal court in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> to other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District courts. Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Belew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> ruled that lawsuits filed by passengers' families will be sent back to the courts where they were originally filed. About half of those 90 suits have been settled. The non-jury trial between the airline and the government could last up to three months and could include testimony from any of 550 potential fact and expert witnesses named by the two sides.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0544EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--WaldenPond     03-02 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Walden Pond,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Swimming Allowed To Continue At Historic Pond</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bill to ban swimming and restrict other recreation at <LOCATION> Walden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION>, the retreat idealized by <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoreau </PERSON> in 1845, has sunk in the Legislature. The <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> declined Tuesday to adopt a bill that would eliminate a manmade sand beach, restrict fishing and boating and require construction of sound barriers beside roadways near the pond in <LOCATION> Concord </LOCATION>, 15 miles west of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherwood </PERSON>, whose group <ORGANIZATION> Walden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forever </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> opposes continued recreation at <LOCATION> Walden </LOCATION>, contends that 50 years of public recreation at the pond have endangered its fragile banks and spoiled a pristine site. But <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gutensohn </PERSON> told the committee, `` I'm sure the Indians swam at <LOCATION> Walden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION>, I'm sure <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoreau </PERSON> swam at <LOCATION> Walden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION> and I'm sure the people of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> should.'' The 62-acre pond, in a 333-acre state-owned reservation, has 350,000 visitors a year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Media     03-02 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Media,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Considering Closing Territories To Journalists</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MASHA HAMILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSUALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government leaders concerned about <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s battered image abroad are arguing increasingly in favor of barring journalists from the occupied territories after nearly three months of violent protests there Most of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 24 Cabinet ministers support closing the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> to journalists as long as the unrest persists, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> said after attending a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> session where the issue was raised this week. Closing areas to reporters `` is done in various countries around the world where confrontations of this sort take place,'' said Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>. `` If it becomes clear that indeed it may limit the damage, I would be willing to consider it,'' he said. The executive committee of <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Likud </ORGANIZATION> bloc voted unanimously Monday evening that journalists should be banned from entering the territories. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> army commander Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Amram </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON> reissued instructions to field commanders to close areas to reporters for several hours if they believe it is necessary to keep or restore calm, army officials told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on condition of anonymity. But <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s government partner, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shimon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> of the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, warned against further restrictions. `` If we were to close off the area, in my opinion, rumors of atrocities would be spread around the world that we would not be able to refute,'' <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said. `` <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is an open society and a free society and even if -LRB- journalists -RRB- are not always pleasant, we have to allow them to fulfill their jobs,'' he told reporters Tuesday. Other officials oppose closing the territories on the grounds that such a move might fuel comparisons between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, an issue about which <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has been particularily sensitive. South African police, like <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> army officers, have the discretion to declare an area closed to media on the spot because of unrest. Journalists then are barred from entry and must leave if already there. <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s bureau chief <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers seized videotape last week from a crew which photographed a Palestinian hanging dead from a pole in the village of <LOCATION> Qabatiyeh </LOCATION> after his neighbors lynched him because he was suspected of collaborating with the Israelis. The army was criticized afterward for failing to rescue the Palestinian. <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON> said the soldiers detained the CNN crew for three hours and refused to return the videotape, saying it contained material damaging to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s security. The Israeli military command said Tuesday that `` our policy is to keep the administered territories open to journalists. However there are exceptions to the rule in isolated incidents where certain troublesome areas can be closed.'' The latest debate over media access was triggered by a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> report last week that showed four Israeli soldiers beating two captive Palestinians. The two were beaten for more than half an hour while a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> cameraman photographed it surreptitiously. After the footage was broadcast, embassies in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> received many complaints and Jewish communities abroad also expressed concern, <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The four soldiers are being investigated, the army said. The CBS office in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> has received anonymous threatening telephone calls, said <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> bureau chief <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Plantinga </PERSON>. `` One more incident like the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> film and the territories will be closed to journalists,'' a government official told The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Rabin </PERSON> met Monday with a delegation from the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and said most Cabinet ministers supported blocking journalists from entering the territories but he did not, according to <ORGANIZATION> FPA </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Slater </PERSON>. `` The voices in favor of closing the territories have become much louder than the others,'' <PERSON> Slater </PERSON> said. `` It appears more likely than ever before that such a step will be taken and the <ORGANIZATION> FPA </ORGANIZATION> is increasingly worried.'' Two Israeli newspapers, the left-wing <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamishmar </PERSON> and the independent Maariv, ran editorials Tuesday criticizing discussions in government circles about closing the territories to journalists. `` Without media in the territories we may live in a warm comfortable bubble next to an erupting volcano,'' <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamishmar </PERSON> said. `` But we will be caught by surprise and off guard when the lava overflows and threatens our very existence.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Fergie     03-02 0232</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Fergie,0238</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor Chastises Fergie For Tanning Parlor Visits</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ELK GROVE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON>, the Duchess of <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, better known as `` Fergie,'' has received a scolding from a suburban <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> dermatologist who contends her visits to a tanning parlor set a bad example. The former <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferguson </PERSON> who is married to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> is especially prone to sun damage because of her fair complexion and Celtic ancestry, said Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> said he wrote to the duchess after reading in People magazine about her tanning parlor visits. `` I am astounded that an intelligent woman such as yourself would, first consent to tan her skin considering the increase in skin cancer caused by ultraviolet -LRB- rays -RRB- and, second, let yourself be an example for the millions of ordinary, gullible women who follow whatever a member of the royal family does as though it were gospel,'' <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> wrote. The duchess and her husband, both 28, are on a 10-day visit to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. They are expecting their first child in August. `` I think she would be grateful for his concern,'' said <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consulate </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, which delivered the letter Tuesday to the duchess' private secretary. The duchess and her husband plan to leave <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> on Friday for a two-day stay in the desert resort <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, before heading back to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Cornish </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Tibet-Monks     03-02 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tibet-Monks,0987</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Crush Tibetan Monks' Peaceful Dissent</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LHASA, Tibet (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese authorities have crushed efforts at peaceful dissent by the nationalist monks of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> as swiftly as they did last year's bold and violent protests by the <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> holy men. Hundreds of monks boycotted the opening of a prayer festival, in the first major clash of wills since at least 14 people were killed in a demonstration Oct. 1. By the second day, however, a major monastery that led the boycott yielded to Chinese pressure and sent more than 200 monks to the festival, other monks reported. Official media had called the gathering a sign of normality in the troubled Himalayan region. `` The monks did n't want to come,'' one holy man whispered at the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> in central <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>, where the prayer festival began last Thursday and continued this week. They finally did, he said, because `` they were afraid _ afraid that the police will grab them.'' He glanced over his shoulder at an approaching plainclothes policeman, one of dozens patrolling the temple. Fear remains the primary legacy of the three pro-independence demonstrations led by monks over a two-week period in September and October in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>, the mile-high Tibetan capital whose name means `` holy ground.'' The monks dispute <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s claim to sovereignty and want independence under the leadership of their exiled god-king, the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>. Chinese authorities have removed all remnants of a police station near the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> that was burned Oct. 1 by hundreds of angry monks and lay Tibetans, prompting police to fire on the crowd. A new stone building is being built on the site. Military roadblocks have been removed from outside the three main monasteries in the <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> area _ Sera, <LOCATION> Drepung </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ganden </LOCATION> _ and police who were billeted inside the monasteries have been withdrawn. Plainclothes Chinese agents now keep watch. All but 15 of the 80 people arrested during the protests have been released from jail after repenting, according to official reports. The prayer festival, called Moinlam Qenmo, has been held at <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> every year since 1409 except for the period 1960-85, when it was banned by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. It gathers monks from the <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION> area for eight days of continuous prayer and is one of the the most important Tibetan <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> events. As a precaution, <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> sent the highest-ranking Tibetan <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> leader in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Panchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, to <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> in early February to persuade monks to cooperate. He is regarded as second in prestige only to the <PERSON> Dalai </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON>, who fled to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> nine years after the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> army entered <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> in 1950. `` The <PERSON> Panchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Lama </PERSON> said ` Do n't demonstrate,''' said a 20-year-old monk at the <LOCATION> Sera </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monastery </LOCATION>, whose whitewashed stone buildings cling to a mountainside on the southern fringe of the city. `` Some -LRB- monks -RRB- said OK, but some were quiet, did n't answer,'' he said, gathering his blood-red robes against a chill wind. Their answer came Thursday, when fewer than 600 showed up in <LOCATION> Jokhang </LOCATION>'s silk-draped central courtyard for the opening of the prayer festival, which attracted more than 1,000 monks last year. Those attending quickly spread the word: `` Not one monk from <LOCATION> Ganden </LOCATION> is here.'' A monk from <PERSON> Sera </PERSON> said the holy men of <LOCATION> Ganden </LOCATION> stayed away because `` the situation is not good. Too many Chinese are here; too many police.'' Other monks said the same. <PERSON> Sera </PERSON> and <PERSON> Drepung </PERSON> sent fewer monks than usual, and those who remained at <LOCATION> Drepung </LOCATION> conducted their own, small-scale prayer festival. `` We're afraid of the police,'' said one boycotter at <LOCATION> Drepung </LOCATION>. `` It's a very big festival, but if we make a small mistake we will be in trouble.'' In addition to plainclothes officers inside, uniformed police were stationed every few yards around the whitewashed stone <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION>, which is the size of a city block. Several policemen watched from the roof of a nearby police building and others photographed foreign visitors, some of the few allowed into <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> since the protests last year. The <LOCATION> Ganden </LOCATION> monks finally arrived quietly Thursday night from their home on a holy mountain 35 miles west of <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>. Their presence brought to nearly 800 the number of monks who sat cross-legged most of the day in the stone courtyard, chanting. A stream of pilgrims, including herdsmen in tattered furs, edged around the courtyard and spooned offerings of butter into lamps that flickered in racks along the wall. Tibetan sources and Westerners who have seen previous festivals said there were fewer pilgrims, as well as monks, this year. One Tibetan said <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>'s population of 40,000 usually doubled with the influx of monks and pilgrims during <PERSON> Moinlam </PERSON> <PERSON> Qenmo </PERSON>. No count of pilgrims was available because most stay only a few days and sleep in the streets. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official media said festival attendance was up, from 1,100 monks and pilgrims last year to more than 2,300. Dozens of Chinese reporters wrote of the event and the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> quoted local authorities as saying: `` Last year's riot has not had any impact on the ceremony.'' Monks who stayed behind at the the <LOCATION> Ganden </LOCATION> monastery, which was leveled by radicals during the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution and is only partially restored, were not allowed to talk freely to visitors. Of more than a dozen monks interviewed at the <ORGANIZATION> Jokhang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> and at <LOCATION> Sera </LOCATION>, Drepung and smaller monasteries, none expressed regret for the violence of the protests. All were emphatic in disdain for the Chinese. `` Chinese are no good,'' a 12-year-old novice monk said in English. `` But we are not afraid.'' A lay Tibetan said: `` <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> had its own culture, its own religion, its own border guards. How can they say we are one country?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-DannytheRed     03-02 0748</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Danny the Red,0775</SECOND>
<HEAD>Danny the Red of 1960s Fame Is More Moderate These Days</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in report for Wednesday AMs.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By JOAN FISCHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Red </PERSON>, leader of student revolts in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in the 1960s, jokingly says he was never quite as leftist as his nickname implied. `` They only meant my hair color,'' said <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON>, referring to his rust-colored hair during an interview in his <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> office. `` I've always been an anti-Communist, more of one than <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.'' He's now 42 years old and an active member of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s anti-establishment, environmentalist <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ the moderate wing _ and publishes a left-leaning regional magazine in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> He ran unsuccessfully for mayor of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> in 1986 in a purely symbolic move, he said. But he is considering seriously running for <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s city council next year. <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> has also become an author. A collection of interviews with other 1960s activists around the world was published in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in September. American activists featured in the book include <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Abbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffmann </PERSON>, leading Yippies of the era, and the Black Panther activist, <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Seale </PERSON>. The book, `` We Loved It So, The Revolution,'' portrays <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> as a Yippie-turned-Yuppie and <PERSON> Seale </PERSON> as hoping for commercial success as a cookbook author. His book is n't the only look back: <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s news media have carried numerous articles on the tumultuous times of 1968. <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> said that he has basically remained true to many views he had 20 years ago. `` I believe that I can still legitimize everything I do from my standpoint in 1968,'' <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> said. As a moderate member of the Greens, <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> favors forming coalitions with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s liberal <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which the <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION>' radical wing opposes. Nor does <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> favor a West German withdrawal from <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>, as some of the radicals do. `` West German militarization is more dangerous on its own than embedded in a larger context,'' he said. `` That's the lesson of World War II.'' <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> has always been a figure who defied traditional national, political, and religious labels. He was born in <LOCATION> Montauban </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, on April 4, 1945, the son of German Jews who fled <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s persecution in the 1930s. His parents moved to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> when <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> was 13. In 1961 <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> became a West German citizen. `` I did it only for pragmatical reasons,'' he said. `` I did n't want to serve in the military. Jews whose parents or siblings were persecuted under the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> are by West German law exempted from the country's mandatory military service. <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON>, who speaks French and German fluently, said he does n't assign his national identify to either country. As a French citizen, he would have been subject to the military draft in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. `` I'm just me. I'm not German or French,'' he added. `` I do n't need a national definition. <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON>'s views have led to occasional flaps with <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s Jewish community. In a highly publicized dispute in 1985 he publicly supported the city playhouse in presenting a play by <PERSON> Rainer </PERSON> <PERSON> Werner </PERSON> <PERSON> Fassbinder </PERSON>, which many Jews wanted banned as anti-Semitic. In the Feb. 18 issue of his magazine `` Pflasterstrand,'' <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> described himself as a `` convinced anti-Zionist.'' In the interview, he said he favored the existence of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> but also a separate <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state and `` a limitation of Zionism.'' Tenants' housing rights and terrorist amnesty are among other issues that have made <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> a household name. But the era that propelled the activist to world fame, the 1960s, is a topic <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> said he no longer wants to talk a lot about. In his book, originally published in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, he writes that people have used him `` like a machine that turns back time.'' <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> captured world attention as a university student in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, at a time when youth protests were rocking the globe. He was a spokesman for students whose demands included greater social equality and an end to war, in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and elsewhere. <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> the </PERSON> <PERSON> Red </PERSON> became the leader of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>' tumultuous _ and occasionally bloody _ student revolts. `` We had the will to change our lives, to participate in history right at the moment it happened,'' <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> writes of his revolutionary days. In May 1968 French authorities expelled him from the country on grounds of disturbing the peace. The ban was not officially lifted until 1978, <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> wrote in his book. <PERSON> Cohn-Bendit </PERSON> lives with his girl friend, but he said he does n't intend to get married
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AcidRain-Cancer     03-02 0540</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Acid Rain-Cancer,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colon Cancer Risk Tied To Acid Rain Pollutants</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Elevated rates of colon cancer in the nation's <LOCATION> Northeast </LOCATION> and north-central region may be due to an acid rain pollutant that absorbs sunlight, impairing the body's ability to make vitamin D, reseachers say Preliminary studies have suggested that vitamin D and calcium combine to lower the risk of colon cancer. According to the new theory, sulfur dioxide in the atmosphere absorbs ultraviolet rays from the sun that trigger the production of vitamin D in the skin, researchers said at a press conference Tuesday. Sulfur dioxide, produced by the burning of high-sulfur coal, is a principal ingredient of acid rain. A similar effect was observed in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> more than 350 years ago, said the originators of the new theory, said <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> and his brother, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. Around 1629, Londoners began burning high-sulfur coal from <LOCATION> Newcastle </LOCATION>, they said. Within a short time, children began exhibiting the leg malformations characteristic of rickets _ a vitamin D deficiency disease. Vitamin D aids the absorption of calcium, and calcium and vitamin D together appear to lower the risk of colon cancer, the Garlands said. Dr. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipkin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center said the Garlands' theory `` is a legitimate theory'' and work is in progress to clarify the role of vitamin D and calcium in colon cancer. `` We're looking into how many individuals might be benefited by calcium _ and the degree to which they might be,'' said <PERSON> Lipkin </PERSON>. Two years ago, he showed that calcium supplements could change the growth of cells in the colons of people at high risk of colon cancer and might therefore lower colon cancer risk. An authority on diet and cancer, <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, cautioned that because this was only a theory, people should not begin taking vitamin D supplements to protect against colon cancer. `` People have trouble distinguishing theories from proven effects,'' she said. `` With evidence such as this, you certainly do n't want to start taking large doses of vitamin <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vitamin </PERSON> D in high doses can be hazardous to your health.'' The Garlands' explanation is not the only theory to explain why colon cancer rates are highest in the north-central and northeastern states. `` Other people have hypothesized that increased exercise, increased fruit and vegetable intake and differences in drinking water may lead to the lower incidence in the South,'' said <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON>. The Garlands cautioned that people should not spend more time in the sun to increase their vitamin D production because exposure to sunlight increases the risk of skin cancer. They suggested instead that people eat foods high in vitamin D, which include anchovies, sardines, salmon and tuna. Milk is fortified with vitamin D, but most other dairy products are not, they said. Breast cancer also occurs at an increased rate in the areas where colon cancer is highest, and the Garlands suggested that breast cancer, too, might be indirectly related to sulfur dioxide in the atmosphere. That theory is more speculative than the colon cancer theory, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-MissUSA 4th-Writethru a0406 03-02 0793</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Miss USA, 4th - Writethru, a0406,0817</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miss Texas, Again, Wins Miss USA Crown</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 15 grafs to UPDATE with quotes from winner,
previous Texas winners, other detail. Picks up at dash.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Courtney </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> became the fourth Texan in a row to win the Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> crown Tuesday, besting Miss <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> in the nationally televised pageant. `` It feels fabulous,'' Ms. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, 21, said moments after being crowned by her predecessor and fellow Texan, <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Royer </PERSON>. `` One of the gifts <PERSON> Michelle </PERSON> gave me was a dictionary with the word ` impossible' whited out. So of course it was possible.'' Ms. <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, won the right to compete in the Miss Universe pageant May 23 in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Royer </PERSON>, of <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>, came in third in last year's worldwide competition, which was won by Miss <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>. The blue-eyed brunette, a junior in advertising and public relations at <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, won over <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Magana </PERSON>, 22, of Rancho <PERSON> Palos </PERSON> <PERSON> Verdes </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, the first runner-up. Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Stacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sacco </PERSON> said she was stunned by the fourth Miss <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> victory in a row. `` What are the odds?'' she said. Second runner-up was Miss <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rampy </PERSON>, 24, followed by <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruni </PERSON> <PERSON> Farrell </PERSON>, 23, and Miss <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Dana </PERSON> <PERSON> Michele </PERSON> <PERSON> Richmond </PERSON>, 20. Soon after the beaming new Miss <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> ascended her throne, the last three title holders posed with her for photographers. Ms. <PERSON> Royer </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fichtner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, called the last four winners `` four aces in a deck of cards.'' The woman who started the string, <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez-Herring </PERSON> of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>, said: `` It's always been known <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> is full of beautiful women, and this just proves it. I just feel sorry for the next Miss <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.'' Actress <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON> and actor <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thicke </PERSON> served as co-hosts for the program, televised by <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. Ten semifinalists, who had been chosen last week, were announced as the pageant opened Tuesday night. The pageant capped three bizarre weeks in which two contestants quit because of police records, animal-rights activists protested the awarding of fur coats and the co-host, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>, was attacked in a hotel elevator. The hosts made no mention of the various problems during the television show. The late departures of two contestants, both from <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, opened a spot for <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, 20, of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, but the lateness meant she arrived about a week after the other contestants. `` Actually, I've found this oddball situation to be quite an advantage,'' she said before the pageant opened. `` Having so short a time to pull myself together, getting all my clothes together, finding a fur coat, dropping everything _ when all the other girls had months to prepare. It shows off my abilities.'' Miss <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> was not among the 10 semifinalists.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Besides a mink jacket and full-length coat worth a total of $ 15,000, <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> wins a $ 25,000 personal appearance contract, $ 46,000 cash, a sports car, $ 10,000 worth of jewelry and other prizes, including a portable home tanning center. About 25 animal-rights activists picketed Tuesday outside the <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> to protest the awarding of the furs to the winner. Members of the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, chapters of <ORGANIZATION> Sangre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cristo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> contend fur ranching and trapping are cruel to the animals. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Sangre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cristo </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION> chapter, had asked <PERSON> Thicke </PERSON> to do as longtime host <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON> had done earlier: resign in protest over the awarding of the furs. <PERSON> Thicke </PERSON> refused, saying the furs were taken from ranch-raised minks that had been treated humanely. He and <PERSON> Young </PERSON> released a joint statement Monday saying they agreed that fur-trapping is cruel but disagreed on fur-ranching. In another prepageant incident, a man accused of attempted sexual assault in the attack on Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON> last week was released on $ 100 bail. Prosecutors usually ask for $ 15,000 bail in third-degree felonies like attempted sexual assaults. A man ripped Miss <PERSON> Scoggins </PERSON>' dress and shoved her into the back of a hotel elevator, authorities said. She fought the man off and a man was arrested at the hotel. The man's bail was later raised to $ 100,000, which he posted. Another person connected with the pageant has a date with the law. <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pitman </PERSON>, Miss Kentucky-USA, is awaiting trial on drunken-driving charges. Two other contestants with arrest records, both from <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and both accused of shoplifting, elected to bow out. The original Miss Minnesota-USA, <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolich </PERSON>, resigned after it was disclosed she'd been accused of shoplifting $ 370 worth of clothing. Her replacement, first runner-up <PERSON> Jolene </PERSON> <PERSON> Stavrakis </PERSON>, quit after disclosing she had pleaded no contest to stealing from a store in March 1986. The first Miss USA pageant was in 1952 in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-DemocraticDelegates Bjt   03-02 0741</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democratic Delegates, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Democratic ``Super Delegates'' Not Yet Backing Candidate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD L. VERNACI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three-fourths of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders who will be national convention delegates are not yet supporting any of the presidential candidates as the initial round of primaries and caucuses draws to a close, an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> survey found. Since late last year, the candidates together have attracted support that will add up to fewer than three dozen votes at the convention, according to the survey, in which hundreds of the party's `` super delegates'' were contacted. And despite the months of debates and the weeks of primaries and caucuses, many of the automatic delegates, who include <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> members, <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> governors and others, are not closing in on which candidate they plan to suppport. `` The more I hear, the more uncommitted I become,'' said <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member from <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the winner of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, leads the pack with commitments totaling just 31.5 votes at the convention. By comparison, the runaway favorite so far is `` uncommitted,'' a category in which delegates with 247.65 votes at the convention place themselves, the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey found. Missouri Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, winner of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses, is next behind <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> with commitments amounting to 21 votes at the convention, followed by <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> with 19.55, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> with 16.55 and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> with 15.5. Only <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, who has acknowledged his chances of winning the Democratic nomination are remote at best, has not received a commitment from any of the delegates contacted by the AP. When added to delegates won by the candidates in the primaries and caucuses so far, that brings the total to 63.5 for <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, 47 for <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, 35.5 for <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, 27.55 for <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 16.55 for <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and none for <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. A total of 258.65 are counted as uncommitted. The survey, conducted during the last two weeks of February, indicates that the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses and the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> primary, along with nearly weekly debates, have made little impression on <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders. The survey found that just 35.25 more convention votes have been won by the candidates since a similar <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey late last year. `` I'm still not convinced that <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> are representative of the cross section of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> party chairman <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Pick </PERSON>. `` Call over to the grammar school and talk to any first-grader _ he knows just as much as I do,'' said J.T. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> DNC </ORGANIZATION> member from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. `` It's up for grabs. I'm just sitting back enjoying it.'' That's not what the <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> campaign had hoped to hear after the victory in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. `` I think we expected a bigger bounce,'' said <PERSON> Jude </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> campaign aide who works on delegate selection. `` We would like people to commit sooner, but we're encouraged by what they're telling us. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutcheson </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> campaign aide involved in delegate selection, said he is not surprised to see the super delegates holding back. `` These are political people; they want to wait and see what the voters in the primaries decide and then they will exercise their judgment,'' he said. However, <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said party leaders may feel some incentive to begin committing themselves after next week's Super Tuesday contests, when nearly one-third of the party's delegates are at stake. `` At that point I think that people start looking at the calendar,'' <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> said. `` People who come in after <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- which holds an April 19 primary -RRB- are really going to be seen as coming late to the party.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> allots 362 convention votes to members of its national committee, some of whom will cast only fractions of votes. An additional 25 votes are given to governors of states and territories and five to former leaders, including former President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, a former vice president who was the party's nominee in 1984. Delegates representing 352.75 convention votes were contacted for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> survey in February. An additional 253 delegate slots will be awarded to Democratic members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in April. The Republican Party makes no such provision for automatic delegates, awarding all the seats to its national convention through the primaries and caucuses. In all, 4,162 delegates are to attend the Democratic National Convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> July 18-21, and 2,082 are needed to win the presidential nomination.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     03-02 0501</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>NY City Opera's Musical Comedy Season Offers `Music Man'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs Planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 That masterpiece of music comedy and nostalgic Americana, `` The Music Man,'' suffered from a lack of strong, clear singing as the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> opened its annual season of musical comedy. The acting, directing, dancing and scenery were first-rate Tuesday at the New York State Theater. But some of the verve and excitement of those glorious, fast-paced songs was lost during the first act as the singing did not carry well over the orchestra. The problem was alleviated after intermission. Perhaps it was the shift to mostly ballads, or perhaps the level of the singers' microphones had been boosted, but Act 2 was the rich, delightful experience one hopes the whole show will be for the rest of its run through April 10 <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunton </PERSON>, debuting with the company as <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, had the most trouble. A Broadway performer, he moves as gracefully as a dancer and sold his `` 76 Trombones'' to the folks of <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> with more charm than brass. But his light voice did n't project in Act 1's `` Ya Got Trouble'' and `` The Sadder but Wiser Girl.'' The female chorus also was difficult to understand in `` Pick-a-Little, Talk-a-Little,'' and the townspeople blurred the words of joyful anticipation in `` The Wells Fargo Wagon.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, smaller than most boys who play the lisping <PERSON> Winthrop </PERSON>, also is no belter, and did n't get his words across the footlights. Opera singers learn to project their voices and they came out best, making themselves understood and never sounding too operatic for the music. <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Munro </PERSON> was a pretty and sympathetic <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> the librarian, <PERSON> Muriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Costa-Greenspon </PERSON> a natural leader of ladies as the mayor's wife, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> McKee </PERSON> as the pompous mayor, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Billings </PERSON> as <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>'s cohort, <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON> <PERSON> Almy </PERSON> as <PERSON> Marian </PERSON>'s mother and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ledbetter </PERSON> as the constable. The dancing chorus was splendid, with choreography by <PERSON> Marcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Milgrom </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodge </PERSON>, making her company debut. There's a generous amount of dancing, in the library, in rehearsals for a `` social,'' in the center of town several times. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>' set of business buildings pulled back to give the dancers room. <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlay </PERSON>'s costumes for 1912 were glorious, from feathered hats to peppermint suits for the four school board members who squabbled every minute they were n't harmonizing `` <LOCATION> Lida </LOCATION> Rose. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Pippin </PERSON>, a Broadway conductor, was conducting at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> for the first time. It was wonderful to hear the overture played by a big orchestra, less wonderful later when words were covered. The late <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> <PERSON> Willson </PERSON> wrote the book, music and lyrics. He and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON> wrote the plot, which came out as a memory of bygone innocent days of <LOCATION> Mason </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Willson </PERSON> grew up. One wonderful song follows another _ `` Goodnight, My Someone,'' `` My White Knight,'' `` Till There Was You'' _ and the audience greeted each gem like a reunion with a long-lost best friend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Baker-Fed     03-02 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Baker-Fed,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Administration Officials Praise Fed Monetary Policies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is trying to soften earlier accusations that the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION>'s tight monetary policies are nudging the country toward a recession. In separate forums, a trio of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration officials said Tuesday they believe the nation's central bank is doing a good job of supplying money to the economy. Just a few weeks ago, administration officials worried about the prospect of a recession during an election year had been complaining that the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> was n't pumping enough new money into the economy. On Tuesday, however, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> that he has `` absolutely no disagreement'' with the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s monetary policy. Speaking at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, Budget Director <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said, `` There seems to be a little bit of easing, and I welcome that.'' And at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economists </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprinkel </PERSON>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief economic adviser, said the administration is `` supportive of present policy as well as the plans for the future'' the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> revealed last week. The suddenly conciliatory administration tone follows a sharp counterattack by <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, who had responded to the administration complaints with some pointed remarks of his own. <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON> said that a looser monetary policy could spark higher inflation. He also said pressure by the administration could push the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> into asserting its independence by doing the opposite of what the White House wanted. The administration began pulling back from its criticisms last week. <PERSON> Sprinkel </PERSON> said he supports the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s policies so far in 1988, and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said at his news conference last Wednesday that he had confidence in <PERSON> Greenspan </PERSON>, whom he appointed to the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> job last summer. The central bank can usually increase the flow of credit by easing interest rates. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told the senators Tuesday that when it comes to finding the balance between keeping interest rates low and avoiding inflation, `` I think the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> is doing that and doing a very good job of that.'' In other testimony, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> played down concerns raised by senators about the growth of the national debt. Projections by the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, cited at the hearing, are that the national debt could reach $ 4 trillion by 1993. The debt was below $ 1 trillion when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office in 1981. `` There are some risks in the growth of debt of this magnitude, but I think they tend to be overstated,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` I think to some extent that's a consequence of the fact that we're moving into 1988, which happens to be an election year.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also said, however, that `` an increase in the debt is not a development about which this administration nor the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> can be very happy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Obit-LePoulain     03-02 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Le Poulain,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Head of Comedie Francaise Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of <ORGANIZATION> Comedie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francaise </ORGANIZATION>, actor and director <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON>, died Tuesday night. He was 63. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON> died at his home on the Avenue de l'Opera, near the famed theater he had administered for the past two years. No cause of death was given. `` It is the theater of yesterday and today which can not, tonight, hide its tears,'' Culture Minister <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Leotard </PERSON> said in a statement. `` The curtain of the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Comedie </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Francaise </PERSON> has fallen on a great voice.'' <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON> had been a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Comedie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francaise </ORGANIZATION> since 1979 and was placed in charge in 1986. During his 40-year career in the theater, he acted in and directed dozens of plays from the classics to contemporary pieces. `` With his disappearance, French theater loses one of its most brilliant servants, an inheritor of the tradition of the <ORGANIZATION> Comedie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francaise </ORGANIZATION>, that which runs from <PERSON> Moliere </PERSON> to <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Charron </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Leotard </PERSON>'s statement said. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Marseille </LOCATION> Sept. 12, 1924, but spent much of his childhood in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, where his father worked. Returning to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> at the age of 19, he studied at the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Conservatory, which he left in 1949 with the first prize in acting. In 1952, he founded his own theater company, directing a variety of plays from <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> to <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Anouilh </PERSON>. <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON> was known to the public as both a buffoon and a tragedien, but he received the most acclaim for his portrayals in the plays of <PERSON> Moliere </PERSON>, such as `` Tartuffe'' and `` Le Bourgeois Gentilhomme.'' After taking over the <PERSON> Comedie </PERSON> <PERSON> Francaise </PERSON>, as the candidate proposed by President <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitterrand </PERSON>, <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Poulain </PERSON> neither acted nor directed. He said he concentrated his time to running the institution _ `` I am the protector of its soul.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugWars     03-02 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Wars,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Warns Mexico and Colombia on Drug Running</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HENRY GOTTLIEB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Alarmed by a rise in drug production and the violence that goes with it, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is warning <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> that their anti-narcotics programs will receive close scrutiny in the coming months. They were singled out Tuesday in the president's annual drug report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> as countries that are making some efforts to stop narcotics traffic but need to improve. They were not classed with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and a new entry on the list, <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, as countries whose support for drug trafficking makes them ineligible for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for international narcotics matters, said the message to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is: `` We believe that you're cooperating and you deserve certification, but we want to put an asterisk next to it and we will be watching closely in 1988.'' In the annual report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the president certifies whether countries are doing enough to battle narcotics to deserve <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance and other benefits. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> made the list this year because its military chief and de facto leader, <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, has been indicted by a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> grand jury on drug conspiracy charges. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is not a major narcotics producing country, but according to <LOCATION> Wrobleski </LOCATION>, `` <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has been a drug traffickers' and money launderers' haven.'' Putting <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> on the list will have no immediate impact, because the country had lost <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid even before <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s indictment But Tuesday's action does permit further steps by the administration, including some tariffs and tightening of customs rules that could hurt Panamanian exports. Sen. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said he would introduce legislation to go further by imposing a trade embargo on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` The good news is that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> is on the list,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Lawton </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiles </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>. `` On the other hand, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> are n't ... I think we have to continue to apply pressure against these countries.'' The president's report faulted <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> for not breaking a cartel of drug dealers and for not fully backing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> requests for extradition of drug suspects wanted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. At the same time, it noted that whatever efforts <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> made in the fight were `` at great peril to its officials.'' It said <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> is the largest single source of heroin and marijuana entering the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and officials there need to do more to eradicate opium poppies and deal with allegations of official corruption. Three countries said to be doing little to stop narcotics escaped inclusion on the list due to special `` national security concerns,'' the report said. <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> was kept off the list out of concern that a condemnation would harm <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to win <LOCATION> Laotian </LOCATION> help in accounting for more than 500 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen listed as missing there after the Vietnam War, <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> does n't get <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid anyway. <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> escaped decertification because officials think it would be counter-productive at a time the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is trying to woo that country toward democracy. <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> retained its certification because there is n't much the central government can do to stop trafficking and production in regions of the country it does not control. In its estimates of worldwide drug production, the report predicted that coca leaf output would increase from a high of 211,400 metric tons in 1987 to as much as 213,650 metric tons this year. Marijuana production will drop from a high of 17,625 metric tons to 10,100 tons, and opium output will drop from a high of 3,017 metric tons to 2,992 metric tons in 1988, the report said. A metric ton equals 2,200 pounds. Ms. <PERSON> Wrobleski </PERSON> said one of the gloomiest outlooks is for control of coca leaf growth, especially in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, the origin of a vast majority of the world's cocaine. <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> has made some strides in eradicating the crop by sending work crews into the production areas to kill the plants. That's impossible in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, she said, because the growers control the regions In <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, for example, 27 eradication workers have been killed, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0544EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--GirlsClubSuit     03-02 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Girls Club Suit,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Girls Clubs Sues to Protect Name</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Girls Clubs of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> leader says the organization's identity and fund-raising are threatened by a competing group it is suing. The suit filed Monday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> asks for an injunction to prevent the <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clubs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> from changing its name to the Boys and <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clubs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` The importance of this is the perception of the public as to who they are and who we are,'' <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON>, national executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Girls </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clubs </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Garth </PERSON>, national director-elect of the <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clubs </ORGANIZATION>, said that organization has about 300,000 girls among it 1.3 million members, and their parents are demanding the name change. The Girls Clubs says it serves about 250,000 girls and that about 40,000 boys participate in its activities. The organization says about 80 percent of it $ 2.7 million operating budget comes from contributions and grants that benefit its many members who come from lower-income families.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-SuperTuesday-Media Bjt   03-02 0951</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Super Tuesday-Media, Bjt,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Final Days Before Super Tuesday, Television Ads Get Tougher</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Presidential candidates are turning to increasingly aggressive television advertising in the week before the high-stakes Super Tuesday contests in 20 states and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>. Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is taking some heat on the Iran-Contra affair from Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> is moving onto the populist turf claimed thus far by Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. And <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> is continuing his broadside against <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, D-Mo., also is running an ad in which Rep. <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Leath </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> praises him for standing `` with us for lower taxes, for an oil import fee to make <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> strong, for a tough trade bill to stand up for American workers. <PERSON> Leath </PERSON> says <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> oppose all three. <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Arlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Schardt </PERSON> said Tuesday it had not been decided yet whether the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> senator would release his own cache of hard-hitting ads. `` We're prepared for any needs that may arise,'' <PERSON> Schardt </PERSON> said. `` We're considering what other messages we may still want to convey over the next few days.'' <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> did mount an indirect TV challenge to <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> on Tuesday, when he started running three new ads promoting populist themes similar to the ones <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> has adopted. One new ad depicts <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> as a fighter against polluters, price-fixers and big corporations _ exactly the type of anti-establishment image <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> has tried to cultivate. The other two ads feature <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> talking to groups of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> oil workers. In one spot he says corporations need to invest in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and create jobs at home, while in the other he tells the workers that `` it's time to put people back to work in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and have the rigs in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> stand idle for a change.'' The `` blame foreigners'' message is strikingly similar to one of <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s strongest ads, the `` <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION>'' spot that helped him win the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> caucuses and is now being used across the Super Tuesday states. In that ad the congressman criticizes <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for putting high import tariffs on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> autos and asks how many Hyundais the Koreans could sell here at $ 48,000 apiece. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> has also revived a highly effective <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> spot, now retooled for Super Tuesday, alleging that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is a tax-raiser and mocking his suggestion that depressed <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> farmers recover by growing Belgian endive. The <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign was planning to take aim at <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>'s newly acquired reputation as an anti-establishment crusader and possibly run an ad featuring a swirling weathervane to raise questions about his consistency <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s communications director, said no final decisions had been made about which ads would be used where and when. But he said the general thrust of the spots is that <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> `` says he is leading the little guy's fight but his campaign is financed and supported by the big guys. His biggest contributors are <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s biggest corporations. He has failed to show a set of principles or a set of values that give a rudder to his policies.'' He said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was also prepared to counter-attack against <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, if necessary. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has commercials on the air in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, the biggest Super Tuesday states, plus <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>. His ad campaign was to expand this week into <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, aides said. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., went on the air Tuesday in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> with an ad contrasting his and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s positions on a number of issues, including the Iran-Contra affair The narrator says <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> `` opposed selling arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supported the arms-for-hostages deal.'' The ad also accuses <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> of waffling on taxes, taking a soft line on the U.S.-Soviet arms control treaty, and opposing a textile bill popular in several Southern states. Another Dole spot running in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> depicts a man walking through snow but leaving no footprints. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> campaign manager <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> said the message is that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` has held all these big jobs'' yet left no mark. The vice president, in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, called the `` footprints'' commercial `` terribly ineffective.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign refused to disclose any details of how or whether it planned to respond. But the vice president said: `` We're not going to sit out there unprotected ... I think I have every right to set the record straight.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used a negative ad against <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> last month, but it ran for only a couple of days before the primary. As the Super Tuesday TV campaign grew more heated, Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, questioned <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s judgment in radio ads throughout <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, which holds a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary on Saturday. The <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> ad asks if the former television evangelist has `` the qualifications and the judgment to be our next president'' and cites some of his more unusual positions such as a 1979 suggestion that public schools be eliminated. <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> later changed his mind about that. In addition to negative ads, the candidates are using more traditional biographical spots and political testimonials. Among them: former Sen. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON> endorses <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> praises <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, and Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON> _ an elderly <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> legislator with enormous clout among senior citizens _ speaks kindly of <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>. At least two candidates, <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, are using Spanish-language ads in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> does the talking himself. `` The governor is fluent in Spanish, so it seemed like the thing to do,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosgrove </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> campaign director. There are 712 Republican delegates and 1,307 Democratic delegates up for grabs on Super Tuesday, March 8. Television is the candidates' major tool in seeking to win them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Soviet-AmericanVentures     03-02 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-American Ventures,0357</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet-American Team To Design Management Guidelines For Joint
Ventures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KAREN SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Academics and business managers from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will team up to study four industrial sites in each country in an effort to develop management guidelines for joint ventures. The study will mark the first time Westerners will be allowed to participate in on-site research of Soviet decision-making methods, project director <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday. The study is not aimed at encouraging joint ventures, but to `` make sure the projects that do get started are operated successfully and the combined management teams of Soviet and American managers will be able to work with each other effectively,'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said. Two faculty members from the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> business school and two representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> External </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, the research arm of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, will work on the study. The study, scheduled to begin in May and end in September, will include <PERSON> Electrosila </PERSON>, a Leningrad-based manufacturer of heavy industrial equipment. The other sites have not been determined, <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said. `` We want to prepare guidelines that will help the day-to-day management of joint ventures in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> with <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> firms,'' <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said. `` This could be in any number of fields.'' The research will focus on capital investments, appointing and terminating a middle manager, introducing a new product and formulating and implementing an annual business plan. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said the choices are a good cross-section of real business decisions. `` They represent quite a range of the kinds of things operating managers do,'' he said. Four case studies based on the research are expected to be completed by November and the final version is scheduled for publication by July 1989. The co-director of the <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> team is <PERSON> Charalambos </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlachoutsicos </PERSON>, a research fellow at the school. Co-chairmen of the Soviet team are <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Faminsky </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and B.I. <PERSON> Fomin </PERSON>, general director of <LOCATION> Electrosila </LOCATION>. The project will be jointly funded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ReporterResigns 1stLd-Writethru a0756 03-02 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reporter Resigns, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0756,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tribune Mideast Reporter Resigns Over Story Resembling One in
Another Paper</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 4th graf pvs, `That material...', to
add comment from Tribune editor, picking up 5th graf, `Broder's
story...'. DELETES last graf, now outdated.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A correspondent for the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> has resigned after writing a story that contained some material taken, without attribution, from a story printed in the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> published a brief notice of <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>'s resignation Monday under its `` Corrections and Clarifications'' headline <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>'s story Feb. 22 `` included a number of sentences and phrases taken, without attribution, from a column by another writer that had been published previously in the <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said. That material `` constitutes only a fraction of the total story and contributed significantly only to organization and imagery,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said. `` There's no justification for what he did. There's an explanation, but no justification,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> Editor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Squires </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` We said he cribbed the story and he resigned,'' <PERSON> Squires </PERSON> said. He declined further comment. <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>'s story began: `` Anyone traveling the roads of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> these days can not fail to notice the fundamental change that has overtaken the area in the last 10 weeks.'' The Jerusalem Post story began: `` Anyone traveling the roads of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> these days can not fail to sense the change that has come over the area in the last two months.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>'s story was accurate, but `` the byline inaccurately implied that it was all Mr. <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>'s work.'' <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>, a full-time reporter with the <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> since 1979, was with family in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said a <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> staff member who asked not to be identified. The staffer declined to provide a telephone number for <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880302-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-02-88 0025EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0857 03-02 1066</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0857,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Dukakis Are Victors In Vermont Beauty Contest</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, Bush was, to show Bush winner; INSERTS two
grafs after 2nd pvs to give Bush, Dole reactions, picking up 3rd
pvs, Former President; INSERTS one graf after 4th pvs, Bush
sounded, to give poll results; SUBS 7th and 8th grafs pvs, In
Vermont, to update percentages; INSERTS graf after 8th pvs, Dukakis
rolled, to give Jackson reaction.
^By DAVID ESPO</NOTE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
