<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DiabetesBoy     11-15 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Diabetes Boy,0456</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Sect Pastor Gets 2-Year Prison Term In Boy's Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN K. WILEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPOKANE, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge on Monday sentenced the former pastor of a faith-healing sect to two years in prison for his part in the death of the son of church members, saying he wanted to send a message to cultists. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Chapel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, was convicted of second-degree criminal mistreatment. <ORGANIZATION> Spokane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON> said circumstances warranted going beyond the standard 90-day sentence for the crime, the maximum the prosecutor sought. `` I have an obligation to send a message ... to anyone who might be interested in beginning a religious cult,'' <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON> told <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON>. <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> was the former pastor of a nameless Christian sect that eschewed conventional medicine in favor of prayer. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, the 10-year-old son of sect members <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, died Dec. 20, 1987, of untreated juvenile diabetes. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>, 43, was convicted last month of first-degree manslaughter for failing to seek medical attention for his son. Charges against Mrs. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> were dismissed prior to the trial. `` Why is it that it takes a tragedy for people to realize what they've been doing is wrong?'' asked <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON>. `` Medicine has been given to us by <PERSON> God </PERSON> as much as the power of prayer.'' <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> also was sentenced to serve six months for a charge of simple assault stemming from a spanking administered to an adult church member in a separate incident. That sentence will be served concurrently, meaning <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> will be eligible for parole in 16 months, <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON> said. Before he was sentenced, a tearful <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> told <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON> he was `` absolutely ashamed'' of his participation in the sect and its `` rigid view of the outside world.'' `` I am absolutely heartbroken for what happened to <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> said. Testimony during the three-week trial indicated the gravely ill boy was beaten the day before his death by his father and sect founder <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON> while <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> and other church elders watched. The beatings were believed necessary to get the boy to confess the sin of masturbation and be healed. As pastor, <PERSON> Siegel </PERSON> knew, or should have known, that <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> was vulnerable, <PERSON> Schultheis </PERSON> said. Spankings and other discipline of the 10-year-old `` manifested deliberate cruelty,'' the judge said. <PERSON> Kleber </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Champaign-Urbana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, has pleaded guilty to second-degree criminal mistreatment and is scheduled to be sentenced later. Testimony also revealed that members were expected to consult with church leaders on matters ranging from buying a car to their sex lives. The fellowship once claimed 300 adult members in four states, but disbanded in February.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HomelessDonations     11-15 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Homeless Donations,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homeless Helped By Harvard Law Students' Hotel Savings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> students are helping the homeless by making less expensive travel arrangements on job interview trips and asking prospective employers to donate the savings to shelters nationwide. `` We've got 125 -LRB- firms -RRB- going in on it, so I guess it's popular,'' school spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Chmura </PERSON> said of the program called Firm Commitment `` We're talking to the business school, the <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, and other schools to set up a similar thing for next year.'' In the job interview season that started in October, students are booking trips through a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> discount service, <ORGANIZATION> Filene </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Travel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chmura </PERSON> said. They are also staying at less expensive hotels than normal. The law firms interviewing the students are asked to donate the savings to a local homeless shelter. In addition to raising money through the firms, <ORGANIZATION> Filene </ORGANIZATION>'s is donating part of its travel agent commission to local shelters, <PERSON> Chmura </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SivaBust     11-15 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Siva Bust,0214</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khmer Bust Auction Record</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A five-headed Khmer bust of <PERSON> Siva </PERSON>, the Hindu god of destruction and reproduction, has sold for $ 574,200, an auction record for any Southeast Asian work of art at auction, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said The 31 -LCB- - inch high, gray sandstone bust was sold Monday by an anonynmous collector and bought by an unidentified overseas bidder The figure dated from the third quarter of the 10th century. No history of it was otherwise recorded, except that the uppermost head had been in the Pan Asian Collection, most of which is in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION>. Each of the heads wears an enigmatic smile. The uppermost head was acquired by the seller, who reunited it with the rest of the figure. The sale at Monday's auction of some 100 lots of Khmer, Thai, Indian and Himalayan art totaled $ 2.8 million. The three top-priced lots were sold by the same collector. A 7th century head of <PERSON> Buddha </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, larger than lifesize, was bought for $ 376,200 by a Swiss collector. Another anonymous buyer paid a similar price for a 4-foot standing figure of a Khmer four-armed male deity from the first half of the 9th century. The bidders included <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and Swiss collectors and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> dealers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     11-15 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0396</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Child's Play' Thriller At Top Of Box Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A thriller called `` Child's Play,'' featuring a homicidal doll named <PERSON> Chucky </PERSON>, carved out first place in the nation's weekend box office sweepstakes with a take of $ 6.5 million Pesky pitchman <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Worrell </PERSON> -LRB- played by actor <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Varney </PERSON> -RRB- teamed up with <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> in `` Ernest Saves Christmas,'' an early holiday offering that was in second place with $ 5.7 million in its first week of release. `` Iron Eagle II,'' with <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Gossett </PERSON> reviving his tough fighter pilot character, was third in formation with $ 3.5 million for its debut. `` They Live,'' director <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>'s exploration of yuppies as space aliens, was in fourth place with $ 2.7 million, followed by `` Everybody's All American.'' The movie about a football hero and his sweetheart earned $ 2.6 million. Several new movies are set for release this week in anticipation of large holiday audiences. They include `` High Spirits,'' `` 1969,'' `` Fresh Horses,'' and two animated offerings: <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> and Company'' and the <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg-George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> `` Land Before Time.'' Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross, and number of weeks in release 1. `` Child's Play,'' <ORGANIZATION> UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 6.5 million, 1,377 screens, $ 4,781 per screen, $ 8 million -LRB- five days -RRB-, one week. 2. `` Ernest Saves Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 5.7 million, 1,634 screens, $ 3,495 per screen, $ 5.7 million, one week. 3. `` Iron Eagle II,'' Tri-Star, $ 3.5 million, 874 screens, $ 4,038 per screen, $ 3.5 million, one week. 4. `` They Live,'' Universal, $ 2.7 million, 1,459 screens, $ 1,900 per screen, $ 8.9 million, two weeks. 5. `` Everybody's All American,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.6 million, 1,123 screens, $ 2,327 per screen, $ 7 million, two weeks. 6. `` The Accused,'' Paramount, $ 2.4 million, 930 screens, $ 2,594 per screen, $ 24.3 million, five weeks. 7. `` U2 Rattle and Hum,'' Paramount, $ 1.7 million, 1,459 screens, $ 1,178 per screen, $ 6.6 million, two weeks. 8. `` A Cry In The Dark,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 334 screens, $ 4,676 per screen, $ 1.5 million, one week. 9. `` Mystic Pizza,'' <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwyn </PERSON>, $ 1.38 million, 440 screens, $ 3,139 per screen, $ 6.5 million, four weeks. 10. `` Without A Clue,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.34 million, 460 screens, $ 2,920 per screen, $ 5.1 million, four weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-People-Jackson     11-15 0138</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People-Jackson,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pop Star Cancels Two Concerts Because of Swollen Vocal Chords</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop superstar <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> canceled a sold-out performance shortly before he was supposed to take the stage Monday night because of swollen vocal chords, his publicist said. The decision, announced about 40 minutes before the start of the show, was made on advice of the singer's physician, publicist <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Solters </PERSON> said. Tuesday's sold-out performance also was canceled, and both will be rescheduled at a later date, <PERSON> Solters </PERSON> said. An estimated 30,000 ticketholders at the Sports Arena were told to save their stubs for admission to the new shows, <PERSON> Solters </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> began a six-concert engagement Sunday night as part of his worldwide tour promoting his `` Bad'' album. Concerts on Nov. 20, 21, and 22 will go on as scheduled, <PERSON> Solters </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearSpread Bjt   11-15 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Spread, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<NOTE>For release 8 a.m. EST; time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Pakistan Now Armed With Nuclear Weapons, Study Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> appears to have finally developed atomic weapons, increasing the threat of a nuclear war with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and representing a major setback to efforts to stem the spread of atomic weapons around the globe, says a study published today. `` After a decade of slow advances, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> appears to have'' joined a group of three other nations that have nuclear weapons but do n't admit it, according to the review by the <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endowment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION>. The other countries in that category are <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, said the report, the fourth such survey published by the non-profit group that specializes in national security studies. Five nations have said they possess nuclear weapons: the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. A sixth, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, exploded a single atomic device in 1974 but said it was a non-military explosion. Efforts to halt the spread of nuclear weapons generally have focused on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, the report noted. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> have been the chief source of concern, since the two countries have fought three wars in the 41 years since they were created by the separation of colonial <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The report, titled `` The Undeclared Bombs,'' was written by <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Spector </PERSON>, author of the three previous reports. <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> formerly worked on non-proliferation issues at the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> and Natural Resources non-proliferation subcommittee. In the past two years, <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> said, `` convincing evidence emerged that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> had crossed the nuclear weapons threshold and had acquired the essentials for its first nuclear weapons.'' That evidence includes production of highly enriched uranium, a key component of atomic weapons; and European reports of a previously clandestine effort by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> officials to smuggle sophisticated nuclear components out of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The Pakistani program is a dilemma for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> said in an interview, because <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> is a prime recipient of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid at the same time <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials are pushing <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> not to develop atomic weapons. Two years ago, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> certified to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> did not possess nuclear weapons, a certification required by Capitol Hill before the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid program could go ahead. But in recent months, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have been less direct in asserting that the Pakistanis do n't have atomic weapons. Meanwhile, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has responded by quietly expanding its atomic weapons capability and has also worked on development of delivery systems, including medium-range rockets, the report said. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has the ingredients to build between 20 and 50 atomic weapons, it said. For the future, <PERSON> Spector </PERSON> said, `` most observers are looking for some sort of mechanism, some kind of regional arrangement, to bring <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> into negotiations. The concept is to find a way to persuade both antagonists to restrain themselves. It will be difficult, but it may be achievable.'' The report also highlighted increasing dangers in the volatile <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION>, particularly in light of the spread of long-range missiles and chemical weapons among Arab enemies of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has refused to admit to possessing nuclear weapons, but the report said the Israelis have `` a substantial, undeclared nuclear arsenal of at least 50 to 60 nuclear devices _ and perhaps significantly more _ some of which are an advanced design.'' The risk of nuclear escalation in a future <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> war has `` seriously increased,'' the study said, because of the improved capabilities of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> nations to inflict damage through missiles and chemical weapons. `` Indeed, in 1988, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> leaders began implicitly referring to this possibility by declaring that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> would have the ability to retaliate against an anti-city missile or chemical attack ` many times over,''' it said. In <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the report said, a nuclear monitoring agreement between <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> should be the `` top non-proliferation priority for the coming year.'' That is because <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> announced last year that it had mastered the process of enriching uranium and had begun a pilot program at a plant that was not subject to international safeguards. <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> had a similar capability at least five years ago, the report noted. While both nations have pledged not to produce weapons-grade uranium, those pledges need to be enshrined in formal policy, the study said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HospitalKidnapping 3rdLd-Writethru a0757NAVAN 11-15
0685</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hospital Kidnapping, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0757,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Premature Kidnapped Baby Found Safe</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 3rd graf `A 32-year-old' with two grafs to UPDATE with
charge filed, comment from suspect's neighbor. Picks up 4th graf pvs
``If she....'</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LR2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FREEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A premature baby stolen from a hospital two weeks ago by a woman posing as a nurse was found in good condition Monday, and the mother recommended the kidnapper `` just ask the Lord to forgive her for what she's done.'' <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who was born weighing only 4 pounds, was found at a home in <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, 50 miles away, by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents and police responding to a tip to a hot line, said <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> Detective <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. The caller said the baby might be at the home, he said. <PERSON> Acqunetta </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushon </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 32, who has worked as a nurse's aide in <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> and has four childre, was charged with kidnapping, said <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> police Lt. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. She was in jail Monday night and bond had not been set. A neighbor of Ms. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said she had not seen the baby during the past two weeks. `` All I heard was that she had had a baby,'' <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Kidd </PERSON> said. `` I never seen him. When I would see her coming in and out of her house, it looked like she could have been an expectant mama, you know, with the clothes she wore.'' `` If she took the baby because of a loss in her own life, I hope that she will have the opportunity to get some help,'' the child's mother, <PERSON> Annette </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON>, said at a news conference Monday night `` I forgive her.'' She held the baby, dressed in a tiny white shirt reading `` Welcome Home,'' and said, `` He looks like $ 250 million wrapped up _ not just a million, but 250 million. He looks fantastic. He looks like his daddy.'' When she first was reunited with <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON>, she said, `` I held him and I looked at him and I checked his fingers out and his toes out and his legs and his stomach and his head and everything's there. `` I feel wonderful, I feel relieved, joyful, thankful. I'm happy,'' she said `` I knew the Lord was going to bring <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> home for us.'' Applause broke out from a crowd of about two dozen neighbors and members the news media when Mrs. <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON>, 32, and her husband, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, 39, emerged from their house on their way to Doctors Hospital to be reunited with the infant. `` Praise the Lord, praise the Lord, hallelujah!'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON> shouted. `` I just want to thank the media,'' she said, tears welling up in her eyes and her voice breaking with emotion. `` Praise the Lord.'' Local broadcasts and newspapers had carried repeated appeals by Mrs. <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON>, her minister and others for information leading to the baby's return. The reports all noted that <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> needed continued medical attention because he was six weeks premature when he was born Oct. 29. Mrs. <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON>, who has two daughters, handed him over Nov. 1 to a woman posing as a nurse at the hospital who said she needed to weigh the baby. A banner at Doctors Hospital read `` Welcome Home, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON>'' in baby blue letters, and small baby blue ribbons were being handed out to employees and visitors by hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Szenher </PERSON>. Authorities first took <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> to <ORGANIZATION> AMI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> for an examination, said hospital executive director <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> <PERSON> Kass </PERSON>. `` The baby is in good condition, needs only what a normal infant should need, as far as we know,'' <PERSON> Kass </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> gained 1 -RCB- pounds since being kidnapped, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agent <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettus </PERSON> said. Dr. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Keathley </PERSON>, a pediatrician from Doctors Hospital who examined the baby, said: `` I was surprised. Somebody has spent a lot of time feeding him to put on a pound in two weeks.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thomas-Jones </PERSON> said: `` I agree. She took very good care of the baby.'' A positive identification was made through a footprint, said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolfe </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s Little Rock office.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugTesting Bjt   11-15 0762</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Testing, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Millions Of Transport Workers To Be Subject To Drug Tests</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of transportation workers including pilots and truckers will be subject to random drug tests under a new federal directive that is likely to be challenged in court before it goes into effect in December 1989. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced the broad-ranging drug testing requirements Monday, and immediately the head of the airline pilots' union promised to fight the regulation both in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and in the courts. The testing requirements cover all types of transportation, including airlines, long-distance trucks and urban transit systems. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people demand and expect a drug-free transportation system. These new rules will take us as far as practically possible toward that goal,'' <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnley </PERSON> said at a news conference. He acknowledged the tests likely will be challenged in the courts. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> already has before it two separate drug-testing cases _ including one involving post-accident testing of railroad workers _ that are expected to be decided next year. The series of federal regulations announced by <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> call for transportation companies _ airlines, trucking companies, railroads and commercial shipping companies _ to have comprehensive testing programs in place by December 1989. Companies with 50 or fewer employees, including tens of thousands of over-the-road independent truckers, have another year to comply. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> estimated the testing will cost businesses more than $ 2.1 billion during the first 10 years, but <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said the testing will save the same companies about $ 8.7 billion in increased productivity, accident reductions and medical cost savings. In addition to random tests, the regulations call for drug testing before employment if there is reasonable cause to suspect drug use, periodically such as during annual physicals, and after an accident. The drugs covered by the tests are marijuana, cocaine, opiates, amphetamines and PCP. The random-testing provision, which requires that at least 50 percent of a given work force be tested during a single year, has attracted the strongest protests, especially from unions. They argue that such tests constitute an invasion of privacy, have minimal benefit and will subject thousands of workers to the consequences of `` false positive'' results. `` Random testing is a counterproductive, shotgun strategy that is at the same time an unwarranted invasion of privacy and of no significant value in the battle against drug abuse,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON>, president of the 40,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The required testing programs cover: _ Nearly 3 million long-distance truckers, including independent drivers and those who work directly for large trucking companies Intercity bus drivers also must be tested. _ More than 538,000 aviation employees, including 50,000 commercial pilots, 80,000 flight attendants and 300,000 airline mechanics Air traffic controllers already are subject to similar testing requirements. _ About 90,000 railroad industry workers, including engineers, brakemen and train dispatchers _ Nearly 200,000 urban transit workers, including subway and transit bus drivers and mechanics _ About 200,000 merchant seamen and other mariners on commercial vessels that carry passengers or cargo Fishermen are not covered by the rules. Critics question whether the regulations can be enforced, at least as they pertain to independent long-distance truck drivers. DOT officials said such independents will have to join in `` testing pools'' or be tested under a program operated by the company for which they do business. Officials acknowledged the rules do not require truckers to carry proof that they are participating in a testing program. `` The big question is how are you going to enforce it'' in the case of the self-employed independents, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trucking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associations </ORGANIZATION>, which represents the trucking companies. <PERSON> Duffy </PERSON> of the airline pilots union said he fears random testing `` may be used by management as a punitive measure against pilots.'' He criticized the DOT regulation for leaving the program to be administered by management with no requirement for rehabilitation. <ORGANIZATION> Burnley </ORGANIZATION> said the aim is `` getting the people -LRB- with drug problems -RRB- off the jobs.'' He said the issue of rehabilitation will have to be worked out through labor-management negotiations. DOT officials said in the last two years there have been 60 railroad accidents in which participants were found to have been using drugs, although drug use was not always directly implicated in the accidents. The worst of these was a Jan. 4, 1987 collision of a <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> locomotive and an <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> passenger train in Chase, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, in which 16 people were killed and 178 were injured. The <ORGANIZATION> Conrail </ORGANIZATION> engineer and brakeman admitted having smoked marijuana shortly before the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bishops     11-15 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bishops,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Bishops Weigh Rejection of Draft Vatican Document</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT FURLOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION> is moving toward a showdown vote on whether to reject a draft <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> document questioning the theological authority of such conferences. The bishops softened the wording of their proposed reply to the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> document on Monday but pressed toward a scheduled Wednesday vote without changing their underlying judgment: `` The draft is not suitable.'' Despite frequent public compliments from both sides, relations have often been uneasy between the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> and bishops' conferences, particularly those such as the Americans' which have seemed to be growing in prestige in recent years. Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> II has publicly supported many of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conference's efforts, including national pastoral letters that stirred controversy outside the church for their criticism of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration policies on nuclear arms and the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy. However, there also has been criticism from high <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials, who have asked for whom the bishops were speaking in commenting on matters of doctrine, and on what authority. Also on Monday, acceding to a <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> request, the bishops postponed a vote on another controversial item _ but did so only grudgingly and with rare public complaints about the way church leaders in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> had handled the situation. While the bishops gave ground, they took pains to say they were not knuckling under to <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> pressure. `` We have not bowed obsequiously to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> in an untoward fashion,'' said Archbishop <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipscomb </PERSON> of Mobile, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, objecting to a reporter's suggestion that that was what had happened. About 300 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Roman Catholic cardinals, archbishops and bishops had been scheduled to vote today on new guidelines for settling disputes between theologians and bishops. But a letter from the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith complained that the guidelines would make the theologians and bishops equals in the settlement process. Bishop <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Lessard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, chairman of the bishops' <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doctrine </ORGANIZATION>, said he felt all that was `` sufficiently addressed'' in the guidelines document However, he added that it seemed wise to postpone action until the bishops' June meeting. Several bishops complained about the timing of the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s complaint, including Cardinal <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernardin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, who said the intervention `` might be perceived as confrontational or as belittling the episcopal conference, which I know is not intended. Cardinal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> said the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> agency was understaffed, a possible explanation for the last-minute nature of the objection. However, Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, president of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bishops conference, said the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> had had the proposal for more than a year. As for the draft <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> document on bishops' conferences, a number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bishops apparently had been stung by news stories quoting in advance from the proposed rejection notice. The new version, distributed by a committee of past conference presidents on Monday, is considerably toned down from the original, which had used such phrases as `` rigid and confusing'' and `` overly defensive and negative'' to describe the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> draft. However, it still calls for the bishops to label the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> effort `` non-placet,'' so flawed that it is n't even suitable to be used as a basis for revision. Several bishops objected to such a label, suggesting it would be a slap at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. This raised the possibility that the conference's objections would have to be softened further if they are to win the two-thirds majority necessary in Wednesday's vote. In other action Monday, the bishops: _ Gave first reading to one proposal that would call for easing of a 1986 law and give legal standing to many more undocumented Hispanic workers, and to another resolution calling for acceleration of religious freedom and an end to intimidation of worshipers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and other Eastern bloc countries _ Postponed action on a resolution calling for movement toward normalization of relations between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Archbishop <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahony </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Vietnamese-American </PERSON> groups in this country were divided on the issue, but he said the postponement was merely to give the bishops time to consider conditions in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> in general. _ Heard Archbishop <PERSON> Pio </PERSON> <PERSON> Laghi </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> representative to the bishops as well as to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, call for greater effort in keeping Hispanic-Americans in the church He did not publicly mention the simmering Vatican-bishops disputes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Heart-Exercise Bjt   11-15 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heart-Exercise, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Shows Poor Physical Fitness Triples Heart Risk in Women</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL Q. HANEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Women in poor physical shape are three times more likely to die at an early age of heart disease than are those who keep themselves in good condition, according to a long-term study. Dr. <PERSON> Lars </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON>, the principal author of the study, said it provides the first strong evidence that exercise protects women from heart disease, just as it does men. Poor physical fitness `` is almost as important as smoking as a risk factor for cardiovascular disease'' in women, said <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON>, a researcher at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>. The study was based on a 10 -LCB- - year follow-up of 2,802 women who ranged in age from 30 to 69 The results were presented Monday at the annual meeting of the American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` This had been seen in males. Now it carries over into females,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> McHenry </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Krannert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>. `` This confirms what we all expected.'' During the study, women walked on treadmills while their heart rates were measured. Those who are physically fit have lower heart rates while exercising than do people who are in poor shape. The researchers divided the women into four groups, depending on their heart rates. During mild exercise, those in the most fit group averaged 107 beats per minute, compared with 152 beats among the least fit women. During the decade of followup, 40 women died of heart attacks, strokes and heart failure. The risk of cardiovascular death was less than 1 percent among the fit women and 2 percent in those who were unfit. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> said that while much of the difference in physical fitness may be inherited, people can also improve their level of fitness by exercise. `` It has been shown by many studies that you can improve fitness levels by just walking,'' he said. `` Many people could benefit from this. Later, if they felt like they needed more, they could progress to jogging. But the important thing is to have a regular exercise program.'' The new findings in women are similar to those reported by the same researchers in a study of men. <PERSON> Ekelund </PERSON> said the risk of being out of shape is close to that of smoking or high blood pressure. Being unfit may be more of a problem for women than for men, he said, because less than 20 percent of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> women say they get regular physical activity, compared with about a third of all men. Among other studies presented at the meeting: _ Consumption of fat by Americans has fallen substantially since the mid-1960s Dr. <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saskatchewan </ORGANIZATION> said people may simply be trimming meat better and throwing away more fat. She said the dietary change may be a major cause of the drop in heart attack deaths that began in the late 1960s. _ Doctors report progress in developing a variety of devices that clean out clogged heart arteries by shaving, sanding and burning away fatty deposits All of them are intended to improve or replace balloon angioplasty, a widely used procedure in which doctors reopen clogged arteries by temporarily inflating tiny balloons inside them. _ The heart disease death rate is declining dramatically among middle-aged white men A study by Dr. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuller </PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> showed that in one county in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, the death rate in this group fell 53 percent between 1970 and 1984. A decline in cardiac arrest accounted for the largest share of the drop.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Bernstein     11-15 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bernstein,0445</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bernstein Celebrates 45th Conducting Anniversary</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: No PMs planned</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, whose 70th birthday in August was marked with a gala at <LOCATION> Tanglewood </LOCATION>, returned to <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philharmonic </ORGANIZATION> 45 years after he made his triumphant conducting debut there with the orchestra. And of course, Monday night's program consisted of three <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> compositions that were played shimmeringly well. As well it should: It was the 1,215 th time <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> conducted the orchestra On Nov. 14, 1943, <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, the Philharmonic's then-assistant conductor, filled for an ailing <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> on such short notice there was no rehearsal. The concert was broadcast nationally on radio. And there was such acclaim that <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>, who had never led the orchestra in concert until that day, was catapulted to fame, at age 25. At intermission, Mrs. <PERSON> Artur </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodzinski </PERSON>, whose late husband was the Philharmonic music's director in 1943 and hired <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> as his assistant, was introduced from a box. Violinist <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Margolies </PERSON>, who played in the Philharmonic that Sunday, is still a member and was playing on Monday night. Eight others who also were members in 1943 _ violinist <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fishzohn </PERSON>, oboist <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Goltzer </PERSON>, timpanist <PERSON> Saul </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, bassist <PERSON> Homer </PERSON> <PERSON> Mensch </PERSON>, cellist <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ormandy </PERSON>, assistant concertmaster <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenker </PERSON>, and trumpeters <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Vacchiano </PERSON> _ went on stage. <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> gave bear hugs to all nine. `` I feel older than all of them,'' said <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> was given a silver box engraved with a reproduction of Monday evening's program cover _ a caricature of him, with jutting chin, bright eye, flowing hair and baton, and reading `` with love and thanks of the Philharmonic family to <PERSON> Lennie </PERSON>.'' `` Will this birthday never end?,'' he told the audience. Monday's concert began with <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>'s `` Chichester Psalms,'' with the splendid Westminster Symphonic Choir. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boychoir </ORGANIZATION> whose voice is high, pure and moving, sang the solo part. Violinist <PERSON> Gidon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kremer </PERSON>, a native of the Latvian town of <LOCATION> Riga </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, was soloist in `` Serenade for Violin, String Orchestra, <PERSON> Harp </PERSON> and Percussion.'' <PERSON> Kremer </PERSON>'s sound is n't warm but his technique is breathtaking. Pianist <PERSON> Krystian </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimerman </PERSON>, who was born in <LOCATION> Zabrze </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, often performs with <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. He was the respectful and thoroughly engaged soloist in the final work on the program, <PERSON> Bernstein </PERSON>'s `` Symphony No. 2 for Piano and Orchestra,'' subtitled `` The Age of Anxiety'' after W.H. <PERSON> Auden </PERSON>'s poem. All the performers donated their services, with proceeds benefiting the Philharmonic's efforts on behalf of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> conductors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Personality-Disease     11-15 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Personality-Disease,0331</SECOND>
<HEAD>Psychotherapy May Help Prevent Cancer and Heart Disease, Studies
Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Risks for cancer or heart disease may be revealed through analyzing personality, and psychotherapy may be able to head off the diseases, according to controversial research. `` If the research ... holds up under ongoing scientific scrutiny, we will be entering a new era of health care and disease prevention,'' British psychologist <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Eysenck </PERSON> writes in the December issue of Psychology Today. The thrust of research by <PERSON> Eysenck </PERSON> and psychologist <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Grossarth-Maticek </PERSON> is that repressed emotions and hopelessness may lead to cancer, and hostility and aggression to heart disease. <PERSON> Grossarth-Maticek </PERSON> has developed a six-question personality quiz to identify people prone to cancer or heart disease, <PERSON> Eysenck </PERSON> writes. But in a statement accompanying Eysenck's article, senior editor <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischman </PERSON> warns that researchers have spotted inconsistencies and technical problems in <LOCATION> Grossarth-Maticek </LOCATION>'s studies. One psychologist found the studies `` unable to achieve the level of certainty that science demands,'' <PERSON> Fischman </PERSON> writes. `` The findings right now represent more hope than certainty, but it is because of that hope, and the hope for further debate and research, that we are presenting them,'' <PERSON> Fischman </PERSON> writes. According to Eysenck, <PERSON> Grossarth-Maticek </PERSON>'s studies supported the theory by predicting disease 10 years or more before people died of it. In that research, almost half the people considered cancer-prone died from that disease and fewer than a tenth from heart disease. Of those considered at risk for heart disease, about a third died of it but only one-fifth died of cancer, <PERSON> Eysenck </PERSON> wrote. Other studies found the risk could be reduced through psychotherapy aimed at the personality flaws, <PERSON> Eysenck </PERSON> wrote. For example, 45 of 50 people considered cancer-prone who went through psychotherapy were still alive 13 years later, compared to 19 of another 50 at risk who did not receive psychotherapy, he said. Some studies also suggest similar psychotherapy can help people with cancer live longer, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-WomanPresident     11-15 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Woman President,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Says Woman President `Inevitable'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told a group of schoolchildren that he believes it's `` inevitable'' that a woman will one day be president, most likely after first serving as vice president. The president's comments came during a question-and-answer session with junior and senior high school students from four Washington-area schools. `` As a matter of fact, the statesman in the world that I have met, that I respect the most, is the prime minister of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, and she's done a remarkable job for <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>,'' the president said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will play host to Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> for an official visit and state dinner at the White House later this week. The <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister has been his closest friend and ally in the <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alliance </LOCATION> during his nearly eight years in office. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the idea of a woman president would take `` a little getting used to on the part of some people. But I think it's inevitable that in this country there will be a woman president because they've come up in so many different fields. He added: `` It's just my feeling that probably, rather than one of them just entering the fray to run for president to begin with, that maybe it would probably start with one of them, as we did in the election in 1984, ... running for vice president. She did n't make it, but that might be the start of it, and I welcome it. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was referring to then-Rep. <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, who had the second spot on the Democratic ticket headed by former Vice President <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-15 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trade Problems To Face Incoming Agriculture Secretary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nagging trade problems and preliminary maneuvering on a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm bill will face the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's incoming secretary of agriculture next year. Lobbying for the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> post already is in full swing, although President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and his advisors have been focusing on other matters and have dropped no hints about who might get the job. Trade issues will be near the top of the agenda for the new agriculture secretary. Little progress has been made in reaching agreement on farm provisions of a new 97-nation General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- agreement, despite two years of talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>. A <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> call for phasing out farm subsidies by the year 2000 has received a chilly reception. Also stalled are talks aimed at reaching a new long-term grain agreement with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The most recent, five-year agreement expired Sept. 30 and there have been no formal talks since Oct. 24, when the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejected a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> proposal calling for a one-year agreement. A free-trade agreement that would phase out most tariffs between the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> had been approved by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> but is running into trouble in <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION>. That is not viewed as altogether bad among some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat producers and potato growers who never had much use for the pact anyway. Failure of the agreement, however, would be guaranteed to make life more complex for the next agriculture secretary. On <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committees </ORGANIZATION> plan to start talking next year about a farm bill to replace the omnibus 1985 farm legislation that expires in two years. The 1985 law is largely a blueprint for a massive cleanout of huge grain surpluses that had piled up, driving down prices and bringing on what came to be known as the crisis in rural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Huge subsidies were provided to boost exports at clearance sale prices as part of the effort to make farm surpluses disappear. Surplus milk and cheese remaining on the shelf were simply given away to the poor. The measure is generally viewed as a success. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> analysts say net cash income for the farm sector in 1988 should be near, and may top by a small margin last year's record $ 57.1 billion, despite the summer drought. For that reason many in the agricultural community think there will be little change in the thrust of the next bill. But the secretary is certain to face an array of tough challenges as lawmakers set about their work. New programs to help specific crops are bound to be debated along with plans to reform the troubled federal crop insurance program and further tighten pesticide regulation. With the 70-year-old Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> saying the time for retirement has arrived, or at least will when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is sworn in, candidates are lining up for the secretary's job. One who says he does not want to serve in the Cabinet and would like to return to private industry is <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>. The one-time <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> feedlot operator had long been mentioned as a possible future agriculture secretary. Getting a strong boost from congressional Republicans is Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, R-Mo. He is a force on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> but is not a farmer and, thus, like <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>, might need to have someone with experience in production agriculture in the deputy secretary's slot <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>'s deputy, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, raised crops and livestock in southeastern <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> between 1955 and 1982, when he came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to become head of the Soil and <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. He has become a favorite at <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign assurances to voters that he is an environmentalist might sway him to opt for <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, the architect of several major soil conservation measures contained in the 1985 farm law. That far from exhausts the list. If <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON>'s low-key, businesslike approach captures <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s fancy, the new president could turn to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lesher </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> consultant and former <PERSON> Lyng </PERSON> business partner. Also being mentioned are former Rep. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> soybean farmer <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> past President <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Delano </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An additional 300,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corn has been sold to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for delivery in the current marketing year, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced. The announcement Monday brings the total of American corn sold to the Soviets for delivery in the year that started Sept. 1 to 4,715,600 tons, the department said in a statement. It did not give further details but at the price of $ 134.50 a metric ton delivered at <LOCATION> Rotterdam </LOCATION>, announced by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> last week, the value of the shipment could be a little more than $ 40.3 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp     11-15 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court: No Abortion Veto Rights for Fathers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, at least for now, is keeping out of the continuing national debate over abortion rights. The justices on Monday refused to give husbands legal power to prevent their wives from terminating pregnancies. Without comment, they rejected arguments by an <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> man who said he had `` fundamental rights and interests in his unborn child.'' The action left intact a state court ruling that upheld a mother's right to have an abortion. There has been speculation that an increasingly conservative high court is prepared to take a new look at its landmark 1973 ruling, <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, that legalized abortion nationwide. The author of the 12-year-old court opinion, Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>, has said he believes there is `` a very distinct possibility'' <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> will be reversed during the court's current term But on Monday, the justices gave no signs they are eager to tackle an abortion controversy now. The court let stand a ruling last July by the <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that said allowing a husband to block a wife's abortion is barred by past high court rulings. The high court in 1976 struck down a <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> law requiring spousal consent before a woman could obtain an abortion during the first 12 weeks of her pregnancy. The <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> case stems from an attempt last summer by <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Conn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Elkhart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, to prevent his estranged wife, <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>, from having an abortion. She was about six weeks pregnant at the time. A state trial judge issued a temporary order barring Mrs. <PERSON> Conn </PERSON> from having the operation, but a state appeals court threw out that order. `` <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> has no right to veto <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON>'s decision ... as such decision concerns only her,'' the appeals court ruled. The <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> upheld the appeals court ruling. The injunction prohibiting Mrs. <PERSON> Conn </PERSON>'s abortion was lifted last July 22 and she had an abortion. The Conns are in the midst of divorce proceedings. <PERSON> Conn </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bopp </PERSON> of Terre Haute, said a decree is expected within days The father argued that the 1973 and 1976 high court rulings did not preclude state courts from taking a husband's rights into consideration `` on a case-by-case basis.'' `` The father has fundamental rights and interests in his unborn child which should be judicially considered, on the facts of this case, along with the rights and interests of his wife in aborting their child,'' lawyers for <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> <PERSON> Conn </PERSON> said. But the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> courts rejected such a balancing test. In other action, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>: _ Cleared the way for enforcement of federal court subpoenas requiring <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> and <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to turn over financial records and other material to a grand jury The justices refused to shield the deposed president and first lady of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> from the subpoenas, related to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> case in which they are charged with looting their nation's treasury of more than $ 100 million. _ Ruled, 6-3, in a case from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> that states may hold a second sentencing trial for a defendant mistakenly sent to prison as a habitual offender _ Let stand a ruling in a <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> case that the federal Voting Rights Act, designed to prevent racial discrimination, applies to state judicial elections _ Agreed to consider the constitutionality of a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> law aimed at assuring that beer sold in the state costs no more than it does in three neighboring states _ Agreed to decide in a case from <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> whether investors' claims against brokers must be settled by binding arbitration _ Agreed to use a case from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> involving truckers and one from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> involving a liquor distributor to determine whether states must refund taxes collected under laws later declared unconstitutional
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BankingChairman     11-15 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Banking Chairman,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gonzalez Says S&amp;L Industry Crisis Is Top Priority</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: St Germain with no period is cq</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> says the savings and loan industry crisis would be his top priority as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, but analysts say his expected selection to the post may might delay a solution. With the backing of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leaders, the 72-year-old <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat is considered the most likely successor to Rep. <PERSON> Fernand </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> St </PERSON> <PERSON> Germain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, defeated last week in his bid for a 15th term. <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, a hot-tempered, outspoken maverick, is urging swift action before the poor condition of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> becomes a `` chaotic crisis.'' He advocates establishing a $ 50 billion line of credit from the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, to be partly repaid from the sale of loans and property from failed S & amp; Ls. `` Nobody wants a taxpayer bailout ... but there are limits to what the industry can do and they've reached those limits,'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brokers </ORGANIZATION> on Monday. <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> later told reporters, `` If it ever gets around that there's nothing insuring those accounts and deposits, you could have chaos.'' Some analysts said they believed <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>' sometimes confrontational style could further fragment an already divided <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, thus complicating congressional efforts to find a solution to the S & amp; L industry crisis. `` He's bright. He understands problems and he can be very direct with what he says,'' said <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ely </PERSON>, a financial institutions consultant in <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` But it's one thing to be able to make cogent comments and it's another thing to be able to forge a legislative compromise. That may be where he has problems.'' A new banking chairman is also taking over in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Mich., is expected to succeed <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON>, D-Wis., who is The new <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration likely will fill the leadership vacuum left by the transition in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, according to <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Brumbaugh </PERSON>, a savings industry consultant and former chief economist of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. But, he added, `` it's hard not to believe this is going to slow momentum.'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, a 27-year veteran of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, gets high marks from colleagues for personal integrity and a willingness to speak his mind. They also say he is a likeable man, despite a temper that caused him two years ago to slug a man who called him a communist. However, many question <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>'s ability to rein in his own views enough to ride herd on a committee with more than 50 members and nearly as many factions. In 1977, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> was appointed to chair a special committee to investigate the assassinations of President <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. But within weeks he quit in a dispute with the chief counsel, leaving the committee in turmoil. As chairman of the Banking subcommittee on housing since 1981, <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> has shown a confrontational style. He once called Housing and Urban Development Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, the only black member of the <ORGANIZATION> Reagan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>, `` a Stepin Fetchit.'' He also had advocated the impeachment of former <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Volcker </PERSON>, who was pushing up interest rates in the early 1980s to fight inflation. Former Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reuss </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Democrat who preceded <ORGANIZATION> St </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Germain </ORGANIZATION> as banking committee chairman, says <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> might do better in the post than many expect. Under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration it just has not been possible to pass housing legislation, <PERSON> Reuss </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> has `` shown a capacity to learn and grow ... and I think that will stand <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in good stead.'' <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> discounted talk that he may be too rigid in his views. `` I've never considered myself an ideologue no matter how I've been labeled,'' he said `` You -LRB- ca n't -RRB- last in politics unless you're in the traditional American vein of pragmatism.'' He said much of the criticisms circulating are `` hobgoblins calculatedly set forth by those who ... have ambitions themselves.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush-Fitness     11-15 0442</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Fitness,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>President-elect Covets Time For Exercise, Fishing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GULF STREAM, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, just finished with a two-mile run, bounded across the beach and threw himself into the choppy waters. He caught a wave, body-surfed in and swam around a while. Later he waded back in shoulder-deep to cast a fishing line against the brisk waves. After an hour or so, he took a break to visit his mother and go to church, then piloted a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs power boat some 40 miles back down the coast and leaped into the water for more fishing. Afterward he played nine holes of golf. This was a typical vacation day for the 64-year-old man who takes over the White House next Jan. 20. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> showed during his four-day stay in this balmy beach community that his idea of relaxation is physical activity. He enjoys a variety of outdoor sports. One day he followed his morning jog with a trip out to a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> cutter 400 yards offshore in a motorized raft. He jumped off the cutter and swam part of the way in, then grabbed a rope off the raft for an arm-numbing tow to shore against the choppy waters. White House physician Dr. <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> has pronounced <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s fitness `` exceptional for a man his age'' and expressed amazement at his health and stamina His loping walk is that of a younger man, and he moves around a tennis court with an alacrity that makes up for his unimpressive serve. In an Election Day match, he and son <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> played doubles with son <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and son-in-law <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> LeBlond </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, just hours before <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> learned he had been elected president. The president-to-be lunged for balls and zigzagged across the court, energetic and clearly competitive with the younger men. Toward the end of his long presidential campaign, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> complained of physical fatigue, saying he missed having the time to jog, which he said invigorates him. Often on the campaign trail he had a stationary bicycle brought to his hotel room. Since the election, he seems to be making up for the inactivity of long airplane rides and motorcades. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters in a beachfront news conference that his Friday-through-Tuesday morning vacation in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> helped him clear his mind. `` I've been able to run every day,'' he said. `` I love the fishing. It does n't matter what you catch, it's the fact you're out there and fishermen know that. And so I'm still of the <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> school, that the days I spend fishing should not be deducted from the time I spend on earth.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Heart-Lifestyle     11-15 0738</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heart-Lifestyle,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lifestyle Changes Reverse Heart Disease Symptoms</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Heart-Exercise Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A vegetarian diet, quitting cigarettes, moderate exercise and up to an hour a day of yoga meditation can help reverse heart disease symptoms without the use of drugs, according to a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> study. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>, a professor of medicine at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, said that instead of using any drugs, his program forced dramatic changes in lifestyle to bring a significant improvement in the health of patients with coronary artery disease. The program is radical, he admits, but for the small group tested, it worked. `` For many who have heart disease,'' said <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>, `` the conventional therapy -LRB- which includes drugs or surgery, some diet revision and exercise -RRB- may not go far enough.'' <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> outlined his research in a paper presented Monday at the annual meeting of the American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. He devised a strict program that started with a week of training and preparation, a vegetarian diet that was less than 10 percent fat, and 16 hours a week of group therapy. Patients who smoked were required to quit. A moderate exercise program, usually walking, was devised individually for each patient. And, to manage stress, the patients were taught yoga meditation and relaxation exercises. To test the concept, <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> put 50 patients with coronary artery disease into two groups. All were tested to find the condition of their arteries, how well their hearts were supplied with blood, and the amount of cholesterol in their bloodstream. Cholesterol is a fatty material in blood that can lead to clogged arteries. For those in the first group, <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> provided the traditional lifestyle care, which included some counseling on how to lower cholesterol levels, controlling high blood pressure and quitting smoking. The second group, however, was placed on what <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> called `` a very demanding regimen'' of lifestyle changes. `` We were asking them to make huge changes in their lifestyle and then evaluated the effects'' using high technology X-ray and imaging techniques, he said. The program started with a seven-day retreat during which the patients were evaluated by a psychologist and by exercise experts. They were taught how to use yoga to relieve stress, and were placed on the strict diet. After the retreat, the group met for eight hours, two days a week for instruction sessions in exercise, yoga and food preparation. `` We provided the low-fat food for some in take-home containers,'' said <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>. `` They found it was not as hard as you would think. The group support goes a long way.'' At the end of a year, 29 patients completed the testing analysis _ 12 in the lifestyle changes group, and 17 in the ordinary care, or control, group. For the control group, the arterial lesions, or clogging of vessels supplying blood to heart, grew worse. Vessels that were 44.1 percent blocked closed further, to 46.2 percent blocked. For the lifestyle group, the progression of the disease was halted and some arteries measurably opened up, providing additional blood flow to the heart. They went from an average of 44.4 percent blocked to 40.8 percent, a clear regression improvement in the artery health, said <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>. `` There was a significant decrease in blockages in the lifestyle treatment group and a significant increase in blockages in the control group,'' he said. <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> said he used yoga and other stress control techniques because earlier studies have shown `` emotional stress can play a role in increasing and reducing lesions.'' Also, he said, `` stress can increase cholesterol -LRB- in the bloodstream -RRB- regardless of diet.'' <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON> said studies have shown, for instance, that cholesterol rates go up for drivers during auto races and for students during final examinations. `` Yoga is an ancient way of managing stress,'' said <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>. `` It's very practical.'' He said patients were urged to meditate an hour a day. Cholesterol counts in the treatment group declined from a median of 227 milligrams per decaliter to 135, well below the recommended maximum of 200. Patients in the study were aged 40 to 74, he said, and those who were the sickest seemed to be helped the most. `` The blockages that were the most severe seem to improve the greatest,'' said <PERSON> Ornish </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> scientist cautioned that though the results were encouraging, they are preliminary, and that the number of patients was too small to draw final conclusions on the value of the treatment system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Sakharov     11-15 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sakharov,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nobel Laureate Steps Up Criticism Of Gorbachev</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, the Nobel laureate and Soviet human rights activist, says Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is using `` undemocratic means'' in attempts to improve conditions in their country. `` From my point of view this is dangerous,'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said. He spoke Monday to a group of American intellectuals after comparing notes on human rights and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION> with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at the White House. Today, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> is scheduled to receive the <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON> peace prize and a $ 50,000 award for making `` an enormous impact on the conscience of the world.'' A nuclear physicist who helped develop the Soviet hydrogen bomb, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> has long been the principal human rights advocate in his country. He was confined to virtual house arrest in Gorky for six years until <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> arranged his release in 1986. The Soviet leader also arranged for <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s first visit to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, at a session Monday of the <ORGANIZATION> Woodrow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wilson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scholars </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may not have a long-range program for reform. He said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> improvises, and often `` compromises with existing forces that negate his efforts.'' Specifically, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear physicist criticized <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s consolidation of power, the absence of multi-party and free-market systems as well as restrictions on meetings and demonstrations `` There is no clear realization how this system should be reformed,'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said. In fact, he said, the partial reforms arranged by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> could lead to `` disequilibrium.'' Before leaving the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> on his first trip to the West, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> leveled similar criticisms at the Soviet president. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> supports glasnost _ a term for openness that has marked <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s 3 -LCB- years in power _ but complains that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> leader has accumulated too much power as both president and Communist party chief. `` His tactic seems to be getting democratic reforms through undemocratic means,'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said. `` From my point of view this is a dangerous action.'' On the human rights front, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said some dissidents remain in psychiatric institutions along with many more people who were chronic critics of their employers. He called the detention system `` one of the most acute abuses'' in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Earlier, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> discussed the plight of dissidents with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> at the White House. The president said until the problem is `` completely eliminated'' human rights will remain an irritant in U.S.-Soviet relations. The 67-year-old <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> for about 20 minutes in the Oval Office. They shared a cautious approach to the measures taken by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, mindful of reporters at a picture-taking session, drew <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s attention to two dissidents, <PERSON> Vazif </PERSON> <PERSON> Meylanov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Kukobaka </PERSON>, who <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> said still are being held. He called the detention of <PERSON> Meylanov </PERSON> `` ironic'' since he was sent to prison protesting the removal of <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to Gorky in 1980. `` I'm free to travel and he is in prison,'' the human rights activist said. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, speaking through an interpreter, said <PERSON> Kukobaka </PERSON> is in prison for refusing to bear false witness against a foreign diplomat. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> as more cooperative than any <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leader before him, but said `` we can only wait and see'' if the Soviet leader makes good on a promise to release all political prisoners. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> told the president `` there are only individuals'' left in jails, implying that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, in principle at least, does not adhere to a policy of detaining dissidents for their views. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, winner of the Nobel Peace Prize, also voiced concern about the impact that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s missile defense program, known popularly as Star Wars, might have on efforts by the superpowers to negotiate a cut in long-range nuclear missile stockpiles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     11-15 0027</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0026</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stocks Up In Tokyo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 28,829.41 points, up 308.51 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Tuesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EnergyEfficiency     11-15 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Energy Efficiency,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Department Corrects Natural Gas Figures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Energy Department says it overestimated how much natural gas American industry has been using, a mistake that had set off false alarms about the energy efficiency of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy. The error arose when a new reporting form confused many of the companies that report gas deliveries to the department's <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> EIA </ORGANIZATION>'s quarterly publication `` Short Term Energy Outlook'' for October, which reached users Monday, said the previous quarter's estimates of industrial natural gas consumption in the first half of 1988 were about 8 percent too high The agency started checking its statistics when the July edition of its outlook reported a 26 percent first-half increase in industrial gas use, implausibly high. In fact, the first half increase was about 6 percent to 3.13 trillion cubic feet. Natural gas is a major source of energy for home heating, electricity generation, chemical manufacture and industrial process heat. A little less than a quarter of all energy comes frm gas; industrial gas use is about 8 percent of the total national energy bill. Without the exaggerated natural gas changes, there would have been no significant change in the estimated energy efficiency in the economy, the closely watched ratio of energy used in producing a dollar's worth of goods and services. Environmentalists use this as a rough indicator of damage to the environment from economic activity; policymakers watch it as an indication of future vulnerability to interruption of oil imports. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> EIA </ORGANIZATION> analyst, said the agency distributed new reporting forms to gas companies delivering gas to industrial users with the start of 1988. The new forms asked for physical deliveries of gas no matter who owned it. The old forms required listing deliveries only of gas owned by the reporting company, no matter who delivered it. Some companies continued to report the old way, which meant some gas was counted twice _ once by the owner, once by the shipper. <ORGANIZATION> EIA </ORGANIZATION> said `` 43 companies apparently have consistently misreported their monthly'' deliveries, resulting in `` an overstatement of industrial consumption in the first six months of 1988 of 0.5 trillion cubic feet.'' Now that the errors have been corrected, the agency expects industrial gas use of 6.15 trillion cubic feet for all of 1988, only a 4.4 percent gain, instead of the 19 percent increase projected in July on the basis of the overestimates. The energy crises of the 1970s prompted major efficiency improvements everywhere. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, for example, autos averaged about 13 miles per gallon of gasoline in 1973; <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> required 27.5 mpg by 1985, a goal since relaxed to 26 mpg. More efficient processes have continued to be introduced in industry, and energy efficiency gains accelerated from an average of 1.2 percent per year in the 1970s to 2.8 percent in 1980-1986. But in 1987, for the first time in 11 years, efficiency failed to improve, a stagnation many analysts attributed to the collapse in oil prices of 1986. It took 19,960 British thermal units, or Btu, to produce a dollar's worth of goods and services in 1987, measured in dollars of 1982 buying power. This was roughly the same as the 19,950 Btu of 1986. A Btu is a standard unit of energy, equal to the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of one pound of water by one degree Fahrenheit. In July the agency forecast a 1988 ratio of 20,180 Btu per dollar, or a 1.1 percent decline from 1987, and a 1989 ratio of 20,050, a 0.6 percent improvement from 1988. The corrected October forecast predicts 19,840 Btu per dollar, an improvement of 0.6 percent from 1987, and improvement of 1.3 percent to 19,590 Btu in 1989. One analyst, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Durning </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Worldwatch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an environmental research group, said, `` I could believe'' an improvement of 0.6 percent. `` I would expect gains ... in the aggregate of about a half percent per year, just from the technologies and how much room for improvement there is, almost indefinitely,'' <PERSON> Durning </PERSON> said. But at the <ORGANIZATION> Lawrence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berkeley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, analyst <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Schipper </PERSON> said that even after the data corrections, `` As far as I'm concerned that's no change. There's a plateau. ... If I were a policymaker I'd be worried.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wetlands     11-15 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wetlands,630</SECOND>
<NOTE>For Release at 10 a.m. EST; Time set by source</NOTE>
<HEAD>Study Recommends New National Emphasis On Preserving Wetlands</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY DARST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A major environmental study today recommended that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> set a national goal of reversing the centuries-old trend of destroying more wetlands than are created. The report called on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve legislation encouraging the formation of wetlands preservation trusts, perhaps by restoring some tax incentives for land donations that were restricted by the 1986 tax law overhaul. The study group, called the National Wetlands Policy Forum, is composed of state and federal government officials, industry representatives and environmental interests. It was convened by the <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a private Washington-based research group, at the request of the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The report urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to add wetlands restoration and creation to the missions of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reclamation </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION> and other agencies. It said these agencies, along with the Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, should be required to organize a major effort to seek out public lands for restoration, especially where government activity had caused wetlands to be lost. Existing federal and state protective programs are `` too cumbersome and the responsibilities too diffuse'' to guarantee protection of wetlands, the report said. `` It is a system that allows hundreds of thousands of wetland acres to continue to be lost or degraded annually, almost unnoticed, while substantial resources and time often are devoted to determining the fate of a few relatively small areas,'' it said. `` The fact that the protection of wetlands makes good economic as well as environmental sense for society but not necessarily for the individual owning them is central to much of the conflict over wetlands protection policies,'' the report said. Setting a national goal of reversing the trend toward a shrinking wetlands base `` does not imply that individual wetlands will in every instance be untouchable.'' the report said. It said the aim should be that `` the nation's overall wetlands base reach equilibrium between losses and gains in the short run and increase in the long term.'' No one knows how fast swamps, marshes, bogs and other wetlands are being lost at present, although the 200 million acres present at the time Europeans settled what became the lower 48 states are believed to have been cut in half through conversion to farms, urban settlement and other uses. One study estimated that in the two decades leading up to 1975, 400,000 to 500,000 acres were lost every year. Only in recent decades has it become widely recognized that wetlands serve important environmental functions by storing flood water, supporting a third of the nation's endangered species, nursing and spawning 60 percent to 90 percent of commercial fish catches, reducing erosion, recharging groundwater, filtering sediment and controlling pollution. `` At the extreme, as in the case of some migratory birds, habitat functions can extend even to other continents,'' the report said. The report called on all states to enact wetlands conservation legislation if they have not done so, and to draft plans showing how they would meet goals of the forum report. Under the Clean Water Act, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> could delegate many of its wetlands responsibilities to states with approved plans. The <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> coast must get priority attention in considering a search for public land for wetlands restoration, perhaps through diversion of <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> sediment into the region. The report said the <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> coast is suffering `` extremely high wetlands losses from erosion ... largely as a result of government flood control and other water resource projects.'' Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> served as chairman of the wetlands policy forum, with Govs. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> as vice chairmen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-ShuttleLands 1stLd-Writethru a0444 11-15 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle Lands, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0444,a0445,a0446,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Shuttle Lands</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: COMBINES bulletin series. No pickup.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet space shuttle Buran touched down on a concrete runway in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> on Tuesday morning, flawlessly ending its unmanned 3 hour, 25 minute maiden voyage, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> said. `` The <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> has successfuly tested its first reusable space craft Buran,'' the official radio said. `` The unmanned shuttle has just landed on a special runway near the Baikonur Space Center,'' it said, interrupting its regular programming. The delta-winged Buran, Russian for snowstorm, had orbited Earth twice, lifting off on schedule despite a cold rain. The official <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency said the shuttle landed exactly on schedule. A previous attempt to launch the Buran had been frustrated by last-minute technical troubles. The shuttle was launched at 6 a.m. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> time -LRB- 10 p.m. Monday EST -RRB- in yellow flame and clouds of white steam from the special launch site in the Soviet republic of <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION>. Forty-seven minutes later it reached orbit, firing its own rockets for the first time. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> shuttle lookalike completed two orbits and then returned to the 2.7-mile concrete landing strip eight miles from its launch pad. Before liftoff, technicians had been concerned that the Buran and <ORGANIZATION> Energia </ORGANIZATION> might get covered with a coat of ice.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881115-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-88 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Shuttle 6thLd-Writethru a0629 11-15 0851</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Shuttle, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0629, a0448,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Soviet Shuttle Lands After Brief, Flawless Unmanned Maiden Flight</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs with details of landing, quotes. Picks up
graf 9 pvs, `The craft's ...' INCORPORATES a0448, AM-Shuttle Lands.</NOTE>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NY16</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
