<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Panama-Bishops 1stLd-Writethru a0728 04-07 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Bishops, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0728,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Bishops Back Mediation Effort by Panamanian Colleague</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: New throughout to UPDATE with McGrath suspending mediation
effort.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 American <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> bishops have lent moral support for Archbishop <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>'s now-suspended offer to mediate talks between the Panamanian government and the opposition which has been trying to oust Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. A letter of support from the American bishops to <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, the archbishop of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, was released on Thursday, just hours before <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> announced he was suspending the mediation effort. <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON> said he was withdrawing his offer because: opposition groups refused to talk to the government until it showed a willingness to discuss <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s departure; <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> had n't offered explicit backing of the initiative in writing; and there were no assurances that the four international leaders who proposed the talks could be present. Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> May </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishops </ORGANIZATION>, in the letter to <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, said: `` The voice of the church in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> has been clear and consistent, denouncing the instances of civic corruption and state violence that have tragically become so much a part of recent news reports.'' The letter was made public Thursday. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Solis </PERSON> <PERSON> Palma </PERSON>, the acting president of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, said his government agreed to talks mediated by the church. But the opposition insists on assurances that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is willing to step down and leave the country. `` I write to express our full support and ecclesial solidarity with you, your fellow bishops and all the suffering people of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' May said in his letter to <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>. He added that `` we continue to urge our own national leaders to exercise the greatest care in balancing pursuit of legitimate <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> interests in the region with the essential quest for a peaceful and just settlement of this crisis.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0851EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--SnowLeopard     04-07 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Snow Leopard,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rare Snow Leopard Makes Neighbors Nervous</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOUGHTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The neighbors are worried about a 110-pound pet snow leopard caged in his owner's suburban yard, but officials say the owner is within his rights. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Porges </PERSON> bought the big cat, member of an endangered species in the <LOCATION> Himalayas </LOCATION>, at auction last year and says there is no town bylaw preventing him from having the animal as long as he meets strict state and federal rules. `` It's an issue everyone in the neighborhood is upset about,'' said <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Conopka </PERSON>, who lives nearby with her husband and three young children. Town animal control officer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Doten </PERSON> said he has visited the leopard's home, a 36-by-12-foot cage that is 20 feet high. `` It's satisfactory to me, but if it ever got loose, I do n't know what we would do about it,'' he said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CollegeCroquet     04-07 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-College Croquet,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Smith Hosts First Croquet Tourney, With Some `Elitist'
Embarrassment</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Heartt is cq.</NOTE>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN LUMSDEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORTHAMPTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's only college croquet court plays host to its first intercollegiate tournament Friday with little fanfare and some embarrassment to <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> officials, says the professor who raised money for the field. `` I'm told that this event promotes the idea that <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is elitist,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, a literature professor emeritus at the 2,000-student school who was instrumental in getting the court built. `` If it were n't, they'd be out of business.'' Administrators at the private women's college denied any embarrassment about the 105-foot by 84-foot field. `` There might have been a few faculty snickers and comments made on why we would spend time and money building a croquet court when there are other more important things to do,'' said Director of Development <PERSON> Charlotte </PERSON> <PERSON> Heartt </PERSON>. `` But it was no skin off our backs. It did n't cost us anything,'' she said. The $ 16,000 court was paid for by donations from alumnae interested in the sport. However, <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said the already jittery administrators were delivered an blow when New England Monthly magazine noted in its January issue that the `` mere $ 16,000'' spent on the `` elaborately irrigated'' court would nearly cover a year's tuition and room and board charges for a scholarship student. `` This is preposterous,'' said <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who has described croquet as a cross between billiards and chess. `` This is the one sport that is absolutely neutral in age and gender. It did n't even occur to me to add ` race.' `` And it's cheaper than golf by a whole lot.'' Concerns about the school's elitist image began with its recent racial problems. The first black woman to earn tenure at the college quit in December, saying <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was lethargic in combating racism. Two black administrators followed soon after. But the school argues that it has taken great pains to fight racism and attract minorities since a spray-painted slur appeared on the steps of a campus building in October 1986. A survey <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> commissioned found its image problem had more to do with elitism than racism. More than half the 788 students, staff and administrators polled said they had been victims of class discrimination, according to the survey released in November. One problem remaining for the croquet court is getting it dedicated. Ms. <PERSON> Heartt </PERSON> said the college had arranged for a ceremony April 23 before learning that the school's croquet team would be in <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION> for a tournament. And President <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Maples </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> will be out of town this weekend. `` We ca n't get a schedule clear that suits both me and the team,'' Ms. <PERSON> Dunn </PERSON> said through a spokeswoman. In the English version that will be played this weekend among 40 competitors from nine of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> schools, from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Wellesley </LOCATION> to the universities of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, teams of two players each shepherd two balls twice around a wicketed turf. Friday's game at the Smith court, which means players no longer have to go 50 miles to a <LOCATION> Lenox </LOCATION> hotel court, is the first of the season for the fledgling <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Collegiate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Croquet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` I can understand why the college is nervous,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NECCA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Xandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Kayden </PERSON>. `` They do n't have enough experience with college croquet to understand the good press it gets. But I can also understand <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, because croquet changed his life.'' Young, 66, lost one leg and suffered a crippling injury to his other foot during World War II. He had trouble moving and had given up on sports until he discovered croquet a few years ago. He organized the <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> team and persuaded alumnae to donate the money for the court.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Kenya'sWildBuses     04-07 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Kenya's Wild Buses,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Riders of Kenya's Commuter Buses Leave Their Fate with the Gods</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DIDRIKKE SCHANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAIROBI, Kenya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the thousands of small commuter buses that careen about <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> every day carries an appropriate bumper sticker: `` You never know, heaven could be nearer than home.'' Authorities say the overcrowded, poorly maintained, wildly driven buses called `` matatus'' have contributed heavily to <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s highway death toll of nearly 200 so far this year At that rate, the toll is roughly on pace with 1987 when 1,889 people died in traffic accidents _ or one person killed for every 166 cars on <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s roads. A similar rate in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would mean that annual highway fatalities, now fewer than 50,000, would reach more than 1 million a year. The privately owned matatus carry such names as `` Survival of the Fittest'' and `` Living Devil.'' Scary as it all may be, the poor people who use them have no other choice. The brightly colored vehicles are legally allowed to carry no more than 25 passengers. But usually matatu crews cram in twice that many or more to get more fares. Those who ca n't fit inside climb onto the roof and cling to luggage as the buses go into a list on high-speed turns. Thirty-one people were killed Feb. 29 in a three-matatu crash that incensed a nation already accustomed to headlines screaming of `` horror smashes,'' and `` matatu madness.'' For days after the crash, newspapers printed pictures of victims strewn across the road and of the crumpled matatus. Commentaries called for something to be done about matatus, and a road-safety program was reintroduced on the government's Voice of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> television. The head of the <ORGANIZATION> Matatu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kenya </ORGANIZATION> resigned rather, he said, than be `` cursed by the innocent blood of the commuters who die daily on our roads at the hands of reckless matatu drivers.'' President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> arap </PERSON> <PERSON> Moi </PERSON>, whose government in 1984 passed the first legislation aimed at controlling matatus, decided they had become more `` an agent of death and destruction than an asset to the commuter.'' Police began a crackdown, netting hundreds of unroadworthy and overcrowded vehicles. Matatu crews, as well as unseated passengers, were hit with heavy fines. The <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> issued a new and more stringent list of regulations and ordered all matatu drivers retested. But the matatu industry retaliated with a strike that stranded hundreds of thousands of people. <PERSON> Moi </PERSON> rescinded the retesting order, and the matatus returned after a day off the roads. <PERSON> Moi </PERSON>'s response to the strike underscored the matatu industry's stranglehold on the nation's transportation sector Less than 1 percent of <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s 22 million people own cars and fewer than 600 buses are on the roads. The lack of vehicles leaves a demand for transportation met by the tens of thousands of matatus, which mostly are vans and minibuses, that travel even the most rural routes. Matatus first appeared as pirate taxis in the mid-1950s when <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> was a British colony and movement by the native population was restricted. The industry burgeoned after independence in 1963 when restrictions were lifted and people were allowed to move to the cities, swelling metropolitan populations and increasing the need for public transport. The name matatu comes from the Kikuyu term `` mang ` otore matatus,'' meaning 30 Kenyan cents, which at that time was the standard matatu Today, the average fare around <LOCATION> Nairobi </LOCATION> is 3 shillings -LRB- 19 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cents -RRB- and routes are flexible. To increase profits and their own $ 40 to $ 75 monthly salaries, matatu crews overload the buses, work overly long hours at the wheel and drive at high speeds in order to meet daily quotas set by matatu owners. At least 80 percent of the matatu crews work seven-day weeks and average 10 hours a day in vehicles that suffer most often from engine, brake or gear-box failure, according to a 1982 study by the Nairobi-based <ORGANIZATION> Mazengira </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. Many drivers admit to chewing khat, a stimulative twig, or smoking marijuana to keep themselves alert. In one of the dozens of commentaries on matatus, a columnist for the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nation </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>'s leading newspaper, blamed `` greed, brainless bravado and showmanship'' for the road carnage caused by matatus. `` The nation should not allow lunatics to ply the roads any longer,'' the columnist said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-07 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0681</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DECATUR, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 61-year-old college professor, infatuated with the lilting Scottish voice recording of his bank's automated teller, finally got to meet the woman of his cash machine dreams. `` I guess the first thing I should say is, ` Your transaction is processing,''' said <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>, a 29-year-old British radio talk-show host, on meeting <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferry </PERSON> after a trans-Atlantic flight Wednesday. The encounter was arranged by the <ORGANIZATION> Decatur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Review's editors, who tracked down Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> after Ferry, an education professor, wrote a Feb. 4 newspaper column about his `` infatuation with the talking teller. `` She is very sweet, she is very charming,'' Ferry said later. `` She is a person I'd very much like to have for a friend.'' `` I think he's smashing,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>. `` He's what I call wacky, because he's got that wacky sense of humor.'' Ferry's wife, <PERSON> Carol </PERSON>, said she first heard Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>'s voice last weekend. Before Wednesday's meeting, Mrs. Ferry asked, `` How would anyone feel if a young sexy person wants to meet your husband?'' Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON>, who is single, made the teller-machine recording three years ago in <LOCATION> Dundee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, for <ORGANIZATION> NCR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` I thought she was charming,'' Mrs. Ferry said. `` I've thoroughly enjoyed this. Ms. <PERSON> Masterson </PERSON> returns to <LOCATION> Britian </LOCATION> on Tuesday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA CLARA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a short-lived stint as a party animal, Bullwinkle the moose has come home to roost atop the pizza palace from which he was moosenapped seven months ago. As you'll recall, in our our last episode, the 40-foot inflatable effigy of Rocket J. Squirrel's best buddy vanished from the roof of Bullwinkle's <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION>' n Fun Restaurant in August. The restaurant, eager to get its $ 17,000 mascot back, offered the culprits free pizza for a year for the 300-pound moose on the loose. Suspicion soon focused on the notorious spy <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Badenov </PERSON> and his companion, <PERSON> Natasha </PERSON>. Finally, on April Fool's Day a deflated Bullwinkle was unceremoniously deposited in the parking lot of the eatery along with a 2-by-3-foot note. `` Hey guys! The moose is no longer loose. He wanted to party with us so we brought him along. It turns out he was too wild for us! Please keep an eye on him, he's dangerous! April Fools, Class of'88. `` P.S. Sorry.'' Police, who say the case is closed, believe the moose's abductors may have been students from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> High who decided to give back Bullwinkle after they realized what it was worth The restaurant manager, however, ca n't just laugh it off, having ordered a replacement moose for the roof. Stay tuned for the next episode: `` Wedding Bells For Bullwinkle?'' or `` Hey, Bub, This Roof Ai n't Big Enough For Both of Us!''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ULITHI ATOLL, Yap (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While many people are griping about having to pay a quarter to mail a letter, the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has given the 700 residents of this <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island chain something to smile about. <LOCATION> Ulithi </LOCATION> Atoll finally has its own Zip Code. The atoll, best known as the site from where the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> launched its World War II invasions of <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> and Iwo Jima, is part of Yap State in the <LOCATION> Federated </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Micronesia </LOCATION>, a former trust territory that holds a compact of free association with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. It is about 1,200 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Ulithi </LOCATION> Atoll includes dozens of islands, but people live on just four of them. Only about 700 people live here now, but in September 1944 hundreds of warships gathered in the atoll's sheltered lagoon to prepare for the 1945 invasions of <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> and Iwo Jima. The <LOCATION> Ulithi </LOCATION> rendezvous was the largest <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> task force assembled during the war. A post office opened here in March to distribute mail flown in from <LOCATION> Colonia </LOCATION>, the island's governmental seat about 100 miles east of <LOCATION> Ulithi </LOCATION>. The postal address is <LOCATION> Ulithi </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Yap </PERSON>, FM 96943.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Iran-Scene     04-07 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Scene,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Children's Hospital Hit By Iraqi Missile</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By HANNS NEUERBOURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEHRAN, Iran (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amid the dusty debris of the bombed-out children's hospital were a stuffed <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON> doll, a white plastic toy horse and a poster for children to learn English from pictures. The director of the <LOCATION> Bahrami </LOCATION> children's hospital in downtown <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> said about 60 children were inside the building when an Iraqi missile blasted into it at about 9:15 a.m. Wednesday. `` All of us were working normally. There was no alarm,'' <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Tayayori </PERSON> told reporters. `` We have recovered eight bodies of children up to now,'' he said, speaking through an interpreter. `` Three are still missing and we fear they are buried under the debris.'' He said he could not give the number of injured as they had been moved to several other hospitals since. But a doctor at the hospital said about 20 children were seriously injured. <PERSON> Tahayori </PERSON> said there were about 60 children in the hospital at the time of the attack. Normally the hospital has about 250 patients, but most were evacuated when the shelling between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> flared anew Feb. 29. He said three nurses also were killed and 20 were seriously injured. The group of foreign reporters was led over a huge pile of debris that was once the kindergarten ward. In the street, a crowd stared at the visiting reporters. A bearded old man shouted frantically, `` Where is the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>? Is this human rights?'' His cries were translated by an interpreter. A young man who spoke English said he heard a `` terrible sound'' before the impact, then saw a huge cloud of smoke rising over the site. `` I was shocked. I saw a woman lying on the street, her face all bloodied.'' he said. As the journalists returned from the trip, they were told that all would have to leave <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by Thursday. The reporters had been invited to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> in the wake of alleged Iraqi chemical-bomb attacks on Kurdish villages in <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. An official of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guidance </ORGANIZATION>, which organizes all press visits, said the reporters were asked to leave to ensure their safety. He said suthorities expected the Iraqis to a launch massive missile attacks on <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> on Friday, the day Iranians elect a new parliament. Newspapers have been carrying daily commentaries warning that <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> will seek to disrupt the elections by making residents leave the capital on that day. <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> last week called on citizens to go to the polls `` even if they are under a barrage of Iraqi misile and bomb attacks'' to `` perform their Islamic and divine duty'' and vote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-Drugs     04-07 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Drugs,0623</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three of Four Reputed Drug Barons Sought in Camerena Case now
Jailed</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With the spiriting away of <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> to an <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> prison, three of four reputed drug barons sought in the killing of an American drug agent are behind bars. The Feb. 7, 1985 kidnapping of <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>, a special agent of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, put the spotlight on the immense power and wealth accumulated by drug traffickers in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The bodies of <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zavala </PERSON> <PERSON> Avelar </PERSON> were found March 5, 1985. <PERSON> Zavala </PERSON> <PERSON> Avelar </PERSON> was a Mexican pilot who worked with <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> in anti-narcotics programs from their base in <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s second-largest city. During the hunt for <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> and then for his killers, an outline of a powerful drug organization became clear. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials called the organization <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Familia </ORGANIZATION> _ the Family. Talk of Mexican cooperation in anti-drug programs was replaced in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by charges of widespread corruption. The narcotics issue has remained a major sticking point in U.S.-Mexican relations. The four top men in the illicit drug trade were said to be Ernesto `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Neto </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Fonseca </PERSON>, reportedly the organization's leader; <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Matta </PERSON>. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> is a Honduran citizen and the others are Mexican. Although they were not all accused of direct participation, their organization that was believed responsible for ordering <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>'s murder. `` These people were all involved in a drug trafficking organization,'' <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Graves </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fonseca </PERSON> were taken into custody in spring 1985 and remain imprisoned, charged in <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>'s murder. <PERSON> Matta </PERSON> was picked up Tuesday in a pre-dawn helicopter police raid at his home in <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION>, the Honduran capital, and put on a flight out of the country without a passport. Honduran legislators angrily called the incident a `` kidnapping'' and the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> started an investigation of the procedures used. The exploits of <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> in particular, his rise from poverty to vast wealth, have given him almost a folk hero status in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Two escape tunnels were discovered last fall near his prison, one almost complete. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> remains at large. No warrant has been issued for him in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Reports surface from time to time that he dined with a governor or made some other public appearace. `` There are more than 50 people imprisoned,'' <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, spokesman for the federal attorney general's office, said Wednesday when asked for a status report on the <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> case. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> count is 63 people in custody in the case, a small number of them sentenced. `` We expect the Mexican judicial system to find these people guilty. We expect convictions, given the overwhelming evidence against them,'' <PERSON> Graves </PERSON> said. In January, a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> indicted nine people, including <PERSON> Caro </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, on charges stemming from the <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> kidnap and murder. The attorney general's office said: `` The respective trials will continue to develop before the Mexican jurisdictional bodies, independent of whatever procedure is opened in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> or in third countries.'' Attorney General <PERSON> Sergio </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON> said in a February interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that recriminations between <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> over which one is lagging in the drug trade war are not in the interest of either country. `` We find it difficult to accept the opinion held in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> of what really goes on in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` The border is not a border between black and white, good and evil. It is a border between countries.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0851EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--TVBreak     04-07 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--TV Break,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>TV Station Urging Viewers To Take 15-Minute Break</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A television station is urging its viewers to take a 15-minute break from watching. As part of its `` For Kids' Sake'' campaign, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>'s KDKA-TV will present a special half-hour edition of `` Story Break'' at 1 p.m. on Saturday, April 16. The program's hosts will read children's stories for the first 15 minutes, then a title slide will appear reading, `` Right now, share a story with the child in your life. For kids' sake.'' `` We've never done anything like this,'' said General Manager <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Berwanger </PERSON>. `` It's our job to air the best and most appropriate programming for our viewers, and we believe this 15-minute break from TV will be a very special time for anyone watching with kids.'' The station also plans to broadcast public service spots in place of local advertisements during the day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Inflation     04-07 0093</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Inflation,0094</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Inflation Rate Fell To 20-Year Low</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inflation in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> fell to an annual rate of 3.3 percent in 1987, its lowest level in 20 years, the government said. Consumer prices rose 3.3 percent during the year, down from 3.9 percent in 1986 and the lowest level since 1967, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. The price of some goods fell. Coffee dropped 8 percent and gas charges were 4.5 percent lower, but that was offset in part by a 22 percent rise in vehicle insurance costs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0313EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Cuba-Smoking     04-07 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Cuba-Smoking,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cuba Joins International Smoke-Out</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, known worldwide for making fine cigars, will participate in an international stop-smoking day. The Cuban news agency <ORGANIZATION> Prensa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Latina </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> participation today should not be considered `` a novelty,'' even though <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> is a major tobacco producer. `` A strong campaign against the smoking habit has been under way for some years and has achieved already positive results, even though at the expense of an important reduction in income from the sale of cigarettes and tobacco,'' said the dispatch received in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> on Wednesday. The campaign intensified after <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> gave up his trademark cigars about two years ago. <PERSON> Prensa </PERSON> <PERSON> Latina </PERSON> said per capita consumption of cigarettes and tobacco has been declining since 1986 and sales dropped by $ 100 million last year. It also said from today onward smoking will be banned on all Cuban domestic flights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AIDS-Teacher     04-07 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-Teacher,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teacher With AIDS Continues Work While Fighting Illness</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONG BEACH, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teacher who won a landmark court decision allowing him to continue teaching despite suffering from AIDS says his life has almost returned to normal even though his body is weakening. `` There are some days that I think nothing is wrong, and there are other times when I know very well something is, uh, lurking in my body,'' <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Chalk </PERSON> said in an interview published Wednesday in the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilot </ORGANIZATION>. Chalk, a vocational counselor for hearing-impaired students at <ORGANIZATION> Venado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, filed a lawsuit against the <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> last year when officials reassigned him to a desk job after learning he had AIDS. In November, the 9th <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled in what is believed to have been the nation's first such AIDS discrimination case, saying he could not be barred from the classroom. Chalk, 43, said he never anticipated the publicity the case generated, which forced his parents to tell their friends that their only son was homosexual, something they had known for years. Chalk said he felt sorry for himself at first. `` I'm not nor ever have been a very sexually active kind of person,'' said Chalk, who lives in <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> with a companion of six years. `` I thought, ` Other people are out there doing a lot more than I am. They would make better subjects.' But you ca n't go through life dealing with ` Why me's?''' But now, he's motivated to remain in the classroom, although he weighs 130 pounds, down from 160, and is plagued by a chronic sinus infection, he said. Chalk has trimmed his work week to three days so he wo n't weaken. `` There are people who want to say, ` See? Knew you could n't do it,''' he said. Chalk said he listens to motivational tapes and uses visual imagery in fighting AIDS, and has given up casual cocaine use and alcohol. `` I'm trying to create as much health in my life and my body as possible,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Curran-Vatican     04-07 0384</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Curran-Vatican,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissident Teacher Sues Catholic University</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A civil court will hear the Rev. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s complaints that <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> illegally ousted him from his teaching post as a result of <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> displeasure with his theology. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, a prominent professor of theology, is suing the university for breach of contract. Superior Court Judge <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> on Tuesday rejected the university's claim that <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s suspension was under church law and therefore is immune to civil court review. `` This court finds the university's position without merit,'' <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> said in a written order denying a motion by the university for dismissal of the suit. `` Professor <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s claim is based on an employment contract governed by the civil law and contract principles of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Beaudin </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the university, said `` we do n't comment on ongoing litigation. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>, in 1986, declared <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> unfit to teach as a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> theologian because of his dissenting views on sexual issues. He had expressed the view that contraception and sterilization `` are not intrinsically evil,'' and that `` in certain circumstances,'' the church should allow divorce. He has also said that for a `` genuine homosexual, homosexual acts in the context of a loving relationship striving for permanency can in a certain sense be objectively and morally acceptable.'' Archbishop <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickey </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, the ex-officio chancellor of <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, suspended <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> from all teaching at the university last January. <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>, who now teaches at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, challenged the suspension in court as a breach of university bylaws and his contract. The school asked dismissal of the suit, principally on the ground that court interference in canon law is barred by the freedom of religion clause in the Constitution. <PERSON> Beaudine </PERSON> said he did not dispute the school's contention that the court lacks authority `` to review and examine the university's interpretation and application of canon law'' and that his ruling applied only to <PERSON> Curran </PERSON>'s academic tenure and employment contract In a statement released by his lawyers, <PERSON> Curran </PERSON> said he is not asking the church `` to do or change anything in its decision concerning me. I am asking the court to ensure that a civilly incorporated university follow its own bylaws and its contract with me.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0239EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-07 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quarantine Ordered To Stop Spread Of Bee Mite</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has ordered an immediate quarantine for 13 states to help prevent the further spread of a tiny killer mite that threatens the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bee industry. The restrictions, announced Wednesday, ban the shipment from those states of bees and apiary equipment, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON>, acting associate administrator of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Animal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inspection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. States affected by the quarantine are: <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. Of the major honey producing states, only <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> so far remain unaffected by the mites, whose scientific name is <PERSON> Varroa </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsoni </PERSON>. The female is about one-twentieth of an inch in diameter, and the male is somewhat smaller. The mites were discovered in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last September in a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> apiary and since have spread to the 12 other states. `` Varroa mites can be spread by the movement of queen bees, package bees, hives, pollen, honeycomb with brood cells, and apiary equipment and vehicles,'' <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON> said. `` Under our regulations, these articles will be prohibited from moving interstate from quarantined areas unless certain conditions are met.'' The female Varroa mite lays 3 to 20 eggs in the protective comb cell of a developing bee. Young mites emerge and suck the blood of the bee larvae, killing or causing them to be deformed and useless to the hive _ in which case they are killed by the worker bees. If agency inspectors determine that there is no risk of mites, they can issue certificates allowing the movement of articles out of the quarantined states, <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON> said. In other cases, a `` limited permit'' may be issued to move articles that do not pose a pest risk, provided that additional precautions are taken. <PERSON> Slagle </PERSON> said the quarantine order `` will help protect our beekeeping industry as well as the estimated $ 20 billion worth of agricultural crops pollinated by bees each year.'' The external parasites can infest bees and their developing larvae so gradually that the mites are unnoticed until serious damage is done. The damage includes decreased broods, deformed bees and a weakening of the colony's ability to pollinate plants and produce honey. <PERSON> Caree </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, an agency spokeswoman, said no termination date for the quarantine was set and that she had no idea when the restrictions might be lifted. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in January approved the use of a chemical, fluvalinate, in the fumigation of bees and hives for mites, she said. A <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> company, <ORGANIZATION> Zoecon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, manufactures a plastic strip under the commercial name Apistan, which contains fluvalinate. Ms. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> said the strips can be used to fumigate bees and hives, with the supers or honey collectors removed first, in order to be certified as free of mites. But as for a general breakthrough in the prevention or rapid eradication of <LOCATION> Varroa </LOCATION> mites, she said <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> scientists are still looking. After the mites were detected last year, some experts speculated that the pests might have come into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as much as two or three years before. But no one knows for sure. Some authorities said the <LOCATION> Varroa </LOCATION> mite orginated in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> where it coexisted with Asian honeybees. However, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bees are of European origin and are highly vulnerable to the pests.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cattle tick fever is being targeted by <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scientists in a new experiment this year on <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. Millions of sterile male cattle ticks will be released on a <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION> test site to see whether the procedure can be used to control cattle fever, officials said Wednesday. `` We hope sterile -LRB- male -RRB- releases will stop female ticks from producing new generations that would infest cattle,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davey </PERSON>, an entomologist in the department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` Island people are safe from the disease. Humans are not bitten by the tick, nor do they get the disease.'' Cattle fever, or babesiosis, kills up to 80 percent of the adult cattle that get the disease, he said. The experiment will be tried for the first time `` late this year'' on <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Croix </LOCATION>. Cattle fever is widespread in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>, including the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, as well as in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and many other areas, he said. <PERSON> Davey </PERSON>, who works at the agency's <ORGANIZATION> Cattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fever </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, Mission, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said cattle become anemic after the ticks bite them and injects a protozoan parasite into the bloodstream. Cattle ticks `` periodically sneak over the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> border into <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>'' where a <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> eradication program stops them from spreading beyond a buffer zone, he said. `` These ticks are tough,'' <PERSON> Davey </PERSON> said in a statement issued here. `` If they were to get a strong hold again in the southern <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the disease could devastate the southern cattle industry. All <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cattle breeds are susceptible.'' The sterile male ticks are hybrids, which produce no offspring when they mate. <PERSON> Davey </PERSON> said the test will be on 130 wooded acres <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> has leased from the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> government. No cattle are in the area now, so <PERSON> Davey </PERSON> expects there are few ticks. As part of the preparation, however, cattle will be put into the wooded area along with some naturally fertile ticks. After those ticks settle in, their numbers will be estimated. Then, <PERSON> Davey </PERSON> explained, about five hybrid ticks for each estimated natural tick will be released at two-month intervals. Until a count is made of the natural ticks, no estimate is available of how many sterile hybrids will be released, but the number could be in the hundreds of millions or even billions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Reagan'sShadow Bjt   04-07 0811</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan's Shadow, Bjt,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON WIRE: Will Reagan Help or Hinder Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s men are dropping hints that the president is ready to hit the campaign trail on <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s behalf after a hoped-for triumphal return from the <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> summit Yet no matter when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> makes his choice known, his involvement in the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign must walk a careful line. It's possible <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s involvement could overshadow rather than enhance the vice president's effort `` The president will help the vice president in any way, shape or form,'' predicted <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s former political adviser. `` But it's got to be <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ... who lays out the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> agenda.'' `` We'd love to see <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> campaign for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Whip `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s strength is his personality and that's not <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strength On the stump, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would make <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> look weak.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been meticulous about maintaining an official neutrality. Now that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has nearly racked up enough delegates to be the nominee, the White House has given notice <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is itching to take a more active role. `` He's ready at the drop of a hat to get out there on the road,'' spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> announced last week. Taking note of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s string of primary and caucus victories, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said he wanted to raise the possibility that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will abandon his pledge to campaign only after a nominee had been chosen at the Aug. 15-18 GOP convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>. `` I think that in view of the way the campaign has developed ... we could see the president involved in some political activities before the nominating convention, activities that are directly associated with the nominee,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. But another <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide, speaking privately, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> realizes he will be a target in the campaign and he will not make a step until <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asks him. `` Clearly a lot of dialogue this fall will focus on us, with the Democrats attacking our record and the vice president supporting it,'' the official said. `` Anything we do will be carefully coordinated with the vice president.'' White House political director <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Donatelli </PERSON> refused to speculate on what form <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s activities might take. But he said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will not take part in any `` active campaigning'' until after the summit with Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The meeting is scheduled for the second week of June. <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON>, who most recently worked on <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s failed bid to win the nomination, said that will be `` the perfect time'' for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to designate his successor. `` He'll come back riding high in the polls; he'll be as popular as he's ever been,'' said <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON>. However, <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> warned that the stature of the presidency could work against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, as well as help him. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> needs to put his own stamp on his campaign,'' <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> said. `` If <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is the one who gets into the debate with the Democrats in the fall, he could overshadow <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' Both <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donatelli </PERSON> contend that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s involvement will help focus, not fuzz, the Republican nominee's message. `` <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> might not be able to determine the future, but he can define the present, and that's an important contribution to make to the dialogue,'' <PERSON> Donatelli </PERSON> said, pointing out that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has referred repeatedly to the strength of the economy and low unemployment. But <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> warned that some favorite <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> topics might well be avoided. `` If the two of them go out and talk about the line-item veto and the economic bill of rights, they'll bore everybody to death,'' he said. And other issues, such as the Iran-Contra affair and <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON>'s legal difficulties, are likely to be ignored. `` If he spends the next months talking defending everything he's done and anybody who's ever worked for him, he wo n't be effective,'' <PERSON> Rollins </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> It is just such issues that will attract voters to the Democratic side, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. He argued that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> voters want a change and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> must present himself as something different from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. `` But when the president goes out for him, it clouds <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s message. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is the ` Great Communicator,' not <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democrat said. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> also argued that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s approach to dealing with the Soviets is one that is `` personally identified'' with the president and that it has `` never transferred to <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s resume is supposedly grounded on foreign policy as his forte and he has n't shown that in eight years,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> also pointed out that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> failed when he attempted in the 1986 campaign to keep the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> hands. Although the president campaigned for months, the Republicans lost eight seats. `` We'd encourage such participation again,'' he added with a laugh.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VoiceofAmerica Bjt   04-07 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voice of America, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>VOA Facing Competition from Liberalized Soviet Media</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Glasnost has brought challenges for the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government radio station reviled for years by the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>: Now that the Soviets have stopped jamming its broadcasts, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> has to be more interesting. `` We now use more actualities and music,'' <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said in an interview. And instead of recycling programs several times a day to go through despite jamming, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> now produces fresh material for every program. `` We now have to be more competitive,'' <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said, citing broadcasts of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and the more-open <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> media under the glasnost _ or openness _ policies of <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. `` We have tried to make our programming more interesting, now that people do n't have to listen through eight frequencies'' of interference. But the <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> has n't softened its view of Soviet affairs. Editorials try to put <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reforms `` within a realistic context,'' <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said. `` Like jamming. It is intellectually difficult to applaud people for stopping what they were not supposed to be doing in the first place. `` One of the things that we have not changed is the tone and tenor of our broadcasting. We are not being kinder to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. We think we have been fair all along.'' <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> last December returned from a 10-day tour of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the first ever by a <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> director. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Z. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wick </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> which administers <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>, also has traveled to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. And the head of <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> service, <PERSON> Gerd </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Demming </PERSON>, is just back from a trip that took him to <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> a week before demonstrations broke out there in February. After they left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Demming </PERSON> and a colleague, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> correspondent <PERSON> Joylon </PERSON> <PERSON> Naegle </PERSON>, telephoned contacts they made in <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION> and broadcast reports on the demonstrations there. Although <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has opened some doors to <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>, he still voices the longtime Soviet complaint about `` foreign voices'' fomenting unrest. `` ` Various radio stations, including official ones, have joined in the subversive activity,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` Especially active ... is <ORGANIZATION> Deutsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welle </ORGANIZATION>,'' West German radio. `` They are trying to interfere in our internal affairs, to exacerbate problems from the outside, and engaging in provocations,'' he said in remarks distributed by <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency. `` At present this is particularly visible in connection with the events around <LOCATION> Nagorno-Karabakh </LOCATION>,'' a scene of Armenian unrest. <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said he hopes that <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> ire will not torpedo <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>'s longstanding request to open a bureau in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> `` In keeping with all the remarkably successful public relations moves by the Soviets, we think we may win approval,'' <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said. Later this month, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> is planning its first call-in show, in which broadcasters will field questions relayed from Soviet listeners dialing direct to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. And on Tuesday, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> conducted its first telephone interview with a Soviet official, <PERSON> Pyotr </PERSON> <PERSON> Morozov </PERSON>, director of the department of scientific research at the <ORGANIZATION> All-Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Morozov </PERSON>'s boss, <PERSON> Marat </PERSON> <PERSON> Vartanian </PERSON>, for years has denied allegations that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> incarcerated dissidents in psychiatric hospitals. During the interview, said <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Morozov </PERSON> repeated the Soviet denials, but acknowledged that some people sentenced for criminal offenses were treated in psychiatric hospitals. Soviet authorities treat political dissidents with debilitating drugs in psychiatric hospitals, according to <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Reddaway </PERSON>, secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Kennan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Russian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Numerous Soviet emigre accounts also have described the practice. `` We have a list of more than 100 people'' who were convicted of political crimes and sent to psychiatric hospitals, said <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Helsinki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> would combine <PERSON> Morozov </PERSON>'s comments with those of <PERSON> Mercer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fitzpatrick </PERSON> and a Moscow-based dissident during a broadcast to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> next week. Previously, said <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> has spoken by phone with dissidents such as <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, but never with an official. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> jammed <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts until 1973, when a period of Soviet-American detente began. Jamming resumed in 1980 with the rise of the independent Solidarity trade union in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. The Soviets stopped jamming broadcasts to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> last May 26, and stopped interfering with broadcasts to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> this January. Polish-language broadcasts had been jammed by military transmitters inside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>. Although the Soviets have stopped jamming broadcasts by <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Deutsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welle </ORGANIZATION>, they still try to block reception of two other U.S.-funded stations, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. To reach different groups in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> broadcasts in a number of languages including Russian, Ukrainian, <LOCATION> Uzbek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Azeri </LOCATION>, Lithuanian, Estonian, Latvian, Armenian and Georgian. <ORGANIZATION> VOA </ORGANIZATION> transmissions to other countries in the Soviet bloc include broadcasts in Polish, Czech, Slovak, Hungarian, Romanian and German.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HousingSurvey     04-07 0580</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Housing Survey,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey Says Majority Of Americans Would Support More Housing
Programs</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: R L Associates in 7th graf is cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PHYLLIS MESSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A non-profit housing group says its new poll shows that people are willing to pay higher taxes to ensure that poor and middle-class Americans get decent, affordable housing. `` There's no doubt the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people support programs to expand home ownership, help low-income renters and aid the homeless,'' <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Atlas </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` And contrary to the conventional wisdom, they're willing to pay. The poll found that most Americans believe there is a lack of affordable housing for the poor and middle class. Most of those surveyed said they would pay an extra $ 10 to $ 15 a month in taxes for programs to aid the homeless, the elderly and middle-class families unable to make down payments to buy houses. The survey also found that nearly 75 percent of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public believes a presidential candidate who advocates housing programs for middle-and working-class families `` understands the real needs in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' The vast majority _ 86 percent _ said they feel homelessness is `` a national disgrace'' and an even higher percentage _ 93 percent _ said homelessness is an important problem that should be eliminated. `` Politically, a presidential candidate who guarantees every American a decent affordable home might have a new home himself _ on <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Atlas </PERSON> said. The report, `` A Status Report On The American Dream: How the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> View </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Problems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Programs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>,'' was based on polling by <ORGANIZATION> R </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> L </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. The firm interviewed 1,001 adults by telephone during February and March. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Rappaport </PERSON>, spokesman for the polling firm, said the margin of error is plus or minus 4 percentage points. In general, the survey found that at least two-thirds of those questioned support programs to finance renovations in housing for the elderly, to rehabilitate old and vacant buildings, to establish a homeless prevention program to help those close to eviction for financial reasons, and to begin a mortgage assistance program to help with downpayments. On the issue of higher taxes to support housing programs, 66 percent said they would be willing to spend $ 10 a month more, while 55 percent said they would agree to pay $ 15 a month more. The poll also found that half of those surveyed said they would be more likely to vote for a candidate who supports `` a package of housing programs,'' while only 6 percent said they would be less likely to support such a candidate. Seventy-four percent said they believe a presidential candidate who advocates housing programs for middle - and working-class families `` understands the real needs in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people are increasingly aware that this nation faces a housing problem,'' <PERSON> Atlas </PERSON> said. `` Our poll shows that <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> understand that it's hard to find affordable housing and that Americans are shocked at homelessness.'' He said the housing institute, which describes itself as a representative of housing interests for moderate - and low-income families, can not lobby <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for housing programs because of its non-profit status It does plan to provide its poll data to other groups that can promote the programs. <PERSON> Atlas </PERSON> said spending authority for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> dropped 57 percent from 1980 to 1987, from $ 35.7 billion a year to $ 15.2 billion. And he said that the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> budget last year represented 1 percent of the federal budget.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ComputerCensus     04-07 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Computer Census,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Only Half Of Adults Use Their Computers, Survey Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only about half the adults who have a computer at home actually use it as opposed to nearly three-quarters of all children, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports. Youngsters use computers for learning and for games, and many children are also exposed to the machines in school, said bureau statistician <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON>, whose survey was released Wednesday. Even though many adults use computers at work, the home computer may have been bought by one adult for a specific use, and not be of interest to others in the home, <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> suggested. In addition, many computers were bought `` as learning tools and game machines for children,'' he said. `` So there probably are quite a few situations in households where children use a computer and not the adults at all.'' The report was based on a survey taken in October 1984, the only time the bureau has looked at computer use. The report was delayed because of other priorities, he said. Computer use has skyrocketed from the nearly 7 million home computers in use at the time of the survey. <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Data </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a Boston-based market research group, estimates that the number of homes with computers reached nearly 16.5 million as of last year. And <ORGANIZATION> Electronic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a trade group, estimates the total at 17.6 million homes as of January. While it deals with a time when fewer machines were in use, the census analysis is the first detailed look at who owns and uses the machines. Of 221 million Americans aged 3 and over in 1984, more than one in five _ 21.1 percent _ reported using computers in some direct way. _ Some 8.2 percent of households -LRB- 6.9 million -RRB- owned a home computer Ownership was most likely in households with incomes of $ 50,000 or more, 22.9 percent. Only 1.7 percent of households with incomes under $ 10,000 had a computer. People aged 34 to 44 were most likely to own computers. Those with children were three times more likely to have a machine than were the childless. _ Of the 15 million adults in computer households, 53.3 percent reported using the machine Use by men was 63.1 percent, compared to 48.2 percent of women. Usage was highest in the 25 to 34 age group. Adults in the West and <ORGANIZATION> Northeast </ORGANIZATION> were most likely to have a computer at home, 10.3 percent and 10.2 percent respectively. But westerners were much more likely to use them, 57.9 percent to 49.8 percent. In the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION>, 8.9 percent of adults had a home computer and 54.5 percent of them used it. The rates were 7.7 percent of adults in the South with a computer and 51.6 percent using it. _ Nearly one-fourth, 24.6 percent of all employed adults, used a computer at work Reversing the home pattern, women were more likely to use them there, 29.0 percent to 21.2 percent. The highest rate of use was 39.1 percent of women in technical and support jobs, while the top rate for men was 38.6 percent in administrative and management positions. _ Among children aged 3 to 17, 15.3 percent had a computer at home, and 74.2 percent of those used it Of those enrolled in school, 28 percent reported using computers. Among youngsters, the study found, boys generally use computers more than girls. `` If you want to risk saying anything is a sociocultural difference at this time, that's certainly where it lies,'' <PERSON> Kominski </PERSON> said. `` People who study computer games find boys use these things much more than girls do, they go to video parlors more, and they use computers more at home and school too.'' In school, the highest usage was in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> where 33.9 percent of students said they had computers. The rate was 30.8 percent in the Northeast, 29.4 percent in the West and 21.3 percent in the South.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Walton-Sprint     04-07 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walton-Sprint,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>San Diego Man Waging Unusual Campaign For President _ Of US Sprint</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three years ago, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> set up a card table on a downtown street corner here to preach the benefits of long-distance telephone competition and sign up customers for a company called <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION>. The 32-year-old <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> entrepreneur returned to that street corner Wednesday to tell customers, shareholders and anyone else who would listen that the company, now called <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, is plagued by billing and management problems that are costing millions in lost business. <PERSON> Walton </PERSON>, who says he signed up more than 600,000 residential customers for <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION>, has been waging an unusual grass-roots campaign to oust the company's management and install himself as president to clean house. `` I'm appealing to customers and shareholders not to rely on the present management to correct the problems,'' <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> said in an interview before a speech to a curious lunchtime crowd outside the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s headquarters. `` Management has been totally unresponsive'' to the problems, which <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> says cost him millions in lost commissions for his sales efforts as well as millions in lost business for the company. <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> Sprint, the nation's third-largest long-distance carrier, has acknowledged its billing problems and admitted that bad debt has contributed to the company's losses. Spokesman <PERSON> Syd </PERSON> <PERSON> Courson </PERSON> said the firm plans to have new computer software installed by January to take care of the problem. `` We've owned up to our billing problems and we've done a lot to correct them,'' <PERSON> Courson </PERSON> said, adding that <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> has become a `` nuisance.'' Last week, <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> took his entourage _ complete with a large campaign banner _ to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. This week he touched down in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> before arriving in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. All this is leading up to `` election'' appeals he hopes to make personally to shareholders at meetings April 12 for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and April 20 for <ORGANIZATION> GTE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> Sprint was formed as a joint venture by those two companies in July 1986. But he faces one big stumbling block: Shareholders do not elect the president. Shareholders, however, can raise issues like his at annual meetings, and since he owns <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> stock, he can make comments at that meeting. `` But since there is no election, I do n't know what his purpose is,'' said <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsythe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> is not a GTE shareholder. <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> worked as an independent sales contractor for <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecom </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> from 1984 to 1986. During that period, the former high school teacher hired a sales force of about 400 young people who worked street corners and college campuses across the country, signing up new customers. But many of those they signed up never got service, were billed for calls never made, never received bills from <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> but were contacted by collection agencies or had other problems with service, he said. For <PERSON> Walton </PERSON>, this meant problems receiving his commissions. He was supposed to be credited when customers made their first <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> Sprint calls. But because of problems installing service and billing customers, <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> estimated that about half his recruits were never counted for a commission. After his contract with <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> was ended in September 1986, <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> wrote scores of letters to <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> executives about his lost commissions and the company's billing problems. At the time, <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> said, the company owed him between $ 3 million and $ 8 million in unpaid commissions. He eventually settled for nearly $ 2 million, including a $ 1.7 million payment in January. In total, he said he received about $ 6 million from <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> during his 2 -LCB- years of recruiting. He said he paid close to $ 5 million of that to his young workers. But <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> says it is not the money that is driving his campaign to oust <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Snedaker </PERSON>. `` My integrity is at stake,'' <PERSON> Walton </PERSON> said. `` I wanted to make more money and feel good about it at the same time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0343EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HensonBurial     04-07 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Henson Burial,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Explorer Given Full Recognition 79 Years Later</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARLINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They were together at the discovery of the North Pole in 1909. But in death, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> was in a shared grave in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> while Adm. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peary </PERSON> was honored at <ORGANIZATION> Arlington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cemetery </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> was black, and for that reason, said supporter Dr. <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> <PERSON> Counter </PERSON>, `` he was denied proper recognition because of the racial attitudes of his time.'' On Wednesday, 79 years to the day after <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> planted the American flag on the North Pole, the two explorers were reunited as <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s remains and those of his wife were reinterred with full military honors at <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>. `` Now, finally, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Peary </PERSON> can talk about old days out there,'' a part-Eskimo grandson, <PERSON> Qitdlaq </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Qaanaaq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>, said through a translator _ his cousin <PERSON> Navarana </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> _ at a news conference following the ceremony. `` I have waited for this day for over 30 years,'' <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s great niece, <PERSON> Olive </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, told the gathering of about 100 relatives and admirers at the windswept hilltop burial site. Recalling that she was expelled from school because she had written a paper about <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> when her assignment had been to write about a hero, Ms. <PERSON> Fulton </PERSON> said: `` Finally, my uncle is given his place in history.'' Counter said the reinterment of <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>, was `` long overdue recognition for our hero ... -LRB- that would -RRB- right a tragic wrong.'' `` Welcome home, <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>,'' he said. `` Welcome home to a new day in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. ... May your presence here inspire generations of explorers.'' Last October, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> approved Counter's petition to allow <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s remains to be reinterred at <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>. He had been buried in 1955 in <LOCATION> Woodlawn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cemetery </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Among those honoring <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> at the ceremony were Gen. <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckton </PERSON> of the White House military office, who conveyed greetings from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the chairman and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes Ebony and Jet magazines; Col. <PERSON> Guion </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bluford </PERSON>, the first black astronaut; and <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Height </PERSON>, the president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Negro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>. Counter, an associate professor of neurophysiology at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> who previously had brought together <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Peary </PERSON>'s part-Eskimo offspring, said <PERSON> Peary </PERSON> had insisted before his own death in 1920 that <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s achievements be recognized Descendants of <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> were joined at the ceremony by <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s part-Eskimo descendants. `` This is a very special day for them,'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> said at the news conference, translating for another of <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s grandsons, <PERSON> Ajako </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Morriussaq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION>. `` They do n't even know how to express that.'' <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s eldest part-Eskimo grandson, <PERSON> Avataq </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>, also of <LOCATION> Morriussaq </LOCATION>, clutched to his chest the flag that had draped his grandfather's coffin. `` When he visited <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON>'s grave the first time in <LOCATION> Woodlawn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cemetery </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, he expected it to be a hero's gravesite,'' Ms. <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> said as she translated for Avataq `` He was disappointed to see him among ordinary people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-BushMoney     04-07 0566</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Money,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Bumps Up Against Fund-Raising Limit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign treasury is filled to the brim and campaign officials say the biggest worry now is guarding against spending more than the $ 27 million pre-convention limit set by federal election law. The vice president's campaign has already spent all but $ 4 million of that cap, with more than four months yet to go to the Republican convention this August, said campaign treasurer <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign hit the contribution limit on Wednesday, reporting that it had raised a total of $ 30 million, including $ 22.5 million in direct contributions and commitments for another $ 7.5 million in federal matching funds. This total includes about $ 3 million earmarked for legal and accounting expenses which are exempt from the $ 27 million-limit. `` The challenge is to take that $ 4 million we have left and maximize it so that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> gets the best benefit out of that he can,'' said the campaign official, who is not related to candidate <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` I'm thrilled,'' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in an interview. `` As far as this process is concerned, we're finished.'' The cap applies to both raising funds and spending them. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contender <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> was the first candidate to actually bump up against the spending ceiling. The former televison evangelist said after the costly Super Tuesday contests on March 8 that he was within $ 2 million of the spending cap. Since then he has laid off staff and dropped an extensive television marketing operation. Though he has only 17 delegates to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 888, he remains in the race and is spending the rest of his money primarily on personal travel. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said staying within the limits is far easier because <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is now running virtually unopposed among Republicans. `` It's a fait accompli as far as the nomination. You do n't have to go on advertising, you do n't have to buy more TV ads, you do n't have to have a huge entourage,'' he said The vice president had already scaled down his campaign schedule in the aftermath of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s withdrawal last week from the race. The vice president plans to go ahead with fund-raising events scheduled for this weekend in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, next week in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and later in the month in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> D.C </ORGANIZATION>. The reason? <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that the campaign is still entitled to raise another $ 2.8 million to go into a `` compliance fund,'' money needed for complying with various provisions enforced by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. He said the campaign will still continue to raise funds until that $ 2.8 million has been met, and then will close up its fund-raising operation. Funds for the general election campaign are provided from tax dollars and from a `` presidential trust'' _ funds that can be raised and spent by the national parties on behalf of their nominees. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said contributors who have written checks to the <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign that have n't yet been cashed soon will be receiving letters. `` We will write those people and explain to them that we are over the legal maximum, and would they allow us to use that check for the compliance fund. We have to have their signature. Otherwise, we will have to return the check.'' `` I think it will be a pretty easy $ 2.8 million to raise,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-Democrats-Optimism     04-07 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Democrats-Optimism,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Look To New York To Annoint Front-Runner</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders are looking to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and asking if <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> can extend his winning streak to four _ and finally give the party a presidential front-runner. While many Democrats were sounding optimistic about the prospects of a breakthrough in the long, roller-coaster race, they also were painfully aware of the many occasions one or another candidate looked on the verge of claiming the title of front-runner. `` Every time we get a front-runner, it seems folks want to slow it down,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, a former national party chairman who is advising <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. Watching most closely are those elected and party officials _ 645 strong _ designated as uncommitted delegates to the Democratic National Convention, the so-called super delegates expected to hold the balance of power. `` The super delegates are looking for a candidate who can rattle off a big string of wins,'' said <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Democratic Party chairman. It was in <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s caucuses in March 26 that <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> trounced <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and surged to the forefront of the contest, raising talk of the likelihood of a brokered convention. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> came shortly after a Dukakis loss in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. But since then, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor has scored victories in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> and now is favored to extend his streak in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> which holds its primary on April 19. `` The nominee will be determined in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Rachelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON>, political director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think we have a two-person race and we have a front-runner. The likelihood is we'll have a nominee and not a brokered convention.'' The <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> vote `` gives a little boost to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Crangle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> Democratic chairman, and one of the party's super delegates. `` But you've got to put a qualifying clause there that you've got to have a pattern, you've got to go two or three states in a row in order to say that you're a front-runner.'' Party chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> predicted the Democrats would choose their nominee on the first ballot of the <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> convention and he vowed to oppose any effort to organize a stop-Jackson movement. `` There's not going to be any organized cabal of party leaders trying to hobble one candidate as opposed to another,'' said <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>. A total of 2,082 delegates is needed for a convention majority. To reach that number, either <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> would need to win more than 1,300 of the 1,600-plus committed delegates yet to be chosen or draw strong support from the super delegates. `` The super delegates are going to stay frozen for a while,'' predicted White. <PERSON> Wiener </PERSON> said the super delegates were `` looking for a candidate who can rattle off a big string of wins.'' He said most of those delegates accept the view that `` if there is a clear leader after <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> -LRB- the last two big states to hold primaries -RRB-, that super delegates ought to play a leading role in propelling that person over the top. At three in a row, Gov. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has gotten a very good start on that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     04-07 0421</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Says Prosecution Plan For Release Of Documents Too
Cumbersome</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The judge in the Iran-Contra case says he wants to streamline procedures for pre-trial disclosure of 150,000 pages of classified documents to the four defendants. Signaling his intention to move the case to trial as quickly as possible, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> on Wednesday rejected independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s proposal to prevent unauthorized disclosure of the classified material as too cumbersome. The proposed procedure for three months of pre-trial discovery `` appears to be far too complex, lacks definite time restrictions and creates undue obstacles to the fair and expeditious disposition of this case,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said in a brief opinion. At a hearing scheduled for next Tuesday, <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he `` intends to determine the timing of discovery disclosures in relation to a realistic trial date.'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he will ask <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> to say which documents `` will be made available immediately'' to the defense. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> had said in pleadings filed Monday that he planned to turn over the material to the defendants in the next three months. The judge also said he wants to set a deadline this month for completion of an interagency review of the documents, which <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> says `` describe in detail some of the nation's most carefully held secrets about its foreign policy, its intelligence activities and its covert activities.'' An objection to <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s plan was filed by defense lawyers for former national security adviser <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON>, Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> and arms dealers <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON> and <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hakim </PERSON>. The four are accused of conspiring to illegally divert proceeds from the U.S.-Iran arms sales to the Nicaraguan rebels. Among elements of the security plan the defense found objectionable was a requirement that the defendants and their lawyers answer detailed government questionnaires in order to obtain security clearances to review the documents. Requiring the defendants to answer detailed questions about their travel, aliases, corporate affiliations `` and other matters potentially at issue in the case'' could violate their Fifth Amendment protection against self-incrimination, the defense said. The joint opposition also noted that North and <PERSON> Poindexter </PERSON> had previously had access to many of the documents when they worked at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said `` it will be necessary to frame a more limited protective order fashioned to the nature of this case, which in essence alleges a course of conduct carried out using classified materials in classified channels from a highly classified site.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880407-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-07-88 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Republicans 1stLd-Writethru a0765 04-07 0611</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Republicans, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0765,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush, Dole Meet To Discuss ``Beating Democrats''</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: ADDS 3 grafs with Robertson saying he won't campaign actively
in New
   York, giving up Secret Service</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
