<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 0511EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ACLU     09-24 0935</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ACLU,0962</SECOND>
<HEAD>ACLU Fights Back against Bush's Attacks</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MITCHELL LANDSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As a student recruiter for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, young <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> found an unwitting and unlikely ally in Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>. The place was <ORGANIZATION> Swarthmore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, the time was the mid-1950s, and <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>'s red-baiting rampages _ his fulminations about `` card-carrying Communists'' _ had galvanized civil libertarians. `` <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> was our greatest membership recruiter,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> recalled in an interview last May with the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times. No one is likely to describe <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as an <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> recruiter, but officials of the civil liberties union say he, too, is helping draw members, money and mail to the organization's cluttered Times Square headquarters. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has persistently attacked <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for being a member of the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>, and has turned <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' tongue-in-cheek description of himself as a `` card-carrying member'' on its head. The organization is fighting back. It is planning an advertising campaign featuring actors <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Eikenberry </PERSON> of `` L.A. Law'' and <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lancaster </PERSON> to battle what it says are misrepresentations by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. `` There's a smell of McCarthyism about those kinds of attacks,'' <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> Executive Director <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` And while that has happened from time to time from people like <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> and <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> ... it has never before been leveled during a presidential campaign by a major party candidate.'' Should membership be an issue in a presidential race? <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> officials say no. In their view, the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> is a non-partisan, non-ideological organization whose sole function is to defend the Constitution and the Bill of Rights. An attack on the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>, they say, is an attack on the very foundations of democracy. But others _ mainly conservatives _ say the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> is not the politically neutral organization it claims to be, but a left-wing `` criminal's lobby,'' to use the phrase favored by former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. `` They are probably one of the most rigidly ideological organizations in the country,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, stung by a newspaper column which noted his past membership in the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>, issued a statement Thursday saying he left the organization because it had a `` separate political agenda, many portions of which I strongly disagreed with.'' The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration tangled frequently: _ The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>, for the first time, took a position on the appointment of a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice when it opposed the nomination of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON>. _ The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> strongly supports the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision which established a woman's right to abortion. _ The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> was on the losing side in a 1987 case in which the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, on a 6-3 vote, supported pre-trial detention of suspects who are determined to be dangerous. _ The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> lost again this year when the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> upheld the Adolescent Family Life Act. <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> attorneys had objected that money was given to groups which were promoting religious positions. But the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration is not the first to battle the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>. The organization was founded in 1920 in response to the <LOCATION> Palmer </LOCATION> raids, the name given to Attorney General <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>'s efforts to deport immigrants for their radical beliefs. The organization has defended all sorts of radicals _ from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, from the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panthers </ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION> _ to hold and espouse their beliefs. The <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> has successfully argued that poor people have the right to a lawyer and that police should inform criminal suspects of their right to remain silent. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> often attacked the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s 1966 Miranda decision that required police to read suspects their rights. <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> once said the ruling `` only helps guilty defendants.'' One past <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> case which figures in this presidential campaign is one in which the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> sided with <PERSON> Jehovah </PERSON>'s Witnesses who challenged a law which compelled them to join in the Pledge of Allegiance. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1943 struck down the law _ and that decision was cited by <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> when he vetoed a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> bill that required teachers to lead the pledge every day. The court's decision in the Pledge of Allegiance case contained `` probably the most ringing language of any <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision on why the constitution forbids the state from telling people to take oaths,'' <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON> said. `` The words are fine. ` Liberty, justice, indivisible.' We love those words. Those words might be the motto of the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>.'' Many of the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION>'s causes have been unpopular, <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON> said, because the government tends to target unpopular groups. `` You know, we do n't choose our clients,'' he said. `` If we are representing more people on the left, it's because the government is prosecuting more people on the left.'' <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, however, believes the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> has a mindset `` of blaming the actions of criminals on society; it's a mindset where the system of justice favors criminals over the law-abiding citizens; it's a view of an extraordinarily libertine society that could probably best be summed up by the phrase, ` If it feels good, do it and do n't make it illegal.''' <PERSON> Glasser </PERSON> puts it this way: `` If I were to asked to characterize what the Constitution means in a single line ... I would say, ` It's the right to be let alone It's the notion that the government has power to do certain things like protect us against foreign domination, maintain the streets, tax us for various things. But they do n't have the right to tell me how to live.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 0626EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CrabShortfall     09-24 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crab Shortfall,0558</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Alaskan Crab Harvest May Put A Pinch On Diners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fishermen preparing to catch <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s premium crab next week face a harvest projected to be 40 percent below last year's, which could produce a quantum jump in prices and put a pinch on restaurant owners State biologists said they were surprised to discover data showing a shortfall of red king crab after anticipating a burgeoning harvest for the <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> fishing grounds this year. They had projected a 20 percent to 30 percent increase in the 1988 haul over the 1987 take of 12.3 million pounds. But when the harvest opens Sunday, it will draw at least 200 boats competing for an estimated 7.5 million pounds of crab, said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> and Game biologist. The harvest will likely last less than seven days, he said. The crab industry is $ 30 million business, <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said. Biologists suspect a variety of causes for the instability in the population of the red king crab, which is available only off the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> coast. The <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> fishing area, off <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s southwest coast, yielded a peak harvest of 139 million pounds in 1980. But for reasons still not understood, the crab population was decimated in 1982, and the fishery was not opened that year. The harvest that begins this weekend will be the year's major catch of the seafood, which vies with cold-water lobster tails as a premium item on restaurant menus in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and abroad. `` Demand is very strong both domestically and in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, a shellfish promotion specialist for the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seafood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. But a massive increase in prices could scare restaurateurs to the point that they substitute less costly seafood as top-of-the-line fare, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. `` The best thing that's happened in the king crab business in the last two years has been the stability of the prices,'' he said Thursday. `` As long as we offer a high-quality product at competitive prices, -LRB- red king crab -RRB- is very popular,'' he said. It brought $ 10 to $ 12 a pound wholesale in 1987. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and blue king crabs also are harvested off the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> coast, but are valued less than their red cousin. <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> said biologists do n't know exactly why the supply plunged. Influences that have been examined include interference from bottomfishing, disease, increased water temperature and harvests of undersized crab. Officials are combatting the harvest of the smaller crabs with a state law requiring monitors to travel aboard vessels processing crab at sea, where previously they had been been unable to observe the catch. That law, similar to a federal measure for some of the vessels in foreign fleets, requires observers to verify the quantities and sizes of crab caught. But some fishermen balked at the law and unsuccessfully sought an injunction to block the requirement for monitors. An attorney for the <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> At-Sea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Processors </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that the refusal to grant the injunction this week was not appealed, and processors were preparing to carry monitors. Attorney <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION> estimated that contractors who provide the monitors will pass on about $ 9,000 in costs to each processor required to use one.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SAfrica-Standoff Bjt   09-24 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SAfrica-Standoff, Bjt,0717</SECOND>
<HEAD>Activists In U.S. Consular Office Testing Americans' Diplomatic
Skills</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The four anti-apartheid activists who have taken refuge in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consular offices are testing the diplomatic skills of their hosts. Since the first three activists escaped 12 days ago to consular sanctuary 11 stories above downtown <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, the activists have demanded the release of all detainees and an end to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s state of emergency. The white-dominated South African government, in contrast to its usual confrontational tactics, has waged a public relations campaign to make itself appear reasonable. It says the first escapees _ well-known anti-apartheid leaders who were in custody at least 14 months without charge _ are free to walk away without fear of arrest. `` They are free men and we have no further interest in them whatsoever,'' said <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Mellet </PERSON>, the Law and <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. Police say the fourth man, who escaped last Wednesday, faces a possible charge of illegal weapons possession. Each of the four escaped from <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where police kept them under guard through use of national emergency laws that give authorities powers to limit, among other things, freedom of speech, press and assembly. So far, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats have said the activists can remain indefinitely, but they also have barred them from direct contact with journalists. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dugard </PERSON>, a human rights lawyer in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, supported the activists' demand for written assurances they will not be harmed but doubted the government would hold to its pledge to leave them alone. `` I do n't believe that for a moment,'' <PERSON> Dugard </PERSON> said. `` But it might be argued that by staying in the consulate they are restricting themselves.'' <PERSON> Mellet </PERSON> said, `` Tthe three have become an embarrassment not only for themselves, but for the Americans as well.'' South African officials have issued one mild complaint about the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to provide temporary refuge, but stronger comments have come from black activist <PERSON> Winnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said Thursday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> the escapees `` provide compelling evidence that the people of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, in their struggle to end apartheid, still look to the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people for support.'' By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the 26 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services. The escapees are <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morobe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Valli </PERSON> <PERSON> Moosa </PERSON>, senior leaders of the banned <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, a nationwide anti-apartheid coalition, and <PERSON> Vusi </PERSON> <PERSON> Khanyile </PERSON>, chairman of the banned <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crisis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. They were joined Wednesday by <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> Ngcobo </PERSON>, an activist from <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> who alleges he was assaulted by police following his detention in April. This is the first publicized sanctuary case at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mission in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, although there have been comparable cases at other missions. Six activists stayed at the British Consulate in <LOCATION> Durban </LOCATION> for several weeks in 1984 before emerging to face arrest for high treason. The charges later were withdrawn. In 1987, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> allowed a Dutchman, <PERSON> Klaus </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonge </PERSON>, to return to the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> after being holed up in a Dutch Embassy office in <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> for two years. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Jonge </PERSON> escaped into the office after being arrested for aiding the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has expressed `` high regard'' for the activists and promised they would not be forced out of the consulate, but subsequent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> statements have been politically neutral, belittling neither the activists nor South African authorities. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, the first black <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, has engaged in behind-the-scenes negotiations about the standoff but has made no public comments, in keeping with the low profile he has maintained throughout his two years here. Supporters of the escapees, while grateful for the sanctuary at the consulate, have voiced annoyance at the Americans' efforts to minimize controversy. Said Mrs. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, wife of jailed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>: `` We would like to see the Americans a little more committed than they are.'' One <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said the Americans relieved because the criticism from militants `` could have been a lot stronger.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Gulf-Truce Bjt   09-24 0653</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gulf-Truce, Bjt,0673</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gulf War Truce Holds, But Peace Brings New Problems</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An uneasy cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war has held for more than a month despite daily claims of violations by both sides. Although the guns have fallen silent after one of the longest conventional wars this century, both sides remain on a war footing and the bloodshed continues as they turn on internal opponents to settle old scores. <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> told his countrymen Aug. 30 that `` we must take it that we are still at war,'' and urged them to man the frontlines against `` constant plots ... by our enemies.'' Diplomats say <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, who used the war to consolidate his power and eliminate any challenges, will have to keep the lid on tight to curb any dissent that might emerge. He has already taken advantage of the Aug. 20 cease-fire to turn his army toward the long-rebellious Kurdish guerrillas who fought on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s side. The autonomy-seeking Kurds say the Iraqis have killed at least 4,300 civilians in poison gas attacks in a major offensive in northern <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. The guerrillas say it is aimed at wiping out Kurdish resistance. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s sudden acceptance on July 18 of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire has intensified political friction between rival factions in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. That is part of a power struggle that has been building up over who will take power when <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, 88 and reported ailing, dies. Not all Iranian leaders, particularly hard-line radicals, wanted to end the war. Many Iranians were bewildered by <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>'s sudden turnaround after eight years of sacrifice, destruction and more than 1 million casualties. <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, who said that endorsing the cease-fire was `` more deadly than poison,'' clearly sought to head off a political backlash by defending government leaders. `` They enjoy my confidence,'' he said. `` Do not blame them for the decision which they have adopted. For them, too, such a suggestion has been difficult and unpalatable.'' <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Robbins </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> specialist with <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, said that with the cease-fire, unity in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> `` is likely to disappear.'' With peace talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> stalled by the deep distrust and hatred between <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, some Western analysts fear the conflict could flare up again if negotiations do not produce a comprehensive settlement. Neither side has made any move to demobilize their armies. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official media reports almost daily that fresh units of volunteers have been sent to the front. Diplomats in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> say the Iraqis remain deeply skeptical of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s acceptance of the cease-fire after a year of prevaricating and believe <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> is only buying time to rebuild its forces for another round of fighting. Analysts believe <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would need at least two years to do that. They said that when the fighting stopped, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> was desperately short of aircraft, tanks, tank engines and even artillery shells. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> accepted the cease-fire only after <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION>, in a chain of lightning offensives between April and July, recaptured all the land <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> had seized in the previous six years. That robbed <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> of an important bargaining chip in peace negotiations and left the Iranian military in disarray. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerr </PERSON>, an analyst with the London-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview: `` While the talks go on, the Iranians are regrouping and rearming their forces as best they can. `` If they see no particular indications that the truce will do something for them, I'd expect to see them starting up the war again somehow.'' But that may depend on who comes out on top in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. At present, Parliament Speaker <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who seeks to end <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s self-imposed isolation, appears to have the upper hand. But he is opposed by hardliners led by Prime Minister <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> <PERSON> Musavi </PERSON> and Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON>, who fear the truce has weakened <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s revolution.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Iraq-Peace     09-24 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iraq-Peace,0636</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iraqis Stumped By Cease-fire Deadlock</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Gulf-Truce, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> claims it won the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, but officials increasingly suspect they are losing the peace. A string of <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> battlefield victories this year devastated <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s war machine and apparently forced the <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> to accept a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire it had rejected for nearly a year. But <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s demand for a permanent settlement of the 8-year-old conflict is stalled in U.N.-mediated peace talks. International condemnation of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s alleged use of outlawed chemical weapons against Kurdish rebels has put the oountry on the diplomatic defensive. `` The present situation is in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s favor, not <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Adnan </PERSON> <PERSON> Khairallah </PERSON> complained last week during a news conference with foreign reporters last week. Diplomats agree. `` The only card they have on the Iranians is military advantage ... and how do they use it?'' one Western diplomat commented. `` They're in a dilemma.'' <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> claims <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> does not want peace, just a breathing space to rebuild its army before resuming efforts to spread its Islamic revolution. The no-peace, no-war situation also leaves <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> unable to use its only seaports _ deeply frustrating <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> rulers who have made renewed shipping a priority. Iraqi suspicions were roused by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s wartime vows to spread its fundamentalist revolution throughout the Moslem world and by <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s remark that accepting the cease-fire was `` more deadly to me than poison.'' Ironically, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and its Arab allies demanded the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> cease-fire measure when <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> was on the defensive and Iranian troops were hammering at the southern port city of <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION>. Between April and July, Iraqi troops recaptured all the territory they had lost to the Iranians over the previous six years and even pushed into <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. They claimed to have captured half of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s tank force. <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> negotiators headed to the U.N.-sponsored peace talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> vowing to negotiate on the basis of victory. But their efforts to capitalize on military success has been frustrated. `` The Iranians have given nothing, absolutely zero'' at the peace talks, the Western diplomat said. The talks have bogged down over <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s demand that its two southern ports be put back in business immediately and that sovereignty over the <LOCATION> Shatt-al-Arab </LOCATION> waterway, the southern border between the two countries, be renegotiated. Silt and the hulks of half-sunken ships block both the ports at <LOCATION> Basra </LOCATION> and Umm Qasr, which lies west of the <LOCATION> Shatt-al-Arab </LOCATION>, and the political deadlock is delaying the lengthy task of clearing them. <PERSON> Khairallah </PERSON> said that leaves <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> free to use its other ports further south down the gulf, while <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> is deprived of its own, a situation that leaves <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> worse off than it was before the war broke out in September 1980. President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> said recently that if <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> can not use its ports, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> should not be able to use its ports. <PERSON> Khairallah </PERSON> said that while renewed warfare was unlikely, if the deadlock in talks persists, `` this might lead to fighting.'' The cease-fire also gave <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> a free hand against Kurdish insurgents deprived of their Iranian ally. That Iraqi military operation against the Kurds succeeded, but at the cost of rousing massive international condemnation of <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> over allegations it used chemical weapons. The criticism fueled <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s obsessive fear that the superpowers and other nations will tilt their policies toward <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, bolstering its foe in future military or political clashes. The chemical weapons furor also threatens to torpedo improving <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the West, which <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> had hoped can help rebuild it war-battered economy. Said one diplomat: `` They've just seen all that shot out from under them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1037EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Burma-DailyStruggle Bjt   09-24 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma-Daily Struggle, Bjt,0729</SECOND>
<HEAD>Getting By Is A Major Struggle in Strife-Torn Rangoon</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SEIN WIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pro-democracy campaign has made daily life a constant struggle in the capital, where residents try to cope with trigger-happy soldiers and the spiraling price of the staple food, rice. `` I lived in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> before -LRB- World War II -RRB-, during the war and after the war up to now. This is the worst period in my life,'' said <PERSON> Aye </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>, about 65. `` Life in <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> is now like hell.'' Residents have heard gunfire nearly every night _ presumably soldiers fighting protesters _ since military commander <PERSON> Gen </PERSON>. Saw <PERSON> Maung </PERSON> seized power one week ago. The government said 263 people, including 238 civilians, have been killed since Sunday's coup. Western diplomats put the death toll as high as 400. With soldiers, looters and others roaming the lawless streets, residents have been cordoning off their homes, and few dare violate the 8 p.m. to 4 a.m. curfew. Even in daytime, `` people are afraid to go out for strolls,'' said one resident who spoke on condition of anonymity. <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> has not been <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s most comfortable capital since Gen. Ne Win ended <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> democracy in a 1962 coup and began a ruinous 26-year path along the `` Burmese Way to Socialism.'' Graceful buildings from the British colonial era have decayed from neglect, the primitive transportation system was overtaxed and only a thriving black market kept the economy afloat. A <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> report has described <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> as <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>'s most rat-infested city. Ne Win resigned on July 23 after a wave of pro-democracy demonstrations, and a quick succession of three new leaders long associated with him has failed to quell the anti-government sentiment. A general strike since Aug. 8 has closed most businesses and paralyzed the government as civil servants symphathetic to the protesters stayed off the job. Residents who have gone weeks without a paycheck are preoccupied with scraping together enough money for rice. The price of a kilogram -LRB- 2.2 pounds -RRB- of rice has tripled since July to $ 2.50, forcing perhaps more than half of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> population's to eat rice porridge or sweet potatoes instead of rice. Gasoline prices have shot up as refineries closed and military and government departments stock up. Virtually the only way to get gasoline is through the black market. A gallon costs about $ 21, five times the price in August. Ironically, the capital's supply of electricity has become less erratic because government factories that are major users have been shut by the general strike. All banks have been closed, so even the rich have problems getting by. Hawkers of black market goods, who previously ran thriving businesses, have trouble getting customers even with big discounts. Other businessmen, such as small manufacturers and repairmen, also find they no longer have a market for non-essential goods and services. `` People do n't come to repair their cars, there's no gasoline,'' said <PERSON> Chein </PERSON>, an automobile mechanic. `` I had to terminate the services of my four assistants. I tried to sell my car at any price because I need money, but nobody is buying. The car is now useless.'' Only small roadside foodstalls seem to be doing some business. Most popular forms of entertainment have disappeared. The usually packed downtown cinemas have been eerily quiet since early August, when troops fired on demonstrators in the area. Large restaurants also are closed. State-run radio and television have featured military songs and war documentaries since the coup Sunday, and popular American television programs such as `` Starsky and Hutch'' and `` <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> to <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>'' have been taken off the air. But some people say they will put up with the hardships in the struggle for democracy. <PERSON> Sein </PERSON> <PERSON> Aye </PERSON>, who works at the government port authority, said he last drew his $ 50 monthly salary in August. He says he will defy the new government's orders to return to work by Oct. 3 _ on threat of dismissal. `` I do n't know whether I will get it this month with the banks closed. With food prices rising and no security in town, life is horrible,'' he said. `` But I wo n't go back to work, even if they sack me. I will get it back when a new government comes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1504EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p BC-DemocratsText     09-24 0929</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Democrats Text,920</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the text of the Democrats' response to President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s weekly radio address: This is <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, senator from <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. Democracy only works if people demand an accounting of those elected officials in whom they have placed their trust, based on their promises. If we allow ourselves to be deceived, allow our attention to be diverted, or simply engage in the cynicism that political promises are n't made to be kept anyway, then we all lose. You recall <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s big promise in 1980, that he would double defense spending, cut taxes by 30 percent and balance the budget _ a broken promise. In 1984 they said, `` It's morning in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' and it sure is. Every morning the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> has to print $ 575 million in new money just for interest to keep the government afloat that day. And if you do n't remember anything else I say, remember this: The deficit will be $ 150 billion this year and $ 135 billion of that is just for interest on that part of the national debt added by this administration. Now comes <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> betting he can fool 51 percent of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s voters until election day, that they wo n't know or care that today's prosperity has come at an unbelievable burden to our children. And he wants more debt. He says he wants billions more to deal with the drug problems, and you and I agree that the drug problem is enormous. But when you ask him where the money's coming from, he says, `` Read my lips _ no new taxes.'' He wants billions more for defense, including Star Wars at a possible cost of $ 1 trillion, but when you ask where the money's coming from he says, `` Read my lips. After this administration steadfastly opposed a day care bill that would give working mothers the peace of mind that comes from knowing their children are well cared for while they're at work, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> read the polls, saw the gender gap and quickly proposed his own $ 2 billion day care bill. And when asked where the money was coming from he said, `` Read my lips.'' He says he wants to be known as an education president yet you will remember this administration wanted to make ketchup a vegetable on school lunches, and vigorously attacked student loans and grants that give less fortunate children an opportunity for a college education. Now <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> holds himself out as an environmentalist and conservationist. But where was he while this administration indulged <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>'s `` rape, ruin and run'' policies until he became an unbearable political burden. This administration just discovered acid rain three months ago. For <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to pose as an environmentalist is like <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> posing as bank examiners. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says judgment is everything in the Oval Office, and Democrats agree wholeheartedly. So when this country was secretly selling arms to the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> and cynically warning every other nation not to; while we were trying to ransom hostages with arms and telling the world we'd never deal with terrorists; <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sat in the Oval Office _ absolutely mute so far as we know. And our question of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is, why did n't he pound the table like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cap </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> who called it a cockamamie idea? There are 240 million people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, and only five or six people thought selling arms to the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> was a good idea, and they all just happened to be in the White House at the same time. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> that he would be tough on crime, but he could n't even hear the shredders in the basement of the White House when they were running at white hot speed. Apparently his toughness on crime will depend on who's committing the crime. And when he told us he was liberated and was now his own man, and made his own very first, unfettered decision, he chose <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> as his running mate. And that decision speaks volumes about his judgment. The people of this nation know we have problems, and they're not afraid to face them. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says elect me and I'll give you more of the same: more debt, more tax relief for the rich, less income for working people. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> says he believes that men and women should be allowed the dignity of a decent job, an affordable home in which to raise their families, a clean environment, oceans free of unspeakable trash, an educational system that will get us out of last place in international competition, health care for the have-nots, an end to the nuclear arms race and the beginning of a strong national defense in fact _ not one just where the only criterion is how much money we spend on it; not one where we buy weapons whether we need them or not, or whether they work or not. Never in our history has this nation needed so much leadership and received so little. We can deal with every one of our problems. I agree with <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldwater </PERSON> when he says <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ought to talk about the issues. No problem has ever been solved by ignoring it, and no nation has ever achieved greatness by electing those who would divide us on the issue of who loves <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> more. And we'll never make it by continuing to elect those who break their promises. So we Democrats plead with you, <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ do n't read their lips _ look at their record.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP880924-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-24-88 1808EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WeatherpageWeather     09-24 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weatherpage Weather,0409</SECOND>
<HEAD>Widespread Thunderstorms Over Southern States</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Thunderstorms erupted Saturday afternoon over northern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> as showers ringed the Gulf Coast, but pleasant autumn weather dominated from the Plains west to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Winds blew a tree onto a trailer near <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, as low pressure over northeast <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> moved slowly east and northeast along a stationary front that extended from northeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. Showers and thunderstorms were scattered along the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> from southeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> into <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, from southeast <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> across southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and were widespread from the middle and lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> into the lower <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> valleys. The heaviest rainfall was over western and central <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> where 1 to 1 -LCB- inches of rain was measured Saturday morning. Southeast winds off the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> were producing showers and thunderstorm across extreme southern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. Hurricane <PERSON> Helene </PERSON> was slowing down as it turned northward over the open waters of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, its center 890 miles east of <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION> with sustained winds at 115 mph. From the Plains west to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, skies were mostly sunny and afternoon temperatures were in the 60s or 70s. Clouds and light rain were hitting parts of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state ahead of a cold front over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>. Temperatures around the nation at 3 p.m. EDT ranged from 48 degrees at <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Arcata </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, to 94 degrees in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Myers </LOCATION>. The low early Friday was 19 degrees at <LOCATION> Gunnison </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. Sunday's forecast called for widespread showers and thunderstorms across the middle and southern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> regions and inland across the central and southern Appalachians and in parts of <LOCATION> Upper </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Widespread rain was expected over the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> and the northern Plateau from a cold front approaching from the west. High temperatures in the 70s or 80s were expected across much of the nation. Highs in the 60s were forecast for the northern tier from the northern <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> across the northern Plateau, the northern rockies, the <LOCATION> northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, the northern Great Lakes region and northern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> into the mid <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>. Highs in the low or mid 90s were forecast for the southern half of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and the western Gulf Coast, southern <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, southern <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and the northern half of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with mid or upper 90s expected in the desert <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>