<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-PoliticalRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0577 10-16 1030</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Political Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0577,950</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dukakis Hits Back on Crime; Bush Says He Won't ``Mess Up''</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 4th graf pvs, bgng: ``I can't ...'' to
UPDATE with report of Dukakis' new 18-state strategy.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT FURLOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> fought to make up ground on <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> Saturday, declaring he has reduced home-state crime through a commitment `` right out of my gut'' while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> merely postures on TV. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, leading the presidential race with just over three weeks to go, said, `` I'm not going to mess up.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> received endorsements from Hispanic law-enforcement groups in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and spoke at a rally there before flying to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> for more campaigning. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, accompanied by <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> actors and two of the Beach Boys singing group, led a bus tour of rallies in seven <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> cities. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' running mate, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, said Saturday that despite polls showing Republican gains `` the momentum is ours.'' But he also brought up a story generally cited only by political longshots _ the 1948 newspaper headline incorrectly declaring Republican <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dewey </PERSON> had defeated Democratic underdog <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. `` I ca n't help but remember <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON> out there when the press had written him off,'' <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> told a crowd at a farmers' market in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> managers held a day-long meeting in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and set out an 18-state strategy, focusing largely on economic issues, for improving the Democratic nominee's election chances, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Sunday editions. `` The issues at stake are too important for the press and the Republicans to shut this election down three weeks before it happened,'' said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dach </PERSON>. Under the strategy, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign plans an `` all-out'' drive in 18 states where <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is favored or competitive, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported. Those 18 states collectively have 272 electoral votes _ two more than needed to be elected. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s running mate, <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, campaigned in <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, telling cheering supporters in <ORGANIZATION> Eau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claire </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Appleton </LOCATION> that the state `` is going for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Eau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Claire </ORGANIZATION>, he ran into demonstrators carrying signs questioning his military record. He brushed past them, saying, `` See you after the election.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s staff welcomed <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with a rally and presented him with a green medical uniform sporting the words `` Dr. Spin,'' in keeping with the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> senator's vow to give his own `` spin,'' or interpretation, to campaign developments. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been striking back aggressively since Thursday night's debate, an encounter that polls indicate put him farther behind <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. He also has been hurt by tough <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> television ads accusing him of presiding over a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> prisoner-furlough system that gave a weekend pass to a murderer who later attacked a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> couple. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said little about such charges for weeks but now addresses them vigorously and at length. On Saturday, he called <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` cynical and hypocritical'' for seeking political gain from what <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> calls a tragic incident. He spoke of murders in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> by inmates on furlough during <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s governorship. And he said that while <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has been vice president there have been thousands of federal prison furloughs and an incident last year in which an inmate on furlough raped and murdered a mother of two in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also speaks of a murder and rape committed by a man who escaped from a <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> halfway house <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supported. The governor said that he and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took responsibility for their programs but that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has refused to take blame for his failures. `` Talk versus action, TV commercials versus results, that's what we're dealing with here,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> said, comparing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and himself. He noted his state's 14 percent decline in the rate of major crime, and its lowest homicide rate among industrial states. That progress, he said, resulted from his personal involvement in a statewide anti-crime council. `` I did n't learn my lessons about crime from a <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> movie,'' he told the law-enforcement officers. `` I've been out there with you.'' `` This is an issue that is very close to me,'' he said. `` It comes right out of my gut.'' In his <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> appearance, <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> spoke warmly of the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> senator who is his running mate. `` <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and I have formed a partnership _ a partnership for the future, a partnership that will make <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> first economically and militarily,'' he said at a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> rally. `` The two go hand in hand. You ca n't have one without the other and we'll have neither if we elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to lead our country.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who like <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has been in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> all week, campaigned Saturday with actors <ORGANIZATION> Telly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savalas </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Norris </PERSON> and singers <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Love </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> of the Beach Boys. He told reporters aboard his campaign plane that he was going to `` go the extra mile to fight hard'' in the final 24 days of the race and would n't `` mess up.'' `` We're going to take the high road and leave the pessimism and the tearing down of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> to somebody else,'' he said. `` Here we go ... entering the home stretch of this national presidential election,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared at a noisy kickoff rally in an airport hangar in <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION>. He is pushing for an advantage in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, where the election is still considered too close to call. In particular, he is trying to energize Republicans and to keep the support of Democrats who may have dropped their allegiance in order to vote for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1980 and 1984. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used his weekly radio address to praise <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, criticize <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and ask voters to support Republicans in <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> races. `` If we do n't want a tax-and-spend liberal in the White House, should n't we give the president a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that will work with him?'' he asked. Rep. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, giving the Democrats' response, said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> would do more than the Republicans to answer Americans' most pressing concerns. He dismissed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as `` a silent partner'' in a <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration `` riddled with corruption, corruption that has reached into the president's cabinet, to the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, from defense contractors to Wall Street.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-NorthernIreland 2ndLd-Writethru a0592 10-16 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0592,0363</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed, Four Wounded In East Belfast Shooting</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 8 grafs to UPDATE with police identifying victims
and background on Protestant group, PICKS UP graf 7 pvs `In the...'</NOTE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two masked men in overalls burst into a pub in east <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> on Saturday, shooting to death a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> paramilitary leader and another man and wounding four others, police said. Police identified one of the dead men as <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>. British television reports named him as a leader in the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> paramilitary <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The second dead man was identified as <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> resident <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Raimey </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Raimey </PERSON>'s age was unknown. No group claimed responsibility for the attack, but suspicion fell on the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which is fighting to end British rule in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. The mainly Roman Catholic <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> seeks to unite the predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> province with the neighboring <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. Police said the gunmen, wearing blue overalls, entered the Castle Inn in the heart of Protestant east <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> and ordered the customers to lie on the floor. The gunmen then opened fire indiscriminately and fled, the police said, adding that at least one of the wounded was in critical condition. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> have been accused of taking part in racketeering throughout the province. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> and two other suspects appeared before <ORGANIZATION> Belfast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magistrates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 on 33 charges related to extortion of money from building contractors. However, the charges were later dropped. In the last 10 months, two leading members of the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> have been slain. Vice Chairman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McMichael </PERSON> was killed last Christmas by a booby trap bomb attached to his car outside his home in <LOCATION> Lisburn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antrim </LOCATION>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quee </PERSON> was shot to death Sept. 7 outside his grocery store. In the border area near the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, meanwhile, police said a gun and grenade attack was launched on the Royal Ulster Constabulary station at <LOCATION> Lurgan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armagh </LOCATION>, causing slight damage but no injuries. There was no immediate claim of responsibility.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 0154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Rebels     10-16 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Rebels,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Contra Coalition Heightens Frictions Among Rebels</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODOLFO GARCIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 U.S.-backed Nicaraguan Resistance leaders rejected an invitation Saturday to join fellow rebels who say they are ready to talk about peace with the government and lay down their arms. Those who formed the new <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> coalition are `` pseudo-leaders,'' said Nicaraguan rebel <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> in a recorded interview. Members of the Nicaraguan Resistance in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, the umbrella group for the rebels or Contras, played it for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. The new coalition of some Nicaraguan Resistance leaders was announced Friday. At a press conference in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> said the group will propose a Nicaraguan peace plan to the leftist Sandinista government that will complement a regional plan proposed by Costa Rican President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON>. However, <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> coalition is `` a new effort to trick the rebels which will only help consolidate -LRB- the power of -RRB- the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> directorate </ORGANIZATION> and leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Block </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> coalition is not breaking away from the Nicaraguan Resistance. He said it will try to win over other members to its ideas. The new group includes four political opposition parties, in addition to <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON>'s Southern Opposition Block. However, <PERSON> Ferrey </PERSON> discounted the group's importance. `` It acts as infiltrators to undermine the resistance,'' he said. One rebel official involved in the coalition said the new group was formed in part with an eye to the end of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, which has backed the rebels since 1981 in their bid to oust the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. The two sides agreed March 21 to begin a truce, which has been periodically extended despite complaints of violations from both sides. Talks have remained at an impasse, particularly over the Sadinista demand that the rebels give up their arms as part of a permanent peace.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Ignorance     10-16 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Ignorance,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>Survey: One In Six Britons Can't Find Own Country on Map</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One in six Britons questioned in a survey could n't find his own country on a map, and more than 40 percent had a big problem figuring a simple restaurant check, a newspaper reported Sunday One person even thought President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> leads <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s socialist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, although 90 percent correctly identified the opposition leader as <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinnock </PERSON>, the survey found The survey of 994 people, published in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>, was conducted last month by Market and <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. The newspaper commissioned it to test knowledge of geography, mathematics, common foreign language phrases, spelling, history, science and current affairs. The newspaper said the 18-question test was `` simple,'' but `` many of the replies were enough to break traditional teachers' hearts. The survey found 83 percent of the sample population could find <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> on a world map, but 7 percent had no idea where to look. Others placed it off the coast of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, off <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, in the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> or in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Asked to spell `` embarrass,'' `` satellite'' and `` exercise,'' one in 10 immediately `` threw up their hands in defeat,'' the newspaper said. Fifty-nine percent spelled `` embarrass'' and `` satellite'' incorrectly, and 28 percent failed `` exercise.'' Mathematics added to the problem, the newspaper said. Asked to add menu prices for the total cost of a hamburger, french fries, apple pie and coffee, 42 percent got it wrong or were unable to try. People aged 15-24 fared the worst in the survey, the newspaper said, and women generally did worse than men, except in spelling. Professor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hargreaves </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Cambridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> was quoted as saying the poor results by young people showed <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was `` in danger of producing a generation of ignoramuses.'' Education Minister <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumbold </PERSON> was quoted as describing the results as `` most depressing.'' In July, the <ORGANIZATION> Gallup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> released results of a geographic literacy test that showed that the Britons polled placed seventh among the nine countries surveyed. Americans tested finished sixth in the survey. Three out of four Americans in the Gallup survey could n't locate the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, most had no idea of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population and the majority were lost when it came to finding <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-FBI     10-16 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-FBI,0390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Communist Says KGB Could Learn Something From FBI</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> secret police could learn from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> by telling Soviet citizens when they are being followed or monitored by its agents, one <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> member says. The campaign for `` glasnost,'' or openness on selected topics, has allowed the publication of some unusual items in Soviet media recently. But a letter in the latest issue of the Ogonyok weekly is believed to be the first suggestion to <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> secret police officers to look to the West for inspiration. Under President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the government reportedly is working on a new statute regulating the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> from its Russian-language initials. But the powerful and secretive agency itself remains virtually above criticism in the state-run press. <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rachkov </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, who identified himself as a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> member, wrote to tell the weekly that one of his friends, <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON>, started to wonder why he was never sent abroad on business trips by the government agency he works for. When <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> signed up for a tourist trip to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, the vacation reservations were canceled two days before departure `` under a clearly invented pretext,'' <PERSON> Rachkov </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> came to believe that someone made a `` slanderous report'' about him to the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> that ruined his chances of ever traveling outside the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But he had no way of making anyone in authority tell him whether his belief was true, <PERSON> Rachkov </PERSON> said. `` He could n't penetrate the wall by banging against it with his head,'' <PERSON> Rachkov </PERSON> said. By contrast, the <PERSON> Muscovite </PERSON> wrote, a recent Soviet press report said an American who thought he was being followed by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> sent the bureau an official request to explain its actions. `` After a time, he received a reply containing an official notice that a file had been opened about his ` anti-American activities,''' <PERSON> Rachkov </PERSON> said. `` Maybe I'm mistaken, but it seems to me that this is a proof of democratization,'' the Soviet wrote. `` Moreover, I'd like to suggest that the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> legalize in this country, too, the same possibility of sending a formal request to the -LRB- government -RRB- organs, so that a citizen of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S.S.R. </ORGANIZATION> could protect himself, if necessary, against false reports and arbitrary sanctions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1124EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-MacArthurStatue     10-16 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-MacArthur Statue,0214</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vandals Bomb MacArthur's Statue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vandals bombed and destroyed a statue of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON> on an island where he led Allied troops retaking the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> during World War II, police said Sunday. The 10-foot statue of marble, granite and cement fell to the ground face down. Most of it was blasted to pieces by the explosive device, which police had not identified. The bombing occurred before dawn Saturday at <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> town on the central island of <LOCATION> Leyte </LOCATION>, about 350 miles from <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION> reported that the blast was heard more than seven miles away. The statue was one of six erected in 1976 on the shores of <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> to commemorate the <LOCATION> Leyte </LOCATION> landing, but only <ORGANIZATION> MacArthur </ORGANIZATION>'s statue was damaged. The bombing occurred five days before the 44th anniversary of the landing of Allied forces he commanded. Their return fulfilled the famous pledge `` I shall return,'' which <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON> made to Filipinos when his troops fled Japanese attackers at the beginning of the war. No suspects were caught in the bombing, and no motive was discovered. However, the island is a stronghold of communist rebels who have been fighting the national government for two decades.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1133EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Lebanon     10-16 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lebanon,0300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Die In First Major Clash Between Rival Moslem Militants In
Five Months</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Lebanon-Syria, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rival Moslem militias fired mortars, rocket-propelled grenades and machine guns in a five-hour clash in which six people died and 25 others were wounded, police said Sunday. They said Saturday night's firefight between Syrian-backed Amal militia and militants of the pro-Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> _ the first major clash between the two groups in nearly five months _ ignited blazes in numerous apartment buildings in south <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. A police spokesman said on condition of anonymity that Syrian soldiers deployed in densely populated districts of <LOCATION> Ghobeiri </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Shiyah </PERSON> stopped the fighting. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God; and <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION>, Arabic for Hope, have been vying for dominance of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 1.2 million Shiites, the nation's largest sect <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> stationed troops to the devastated suburbs on May 27 to put an end to a three-week bloody confrontation between the two militias in which nearly 300 people were killed and 1,000 wounded. It was not immediately known what set off the clash. Each side accused the other of starting it. The conservative Ad-Diyar daily quoted an <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> source as saying <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> militants kidnapped five members of Amal and released them several hours later after beating them. The source said two were hospitalized with various injuries. The same newspaper, based in <LOCATION> Christian </LOCATION> east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, quoted <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> sources as saying the fighting erupted when <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> militants tried to prevent <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> militiamen from raiding an apartment belonging to <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> `` sympathizers,'' claiming they wanted to search the flat. The <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> sources said the Amal fighters fired a rocket into the apartment when the Hezbollahis tried to defend themselves, the newspaper said. There was no way to confirm either report.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-BusCrash     10-16 0124</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-Bus Crash,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Topples Into Ditch, 43 Dead</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An overloaded bus traveling without windshield wipers in the rain toppled into a ditch and burst into flames, killing 43 people and injuring 40, an official report said Sunday. The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said the survivors managed to climb out the rear window, while the rest of the 83 people on board burned to death. The vehicle's official capacity was 38 people, the report said. The bus crashed Wednesday in a rural area of <LOCATION> Shaanxi </LOCATION> province in northern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the paper said. It said the driver, He Guangbi, was driving fast in rain without windshield wipers. The newspaper said the bus was traveling on a narrow road between deep irrigation ditches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Hirohito     10-16 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hirohito,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hirohito Stable, But Doctors Worried About Anemia And Jaundice</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> remained in stable condition Sunday, but doctors were concerned about his anemia and jaundice, palace officials said. Imperial Household spokesman <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> quoted palace doctors as saying the 87-year-old emperor discharged a small amount of blood Sunday morning. The emperor's temperature was 99.5 Sunday night, the palace said. His normal temperature is 95.9. Doctors gave <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> another .84 pint of blood, bringing the total he has received since he fell seriously ill last month to 17.4 pints. An <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> source said on condition of anonymity that physicians were worried about <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s worsening anemia and jaundice, but he declined to elaborate. Two doctors and three nurses have kept a round-the-clock watch over the world's longest reigning living monarch since he vomited blood Sept. 19. News reports Sunday said nurses have been massaging <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s legs and arms daily to relieve a dull feeling he has complained of since last week <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> quoted palace sources as saying the emperor has received guests with his eyes closed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DirtyDecal     10-16 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dirty Decal,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Arrested for Obscene Bumper Sticker</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NAPLES, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man whose pickup sported a bumper sticker with an unmentionable four-letter word was chased by police and charged with violating <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s new law banning obscene stickers. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Beasley </PERSON>, 25, remained in jail Sunday, five days later, unable to post $ 3,325 bail on charges of fleeing and attempting to elude police and violating probation. He is scheduled to appear in county court Tuesday. Sheriff's deputy <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Morera </PERSON> tried to pull over <PERSON> Beasley </PERSON>'s truck on Tuesday after seeing stickers on his bumper. One sticker read `` Life's a Beach,'' another had the four-letter word. The driver sped off and jumped out of his pickup at a dead-end street, <PERSON> Morera </PERSON> said. Police found him hours later hiding along the beach. Having an obscene bumper sticker or decal is a second-degree misdemeanor punishable by up to six months in jail and a $ 500 fine. `` I was wondering when we were going to get our first one -LRB- person charged under the new law -RRB-,'' State Attorney <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Alessandro </PERSON> said of the law that became effective Oct. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Algeria     10-16 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Algeria,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Orders Release Of Minors Arrested During Revolt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ALGIERS, Algeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Chadli </PERSON> <PERSON> Bendjedid </PERSON> ordered the release on Sunday of about 500 minors arrested in a week of rioting over the worsening economy, the government announced. In addition, the president suspended all hearings before the special courts set up to try the youths, most of whom were arrested for looting and acts of vandalism during the unrest that began Oct. 4. The government has said 180 people died in the rioting, but unofficials reports said at least 500 people died and more than 1,000 were injured. The government also ordered the release Sunday of all those imprisoned during the unrest who were not directly involved in the revolt and those `` arrested for crimes of opinion.'' More than 3,000 people were reported arrested in <LOCATION> Algiers </LOCATION> and provincial cities during the riots over shortages, high food prices and the government's program of austerity and economic reform. Schools reopened Saturday, and the country was relatively calm. Those still held in prison will `` benefit fully of the rights of defense in accordance with the law,'' the government said. `` No judgment will be pronounced other than in the strict respect of legality.'' <PERSON> Miloud </PERSON> <PERSON> Brahimi </PERSON>, the president of <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>, last week protested the special tribunals, which he charged with violating the fundamental rights of presumed innocence. Also on Sunday, Interior Minister <PERSON> El-Hadi </PERSON> <PERSON> Khediri </PERSON> announced a nationwide revision of electoral lists as a first step to the Nov. 3 referendum that is to launch Bendjedid's program to democratize his country. In the referendum, the citizens will be asked to approve a revision of the constitution that would make the future prime minister answerable to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Other, more far-reaching reforms are to be discussed in December at the national congress of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. No one except foreign-based opposition groups has publicly proposed the introduction of a multiparty system. The official <ORGANIZATION> Algerie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the referendum `` introduces the fundamental problem of the full participation in the political life of the country for all citizens.'' The news agency said the reforms to be introduced would permit the removal of top officials `` who have impeded the changes by inertia or incompetence.'' One of the likely victims of these changes is the leader of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mohamed </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherif </PERSON> <PERSON> Messaadia </PERSON>, who has not been heard from publicly for nearly two weeks. Many other personnel changes are expected in the government, including the possible replacement of Prime Minister <PERSON> Abdelhamid </PERSON> <PERSON> Brahimi </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Candidates-GutIssues Bjt   10-16 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Candidates-Gut Issues, Bjt,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Campaign '88: Emotional Issues Rule the Race</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Another in a series on key issues in the presidential race.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been a down-and-dirty presidential campaign, from gleeful Democratic denunciations of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as a wimp to the Republicans' skewering of <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> over crime, the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> and the Pledge of Allegiance. While the dismal tenor of this year's campaign discourse has elicited groans from past presidents <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, political analysts credit <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with tapping some of the same emotional issues that helped <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> capture the White House in 1968 and 1972 and laid the groundwork for <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s twin landslides of the 1980s. Some experts say it is a serious mistake for the Democrats, who have lost four of the past five presidential elections, to underestimate the seriousness with which the electorate responds to emotional appeals to its patriotism or fear of crime. The gut issues, symbolic or not, are real issues for many voters. `` Politics is a matter of gut responses, otherwise known as emotions,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Masters </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor of government. `` It's not just media manipulation,'' said <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> associate professor of government and expert on media and politics. `` If the Democrats continue to believe that symbolic issues do n't matter, they're going to foul up time and time again.'' <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, a senior fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, said symbolic issues loom larger in this election because `` American politics, like nature, abhors a vacuum. The candidates seemed quite deliberately to choose not to face up to the pragmatic issues.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said the race unfolded during a time of economic prosperity when there were few differences between Democrats and Republicans on dealing with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. `` When you subtract the issues of peace and prosperity, you leave very little, so we are left to fight on those gut isues of symbolic issues,'' he said. Conservative analyst <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, publisher of the American Political Report, said, `` The Republicans have replayed the key cultural and patriotic issues with the swing voters that got the Republican presidential majority started in 1968 and 1972 and 1980.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign flogged the crime spree of <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Horton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> lifer who escaped while on a weekend furlough from prison, and pummeled <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for being a self-proclaimed, card-carrying member of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. In doing so, <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s people succeeded in rekindling in the minds of wavering <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Democrats the emotions that `` pulled them to vote for Republican presidents in earlier years,'' while <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> failed to develop rival issues to appeal to the same swing voters. In their final debate last Thursday, both candidates sounded apologetic about the low-road campaigning. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, recalling the almost non-stop attacks the Democrats unleashed against him at their July convention in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, said, `` I do n't want to sound like a kid in the schoolyard -LRB- but -RRB- he started it.'' `` It was both ways,'' said <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Wattenberg </PERSON>, a senior fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` Two months ago, the best issue that <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was ` wimp' and the best issue <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had on <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was ` L-word' -LRB- liberal -RRB-.'' The Republicans `` went after <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> on all the L-word stuff, which they had some nice symbols for _ prison furloughs and <ORGANIZATION> Pledge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allegiance </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> and stuff like that. But it was n't about those issues,'' said <PERSON> Wattenberg </PERSON>, a Democrat. `` The reason they played was because they resonated in terms of 20 years of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> history as too liberal,'' he said. `` It's not a small issue. It is haunting this party. It is which direction the plurality party in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> wants to take the country.'' On the other hand, the Democrats' wimp charge quickly lost its punch as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> emerged from the GOP convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> as `` Captain Marvel,'' said <PERSON> Wattenberg </PERSON>. <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said, `` By going hard-line on the cultural and patriotic issues, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> drove down the wimp factor. ... <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> put on a bit of a <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> outfit.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s highest negative rating in polls remains the perception that he is too close to the wealthy and too far from the middle class. But <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> failed to `` come on hard and tough and use economic populism and nationalism to get the guys in the bar in the ethnic sections of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> or your dirt farmer in rural <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> angry at the Republicans.'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said, `` In a time of real prosperity, questions of economic justice and hostility toward big business do not cut it with the American public.'' As for such emotional issues as flag and country, `` you ca n't pretend that something that is an issue is not an issue,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said `` It hurts the Democrats when they try to dismiss this in some way as bigotry or tasteless or un-American.'' `` It is an issue to Americans whether you wear your flag on your sleeve or whether you wear it on the seat of your pants,'' he said. `` Republicans are not only willing to wear their flag on their sleeves, they're willing to wear it on their foreheads. The Democrats are willing to move it off their keester, but they still want to keep it half covered, and Americans do n't like that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-GunBattle     10-16 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gun Battle,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRA Slamming Dukakis in Radio Ads He Says Are `Outrageous
Distortion'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> is saturating more than a dozen states with radio commercials slamming <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' record on crime and guns as `` up-North nonsense'' that should n't spread beyond his native <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the Democratic presidential nominee, says the advertisements are an `` outrageous distortion'' of his positions. His campaign has asked the gun lobby to pull them, and is counter-attacking with its own radio and TV ads. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, general counsel for the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign, told the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> by letter that it was wrongly attributing statements to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and ignoring an issues questionnaire the governor had filled out, according to campaign spokeswoman <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Voles </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s lobbying arm, said the ads were factual. He accused the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign of `` a heavy-handed attempt to keep us from relaying the truth.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> started running the radio spots a week ago in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, among other states. `` We're covering those states from one end to the other _ probably thousands of stations,'' said <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>. He declined to say how much the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> had spent on the radio ads or on a companion direct-mail campaign. La <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> said `` there is tremendous support for gun ownership and hunting'' in the target states. `` <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' strident position as governor ... could very well cost him those states. He's making a last-ditch, desperate attempt to say he's really pro-sportsmen and pro-firearms ownership,'' he said. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> tried to defuse the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> ads last weekend before they began, calling them `` another outrageous distortion of what I believe.'' His campaign is counter-attacking with its own radio ads and, in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, with two television ads on the crime and gun control records of Republican nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, operating independently of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign, is running three 60-second radio spots. One quotes <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> as saying he was `` going to do everything I can to disarm this state.'' The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> narrator says, `` Do n't let this up-North nonsense go nationwide.'' Another NRA spot features actor <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON>, who says <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> `` opposed mandatory jail time for drug pushers, vetoed the death penalty for cop killers, gave murderers weekend vacations from prison. He also did everything he could to take guns away from honest citizens. ... <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is not just challenging your rights. He's taking on the Constitution.'' Another ad is aimed at Pennsylvanians. A `` sportsman'' says he loves the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> woods and accuses <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> of raiding his state's conservation fund to pay off state debt. `` Protect our outdoor heritage. Defeat <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>,'' an announcer concludes. In his letter, <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has denied ever saying he was going to try to disarm his state. He also said <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> had completed a questionnaire for the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> in which he said he supported firearm ownership for personal protection, hunting, competitive shooting, informal sport shooting and collecting. `` He did support a ban on ` Saturday night specials','' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. One of the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> TV spots running in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> says only one candidate for president has voted for federal gun control _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The ad cites a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vote as a congressman and adds, `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> supports gun ownership by hunters and sportsmen. Do n't be confused.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' other <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> TV ad says `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sat by while a federal furlough program released thousands of prisoners, many of them drug dealers _ almost 14,000 in 1987 alone. And now suddenly <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is attacking <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> for just one case in his furlough program. But <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> took action and changed that program, in his state he's reduced crime by 13 percent and the murder rate is the lowest of any major industrial state.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CongressRdp Bjt   10-16 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Aims To Finish Campaign-Year Bills; Leave Town</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM AHERN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, running behind schedule, is trying to finish work this week on election-year bills dealing with drugs and taxes so members can return home to campaign. Some legislators were so itchy to leave town that on Friday they sported buttons reading, `` Free the 100th.'' `` I certainly would hope we would n't have to stay beyond Wednesday. But nobody can predict that,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. Va.. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> originally aimed to quit Sept. 30, but bogged down in a fight over the The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> finally passed its $ 2.6 billion version on Friday. The bill calls for the death penalty for drug traffickers who murder, funnels more money to treatment programs and creates a new, Cabinet-level drug `` czar'' to coordinate the federal government's anti-drug effort `` This has taken more time than we expected, but it was very complicated and a lot of issues had to be considered,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., one of the chief authors of the anti-drug package The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed its drug bill Sept. 22. Senators hope <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members will accept some version of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> legislation rather than appointing a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> conference committee. `` If we have a conference, we'll be here until Thanksgiving,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION> `` We wrote our bill with an eye toward language the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> might accept.'' Election-year demands from voters to do something about drugs have driven the bill, <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON> said. `` People want us to respond, they want leadership from the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' Also unfinished is a compromise tax bill, but <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiations broke off in disagreement Friday, imperiling chances of reaching a plan both chambers can accept. The measure includes a package of corrections to the landmark 1986 tax law, some new tax cuts along with other tax increases to offset the reductions, and a taxpayer `` bill of rights'' for persons facing <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> enforcement actions. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan raises taxes between $ 7 billion and $ 7.5 billion over the next three years, compared to the price tag of just under $ 3 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> package. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiators proposed a compromise $ 3 billion package, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> responded Friday with a $ 4.5 billion counter, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> side turned that plan down, and the talks stalled. `` We have not selected the pallbearers yet,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., head of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> negotiating team He said the two sides would try to talk again Monday. Also pending on the legislative agenda are a variety of other bills, including one that would elevate the Veterans Administration to Cabinet-level status. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved that bill Oct. 6. Supporters of the legislation say upgrading the agency's status will give the nation's 27 million veterans direct access to the White House. It would be the government's 14th Cabinet department. When the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meets Tuesday, one of its first votes will be on a bill requiring full disclosure of credit card information to consumers. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, which returns to work on Monday, passed the bill last week. The proposal requires banks, department stores and other firms which offer credit cards to tell consumers about annual fees, interest rates, late fees and other information. Only a few states now have laws requiring public disclosure of such information before consumers receive the cards. Another piece of unfinished business is legislation providing the first-ever restrictions on lobbying by former members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, a plan that is part of a general tightening of federal rules against influence peddling by top government officials. Differing versions of the legislation have passed each chamber and the discrepancies must be worked out before it can win final approval.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Cambodia Bjt   10-16 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Cambodia, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Seeks To Block Pol Pot's Return To Power</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials engaged in quiet discussions last week about a man who, although unseen by the outside world for nine years, is at the heart of a diplomatic debate over one of the world's most unfortunate countries. He is <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON>, whose 3 -LCB- - year rule in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> during the late 1970's led to the slaughter of perhaps 2 million of his countrymen before he and his <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> allies were driven out by Vietnamese invaders <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawk </PERSON>, an authority on the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, says <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON> is believed to be operating out of a small town in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> border, plotting a return to power once the Vietnamese carry out their stated intention to withdraw from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in 1990. Hawk has written on <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> for <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a New York-based human rights group, and formerly worked for <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has been using diplomatic pressure to encourage the Vietnamese to fulfill their promise to withdraw but is trying to find a way to prevent the <ORGANIZATION> Marxist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> from retaking power once that happens. This issue is a major concern of pro-western countries in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and was discussed this past week during a visits to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by former Cambodian head of state Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> and officials from the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. The dilemma facing the administration is that the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, with help from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, is by far the strongest of the three rebel groups fighting the Vietnamese occupation forces. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is providing non-lethal equipment to the other two groups _ one led by <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, the second by former Prime Minister <PERSON> Son </PERSON> <PERSON> Sann </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> told reporters Wednesday that his solution is the formation of a national reconciliation government after the Vietnamese forces leave. <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> `` moderates'' would be allowed a role, while <PERSON> Pol </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON> and other top leaders would be sent into exile, possibly <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, insist they recognize their past excesses and have now become `` liberal capitalists.'' <PERSON> Hawk </PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> actions at the refugee camps they run along the Thai-Cambodian border suggest little has changed since their 1975-78 period in power. `` All evidence points to the fact they are the same as they were,'' Hawk says. `` If you look at treatment of civilians under their control in resistance base areas in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, their basic pattern of rule by terror and denial of human rights is still present.'' Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, R-Ore., said in a speech last month that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and, to a lesser degree, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, bear responsibility for the continued existence of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> as an effective fighting force `` Ten years ago, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> were all but dead,'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said. `` But because of questionable regional strategies and the self-imposed silence of the American government, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> beast was nursed back to health by Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and now the resolution strategy for <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> has to deal with the fact that the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> are poised to return to their old ways of torturing and terrorizing the people of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> sees <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> as a strategic issue. Worried about encirclement by pro-Soviet countries, including <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s highest priority is to hasten <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s withdrawal from that country by assisting the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> The degree to which the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> engaged in terror was outlined in a book written by a survivor of the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> rule. Writing under her adopted name in `` The Stones Cry Out,'' <PERSON> Molyda </PERSON> <PERSON> Szymusiak </PERSON> recalled the inhumanity of that era: `` It has rained over the past few days, and the ground is so soft that corpses not buried deep enough are rising up out of the earth ... I start praying as I walk along.'' In an article in a 1987 issue of Commentary Magazine, <ORGANIZATION> Arch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Puddington </ORGANIZATION> quoted a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> official as saying that the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> atrocities `` were the most serious committed in the world since Naziism.'' <PERSON> Puddington </PERSON> wrote that one of the most important objectives of <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> training was to infuse young cadres with `` a callousness toward violence, pain and killing. `` A key technique was the torture game. Animals, including domestic animals like dogs and monkeys, were systematically dismembered or burned by children-soldiers.'' <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> himself, who was under house arrest in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> during the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> era, once recorded his own reaction after witnessing these activities. `` The screams of the poor beasts were heart rending,'' he wrote. `` The sights and sounds of them were unbearable. But the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> youths could n't get enough of it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e AM-APArts:Whitaker 1stLd-Writethru b0436 10-16 0872</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AP Arts: Whitaker, 1st Ld - Writethru, b0436,0891</SECOND>
<HEAD>Getting to Know Charlie Parker</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 11th graf, `Whitaker beat...', to CORRECT spelling of
Scorsese, sted Scorcese. Writethru to b0436, sent Oct. 11 for
release in Monday AMs cycle.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>BY HILLEL ITALIE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For <PERSON> Forest </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON>, playing <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> did n't just mean looking or sounding like the great jazzman. It meant making sure everything fit. `` I was nervous. I was scared,'' admitted <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON>, who stars in `` Bird,'' <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>'s critically acclaimed film biography of the late jazz saxophonist. `` I was going into areas I had n't really dealt with. It was a most challenging role. As a person, I felt really honored to bring the character to life. It was so fortunate that it happened.'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who died in 1955 when he was just 34, moved into musical areas that few touched. With such musicians as <PERSON> Dizzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON>, he revolutionized jazz in the 1940s, helping create the style called be-bop. A brilliant and troubled man, he was no less overwhelming as a person. `` I think he embraced life,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> said. `` He took whatever pleasure he could find in it. He was n't afraid to do that. It held a lot of bad consequences for him, but he did that and that's where he hurt himself.'' Where <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> primarily hurt himself was by a heroin addiction that plagued him for much of his life. `` He was trapped and he started very young,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> said. `` I think it has to do with his particular way of life. He was very sensitive about a lot of things. I think he knew it was destroying him. He did n't want other people using it.'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON>, awarded this year's prize for best actor at the <ORGANIZATION> Cannes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>, gives a performance that should get Academy notice. He was born in <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and grew up in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. He attended the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> and originally studied opera. But he became interested in acting and began appearing in local equity productions. His involvement with movies came later. `` I was probably going to go to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and work on stage and that was it,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> said in an interview. `` It just so happens I was working on a play and it turned into an opportunity to do a film.'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> beat <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> at pool in `` The Color of Money,'' and played <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' protege in `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.'' He has been directed by <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON>, <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>. `` They all have a very keen sense of focus, although their focuses are different. Some go out in a circle and encompass everything. Some just focus on this little tiny thing.'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> had not even met <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> when he was given the part. `` I did n't know he had any interest in jazz whatsoever. I did n't have any preconceived ideas about him I never expected to see Dirty <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> walk into that meeting. He turned out to be a real jazz aficionado and really easy to work for.'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> is something of a rarity in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, a successful black actor. He had always been aware of the difficulties in getting good parts, but was not deterred from going into films. `` I'm fortunate because I never wanted to do film. I'm real fortunate that I never really thought about it. That fear was n't there because there was n't a great need at first,'' he said `` A lot of the roles I've played have not been written for black actors.'' As part of his research for `` Bird,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> talked to those who knew <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, including the jazzman's wife, <PERSON> Chan </PERSON>. He discovered that no one really `` knew'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>. `` It seemed they did n't know what was going on with him. That helped me immensely to understand where he was coming from,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> said. `` What did he really say to them? What did they really know about his fears, how he felt about this? When they told me what they knew, it was more important what they did n't know. Someone would say he had no fear and that would tell me how much they knew.'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> was true to the spirit of his music, spontaneous and emotional, given to extreme highs and lows. Understandably, <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> was drained by the effort to sustain those feelings. `` There are scenes in the latter part of his life when he's closer to death, when he's lost almost everything He's walking around like a lost soul, the only thing that's moving him around is a little pilot light,'' the actor said. `` That was difficult to understand, trying to find that place where you're still alive but you have nothing left.'' But how well could anyone really understand <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>? `` Bird has disentegrated into pure sound,'' a musician once said. Was Parker beyond words? `` He was pushing towards sound,'' <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> said. `` The sound was totally coming from emotion. More than words can express. I think that was something he felt, understood and put in his music.'' But <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> believes he shares an important philosophical goal with <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>. `` I think he had a quest for understanding, openness. I believe I have that, trying to figure that stuff out, being open to all kinds of different things.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MissingSnakes     10-16 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Missing Snakes,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thieves Pilfer Pythons, Boost Boas</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thieves who stole eight snakes from the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> zoo picked the most valuable snakes and the easiest to handle, authorities said. The snakes, worth about $ 8,000, were reported missing Saturday morning. Workers found no sign of forced entry at the Bird and Reptile Building and lids still covered the snakes' cages, some of which were found latched, suggesting the snakes did not escape. `` The thing is it's just these specific snakes that were taken,'' said <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Furber </PERSON>, zoo spokeswoman. `` We figure that somebody knew what they were doing and just went after some of the most valuable snakes in that section.'' Gone were three ringed pythons, three carpet pythons and two endangered Dumeril's ground boas. <PERSON> Ardell </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, animal care manager for the zoo's reptile department, said the snakes probably were taken for resale to underground pet traders or collectors. `` These little snakes that were taken may bite, but it would n't hurt at all So they took the easy ones to handle,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. The stolen snakes were between 2 and 3 feet long. The loss of the boas, which were brother and sister, especially worried zoo officials, Ms. <PERSON> Furber </PERSON> said. The snakes came from <LOCATION> Madagascar </LOCATION> and are listed as an endangered species because their forest habitat is being destroyed. `` They're pretty valuable animals,'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said. `` I'd hate for them to go off and sit in someone's garage somewhere.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1241EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-NuclearProblems Bjt   10-16 0877</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuclear Problems, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Moves To Tighten Up Safety At Nuclear Weapons Reactors</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, disturbed by evidence the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has mismanaged nuclear weapons reactors, has passed a law to put them under standards nearly as stringent as those applied to reactors used to produce electricity. Some lawmakers, however, believe even tougher legislation is needed in the wake of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s acknowledgement that its aging reactors at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, have experienced problems and that other plants have spewed radioactivity into the environment. `` The main difficulty is that the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> has been its own policeman,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>, one of the authors of a bill passed in September creating the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facilities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> to monitor the operation of weapons reactors. The board, yet to be appointed by the president, has the authority to inspect the facilities at which the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> manufactures nuclear weapons for the Pentagon. It will make recommendations to the secretary of energy, the president and to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, but it will not have the power to close down facilities which are operating unsafely. In the past, the need to maintain a nuclear deterrent has overridden concern over the environmental hazards posed by weapons reactors. Finding a means to balance those concerns will be expensive. The cost of building a new generation of safer nuclear weapons reactors is between $ 3.2 billion and $ 6.8 billion, <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say. And it is expected to cost more than $ 110 billion to clean up contamination from the reactors at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION> and other facilities near <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Golden </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> `` We quantified that as best we could, the tens of tens and tens and tens of million dollars that this government, this department, has to address in the future if it would in fact meet what we believe is a moral obligation to rectify past sins,'' Deputy Energy Secretary <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> told reporters. <PERSON> Salgado </PERSON> and other department officials say they are delaying until early next year the reopening of the first of three reactors at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION>, where they manufacture nuclear weapons materials for the Pentagon. And they announced the appointment of an extra layer of managers at the site to draft safer operating procedures for the start-up. By the end of next year, they said, all three reactors at the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plant </LOCATION> should be in operation. Meantime, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckert </PERSON>, chairman of the E.I. du <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nemours </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which operates <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, said the government has exaggerated the problems with the nuclear facility. `` The plant is not in disarray,'' <PERSON> Heckert </PERSON> said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` These facilities are safe, will work and will produce and meet the nation's requirements. The operators are well qualified and well trained.'' <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION>, which has been operating the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> facility since 1950, has opted to let its contract lapse. The plant will be taken over by <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> on April 1. <PERSON> Heckert </PERSON> claimed the government wants to criticize the plant so that <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> will look good in comparison when it begins operations next year. Pentagon officials say national security could be endangered by a prolonged delay in manufacturing one of the materials, tritium, a radioactive isotope of hydrogen, which boosts the power and efficiency of nuclear weapons. Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are warning, however, that they want prior assurances about safety procedures before production resumes at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. And some lawmakers may demand the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> boost expenditures to clean up past contamination. One idea circulating on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> is to require that <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reactors be monitored by the <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Nuclear Safety, an adjunct to the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which licenses civilian atomic plants. A panel of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> also recommended, in a report released in March 1987, that the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> operate under standards as strict as those of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>. But even some of the staunchest advocates of nuclear safety say that may not be the best immediate solution. Although the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> has years of experience with reactors used by utilities, it has little with reactors used in making nuclear weapons materials, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahearne </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ahearne </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> chairman who is head of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s independent <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facilities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION>, said it could take four or five years to draw up a set of requirements for weapons reactors that would be as detailed those developed for civilian reactors. `` However, some of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> criteria can be applied,'' he said. `` The first criteria is that the plant should be constructed and operated in such a way as it does not release radioactivity. Production goals should not be the first criteria.'' Until those standards are worked out in more detail, and until the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facilities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> is appointed and hires its authorized 100 employees, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> say they will oversee the safety of <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reactors. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Environment, Energy and Natural Resources, have vowed to key a close eye on efforts to restart the facility.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Reagan'sLastCampaign 1stLd-Writethru a0644 10-16 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reagan's Last Campaign, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0644,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Got Nixon Advice About Surrogate Campaign Role For Bush</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS lead to insert dropped word ``says.''</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s no-holds-barred campaign on behalf of <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was partly inspired by the lessons of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s loss in the 1960 election, says one of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s closest aides. White House chief of staff <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said that `` <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and I spoke several months ago, and I asked him to give his historical perspective _ what -LRB- President <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> did and did n't do for him.'' It is n't known how much 1988 campaign strategy figured late last summer when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> invited <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> to the White House for dinner. But history shows that <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> did little to help his vice president, which embittered <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, who narrowly lost the 1960 election to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. After remaining steadfastly neutral in the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> primaries this year, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has steadily increased his role as Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s celebrity surrogate in the campaign against Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has left no doubt in anyone's mind _ as <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON> did _ on his feelings about his vice president. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> mentions <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s name in official statements whenever he can. Last Friday, for instance, he sought to give <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> some credit for the successful flight of the space shuttle Discovery and for enactment of legislation intended to lessen American reliance on gasoline as a motor vehicle fuel. The president has worked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s name into ceremonial bill signings that otherwise were bipartisan events, such as the recent signing of a fair housing bill which congressional Democratic sponsors attended. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has hit the road to campaign for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> among so-called Reagan Democrats, conservative-minded Democrats in key states who helped elect the president in 1980 and 1984. `` I think it's fair to say that <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has campaigned for his vice president in an unprecedented manner,'' <PERSON> Duberstein </PERSON> said in a recent interview. `` I think the president's thriving. He's enjoying himself. He thinks he's making a difference.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> is enjoying his campaign role `` at a time when people said he was a lame duck and had no authority.'' It remains to be seen how much <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s aggressive campaigning will benefit <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The president has n't always demonstrated an ability to transfer his personal popularity to others. He was unable to prevent the Democrats from seizing control of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1986, even though he campaigned vigorously for <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates that year. `` If <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> goes out and says, ` This guy is a bad guy and this guy is a good guy,' is that going to move those people? Who knows?'' said Republican consultant <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON>. Yet, campaign aides say <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s speeches amount to a powerful `` reinforcing mechanism'' for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign messages. This happened recently when <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> went into ethnic strongholds of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> to urge <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s election a couple of days after the vice president had campaigned there. In the past three weeks, the president has visited <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, and he'll take his peace-and-prosperity pitch into <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> in the coming week. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s standard stump speech argues that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will safeguard conservative gains of the past eight years against a threat from liberal Democrats to raise taxes and weaken the national defense. Republican strategists initially envisioned using <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> mostly in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> and the Sun Belt and, of course, in his home state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. But as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strengthen solidified in those regions, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> concentrated instead on other, more closely fought swing states in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and Northeast. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s value to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has soared as troublesome issues, such as the Iran-Contra affair and ethics questions centering on former Attorney General <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> faded into the background as time passed. `` They have had a marvelous campaign in which they have integrated the message themes very well,'' said Democratic consultant <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> said it is `` just right'' to redirect <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s appearances where they might count the most. `` You're sending your biggest guns into the biggest battles,'' he said. `` There's no surrogate bigger than <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1403EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Angola-Savimbi     10-16 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Angola-Savimbi,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Savimbi Says Peace Process Difficult But Irreversible</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto JOH1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW TORCHIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JAMBA, Angola (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Angolan rebel leader <PERSON> Jonas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> says peace negotiations to remove <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> soldiers from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and establish independence for <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> are at a difficult but irreversible stage. `` I do n't see how the process can be interrupted. It can only be expedited. I don ` ock can be turned back,'' <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> said Friday in an interview at a supply camp for his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Independence of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, known as Under a U.S.-mediated peace accord among <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, more than 50,000 Cubt see how the clan troops supporting <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>'s Marxist regime are expected to withdraw within two years <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> said all but 5,000 troops should pull out in the first year. The four nations also have been negotiating the withdrawal of South African troops from <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, which is to gain its independence. The discussions _ which have excluded <ORGANIZATION> UNITA </ORGANIZATION> _ are to resume in about a week in <LOCATION> Brazzaville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION>, to meet a Nov. 1 target date for implementing a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> independence plan for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> said he has conferred separately with both <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and South African representatives. <PERSON> Savimbi </PERSON> moves elusively through the <PERSON> bush </PERSON>, rarely spending more than one night in a place. He was interviewedill go toward construction of a $ 2.5 million memorial to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> veterans. Others peforming at the <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> were <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> and the Americans, <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Johnny </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maestro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; The <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> celebrated his 10th anniversary as pope Sunday by beatifying three 19th century priests during a Mass in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s Square. The pope said the Mass before 28 cardinals, 50 bishops and about 20,000 other people in the huge square at the foot of the steps to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peter </LOCATION>'s Basilica. The three beatified by the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday were the Rev. <PERSON> Venceslao </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozminiski </PERSON>, a Polish priest who founded 20 religious orders and associations; the Rev. <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvestrelli </PERSON>, an Italian who headed the <ORGANIZATION> Passionist </ORGANIZATION> order for 25 years; and the Rev. <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Houben </PERSON>, a Dutchman who worked as a missionary in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. Beatification is a step toward possible sainthood. The ceremony came on the anniversary of the day 10 years ago when <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> became the surprise choice of the conclave to succeed Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> I </PERSON>, who died after just 33 days on the throne of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peter </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>. Before the Mass began, Cardinal <PERSON> Angelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rossi </PERSON>, the dean of the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cardinals </ORGANIZATION>, congratulated the pope on behalf of all the cardinals. The cardinal noted that during the past decade the pope has made 40 trips to 73 countries, made 74 trips within <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, wrote seven encyclicals and has proclaimed 247 saints and beatified 311 people. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> did not mention his anniversary during his homily, but afterward thanked the cardinals, bishops and the pilgrims for their good wishes.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> P.J </PERSON>. Powers, a white singer who has been banned from the radio in her native <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> for her support of blacks, is bringing her politically aware songs to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Powers, 26, has become popular among black audiences with songs like `` <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON>,'' a tribute to singer and anti-apartheid activist <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Makeba </PERSON>, and `` Yellow Buses,'' about the police vans in the black townships. `` I will never be a politician, but I ca n't sit back and ignore what I see without trying to do something in my own manner,'' Powers says. `` I do n't want to be sitting in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> when apartheid has been abolished. I want to be there.'' She makes a one-night appearance here Oct. 25.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1430EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Libya-AncientCity Bjt   10-16 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Libya-Ancient City, Bjt,0812</SECOND>
<HEAD>Libya Appeals For Aid After Flood Ravages Ancient Roman City</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ROM1</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FRANCES D'EMILIO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEPTIS MAGNA, Libya (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A flood has severely damaged one of the world's greatest ancient cities, and the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> government has appealed for help in repairing the ruins of the once-glorious Roman metropolis. A torrent of water rushed over <LOCATION> Leptis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Magna </LOCATION>, about 75 miles east of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, in November after several days of heavy rains sent water over a dam three miles from the ancient trading center on the Mediterranean coast. For three days, the rampaging river carried tons of dirt and uprooted vegetation through the ruins, leaving mud yards deep in such remarkable areas as the Roman Emperor <PERSON> Hadrian </PERSON>'s baths and one of two forums. Most heavily damaged was the <LOCATION> Colonnaded </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, a 400-yard-long road on which visitors strolled from the bath complex to the ancient port. Much of the stone carriageway, lined with more than 200 marble columns with lotus designs, broke under the weight of the floodwaters. The port end of the street disappeared and is now covered by a small river. Near the heart of the ancient city, the waters reduced the path to a jumble of stone blocks and columns fashioned from Egyptian granite and Italian marble. Only the ancient market, theater and forum were spared the wrath of the flood. <PERSON> Sandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Stucchi </PERSON>, an Italian archaeologist who surveyed the site, estimated restoration would cost $ 33 million and take 10 years. <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Almahgiub </PERSON>, superintendent of the archeological district that includes <ORGANIZATION> Leptis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magna </ORGANIZATION>, said the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> government is hoping to restore the site with help from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization. `` We want to make an appeal to all people who love monuments,'' said <PERSON> Almahgiub </PERSON>, looking at the weeds sprouting from several inches of sun-baked dirt covering the base of the basilica's pulpit. <PERSON> Almahgiub </PERSON>, who was born in <LOCATION> Leptis </LOCATION> and whose father was a caretaker of the site, said <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> would provide the personnel to do the manual work but does n't have the technical expertise. <PERSON> Bekaddour </PERSON> <PERSON> Ouldali </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> said the organization has asked <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> _ which colonized <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> until World War II _ to provide funds for a archaeological supervisor, preferably <PERSON> Stucchi </PERSON>, and has provided earth-removal equipment and a pump in case a flood strikes again An Italian Foreign Ministry official, <PERSON> Manfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Incisa </PERSON>, says his government is willing to help but is waiting for a more detailed report from <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>. Little is known outside <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> about the disaster because <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s magnificent archaeological inheritance is not easily seen Tourism per se does n't exist in the state ruled by Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>. A recent summer Tuesday brought only about a dozen visitors to <ORGANIZATION> Leptis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magna </ORGANIZATION>, almost all of them foreign diplomatic, construction or oil employees. In addition, lovers of archaeology must step delicately in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, whose regime frequently rails against foreign imperialism. For the more militant <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> supporters, reminders of ancient colonialism like <ORGANIZATION> Leptis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magna </ORGANIZATION> are unwanted souvenirs to be destroyed. Italians began excavating the sprawling city about 1912, the same year the Rome-based government of dictator <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> occupied <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>, which <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> controlled until the arrival of the Allied forces in 1943. The flood halted dreams for extensive excavation of the harbor, considered one of the best preserved in the ancient Roman world and expected to yield many relics from Leptis' beginnings as a key Phoenician port and later a prosperous Roman city. <PERSON> Leptis </PERSON> was founded by seafaring Phoenicians from <LOCATION> Carthage </LOCATION> as a trading post in the first millennium B.C. As merchants developed a brisk business in ivory, ebony, slaves, gold and precious stones from <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the site was established as a colony of <LOCATION> Carthage </LOCATION> about the 7th or 6th century B.C. In 101 B.C., <PERSON> Leptis </PERSON> became an ally of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and its residents gained full rights of citizenship. The city prospered during the reign of Emperor <PERSON> Septimius </PERSON> <PERSON> Severus </PERSON>, who was born here in A.D. 193 and whose arch of triumph greets visitors. With the decline of the Roman empire, <PERSON> Leptis </PERSON> eventually succumbed to the raids of Germanic tribes that maintained a kingdom in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> in the 5th century, then to Byzantine rule in the 4th century and finally to an Arab invasion in 642. Its name may derive from a Phoenician combination `` li'' and `` bada,'' meaning town at the edge of the desert. `` Magna'' _ meaning great in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> _ has been added to distinguish the town from another <LOCATION> Leptis </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>'s rich collection of archaeological sites include prehistoric cave paintings in the south, the ruins of a Greek site called <LOCATION> Sabratha </LOCATION> west of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, and various relics from the series of conquerors.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1509EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Ohio-Poll     10-16 0204</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ohio-Poll,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Poll Shows Bush With 11-Point Lead in Ohio</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Political Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AKRON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has an 11-point lead over Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> but neither candidate is favored by a majority of likely voters in the state, according to a poll published Sunday by the <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beacon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was supported by 47 percent of those surveyed and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> by 36 percent, with the balance undecided, the poll said. The vice president was ahead by a similar margin among all registered voters, with a larger percentage undecided, the poll indicated. The survey, conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Beacon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION>, was based on telephone interviews with 1,062 <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> voters between Oct. 3 and Oct. 13 and had a margin of error of 3.5 percent. The poll showed that 38 percent of the undecided voters were Democrats and 46 percent were independents. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made inroads in both groups, the poll showed. The poll found <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> attracted 12 percent of the Democratic vote, was running slightly ahead of <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> among middle-income voters, was getting more than one-third of voters from union households and was favored by 10 percent of black voters in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881016-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-16-88 1541EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-MickeyinMoscow Bjt   10-16 0708</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mickey in Moscow, Bjt,0725</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Mikki Maus,' 60 This Year, Makes His First Live Appearance in
Moscow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
