<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-GettingOutTheVote Bjt   11-06 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Getting Out The Vote, Bjt,830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parties, Unions Scramble To Boost Turnout</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 With two Texans on the national ticket, voter turnout in the <ORGANIZATION> Lone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> is expected to be high. But elsewhere, political parties and other groups are scrambling to get a reluctant electorate out on Election Day. `` I do n't see nearly as much enthusiasm as you typically see in a presidential year,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Verenes </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, in a comment echoed across the country. With only half of the country's eligible voters expected to turn out Tuesday, down from the 1984 figure of 53 percent, Republicans and Democrats alike know that getting people to vote will be their No. 1 challenge. The White House, 33 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats and all 435 seats in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> are at stake, and state and local races and issues abound. Parties, unions and other special-interest groups are running phone banks to reach swing voters as well as the faithful. As usual, workers will hand out leaflets, arrange for baby-sitting and escort people to the polls. But there are also some more unusual strategies. In <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, where the deer-hunting season opened Saturday, Republicans mounted a mail campaign encouraging deer hunters to get an absentee ballot if they wo n't be back from hunting in time for the election. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> has saturated <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and a dozen other states with ads claiming <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> would disarm sportsmen, a charge the Democratic presidential candidate denies. Coalition'88, a group of gays and others who want two <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> AIDS initiatives defeated, will have hundreds of volunteers on Election Day erecting `` human billboards'' at 70 major intersections in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> urging voters to get out and turn down the two propositions. Both parties are conducting massive drives for the state's 13.5 million registered voters but worry about the dampening effect of a ballot with nine state initiatives and possibly hundreds of local measures. Says state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Naylor </PERSON>: `` I'm very concerned that people will be confronted with long lines at the polls, get early results from the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and absentee ballots and say, ` What the heck. I wo n't vote.''' Reasons for the low turnout projections vary, but many pundits point to laws requiring registration days or weeks before the election. Many voters also may simply be uninterested in the races and find no compelling issue or inspiring candidate. In <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, where there is no race for governor, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> or a major statehouse post, officials expect many voters to stay home. <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> officials blame the tenor of the presidential race. `` There is more negative campaigning than there was four years ago, and I think it might affect the turnout,'' says <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, secretary of the <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> election board. But in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, home state of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential nominee <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and Republican presidential nominee <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the chief election officer is predicting a record turnout. Registration is up 345,500 from the previous high in 1984, and there is a larger than normal number of statewide races on the ballot to boot. `` If we ca n't get them excited about this election, I do n't know what it's going to take,'' said <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Rains </PERSON>, the secretary of <ORGANIZATION> state </ORGANIZATION>, who conducted the voter registration campaign. In <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, three tax-limitation initiatives are seen as the biggest hope of getting voters to the polls. And a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> gun-control referendum that's the subject of an expensive <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> campaign could increase voter turnout there by as much as 3 percent, officials suggest. Although the role of getting out the vote traditionally belongs to the parties, unions and other special-interest groups are doing their part. In <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, opponents of a proposed amendment to the state constitution to make <LOCATION> English </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s official language are conducting a major get-out-the-vote campaign, focused primarily on Hispanic neighborhoods. `` We will make 175,000 calls to Spanish-speaking voters and distribute about 300,000 pieces of literature,'' said <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> DeGraw </PERSON>, a political consultant coordinating the effort. `` There are 27 different organizations, some of them very small, working on this statewide.'' The <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> will have 500,000 volunteers out on Election Day, a majority of them in states with the most union members which also happen to be states with big electoral votes. The union has a computer information bank that lets volunteers know how to reach 13 million members. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> is dispatching buses to meet <LOCATION> Carlsbad </LOCATION> potash miners getting off work and take them directly to the polls. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> union is conducting its own telephone campaign and will have volunteers at key precincts. But even union officials say they are not sure they can get their members to turn out in heavy numbers. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> president in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, predicted a significant dropoff from the 1984 election and summed up the reason for some frustrated voters: `` I do n't believe there's a candidate running for office in this state who's given people a positive reason to go out of their way to vote.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FamilyIncome Bjt   11-06 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Family Income, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rich-Poor Gap Widening, More Families Depend On Women Earners</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s wealthiest families are keeping ahead of inflation, the poorest are losing ground, and many of the rest are holding even only because more family members are working, according to a new economic study. The study conducted for the <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> shows a widening gap between rich and poor since President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office, with the top-earning 20 percent making nine times as much money in 1986 as the poorest 20 percent, compared with seven times as much in 1979. Institute president <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Faux </PERSON> said the report shows average <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families have been under greater economic pressure during the past decade than at any time since World War II. `` Without new economic policies it is clear that families can no longer count on steadily increasing incomes and that the next generations can not expect to live better than their parents,'' <PERSON> Faux </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> economist who wrote the report along with economist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Fasenfest </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, said the widening gap between rich and poor is a reversal of trends in earlier decades. The study concludes that without big increases in the number of women working, as many as 60 percent of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families _ those earning less than $ 40,000 a year in 1986 _ would have been unable to keep up with inflation between 1979 and 1986, the latest year for which complete data is available. The report says the number of working wives increased from 55.4 percent in 1979 to 66.1 percent in 1986. `` This is an important first step in measuring the real economic benefit of having a wife work,'' <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said in a telephone interview Sunday. But he cautioned that more study is needed to determine the additional costs families incur when the wife works, such as greater need for child care. The institute, formed in 1986, is a non-partisan, non-profit organization which has often been critical of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s conservative economic policies. It said that with more women in the work force, average adjusted family income increased 7.3 percent from $ 38,492 in 1979 to $ 41,288 in 1986. The study multiplies 1979 earnings by 1.609 to adjust for inflation. But it showed that income for the lower two-fifths of the nation, or those earning under $ 27,000, is slipping behind inflation. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said the study used a standard economic practice of dividing the country into fifths by income. The top group includes families that earned over $ 59,533 in 1986. Their income averaged $ 94,104, compared with $ 9,133 for families in the lowest fifth. The report said salaries for most working wives have increased faster than inflation, while salaries for all but the richest <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> men have n't kept up. Wives' earnings, adjusted for inflation, increased 12.1 percent from an average $ 14,064 in 1979 to $ 15,768 in 1986, the study said, while husbands' adjusted earnings dropped from $ 23,204 to $ 22,240. It also said young adults who do not finish college are doing `` substantially worse'' than those who were the same age a decade ago. Low wages are forcing growing numbers of unattached young people _ 1.5 million more than a decade ago _ to `` return to the nest'' of their parents' households rather than living on their own, it said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Haiti-Paul 7thLd-Writethru   11-06 0721</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Haiti-Paul, 7th Ld-Writethru,a0829,0741</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Colonel Stripped Of Command After Coup Dies at Age 49</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with friend of Paul saying he
died under supicious circumstances. Pick up 3rd pvs, The military's</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL NORTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> PORT-AU-PRINCE </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Col. <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, the forcibly retired commander of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s most feared army unit who was indicted on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug charges, died Sunday under suspicious circumstances, a family friend said. He was 49. Radio Haiti-Inter said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>, a 29-year army veteran and one of <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s most powerful figures, died of a heart attack at about 3 p.m. in his home in suburban Fermathe. The independent station gave no other details. A family friend said there was speculation <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was poisoned, possibly prior to having a heart attack. The friend, who would not be identified further, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s housemaid and yardman were arrested and taken to <LOCATION> Petionville </LOCATION> police station for questioning about the colonel's death <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s former wife, <PERSON> Mireille </PERSON> <PERSON> Delinois </PERSON>, was taken to the station Sunday night and was under police protection because of fear of reprisals by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s relatives, the friend said. The military government's spokesman, <PERSON> Frantz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubin </PERSON>, said he had no information on <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s death. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> also said she had nothing. The capital, <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION>, appeared calm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> was fired Sept. 30 after a coup led by noncommissioned officers ousted <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s military leader, Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Henri </PERSON> <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON>, replacing him with Lt. Gen. <PERSON> Prosper </PERSON> <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>. The coup leaders said they were outraged with the state-sponsored murder and corruption <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> tolerated. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> had commanded the 700-man <ORGANIZATION> Dessalines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Battalion </ORGANIZATION>, the most brutal unit in <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s 7,000-member army, and had been linked to the <ORGANIZATION> Tonton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Macoutes </ORGANIZATION>, the hated private army of the 29-year <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> family dictatorship. Soldiers under <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s command have been blamed for widespread violence that has thwarted moves toward democratization promised after a popular uprising drove <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> into exile in February 1986. The violence included attacks on polling stations that forced the cancellation of independently run general elections last November, leaving at least 34 people dead. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> had been considered one of the most powerful members of the army, which has run this impoverished <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> nation for most of its 144 years. In March, he was indicted by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on charges of conspiring to import cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Soldiers who staged the Sept. 17 rebellion that ousted <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> said they wanted to name <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> the army chief but decided not to because of the drug charges. Immediately after the coup, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> appeared to be allied with <PERSON> Avril </PERSON>, but the new leader reportedly became concerned that <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> might turn against him. <PERSON> Avril </PERSON> had already ousted about 60 of the army's most repressive commanders. Haitian and diplomatic sources later said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s retirement could help lead to the renewal of a $ 70 million annual aid package the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> cut off after the November 1987 election massacre. One of the conditions the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has set for renewing aid is that <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> cooperate in halting the flow of drugs through <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION> into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The drug trafficking indictment alleges <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> conspired to import 220 pounds of cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in December 1986. It says the traffickers used a landing strip on <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s farm 90 miles outside <LOCATION> Port-au-Prince </LOCATION> to load and fly the shipment to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fritz </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierre-Louis </PERSON>, a former lieutenant in the Haitian army who later defected, told Sens. <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>. in a special <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing that 70 percent of <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s troops were involved in drug <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> led a military junta that assumed power when <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Duvalier </PERSON> fled into exile in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>. An attempt to dismiss <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> in June failed and led to the fall of the civilian government of <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>, who won military-run presidential elections in January. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> had reassigned <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> to an administrative post, but <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> refused and was backed by <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> ousted <PERSON> Manigat </PERSON> on June 20, accusing him of meddling in army affairs, and <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> remained head of his battalion. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> did not intervene when soldiers overthrew <PERSON> Namphy </PERSON> in September. The soldiers who formed <LOCATION> Haiti </LOCATION>'s new government have said they want to end random, state-sponsored violence and institute democratic reforms, but the government has set no dates for elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--FranceNuclear     11-06 0093</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--France Nuclear,0093</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report France detonated nuclear device at Mururoa</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLINGTON, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> on Sunday detonated another nuclear device at its Mururoa testing site in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zealand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> observatory reported. It said the blast had an estimated yield of 50 kilotons and was the 101st such test recorded since <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> began undergound testing at the site in 1975. It was the second in a series of tests that began last week with a 2 kiloton explosion, according to the department.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-ElSalvador-OAS     11-06 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-El Salvador-OAS,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grenade fired at hotel that will be site of OAS meeting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An anti-tank grenade was fired Saturday at the <LOCATION> Sheraton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> where delegates of the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will meet later this month, the armed forces press office reported. It said the rocket-propelled grenade missed its target and no one was hurt when it exploded at 7:45 p.m. near the hotel in the northern section of the capital. Army officials blamed the attack on leftist guerrillas who have been fighting for eight years against the U.S.-backed government. The Sheraton Hotel will be the site of the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> meeting from Nov. 14 to 19. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> is expected to attend at least part of the conference. The army also reported that rebels attacked a small army command post in the suburb of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ramon </LOCATION>, northwest of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, killing two soldiers and wounding five. It did not mention guerrilla casualties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-TyphoonSkip 1stLd-Writethru a0665 11-06 0275</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Typhoon Skip, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0665,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Another Typhoon Headed Toward Philippines</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to fix cycle slug</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Typhoon Skip headed toward the central <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> Sunday packing winds of 102 mph in the wake of a tropical depression and two weeks after another typhoon killed hundreds of people. The government weather service issued storm warnings Sunday for the eastern <LOCATION> Visayas </LOCATION> islands and northeastern <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION>. Small craft were ordered to remain in port. A weather service bulletin said that as of 10:30 a.m. -LRB- 9:30 p.m. EST -RRB-, <PERSON> Skip </PERSON> was about 380 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Borongan </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Samar </LOCATION> island and was moving west-northwest at 13.6 mph. The town lies 230 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The weather service said advance winds from the typhoon would begin pounding <PERSON> Samar </PERSON> and other islands of the <LOCATION> Visayas </LOCATION> chain with rain and gusty winds by late Sunday. A tropical depression code-named <PERSON> Tess </PERSON> moved into the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> on Saturday after flooding parts of the central <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. The Office of <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> reported at least eight people were killed Saturday in flash flooding near <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION>, 350 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The country is still reeling from the devastating effects of Typhoon Ruby, which slammed into <LOCATION> Samar </LOCATION> on Oct. 24 and swept across <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> island with winds topping 100 mph. Officials said at least 181 people died on land. In addition, more than 200 people remain missing after the passenger ship <PERSON> Dona </PERSON> <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> capsized and sank Oct. 24 in the <LOCATION> Visayan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> about 300 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> as <PERSON> Ruby </PERSON> roared through the central islands. The ship's owners, <ORGANIZATION> Sulpicio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>, said last week that about 64 people were confirmed dead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Maldives 4thLd-Writethru a0667 11-06 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Maldives, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0667,a0629,0776</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen In Ship Reportedly Give Up To Authorities</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Combines urgent lead with pvs. No pickup</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By RAJU GOPALAKRISHNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MALE, Maldives (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen who staged a failed coup in the <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION> and were holding 25 hostages aboard a crippled boat surrended on the high seas to <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> navy ships Sunday, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> reported. The agency quoting an official statement issued in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> said the foreign mercenaries surrended at 9.30 a.m -LRB- 11 p.m. EST -RRB- in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> between the <LOCATION> Maldivian </LOCATION> capital Male and <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> said. There was no immediate independent confirmation of the <ORGANIZATION> UNI </ORGANIZATION> report. Two Indian warships had been tailing the boat and military officers negotiated by radio with the gunmen for release of the hostages, Indian and <LOCATION> Maldivian </LOCATION> officials in Male said Saturday. Among the captives was a Maldivian Cabinet minister, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday night that the captain of the crippled vessel said the mercenaries fatally shot two hostages, wired the ship with explosives and threatened to blow it up if attacked. The report said a <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent had spoken to the captain in a ship-to-shore call. Maj. <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Maldivian </LOCATION> security forces said he could not verify the report. He was contacted by telephone in Male by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and said the captain's statement `` may have been propaganda.'' The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> report identified the ship as the Progress Light. <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ships </ORGANIZATION> lists the Progress Light as a 5,180-ton freighter owned by <ORGANIZATION> Maldives </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION> in Male Maldivian President <PERSON> Maumoon </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON> said in a telephone interview broadcast by the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> that the safety of the hostages was the paramount concern. <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON> said Saturday from Male, `` We would n't want to do anything that would engander their lives.'' Officials said an aide to former President <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> participated in Thursday's pre-dawn attack and may have instigated it. <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, denied involvement. In Male, members of the security forces patrolled the gray sand streets on Saturday. Businesses and shops were closed because of a national day of mourning for those who died in the violence. Bloodstains were visible near the bullet-scarred presidential palace and security force headquarters. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s top diplomat in <PERSON> Male </PERSON> said 27 to 32 people were killed when 150 gunmen _ believed to be Tamil mercenaries from nearby <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> _ attempted to overthrow President <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON>. `` This figure is probably understated, because the mercenaries may have removed their dead,'' Ambassador A.K. <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> said. He provided no breakdown on the deaths, but said 25 people were taken hostage aboard the vessel. Earlier reports had said there were 18 to 20 hostages. The mercenaries fled early Friday after Indian paratroopers landed to help <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON> and his lightly armed security forces in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> nation, which is also known as the <LOCATION> Maldive </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Fathulla </PERSON> <PERSON> Jameel </PERSON> said they suspected the coup was instigated by <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Luthufi </PERSON>, a former <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> aide. `` He was brandishing a gun as if he was the leader,'' <PERSON> Jameel </PERSON> said when contacted by telephone from <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. `` He gave orders to different groups of people, and for a short time this character went into the president's office and to satisfy himself, he sat on the president's desk just to assert he had taken over the country.'' <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> said <PERSON> Luthufi </PERSON> and two <LOCATION> Maldivian </LOCATION> businessmen accompanied the gunmen. He said said none of the three was caught and may be on the boat with the gunmen. He said the cargo ship, hit by fire from <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> troops Friday, was limping northeast at 9 mph toward <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> with the Indian warships staying close at hand. He said the hostages included Transport Minister <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Mujithaba </PERSON>. Western diplomats, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> supporters have been trying for up to five years to recruit guerrillas from <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s Tamil ethnic minority. Tamil militants have been waging a separatist war against the Sri Lankan government since 1983. The diplomats said <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON>'s supporters were thought to be behind coup attempts in 1980 and 1983. <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON>, 50, was first elected president in 1978 after <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> resigned. Indian paratroopers captured four gunmen Friday. <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> said said other gunmen escaped in two boats, including the one with the hostages. Indian paratroopers were conducting an island-by-island search for the other boat, <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON> said some Indian troops withdrew from <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION>, and reporters saw no Indian soldiers in Male on Saturday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-China-Quake     11-06 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-China-Quake,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strong Tremor Hits Remote Parts Of Western China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake hit remote areas of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Qinghai </LOCATION> provinces in western <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, seismology officials said Sunday. The quake measuring 7.0 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale occurred Saturday morning and was centered in the <LOCATION> Tanggula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> about 620 miles west of <LOCATION> Qinghai </LOCATION>'s capital <LOCATION> Xining </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jili </PERSON> at the <LOCATION> Xining </LOCATION> seismology bureau. No casualties were reported, officials said. Western tourists reached by telephone in <LOCATION> Lhasa </LOCATION>, the capital of <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION> more than 190 miles south of the <LOCATION> Tanggulas </LOCATION>, said they did not feel any tremors. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seismology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> said mild earthquakes occur frequently in the Tanggulas, whose peaks reach 19,680 feet. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. A 7 reading is a `` major'' earthquake, capable of widespread heavy damage in a populated area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0411EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Maldives 2ndLd-Writethru a0671 11-06 0649</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Maldives, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0671,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mercenaries Holding Hostages Aboard Ship Surrender</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS grafs 13-15 ``India's ambassador...were killed'' with 6
grafs to UPDATE with coup attempt death toll adjusted downward to
14, foreign minister saying no mercenaries left in Maldives,
details. Pickup 16th graf `The BBC...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By NILOVA ROY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MALE, Maldives (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sri Lankan mercenaries who fled with 27 hostages in a ship after an attempted coup in the <ORGANIZATION> Maldives </ORGANIZATION> surrendered Sunday when an Indian navy frigate fired on the vessel, an Indian naval commander said. The commander said all the hostages were safe. He said the Indian warship Godarvari fired on the mercenaries' ship, hitting it below the waterline `` It was a controlled, minimum action to stop the boat from moving and increase psychological pressure. There were no casualties,'' he said, speaking on condition of anonymity. Officials said Maldivian Transport Minister <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Mujithaba </PERSON> was among the captives aboard the M.V. Progress Light, a Maldivian freighter. The gunmen fled in the 5,100-ton vessel Friday after about 150 mercenaries tried the day before to topple President <PERSON> Maumoon </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gayoom </PERSON>, who asked <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> to send hundreds of troops to the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island chain to help rout the attackers. The Indian naval commander said the mercenaries on the ship surrendered at 9:30 a.m. 11 p.m. EST about 60 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION> are about 500 miles southwest of both <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>, an island nation 100 miles off the Indian coast. `` The hostages, numbering 27, have been flown by helicopter to <LOCATION> Trivandrum </LOCATION>,'' the south Indian airport used as a staging base for the Indian military operation that foiled the attempted coup. Earlier reports said 25 hostages were aboard the Progress Light, but the naval commander said he was including the cargo vessel's Indian captain as a captive He did not account for the other discrepancy. `` The mercenaries are to be brought to Male by ship,'' the commander said. The vessel was listing badly, moving slowly and was not expected to draw near <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s capital city of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> before 5 p.m., said <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> port authorities speaking on condition of anonymity. At a news conference in the capital Male on Sunday, <PERSON> Fathulla </PERSON> <PERSON> Jameel </PERSON>, foreign minister of the <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION>, gave an official death toll of 14 in the attempted coup: eight <LOCATION> Maldivian </LOCATION> security men, three civilians and three mercenaries. He said 40 people were injured and four mercenaries were captured. He said no mercenaries were left in the <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION>, a 475-mile chain of 2,000 coral atolls and tiny islets. He said all mercenaries fled by boat or were captured or killed. Casualty figures have fluctuated widely since the coup began. On Saturday, the Indian high commissioner -LRB- ambassador -RRB- in Male, <PERSON> A.K </PERSON> <PERSON> Banerjee </PERSON>, put the toll at 27 to 32. <PERSON> Jameel </PERSON> said the mercenaries were Sri Lankan Tamils, echoing statements made earlier by several officials in the <LOCATION> Maldives </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. Tamil militants are fighting a separatist war against the Sinhalese-dominated government in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>. He blamed the coup attempt on on ex-President <PERSON> Ibrahim </PERSON> <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> and a former <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON> aide, <PERSON> Abdullah </PERSON> <PERSON> Luthufi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Nasir </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>, has denied involvement. A senior security officer in Male discounted an earlier report that two of the hostages were killed. The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> reported late Saturday night that the captain of the Progress Light said the mercenaries fatally shot two hostages and threw their bodies overboard. The <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> said its correspondent had spoken to the captain by ship-to-shore radio. But Maj. <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Maldives </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said the captain told him at 4:30 a.m. Sunday that no hostages had been killed. <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> quoted Capt. <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jayadevan </PERSON> as saying the hostages had been treated well. <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON>, who gave only one name, said he spoke to <PERSON> Jayadevan </PERSON> by radio and believed the Indian captain had been pressured by the mercenaries to tell the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> two hostages were killed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0432EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Obit-TanZheng     11-06 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Obit-Tan Zheng,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senior General, Long March Veteran Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senior Gen. <PERSON> Tan </PERSON> <PERSON> Zheng </PERSON>, a former vice minister of defense and Long March veteran, died Sunday in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> said. He was 82. The official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which carried the announcement, did not give the cause of death or other details. Tan was a native of central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hunan </LOCATION> province, like the late revolutionary leader <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>, and joined in an abortive peasant uprising led by <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> in the autumn of 1927 against the Nationalist government under <PERSON> Chiang </PERSON> <PERSON> Kai-shek </PERSON>. Tan briefly served as <PERSON> Mao </PERSON>'s personal secretary and took part in the Long March, the grueling 1934-35 retreat by the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> from southeastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to the northwest. He held political posts in the army throughout the civil war against the Nationalists, which ended in 1949 with <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> victory. In 1954 he became vice minister of defense and later was named head of the army's <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. He lost both posts in the 1960s shortly before being purged during the radical leftist Cultural Revolution of 1966-76. After being rehabilitated in 1975, he was an advisor to the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which sets overall military policy, and held several posts in the legislature. He retired in 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0454EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Hirohito     11-06 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hirohito,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Emperor Vomits And Discharges Blood, Receives More Large
Transfusions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID THURBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> vomited blood Sunday and discharged a substantial amount of blood twice from his bowels, palace officials said. Doctors gave the 87-year-old emperor several emergency transfusions totaling 3.4 pints, the officials said. The frail monarch's pulse rate rose to 118 per minute early in the evening, <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said. The rate is about the same as that of a normal person while running. His systolic blood pressure, which has been about 150 in recent days, dropped to 122, <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said. He said <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> discharged a considerable amount of blood in the morning, then a large amount late in the afternoon. At the same time as the later discharge, the frail emperor also vomited a small amount of blood, he said. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has discharged blood from his bowels intermittently since he became seriously ill Sept. 19. Palace officials have described three past discharges as `` considerable,'' and one last Sunday as `` large.'' Doctors believe the blood is coming from a hemorrhage in the area of the emperor's upper intestine. Sunday's transfusions brought the total amount of blood the emperor has received since Sept. 19 to 38.9 pints, close to four times the normal amount in his body. <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was awake and had talked to attendants in his room in the Fukiage Palace. In recent days the emperor has spent much of the time sleeping, according to palace sources. After a brief visit Saturday, his daughter described him as fatigued. The emperor's temperature declined again Sunday, following a decision by his doctors Friday to resume the use of antibiotics to control a worsening infection around his bile duct. The doctors had stopped the powerful drugs two weeks ago because of concerns about possible side effects. Palace officials have refused to confirm or deny reports that <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> has cancer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 0558EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Aleutians-Quake     11-06 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Aleutians-Quake,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Moderate Tremor Hits Remote Islands Off Alaska</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A moderate earthquake hit the remote <LOCATION> Aleutian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and was felt on a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base there, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey said today. The quake measured 5.2 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale when it was measured at 3:21 a.m. EST in the <LOCATION> Andreanof </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, part of the chain of volcanic islands that spreads out southwest of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Terrell </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION>, said the center of the earthquake was about 80 miles from Adak, an island which is about 1,000 miles from <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> and holds a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> base. Tremors were felt on the base but there was no initial report of damage, said <PERSON> Terrell </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. A quake of magnitude 5 can cause considerable damage in a populated area.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Israel-Lebanon     11-06 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Lebanon,0173</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Stages Air Raid On Guerrilla Base In Lebanon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli warplanes raided and destroyed a guerrilla base near the southern Lebanese city of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION> on Sunday, the army command said. The base was used for launching attacks and storing ammunition, the army said. It said all planes that participated in the raid returned safely to base. The brief army announcement gave no further details. Lebanese reports said the attack was carried out by helicopter gunships which fired four rockets in two sorties against <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> bases in the Ein-el-Hilweh refugee camp. Lebanese police, who had no immediate report of casualties, said Israeli-backed militiamen also clashed with leftist guerrillas east of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION>. The raid was the sixth by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> in three weeks and the 21st this year. By police count, 108 people have been killed and 199 wounded since Jan. 3 in the earlier raids. Sunday's raid followed mock dive-bombing runs by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> aircraft over <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> bases east of <LOCATION> Sidon </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-YellowSnow     11-06 0348</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yellow Snow,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yellowstone Snow Studied for Effects of Summer Fires on Animals</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A scientist is studying the effects of last summer's fire in Yellowstone National Park by analyzing urine-soaked snow to determine whether animals are getting enough to eat. Biologist <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON> perfected the testing, which experts think has great promise for aiding wildlife studies around the world. `` <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s technique is generating a great deal of excitement among researchers,'' said <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mech </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Fish and <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> scientist who is an internationally known wolf expert. `` It can be applied anywhere animals live in snow for part of the year.'' Mech and <PERSON> Ulysses </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Seal </PERSON>, a biochemist widely recognized for his research on endangered wildlife, initiated the technique of using snow-urine samples in wildlife research. But several years ago, they turned over perfection of the technique to <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON>, then a graduate student at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>. For the past two years, <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON> has studied <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION>'s elk and bison under an agreement between the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, for whom he works, and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which manages the 2.2 million-acre park in <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON>'s work will allow scientists to compare the health of the bison and elk before and after the summer fires, which affected 500,000 to 880,000 acres in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. There are no findings yet from the study. About 20,000 elk and 2,600 bison spend the winter in <LOCATION> Yellowstone </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> estimates that four bison and 250 elk died in the fires, which simply forced most big mammals into different parts of the park to find forage. <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON> was among about 25 scientists who recently met at <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> to prepare a plan for studying the effects of the fires. He stressed that, while the fires charred extensive timber and brush, the burned-over areas form a mosaic pattern, rather than a contiguous tract. That's important, <PERSON> DelGiudice </PERSON> said, because while vegetation has not yet returned to areas burned in late summer, young plants already have emerged in tracts that were charred earlier. Those plants should help bison and elk survive this winter.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Queen'sCorgis     11-06 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Queen's Corgis,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palace Silent On Report That Queen's Dogs Seeing Psychologist</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>'s corgi dogs are being treated by an animal psychologist because of their bad record of nipping members of the royal household, The Mail on Sunday reported. The paper said guardsmen, policemen, footmen and even the royal clockwinder have fallen prey to the corgis' nips. Buckingham Palace refused comment. `` I do n't think we'd like to comment on that kind of story,'' said a palace spokesman who by custom was not identified. The dogs are being seen by animal behavior specialist Dr. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Mugford </PERSON>, who firmly believes in counseling owners as well, The Mail on Sunday said. <PERSON> Mugford </PERSON>, whose office was closed Sunday, was quoted by the paper as saying of corgis: `` They are, of course, collie-type dogs, originally bred for cattle herding. As such, they will chase anything, particularly ankles.'' The present generation of royal corgis, according to the paper, are named: Spark, Mist, Sable, <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Kelpie </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Piper </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chipper </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. The article did not say how many of the dogs are receiving treatment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--India-Dogs     11-06 0144</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--India-Dogs,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dogs Found In Hospitals To Be Shot On Sight</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Readers may find some material offensive</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> authorities have ordered police to shoot all dogs found inside hospitals in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> state after a dog killed a baby, a newspaper reported Sunday. State Health Minister <PERSON> Prasanta </PERSON> <PERSON> Sur </PERSON> believes this is the only way to prevent stray dogs from biting, killing or carrying away infants, the Calcutta-based Statesman daily said. On Tuesday, a dog attacked and killed a baby at the <LOCATION> Sainthia </LOCATION> primary health center, the newspaper said. The Statesman quoted Sur as saying dogs periodically enter hospitals and bite or carry off babies. The Statesman quoted Sur as saying pigs also are sometimes found in hospitals. It said it had given hospitals one year's warning to keep swine out of hospitals or face unspecified stern action.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--China-Prostitution     11-06 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--China-Prostitution,0151</SECOND>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hainan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> approved the death penalty for anyone convicted of forcing women to be prostitutes, a newspaper reported Sunday. The provincial government enacted the law Saturday as part of a crackdown on prostitution and venereal disease, which officials say have infiltrated all walks of life on the island, the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. The island off the southern Chinese coast also approved laws in which prostitutes and customers would be fined $ 1,300 and jailed two weeks upon conviction. Those who commit `` severe cases'' will be sent to labor camps, the report said. It did not explain `` severe cases.'' Prostitution is reportedly more prevalent in areas where the communist government's economic reform policies have encouraged private enterprise and labor mobility. <PERSON> Hainan </PERSON> was named <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s newest Special Economic Zone this year to attract foreign investment
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--CabbageFlood     11-06 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Cabbage Flood,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shock Teams Clean Streets Of Cabbage During Buying Season</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sanitation teams worked around the clock to clear tons of cabbage leaves from the streets of the capital during the cabbage-buying season, a newspaper said Sunday. The teams have picked up more than 10,000 tons of cabbage, the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Daily said. The cabbage fell off some of the hundreds of trucks piled high with the produce that began rattling into the city from farms last week. More of the leaves were scattered at marketplaces where families bought cartloads of cabbage, a staple they stack on their roofs or fire escapes and eat over the winter months. More than 500 garbage trucks and more than 2,000 workers were enlisted in the clean-up effort, the paper said. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents are expected to buy more than 660 million pounds of cabbage this season, or more than 66 pounds for each of the city's nearly 10 million people.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--HeroinBust     11-06 0066</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Heroin Bust,0066</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Seize 17 Pounds Of Heroin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SINGAPORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities seized 17.6 pounds of heroin at the <LOCATION> Changi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> from a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> couple, the state-owned <ORGANIZATION> Singapore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. The broadcast said a 28-year-old man and 24-year-old woman would be charged Monday. It did not identify the couple by name, list the charges or say when the seizure took place.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Senegal-Libya     11-06 0068</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Senegal-Libya,0068</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dakar And Tripoli Re-establish Diplomatic Relations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAKAR, Senegal (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> have re-established diplomatic relations after an eight-year break. <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION>'s government, which made the announcement Saturday, broke relations with <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> in June 1980, accusing <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> of `` unacceptable interference'' in the internal affairs of <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION>. At the time, <LOCATION> Senegal </LOCATION> said Moslem fundamentalist Senegalese were being supported by <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> in efforts to destabilize the government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--GulfExercises     11-06 0137</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Gulf Exercises,0138</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Gulf States Conducting Largest-Ever Joint Air Exercise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUWAIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The six states of the <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> have launched their largest-ever joint air force maneuvers, involving 44 warplanes, a government spokesman said Sunday. The 10-day exercises aim to train pilots and officers on how to deal with the different types of aircraft used by the <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, said Maj. <PERSON> Bader </PERSON> <PERSON> Saleh </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Kuwait </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. He said land contingents from the <ORGANIZATION> GCC </ORGANIZATION> states will take part in the final stage of the exercise, when the warplanes will use live ammunition. <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Qatar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> formed the alliance to strengthen collective security and economic unity shortly after war broke out between their two northern neighbors, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, in September 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-CongressRdp Bjt   11-06 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Gun for Bigger Senate Advantage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There is an unusual unanimity this year about prospects for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in Tuesday's balloting: Democrats will remain in control, and may well increase their eight-seat advantage. `` The Democrats will hold onto 54 seats at a minimum, and I believe have a very good opportunity to add,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` We realize it's still quite volatile out there,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senatorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` We could end up on Election Day minus two. But we could just as easily be plus two or better.'' One reason little change is expected is that, unlike some past presidential elections, there has been no overriding national theme dictated by the top of the ticket, the kind of compelling issue that would propel voters to seek massive changes. Rather, polls have show a general contentment with the status quo, and that works to the benefit of incumbents. That advantage extends to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, where very little movement is expected in the Democrats' 255-177 majority. `` There is n't the thematic difference'' that has pervaded presidential contests in the past, <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said. `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said it best: We are the change. It's not as clear a mandate as in 1980, when there was such a screaming need for change.'' That was the year Republicans rode <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s coattails to a 12-seat pickup and control of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for the first time in a quarter-century. In 1986, an eight-seat gain enabled Democrats to retake control. This time, Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> have been criticized for running a race devoid of issues, devoted mostly to personal attacks and distortions of each other's records. So issues in this year's <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> campaign have been largely drawn from a list of topics that Democrats claim as their own, although they have been used by candidates of both parties: the environment, education, Social Security, health care and `` family issues'' like child care. Also prominent in <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> stump speeches and advertising have been the problems of drugs and crime, which register near the top of Americans' concerns in national polls. Most <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> incumbents of both parties appeared likely to win re-election on Tuesday, but there were several prominent exceptions. Analysts said Republican Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Karnes </PERSON>, who was appointed in 1987 to fill an unexpired <ORGANIZATION> Nebraska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> term, was the most likely to be ousted. Democratic former Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerrey </PERSON>, a popular figure with a Hollywood-like appeal in the state, held a heavy lead in polls. Three other incumbents _ two Republicans and one Democrat _ also faced difficult battles for survival. In <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, GOP Sen. Chic <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, who for months had been considered the most vulnerable Republican incumbent, has fought back to a dead heat with his challenger, Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>. A political action committee of import car dealers was pouring $ 382,000 into mass mailings and TV spots for <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON> was running ads linking himself to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON> to <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. Sen. <PERSON> Lowell </PERSON> <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON>, the veteran maverick Republican from <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>, has resorted to his own negative ads attacking challenger <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, the state's Democratic attorney general. The race is the most complex political matchup in the country. <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON> has sought to outflank <PERSON> Weicker </PERSON> by portraying him as aloof from <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> concerns, and has attracted support from all parts of the political spectrum. Republicans hungry for an upset were pointing to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, where they claimed to have <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> incumbent <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON> on the run. His GOP rival, <ORGANIZATION> Yellowstone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, was running positive biographical ads in the closing days of the campaign, while <PERSON> Melcher </PERSON> was airing man-in-the-street testimonials advising against sending `` a greenhorn'' to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Six open seats, where no incumbent was seeking re-election, were the other major battleground. Democratic former <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> appeared poised to claim a formerly Republican seat, and Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Vt </LOCATION>., was likely to enter the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from his state Rep. <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Lott </PERSON>, R-Miss., also seemed to be holding firmly to a polling lead in his bid to replace retiring Democratic Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stennis </PERSON> But in three other open seats, the outcome was up for grabs. Former Sen. <PERSON> Slade </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON>, a Republican, picked up a spate of last-minute newspaper endorsements in his bid to keep <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat in <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> hands, but polls showed Democratic rival Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowry </PERSON> in a dead heat <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> promised a similar cliffhanger, with Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> MacKay </PERSON> seeking to beat out Republican Rep. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> in a state where <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> held a heavy advantage. Like <PERSON> Hecht </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> was receiving substantial last-minute backing from the import car dealers PAC. In <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, Democrat <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, a millionaire who owns the <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bucks </ORGANIZATION> basketball team, was holding onto a narrowing lead in his effort to retain the seat of retiring Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Proxmire </PERSON> for the Democrats. Republican state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> minority leader <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Engeleiter </PERSON> was pressing hard, and both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> campaigned for her in the state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Candidates-Housing     11-06 0963</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Candidates-Housing,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Campaign '88: Next President Must Face Housing Crunch</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Election Rdp Bjt</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: This is the last in a series of stories highlighting issues
in
the White House race.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> relishes talking about how he and President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> solved the `` malaise'' of the <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> years, when inflation was in double digits and the prime interest rate soared past 20 percent. `` Now, with low inflation and low interest rates, housing is again within reach of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s families,'' boasts <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, the Republican presidential nominee. `` Sound Republican policies have helped more families than ever to realize the dream of home ownership.'' Interest rates did come down, but housing prices rose rapidly and a smaller percentage of Americans live in their own homes today than when the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration started: 63.7 percent compared with 65.6 percent in 1980. Tenants in many cities are confronted with soaring rents and a dwindling supply of apartments. Homelessness has become a major social ill, with estimates of the number of people living on the streets or in shelters ranging from 250,000 to 3 million. It adds up to a crisis in housing for millions of Americans that poses a major challenge for the next president. The vice president's Democratic rival, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, has sought to make housing one of the major campaign issues to support his claim that `` I'm on your side.'' Despite his upbeat talk, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has acknowledged the problems and offered the outlines of the strategy he would employ to solve them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has promised that one of his chief goals `` will be to see that all American families are able to obtain decent, affordable housing. ... To do this, we will maintain the policies that have brought us low inflation, low interest rates and strong job creation, which have given many Americans the income to buy homes.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> wants to allow first-time home buyers to withdraw up to $ 10,000 in tax-free savings from their Individual Retirement Accounts or 401-K accounts to apply toward their downpayments. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Levittown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, the post-World War II model community, to unveil his plan called Home START -LRB- Saving Toward An Affordable Residence Today -RRB-. It would cost the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> $ 400 million in lost revenues. Both candidates propose relaxing <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> loan rules for first-time buyers. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he will ask the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> to experiment with reduced downpayments, possibly as low as $ 1,000. He also wants the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> to allow higher loan limits in expensive housing areas. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' Home START would allow people to get <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> mortagages with only 3 percent down. The agency now requires 3 percent down for the first $ 25,000 and 5 percent for the remainder of the purchase price. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> also would remove the current ceiling on <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> loan guarantees of $ 67,000 nationally and up to $ 101,250 in high cost areas, and would expand <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> financing of adjustable rate mortgages. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, criticized by Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> during the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primaries for saying most of the homeless were mentally ill, now acknowledges that `` too many are families with children.'' He promises to form public-private partnerships to build more single-room occupancy shelters, and he backs the $ 280 million McKinney Act to aid the homeless. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is an enthusiastic supporter of housing vouchers for the poor and allowing tenants to take over ownership of public housing. Both <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> support the home mortgage interest deduction. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> notes that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> built its 100 millionth home last year, and that housing starts were 25 percent higher in 1987 than in 1980. Builders have constructed 10 million homes in the past six years. But with the median price of new homes up to $ 112,400 in the second quarter of 1988, many young families find it increasingly difficult to climb onto the first rung of the housing ladder. `` Since this administration took office, the price of houses has raced ahead of people's wages and has made it impossible for many people to buy the homes they grew up in,'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> charged. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> cut deeply into the budget for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, which has fallen from $ 34 billion to $ 15 billion. The government, which used to help build or rehabilitate 200,000 units of housing for low and moderate income families each year, now backs just 25,000. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> promises to launch a National Partnership for Affordable Housing to spur construction of low and moderate income housing with federal grants and other support. A report last March by the <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> warned, `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is increasingly becoming a nation of housing haves and have-nots.'' `` Young households find purchasing a first home especially difficult. ... Unable to secure a home of their own, these persons remain renters and bid up the price of rental housing,'' the center said. `` The problem of first-time home buyers has gotten worse during the -LRB- past -RRB- eight years,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Driesler </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realtors </ORGANIZATION> senior vice president for government affairs. For people who already owned homes, `` the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years were very good.'' According to the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, the homeownership rate among households in the 24-29 age group fell from 43.3 percent in 1980 to 35.9 percent in 1987, while the rate fell from 61.1 to 53.2 percent for those in the 30-34 age group. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Builders </ORGANIZATION> says the 1986 overhaul of the nation's tax code stripped away many incentives to build apartments. Builders are starting only 385,000 multifamily units this year, down from 669,000 in 1985. `` The rent burden has become particularly onerous for young, single-parent families whose rents have increased from 34.9 percent of their incomes in 1974 to 58.4 percent in 1987,'' a report by the home builders says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Teen-ageParents     11-06 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Teen-age Parents,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Video Warns Students That Unwed Parents Must Pay Child Support</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY EYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>YAZOO CITY, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Long after they've paid for their stereo or first car, some <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> teen-agers could be making monthly payments they never anticipated _ child support. Faced with the highest percentage of teen-age pregnancies in the nation, the <ORGANIZATION> Mississippi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> wants youths to know they can be held financially responsible for illegitimate offspring. A new educational program, which will include a video presentation and a brochure, explains that if an unwed mother accepts welfare benefits, she must help locate her child's father. Once a court has ordered child support payments, the state can collect them to offset welfare costs. If the mother refuses, her portion of the family's welfare benefits will be cut. The program, geared for junior and senior high school students, is being explained personally by state Welfare Commissioner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> to school boards around the state. The schools can decide how to use the program. It points out the state's right to require men to submit to blood tests to legally establish paternity. `` We owe it to the taxpayers to have the young men begin to take responsibility as well,'' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said last week as he explained the program to school officials. Of all babies born in <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> during 1987, 20 percent, or 8,302, were born to teen-age mothers, said <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, director of reproductive health for the state <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Too many of those children end up on welfare rolls, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. `` We want to take a message out to young men as well as young women that there's a hard economic consequence to an unwed pregnancy,'' he said. `` That economic consequence is that if you participate in having someone become pregnant, then you're going to pay that child support payment until that child is 21 years of age.'' `` When we begin to diagram that out for students and show them what that means, they'll say back to us things like, ` Gee, I've got this part-time job and I need the money for paying for my stereo or I need the money for gasoline,' and we basically will be saying, ` Tough luck, that money first has to go for child-support payments,''' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. The welfare department has sought bids for the teen-age parenthood video, which should be ready for distribution to classrooms in January, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. The program also has a dollars-and-cents guide that extends into the students' adult lives, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. Students will be given a chart listing how much they can expect to earn in several occupations ranging from a minimum-wage job to corporate executive. The chart also tells them how much they could expect to pay in child support. For example, if a student someday becomes a janitor and makes $ 700 per month, then he can be required to pay $ 119 monthly, or $ 29,988 covering his child through age 21. <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> explained that the state can enforce child support collections by requiring an employer to withhold a portion of the parent's pay check, by intercepting state and federal tax refund checks, and by putting liens on real estate and personal property. Information regarding past-due child support will be distributed to credit reporting agencies for determining the parent's credit rating, <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Yazoo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> school board member <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> said he thought the new educational program could prevent some teen-age pregnancies. `` I think it would wake me up pretty quick,'' <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said the educational program is similar to those offered by welfare departments in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. He said the plan also was presented recently to the state's judges association, since the courts are responsible for setting child support payments Chancery Judge <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Rankin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> has volunteered to speak to students. `` I enforce it just like I do in a divorce case,'' the judge said of child support involving unwed parents. `` I would assume that all judges take the same position that I do. It's the law.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SealDeaths     11-06 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Seal Deaths,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Virus Killed Thousands of Seals, Researcher Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BERGEN, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A contagious virus that causes a respiratory infection and high fever was to blame for the deaths of thousands of seals in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> during the summer, a researcher said Sunday. <PERSON> Nina </PERSON> <PERSON> Hedlund </PERSON> <PERSON> Markussen </PERSON>, a biologist appointed by the <ORGANIZATION> Norwegian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> to study the seal deaths, said the epidemic appears to be over in Norwegian, <LOCATION> Danish </LOCATION> and Swedish waters but that some cases of seal death are still registered by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hedlund </PERSON> <PERSON> Markussen </PERSON> was quoted by the national <ORGANIZATION> NTB </ORGANIZATION> news agency as saying: `` Autopsies and analyses carried out at the <ORGANIZATION> Veterinary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> give no factual evidence that the illness symptoms causing the seal deaths have anything to do with pollution or distemper. A contagious virus appears to cause the symptoms and subsequent infection of the respiratory passage with coughing and fever up to 41 degrees Celsius -LRB- 102 F -RRB-.'' Researchers estimate that nearly 12,000 seals along the coasts of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> countries died during the summer because of the illness.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Burma-Fire     11-06 0079</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma-Fire,0080</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Razes Nearly 2,000 Houses</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RANGOON, Burma (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire that started in the kitchen of a home destroyed nearly 2,000 houses and a primary school in the southeastern city of <LOCATION> Mergui </LOCATION> on Sunday, but state radio said only one person was injured. A strong wind fanned the blaze, which raged for six hours before it was extinguished by the fire brigade and the military, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Mergui </LOCATION> is 350 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Fire     11-06 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Fire,0076</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blaze At Firecracker Store Kills 14 People</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A firecracker store caught fire in the east Indian city of <LOCATION> Patna </LOCATION> and 14 people burned to death, a news agency said Sunday. The fire, started by an electrical short circuit, caused an estimated $ 357,000 in damage to the store on Saturday night, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> said. The building was selling firecrackers for a Hindu festival on Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CentralAmerica-Diplomats     11-06 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Central America-Diplomats,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Envoys Face Risks in Isthmus</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Spelling of Dlouhy in 13th graf is cq.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is becoming one of the most inhospitable and risky areas for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats and military personnel. Nagging concerns over personal security, widespread anti-American sentiment and the career risk of having to defend highly controversial <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies plague <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials assigned in the region, particularly in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. As an example of the potential risk to career advancement, Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., an outspoken critic of administration policy in the region, recently blocked the promotion of two foreign service officers stationed there A country-by-country rundown of the difficulties facing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> personnel: <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ In October, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> sentries at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> exchanged gunfire on four occasions with unidentified intruders. Between February and October, there were 240 reported cases of harassment of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> servicemen in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>. In September, the administration decided to reduce the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic presence because of what one official called a `` potentially confrontational situation'' linked to continued U.S.-Panamanian hostility. The administration's decision not to have dealings with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s military-dominated government has produced a variety of problems for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats Some are forced to drive with expired licenses because the government wo n't renew them, while others rent cars rather than risk driving with expired plates. <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> _ Concern over personal security has heightened with stepped up leftist rebel activity in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, the capital. In late October, the offices of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> were struck by a projectile that cracked several windows and caused minor damage. In previous years, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has been the target of rebel attacks on several occasions but without serious incident. Diplomats posted in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> long have been security conscious, never taking the same route twice in a row when commuting. To avoid detection, one diplomat had his car repainted every few weeks. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ In July, <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Melton </PERSON> and seven other members of the embassy staff were expelled by the Sandinista government on grounds of interfering in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s internal affairs. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> has refused to allow the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to send replacement envoys to <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, placing an unusually heavy work load on the remaining skeleton staff. Their mission is complicated by an atmosphere of almost complete mistrust between the two governments. Several <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said the biggest concern of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomats posted in the region is not personal security but the possibility that their association with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s policies could damage their careers. <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> recently blocked the promotions of <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dlouhy </PERSON>, who is stationed in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and spent a brief period as head of the embassy. <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> complained that the two envoys impeded congressional attempts to exercise oversight of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy. His action underscored the continuing animosity between the administration and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> liberals over <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dlouhy </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> of `` McCarthyite tactics that would send a chilling message to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>.'' Said <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shankle </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the union of career diplomats: `` As a career officer you do put your career on the line in these highly charged situations. There are a lot of dangers involved.'' Despite the risks, there is no shortage of career diplomats willing to serve in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials say. One reason is that service in that region is a quick route to `` in-house'' promotions, the officials say, noting that congressional approval is required only for promotions involving the highest ranking officials. Still, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has been a career-threatening area for some time. When the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration assumed office eight years ago, numerous officials who had a hand in implementing President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s policy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> were either fired or sent to low-priority areas as punishment for perceived misjudgments. The most dramatic example was <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s last assistant secretary for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowdler </PERSON>, who shortly before <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first inaugural was summarily evicted from his office Shattered by the experience, he soon left the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and has lived in virtual seclusion with his wife in southern <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> ever since.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-StudentLoans     11-06 0503</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Student Loans,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Education Secretary Solicits Help In Curbing Loan Defaults</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> is seeking the advice of thousands of lenders, colleges and universities, and public officials on how to hold down the escalating default rate on student loans. The Education Department says taxpayers spent $ 1.5 billion to cover defaults on the guaranteed student loan program in the fiscal year that ended Sept. 30, almost 43 percent of the program's entire cost. The figure represents a 200 percent increase over the past five years in what is now known as the <LOCATION> Stafford </LOCATION> loan program, the department said. `` We want the advice of all parties _ the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the public, schools, lenders, guarantee agencies and borrowers,'' <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said in a statement. `` A lot has already been done, but clearly, additional action is necessary.'' The program has loaned about $ 40 billion since it began. Of the current $ 12 billion in outstanding loans, about $ 5 billion is overdue, the department said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON>, acting deputy undersecretary for planning, budget and evaluation, said <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> has sent letters appealing for advice to more than 7,000 participating colleges and universities, 13,000 lenders, 54 agencies that guarantee student loans, 50 governors, and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON>, who was president of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> until taking over as education secretary in September, is also accepting suggestions from students. He is especially concerned about those who defaulted on their loans because they were unable to earn a living after attending unscrupulous trade or other schools that award a certificate but do not provide necessary job skills. <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said some schools have 100 percent default rates, suggesting they may not be providing the kind of education necessary for students to hold a job and earn enough money to repay their loans. `` There are a lot of scams going on here,'' <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said. A school must be accredited to qualify students for guaranteed student loans, but <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said there are still `` fly by night operations'' that `` do n't give students a technical background _ just a paper certificate, no skills, and a debt. `` It's getting just unbelievable. Schools are recruiting right out of welfare lines. They get the students to get federally backed loans and the school gets the money and the kid gets the debt,'' <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said former Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> had proposed that schools that fail to get their default rate below 20 percent could be cut from the program. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> has extended the comment period on that proposal until the end of February. <PERSON> Kolb </PERSON> said of the 7,300 schools participating in the program, 30 percent have default rates above 20 percent. <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> also wants to know to what extent lenders, guarantee agencies and schools should share in the risk and cost of defaults; how communication can be improved among those participating; whether credit reports and co-signers should be required for borrowers with poor credit histories; and how consumer and personal financial counseling can be used most effectively.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WrongCapital     11-06 0183</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wrong Capital,0188</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cultural Literacy Dictionary: Jacksonville Capital Of Florida</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The author of `` Cultural Literacy: What Every American Needs To Know'' says he knows <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> is n't the capital of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ no matter what it says on page 382 of his sequel. But E.D. <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> said he did n't know <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s capital for 175 years, had been snubbed in `` The Dictionary of Cultural Literacy: What Every American Needs To Know. `` Do n't tell me that,'' he told the <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> Democrat in a telephone interview Friday. `` Tell <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Kett </PERSON> that. Let's let him have this conversation.'' <PERSON> Kett </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON>, both professors at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION>, are co-authors of the dictionary. <PERSON> Kett </PERSON> `` wo n't live that one down for a long time,'' <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> told the newspaper. `` You tell your readers you called me up and I knew the capital.'' On page 382 of the sequel to <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON>'s bestseller is this listing: `` <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Capital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, located in northeastern <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>.'' The book's chapter on American geography begins: `` Tests have revealed that many Americans are amazingly ignorant of the geography of their nation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica-Botha     11-06 0538</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa-Botha,0554</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Minister Has Shouting Match With Foreign Journalists</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG MYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a bitter shouting match with journalists, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Pik </PERSON> <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> described the foreign media as `` thieves and enemies'' who know `` absolutely nothing'' about <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> held the exchange with journalists during a hostile question-and-answer period that followed his speech at a Saturday night dinner banquet put on by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correspondents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Among other issues, questions touched on the closing of an anti-apartheid newspaper and on detentions of anti-apartheid activists. `` I am sick and tired of a lot of foreign representatives descending on my country and picking up on all the dirty work instead of all the beauty, promise and goodwill,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said after an argumentative exchange with one journalist. `` You do n't understand <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. You do n't understand African aspirations. You do n't understand African history,'' he said. The 400 people attending included foreign and local journalists and their guests, such as <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>. `` I accuse you of being superficial. I accuse you of glibly gliding over the African realities of which you know nothing, absolutely nothing,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> told the audience. After a prolonged exchange with one women, he said: `` I do n't want to quarrel with beautiful ladies I do better things with them.'' He wondered out loud whether one questioner had `` psychological problems.'' `` Will you just sit down and listen to a man who has traveled through <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> told another persistent questioner. `` Blacks do n't want a Westminster-style democracy,'' he said. `` Even if you could remove all the whites from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> tomorrow ... what you put here will not work.'' Asked about last week's government suspension of the anti-apartheid Weekly Mail newspaper, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said he supported the move. He described the newspaper as one of the most `` vicious'' he has seen in his travels around the world and said it contributed to `` more violence in this country.'' Asked why members of an extreme right-wing white group are not detained as frequently as anti-apartheid activists, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said: `` Do n't be stupid. It's not a question of arresting a few people and that's the end of it.'' `` There are whites in this country who can put together a more efficient violent organization than the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla movement -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> is the main group fighting <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s white-led government and its system of apartheid, under which the black majority has no voice in national affairs. At the end of the hour-long impromptu debate, the host offered to thank <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, but the foreign minister refused to accept. Instead he returned from his seat to the podium and quoted a speech by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kruger </PERSON>, a 19th century South African politician. `` -LRB- <PERSON> Kruger </PERSON>'s -RRB- opening words were, ` friends, citizens, thieves and enemies.' And that is how I look at you this evening,'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> said. The audience responded with boos, hisses and shouts of `` go home!'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> left shortly afterward, before dessert was served. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s media restrictions have been further tightened under the 29-month-old state of emergency. The emergency regulations prohibit reporting on security force actions, most forms of protest and a wide range of statements the government considers subversive. Enforcement has not been comprehensive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0032 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-AmmunitionFind     11-06 0121</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Ammunition Find,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amateur Diver Finds Crates Of Ammunition Off Sicilian Beach</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GELA, Sicily (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An amateur diver found more than 20 crates of ammunition in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gela </LOCATION> near the beach where allied troops invaded <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> in 1943, a news agency said Sunday. The diver found the crates in an unidentified wreck, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported. The diver opened one crate and found it full of `` military type ammunition.'' The navy will recover the other crates, which may include weapons, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said. Police believe the munitions were lost during the allied invasion in July 1943, but they have not ruled out the possibility the shipment was the result of illegal arms traffic along the southern Sicilian coast, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881106-0033 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-06-88 1247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-KidsPresident     11-06 0357</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Kids President,0367</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kids Offer Suggestions For Next President</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED WHITE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
