<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 2335EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Candidate-TWAFlap     10-02 0498</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Candidate-TWA Flap,0512</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Democrats Disavow Congressional Candidate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JULIA RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday disavowed a congressional candidate who it said failed to respond to allegations in a lawsuit that he distributed posters connecting an airline with AIDS. The executive committee of the state party voted 33-1 to deny <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> the use of the name Democrat in his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> campaign. `` The party needed to deal with this openly. Do n't flinch, do n't blush, just do business, and I think that's what we've done here,'' said state <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Buie </PERSON> <PERSON> Seawell </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Trans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> has accused <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of distributing anonymous posters with such messages as `` AIDS is Spread Through <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>'' and `` <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>: Travel With AIDS.'' According to <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>'s lawsuit, which seeks $ 500,000 in damages, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> sent a poster to the airline's <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> offices in July saying: `` Thousands of these have been sent around the country. Our staff is working on a new poster. They will continue to be sent until <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> corrects the hurt you have caused-cost me.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s squabble with <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> apparently began in 1983 when he took the airline to small claims court in two separate cases to recover `` frequent flyer'' benefits he felt he deserved. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> won one case and lost another. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> did not attend Sunday's meeting. State party leaders said he has not made himself available to talk with them about the matter since the lawsuit was filed Sept. 19 in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. The 53-year-old teacher and Realtor from <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> reportedly has denied the charges made by <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>. He did not respond to messages, including one Sunday night, left by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on his home phone answering machine. In his first foray into politics, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> was unopposed for the Democratic nomination to run against <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> Rep. <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON> in the heavily <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 5th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>, which encompasses <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>. The district <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> committee met first Sunday and issued a complaint saying <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s failure to respond to the controversy surrounding the lawsuit has hurt the campaigns of other <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidates in the district. `` I can verify that it is hurting my candidacy. People ask me, ` What craziness are you going to come up with?','' said <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, who is running against an incumbent Republican for a legislative seat in the district. The party's vote Sunday wo n't affect the ballot, which already has been printed. But the party said it would publish the disavowal in newspapers. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Daily </PERSON>, the party's attorney, stressed that the party was n't making a judgment on <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION>'s allegations against <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, but was moving against him only `` because of Mr. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s failure to act like a responsible candidate and step forward and deal with those issues. <PERSON> Seawell </PERSON> called <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> a `` walk-on candidate'' and said he was nominated `` with the best of intentions.'' `` He was a Realtor, an educator and seemed like a nice guy,'' the party chairman said. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> teaches communications at <ORGANIZATION> Pikes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Self-DefeatingCandidate     10-02 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Self-Defeating Candidate,0303</SECOND>
<HEAD>Candidate Late To Polls; Loses By One Vote</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN COOPERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Next time, <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> probably wo n't wait till the last minute to vote The Democratic candidate for the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Governor's <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> arrived too late at the polls, and lost the election by one vote. A recount last week showed that <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> lost the Democratic nomination in the Sept. 15 election. The recount showed <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON> with 14,715 votes. His opponent got 14,716. The 67-year-old car dealer said he had been campaigning on election day, `` and I waited until the last minute to race over'' to vote. The result `` gives new meaning to the phrase ` one-man, one-vote,''' said <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>, a member of the council since 1969, is protesting the election, claiming that some ballots are missing and others are invalid. The eight-member Governor's Council, which dates from the Colonial era, lost many of its powers in the 1960s. Its chief remaining duties are to approve criminal pardons and confirm judges nominated by the governor. <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> said he would go to court today to request that the primary be invalidated and a special election be held to decide the nomination. The lawyer also suggested the close vote might have had something to do with the last name of <PERSON> Connolly </PERSON>'s opponent, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. Also on the ballot were Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, both D-Mass. Although <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> Councilor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> is not a member of the famous <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> political clan, <PERSON> Galvin </PERSON> said, he may have benefited from uncertainty on that point. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> opposes another election. `` All another election would do at this point would be to give my opponent an opportunity to vote,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Shuttle-Student     10-02 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle-Student,1st Ld-Writethru, a0610,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Astronaut Assures Worried Teen-Ager America is `Back on Track'</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS last graf to update with quote from youth.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Discovery commander <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> interrupted the crew's schedule on Saturday to read aloud a letter from a student who wrote that `` some of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future is riding on you and your crew's shoulders.'' <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> said he had received the brief letter within the last year and a half from <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. `` P.J.'' <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, and had talked to the boy by telephone just before Thursday's launch of the first shuttle since the Challenger disaster 32 months ago. `` Dear Mr. <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON>, I'm a worried 14-year-old that is worried about the future,'' the letter said. `` I feel that some of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s future is riding on you and your crew's shoulders. I give you all the inspiration I can give you because your ride this fall means so much to me.'' <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> said he thought it was `` a particularly good letter and really sent home to us how much the experiences we have here in space can have an effect on the youngsters of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' He said <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who graduated from <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mark </ORGANIZATION>'s parochial school in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> and now attends high school, `` had some concerns about the future of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and whether we were still capable of doing the things that make us a great country.'' <PERSON> Hauck </PERSON> thanked the boy for the letter and said he hoped `` all the other youngsters out there not only in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> but in other parts of the world that may be watching and can see that we are back on track and we have a lot of technological benefits that will come in the future.'' The commander read the letter just after astronaut <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lounge </PERSON> had finished conducting a scientific experiment that was designed by a high school student. Appearing later on the CBS evening news program, young <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> said, `` I just meant to ... like, uplift the space program.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-WorldReax     10-02 0417</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-World Reax,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan Hopes For Better Ties, Others Send Congratulations</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Kremlin Shake-up, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS GINSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> expressed hope for improved relations and <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> European nations offered effusive congratulations on Saturday after sweeping changes in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> leadership left <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> holding the nation's top two jobs. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, already the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> general secretary, took over the goverment presidency Saturday from <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gromyko </PERSON>, who retired after a 50-year career that started under <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has proposed expanding the powers of the largely ceremonial presidency, along with slashing the massive party apparatus. In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said they hoped the shakeup will produce a new Soviet policy toward <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. The countries have never formally resolved their World War II antagonism because of competing claims on a group of islands in the Kurile chain that Soviet troops have occupied since the closing days of the war. There was no immediate response from <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> officials. East European leaders were quick to shower <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> with congratulatory telegrams Saturday. Notes were sent from Hungarian Communist leader <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Straub </PERSON>, Czechoslovak President <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON>, Polish leader <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> Romanian </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, who is scheduled to meet with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> next week in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. `` This is a meaningful expression of the Soviet nation's esteem for your services as a precursor, creator and unremitting executor of the policy of perestroika - openness, democratization and new thinking,'' <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s message said, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> PAP </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. Italian Premier <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON> congratulated <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and said he `` will be able to give a renewed and accentuated push to the work of stabilization and reinforcement of international relations which you have already undertaken with such effectiveness.'' Indian President <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Venkataraman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s `` outstanding personal contribution'' to the world peace and disarmament created a new climate in international relations Austrian newspapers Saturday said the changes signal a strengthening of the <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> camp. `` Successful -LRB- and -RRB- surprising coup of the Kremlin Chief: <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> removes all opponents of his reform policy,'' was the headline in the independent Kurier, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s second largest daily in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said on Friday the shake-up was difficult to assess immediately. But he added: `` Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is a very strong and determined person. He has a major reform program that he is working on. And if there is any message from this it is that he intends to pursue that program.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Papandreou     10-02 0217</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Papandreou,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Greek Prime Minister Reported Doing Well After Heart Surgery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HAREFIELD, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> was disconnected from his respirator and progressing well Saturday after open-heart surgery, officials said. The 69-year-old premier, who underwent delicate surgery Friday to replace a damaged heart valve, ordered a steak but was denied it, a <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said. `` Doctors said it was too soon _ he can not eat solids like that yet. He did have soup though, and some ice cream,'' said the spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity. One of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s leading heart surgeons, Egyptian-born <PERSON> Magdi </PERSON> <PERSON> Yacoub </PERSON>, carried out the surgery at <LOCATION> Harefield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, 17 miles north of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Yacoub </PERSON> issued a statement Saturday saying <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> was progressing satisfactorily. Later in the day, the embassy spokesman said: `` Mr. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> has already been disconnected from the respiratory machine and is sitting up in bed. It seems that he has passed the critical hours after the operation and avoided any complications.'' <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> had a glass of orange juice in the morning, waved to his bodyguards and asked about the weather, which was cool but sunny, said government spokesman <PERSON> Telemachos </PERSON> <PERSON> Chytiris </PERSON>. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> was first elected in October 1981 when his <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> won a landslide victoy. He won a second term in June 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BrushFires 1stLd-Writethru a0630 10-02 0468</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brush Fires, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0630,0479</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Calif Fires On Wane After Threatening Homes</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 4th, `Fire officials...' to UPDATE with
near containment and damage estimate, picks up 5th graf pvs, `The
fire...'.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>DIAMOND BAR, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Firefighters had all but doused a fire that once threatened 30 luxury homes, thanks to a favorable wind shift and residents who had already cleared away dry brush, officials said Saturday. `` The Diamond Bar fire is fully under control and we've returned all our units to <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION>,'' <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> firefighter <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Westbuy </PERSON> said early Saturday. He said a few local firefighters remained, putting out the blaze's remaining hot spots. Elsewhere, <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> officials reported they were gaining the upper hand against a brush fire 25 miles away in the <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cucamonga </LOCATION> area that had burned 10,665 acres and destroyed one house since it was ignited Wednesday. Fire officials said that blaze was a result of arson, one of 30 set recently in the <LOCATION> Lytle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, about 55 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. It was declared 75 percent contained Saturday, and officials estimated it damaged property worth about $ 375,000. The fire at <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION>, which burned 300 acres, came within a few yards of 30 expensive ridgeline homes in the Tonner Canyon area, forcing the evacuation of about 120 residents. All had been allowed to return Saturday. Authorities said the blaze, which started Friday, was of suspicious origin. `` It was a matter of expert firefighting and the wind shifting in our favor, `` <PERSON> Westbuy </PERSON> said. `` We got a big break from the wind.'' He said firefighters were also aided by residents who had adhered to an aggressive program mandated by the Fire Department to clear dry brush from around homes each year. Approximately 120 firefighters battled the blaze in 90-degree weather Friday. <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Peralez </PERSON>, who was riding a horse in Tonner Canyon when the fire broke out, said it turned into an inferno in a matter of seconds. `` Within 60 seconds, the brush and trees just went up,'' she said. `` I looked over my shoulder, and there was a big wall of flames.'' County Battalion Chief <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON> said the fire, in an area about 30 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, was being investigated. In <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cucamonga </LOCATION>, about 55 miles east of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, 1,155 firefighters battled the so-called <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> fire, which started Wednesday, said <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Spann </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION>. The fire destroyed one home earlier in the week, but no houses were threatened Saturday and the blaze was 75 percent contained, <PERSON> Spann </PERSON> said. High temperatures and erratic wind that gusted up to 60 mph early in the week made fighting the blaze difficult, but the weather had eased by Saturday, <PERSON> Spann </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0041EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Germany-ElvisStatue     10-02 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-Elvis Statue,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Statue of Elvis Presley Commemorates His Arrival 30 Years Ago</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BREMERHAVEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A life-sized bronze statue of <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> was unloaded in <LOCATION> Bremerhaven </LOCATION> port Saturday, exactly 30 years after the real-life rock' n'roll idol came down the gangplank here as a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> soldier. The statue, brought from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to commemorate Presely's arrival Oct. 1, 1958, was hoisted off the ship Helgoland by a crane as performer <PERSON> Dirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Juettner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> sang Presley hits including `` Wooden Heart,'' and `` Love Me Tender.'' While <PERSON> Juettner </PERSON> imitated Presley's hip-jerking style, a crowd of about 300 gathered to watch the ceremony, which included a rock' n'roll dance group performance on the dock in this northern port city. After the arrival ceremony, the statue was taken by a convoy of vehicles with organizers and fans to <LOCATION> Bad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Neuheim </LOCATION> 225 miles south, where it was to remain on display for 24 hours. Presley lived in <LOCATION> Bad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Neuheim </LOCATION> during his 17 months as a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldier in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The statue was sent to <LOCATION> Bremerhaven </LOCATION> for the commemoration by the <ORGANIZATION> Elvis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, where it was to be returned after a one-day stay in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the center said in a statement released to the news media. <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> was born Jan. 8, 1935 in <LOCATION> Tupelo </LOCATION>, Miss. He was 42 when he died in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, on Aug. 16, 1977.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PTLCreditors     10-02 0188</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PTL Creditors,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fairfax S&amp;L Wants to Foreclose on PTL Property</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fairfax Savings and Loan of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> is seeking court permission to foreclose on <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>'s hotel, retail mall and water park after <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> missed its Sept. 10 loan payment. <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> did not ask for an extension of the payment deadline so <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> should be allowed to `` take immediate possession of all rents, profits and revenues,'' attorneys said in documents filed last week in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Bankruptcy Court. <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> loaned founder <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> money to build many <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> attractions during <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s years of rapid growth. Its claim against <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> totals $ 12.2 million. Calls to the offices of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> attorneys were not answered. The <LOCATION> Fairfax </LOCATION> foreclosure request is scheduled for hearing on Oct. 17. A federal judge handling <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s bankruptcy case has given the ministry until Oct. 14 to find a buyer for its properties or face the prospect of liquidation. <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> filed for protection from its creditors under Chapter 11 of bankruptcy court rules in June 1987, three months after <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> admitted having a sexual encounter with church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and resigned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Peru-Inflation     10-02 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Peru-Inflation,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peru Price Rise Highest Ever, Economic Analysts Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Consumer prices rose 117.9 percent during September, a respected economics analysis firm said Saturday. It is by far the largest monthly inflation increase in Peruvian history. The dramatic rise pushed inflation from January through September to 754 percent, according to the report by <PERSON> Apoyo </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> said its inflation figures, which were due for release Friday, had been delayed until early this week. Apoyo's figures, which have in the past reflected the government's official report, showed the categories of books, transportation and food had the highest price gains during September, registering 180 percent, 177 percent and 120 percent, respectively. According to government figures, the highest single month price rise since figures were kept in 1922 previously occurred in July, registering 30.9 percent. The previous highest yearly mark was 158.3 percent set in 1985. The sharp cost of living increase was anticipated after the government early in September devalued currency 86 percent and allowed prices for food, gasoline and other goods to rise as high as 200 percent in an effort to control runaway inflation, which is still expected to reach 900 percent this year. The government said the austerity plan, aimed at eliminating costly government subsidies, will begin to show results this month and cut inflation to near zero by early next year. Independent analysts said the chief causes of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s record inflation are a government deficit estimated at more than 12 percent of the gross national product, dwindling production coupled with hot consumer demand, and a widening trade imbalance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-LouisianaPrimary 5thLd-Writethru a0721 10-02 0876</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Louisiana Primary, 5th Ld - Writethru, a0721,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Incumbents Claim Victories; Holloway Faces Runoff</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Subs 13th graf, `McCrery won ...' and 18th graf, `In the ...'
to UPDATE with vote totals.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ALAN SAYRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> swept to an easy victory in his re-election bid against Gov. <PERSON> Buddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s mother in Saturday's primary, but Rep. <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> was forced into a repeat of his 1986 runoff. <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON>, who defeated attorney <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> in a runoff two years ago, will face her again Nov. 8. Democratic Reps. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON> joined <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> in claiming victories without runoffs. Under <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s open primary system, all candidates run in the same primary, regardless of party affiliation. If no candidate in a race wins a majority, the top two contenders meet in a runoff. With all the votes counted, <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON>, the 8th District's <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> incumbent, had 58,479 votes or 44 percent to 44,904 or 34 percent for <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a Democrat. Other Democratic challengers, state Sen. J.E. <PERSON> Jumonville </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>, former Lt. Gov. <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> and former <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> `` Tillie'' <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> trailed far behind. <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> said he felt great about the results and said he would `` run on our record'' in the runoff. `` There's no way to go but up from here,'' he said. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said she expected to receive the support of the other Democrats in the race. `` They've -LRB- Democrats -RRB- won over the years on the strength of the black vote,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said, who is black. `` I'll have the support of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> because I'm the only Democrat now in the race. The party has targeted this as the No. 1 race they want to take from the Republicans.'' In the 4th District, <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, a Republican elected last spring to fill the remainder of <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>'s unexpired term in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, claimed victory over two Democratic opponents, including <PERSON> Adeline </PERSON> <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>, the governor's mother. After seeing that she was being swamped in the returns, Mrs. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said, `` I have been heard in this campaign. This just might make our present congressman a better one.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said there was a lot of apathy in the campaign and `` I'm disappointed more people did n't exercise their right to vote. It was a low turnout.'' <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> visited with his mother while the voters were being counted. `` I just came for a little while to hug my mom and tell her how proud I am of her,'' he said. <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON> won with 72,128 votes or 69 percent to 27,829 or 27 percent for Mrs. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON>, a retired military officer, had 5,103 votes or 5 percent. With all of the vote counted, <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, tallied 72,010 votes or 89 percent to 8,601 or 11 percent, for <PERSON> Millard </PERSON> <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, a fellow Democrat and a distant cousin by marriage. <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON> has represented the 3rd District since 1981. <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON> overwhelmed Democrat <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomason </PERSON> <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> in his race for a seventh term in the 5th District. <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON> had 50,991 votes or 71 percent, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had 14,321 or 20 percent and <PERSON> Roark </PERSON> tallied 6,396 votes or 9 percent. In the 1st District, <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON> won handily over two <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> opponents _ <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Honig </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mustakas </PERSON> _ in his bid to keep the seat he has held since 1977. <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON> had 67,374 votes or 78 percent to 13,046 or 15 percent for Mustakas and 5,433 or 6 percent for <PERSON> Honig </PERSON>. In the 2nd District, <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> had 63,327 votes or 90 percent, while Republican opponent <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> `` Captain'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> had 7,665 votes or 10 percent. <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> had held the seat since winning a special election in 1973 to replace her husband, <PERSON> Hale </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, who was lost in a plane crash in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republican <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> of the 6th District and Democrat <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> of the 7th District, both freshmen, were unopposed. A national magazine, `` Campaigns and Elections,'' listed <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> as holding one of the `` seven most vulnerable Republican seats'' and called his 1986 victory a fluke. His four challengers contended that the district's representative should be more sensitive to the region's high unemployment rate He was criticized during the campaign for his record, including votes against a federal catastrophic health care bill and funding for the Red River Waterway project. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, who garnered an endorsement from the Rev. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and appealed for multiracial support, predicted she would win the race without a runoff. <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON>, who lost a bid for a third term as lieutenant governor last fall, and <PERSON> Jumonville </PERSON>, a state senator since 1975, both stressed their experience in government. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, who left office in 1986 after deciding not to seek re-election, stirred controversy several years ago when he called a black city councilman a chimpanzee. Mrs. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> said she decided to enter the 4th District race because she was disappointed with <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>'s brief performance in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, a former congressional aide to <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> who garnered the governor's support in his initial race, defeated state Sen. <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> in a runoff last April. <PERSON> Roemer </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Patti </PERSON>, appeared at a $ 1,000-per couple fund-raiser for his mother, while <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>'s major fund-raiser included an appearance by former Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, a major figure in the Iran-Contra investigation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Yugoslavia-Inflation     10-02 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Yugoslavia-Inflation,0297</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inflation Tops 200 Percent For First Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Annual inflation in this crisis-ridden communist nation topped 200 percent for the first time last month, the federal statistics bureau announced Saturday. September inflation was 217 percent over the same month last year, with a 15.4 percent increase over August, the bureau said. Meanwhile, the Yugoslav government, in an effort to contain runaway inflation and growing labor unrest, demanded cancellation of planned sharp price hikes of electricity, rents, rail and postal services, press reported Saturday. The last minute government appeal came after the state-run electrical company announced a 31 percent price hike of electricity, due to take effect Saturday. Also as of Oct. 1, postal services in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> were to go up by 10.5 percent, rents by 36 percent, and rail transport by 36.7 percent for passengers and 46.7 for cargo. The government communique, published in the official press, said such sharp price hikes `` are unjustified at the time of the country's very difficult social and economic situation.'' The price increases would boost the country's rampant inflation and lead to a further drop in living standards of Yugoslavs, the government said, adding that the companies should reconsider the planned hikes by Oct. 4. The statistics bureau said that since December of last year, inflation measured 129.5 percent. Prices of electricity, rail transport and postal services already were considerably boosted in July. Workers have staged several protest marches in <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> following the introduction in May of a government austerity program which allowed substantial price hikes and hefty wage cuts. The steps are designed eventually to curb <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s highest inflation rate and repay <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>'s $ 21 billion foreign debt by introducing a more market-oriented economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua-Devaluation     10-02 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Devaluation,0310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nicaragua Again Devalues Currency, Raises Gas Prices</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODOLFO GARCIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government cut the value of its currency by 77 percent and nearly doubled the price of gasoline Saturday in another round of measures aimed at shoring up the battered economy. The official exchange rate for the national currency, the cordoba, went from 180 to the dollar to 320 to the dollar and gasoline rose from the equivalent of $ 1.02 a gallon to $ 2.03 a gallon. The leftist government also said state workers will immediately get a 35-percent raise. Planning Minister <PERSON> Alejandro </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuenca </PERSON> said the devaluation is designed to `` establish a realistic relationship between prices in the domestic and international markets,'' according to the official newspaper of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> party, <PERSON> Barricada </PERSON>. The government blames the 8-year-old war with the U.S.-backed rebels, known as Contras, for its economic woes which include rampant inflation, serious shortages of food, fuel and other basics and a shrinking economy. It was the fourth round of adjustments this year. In the previous round a month ago, gas prices rose from the equivalent of 46 cents a gallon to $ 1.02. The cordoba went from 80 to the dollar to 180. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> described the economic steps last month as a matter of `` survival'' until <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> is at peace. In the government-controlled exchange market restricted to a handful of transactions such as those involving medical supplies, the cordoba now trades at 485 to the dollar. The Sandinista government began making economic adjustments in February, when inflation was said officially to be at 1,300 percent. The new currency, then valued at 10 to the dollar, was issued. A series of devaluations and gasoline price hikes have followed. In June, many wage and price controls were lifted.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Quayle-Arms     10-02 0306</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle-Arms,0315</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Expresses Difference with Bush Over Arms Talks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should make completion of a treaty on long-range nuclear weapons conditional on Soviet concessions on conventional arms, a position that differs from that of Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. In an interview reported in the newspaper's Sunday editions, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he was worried the Soviets would not negotiate seriously on cutting conventional weapons if the two superpowers reach a prior agreement in their strategic arms reduction talks. `` If we negotiate on START, what leverage do we have on conventional,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told the Times. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has rejected the idea of linking talks on strategic nuclear arms with talks on conventional arms, saying it would delay completion of a strategic arms treaty. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign has endorsed that position. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said in the interview he would follow administration policy if he became vice president. `` The view of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign is that we are going to proceed with START, and we want to talk about conventional arms control,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` But there has not been the linkage that I discussed.'' If <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is elected President, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said top officials `` will sit down and discuss what the strategy is going to be'' on nuclear and conventional arms issues. `` And the strategy, as far as the connecting of these, you've got to wait until you get into the administration for some of those very important subtle issues. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, had not previously revealed these positions in the campaign, the Times said. Democratic presidential candidate <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and running mate Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> have said they would try to complete a strategic nuclear arms treaty as soon as possible without injecting new demands in the talks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0140EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--PrisonProtest     10-02 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Prison Protest,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmate Protesters Removed from Yard at Oregon Prison</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALEM, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-eight inmates were removed from a yard at the <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> Women's Correctional Center Saturday after staging a two-hour sit-in to protest overcrowding and other conditions. `` There was no violence, none whatsoever,'' said prison spokesman <PERSON> Robey </PERSON> <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON>. However, some of the protesters were physically removed from the yard, he said. There were no injuries, but one woman with a history of medical problems was taken to <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> for evaluation, said <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON>. The protesters were taken to prison cells and will be segregated from the main prison population pending a disciplinary hearing within one week, <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> said. No criminal charges were anticipated, he added. The other 114 inmates were locked in their cells. <PERSON> Eldridge </PERSON> said the prison was looking for ways to reduce overcrowding. The facility currently houses 142 prisoners in space built for 80. The protesters also complained of inadequate health care, unsanitary conditions and insufficient educational programs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-FairScare     10-02 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Fair Scare,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>45 Trapped In Bloomsburg Fair Ride</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID MORRIS</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Associated Press Writer</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BLOOMSBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 45 people were trapped upside down and had to be removed by aerial ladder after the Super Loops ride at the <ORGANIZATION> Bloomsburg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> became stuck in the middle of a loop Saturday night, authorities said. At least 12 people were taken to hospitals with minor injuries, authorities said. The ride uses cars that run on tracks and have wire cages over their tops and open sides. <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Vangroski </PERSON> of <PERSON> Hazleton </PERSON>, who was at the fair with friends and relatives, said the riders were stuck about 40 feet in the air for up to an hour and a half before emergency workers freed everyone. `` They were up there upside down, waving their arms, just hanging there,'' he said. `` They started to panic a little bit. Being upside down for that period of time is scary.'' At <ORGANIZATION> Geisinger </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Danville </LOCATION>, seven people were being treated mainly for breathing problems, dizziness and other conditions associated with hanging upside down for a prolonged period, nursing supervisor <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. No one was seriously injured, she said. Five others were treated for minor injuries and released from two other hospitals, officials said. A state police spokesman said about 100,000 attended the fair Saturday, the last night of the agricultural exhibition and carnival.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Hirohito     10-02 0423</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Hirohito,0434</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japanese Emperor Receives Another Transfusion; Blood Pressure
Increases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> received another transfusion Sunday, as his internal bleeding continued and his blood pressure rose to equal its highest reading since his condition deteriorated two weeks ago. But palace officials said the 87-year-old monarch stabilized after a crisis Saturday, when he suddenly discharged a large amount of blood and his blood pressure dropped precariously for about 30 minutes. The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which handles the imperial family's affairs, said the emperor was given a 0.4-pint transfusion Sunday morning. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> discharged a small amount of blood from his bowels twice, it said. The transfusion brought to 10.2 pints the total amount of blood he received since internal hemorrhaging caused him to vomit blood Sept. 19. That amount is considerably larger than the total volume normally in the emperor's body, news reports said. Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and Crown Princess <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> visited the emperor and exchanged words for a short time Sunday morning, along with <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s grandson, <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, who was summoned back from studies in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Two other op nirograndchildren visited later, <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Kenji </PERSON> <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said. At midafternoon, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s temperature was 99 degrees, compared with his normal reading of about 95.9, <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said. His blood pressure was 168 over 76, matching the highest reported level since his condition worsened. Sunday morning it had been 135 over 70, the imperial agency said. The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the emperor's normal pressure was not immediately available, but a typical normal reading is about 120 over 80. High blood pressure can pose a strain on the heart and worsen internal bleeding. <PERSON> Maeda </PERSON> said it was unclear how much blood the emperor lost Saturday, but news reports said it could have been as much as 2.1 pints. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s vital signs stabilized later Saturday after he was given two emergency transfusions totaling 1.7 pints. Doctors have expressed concern that the volume of transfusions needed to compensate for <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s internal bleeding may have side effects. They said he is losing strength because intraveneous feeding alone can not supply enough nutrients, and he reportedly also is suffering from jaundice. Other than five or six spoonfuls of porridge Saturday morning and two small fragments of ice more than a week ago, the emperor has been unable to eat or drink since the onset of the crisis. News reports have said <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> is suffering from cancer of the upper intestine, but imperial officials have not confirmed or denied the reports.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0502EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Germany-StraussIll     10-02 0355</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Germany-Strauss Ill,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT
^Influential Bavarian Governor Fighting for Life after Collapsing
Day Before</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MUNICH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bavarian Governor <PERSON> Franz-Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, the country's leading ultra-conservative, was fighting for his life Sunday after collapsing the day before from a heart attack, officials said. `` His situation is serious,'' according to a state government statement released to the news media early Sunday. `` He is not out of life-threatening danger.'' <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>, 73, is head of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, the Bavarian sister party of the nationally dominant <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>. He was hospitalized in the Bavarian city of <LOCATION> Regensburg </LOCATION> after suffering a possible stomach rupture in addition to a heart attack that at first was suspected to be slight, the state governor's office said State spokesman <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwaabe </PERSON> said <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> was stricken Saturday afternoon while on a hunting trip in the <LOCATION> Regensburg </LOCATION> area of <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION>, about 65 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Schwaabe </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview from his office in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> was conscious and his condition had stabilized by late Saturday evening. Doctors were planning to operate to correct <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON>' condition, <PERSON> Schwaabe </PERSON> said. However, the statement issued early Sunday superseded the earlier statements, indicating <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> had taken a turn for the worse. The outspoken <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> often has been at the center of national policy-making and has used international travels to wield influence over foreign policy as well. His thick Bavarian accent coupled with stinging comments also makes the outspoken, corpulent state governor <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s most colorful politician. From 1966 to 1969, <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> served as finance minister under then-Chancellor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiesinger </PERSON> in the so-called `` Great Coalition'' of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s conservative parties with the left-leaning Social Democrats. After the Social Democrats took over the government in coalition with the centrist, business-oriented <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1969, <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> remained as a member of the federal parliament's conservative opposition until 1978, when he was elected Governor of <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION> Two years later he was nominated to run for chancellor but lost the election against Social Democrat <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmidt </PERSON> in 1980. He kept his post as Bavarian state governor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 0925EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-CoffeeAgreement 1stLd-Writethru a0733 10-02 0280</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Coffee Agreement, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0733,0371</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Quotas Aim To Stabilize Prices, Improve Availability</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Leads with 8 grafs to ADD background on agreement. Pickup 7th
graf pvs `The basis...'</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By ROBIN STAINER</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Coffee-producing and consuming nations belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> agreed Sunday on new producers' export quotas aimed at stabilizing prices and improving availability of choice grades. The final negotiations were difficult, but the result was a `` good one,'' said <PERSON> Jorio </PERSON> <PERSON> Dauster </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s negotiating team. `` It was a positive outcome,'' said chief American delegate <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenbaum </PERSON>. Delegates said the new deal is very complicated but is primarily designed to keep the average price of coffee _ currently $ 1.14 a pound _ above $ 1.15 dollars and below $ 1.45 in the 1988-89 marketing year which began Saturday. It calls for a global export quota _ the organization's means of price-control _ of 56 million bags for 1988-89. One bag equals 132 pounds. The group also agreed to ensure that consuming nations can obtain the sort of coffee they want, mainly the popular Latin American arabica grade. Under the old agreement, all cuts or increases in the global export quota were applied equally to all types of coffee. The new agreement favors the arabicas. Such a system would likely reduce market share for African robusta producers, delegates said. The basis for the 74-member group's final agreement was hammered out late Saturday at a meeting between top negotiators from <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the world's biggest producers and consumers, delegates said. The talks had been bogged down over the system for adjusting quotas in relation to the movement in world prices.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-RunningMates Bjt   10-02 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Running Mates, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experts Say Top of Ticket, Not Running Mates, Sways Voters' Choice</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats who hope Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> will help the ticket win his home state of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and perhaps the presidential election could do well to regard the fate of <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gassaway </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. In case anyone does n't remember, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was Democrat <PERSON> Alton </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s running mate when <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> ran for president against <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teddy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roosevelt </ORGANIZATION> in 1904. The voters chose between <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, and their choice was <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> by a 3-2 margin. Experts concede that the vice presidential debate in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, on Wednesday between <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> and Republican <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> may make a difference, but they say the voters' final decision will come down to a choice between the top of the tickets, Democrat <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` Unless <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is absolutely destroyed in the debate with <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, I do n't think it will hurt <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ribuffo </PERSON>, a specialist in political history at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` People will be looking for <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to blow it,'' said <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kernell </PERSON>, professor of political science at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. `` If he can get through the debate in a competent fashion where he looks unexceptional, it will be a real success for him.'' <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a Republican political consultant, said, `` I think it is reasonable to suggest that <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would have won <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> -LRB- <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s home state -RRB- without Mr. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, and with Mr. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> is still not going to carry <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. So you wash that out.'' `` I think the odds are that <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> will have little or no effect on the ultimate choice,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, program director for governmental studies at the Brookings Institution here. <PERSON> Elspeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON>, a political scholar at the <ORGANIZATION> Lyndon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> B. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Johnson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s choice of <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> `` does n't seem to have too much effect on the voters, at least so far.'' `` I do n't think, if indeed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was disposed to choose <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> to appeal to women, that so far it has had that effect,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON> said. `` I think the conventional wisdom that the selection of a running mate is rarely decisive one way or another is absolutely true,'' said <PERSON> Ribuffo </PERSON>. A survey conducted this year by the <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> supports this view. Eighteen percent of the 1,001 voters surveyed said they had changed their minds about a presidential candidate at one time or another because of their opinion of his running mate. Of those, 70 percent said they voted against that ticket. Political experts agree that if a running mate has any effect, he is more likely to hurt than help. Examples cited include President <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>'s selection of Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, who was criticized for his slashing debating style in 1976, and <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>'s choice of <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON>, who suffered from examination of her family's finances in 1984. `` Clearly in my opinion <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> in 1976 in that debate -LRB- with <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s running mate -RRB- cost <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> votes,'' <PERSON> Mahe </PERSON> said. `` Clearly in 1984 in my opinion, <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferraro </PERSON> cost <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> votes probably.'' In <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s unsuccessful campaign of 1960, some thought that <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabot </PERSON> <PERSON> Lodge </PERSON> hurt the ticket's chances by pledging that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> would appoint a black to the Cabinet _ a statement <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> disavowed. Lodge, a former ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, also was criticized for taking naps and not campaigning hard enough. `` Some have thought that if he had used his prestige from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> more effectively, <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> might have edged out <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON> said. There are exceptions to the rule that running mates do n't help much, the experts said. While there is disagreement over whether <ORGANIZATION> Lodge </ORGANIZATION> hurt <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in 1960, almost everybody agrees that <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> helped <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> by enabling him to carry <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` I do n't think <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> would have won without <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Ribuffo </PERSON> said. Also, <PERSON> Ribuffo </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Mondale </PERSON> may have helped <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> win election in 1976 by imparting legitimacy to the former <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> governor in the eyes of skeptical liberals. Then there was the running mate that Republicans chose in 1900 to help the colorless <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> win a second term against the dynamic Democrat, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>. The ticket of <PERSON> McKinley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Roosevelt </PERSON> became known as `` the kangaroo ticket because it had a kick in the tail,'' Ms. <PERSON> Rostow </PERSON> said. There have n't been many tickets in any other year, including 1988, with that much of a kick in the tail, the experts agree.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Shuttle-Landing Bjt   10-02 0892</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle-Landing, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shuttle Launch Fraught With Tension, But Landing Also Risky</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE SIEGEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EDWARDS AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Challenger tragedy highlighted the danger of space shuttle launches, but astronauts also face risks when their orbiter rips through Earth's atmosphere and plunges toward landing `` like a streamlined brick,'' experts say. `` The landing is not as dramatic and exciting as the launch and does n't involve extremely powerful rockets, but there's no question landing is a very critical operation and requires a great deal of attention,'' said <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON>, president of a <LOCATION> Newport </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> engineering consulting firm. Discovery is to conclude its four-day mission with a landing here Monday morning at 9:33 a.m. PDT. It will swoop across <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s coast at 4.37 times the speed of sound, slow to subsonic speeds, then drop at a steep angle before leveling out without any power and glide toward touchdown on the unpaved surface of <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION>. `` It comes down like a streamlined brick,'' said <PERSON> Milt </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, chief engineer for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Dryden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Facility </ORGANIZATION> at this <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> military base, where 18 of 24 previous shuttle missions landed. Five flights landed at <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and one at White Sands Missile Range, <PERSON> N.M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said that while shuttle landings are less dangerous than launches, `` there is still an element of risk on whether or not you make this landing properly because a lot of it does rely on the pilot's judgment and you are approaching the ground at an extremely high rate of descent.'' The Jan. 28, 1986, explosion that destroyed Challenger and killed seven crew members 73 seconds after liftoff from <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> prompted redesign of faulty shuttle booster rockets and many other changes, including installation of an emergency escape system so astronauts can bail out while approaching the landing site. The braking and steering systems also were modified in hope of avoiding the brake and tire damage that had occurred during earlier landings. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said the changes were meant to eliminate mechanical and heat-caused brake damage, improve steering to provide better control in crosswinds or if tires blow out, and prevent bending of main landing gear axles caused by brake overheating. At the urging of astronauts and the <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which investigated the Challenger disaster, shuttles will land here for the foreseeable future, frustrating <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s initial plans to save time and money by landing the spacecraft regularly back at the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canaveral </LOCATION> launch site. The 44-square-mile dry lakebed at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> leaves plenty of room for safety if brakes fail or tires blow, while a similar mishap at the Cape could put the shuttle in the water. One of the first dangers associated with landing is the possibility that the shuttle could burn up in the atmosphere after the pilot turns the shuttle upside-down and backwards, fires small rockets in what is called the `` deorbit burn'' an hour before landing, then flips the shuttle forward again for re-entry. Onboard computers help keep the shuttle at the proper angle for re-entry, and <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> also modified Discovery's thermal tiles and blankets to improve its ability to withstand heat. `` I'm always a little concerned until he gets into the atmosphere,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> research projects office at Edwards. Years before shuttles flew, <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials built Mercury, Gemini and Apollo capsules that parachuted to ocean splashdowns. They doubted a spacecraft could be built to land on Earth like an unpowered airplane. But they wanted a reusable space shuttle. Plane-like shuttle landings were made possible by years of experimental flights with X-series aircraft, wingless `` lifting bodies,'' and the Enterprise shuttle prototype, and by the advent of sophisticated computer guidance systems and heat-shield tiles that do n't burn during a return to the atmosphere. `` If we did n't have good computers, we would n't be able to do re-entry,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> aerospace engineer. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said another big hurdle for a shuttle pilot is `` energy management,'' which means making S-turns and other maneuvers to reduce the shuttle's speed as it approaches the landing site. `` If he does n't control his energy accurately enough he may overshoot <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> and not have a place to land or undershoot and land in the water,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. Because the shuttle glides to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> without power, `` there's no opportunity to go around,'' <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said. `` You've got to hit it the first time.'' `` There are a lot of systems where, if they fail, you'd have a problem,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. `` If the landing gear did n't deploy, you'd have a belly landing, which could be catastrophic.'' Another possible failure involves the shuttle's three auxiliary power units, or APUs, which power the hydraulic system that runs the spacecraft's control flaps, rudders and speed brakes. In a study commissioned by <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and publicized last summer, <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON>'s engineering consulting firm of <PERSON> Pickard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON> estimated there is a one-in-70 chance that all three APUs will fail during a landing attempt and cause the shuttle to crash. That estimate contains so much uncertainy that the actual risk could be as high as one in 30 or as low as one in several hundred, <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON> said Friday. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> contends the risk is even lower. On Sunday, the Discovery astronauts briefly switched on the APUs and reported they were working fine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-TruckCollision     10-02 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Truck Collision,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trucks Ram Into Houses After Collision, Killing Four</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAGAYAN DE ORO, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two trucks collided head-on in a ball of flames and rammed into a group of houses, killing four people, officials said Sunday. The incident occurred just before midnight Saturday on a blind curve in the road near the village of <LOCATION> Carmen </LOCATION>, about 500 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, according to Lt. Col. <PERSON> Joselito </PERSON> <PERSON> Serena </PERSON>, provincial fire chief. A truck carrying a drum of gasoline exploded in flames when it hit a military vehicle, which hurtled into a wooden house and killed four sleeping students, <PERSON> Serena </PERSON> said. The first truck rammed into three nearby houses, starting a fire that gutted them, he said. The driver of the military truck escaped with only superficial injuries, while the second driver suffered third-degree burns, <PERSON> Serena </PERSON> said. He estimated property damage at $ 66,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CongressRdp Bjt   10-02 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate To Consider Tax Changes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Tax Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Just when it appeared <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> might finish a year without amending the tax laws, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is preparing to consider a bill that would make hundreds of changes and create some protections for taxpayers involved in disputes with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. Unlike most of the other tax bills of the 1980s, there is little in this legislation to draw the concern of the average family. Most of the changes are intended to clear up ambiguities or correct errors in the 1986 tax overhaul. But there are tidbits for some farmers, oil drillers, free-lance writers, first-time homebuyers, banks and workers who receive educational assistance from their employers. All told, the bill would parcel out tax benefits worth $ 2.3 billion over three years. Most of the money to pay for those benefits would come from a higher tax bite on some corporations. The House has passed a much larger bill, costing about $ 7 billion. If the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passes its bill, negotiators would attempt to work out a compromise between the two versions before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> adjourns for the year, likely by Oct. 15. Also awaiting action before adjournment are two issues with major political importance in this election year. One is the melding of separate anti-drug bills passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The second is final action on a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> package of parental leave and anti-child-pornography legislation that could end up with a provision expanding benefits for child care. More than 100 amendments to the tax bill are awaiting consideration. One of the most contentious, written by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, R-Colo., would deny a tax exemption to any clinic that regularly performs abortion Although opponents say they have the votes to defeat that amendment, <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> could tie up the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> for a considerable amount of time before the proposal ever reaches a vote. One of the few points of controversy already in the bill is drawing fire from tobacco-state lawmakers. It would require the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to study what effect the tax on cigarettes has on reducing smoking-related health problems. There is wide <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> support for the `` taxpayer bill of rights'' included in the legislation. The chief sponsor of the bill of rights, Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., says it is necessary to rein in some <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> employees who, he contends, have trampled on taxpayer rights The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration has opposed the bill of rights, saying some of its provisions would duplicate improvements already made by the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> while others would hamper the agency's ability to collect taxes. Included in <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>'s plan are requirements that the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> fully inform taxpayers of their rights any time a tax dispute arises and waive any penalty that is attributed to relying on written advice furnished by the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION>. It would prohibit the agency from promoting employees on the basis of how much tax they collect and extend to 30 days the 10-day waiting period before assets may be seized to satisfy overdue taxes. The tax bill has been more than two years in development. The administration and tax professionals have been urging passage to clear up uncertainties left after the tax code was overhauled in 1986. The push for passage picked up support this year when <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> tax committees added amendments exempting farmers and certain other business people from paying the federal diesel tax on fuel for off-road use. Under a 1987 law, they are required to pay the tax and file later for a refund. Other popular provisions in the bill would extend tax breaks for first-time homebuyers, corporate research, businesses that hire disadvantaged workers, and workers whose employers provide them with educational or legal assistance. In the last quarter-century, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has passed _ and presidents have signed _ major tax bills on the average of one a year. Since President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> took office less than eight years ago, taxes were cut in 1981, raised in 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985 and 1987, and thoroughly overhauled in 1986.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-TrainAccident     10-02 0086</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Accident,0086</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Killed, 30 Wounded, In Train Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A locomotive separated from a train, sending the cars hurtling into each other, killing two passengers and injuring 30 others, the <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. The agency said eight of those wounded in Thursday's accident in the central Sudanese area of <LOCATION> Khor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dunia </LOCATION>, about 190 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, were in serious condition. The accident happened when the locomotive disconnected and the wagons collided with each other, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Bush-Vague Bjt   10-02 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Vague, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Makes Himself A `Stealth Candidate' on Some Issues</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> frequently calls <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> the `` Stealth candidate'' who makes his positions invisible on political radar, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself is doggedly vague on some issues when it finds it convenient. Where does the vice president stand, for instance, on raising the minimum wage or on parental job leaves? As he has reached out to low-income voters in recent weeks, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he favors boosting the federal minimum wage, which has stood at $ 3.35 an hour for eight years. On parental leaves, he said women should not have to worry about getting their jobs back after having a baby or caring for a severely ill child. In neither case, however, has <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> filled in the blanks with specifics. Neither issue is very popular with conservatives and his statements leave him at odds with the White House. So perhaps the less <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says, the better. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON>, who is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief of staff, said both are `` the kind of issue one ought not to be silent on'' during a political campaign. On the other hand, he said, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> does not have to be specific. After a Republican-led filibuster, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> dropped a bill that would have raised the hourly minimum wage to $ 4.55 over three years. As president of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made no effort to bring the filibuster to a halt. The vice president has never said how much of an increase in the minimum wage he supported. `` He has not and will not attach any numbers to that,'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said. With the minimum wage bill dead, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is turning to a measure that would require employers to give unpaid leave to workers after childbirth or while caring for a sick child. Again, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not outlined his policy, other than a general statement of support for the concept. `` He made a passing reference to it,'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> said. `` We have not laid out any particular formula.'' Is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s staff working on a formula? `` Not at this point, no,'' <PERSON> Fuller </PERSON> replied. There have been other times when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has raised an issue but not explained what he meant. In his first nationally televised debate with <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> last week, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked what he would do for the 37 million Americans who can not afford health insurance, many because they earn too much to qualify for Medicaid coverage for the needy. `` What I will do,'' he said, `` is permit people to buy into Medicaid. I believe that's the answer.'' The next day, a reporter asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s campaign chairman, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, to explain what <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was talking about. `` Well, all I know on that is that he thinks that would be an appropriate approach to explore,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. Asked to elaborate on how the poor would `` buy into Medicaid,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> replied, `` It means taking a look at the Medicaid laws and Medicaid system, seeing if there's a way that these 22 to 37 million people have some way at minimal cost to finance health coverage for themselves.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also pulled <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> back from his statement in the debate suggesting that he would favor criminal penalties for women who have abortions if the procedure is declared illegal. `` I have n't sorted out the penalties,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had said. `` ... there's got to be some penalties to enforce the law.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> immediately criticized that statement. The next morning, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> conferred with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and told reporters that `` it is his view that he would not wish to see a woman labeled as a criminal, not withstanding his view in favor of right to life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1129EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Gulf-USShips     10-02 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Gulf-US Ships,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five U.S Warships Cross Suez After Duty In Gulf</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SUEZ, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> warships entered the Suez Canal on Sunday after ending their duty in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>, a canal official said. The official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, identified the five vessels as the frigates <PERSON> Halyburton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, Fahrion and <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> and the destroyer, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>. The five ships entered the canal's southern end at <ORGANIZATION> Suez </ORGANIZATION> early Sunday and were expected to leave the canal and enter the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> by Sunday night. The movement of the ships, which have been replaced by other American vessels in the gulf, was part of a planned rotation, according to sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1142EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vietnam-MIAs     10-02 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-MIAs,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Americans, Vietnamese, Hunt For U.S. MIAs in Vietnamese Mountains</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HANOI, Vietnam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A U.S.-Vietnamese team embarked on a new expedition Sunday after a grueling trek through leech-infested mountains to retrieve the wreckage of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> warplanes and interview villagers about the fate of crew members. During a search last week of <PERSON> Vinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Phu </PERSON> and Bac Thai provinces northwest of <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, the team found villagers who recalled in detail what happened to airmen who bombed them during the Vietnam War more than 15 years ago. No human remains were recovered, but the villagers' accounts may help resolve the cases, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team members, who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` The war is over,'' one American investigator quoted villagers as saying. `` You caused a lot of death and destruction, but if you need help, we will help you.'' Two teams are conducting the first joint U.S.-Vietnamese field investigation to try to account for 1,757 Americans listed as missing in action, or MIA, in the country. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces withdrew from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1973. Fighting ended when the communists defeated U.S.-backed <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in 1975. The cooperative effort is seen as a major breakthrough in an issue marked by frequent bickering, deep distrust and <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>'s reluctance to allow <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> experts to work in the countryside The team that searched crash sites in <PERSON> Vinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Phu </PERSON> and Bac Thai for six days drove off in jeeps Sunday to investigate an area in <LOCATION> Ha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nam </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ninh </LOCATION> province south of <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>. The second team continued work in <LOCATION> Lang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Son </LOCATION> <LOCATION> and </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ha </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bac </LOCATION> provinces just northeast of the capital. The 10-day search ends Wednesday. The teams each are comprised of three specialists from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Joint Casualty Resolution Center and the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Identification </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, and four experts from <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s Office for Seeking Missing Personnel. They focused on a half-dozen of the 70 `` discrepancy cases'' that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has asked <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to resolve urgently. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials say Vietnamese authorities at some level should have information about the 70 missing men. Some are known to have been captured but never were heard from again. Many areas of mountainous <PERSON> Vinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Phu </PERSON> and Bac Thai were not reachable by jeeps or by the motorcycles. The Americans said they walked, climbed and crawled about 30 miles investigating two cases in the area. They showed the marks left on their skin by the briar patches that sliced their arms and legs and by the numerous leeches that sucked blood from their feet. Each carried a backpack weighing up to 40 pounds containing metal detectors, satellite navigational devices and food. `` We went to some places where we were up to 2,000 feet and all you could see below was jagged rock, and the ledge we stood on was only a foot wide,'' one American said. `` It was breathtaking.'' They slept wherever they could, one night in a wooden hut that appeared to have been a guard post during the French colonial period, they said. Food was canned army rations and meals served by local officials, including roasted dog meat, snails, small wild birds, and as one American put it, chickens with their heads still on. `` The snails were great,'' one American said. `` The first snail I ate for my country and the rest for enjoyment.'' The search focused on the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nguyen </LOCATION> area of Bac Thai, a railway junction and steel mill center that was targeted by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bombers during the war. The Americans retrieved pieces of wreckage which they will bring back to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for analysis. They photographed other evidence, including certificates people hung in their houses in which the government commended them for shooting down <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft. No human remains were recovered, but Vietnamese officials said that in some of the half-dozen cases, villagers claimed they knew where remains were.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-MilitaryAirAccidents Bjt   10-02 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Military Air Accidents, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jet Fighters' High Accident Rate Puzzles Military</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, each puzzled by an unexpected increase in accidents this summer involving high-performing jets, have failed to find a common thread to explain the mishaps, officials say. From a historical standpoint, the current accident rates for <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter and attack jets are not out of line, officials say. Indeed, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> is actually enjoying one of its all-time safest years for aviation. Both services have mounted careful monitoring campaigns because of accident spurts involving the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s F-14s and the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s F-16s The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says it has found no equipment problems, but has changed some of its pilot training techniques and increased supervision because of the rise in mishaps. Officials say several of this year's F-16 accidents involved pilots who lost consciousness as a result of fast aerial maneuvers or who became disoriented and lost track of where they were. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has n't detected any equipment problems, either, but has made no change in pilot training. `` We're just not seeing any common threads at all to justify changes,'' says Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman at the Pentagon. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s accident spurt involves the service's top-of-the-line fighter, the F-14 Tomcat. The service went through the first eight months of 1988 with only one so-called Class A accident involving the F-14. The plane was lost but the two-man crew survived in that accident. A Class A mishap is one in which there is either a fatality or damage exceeding $ 500,000 to an aircraft. But in the single month of September, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lost five Tomcats _ two on one day _ and saw three of its aviators die. Two of the planes were lost on separate days from the same aircraft carrier, the USS <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Vinson </PERSON>, while on patrol duty in the northern Arabian Sea. During 1987, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lost eight F-14s in accidents that produced two fatalities. The mishap rates this year for the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s F-A-18 Hornet and A-6 Intruder, meantime, have dropped significantly below last year's levels Indeed, after the worst year ever for the F-A-18 in 1987 _ when 10 Class A accidents were reported _ only three such mishaps have occurred so far this year. On the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> side, the accident spurt involves the F-16 Fighting Falcon. Serious mishaps with that single-engine fighter have ballooned from 12 in fiscal 1987 to 23 in fiscal 1988, the year that ended on Friday. Seven F-16 pilots died in fiscal 1988, compared to five in fiscal 1987. And for the first time ever, fiscal 1988 saw the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> lose three of the planes on one day _ June 29 _ in two accidents. The service acknowledges this year's increase in F-16 accidents has raised concerns about pilot training and whether the plane is too `` hot'' for some pilots to control. `` We attribute almost 70 percent of these F-16 losses to human error and have taken steps to correct that trend by focusing on causes of mishaps and placing emphasis on training and supervision,'' says Maj. <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastor </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. `` We believe the F-16 is a very safe aircraft, and the lifetime statistics for the plane bear that out,'' added Col. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, the chief of safety and nuclear surety in the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's office. `` But it's also a pretty sophisticated aircraft that can do a lot of things that aircraft in the past could n't do,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> added. The safety official said `` several'' of this year's accidents with the F-16 had involved pilots who lost consciousness as a result of unusually rapid aerial maneuvers. They said `` several more'' involved pilots who suffered `` spatial disorientation,'' losing track of where they were in the air. To counter those problems, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> has stepped up pilot training in breathing and other techniques to handle heavy gravity forces; started a special education program on the type of physical fitness workouts needed to counter gravity forces; begun using huge centrifuge machines more frequently to condition young pilots, and added extra training in instrument flying so that pilots can maintain control of a plane even when they are physically disoriented. By contrast, the top-of-the-line <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> fighter, the F-15 Eagle, enjoyed a banner year for safety. Only one Eagle crashed in fiscal 1988 and the pilot survived. Three of the planes and two pilots were lost in fiscal 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says the F-15 normally posts a better safety record than the F-16, in part because the Eagle has two engines and the Falcon only one, and in part because the Falcon must train for air-to-ground attacks as well as air-to-air fight.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1213EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     10-02 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0692</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MEADVILLE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A little wooden bridge is saving motorists and buggies a lot of trouble in this northwestern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> town. When the state proposed a 4.5-mile detour rather than put up a temporary structure while it replaced a small 60-year-old bridge spanning a creek, a group of <LOCATION> Sparta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> residents got together and built their own. The state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> estimated building a temporary bridge would take two weeks and cost at least $ 50,000, but the local people built theirs in two days with donated materials, their own labor and $ 7,722. About half of the residents along the road are <LOCATION> Amish </LOCATION> and Mennonite farmers who drive horses and buggies and they wanted to avoid the proposed detour along two miles of bumpy dirt road. `` Did n't cost the state a thing,'' said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Graves </PERSON>, who helped organize the bridge work when it was built in June. `` We saved them money, and we saved everyone around here a lot of money and inconvenience.'' The temporary bridge, which had no trouble passing state inspection, will be out of business in about two weeks. The new $ 239,000 permanent bridge is almost finished.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LYNCHBURG, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Distillery </PERSON> unveiled its first new label in over a century, but none of the 1,000 guests on hand to celebrate tasted the premium whiskey. The ceremony was held in a dry county, where the sale and service of alcohol is illegal. <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, executive vice president of the distillery, removed a black cloth covering the first bottle of Gentleman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> on Friday afternoon. The 80-proof whiskey is meant to compete with big name premium whiskeys such as Chivas Regal. <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON> said that when the distillery was choosing its first new label in more than a century: `` We sort of looked at it as like Mr. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> had matured and had perfected something his lady friends and he would like. So it kind of fit _ Gentleman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON>.'' Gentleman <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> wo n't be immediately available except in limited quantities in selected restaurants and liquor stores in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, officials said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Roll over, <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>, and tell <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON> the news: Classical music prevailed over rock' n' roll in a fund-raising contest staged by two <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> radio stations. The `` Rock Vs. Bach'' promotion ended Friday, with classical WQRS-FM drawing 6,209 votes and rock station WCSX-FM garnering 4,311. Each vote, cast at area businesses participating in the contest, was worth $ 1. The $ 10,520 was donated to the <ORGANIZATION> Ronald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION>, which provides inexpensive lodging for families with children hospitalized at <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, WQRS program director <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said Saturday. `` We feel real good about winning,'' <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said. `` With classical music stations, it's always been assumed we have a smaller audience.'' <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Perry </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> WCSX </ORGANIZATION>'s morning host, conceded victory to <ORGANIZATION> WQRS </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>, who as winner of a side bet will escort <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> to the concert of <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s choice. `` I'm going to take him to the opera, and he's going to be amazed at how much he likes it,'' <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At their wedding, some couples may feel like they're on parade, or like they're floating, but in a few months one couple will take the experience to new extremes _ with an estimated audience of 350 million people. The search is on for a couple willing to exchange vows aboard a float, titled `` Romance in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>,'' in the Tournament of Roses Parade on Jan. 2. The annual parade, which precedes the Rose Bowl matchup of the Big 10 and <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> 10 collegiate football champs, usually takes place on New Year's Day. But when Jan. 1 falls on a Sunday, as it does in 1989, the parade and bowl game are held on Jan. 2. `` The Search for the Most Romantic Couple in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'' is sponsored by a local hotel, a radio station, a department store chain and a magazine. The winning couple will be announced Dec. 3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881002-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-02-88 1232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Quayle-Debate     10-02 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Quayle-Debate,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Says He'll Focus on Dukakis in Debate With Bentsen</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: The following dispatch serves as a political roundup.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN PUTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
