<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SoCalStorm 1stLd-Writethru a0749 12-15 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SoCal Storm, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0749,0639</SECOND>
<HEAD>Southern California Hit By Snow, Sleet</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 2nd graf, `Snow flurries ..., to UPDATE
with evening temperatures, shelters opening; SUBS grafs 8-9,
``Interstate 5 ..., with 7 grafs on motels filling up with stranded
motorists, precipitation reports.</NOTE>
<HEAD>With AM-Wind Problems, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ANTCZAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Snow and sleet blanketed much of <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Thursday and dozens of cars crashed on an icy mountain interstate, killing two people. The snow also blocked thousands of motorists on a coastal highway. Snow flurries appeared in the southern <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> and sleet and rain fell around <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, including hills that were dry and ablaze only a week ago, as the storm swept from <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s midsection. As temperatures headed down to the 40s for the night, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> gave hotel vouchers to homeless people and opened shelters in a recreation center and an armory. Two armories opened as shelters in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Ten crashes involving dozens of vehicles and two deaths occurred on Interstate 15 in <LOCATION> Cajon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>. No information was immediately available on the deaths. At midmorning police began slowly escorting groups of cars through the pass behind snowplows rather than require use of chains, which causes miles of backup and hours of delay. `` It's just like a winter wonderland up there,'' said Officer <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Roden </PERSON>. Thousands of motorists were stuck when snow closed Highway 101 north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION>, which is about 150 miles north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, police said. `` One of the problems is here we do n't have the snow equipment to take care of this _ it does n't happen here,'' said <ORGANIZATION> CHP </ORGANIZATION> Officer <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Stricker </PERSON>. Cuesta Summit is only 1,500 feet above sea level, and <PERSON> Stricker </PERSON> noted, snow fell not only at the top but at the bottom of the grade as well. A college basketball game between <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Cal </LOCATION> Poly-San <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Obispo </PERSON> was canceled because the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> team was stranded at <LOCATION> Atascadero </LOCATION> on the north side of the grade, said <LOCATION> Cal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Poly </LOCATION> official <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON>. Motel rooms filled up fast in <LOCATION> Atascadero </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Paso </PERSON> <PERSON> Robles </PERSON> as the highway traffic ground to a halt, said <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who works at the Paso Robles Inn. It was the first snowfall Ms. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> had seen there in 22 years. Interstate 5 over the <LOCATION> Tejon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pass </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> was snowy and slick but the major north-south route through the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gabriels </LOCATION> remained open. The storm was generated by a cold, upper-level low over <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> that moved through central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. The low was expected to drift west on Friday. <LOCATION> Downtown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> warmed only to 56 degrees Thursday, compared to a normal of 68. Rainfall totaled .77 inch by 6 p.m., bringing the season total to 1.56 inches compared to a normal 3.29 inches by Dec. 15. Elsewhere, rainfall totaled 1.69 inches at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wilson </LOCATION>, 1.68 inches at <LOCATION> Newhall </LOCATION>, .95 inch at <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, and 1.14 inch at Point Mugu by evening. Just a week earlier the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Basin </LOCATION> was swept by warm and fierce <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ana </LOCATION> winds. Dozens of homes were burned by wind-blown fires in two suburbs on Dec. 8, and the next day more burned in a 3,000-acre brush fire in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Susana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> above the northern <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Snow flurries were reported on the floor of the southern <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> and <PERSON> McFarland </PERSON>, the weather service said. Snowfall ranged from 2 to 6 inches in northern <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Luis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Obispo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and some schools were closed, said sheriff's Lt. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dooley </PERSON>. `` Of course, people in this area are n't prepared for snow,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TysonCharge 1stLd-Writethru a0752 12-15 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tyson Charge, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0752,0348</SECOND>
<HEAD>Second Woman Accuses Tyson Of Harassment</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: SUBS 6th graf, `Tyson was ..., to ADD boxer's comments; note
contents of grafs 3-4, `Davis said ..., may be offensive to some
readers.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAT MILTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GARDEN CITY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman charged Thursday that heavyweight champion <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> sexually molested her in a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> disco last week, the second woman to make such a charge. The woman, <PERSON> Lori </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 29, of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shore </LOCATION> on <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> said she planned to sue <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> for mental anguish and trauma. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said she was dancing with a male partner at <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>'s Disco Lounge around 2 a.m. Sunday when `` Someone grabbed my behind under my dress. `` I turned around and screamed, ` try that again and I'll slap the -- -- out of you,''' she said. `` Then it dawned on me that I was screaming at the heavyweight champion of the world,'' she said. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to announce his upcoming fight with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruno </PERSON>, said, `` I do n't even know this person, I do n't know what happened.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> was standing on the dance floor with two male companions when the incident occurred. `` He put his hands up in the air and said `` Whoa, whoa, we have a live one here,''' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> and his friends then moved away to another area of the disco. Asked if her male partner confronted <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> on the dance floor, she replied: `` No, the man had common sense.'' She said she was willing to put aside the incident but when she read two days ago that another woman had charged <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON> with sexually molesting her at <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>'s on the same night she decided to come forward. Her attorney, <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Berg </PERSON>, said the lawsuit will seek $ 1 million in damages for `` trauma, shock and mental anguish.'' <PERSON> Berg </PERSON> said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> is scheduled to be interviewed by detectives in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> to determine if any criminal complaints should be filed. `` I am really angry and embarrassed at the whole thing,'' said <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-PLO 1stLd-Writethru a0641 12-15 1018</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-PLO, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0641,980</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Defends PLO Move; Says US Steadfastly Supports Israel</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDs: DELETES 6th graf pvs bgng, `State Department,' and INSERTS 1
graf after 7th graf pvs bgng, `White House' to UPDATE with State
officials saying talks with the PLO probably will open in Tunis on
Friday afternoon</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on Thursday defended opening a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, calling it `` just another step'' in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> peace process and saying <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should n't worry about <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s commitment to its security. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also said he would not hesitate to `` break off communications'' if <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> reneged on its acceptance of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s sovereignty or its renunciation of terrorism as an instrument to achieve policy objectives. During separate Oval Office picture-taking sessions with Turkish Prime Minister <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> and Italian Prime Minister <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>, the president said he decided to reverse his longstanding opposition to contacts with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> on the basis of statements that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> made in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> on Wednesday. When asked if he thought that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was justified in being upset with his administration's move, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> replied: `` Well, I do n't think so, in the sense that we have made it very plain that we have not retreated one inch from our position of guaranteeing the safety of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Acting on the instructions of Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pelletreau </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, called the director general of the political section at the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> headquarters to try to make arrangements for the talks, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said White House spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters that `` at this point, there has been no substantive response in terms of time, place or location.'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials later said that talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> probably would begin in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> on Friday afternoon. On <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, leading members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> gave the new opening a wary welcome, and they joined <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in seeking to reassure <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials will be alert to any <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> tricks. `` This is good news and the right path to follow,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think we would best be very careful that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> continue to show real seriousness and be wary of any decepion.'' Sen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, the newly elected <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> majority leader, welcomed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> move and called it a `` significant step toward advancing the peace process.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the administration agreed to open a substantive dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> after it became satisfied that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had complied with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for such direct contacts. Asked to explain the policy reversal, the president said: `` Well, because the words have been spoken, and the words were the words that we have been stating were necessary.'' But he said, `` Of course, ... the words must be matched by performance, and if they're not, why, we're back where we started. Questioned about what he would do if the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> failed to live up to its commitments, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` Well, we'd certainly break off communications.'' He stressed that the ultimate solution in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> `` does not depend on outsiders _ or us.'' `` Peace must be brought about by the involved nations meeting with each other and settling their differences,'' he said. Asked why the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> does not recognize a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` ... Because there is no such thing as of now. There is n't a Palestinian state. And if you recognize someone ... as that, it would be us declaring who was in charge there.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said commencing exploratory talks with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> was `` just another step in what we've been trying for eight years _ to bring about peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>.'' President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told reporters he supported <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision `` I have n't spelled out any hopes about it,'' he added. `` <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> met the conditions of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and we will go forward with a dialogue, not negotiations, but a dialogue. ... Let's see how things evolve.'' As for the discussions, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` There's no game plan; there's no five-point program.'' Asked if he would prefer that the talks wait until his administration starts next month, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> replied, `` I am vice president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. I become president on Jan. 20. On Jan. 21, I'll tell you what I want to do.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> announcement late Wednesday left <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in diplomatic isolation and came just a few hours after <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had taken a tough line against the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, declaring it failed to meet the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions. But <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>, in statements made in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> about the same time that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was speaking, had met the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for a `` substantive dialogue'' _ a form of diplomatic acceptance long sought by the Palestinian group. Only a day earlier, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had said <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> failed to meet the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions. And less than three weeks ago, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> had accused the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> of terrorism, said <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> was `` an accessory to such terrorism'' and denied the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader an entry visa to address the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> long has insisted that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> accept <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> resolutions, adopted in 1967 and 1973, affirming the right of all states in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to live in peace. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is not specifically mentioned. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also has demanded that <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s organization renounce terrorism and accept <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s right to exist. White House spokesman <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials would move `` cautiously into the dialogue'' with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> representatives and that the talks would `` establish a foundation'' for the organization `` to prove that they have changed their ways.'' `` It's too early to speculate on how these things might take place,'' he said. `` This is a first step ... and how the follow-on steps will evolve, we really do n't want to draw parameters at this point.'' `` We did have strong feelings about the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and we still have strong feelings,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. But he said the administration decided to permit contacts because there has been `` evidence of change.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:Bird     12-15 0812</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Bird,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jazz on the Screen</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DOLORES BARCLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Arts Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 There's a moment in <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>'s movie, `` Bird,'' when the great jazzman <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> stands on a blackened <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> stage after finishing a concert, consuming massive doses of applause and sniffing a long-stemmed red rose. He was something of a god to jazz zealots, but perhaps the tortured musical genius never really got a chance to wake up and smell the roses. He mutilated his life with drugs and alcohol, and died at the age of 34 in 1955. <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>, who has loved jazz since his childhood and who always wanted to film a portrait of <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, attempts to harness the Bird's creative spirit and all the creative juices of that time _ a time when bebop came to the fore and brought jazz into the modern age At the same time, it pokes into the underbelly of the jazz world with its stark portrayal of drugs, alcohol, debauchery. `` His life was obviously filled with many excesses _ sort of a dichotomy,'' <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> says. `` How a person who can be so brilliant and who spent hours and hours to become as great as he did and have that kind of discipline could not in any other part of his life. That was always a wonder to me. `` But I wanted a movie where you root for him. ... I just wanted to explore the fact that he was brilliant and innovative, and the other just became a part of his life.'' <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> even films `` Bird'' in a dark, brownish hue. `` Most of the jazz world is nocturnal,'' he says. `` TV unfortunately has shown a whole generation that flat light is the only way. I do n't like flat light. I like the feel of the movie; I like to look into a film instead of having it look out at you. I approached the color of it in terms of black and white.'' Forest <PERSON> Whitaker </PERSON> -LRB- `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' `` Platoon'' -RRB- is gentle yet fierce, playful yet obsessed in his role as <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, for which he was awarded the best actor prize at the <ORGANIZATION> Cannes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Festival </ORGANIZATION>. It was well deserved for a stunning performance that even captures the hunched body stances once assumed by the musician as he performed. As <PERSON> Chan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Venora </PERSON> -LRB- `` Ironweed,'' `` F-X'' -RRB- finds the right balance between free spirit and strong, loving wife who battles her husband's philandering and personal demons and at the same time champions his work and well-being. `` Bird'' followed the success of last year's `` Round Midnight,'' the story of an expatriate sax player in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Tenor saxophone great <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, who once worked with <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, received an Academy Award nomination for his role as the tragic <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>. Though based loosely on the late jazz musician <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bertrand </PERSON> <PERSON> Tavernier </PERSON>'s movie is a universal story of jazz artists who fled bigotry and rough times in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> for the allure of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Amsterdam </LOCATION> during the 1940s,'50s and'60s. `` <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> Blues,'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritt </PERSON>'s 1961 jazz movie starring <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Poitier </PERSON>, takes a more romantic, <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> approach. The late <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellington </PERSON> received an Oscar nomination for his score. In `` Bird,'' <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Niehaus </PERSON> did the score, which isolates <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s original playing of `` <PERSON> Laura </PERSON>,'' `` April in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>,'' `` Ornithology,'' `` <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>'s Mood'' and other jazz tunes and remixes his recorded solos with contemporary musicians including bassist <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, trumpeter <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Faddis </PERSON>, pianists <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> Jazz purists have been rankled by the soundtrack, which they say is technically excellent but misses the interplay between <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> and his sidemen. But <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> defends his decision: `` If you're going to do a film and have stereophonic sound, you need to record well. <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> never had the opportunity to do stereophonic sound.'' <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and took up first baritone and then alto sax while still in high school, which he left at the age of 14 so he could study such greats as <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> and <PERSON> Count </PERSON> <PERSON> Basie </PERSON> in the local clubs. He soon found himself in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> where a young trumpet player named <PERSON> Dizzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> was all the rage. With Thelonious Monk and <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> on piano, <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON> on drums and later a young <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> on trumpet, <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gillespie </PERSON> helped define and create a new musical venture in jazz _ bebop. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, whose nickname was Yardbird and shortened to <PERSON> Bird </PERSON>, stumbled into the lost world of night life. But even with the debiliation of drugs and alcohol, he never failed to solve musical problems and invent new directions. `` There have been no great harmonic changes in jazz since <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> and Dizzy,'' <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> says. And then he muses, what musical levels would <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> have reached today had he lived? `` It would be interesting,'' the actor-filmmaker says.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-HongKong-PhoneCraze     12-15 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hong Kong-Phone Craze,0524</SECOND>
<HEAD>Portable Phones are All the Rage in Hong Kong</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The rage of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> these days is easy to spot. Just look for the tiny antennas, the telltale sign of the portable telephones so many people are carrying wherever they go. Despite price tags of $ 2,000 or more, the hand-held telephones have become a huge hit in this British colony, where doing business is a 24-hour preoccupation and new status symbols are always in demand. Downtown streets are filled with professionals ready for business with the cellular phones tucked under their arms or stuffed, antenna-up, into briefcases. Away from the financial district, people can be seen barking into the phones while eating in restaurants, riding public buses and ferries, or sitting in darkened movie theaters. Everyone from executives to proprietors of produce stalls can be seen chatting away. The <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> newspaper spotted a telephone in a recent 100-kilometer -LRB- 62-mile -RRB- charity walk along a rural trail. `` In driving rain and a lashing wind, a young man was spotted eagerly and conspicuously talking into his mobile telephone,'' it said. `` In a more normal society one would expect -LRB- him -RRB- to hand the phone over to one of his seconds before starting the race. -LRB- But -RRB- a few kilometers down the track, the young man was spotted merrily informing the financial markets at large of his continued existence.'' The government estimates about 60,000 portable cellular telephones _ roughly six times earlier projections _ will be in use by the end of the year in this territory of 5.7 million people, said Deputy Postmaster General <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, whose department is in charge of telecommunications. While most cellular telephones sold in other countries are for use in cars, roughly three-fourths of the units sold in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> since the market opened three years ago have been the more expensive handheld models. `` We were amazed when the whole thing really took off in a great way,'' Wise said. <ORGANIZATION> Hutchison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>, which has sold about 26,000 cellular telephones, recently stopped sales for six weeks because demand was outpacing the company's capacity to handle all the calls. `` The market just caught everybody by surprise,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, a rival firm `` We're all frantically rebuilding networks. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hui </PERSON>, a psychology lecturer at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION>, attributed the popularity of the telephones here in part to `` the importance of face. It's a status symbol.'' Wise believes the <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> work ethic of doing business whenever and wherever possible is largely responsible for the tremendous sales. `` Virtually the whole day is part of the working day,'' he said. Although industry officials see no end in sight to demand for the telephones, their indiscriminate use in public places already is viewed as an irritation by some. `` People are becoming aware of the annoyance factor,'' acknowledged <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>. Several exclusive clubs demand that their patrons and guests check their telephones at the door.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-IrishWhiskey     12-15 0860</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Irish Whiskey,0889</SECOND>
<HEAD>Some Eyes Aren't Smiling As French Take Over Whiskey Industry</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</NOTE>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By COTTEN TIMBERLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pub conversations in <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>, where people are fond of their drink and free with their opinions, are likely to be spiced with some regret these days. <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s whiskey industry, the world's original, is now owned by the French. Losing its treasures to outsiders _ principally the conquering <ORGANIZATION> Vikings </ORGANIZATION> and English _ is no new experience for this small island nation. Today, with liquor industries around the world tending to consolidate, and with <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> a member of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, losing a major industry to an <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> partner is perhaps inevitable. But it hurts all the same. <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION>, which makes all the world's Irish whiskey and calls itself `` the spirit of <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>,'' was won on Nov. 24 by the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> liquor company <ORGANIZATION> Pernod </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ricard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> SA </ORGANIZATION> after a six-month battle with a hostile bidder, the <ORGANIZATION> Grand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLC </ORGANIZATION>, liquor company of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The news is by no means all bad: analysts say a fair price is being paid for <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION>' shares; its 1,100 employees' jobs are assured; and the future looks brighter for its brands, which include <PERSON> Jameson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paddy </PERSON> and Bushmills. But over a neat measure of Irish whiskey or a pint of dark, frothy <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> O'Donoghue </ORGANIZATION>'s _ arguably <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>'s most famous pub _ it's the losses, not the gains, that come to mind. `` I would obviously be disappointed when a company based in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> becomes owned by someone other than <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> people,'' said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> McEvoy </PERSON>, echoing the sentiments of several customers, shouted over lively Irish music. Ms. <PERSON> McEvoy </PERSON>, a mental health worker, is reticent about her age, but not about her preferred whiskey: Bushmills. `` Irish whiskey is one of the most traditional products that this country exports,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Fell </PERSON>, chief executive of the <ORGANIZATION> Licensed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vintners </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` We were anxious to maintain the integrity of Irish spirits. The main problem we were concerned with was that the company would be broken up.'' The issue was important enough for the government to step in and ensure that <PERSON> Pernod </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricard </PERSON> did not alter the Irish whiskey industry, which is a monopoly, or sell off brands without official approval. <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION> sought out <LOCATION> Pernod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ricard </LOCATION> as a friendly bidder to fend off Grand Met, which offered $ 499 million. <PERSON> Pernod </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricard </PERSON>'s offer was lower, at $ 442 million, but it promised to safeguard jobs and develop brands, while Grand Met said it intended to dispose of at least one brand Grand Met threw in the towel after several regulatory and court rulings in <LOCATION> Pernod </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ricard </LOCATION>'s favor, but retains a stake in <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION> limited by the government to 30 percent. The battle for <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION> has been a headline-making event, and very stressful for the company's workers. `` Certainly everybody had views about it. But the overwhelming feeling we got was of support,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION>' managing director, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>. So, is Irish whiskey still Irish? `` I do n't think people will feel any different,'' <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON> said. `` With <PERSON> Pernod </PERSON> <PERSON> Ricard </PERSON>'s support, we'll be able to go on with the development of our brands. I think it's a good thing for the Irish industry.'' But <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON>, in an interview at the company's <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> headquarters, conceded: `` I do have a twinge of regret that <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION> is not remaining an independent Irish company. There is a lot of heredity and tradition.'' The secret of perfume distillation reached <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> in the 6th century and monks soon figured out how to use it for making whiskey. Irish Distillers' origins date to 1608 when Old Bushmills, which claims to be the world's oldest distillery, was licensed in northern <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antrim </LOCATION>. In 1966, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Power </PERSON> and Son merged with <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jameson </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Cork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION>. Bushmills joined the group in the 1970s, creating the monopoly. Irish Distillers suffered in the 1980s from the abstinence trend, and profits have been hurt by attempts to expand sales abroad. But sales now are growing here and overseas, <PERSON> Burrows </PERSON> said. In the six months ended March 31, the company produced a 40 percent year-to-year gain in net profit to $ 9.8 million, or 15 cents a share, on an 8 percent gain in revenue to $ 197 million. With 1.635 million standard cases in the year ended Sept. 30, 1987, Irish whiskey captured 36 percent of the spirits market in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, and imported whiskeys accounted for 12 percent. Irish whiskey sales outside <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> came to nearly 1 million cases. The Scotch whisky industry shipped 75 million cases in 1987. Regrets aside, the overwhelming emotion at the company is relief that the suspense is over and that the friendly bidder prevailed. `` I just feel the best people won,'' said <PERSON> Rachel </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Donnell </PERSON>, 25, a receptionist at <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Distillers </ORGANIZATION>' largest bottling plant, in <LOCATION> Clondalkin </LOCATION>, outside <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>. Said Burrows: `` There will be continuity, but certainly there will be certain changes.'' In the meantime, nothing is going to interfere with Irishman <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON>'s plans. `` I'll still have my Paddy,'' <PERSON> Doyle </PERSON> said as he stepped off to his favorite pub. Yes, <PERSON> O'Donoghue </PERSON>'s. And yes, his eyes were smiling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0826 12-15 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0826,0625</SECOND>
<NOTE>Eds: ADDS Seymour; A separate moved for AMs as a0736 on Symington.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Stuart Symington</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW CANAAN, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Symington </PERSON>, the nation's first <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> secretary and a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senator from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> for 24 years, died Wednesday of heart failure. He was 87. <PERSON> Symington </PERSON> served in World War I as an Army second lieutenant. He held six various posts within President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>'s administration between 1945 to 1952, including the nation's first <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> secretary from 1947-1950 <PERSON> Symington </PERSON> served in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> from 1953 to 1976, deciding at that time not to seek re-election. He was a `` favorite son'' candidate for the Democratic presidential nomination in 1956 and 1960. <PERSON> Symington </PERSON> retired from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1976.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Dorothy Jordan</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, an actress who starred opposite <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrea </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Novarro </PERSON> in motion pictures of the 1930s, died Dec. 7 of heart failure at age 82. Miss <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> landed small parts in such Broadway musicals as `` Garrick Gaieties'' and `` Twinkle Twinkle.'' She was the understudy for <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Astaire </PERSON>'s sister, <ORGANIZATION> Adele </ORGANIZATION>, in `` Funny Face.'' Miss <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> began her movie career when she was cast in the 1930 film `` In Gay Madrid'' with <PERSON> Novarro </PERSON>. Her other credits included `` Min and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON>,'' `` The Taming of the Shrew,'' `` Young Sinners,'' and `` Hell Divers'' with <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Gable </PERSON>. In 1932 Miss <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON>, appeared opposite <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> McCrea </PERSON> in `` The Lost Squadron'' and in `` Bondage'' a year later. She emerged briefly in the 1950s to appear in character roles in `` The Sun Shines Bright,'' `` The Searchers'' and `` The <ORGANIZATION> Wings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eagles </ORGANIZATION>.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Shellhase</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OCEAN RIDGE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shellhase </PERSON>, 93, a artist who captured the diversity of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> life through sketches and drawings, died Monday. <PERSON> Shellhase </PERSON>'s works have been shown in galleries such as the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Illustrators </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Norton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gallery </LOCATION> and the New Chapellier Gallery of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. His illustrations and cartoons appeared in the Saturday Evening Post, The New Yorker, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Collier </PERSON>'s and <ORGANIZATION> Esquire </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Perry Lieber</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieber </PERSON>, a well-known publicity agent who was a confidant of the late billionaire <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, died Monday at the age of 83. <PERSON> Lieber </PERSON> joined the publicity department at <ORGANIZATION> RKO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> in 1930, working there for 25 years and becoming the studio's publicity director. He worked with many of RKO's top stars, including <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ingrid </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>. <PERSON> Lieber </PERSON> began his association with <ORGANIZATION> Hughes </ORGANIZATION> in 1948, when <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> purchased RKO. He handled all public relations for <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>' <ORGANIZATION> Summa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> until his death.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Anne Seymour</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON>, a actress who was heard almost nightly during radio's Golden Age of the 1930s and 1940s, died Dec. 8 of respiratory complications. She was 79. Miss <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> made her Broadway debut in 1928 as an understudy in `` Mr. Moneypenny.'' Her stage credits include `` Sunrise at <LOCATION> Campobello </LOCATION>,'' `` Hay Fever,'' `` Saturday's Children,'' `` The Intimate Strangers,'' `` The Sorcerer,'' `` Troilus and <PERSON> Cressida </PERSON>'' and `` Time Out for Ginger.'' <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seymours </ORGANIZATION>' radio credits include `` <ORGANIZATION> Portia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Faces </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` The Ford Theatre,'' `` Grand Hotel,'' `` Against the Storm,'' `` The Magnificent Montague'' `` Armstrong Theater'' and others. Her first film was `` All the King's Men'' in 1949. Other movie credits include `` All the Fine Young Cannibals,'' `` Misty,'' `` How to Succeed in Business Without Really Trying'' and her last, `` Shoeless <PERSON> Joe </PERSON>,'' which has not been released. On television Miss <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> appeared in `` Studio One,'' `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> Presents,'' `` <ORGANIZATION> Kraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` The <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleason </PERSON> Show,'' `` Naked City'' and `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>,'' and recently, `` <PERSON> Cagney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lacey </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HousingProjectDeath     12-15 0341</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Housing Project Death,0352</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother Sues City For $60 Million In Son's Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city was hit with a $ 60 million lawsuit Wednesday alleging negligence on the part of Fire Department paramedics who did not treat a 9-year-old boy who eventually died from an asthma attack. Fire department spokesmen claim the ambulance was pelted with eggs and rocks and paramedics were forced to retreat when they arrived at a housing project Monday. `` All the evidence we have says there was nothing being thrown at the paramedics,'' attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON> said. `` They just flatly refused to go up'' to the apartment. <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON> filed a lawsuit on behalf of <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarnagin </PERSON>, whose son, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON>, died. The lawsuit asks for $ 10 million in actual damages and $ 50 million in punitive damages. A city attorney, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON>, said he was aware of the lawsuit but had no comment. The paramedics, summoned by an emergency call at 4:16 p.m. Monday, were not aware of the seriousness of the asthma attack when they first arrived at the housing project, the Fire Department says. They left the scene and returned 24 minutes later when police arrived, according to the Fire Department. Police officers said they found the boy in a bedroom in the family's fifth-floor apartment. He was taken to a hospital, where he was pronounced dead. Fire Department employees Tuesday washed the ambulance used by the paramedics, removing any trace of egg that may have been on it, <PERSON> Bledsoe </PERSON> said. `` When we heard about it we got a protective order barring anyone from doing anything to the ambulance until we could inspect it,'' he said The order was issued Wednesday by Cook County Judge <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Foreman </PERSON>. Fire Department spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> said tapes of communications between the paramedics and dispatchers show proof that the ambulance was hit by flying objects. `` At all times paramedics and emergency medical technicians should avoid placing themselves in danger,'' <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> said, reading a city policy. The boy's mother and neighbors insist there was no danger to the paramedics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-ShuttleSleuths Bjt   12-15 0636</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle Sleuths, Bjt,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amateur Astronomers Tracked Atlantis' Spy Satellite Deployment</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SOLL SUSSMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TORONTO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Amateur astronomers using home computers and high-powered binoculars were able to track the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space shuttle <LOCATION> Atlantis </LOCATION> as it deployed a secret spy satellite. `` If we could figure it out, you could bet that the Russians figured it out too,'' says <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON>, a self-described `` space enthusiast'' who helped organize the tracking. Although he said the information gathered had little practical use, the project showed secrecy is a rare commodity in the sky. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said, `` We do n't comment on secret satellite launches.'' <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON>, 35, said in a recent interview that the satellite watchers are hobbyists who work together informally, trading information through telephone calls, letters and electronic mail. The secrecy of the Atlantis' early December mission made their research challenging and intriguing `` detective work,'' <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> said. `` As space enthusiasts, for us to see the space shuttle is a very exciting thing,'' he said, adding that he was thrilled by the rare prospect the shuttle would be visible over Canadian skies. Shuttle orbits generally are farther south. <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> is an engineering technologist who specializes in energy conservation. His interest in space is visible in his sparsely furnished 23rd floor apartment; a computer and charts lie on his desk, books on the subject cram a bookcase and high-power binoculars sit on a stand near the door. The binoculars, said <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON>, are more useful than telescopes for satellite watching because they are easier to point and have a wider field of view. <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> had been in contact with about 150 other satellite watchers from as far away as <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> about the Atlantis' probable orbit. He circulated information including a `` test yourself'' page to make sure all participants could handle the necessary calculations. The <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> skies were cloudy on Dec. 2, the day of the Atlantis' launch, and <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> was unable to see it passing over Others did, and the calls started coming in while the craft was on its sixth orbit in the late afternoon. There were two sightings from the <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION> region and one from <LOCATION> Ashtabula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. `` To get three confirmations like that in the space of half an hour was very exciting,'' <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> said. `` We had more than a dozen people in this area looking for it.'' Knowing the times of the sightings allowed him to calculate the height of the orbit and, with the computer, he quickly was able to determine where the shuttle could be seen for the rest of the mission. <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> said the watchers sighted only the Atlantis on the sixth revolution, and the satellite was sighted by the seventh revolution three miles ahead of it. Continued sightings showed that for two days the shuttle stayed close to the satellite, which was observed to have a reddish color. He said it was very satisfying to determine that the satellite, known as Lacrosse, was deployed on the shuttle's first day in orbit. The news media was speculating that it would be released on the second day. `` The mission went the way we hypothesized it would,'' <PERSON> Molczan </PERSON> said. The industry magazine <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Week </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> reported last week, citing <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> sources, that the $ 500 million radar-imaging satellite's deployment took place on the shuttle's fifth orbit, or about seven hours after it was launched at 9:30 a.m. EST Molzcan suspects the reddish color was from the thermal coverings of the satellite, because gold coverings in the past have been seen as reddish. `` It's sort of fun to speculate,'' he said. `` We'll probably never know, but it added to the whole fun of the exercise.'' His own glimpse did not come until the 37th revolution, about halfway through the four-day mission.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gulf-Italy     12-15 0260</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gulf-Italy,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Last Five Italian Warships Leave Persian Gulf</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD PYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAMA, Bahrain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The last five Italian warships have left the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> in the latest and largest cutback of foreign naval forces following the Iran-Iraq cease-fire, Italian officials say. The frigate Euro, flagship of the Italian flotilla, and the minehunters <PERSON> Castagno </PERSON> and Loto sailed through the Strait of Hormuz at the mouth of the gulf last week, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> said Wednesday. They were bound for home. The frigate Sagittario and the supply tanker <PERSON> Stromboli </PERSON> left Nov. 24 and reached their home port at the <LOCATION> Taranto </LOCATION> naval base in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> on Monday, the ministry said. Italian officials announced the withdrawal in early November, saying the Aug. 20 cease-fire, which halted fighting in the 8-year-old war, had brought a `` consolidation of stability'' to the strategic waterway. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> deployed warships in the gulf after the Italian container ship <PERSON> Jolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubino </PERSON> was attacked by Iranian gunboats while sailing to <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> on Sept. 2, 1987. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> kept up to eight ships in the gulf at once. The <PERSON> Jolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubino </PERSON> was the only Italian-flag vessel among more than 500 ships attacked by both sides during the four-year `` tanker war.'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> regularly intercepted ships suspected of carrying war-related cargoes for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> during the war. The Italian departure reduced the number of foreign warships in or near the gulf to about 50, with half belonging to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. At its peak late last year, the foreign naval force comprised more than 70 ships from seven countries.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Derailment 1stLd-Writethru a0817 12-15 0520</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Derailment, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0817,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Train Derails, Forces Evacuation of 100 Residents</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 6 grafs after 6th graf pvs, `They can't...', to UPDATE
with crews considering transfer of propane, which could take 36
hours, and to move up and update detail on highway, railroad
closing. Picks up 7th graf pvs, `State police...'. DELETES last 3
grafs, now redundant.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>FLAGSTAFF, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two derailed railroad cars leaking highly explosive liquid propane Wednesday forced the evacuation of about 100 residents and closed an interstate highway and rail routes in northern <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. A total of 26 cars derailed early Wednesday about 10 miles east of <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION> after 84 <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> cars somehow became uncoupled during a stop, said a company official. Residents near the derailment were told at about 11 a.m. to plan to spend at least 24 hours away from their homes while authorities tried to defuse the cars leaking liquid propane. `` This has the potential to become a very dangerous situation,'' said <LOCATION> Coconino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON>. He said hazardous-materials teams from the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railroad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> hoped to siphon off the propane through a makeshift rigging of pipes and valves and ignite it in a controlled burn. `` They ca n't offload it, because that would be too dangerous,'' <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said. `` It's too dangerous to move heavy equipment in there because of the potential for an explosion.'' But later in the day, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said that hazardous materials experts were considering an alternate strategy, an intricate process of pumping the propane out of the leaking propane cars with special equipment. The process would take up to 36 hours, he said. If it is used, the propane would be taken by truck and would be reloaded on different tank cars later, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. The experts hoped to decide on a stragegy by early Thursday, he said. The residents evacuated earlier Wednesday would not be allowed to return to their homes until the propane was completely removed. Authorities sealed off both the railroad right-of-way and Interstate 40 over the 58-mile stretch between <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Winslow </LOCATION>. By late evening Wednesday, the road and railroad remained closed. State police helicopters also closed off the airspace over the wreckage, chasing away aircraft carrying photographers. An <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the derailment held up two trains. Two other cars carrying propane, one with a hazardous-cargo label, and 21 others derailed, but they were not leaking. The car with the hazardous-cargo label was believed to be carrying an industrial solvent, and was not considered explosive, officials said. <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fe </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said the train was parked at the <ORGANIZATION> Ralston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Purina </ORGANIZATION> pet-food plant in East Flagstaff to drop off one car when the cars became uncoupled and began rolling east down a slight grade. The runaway reached an estimated 40 mph before the cars derailed on a curve. No one was injured, he said. Investigators began a probe to determine why the train sections became separated, but the cause was not immediately determined, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said. The westbound train originated in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;LCrisis Bjt   12-15 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;L Crisis, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Biggest Pricetag Estimate Yet for Failing S&amp;Ls: $112 Billion</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A congressional study places the largest government estimate yet on the price of bailing out the nation's failing savings and loans, and says the cost could soar even higher unless action is taken quickly The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> says the government should spend $ 112 billion to close failed institutions and abandon its current strategy of trying to keep the institutions alive through assisted mergers. <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>, will need $ 85 billion over and above the $ 27 billion it expects to collect in fees from S & amp; Ls through 1998. However, the congressional auditing and investigative agency warned that the pricetag will be even higher if interest rates rise. Most economists expect rates to climb through the middle of next year, but offer no firm predictions beyond that. The investigative agency, in a draft of a report to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, sharply criticized the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, regulator of the nation's 3,000 <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls, for attempting to rescue failed S & amp; Ls by providing money to private merger partners. The report noted that the insurance fund spends on mergers about 90 percent of what it would cost to simply close insolvent institutions and pay off depositors. However, mergers do not always resolve the problem and, counting tax losses to the government, may well be more costly, it said. `` Regulators and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have resisted massive closings of insolvent savings and loans in the hope that the fortunes of these institutions would reverse themselves,'' it said. `` This hope has proven both futile and costly.'' It noted that industry losses totaled $ 9.4 billion in the first nine months of this year. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said failed S & amp; Ls should be placed into receivership in the next year and most of the $ 112 billion should be spent in the next three years. The bank board has avoided that approach, arguing that massive closings could leave some areas of the nation without service from an S & amp; L and that a flood of repossessed real estate from failed institutions could deepen the regional recession in the <LOCATION> Southwest </LOCATION>. Breaking down the $ 112 billion, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said $ 77 billion will be required to close insolvent _ but still open _ <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls, which numbered 434 at the end of September. Previously, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> and the bank board had estimated that closing insolvent S & amp; Ls would require about $ 50 billion. The new report also cites additional expenses, including $ 10 billion needed to finance borrowing by the <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>, which guarantees S & amp; L deposits up to $ 100,000, and $ 5 billion likely to be required for losses that have occurred but have n't been discovered yet. An additional $ 20 billion should be set aside as a reserve against future losses, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. The thrift industry can contribute $ 5 billion to $ 10 billion, but the rest `` may have to come from the federal government unless others, such as -LRB- commercial -RRB- banks and depositors, are required to share the cost,'' the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said. The report did not specifically recommend a taxpayer bailout, saying only that `` <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must make difficult choices.'' However, it warned that continuing an extra fee charged S & amp; Ls for deposit insurance, over and above what competing commercial banks pay, `` could weaken healthy thrifts and thereby prove self-defeating.'' Separately, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is working on its own recommendation to the incoming <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration sources have said the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> is considering a plan to borrow the money through a newly created agency, keeping most of the spending out of the federal budget deficit. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> recommended `` at this time'' against merging <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which backs deposits in commercial banks. `` <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> strongly advises against further weakening the deposit insurance system through a merger in which <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION>'s reserves and premium income, both of which are needed for bank problems, are simply diverted to cover some of <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>'s losses,'' it said. However, the report said healthy <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls that want to change themselves to commercial banks and join the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> should be allowed provided they pay the appropriate fees to the <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> is circulating its draft report for comments and hopes to issue the final version in January or February. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutions </ORGANIZATION>, an industry trade group, called the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> recommendations `` provocative'' and `` refreshing.'' His group represents many savings institutions which are already members of the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> and others which would be healthy enough to transfer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AerospaceProfits     12-15 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Aerospace Profits,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Aerospace Employment Falls; Flat Sales Predicted into 1990s</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Aerospace employment declined by 21,000 jobs in 1988 as the industry recorded its first annual sales drop in 17 years, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` The reason is a substantial decrease in sales to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION>, hardly a surprise in view of the zero-to-negative-growth defense budgets of the last four fiscal years,'' the association's president, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON>, said Wednesday Overall sales volume was projected to reach $ 111 billion for 1988, a reduction of slightly more than $ 1 billion from last year. `` An analysis of orders on hand indicates a defense sales rebound in 1989 but we look for further substantial declines as we move into the early years of the 1990s,'' <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON> said. The sales projection for next year is for $ 129 billion but `` our real, inflation-adjusted sales curve for the next few years will be relatively flat,'' according to <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON>. Statistics released by the association said the number of jobs in the aerospace industry will drop to 1,307,000 for the year and that there will be 14,000 fewer jobs still in 1989. `` We did not set a new record for sales ... for the first time in 17 years,'' <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON> said. Still, industry profits were expected to improve to $ 5.1 billion, and the backlog of unfilled orders to reach an all-time high of $ 170.3 billion, the association said. An increase in civil aerospace business, <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON> said, will offset the military decline. `` We must face this fact,'' <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON> said at the joint <ORGANIZATION> AIA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Aviation-Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> luncheon. `` The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration and the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must continue to accord top priority to further reduction in the national budget deficit. `` So, barring an unexpected change in the international climate, we must realistically anticipate lower levels of defense appropriations and therefore reduced industry sales of defense equipment.'' <PERSON> Fuqua </PERSON> said <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> industry is severely handicapped in international competition by trade restrictions imposed by its own government. He called the government's role `` purely administrative and often obstructive'' when it should be an active supporter of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> exports. He announced creation of a foundation to be called the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, which will pull together everything being done in technology and create a data base for companies and agencies taking part.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PTLMinistries 2ndLd-Writethru a0848 12-15 0797</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PTL Ministries, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0848,0814</SECOND>
<HEAD>Religious Organization Seeks Part of PTL Assets</HEAD>
<NOTE>Eds: INSERTS 4 grafs after 9th graf pvs, `We want...', to UPDATE
with lawyer for losing bidder saying sale will be contested. Picks
up 10th graf pvs, `Johnson indicated...'.</NOTE>
<BYLINE>By PAUL NOWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> expressed concern Wednesday that his former evangelistic empire would vanish, but officials of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s successor group continued negotiating with their new landlord to salvage some part of the ministry. The fate of the television ministry and church at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, was left up in the air Tuesday when <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON>, a 34-year-old Orthodox Jew, purchased the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> assets for $ 65 million. Since last year, the facilities have been leased to <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit religious group created by the bankruptcy court. In a statement Wednesday, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, accused in a federal indictment with misusing millions of dollars of his followers' money, said he was concerned that <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> would ignore the rights of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s so-called lifetime partners who contributed $ 1,000 or more to the ministry in exchange for free lodging at <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s lavish religious theme park at Fort Mill `` Our hearts are broken over the fighting over <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> that was built to bring people together in God's love,'' <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> and I still have as our goal to restore <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> and all lifetime benefits to the partners who built it.'' But Heritage Ministries President <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who has met with Mernick three times since Monday, said Wednesday that he expects no immediate changes. `` He -LRB- Mernick -RRB- was very conciliatory in his tone,'' said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, who also is pastor of the church. `` The ministry is the heart and soul of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` When you take out the heart, all you have is a cadaver.'' Heritage Ministries officials told viewers of Wednesday's broadcast of `` Heritage Today,'' the successor to the `` <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>,'' they would continue in their effort to buy all the assets of <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> `` We want to be prepared in any event,'' said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, explaining that a number of developments could occur before the deal was final. `` Some assets he -LRB- Mernick -RRB- may not be interested in.'' Meanwhile Wednesday, an attorney for one of the unsuccessful bidders for <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> broadcasting executive <PERSON> Cy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bahakel </PERSON>, said his client will fight the sale in court. `` We are going to contest irregularities in these proceedings, and we are very firm in our intention to do that,'' said the lawyer, <PERSON> Faison </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnes </PERSON>. Tuesday, in bankruptcy court in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> raised his offer to $ 65 million, after being the high bidder at $ 36.25 million at an auction the previous day. <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> then accepted the offer. When <PERSON> Bahakel </PERSON>, who showed up about 25 minutes late, asked to be allowed to bid $ 70 million, <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> turned him down. <PERSON> Bahakel </PERSON>'s lawyer said Wednesday that <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> should not have been allowed to raise his bid <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> indicated that the money the group raised in an unsuccessful telethon effort to buy <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> _ reportedly about $ 5 million _ may be used to buy the assets it needs to maintain the ministry. Mernick would not answer questions Tuesday about the future of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION>, but said he would unveil plans in the next two weeks for <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s assets, which include the satellite network carried on 800 cable systems, 1,700 acres of undeveloped land, a 500-room hotel, a water park, and the 2,000-seat church. When he entered the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> bidding in October, <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> said he was interested in the assets `` purely as a real estate deal.'' The Charlotte Observer, quoting sources close to <LOCATION> Mernick </LOCATION>, said he intends to hold onto the undeveloped land for 10 years as its value rises. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mernick </PERSON> told officials of <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministries </ORGANIZATION> he is interested in maintaining the retreat's atmosphere. `` He's extremely sensitive to the people who have invested,'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> faces a bond hearing Thursday on the indictment issued last week. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Toms </PERSON>, one of the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> founder's attorneys, said he does not expect his client to enter a plea until next month. <PERSON> Toms </PERSON> has said previously that <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> would plead innocent to all charges. A federal grand jury on Dec. 5 indicted <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and his former top deputy at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON>, on 24 counts of wire and mail fraud and conspiracy. The panel has accused <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> of diverting more than $ 4 million in <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> money to support their own `` lavish and extravagant'' lifestyles. Two other former aides, brothers <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, each were indicted on six tax charges. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, 48, resigned as <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> president in March 1987 after it was revealed he had a sexual tryst in 1980 with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and paid her to keep quiet about it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RetreadCabinet Bjt   12-15 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Retread Cabinet, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush Administration Short on New Faces</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who ran for the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> insider, is staffing his administration with just what you'd expect: <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> insiders. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s announcement Wednesday that he is tapping <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration Trade Representative <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> to be his secretary of agriculture is just the latest example. He is retaining <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> as attorney general, <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> as secretary of the treasury, <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> as secretary of education, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> director and <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> as the White House spokesman. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, a longtime <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> associate who served <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as White House chief of staff and secretary of the treasury, will be secretary of state in the new administration. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, an aide to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> at both the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, will head the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>. The national security adviser will be <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, who had the same job in the Ford administration. It is not unheard of for newly elected presidents to pick people with <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> experience to do <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> jobs. But no administration in recent memory has had so many retreads as the one now shaping up. `` I think they are his kind of people,'' said <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ranney </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is an old <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hand and these are the people he feels comfortable with.'' `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s whole argument this fall was ` I'm the insider, I understand how government works, I can handle things,''' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON>, professor of political science and dean of humanities at <ORGANIZATION> Purdue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. That campaign contrasted sharply with those of his two predecessors. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ran as the ultimate <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> outsider, often telling audiences that government, far from being the solution to their problems, was part of the problem. Even <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> picked some veterans of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> scene. His first secretary of defense, for instance, was fellow <PERSON> Californian </PERSON> <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, who had been budget director and secretary of health, education and welfare in the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> administration. Most of his initial choices, however, were people like <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, picked to be treasury secretary after a career on Wall Street, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who jumped from a seat on the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> to the No. 2 job in the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> governor and peanut farmer, also took pride in his status as a stranger to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> scene. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Jordan </PERSON> said before the election: `` If, after the inauguration, you find a <PERSON> Cy </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON> as secretary of state and <PERSON> Zbigniew </PERSON> <PERSON> Brzezinski </PERSON> as head of national security, then I would say we failed. And I'd quit. But that's not going to happen.'' It did happen, and he did n't quit. But <PERSON> Vance </PERSON>, a former secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and deputy secretary of defense, and <PERSON> Brzezinski </PERSON>, an academic with strong ties to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> foreign policy establishment, were also exceptions. More typical of <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>'s choices was <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lance </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> banker he chose to head the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> all had their troubles in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Regan </PERSON>, the former Wall Street executive, was fired as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s chief of staff after a presidential board blamed him for many of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s troubles in the Iran-Contra affair <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> judge, was ridiculed after he was unable, in his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation hearings, to name the prime minister of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> or express a view on nuclear nonproliferation, foreign aid or <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations with Third World countries. He was confirmed anyway and satisfied <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> well enough that the president later made him national security adviser and then secretary of the interior. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> left the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration under a cloud of alleged past banking irregularities, then was acquitted of those charges by a federal grand jury. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> were past associates in state government of the former governors who appointed them _ people they knew and trusted. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s background for the past 20 years has been in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> orbit, as a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, Republican national chairman, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representative in Peking, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and vice president. He, too, however, apparently wants some familiar faces around him. `` Many of the people he knows well personally and he probably implicitly trusts them,'' said political scientist <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON>. `` He does n't want high risk.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-PLOPolicy Bjt   12-15 0619</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-PLO Policy, Bjt,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>PLO Decision Raises Problems for Israel, Questions About Bush</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sudden <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to deal with the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> raises tough political problems for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and suggests disarray within the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration in its final weeks. Even while Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and other senior officials were making preparations at the White House for Wednesday's historic announcement, President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was criticizing the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> for failing to meet <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions for a dialogue. Speaking at the Executive Office Building just across the street, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vowed to continue the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's tough stand against <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s organization. He demanded `` a clear and unambiguous statement'' explicitly recognizing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, renouncing terrorism and accepting two major <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolutions on the right of all states to live within secure boundaries. `` Before we have a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> the signals have to be clear, unmistakable, unambiguous,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, biting off each word with decisive crispness. Simultaneously, however, <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> was giving a news conference in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> that <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> seized on as evidence that the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman had come around to accepting the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions. The result was announcements by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and by <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> that there would be a `` substantive dialogue'' with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION> _ leaving <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> looking like the odd man out. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON>, meanwhile, did not explain later at a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> news conference how what <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> said on Wednesday had differed from what the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader had said a day earlier. The day-earlier comments had been declared unacceptable. Having denied <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> a visa less than three weeks earlier, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> suddenly was approving direct dealings with a man he had denounced as an `` accessory'' in acts of terrorism against Israelis and Americans. Asked what was different about <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s most recent statement, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said cryptically: `` It was clear. It was not encumbered.'' The decision was in a long <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> tradition of policy shifts that always are defended as not policy shifts at all. It clearly backs <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> into a corner, now standing alone in shunning the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said he would not presume to advise another country what it ought to do. `` It's totally for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to make its own decisions about what it wants to do, and there's nothing to be inferred judgmentally about what they should do,'' he said. The choice <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> faces is to watch the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, its closest friend, make arrangements for <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and not participate, or to agree to attend a peace conference with the participation of the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> now a virtual certainty. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> could come under pressure, too _ from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to make good on <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s declaration renouncing terrorism in all forms. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, undoubtedly, will be asked by reporters in the next few days why he seemed so out of step with what was brewing within the White House. In a way, though, he may benefit from the decision taken by the outgoing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Any political storm caused by embracing the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> will not fall on him. It's a decision that may have been inevitable, and one he now will not have to make. But he may have to make one just as tough _ whether to support a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> said he was not endorsing statehood for the Palestinians by approving the dialogue. And yet, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s demand for a state carved out of Israeli-held territory will be bolstered by its entry into <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s diplomatic community.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON>, who heads the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> staff, have covered <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomacy on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> for 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-15 1003</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1042</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Commercial filming has been banned during the winter season in this exclusive community after some residents complained that filming might encourage `` some kook'' to commit a `` dastardly act.'' But the Town Council made an exception for <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> native who married actress <PERSON> Loni </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> here and lives in nearby <LOCATION> Jupiter </LOCATION>. The actor has been filming a detective series for <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> called `` B.L. Stryker'' since early last month. His filming application for the next three months was approved Tuesday. Later, the council approved an ordinance that bans filming between Nov. 15 and April 15. At other times, it will prohibit filming near the police station or any other government building and restrict filming to streets wider than 30 feet. Some residents had asked the council for a complete ban. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Grace </PERSON>, who served on the council from 1970-84, said filming in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> might encourage `` some kook or criminal to come over here and do some dastardly act.'' `` I do n't think this town should be a movie set for <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> or anyone else,'' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON> told the council. `` It's going to attract the kind of people we do n't want here, people who are not going to spend any money here because, number one, they probably do n't have any money. We're going to get a lot of Budweisers, cutoffs and yobbos -LRB- hoodlums -RRB-.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FIGUERAS, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An ambulance took surrealist painter <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Dali </PERSON> back home after 16 days of hospital treatment for heart and respiratory problems, <ORGANIZATION> Spanish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> reported. Quiron Clinic spokeswoman <PERSON> Cristina </PERSON> <PERSON> Bas </PERSON> said <PERSON> Dali </PERSON>'s release Wednesday was authorized by doctors that cared for him after he was taken to the <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION> clinic Nov. 28. He was stricken by what doctors described as heart failure aggravated by blood clots in his lungs. The 84-year-old artist had been admitted to a hospital in his hometown of <PERSON> Figueras </PERSON>, 60 miles north of <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION>, the day before for treatment for pneumonia. After several days in critical condition, <PERSON> Dali </PERSON> was moved from the clinic's intensive care unit Dec. 5. On Friday, doctors said his vital signs had stabilized at the same levels as before he was stricken.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ma </PERSON> <PERSON> Anand </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheela </PERSON>, former secretary of Indian guru <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shree </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajneesh </PERSON>, said she arrived here with no money after leaving the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> owing more than $ 269,000. The Indian-born <PERSON> Sheela </PERSON>, 39, flew into <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> after serving 2 -LCB- years of a 4 -LCB- - year sentence for attempted murder, wiretapping and other convictions She won early release from prison Tuesday and was deported after pledging not to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for five years. `` I have no money,'' <PERSON> Sheela </PERSON> told reporters after arriving with no luggage Wednesday. <PERSON> Sheela </PERSON> said she will go back to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> but did n't think she would see the guru, who is at a commune there. She then left for the southern West German spa town of <LOCATION> Baden-Baden </LOCATION>, accompanied by her German lawyer. <PERSON> Sheela </PERSON> was a prime force in the <PERSON> Bhagwan </PERSON>'s commune in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> that was started in 1981 but collapsed after he was convicted of immigration fraud and deported in 1985. Authorities in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> complained she left behind more than $ 269,000 in unpaid fines and restitution. `` It's a heck of a lot harder to collect money from someone in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> or wherever she is than if she's in prison in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Marla </PERSON> <PERSON> Rae </PERSON>, spokeswoman for state Attorney General <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Frohnmayer </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Versions of the following moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> has a dilemma: Should he cut short his Gator Bowl partying in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> to hop on a plane for the Rose Bowl? <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>'s alma mater, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> State, faces <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> in the Jan. 1 <LOCATION> Gator </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bowl </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>. The next day, the <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wolverines </ORGANIZATION> take on the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> in the Rose Bowl in <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>. `` I would have to spend all of my time in motion,'' <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said Wednesday. `` I'm superstitious about sports and I'd feel bad if I was n't there because I've never seen my team lose in the Rose Bowl,'' he said `` If I'm there physically I'll feel a little bit better.'' <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> said he could end up watching the Rose Bowl on television. `` I just want my <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> friends to know when they're in the Rose Bowl, I'm rooting for them. When they're playing the <ORGANIZATION> Spartans </ORGANIZATION>, I'm not.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rocket </ORGANIZATION>'s center <PERSON> Akeem </PERSON> <PERSON> Olajuwon </PERSON> has been sued by a TV news cameraman for unspecified damages for injuries he allegedly received in a scuffle outside the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> star's home. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> KHOU-TV </ORGANIZATION> said in the lawsuit he suffered mental and physical harm from the Aug. 30 struggle, during which <PERSON> Olajuwon </PERSON> allegedly grabbed a camera from him. <PERSON> Shipley </PERSON>, who filed the lawsuit Tuesday in state district court, went to <PERSON> Olajuwon </PERSON>'s home with a reporter to discuss a lawsuit involving a former companion of <PERSON> Olajuwon </PERSON> who claimed the player broke a contract to marry her. `` Let him sue,'' <PERSON> Olajuwon </PERSON> said from his hotel room in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, where the <ORGANIZATION> Rockets </ORGANIZATION> played the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuggets </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. `` It's not important.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BUFFALO, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bills </ORGANIZATION> quarterback <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> was served with a $ 1 million lawsuit from a woman who says he assaulted her in a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seneca </LOCATION> restaurant a year ago, according to <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>'s attorney <PERSON> Eugenia </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON>, 24, said she suffered neck injuries when the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> star threw her to the floor Dec. 20, 1987. In her lawsuit filed Wednesday, she also said <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> manhandled her after she criticized his recent play. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tobia </PERSON>, said Miss <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON> deliberately started an altercation while <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> was dining with his parents and other guests and was thrown out of the restaurant after she allegedly poured a drink over <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>'s head without provocation. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> says he merely grabbed Miss <PERSON> Lyons </PERSON>' hand and said, `` Are you crazy?'' after she doused him, <PERSON> Tobia </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP881215-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-88 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Shultz-Text     12-15 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Shultz-Text,700-Up</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-US-Arafat Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Text of Shultz Statement on PLO</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
