<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-HongKong-Stocks     06-06 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hong Kong-Stocks,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shares Open Firm, Trading Active</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Share prices opened firmer Wednesday on reports that Chinese troops responsible for the slaughter of pro-democracy demonstrators were leaving <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Brokers said trading was active, but investors remained cautious awaiting further developments. The Hang Seng Index of blue chips, which plummeted on Monday to its worst loss since the worldwide market collapse in 1987, gained about 140 points to 2,289 within the first hour of trading. Before the morning session, members of the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> stood for three minutes of silence tribute to victims of the military attack Sunday, in which hundreds and perhaps thousands were killed. On Monday, the index closed at 2,093.61 points, down 581.77 points from Friday. The drop was the worst since the 1987 international market collapse, when the index fell 1,120.99 points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     06-06 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0615</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Indiana Jones' Continues to Smash Box-Office Records</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hulk </PERSON> <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> may be unbeatable in the wrestling ring, but he's clearly no match for <PERSON> Indiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>'s new movie `` No Holds Barred'' was body slammed by `` <PERSON> Indiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' which continued to break box-office records by collecting another $ 21.2 million at the nation's theaters over the weekend. According to figures released Monday by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, `` No Holds Barred'' gathered $ 5 million in its first weekend of release. `` The Last Crusade,'' which set four major box-office marks in its first week of release, broke two more records in its second week and took in as much as the next six most popular movies combined. The film, in which <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> as the dauntless archaeologist joins his father -LRB- <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> -RRB- to save the Holy Grail from the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION>, set new records for the best 12 days and best second weekend in movie history. It could pass the $ 100 million mark next weekend and shatter yet another record. `` No Holds Barred,'' a new action-adventure film featuring wrestler <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON>, debuted in second place. `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' a crime comedy with <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, landed in third on ticket sales of $ 4.1 million. In fourth was the <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> baseball movie `` Field of Dreams'' on gross of $ 3.7 million. It was followed by `` Renegades,'' starring <PERSON> Kiefer </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutherland </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, opening in fifth with $ 3.1 million. `` Road House,'' featuring <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> as a bar bouncer, placed sixth with $ 3 million. Continuing its sluggish pace, <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON>'s `` Pink Cadillac'' collected only $ 2.5 million to land in seventh place. `` K-9,'' starring <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Belushi </PERSON> and a dog as a police team, finished in eighth with $ 1.8 million. Rounding out the Top 10 were `` Pet Sematary,'' in ninth on gross of $ 1.7 million, and `` Major League,'' in 10th with $ 963,636. `` Rain Man,'' a Top 10 movie for all of 1989, finally fell off the leader board. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' `` Dead Poets Society,'' playing on only eight screens, collected a lively $ 340,456. Its per screen average _ $ 42,557 _ was the third best in the history of limited releases, in which a movie opens in just a handful of theaters. The only films to surpass `` Dead Poets Society'' in a limited release opening were `` Good Morning, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'' and `` The Last Temptation of Christ.'' Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade,'' Paramount, $ 21.2 million, 2,327 screens, $ 9,123 per screen, $ 77.1 million, two weeks. 2. `` No Holds Barred,'' New Line, $ 5 million, 1,318 screens, $ 3,761 per screen, $ 5 million, one week. 3. `` See No Evil, Hear No Evil,'' Tri-Star, $ 4.1 million, 1,680 screens, $ 2,415 per screen, $ 28.9 million, four weeks. 4. `` Field of Dreams,'' Universal, $ 3.7 million, 1,100 screens, $ 3,400 per screen, $ 35.6 million, seven weeks. 5. `` Renegades,'' Universal, $ 3.1 million, 1,627 screens, $ 1,890 per screen, $ 3.1 million, one week. 6. `` Road House,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3 million, 1,880 screens, $ 1,599 per screen, $ 17.5 million, three weeks. 7. `` Pink Cadillac,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.5 million, 1,993 screens, $ 1,250 per screen, $ 7.8 million, two weeks. 8. `` K-9,'' Universal, $ 1.8 million, 1,307 screens, $ 1,410 per screen, $ 33 million, six weeks. 9. `` Pet Sematary,'' Paramount, $ 1.7 million, 1,248 screens, $ 1,370 per screen, $ 48.4 million, seven weeks. 10. `` Major League,'' Paramount, $ 963,636 million, 960 screens, $ 1,003 per screen, $ 45 million, nine weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BloodTest     06-06 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blood Test,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blood Test May Indicate Death Risk in High Blood Pressure, Study
Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A standard test of kidney functioning may signal a higher risk of dying within eight years in people with high blood pressure, including death from heart attack or stroke, a new study suggests. The blood test is for a muscle byproduct called creatinine, and it is not clear why the substance would have anything to do with heart attack or stroke, said study co-author <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON>. But he said his work suggests that people with high creatinine levels and high blood pressure should pay extra attention to reducing smoking, cutting cholesterol and taking other steps to reduce their risk of heart attack and stroke. `` It's sort of like a flashing light saying, ` I'm in a high-risk group, I better pay attention,''' he said Monday in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON>, associate professor of medicine at <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medicine </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, and colleagues from several medical schools present the work in the May issue of the journal Hypertension. The study included 10,768 people with high blood pressure. It found that those with high levels of creatinine in their blood showed higher death rates from heart attack and stroke, as well as kidney disease, researchers said. Creatinine is a waste product produced by muscle tissue. Kidneys normally remove it from blood, so high levels of creatinine remaining in the blood can signal kidney trouble. A normal creatinine reading is usually considered to be 0.7 to 1.5 milligrams per deciliter, <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> said. The new study found that people with a reading of 1.7 or higher showed more than three times the mortality from any cause within eight years than other people did. Death rates rose with rising creatinine levels, starting with as low as 0.8 to 0.99, but with a marked jump at 1.5, <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> said. About 23 percent of study subjects who showed creatinine levels of 1.5 to 1.69 were dead within eight years, rising to nearly 30 percent for those with levels between 1.7 and 1.99, <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> said. Still higher creatinine levels were associated with death rates of about 40 percent and more than 50 percent. In contrast, people with levels of 0.7 to 1.09 showed death rates only around 10 percent, he said. In a separate analysis that took into account differences in age and other risk factors among the different groups, creatinine levels remained a potent predictor of death within eight years, <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CountryAwards 2ndLd-Writethru a0779 06-06 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Country Awards, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0779,0599</SECOND>
<HEAD>Randy Travis, Ricky Van Shelton Win Top Country Music Honors</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with other winners, quotes. No pickup. ^LaserPhoto
covering</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE EDWARDS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former pipe fitter <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> won four honors and <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> was chosen entertainer of the year Monday night at the 23rd annual Music City News Country Awards. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, appearing on videotape, joined in saluting veteran entertainer <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON>, who was selected by country music fans for the Living Legend Award. `` Your songs have helped reawaken patriotism in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' the president said during the live telecast to a syndicated audience. `` In every sense of the word, you are a true living legend.'' Cash, who spoke by satellite from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, said, `` It's a very humbling experience to receive an award like this.'' <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> was chosen top male vocalist over competitors <PERSON> Vern </PERSON> <PERSON> Gosdin </PERSON>, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Strait </PERSON>, <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Yoakam </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>. He also won single of the year and favorite music video, both for `` I'll Leave This World Loving You,'' and best album for `` Loving Proof.'' `` I'm very honored by all the people who voted for me and who love country music,'' <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> said in accepting his award as best male singer. <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> worked as a pipe fitter for 10 years before leaving the mountains around Grit, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, in 1984 to pursue his musical dreams. Wearing a trademark white cowboy hat, he began visiting <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> nightclubs to meet people in the music business and, during a performance one night, was spotted by a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> executive who signed him to a recording contract. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> had won nothing until the final category of the evening was announced at the Grand Ole Opry House. He won over fellow nominees <PERSON> Reba </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Statler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>. `` I was beginning to get worried,'' <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> said. `` I try my best to represent country music in a good way.'' For the fifth straight time, Miss <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON> was voted female vocalist of the year over nominees <PERSON> Rosanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Cash </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>, K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tanya </PERSON> <PERSON> Tucker </PERSON>. `` If I've said it once, I've said it a thousand times; no one is as lucky as country music performers to have country music fans,'' she said. <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Loveless </PERSON> was voted star of tomorrow, outpolling three others, including the late <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>. In her acceptance remarks, she paid tribute to <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON>, who died of an alcohol overdose May 9. `` <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitley </PERSON> lives on with his music as far as I'm concerned,'' she said The Statler Brothers were voted group of the year for the sixth straight time, raising their total number of awards in that category to 39. Other winners were: <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, comedian of the year; <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> instrumentalist of the year; the <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION>, vocal duo of the year; the Whites, gospel group of the year; the <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> Now,'' TV series `` A Country Music Celebration: 30th Anniversary of the <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>,'' as best TV special; and <PERSON> Yoakam </PERSON> and <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, vocal collaboration -LRB- two or more performers -RRB- Voting on the winners was done by subscribers of <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, a magazine published in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, and the deadline for receiving the ballots was May 1. The awards show, which was hosted by the <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON> sisters, was one of many special country music events this week in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> for the 18th annual Fan Fair celebration. Approximately 23,000 country music fans from around the world attend the festivities and 4,400 turned out for the nationally televised awards show.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BBC-China     06-06 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--BBC-China,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>BBC Increases Broadcasts to China</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The British <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. World Service today added 30 minutes to its daily Chinese service That will be in addition to the normal 2 -LCB- hours of evening broadcasts in Mandarin, the main <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> dialect, the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> said. Student demonstrators reportedly have been playing tapes of <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> news reports over loudspeakers. `` In recent weeks we have had evidence from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> of a dramatic increase in awareness of our broadcasts,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Udell </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>'s controller of overseas services `` This extra time on air will enable us to cover world news even more extensively _ including both the latest events in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> itself and international reaction to them.'' Chinese troops trying to end a seven-week student protest fired on unarmed civilians in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> over the weekend, and the firing has continued. Hundreds, perhaps thousands, have been killed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0020EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-HongKong 1stLd-Writethru   06-06 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Hong Kong, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0682,0641</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hong Kong Share Prices Plummet, Protesters March</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with Tuesday figures. Pick up
12th pvs, `In nearby...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HK2</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONG KONG (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Share prices opened lower Tuesday in nervous reaction to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s military crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrators, and thousands of residents staged funeral processions for slain protesters. The developments in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have focused new public attention on the accord under which the British colony will revert to Chinese rule in 1997. Officials reported a run on some China-owned banks Monday in withdrawals aimed at protesting the Chinese military's killings of hundreds and perhaps thousands of unarmed protesters in efforts to quell a popular uprising in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Thousands of angry <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> residents gathered outside the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the mainland government's de facto embassy in the territory. Governor Sir <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> also met <PERSON> Xu </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiatun </PERSON>, head of the agency, to express his concern over the brutal force used, the government reported without giving details. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> originally was to leave Monday for <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to discuss <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s future with members of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. He delayed his departure to Wednesday because of the developments in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, some lawmakers called for a reconsideration of the agreement. But British Foreign Secretary <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> reaffirmed <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s agreement to the accord. Under a Chinese-British agreement signed in 1984, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has said the territory can maintain its capitalistic lifestyle under a `` one country, two systems'' concept run by <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> people without <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> interference. <PERSON> Ming </PERSON> <PERSON> Pao </PERSON>, a Chinese-language daily respected for its <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> coverage, said a young guard fired four shots at Chinese Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> in the Great Hall of the People on Sunday and the premier was hit in the thigh. He was not seriously injured, and the guard was killed, the newspaper reported. The Hang Seng Index of blue chips, which plummeted on Monday to its worst loss since the worldwide market collapse in 1987, fell about 70 points shortly after the market opened Tuesday, but rebounded within an hour to 2,075 points. On Monday, the index closed at 2,093.61 points, down 581.77 points from Friday. The drop was the worst since the 1987 international market collapse, when the index fell 1,120.99 points. In nearby <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, the weighted stock market index dropped 455.44 points to close at 9,120.54, the largest single-day loss in the market's 27-year history. Real estate specialists in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> said property values could fall 15 to 20 percent unless the Chinese situation stabilizes. `` This is the worst scenario come to pass,'' said real estate executive <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Varty </PERSON>. `` Over the past few weeks everyone has been looking at how this matter will be played out, and this bloodshed is the worst possible way.'' Monetary Affairs Secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Nendick </PERSON> urged investors to remain calm and cautioned a run on mainland banks could reflect adversely on the territory's status as the world's third financial center after <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Some banks said their rate of withdrawal was 30 percent higher than usual, but no figures were available. `` I think they have gone mad,'' said <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, an outspoken member of the <ORGANIZATION> Legislative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. `` I believe it -LRB- the military crackdown -RRB- is the work by a group of very old men who want to cling to their power and are prepared to sacrifice thousands and millions of lives.'' Protesters continued the rallies held daily to support the democracy movement since martial law was imposed May 20. On Monday, about 3,000 Catholics and Protestants marched past the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> office in a funeral procession for the dead. About 98 percent of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s population of 5.7 million are Chinese, and two-thirds are refugees from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> or their descendants.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Storm     06-06 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Storm,0157</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Dot Hits Central Philippines</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical storm Dot hit the central <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> today with heavy rain and 47 mph winds, officials said. There were no immediate reports of damage or casualties. Chief weather forecaster <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Parong </PERSON> said the center of the storm came ashore at the southern tip of <LOCATION> Samar </LOCATION> island, about 410 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The storm was moving west northwest at 14 mph, he said. A weather bulletin said the storm, the third to hit the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> this year, dumped rain over a wide area stretching from <LOCATION> Bataan </LOCATION> province west of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> across <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> to northern <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION>. The coast guard said it prevented ships from leaving various ports. There were no reports of damage or casualties from <LOCATION> Samar </LOCATION> or the neighboring island of <LOCATION> Leyte </LOCATION>, which also lay in the storm's path. Such reports take days to reach the capital because of poor communications.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Walesa     06-06 0750</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walesa,0777</SECOND>
<HEAD>Walesa Sends Letter to Bush, Emphasizes Coming Challenges</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt ^An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GDANSK, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As the scope of Solidarity's massive election victory became clear, <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> sent some advice to his friend President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>: keep promoting investment in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Then, the shipyard electrician who rallied a restless people to challenge the Communist system got into his blue <ORGANIZATION> Volkswagen </ORGANIZATION> van on Monday afternoon and drove off down the streets of this proud port city. International labor hero <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> still retains a host of folksy touches nearly nine years after strikes at the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> that spawned Solidarity catapulted him to fame and a Nobel Peace prize. He walked with wife, <PERSON> Danuta </PERSON>, and 19-year-old son, <PERSON> Bogdan </PERSON>, to cast his ballot at city polling station No. 169 in Sunday's historic elections A young woman outside the polling station gave him a red rose and praised his tireless efforts. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> replied with a smile: `` Well, I did n't do all this just for myself.'' Like many busy men wrapped up in their work, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> has trouble taking time off. `` We hope you can go on vacation. You deserve it,'' the Rev. <PERSON> Henryk </PERSON> <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON>, a close adviser, told him as 3,000 people cheered outside <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brygida </LOCATION>'s church. `` We hope you can go to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' Only half of <PERSON> Jankowski </PERSON>'s wish is officially scheduled now: <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is heading to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> this fall for a speech to the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> and most likely another meeting with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. In fact, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is heading over to the <LOCATION> Walesas </LOCATION>' for lunch next month. There, the president will sit down to a traditional Polish meal with the 45-year-old <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, his wife and at least some of the couple's eight children in a pleasant residential area outside central <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>. `` This is a rehearsal for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s visit,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said with a hearty laugh as he acted as host at a private party on election eve at his single-family home on 54 Polanki Street. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will sit at a plain wooden table, surrounded by paintings of nature scenes and religious motifs. When <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> shows <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> into the living room, the president will see a picture of Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> on the wall. `` My highest authority'' is the way <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Catholic </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> refers to his Polish-born hero and mentor in the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> met when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as vice president visited <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> in 1987. A photograph of the two conferring adorns the wall outside <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s office in the gritty local headquarters of Solidarity two blocks from the shipyard. Like any folk hero, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> has his trademarks _ the handle-bar mustache, the Solidarity badge, the <PERSON> Black </PERSON> <PERSON> Madonna </PERSON> of Czestochowa pin on his lapel. Less well-known is his bluntness. On Monday, the labor federation leader, wearing a blue sportcoat, bulldozed through reporters seeking a statement from him on election results. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said the voting shows Poles want `` very big reforms'' but also cautioned `` we have to keep searching further'' to solve the nation's woes. Then he bounded up the steps back into the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brygida </LOCATION>'s rectory to cap a victory he has been seeking along with his larger successes: assuring the future of the <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION>. In what he called an act of providence, Polish-born American multimillionaire <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Piasecka-Johnson </PERSON> stepped in with a promise of a huge investment to rescue the ailing yard from a government-ordered shutdown. After lunch with Mrs. <PERSON> Piasecka-Johnson </PERSON>, her advisers and members of the Communist-picked shipyard management Monday, <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> used the occasion to promote the next phase of his cause: reform of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s faltering and often chaotic economy `` All our political victories will mean nothing if we do n't improve the economy,'' said <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> faces constant shortages of consumer goods, spare parts and food items. Many Poles disillusioned with the country's plight seek work in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and elsewhere. To ease the situation, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> has been seeking to attract foreign investment. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration recently began leading the cheers for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s success in that area. `` What Mrs. <PERSON> Piasecka-Johnson </PERSON> is doing is a continuation of what President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has already told us,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said in reference to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration support for Polish economic reforms. `` She is fulfilling it immediately.'' `` So I am sending a personal letter through her to the president in which I thank him for wanting to meet <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> halfway,'' <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> then handed Mrs. <PERSON> Piasecka-Johnson </PERSON> a plain white envelope containing the letter for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, as news photographers' cameras clicked and TV cameras whirred.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-VeteransHospitals     06-06 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Veterans Hospitals,000</SECOND>
<HEAD>GAO Clears VA Official, Agency Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that the chief medical officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> did not try to improperly dictate the outcome of a study of death rates in VA hospitals, an agency spokesman said Monday night. However, the study does conclude that expressions of concern by Dr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gronvall </PERSON> over the impact of such a study on the VA image `` led some people to believe'' he was giving such instructions, said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>, successor to the VA.. Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, asked for the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> investigation after <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported last October that <PERSON> Gronvall </PERSON> had ordered a change in methodology to lower the percentage of VA hospitals showing abnormal death The newspaper reported results of the study in Tuesday editions. The telephone number listed for the author of the study was answered by someone who said he no longer lives there. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said he had seen a copy of the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report earlier in the day. <PERSON> Gronvall </PERSON> was traveling and could not be reached, but judging by his letter to <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> contained in the report commenting in the findings, `` I think he feels somewhat vindicated,'' said <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. The dispute arose when another VA staff member, the late Dr. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, argued in memos that chaging the study methods could be seen as `` self serving.'' The issue is what statistical cut-off to use in judging whether death rates are within the normal range of variation. Only six of the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s 172 hospitals _ 3.5 percent _ would be judged to have abnormal death rates if the analyst wants to be 99 percent sure that the determination is not the result of normal fluctations. But if the analyst wants to be 95 percent sure, 12 hospitals or 7 percent would be judged to have abnormal death rates. VA began the study after the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Financing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> found that 2.5 percent of the nation's private hospitals had abnormally high death rates. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> and the financing agency kept records differently and the percentages arrived at by the two studies could not be compared. The Veterans Department plans to release its study next week using both statistical cutoffs, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PipelineExplosion     06-06 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pipeline Explosion,0503</SECOND>
<HEAD>Railroad, Pipeline Company Agree on Community Reparations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A railroad and a fuel-shipping company announced plans Monday to reimburse residents of a neighborhood stricken by twin disasters last month. The deal outlines community reparations, promises $ 5,000 for each family evacuated, assures residents that the site is safe and calls for a study of utilities in the area. For the <ORGANIZATION> Calnev </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the agreement cleared city objections to plans to replace its 14-inch diameter petroleum fuel line, which exploded in a deadly fireball on May 25, about two weeks after a <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> train derailed on May 12. Four people, including two residents were killed in the derailment, and two residents were killed in the pipeline explosion. Dozens more were injured in the explosion. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> investigators have focused on the possibility that the out-of-control freight damaged the nearby pipeline as it vaulted from the tracks. The plan was announced jointly by city officials, executives of <LOCATION> Calnev </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>. ` No court would have ordered them to do what they've agreed to do today,'' City Attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said. `` The question now is whether this is going to be finalized.'' One of the things city officials had sought was immediate assistance for displaced families, and <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said, `` that $ 5,000 reimbursement really helps.'' The $ 5,000 is to be paid to each family that returns to their home. Calnev officials said the payments, estimated to total about $ 750,000, would begin Wednesday. `` What the agreement is today is a first crack at getting started,'' said <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrukaitis </PERSON>, vice president of <ORGANIZATION> GATX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Terminals </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON>'s corporate owner. `` It is nowhere near a comprehensive settlement.'' The companies tentatively agreed to reimburse the city for overtime paid for police, fire and other emergency personnel, continue to pay for housing and meals for displaced families and to buy the homes that were destroyed or severely damaged. The new pipeline will buried at least six feet deep, twice the federal standard and covered with concrete for 600 feet, the length of the rail disaster area, <PERSON> Andrukaitis </PERSON> said. `` If we can get the new line in by Wednesday, we'd test it Thursday and possibly be operating by Friday,'' <PERSON> Andrukaitis </PERSON> said. Mayor <PERSON> W.R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holcomb </PERSON> said Monday that 95 homes out of the 178 that were evacuated would be immediately reopened for residents' return. `` All the environmental and safety experts agree on the safety and integrity of the area,'' <PERSON> Holcomb </PERSON> said. The city attorney emphasized <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON>'s support for a federal study of the placement of gasoline, natural gas pipelines and other vital utilities in the greater <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> area. If the study recommends moving the <LOCATION> Calnev </LOCATION> fuel line, the company has agreed to do it, <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said. The proposed engineering study would examine the sort of juxtaposition that apparently played a role in the double disasters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-S&amp;Ls 2ndLd-Writethru a0423 06-06 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-S&amp;Ls, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0423,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>EDs: Subs 14th graf to CORRECT time element, Tuesday sted Monday;
pick up 15th graf: Supervisory goodwill ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House members have flooded the Rules Committee with more than 100 proposed amendments to savings and loan bailout legislation, dimming the chances of floor action this week. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, which announced its <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L proposal on Feb. 6 and challenged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to act within 45 days, has shown increasing impatience with the pace of action in the House. The Rules Committee, chaired by Rep. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, the ranking Democrat after the death last week of former chairman <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>, is scheduled to consider the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L legislation on Tuesday. It will decide which amendments will be considered by the full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> when it takes up <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L legislation written by the Banking, Judiciary and Ways and Means panels. House Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., told <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON> last week that he wants the Rules panel to finish work Tuesday so the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> can take up the bill on Wednesday However, nearly 50 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members have asked to speak to the Rules Committee and the panel must wade through more than 109 amendments, a difficult task to achieve in one day. If the <ORGANIZATION> Rules </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> finished work Wednesday, the full <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> could begin debate on Thursday, but, since the chamber is out of session on Friday, any vote likely would be delayed until next week. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed this thing on April 19 and the losses -LRB- in S & amp; Ls -RRB- have grown by over $ 500 million since that date,'' said Assistant Treasury Secretary <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON>. The industry `` is just hemorrhaging out there and every day they delay passage costs at least $ 10 million,'' he said. More than half a dozen of the amendments under consideration would weaken what the administration considers the key change in the bill _ a requirement that <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L owners invest at least $ 3 in tangible or `` real money'' capital for every $ 100 in lending. A high capital level acts as a buffer, absorbing losses before federal deposit insurance kicks in. Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, D-Ill., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> on Financial Institutions, had planned to offer an amendment that would allow regulators, at their discretion, to count `` supervisory goodwill'' as tangible capital, but pulled back after the administration decided to oppose it The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in Tuesday editions that Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Tenn </LOCATION>., planned to urge the Rules Committee to allow the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to vote on an amendment that would weaken restrictions on counting goodwill as tangible capital It said the measure would benefit several hundred S & amp; Ls, including <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Kingsport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON> has at least $ 200,000 on deposit. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON>, chief executive of the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L, was quoted by the newspaper as saying that without the amendment the institution would have to come up with cash to replace $ 28 million in goodwill it currently counts as capital. <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> was quoted as saying he asked <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON> to sponsor the measure. <PERSON> Kirk </PERSON> said the amendment's effect on <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON> would be minimal, perhaps $ 250, and added: `` If you try to pin a conflict on him it would be criminal. It would be low down.'' <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON> was quoted as saying: `` In my mind, there is no conflict'' of interest. Efforts to reach him by telephone Monday night were unsuccessful. Supervisory goodwill is an accounting break offered by regulators in the early 1980s to institutions that took ailing S & amp; Ls off the government's hands. <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON> argues that it is unfair to penalize S & amp; Ls who took the accounting break at the government's urging. However, the administration argues that it is unfair to taxpayers to allow the institutions with supervisory goodwill to operate with none of their owners' money at risk. <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members from <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, including Republican Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, met with <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> officials last Thursday in attempt to secure the administration's support for their compromise amendment However, <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON> said the proposal `` is simply not acceptable to us.'' As an alternate, <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON> will back an amendment by Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ill </LOCATION>., that would permit institutions with goodwill to use administrative appeals to delay the imposition of tougher capital rules for up to 18 months Other amendments before the Rules Committee would, if permitted to reach the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor, reopen virtually every major battle already fought in the committees that wrote the bill. Several amendments would delete provisions designed to help provide housing to poor people. Others would weaken the requirement that the S & amp; L industry contribute $ 300 million a year to pay interest on government bailout borrowing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 4thLd-Writethru   06-06 0990</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0783,1020</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunfire Spreads, Reports of Military Infighting</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: SUBS grafs 7-8, `A Hong...to death' with one graf to attribute
directly to paper. Pick up 9th pvs, `By late...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserColor BEJ15, LaserPhotos BEJ12, NY28</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunfire spread around the capital Tuesday morning, and sources said an army corps opposed to the government's assault on pro-reform demonstrators was preparing to attack the corps that carried out the crackdown Soldiers were fighting soldiers around <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> and in southwestern <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, the sources said on condition of anonymity. A Chinese source reported seeing seven wounded soldiers lying on a street in southeastern <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Hundreds of people were killed Saturday when troops shot, beat and crushed students and other protesters who had been occupying Tiananmen Square since May 13, demonstrating for democratic reforms and against corruption. Chinese and diplomatic sources said the <ORGANIZATION> 38th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which is commissioned with defending the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> area, was preparing to move against the <ORGANIZATION> 27th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which carried out Saturday's attack. The 38th was originally told to enforce martial law imposed by Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> on May 20, but refused to send troops into the city. The 27th is based in <LOCATION> Hubei </LOCATION> province south of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Each corps is made up of three divisions and has between 35,000 and 40,000 men. The Ming Pao newspaper of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> quoted what it said were informed sources in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> as saying a young guard shot <PERSON> Li </PERSON> in the thigh Sunday in the Great Hall of the People. It said <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s wound was not severe and that his assailant was immediately shot to death. By late Monday, the defensive positions taken by troops occupying central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> clearly indicated their focus switched from shooting citizens to preparing for a battle. Troops occupied bridges and other strategic locations going into the square and shot at cars and pedestrians trying to get through. Thousands of troops and tanks occupying the square lined up along the northern perimeter facing the former imperial palace. Other tanks took up new positions on key intersections off the 100-acre square. Gunfire could be heard from behind the palace, and artillery shelling was heard in a far northwest suburb of the city. Nine tanks and 10 armored personnel carriers left the square Tuesday morning, heading eastward. At least three people died and four were injured Monday as troops armed with machine guns and automatic rifles kept up sporadic, indiscriminate firing. Chinese witnesses said the dead included a man machine-gunned from his chin to his stomach. The wounded included a girl shot in the chest when troops charged up a narrow residential street. Anti-government disturbances were reported in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nanjing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Changsha </LOCATION> and at least three cities in the northeast. In <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most populous city, all public transportation stopped Monday as people moved buses and other barricades into intersections. Thousands of people joined funeral marches through <LOCATION> Nanjing </LOCATION> on Monday, and students blocked major streets to prevent buses from running. Chinese sources said Defense Minister <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiwei </PERSON> was stripped of power for opposing the decision of senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> to end seven weeks of student demonstrations with military force. Despite repeated announcements on Chinese television praising the military action against the people of the capital, no national leader has appeared in public or on television to take responsibility for the military takeover of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The student unrest triggered a major power struggle in the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> leadership, with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, <PERSON> Li </PERSON> and other conservative hardliners gaining the upper hand and reportedly stripping power from Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, who favored making concessions to the students. There was a chorus of condemnation from around the world at the army's attack on the demonstrators. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would suspend all military sales and visits of <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> military leaders but announced that diplomatic ties would not be severed. The American, British and other embassies were evacuating some of their nationals from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> universities out of fear troops would move onto campuses to stifle anti-government activities. A <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student said, `` Many of the -LRB- Chinese -RRB- students have left the dormitories to go home or to find shelter in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> because they fear an imminent attack by the army.'' The <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> government sent a special flight Monday to evacuate residents of the British colony. Residents in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> spent the day preparing for food shortages, with lines forming for milk, oil, soy sauce and other staples. Blockades of buses and burning vehicles made major streets impassable, and many <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents stayed home from work out of fear of the roaming bands of soldiers. One convoy of 50 to 100 military trucks rumbled through the diplomatic quarter firing indiscriminately, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy official said. More than 40 soldiers later swaggered down the main street bordering the diplomatic section, firing in the air. Residents scattered but reappeared to shout jeers after the soldiers. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents enraged by the shooting defied the heavily armed military by blockading streets and vowing continued support for the pro-democracy students. Many wore black armbands to honor the dead. `` It's not over, it's just getting started,'' said a 38-year-old educator outside the main gate of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Normal University, where hundreds of people gathered to back the students. `` The people have just found out what democracy is really about.'' On man climbed on top of the lead vehicle of a 20-tank convoy. He got down but again moved to block its way when the tank tried to drive around him. Several people had to drag him to safety. The official media continued to defend the military crackdown on unarmed civilians as a justified battle against `` thugs'' and `` ruffians.'' The national television station late Monday showed footage of young people throwing rocks at troops and military personnel carriers entering the city. One segment showed people attacking a stalled truck, heaving rocks through the windshield and saying the two soldiers inside were beaten to death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BlackFilmMakers     06-06 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Black Film Makers,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spike Lee and Robert Townsend Honored as Independent Film Makers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ALAN HARPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Spike </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON>, the two major representatives of the newest wave of make-it-on-your-own black film makers, were honored Monday night for doing things their way. `` They are independent in spirit, they are determined and they fought against insurmountable odds and surmounted them,'' said <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Peebles </PERSON>, who overcame the odds a generation ago with `` Sweet Sweetback's Baadasssss Song.'' <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Peebles </PERSON>, an elder statesman of black film making, presented a special award to <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Filmmaker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>'s 10th anniversary gala and tribute at the Majestic Theater in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The foundation is the nation's largest distributor of independently produced work by black film makers. Its 1,500 members include major film and television producers, writers, directors, actors and film students. Also being honored were films and videos produced independently of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> and commercial television in the last 10 years. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> first became known three years ago for `` She's Got ta Have It,'' a sexual comedy about a young woman and her partners. He furthered his reputation with `` School Daze,'' a peek at black colleges, and his `` Do the Right Thing'' was the talk of the <LOCATION> Cannes </LOCATION> film festival last month. It premieres later this month. <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> raised cash with his credit cards to finance `` Hollywood Shuffle,'' a revealing look at the stereotypes and prejudices black actors face on and off the screen in the movie-making world. He has moved on to four HBO specials and a feature film, `` The Mighty Quinn,'' with <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> nominee <PERSON> Denzel </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>. <PERSON> Townsend </PERSON> now is writing and starring in a musical comedy, `` Heartbeats,'' about a singing group.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Sun-TimesChanges     06-06 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sun-Times Changes,0430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names Philadelphia Publisher as Chairman, Promotes Acting Publisher</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> announced Monday it has hired <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> publisher <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> as president and chief executive officer in a move to become a national media company and improve the city's second-largest newspaper. <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON>, 62, is a 35-year veteran of <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, most recently as publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION> and The Daily News of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, and chairman of the firm that oversees both. In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION>' acting publisher, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, has been promoted to publisher of the paper, the nation's 10th-largest metropolitan daily, the holding company announced `` These appointments strengthen our management team and represent our continued commitment to the future of this organization,'' said <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaykin </PERSON>, company chairman. At a brief afternoon news conference in the downtown Sun-Times building, <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> said the holding company's offer `` was a lure I could n't really resist.'' He acknowledged that one of his first tasks will be to help reverse circulation decline. With a daily circulation of 554,670 and 595,311 on Sundays, the <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> is second in the city to the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> indicated no major immediate changes are planned in management or staff, although he declined to specify his agenda. `` It would be very presumptuous to think I had changes in mind'' other than to make the newspaper `` more interesting, to expand readership and expand sales,'' <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> said. Price, 45, called his new boss `` a proven competitor and he is a winner'' who will help make it possible for the <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> `` to better serve the community and also to better serve our advertisers.'' <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> said the parent will seek compatible media companies to acquire in its move to become a national media organization, but he declined to elaborate. Besides the newspaper, the <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s holdings include the <ORGANIZATION> Pioneer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, which publishes 43 weekly papers in the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburbs, and <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 18 twice-weekly suburban newspapers. <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Ridder </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> newspaper division, said in a statement that `` <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON>'s vision and leadership are treasured assets that will be difficult to replace. He'll be missed by all of his colleagues.'' `` <PERSON> Sam </PERSON>'s legacy will be the fine team he has built here which will help to ensure the continued excellence of the Inquirer and the Daily News. That team will have my close support and assistance.'' <PERSON> McKeel </PERSON> will continue to live in the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Rosemont </LOCATION>, commuting to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> when necessary.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusRdp Bjt   06-06 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Rdp, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Race-Bias Ruling Assailed by Civil Rights Groups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES H. RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights advocates are accusing the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> of abandoning the nation's 25-year-old commitment to fair treatment in the workplace for minorities and women. They expressed alarm and dismay over a ruling Monday they said undercuts the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and will make it far more difficult for workers to prove with statistical evidence that they are victims of racial or gender bias. Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on civil and constitutional rights, said, `` If the court continues down this path, the civil rights laws will be just an empty shell. But <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> did not predict any immediate action in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to reverse the 5-4 court ruling. `` It's a major step backwards,'' said <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> and Educational Fund. `` The court has made it much more difficult for -LRB- plaintiffs -RRB- to win and at the same time has made it easier for employers to defend themselves.'' <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, also with the fund, predicted civil rights lawyers now will concentrate on cases where they can prove intentional discrimination and seek big money damages to punish employers who discriminate. `` It is going to make litigation a lot tougher and a lot nastier,'' he said. `` It means fewer cases and bigger awards.'' But business leaders hailed the ruling and said most employers will remain committed to affirmative action even if the threat of losing lawsuits is reduced. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Bokat </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> said, `` I'm really pleased. It went much further than I thought the court would go. This means fewer specious cases will be brought. Employers are going to be able to defend these cases more easily,'' he said. Monday's ruling focused on so-called `` disparate impact'' cases where allegations of bias are based on statistics showing under-representation for minorities rather than deliberate discrimination. The decision divided the high court sharply and prompted bitter remarks from the dissenting justices. `` One wonders whether the majority still believes that race discrimination _ or, more accurately, race discrimination against non-whites _ is a problem in our society, or even remembers that it ever was,'' said Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> in a dissenting opinion. The court overturned a lower court ruling that had favored Filipinos, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> natives and Asians employed during the summer at <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> salmon canneries. The minority groups said they have been relegated to the lower-paying jobs there. The justices sent the case back to the lower courts with instructions to use the high court's new guidelines making it more difficult for the minority groups to win their lawsuit. Justice <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, writing for the court, said that when minorities use statistics to show they are bias victims, employers only must produce evidence that there is a legitimate reason for apparently neutral business practices. The burden of proving the practices are non-discriminatory _ of persuading a jury there is no bias _ does not shift to the employer, <PERSON> White </PERSON> said. He added that the workers must suggest alternative practices that do not have an unfair impact on minorities, but said employers can not be forced to adopt the alternatives if they are more costly. The court also limited the statistical evidence that minorities can use to prove discrimination. For example, <PERSON> White </PERSON> said a lack of minority group members in skilled jobs is not evidence of bias if the absence reflects `` a dearth of qualified non-white applicants for reasons that are not -LRB- the employer's -RRB- fault.'' He said the minority groups must show that any under-representation in skilled jobs is tied directly to specific business practices under attack. White said that without such protection for employers their only recourse to eliminate racial imbalance in their work forces would be unlawful quotas. In other action, the court: _ Ruled, 5-2, that the main method used by the Church of Scientology to receive money from members does not entitle them to federal income tax deductions _ Handed artists and authors a victory by unanimously ruling that a homeless-rights group in the nation's capital does not hold exclusive copyright to a sculpture it commissioned an artist to create _ Cleared the way for trial of a government lawsuit against junk bond specialist <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Milken </PERSON> and removed a major obstacle to a $ 650 million payment by his former employer to investors and the federal treasury _ Rejected an appeal by <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> patients who want to use their own money to pay for an assistant surgeon in eye cataract operations
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-China Bjt   06-06 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-China, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's China Experience Shaping US Policy</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> once suggested that the more he learned about the Chinese the less he understood them. Now, his experience in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is a guiding influence in setting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy toward the troubled giant. In his announcement Monday of a cutoff in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> arms sales to protest the bloody suppression of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s pro-democracy movement, the government's No. 1 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> hand said he took the action because he understands <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> `` reasonably well.'' For that reason, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the events of the past few days could only leave him with `` a saddened heart.'' `` I am trying to take steps that will encourage a peaceful change, and yet recognize the fact that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> does have a great pride in its own history. And my recommendations are based on my knowledge of Chinese history,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. That does n't mean he understands what has happened, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who less than four months ago shook hands with bicyclists in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, presented <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cowboy boots to Prime Minister <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> and bantered about exercise regimens with senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>. Of the military assault that left hundreds dead and thousands wounded, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` I condemn it; I do n't try to explain it.'' Asked for his best assessment of the political situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also demurred. `` It's too obscure,'' he said at a news conference Monday. But <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> expertise has always been a major element of the well-laden foreign-policy resume that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brought to the Oval Office. For <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who headed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> liaison office in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for 16 months in 1974-75 and since then has visited the nation five times, this expertise is also the source of extreme caution _ a caution that previously provoked criticism. In his 1987 pre-election autobiography, `` Looking Forward,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wrote that during his tour of duty in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> he often had the `` feeling the more you learn about the Chinese, the less you really understand them.'' `` I have a special affection for the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> people. I've kept up my knowledge of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and my relationship with various leaders there,'' he told a business audience Monday night. Although <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders of both parties were near unanimous in their praise for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s stern but careful actions Monday, his reticence in speaking out for human rights when he visited <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> in late February prompted criticism. The criticism intensified when a dissident he invited to a farewell banquet, astrophysicist <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, was barred by Chinese police from attending the ceremony. Still, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> defended this caution anew on Monday while issuing his strongest criticism thus far of the Chinese government. `` This is not a time for anything other than a prudent, reasoned response,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said his actions Monday will deny the Chinese more than $ 600 million worth of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government military equipment sales and an estimated $ 85 million or so annually in private arms sales. He also banned visits by <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> military officials, offered humanitarian and medical assistance to those wounded in the assault and suggested that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would extend the visas of Chinese students here afraid to return to their homeland. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, however, said he was not ready to do `` something more flamboyant,'' such as recommend trade sanctions or recall the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador, `` because I happen to believe that this relationship is vital to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> suggested, as he has in the past, that he's sensitive to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s own sensitivity to outside criticism. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> historically has been less than totally interested in what other countries think of their performance,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. Still, he expressed hope that `` the depth of the feeling towards democracy is so great that you ca n't put the genie back in the bottle and return to total repression.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s actions won support from many on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` This is a time to allow the president to lead on that kind of issue, especially when you have a president with this level of personal expertise in Chinese affairs,'' said Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0942EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Brown-Desegregation 1stLd-Writethru a0474 06-06 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Brown-Desegregation, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0474,0615</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Rules Topeka Schools Allowed Desegregation to Falter</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to RECAST; PICKS UP 3rd graf pvs, `The
case ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HANNA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOPEKA, Kan. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vestiges of school segregation remain in <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> 35 years after it lost the <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> decision, which paved the way for desegregation of schools nationwide, a federal appeals court ruled. The 10th <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> panel's decision, made available Monday, reversed a ruling that would have closed the case that found `` separate but equal'' schools for blacks and whites unconstitutional. The case was reopened 10 years ago by parents who said <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION>'s schools were still segregated `` We won,'' said <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, an attorney representing the parents of 17 black schoolchildren. `` We feel that 10 years of work was not in vain. We feel vindicated by the decision. It's been quite a long time coming.'' The group involved in the lawsuit included parent <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>, who was a student when her name went on the original lawsuit. `` My first reaction was shock, then I was pleased, very pleased,'' said <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Buckner </PERSON>'s sister. `` I believe that the case showed that there is a lot of educational enhancement that is not taking place here.'' In its decision published in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> on Friday, the panel rejected <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>' contention in April 1987 that parents of minority students had to prove a pattern of intentional discrimination to force the district to come up with a plan for more racially balanced schools. `` Because we are convinced that <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> has not sufficiently countered the effects of both the momentum of its pre-Brown segregation and its subsequent segregative acts in the 1960s, we reverse,'' the appeals court said. The judges also reversed a lower court ruling that the <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> school district had not violated Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebelius </PERSON>, an attorney for the the school district, said officials were awaiting receipt of the dissenting opinion in the 2-1 ruling before deciding whether to appeal. He added that the ruling confirmed the high quality of <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION>'s schools `` Throughout their decision they note that <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> offers excellent educational opportunities to all its students, wherever they be,'' <PERSON> Sebelius </PERSON> said. `` There was absolutely no hint or contest of the quality education the district provides.'' The court noted that neither the school district nor the <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> community was actively resisting desegregation, and cited the national recognition of the district's innovative curriculum. `` This active engagement has largely been directed at concerns other than desegregation, however,'' the appeals court said. `` For the most part, the <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> school district has exercised a form of benign neglect.'' The original class-action lawsuit challenged the constitutionality of a <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> law authorizing school segregation. The May 17, 1954, <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision paved the way for nationwide school desegregation and busing. <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> schools were required to submit an integration plan, which was approved in 1955. In 1979, the case was revived by black parents who claimed <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> had failed to desegregate its schools. <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> found the school district to be integrated and unified. Local officials of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> for the Advancement of Colored People at the time blasted <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>' decision, saying blacks could not get a fair hearing because of racism in <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION>. The appeals court ruled that the district's policy of permitting students to attend neighborhood schools was insufficient to desegregate schools because neighborhoods are still racially segregated. <LOCATION> Topeka </LOCATION> is 90 percent white. There are about 14,000 students in the city school district.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0948EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Navy-Nuclear 3rdLd-Writethru a0521 06-06 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy-Nuclear, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0521,640</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Least 50 Nuclear Weapons Dropped on Ocean Floor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs 7th graf, Twenty-seven, to CORRECT that all sunk submarines
were not nuclear-powered</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN BRUMLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet naval accidents have littered the ocean floor with at least 50 nuclear weapons and 10 nuclear reactors since World War II, according to a report released today by the <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> environmental group. Forty-three of the 50 weapons and six of the nine reactors are Soviet, and the real number may be much higher because so few details are known of secretive Soviet navy operations, said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>, an analyst who worked with <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> on the project. `` We got no information at all from the Soviets,'' said <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>, who works at the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, a liberal <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> interest group. `` We were totally unsuccessful in getting any kind of real response from them. And we were totally unsuccessful in getting any information from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence about Soviet naval accidents.'' Using material obtained from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government under the Freedom of Information Act, the researchers listed 1,276 accidents since World War II involving military vessels. The accidents caused more than 2,800 deaths and ranged in severity from the loss of an entire vessel and crew to minor collisions and fires that caused little damage and few if any injuries. <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> said that of the accidents, 228 involved aircraft carriers, 406 other major surface warships, 182 supply ships, 142 minor military ships and 75 amphibious vessels. Separately, 75 incidents involved sinkings. Twenty-seven submarines have sunk in that period, including five Soviet, four American, four French and three British, as well as submarines from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, the analysts reported in their 101-page study. Perhaps the most serious accident was the sinking of a Soviet Yankee-class submarine on Oct. 6, 1986, with 32 nuclear warheads and two nuclear torpedoes aboard 600 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. More recently, a Soviet ` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>' class submarine sank off the coast of <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> in April with two nuclear reactors and two nuclear tipped torpedoes aboard, the report said. `` Between 1975-1985, according to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> had over 200 serious submarine accidents,'' according to a summary of the report. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has had more sinkings, more propulsion failures, and according to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence sources, more accidents than the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> earlier revealed information about two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> accidents that received wide publicity over the past month. In 1965, an A-4 warplane fell off the USS Ticonderoga off <LOCATION> Okinawa </LOCATION> with a hydrogen bomb aboard, and on Nov. 22, 1975, a fire aboard the USS Belknap came within 40 feet of nuclear weapons. Although the report carried the greatest detail about incidents involving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> vessels, its sharpest criticism was of the Soviets. <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON> said he planned to deliver a Russian-language version of the study to the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and would seek a meeting with Soviet officials. `` Official secrecy, particularly that of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, as well as sporadic news media interest in reporting routine accidents, are major impediments to compiling a complete record,'' the report said. `` Of the 1,276 accidents, 799 have involved naval ships of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' it said. `` This preponderance of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> accidents does not mean a higher accident rate than other navies, particularly the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. `` Many hundreds more Soviet accidents are known to have occurred, but due to inadequate data and excessive secrecy, we have been unable to document specific dates or circumstances,'' it said. Asked in a telephone interview to give an example of a Soviet naval accident in which nuclear weapons or reactors were suspected but not documented to be involved, <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON> cited the sinking of a destroyer in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> in 1974. `` A Kashin-class destroyer with 275 crewmen sank with all hands. Our speculation is that there were probably nuclear torpedoes aboard,'' said <PERSON> Arkin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 0952EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Abortion-Trial     06-06 0266</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-Trial,0274</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Selected As Abortion Demonstration Trial Takes Center Stage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The judge sat center stage, the defendants took up the orchestra, mezzanine and balcony and a defense attorney asked potential jurors if they'd ever had an abortion. Set in a 300-seat theater, the drama was real as 155 anti-abortion activists went on trial Monday for trespassing during a protest at a clinic April 15. The judge had to rent the hall intended for nightclub acts and jazz ensembles because no local courtroom was big enough. `` Here in the first row,'' attorney <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> asked before a jury of six was selected, `` has anyone had an abortion?'' When a prosecutor objected, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> asked whether any of the 95 prospective jurors knew of anyone who had had an abortion. About half said yes. More than 180 people were arrested and charged with trespassing during the protest organized by Operation Rescue. The charge carries up to a year in jail and a $ 1,000 fine. Some pleaded no contest and received six months' probation. Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> merged the cases and rented a theater at the <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> complex for about $ 5,000 for what is expected to be a weeklong trial. `` We're not here to determine the issue of abortion,'' said Assistant State Attorney <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavandera </PERSON>, standing before a stage set up with a makeshift judge's bench. `` You are being selected to serve on a jury, not on a legislative delegation,'' he said. `` What I'm concerned with is if you can set aside your own preconceptions and follow the law.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Court-SemenDonor     06-06 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Court-Semen Donor,0270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agreement Must be Studied in Artificial Insemination Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman who got a semen sample from a friend and bore a child _ then got a court to rule that the man had no rights as the father _ has been dealt a setback by the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. The Juvenile Court judge who held that the friend was not, technically, the father must take another look at the case to determine precisely what the pre-conception agreement between the two was, the high court ruled Monday. The woman had argued that she never promised to recognize her friend as the father and that even if she had, state law specifies that sperm donors have no parental rights. Court papers identified the couple only by initials. Records showed that in 1985, <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> donated semen to E.C., a woman he had known for two years. A doctor inseminated her, and she gave birth in 1986. <PERSON> J.R. </PERSON> then sought a declaration he was the father, alleging that he and E.C. had agreed in advance that he would be treated as the father. He also argued that the law giving sperm donors no parental rights did not apply to unmarried women who knew the donor. Juvenile Court Judge <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> ruled that evidence of a pre-conception agreement was irrelevant. But Justice <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Vollack </PERSON> said that what the man and woman agreed to in advance is indeed relevant. The high court cited a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> case in which a sperm donor was declared the legal father and given visitation rights.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SubliminalEssay     06-06 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Subliminal Essay,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Subliminal' Gimmick May Have Won Essay Contest For Senior</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUMA, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The subtle commands sprinkled through <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Loupe </PERSON>'s essay on `` The Power of Subliminal Messages'' might very well have helped the youngster win a state writing contest. The high school senior's 250-word essay told how advertisers use hidden messages to influence consumers. Printed in tiny letters at 13 locations within the work was the message: `` Give this essay first place.'' `` <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> had that little gimmick in there, which I think the judges went for,'' said <PERSON> Loupe </PERSON>'s English teacher, <PERSON> Raphael </PERSON> <PERSON> Songe </PERSON>. `` Everything else being just about equal, I think it gave him the edge.'' `` When I entered the contest, everybody said we should write something that would intrigue the judges and add a little twist to make it something special,'' said <PERSON> Loupe </PERSON>. `` I thank that little twist is what did it.'' <PERSON> Loupe </PERSON> got a typewriter for finishing first among 10,000 students from 47 public schools.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Jews     06-06 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Jews,0189</SECOND>
<HEAD>Emigration Drops During May, But Exodus Still at 10-Year High</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GENEVA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jewish emigration from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> dropped sharply last month but is still at a 10-year high, according to figures released today. The <ORGANIZATION> Intergovernmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Migration </ORGANIZATION> said 3,333 Soviet Jews registered at a <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> transit center in May, a 20 percent drop from April. The committee helps Jews leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and resettle elsewhere. Only 96 emigrants opted for new homes in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, said committee spokeswoman <PERSON> Regina </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucault </PERSON>. Most want to settle in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, she said. Ms. <PERSON> Boucault </PERSON> said the agency had no explanation for the decline in emigration. The May arrivals brought the 1989 total to 16,197; 524 chose the Jewish state as their destination, she said. The total for all of 1988 was 20,082. The program began in 1971 and reached a peak in 1979 when 51,328 Jews were allowed to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The numbers dropped sharply after the Soviet intervention in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> chilled East-West relations. The pace of emigration is now at its highest level since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RiverboatGambling     06-06 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Riverboat Gambling,0233</SECOND>
<HEAD>Illinois Trying to Catch Up in Riverboat Gambling Race</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS CONRAD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Like a paddlewheel steamer trailing in a <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> race, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> is trying to pass <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> in the riverboat gambling sweepstakes and pull in the fresh catch: dollars. Backers of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> legislation to legalize riverboat gambling say the payoff could be 2,500 new jobs, $ 200 million in initial riverfront investment and as much as $ 700 million a year in economic spinoffs. The loser, they say, could be left at the dock. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> already has authorized riverboat gambling on the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> beginning in 1991. `` The -LRB- state -RRB- there first is going to attract the people,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Denny </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, sponsor of legislation to legalize riverboat gambling next year on the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> side of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and much of the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>' bill, and one allowing betting on the <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plaines </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, were overwhelmingly approved by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> last month and are now in the House. The proposals would allow blackjack, poker, slot machines and other games on 19th-century-style riverboats or casino cruise ships. Unlike the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> legislation, which limits bets to $ 5 and losses to $ 200 per person per excursion, the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> bills permit losses up to $ 500. Gamblers can wager no more than an initial $ 5 but can parlay their winnings without limit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChainGame     06-06 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chain Game,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>Necklace Fight Throws HS Baseball Playoffs Into Weekend of Doubt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The score was tied 1-1 in the bottom of the last inning. The bases were loaded. Then the <LOCATION> Bayside </LOCATION> pitcher walked the batter. There was joy in <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION>. But wait _ the <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> boy was wearing a necklace! It was n't a bad hop but a little-known rule against wearing jewelry in high school baseball games that almost toppled <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> last week in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> playoff. But after a weekend of wrangling, the <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> nine came out on top. National high school baseball rules say that the second person on a team found wearing jewelry heads for the bench. The first offender gets a warning. When <ORGANIZATION> Tottenville </ORGANIZATION> shortstop <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Kish </PERSON> drew a walk Friday in the seventh and final inning, <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> was declared the winner. But <LOCATION> Bayside </LOCATION> coach <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Torney </PERSON> cried foul, saying he had spotted a gold chain around <LOCATION> Kish </LOCATION>'s neck. <PERSON> Torney </PERSON> said he had already complained about a <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> player wearing a bracelet. He said the umpires refused to warn the first player or eject <LOCATION> Kish </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Bayside </LOCATION> appealed to a league commissioner, who ruled that <LOCATION> Kish </LOCATION> should have been ejected and ordered the game restarted at the bottom of the seventh with the score tied, the bases loaded and someone else batting for <LOCATION> Kish </LOCATION>. There was no joy in <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION>. The team appealed. The league director ruled that the original result should stand since the umpires did not issue a warning when the first piece of jewelry was found. <LOCATION> Bayside </LOCATION>, behind again with just one pitch to go, appealed to <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schecter </PERSON>, director of health, physical education and school sports. After an hour of testimony Monday, she declared <LOCATION> Tottenville </LOCATION> the winner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-PepperElection     06-06 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pepper Election,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Martinez Sets Special Election Dates For Pepper's Seat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> today set an Aug. 29 election to fill the congressional seat vacated by the death of 88-year-old <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>. Pepper, a Democrat who championed the elderly during six decades of public service in the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> and in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, had held the 18th district seat since its creation, first winning election in 1962. The <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, holding its first majority in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s congressional delegation, plans a major effort to capture the seat Several candidates have expressed interest in trying to become the first Cuban-American elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. A primary was set for Aug. 1. A runoff, if needed, would be held Aug. 15. Pepper, who died Friday, was buried Monday next to his wife, <PERSON> Mildred </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> after lying in state the Capitol Rotunda in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ChelseaSchools     06-06 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chelsea Schools,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Massachusetts Senate Approves BU Takeover of Chelsea Schools</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has approved a plan by <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> to take over the troubled <ORGANIZATION> Chelsea </ORGANIZATION> schools for 10 years. In a 29-10 vote Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> endorsed the first-in-the-nation plan for a private university to run a public school system. <PERSON> Chelsea </PERSON> schools have been woefully underfunded, according to officials, and the 3,400 students in the largely working-class and predominantly Spanish-speaking city outside <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> have one of the highest dropout rates in the state. The bill now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, which gave its approval last week but must consider a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> amendment requiring periodic reports to the state by BU. Monday's vote was criticized by teachers unions who say the plan would deprive teachers of access to important personnel records. Many officials, including Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, have also criticized provisions exempting <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION> from open meeting laws. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> has not said whether he will sign the legislation. <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION> said it will raise money from foundations and corporations and offer a variety of programs, including education of preschoolers and aid for pregnant teen-agers. `` The schoolchildren of <LOCATION> Chelsea </LOCATION> are going to be very happy,'' said <ORGANIZATION> BU </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>. `` We're going to abide by the open meeting and the public records laws, and we've said all along we're going to abide by those. `` The fight is not over,'' declared <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Devlin </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, which represents <ORGANIZATION> Chelsea </ORGANIZATION>'s teachers. The union has sued to block what he called `` an arrogant kind of takeover.'' <PERSON> Rosanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, called the takeover an embarassment for the state. `` It's outrageous that <PERSON> Chelsea </PERSON> has been allowed to get to the condition it's in,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890606-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-06-89 1106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Iran-Khomeini 6thLd-Writethru a0543 06-06 0936</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Khomeini, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0543,0967</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khomeini Buried After Mourners Grab Body, Rip Shroud; Scores Crushed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 13 grafs to UPDATE with quotes, detail of graveside
scene. Pickup 13th pvs, `The chaos ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALEX EFTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEHRAN, Iran (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
