<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 2333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Politics     05-26 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Politics,0559</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Minister Cited as Possible Takeshita Successor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign Minister <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> has emerged as the most likely candidate to succeed scandal-tainted Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, who will resign soon, news reports said Saturday. Party leaders said <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> emerged as the top contender after talks Friday between <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> and <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>, chairman of the party's policy-making Executive Council, according to reports in the mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Yomiuri </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Mainichi </ORGANIZATION> newspapers <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> was scheduled to meet with party Secretary-General <PERSON> Shintaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> Saturday afternoon to discuss the selection of Uno, the reports said. Uno, 66, a 10-term member of the powerful lower house, has served as foreign minister under <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> since 1987. He has held the international trade and industry portfolio and served as party deputy secretary-general. An official at Uno's office said the reports about his being top contender were rumors and refused further comment. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s office was closed Saturday Party leaders reportedly favor <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> because he is untainted by the Recruit scandal, which already has led to more than a dozen arrests, and has experience in foreign affairs. Opposition to Uno remains, however, as he is a leading member of the party faction headed by <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s predecessor, <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, who earlier this week was forced to testify about his links to the scandal before parliament. <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>'s refusal May 13 to take the top job created a leadership vacuum in a governing party desperately in need of a leader with a clean enough reputation to steer the party out of scandal. The <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a publishing conglomerate at the center of the scandal, is accused of trying to influence government policy by selling underpriced, unlisted shares in a real estate subsidiary and by doling out millions of dollars of political donations. Along with <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s resignation, the scandal has led to the downfall of three <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> ministers and the arrest of a former chief <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretary. Many governing party members have called it the worst crisis since the party was founded 34 years ago. In the meeting with <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> on Friday, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> agreed to stay on as prime minister until a successor is found, though on April 25 he vowed to leave office soon after the year's budget clears parliament. The budget package is due to become law on Sunday. The head of the governing party routinely serves as prime minister because of the party's large majority in both houses of parliament. But due to the current crisis, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> are reportedly considering installing separate individuals in the two posts _ thus placating party elders who fear they may lose power if a young prime minister is named. The reports said a possible combination is former Prime Minister <PERSON> Takeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Fukuda </PERSON>, 84, who would assume the party presidency, and Uno as premier. <PERSON> Fukuda </PERSON>, now in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, said Friday said a younger man should be chosen for prime minister. He is to return to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Sunday. <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> also cited his age and poor health as reasons for declining the job. Other names that have come up in the leadership race are lower house speaker <PERSON> Michita </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakaka </PERSON>, 72, former Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON> Shin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanemaru </PERSON>, 74, and <PERSON> Masaharu </PERSON> <PERSON> Gotoda </PERSON>, 74, who heads the party <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 1stLd-Writethru a0663 05-26 0808</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0663,0830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Li Solidifies Support Among Hardliners</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERT 3 grafs after 15th graf, `Students by...' UPDATING with
students' reasons for leaving. Picks up 16th graf, `The main...' with minor
editing to trim</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BEJ3,9,11,14,15,NY6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hardliners moved to tighten their control of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on Friday after moderate <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON> was stripped of his power and placed under house arrest. Students leading the demonstrations that have forced the power struggle continued to occupy <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Tiananmen Square one week after martial law was declared in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. But thousands could be seen leaving, and crowds dwindled to about 15,000. Despite the drop and the apparent ouster of <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>, who had been more conciliatory toward the protesters, students vowed to continue to press for social reforms and the resignation of hard-line Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. The protesters previously have demonstrated the ability to rally huge numbers of citizens on short notice. Communist Party members nationwide were studying two sets of documents as the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> prepared to meet. One document blamed <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> for the 6-week-old student movement and the other called for a `` resolute suppression of the disturbances,'' sources said. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> had expressed sympathy for the student movement, was the first to call it `` patriotic'' and apparently worked behind the scenes to oppose the May 20 declaration of martial law in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. But sources said conservatives accused <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> of splitting the party, instigating disturbances, revealing party secrets, corruption and taking credit for achievements of senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> during the past decade. On state-run news Wednesday night, <PERSON> Li </PERSON> was quoted as saying that <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> `` is the main reformer in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, not anyone else.'' Although <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> ushered in market-oriented economic reforms, student protesters have been pressing for political freedoms, such as a free press, and an end to official profiteering. Millions have taken to the streets in recent weeks to call for the resignation of <PERSON> Li </PERSON> and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, who are more resistant to social reforms than is <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> was quoted Friday in the state-run press as calling on soldiers surrounding <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to conduct `` a resolute struggle against the plots of a small minority.'' Eastern European and <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> sources said <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> was stripped of power Wednesday night during a meeting of top government officials and was under house arrest. The party's <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would have to ratify any leadership change. It is expected to meet soon. Sources said officials who have worked under <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> on political and economic reforms also were facing punishment. They include the party's propaganda chief, <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Qili </PERSON>; Vice Premier <PERSON> Tian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiyun </PERSON>; and <PERSON> Bao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tong </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> aide. They said the main winner in the struggle appeared to be <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, 84, who apparently was behind <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s imposition of martial law and is believed to still have final say on major decisions. Students by the thousands were leaving <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, the focus of two weeks of continuous demonstrations. By nightfall Friday, about 15,000 students remained on the vast expanse that once was occupied by more than 100,000. Students insist the drop in numbers does not mean their movement lost momentum or was cowed. A few students admitted they feared violence now that the conservatives seem to be in control, but most said they were tired of sleeping on concrete in unsanitary conditions. Student leaders said they were urging non-Beijing students to go home because they can do more in spreading the movement there than by staying on the square. The leaders expressed confidence they could again quickly mobilize large groups of students and residents if the confrontation with authorities escalated. The main train station was packed with students returning home. The television news quoted a station official as estimating 20,000 were leaving Friday. But some said they would not leave. `` Everybody in the country is watching the square,'' said one student leader. `` If we leave, we will betray their hopes.'' On Friday, more government leaders embraced <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s hard-line stance. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Yun </PERSON>, the 84-year-old head of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, a powerful advisory group, appeared on TV to support martial law and the commission later followed suit. A government source said <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiannian </PERSON>, 81, who formerly held the ceremonial post of president, spoke at the meeting where the decision was made to strip <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> of power. He criticized <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> for fomenting the student movement and equating it with `` a struggle between two army headquarters.'' Such a description indicated conservatives view the general secretary's alleged crimes as serious That speech and one given by <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 81-year-old President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON> made up one of the documents being studied by top party members and officers, said a government source. <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> said <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s actions `` had a very bad effect'' on the nation, the source said, and indicated that party members, intellectuals and journalists who participated in the movement would be punished.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 2343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Coelho-Thumbnail     05-26 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coelho-Thumbnail,150</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, the third-ranking Democrat in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, began his political career with advice from comedian <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> was raised on a dairy farm near <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. In college at <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, he discovered he had epilepsy and was turned down for his first career _ the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> priesthood. But <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Dolores </PERSON>, heard about <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s situation and the comedian suggested that <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> try politics. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where he worked for Rep. <PERSON> B.F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisk </PERSON>, the 15th District's congressman, for 15 years When <PERSON> Sisk </PERSON> retired in 1978, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> ran for his seat and won. Three years later, shortly after <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was elected president, he took over as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and proved to be a master at raising money. After the 1986 election, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> was picked as majority whip, the third-ranking position.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Bush-NATO 3rdLd-Writethru a0678 05-26 1104</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-NATO, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0678,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's European Trip Complicated by Weapons Policy Rift</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 8th graf pvs, bgng: ``As Bush...''; picks
up 9th graf pvs, bgng: ``Numerous administration...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> arrived Friday enroute to a summit with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders, hoping to use personal diplomacy to resolve a long-simmering dispute over European-based nuclear weapons. In brief arrival remarks, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made no reference to reports that he would use the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit next week in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> _ his first as president _ to announce a reduction in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Instead, he declared the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> wants a `` stronger and more united <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' and said he plans to be `` actively engaged in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, promoting measures to encourage political and economic liberalization in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plans to visit <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in July. The dispute over short-range nuclear weapons has defied resolution by the two main countries at odds _ <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, pressing for negotiations with the Soviets to rid <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> of such weapons, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, supported by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, wanting to keep the weapons there and make them better. Other members of the 16-nation <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> alliance have lined up on one side or the other, with a few stradding the fence. Officials on all sides have sought to dismiss suggestions that the issue would seriously disrupt the summit, which was designed to celebrate 40 years of Cold War unity against the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. As <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times reported that he planned to use the summit as the stage for announcing a reduction of up to 10 percent in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop strength in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, `` as many as 34,000 troops.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> quoted sources in Saturday's editions as saying the administration is considering an offer to negotiate cuts in troop strength, aircraft and helicopters in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> if the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> agrees to cuts in tanks, armored personnel carriers and artillery pieces. Numerous administration officials, with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and back in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said any word on that would have to come from the president himself. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters aboard Air Force One en route to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>: `` Any ideas in this area would be one the president would want to discuss with the allies, he would raise with his partners at this session before he discusses anything publicly. ... I am not confirming or denying any decisions.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> did not dispute the newspaper's account. He said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` will be discussing a lot of different ideas with the allies'' but that he `` just ca n't speculate on what the conversations might amount to or what the president might suggest.'' The White House spokesman also stressed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would make no move on troop deployments in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> without having consultations with <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> first. Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> that 10 percent `` is the probable amount of reduction that would occur if the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> accepted the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> proposal on conventional arms control which is now tabled. In <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, West German spokesman <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON> said, `` We have no official word of such a decision.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in comments just before leaving on his first trip to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> as president, expressed hopes to see a <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> `` that is truly free, united and at peace.'' He repeated his desire to move beyond any Cold War policy of containment `` to integrate the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> into the community of nations.'' `` We welcome the political and economic liberalization that has taken place so far in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and in some countries of <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. We watch hoping that more changes will follow.'' As for the Western military alliance, he said, `` <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> has been a success by any measure but success breeds its own challenges. Today, dramatic changes are taking place in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, East and West. For us, those changes bring new challenges and unparalleled opportunities.'' In remarks prepared for his arrival in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, he praised U.S.-Italy ties of friendship and said, `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> welcomes a stronger and more united <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' Several weeks of busy diplomacy, including a high-level meeting in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> and two others in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, failed to settle the missiles issue, a subject that Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> called `` extraordinarily important.'' The issue is whether the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> should negotiate to reduce and possibly eliminate all the short-range nuclear missiles <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact have deployed on European soil or delay indefinitely while the two military alliances negotiate over reductions in troops, tanks, artillery and other conventional armories. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> insist that <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s missiles, which they want to make more powerful, are vital to the defense of the alliance. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and its supporters contend a series of moves by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to reduce nuclear and non-nuclear weapons reduce the missiles' significance The dispute has symbolic as well as strategic facets. It reflects, on the one hand, a a determination by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to stick to its position, and on the other the emergence of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> from post-World War II acquiescence to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> affairs. `` It should not be resolved at all costs,'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said while predicting the missile issue would not dominate the summit next Monday and Tuesday in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>. Until the dispute boiled over, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and the White House staff were planning on a calm presidential visit to friendly countries where he could step serenely through a series of picture-taking events. He will visit <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as well as <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. That schedule remains intact, though the missile dispute probably will require some clever draftmanship to paper over the differences in a windup <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> communique that stresses Western solidarity. In <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, besides talking with Italian government leaders, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will meet with Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> on Saturday in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and attend Roman Catholic mass and a Memorial Day ceremony in an American cemetery in <LOCATION> Nettuno </LOCATION>, on the seacost 39 miles south of the capital, on Sunday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is an Episcopalian. After te two-day <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, the president will continue his discussions with West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> on Wednesday over dinner in a ballroom where <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s `` Magic Flute'' opera premiered in 1793 and on a riverboat cruise on the <LOCATION> Rhine </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Thursday <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will have the comfort of winding up his travels meeting with his strongest supporter in the alliance, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, at 10 Downing Street, and lunch with Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Buckingham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION>. Then, on Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> flies to <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> for a weekend off.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Deaths CORRECTIVE   05-26 0087</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deaths, CORRECTIVE,0087</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Members who published a New York-datelined obituary for Maggi
McNellis, one of the obituaries in PM-Deaths, a0502 of May 25, are asked
to publish the following story. Item a0502 was corrected late in Thursday's
PMs cycle.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a report May 25 on the death of radio-television talk show host <PERSON> Maggi </PERSON> <PERSON> McNellis </PERSON>, The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously reported that her late husband, art gallery owner <PERSON> Clyde </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON>, was a member of the communications industry family of the same name.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Libel     05-26 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Libel,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>Libel Award to Mass Murderer's Wife Prompts Calls for Reform</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Making the racy tabloids pay large sums for libel to pals of royalty and other notables is one thing, but an award of nearly $ 1 million to the <ORGANIZATION> Yorkshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ripper </ORGANIZATION>'s wife is provoking comment that things have gone too far. `` Whose justice is this?'' the Daily Mirror asked on Thursday. `` Preposterous,'' declared the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION>. The 600,000-pound -LRB- $ 942,000 -RRB- award Wednesday to <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> was the largest ever made by a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> jury. Her husband, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>, is known as the <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> Ripper for terrorizing northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1975-80 with the murders of 13 women. It was levied against <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Eye </ORGANIZATION>, a satirical magazine that has thrived on the notoriety of frequent libel cases. The 200,000-circulation magazine, which is partly owned by actor-comedian <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, has begun a fund-raising campaign to avoid bankruptcy. Private Eye said in 1981 and 1983 that Mrs. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> had sold her story to the Daily Mail for $ 392,000 after carousing with the tabloid's reporters at a hotel. After she filed the libel action, Private Eye published two articles implying she knew about her husband's crimes. In the trial, which began May 19, Private Eye admitted there was no deal with the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mail </ORGANIZATION> but claimed the gist of its statements was true: that Mrs. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> negotiated with newspapers and was prepared to capitalize on her husband's crimes. Legal experts said the growth of libel awards would make newspapers reluctant to defend stories in court, for fear of high jury awards, and incline them to out-of-court settlements even on statements that were true. They and several national newspapers recommended changes in the libel laws, which allow juries to set damages without guidance from judges. In no other area of English civil law do juries have such great discretionary power. Plaintiffs in libel suits do n't ask for a specific sum, preferring not to limit the jury. `` In <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, you are now going down the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> route, which would allow punitive damages,'' said <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>'s judicial system, judges assess libel damages. `` Damages are there to compensate, not to punish,'' <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> said. `` We could suffer from all the deficiencies and defects of the American system which allow punitive damages to come in. They are unfair, they are inconsistent.'' Lord <PERSON> Blom-Cooper </PERSON>, chairman of the watchdog <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, agreed that `` the assessment of damages should be left to judges.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wakeham </PERSON>, Conservative majority leader, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday the government was considering changes in the libel laws, but he was not specific. Newspapers said that if Mrs. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON>, 38, died before her husband, he would inherit the remainder of the award. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> is in a hospital for the criminally insane. In it's editorial, the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> said: `` The <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ripper </LOCATION> has claimed his 14th victim _ justice.'' The Daily Express said the award made `` a mockery not only of the libel laws but of the system of justice itself.'' `` Mrs. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> was right to fight for her reputation if she believed it maligned, but how on earth could a jury seriously believe that it was damaged to the extent of 600,000 pounds tax-free?'' the editorial said. `` As this award now sets a new record for libel damages, the jury must have thought the wrong done to her good name was the most grievous ever considered by our courts. In reality, it probably thought nothing of the kind.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> has not commented on the award. Her lawyer, <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Macgill </PERSON>, said Thursday: `` <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutcliffe </PERSON> was n't the person convicted. She is an entirely separate entity.'' The previous record for libel damages by a jury was $ 800,000 awarded to novelist and former politician <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> in July 1987 after the Star reported he had a sexual liaison with a prostitute and paid her hush money. American actress <PERSON> Koo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stark </PERSON> received $ 480,000 from the Sunday People last year because of false allegations that she dated Prince <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> after her marriage. Newspaper publisher <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> won $ 77,000 damages in 1986 from Private Eye, which said he financed overseas trips by <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinnock </PERSON> in hopes of receiving a peerage from a future <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> government. Pop star Elton <PERSON> John </PERSON> got received $ 1.6 million from the Sun, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s largest-circulation newspaper, which admitted its lurid allegations about his private life were false. That action was settled out of court in December. The judge scheduled to hear the case accused both sides of milking it for publicity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Past     05-26 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Past,0663</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Parliament Illustrates Break with Past</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Soviet, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The sleeping deputies, docile votes and fulsome tributes to leaders are gone. In their place is vigorous, emotional debate with the sound of a political and moral reawakening in this vast land. Freed from the fear that permeated decades of authoritarian rule, citizens chose delegates to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s first competitively elected parliament. They hoped for change, and got it. As soon as the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> convened on Thursday, deputy <PERSON> Vilens </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolpozhnikov </PERSON> of independent-minded <LOCATION> Latvia </LOCATION> took the floor. He requested a moment of silence for the 20 people killed last month when security forces broke up a peaceful nationalist demonstration in <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. His appeal set the tone for a surging debate that expressed the feelings of of a diverse country that has spent four years under <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> probing its past and rediscovering politics, ethnic identities and national morality. `` Each of us wants to talk out a sea of emotion,'' deputy <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lubenchenko </PERSON> said. Symbolizing the change, one of the first to take the floor was <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, the 1975 Nobel Peace Prize laureate who only 2 -LCB- years ago was an internal exile confined to <PERSON> Gorky </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> made one of his most passionate speeches in response to tough questions about his privileges as leader, his position on ethnic conflicts and his plans for the future. `` We are still learning democracy,'' he said. `` We are still forming a political culture. We understand with our brains that it's necessary to change, but the system does n't let us.'' `` We have now reached the most difficult stage of perestroika,'' he said, referring to his `` restructuring'' program of economic and social change. A leader of his energy and candor could hardly be imagined in the days of such lumbering, silent figures as <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>, who even had himself given the nation's top literature prize in a campaign of self-glorification now openly reviled in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> media. On Thursday, young and businesslike deputies unseen in <PERSON> Brezhnev </PERSON>'s time took the microphone to argue with conviction and detail. There was a sense of shame about the past, an earnest desire not to repeat the tragic mistakes. `` It's difficult for us all to live,'' said <PERSON> Valentina </PERSON> <PERSON> Petrovna </PERSON>, a deputy from <LOCATION> Irkutsk </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>. `` Let's think hard, and not allow anybody to restructure the restructuring.'' <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Yavorivsky </PERSON>, a writer from <LOCATION> Kiev </LOCATION>, declared `` this will be the last time'' the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> people will allow a president to be elected without democratic opposition. Without change, he said, `` the people will turn away from us. They will go back to silence, to vodka and to their anecdotes.'' Five years ago, those were among the few comforts for citizens who watched a closed, secretive Kremlin choose the elderly, obviously infirm <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> U. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON> to replace the deceased <PERSON> Yuri </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader. <PERSON> Chernenko </PERSON> pulled the country out of the 1984 <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Olympics, backed off arms control negotiations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and turned away from the tentative reforms begun by <PERSON> Andropov </PERSON>. Deputies in the new parliament said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s standing in the world has been restored by what one called `` brilliant successes'' in diplomacy. Then they contrasted that with the performance at home: a rising budget deficit, continuing shortages, social tensions and speeches that lack the bold tone of the early <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> period. A deputy from <LOCATION> Kharkov </LOCATION> warned <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> not to act like the `` great <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> who, fearing neither bullets nor death, led his people to victory, but due to sycophants and his wife ended with an empire, and not the republic he started with.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Alison </PERSON> <PERSON> Smale </PERSON> has covered Soviet and East European affairs for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1983.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0108EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     05-26 0974</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,970</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ag Expert Says low Mississippi River Could Trap Barges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> transportation expert says the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> has not recovered from last year's drought and its reduced streamflow could bottleneck barges moving grain and soybeans into export this fall. T.Q. <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> of the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said a sharp upturn in demand for jumbo covered railroad cars and `` continued low-water conditions on the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> rivers will create a tight transportation situation for grain marketing.'' However, <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> said there will be `` sufficient capacity'' available to meet the current export forecasts for feed grains and wheat. `` Replacement of Lock 26 at <LOCATION> Alton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, will close the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> for about one week in October-November 1989,'' he said. `` The closing, combined with low water and a tight rail car supply, could limit a post-harvest upturn in export shipments, but should not markedly disrupt grain distribution.'' <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> said in a report that water levels for the lower <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> in the first four months of this year were well below those of the same period in 1988. However, the January-April levels averaged above those of the 1988 drought months, June through December. `` Navigation on the middle and lower segments of the river will probably remain impaired in 1989, as in 1988,'' he said. `` However, sufficient capacity exists to carry the volume of grain implied by current marketing estimates.'' <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> said that between 1944 and 1988 the flood measure at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, averaged 19.5 feet in April, falling to between 6 and 9 feet in September. Thus, he added, `` a substantial reduction in water depth can be expected to occur between spring and fall.'' Last year, the water level at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> fell from 15.1 feet in April to 0.4 feet in September. The gauges do not indicate the channel's depth, but measure the quantity of water available. Channel depths are affected by dredging and other activities. In April, <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> said, the flood gauges at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> averaged 13.5 feet, nearly two feet below the previous year and six feet below the 1944-88 average for the month. `` In the coming months, flood gauges will likely reflect decreasing amounts of water, as they did last year,'' he said. `` Much of this will result from continuing low flows from the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>.'' Last year the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> supplied 65 to 70 percent of the flow at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, he said. Normally, the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> would account for 45 percent. Although water releases in 1988 were below average, the Missouri's increased share of the flow stemmed from reductions in the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and its tributaries. `` Currently, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reservoirs are 50 percent to 60 percent full,'' <PERSON> Hutchinson </PERSON> said. `` The <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> division -LRB- of the -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> plans to release slightly more water than last year _ but less than in a normal year.'' Also, he said, the <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> plans a shortened navigation season this year because of the low levels of storage reservoirs. The river opened one week later and will close 25 to 30 days earlier than usual.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retail food prices in 1989 have been pushed up sharply by crop-biting cold weather in the first quarter and may gain an average of 5 percent to 7 percent over the entire year, according to an <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> forecast. That would compare with a 1988 average gain of 4.1 percent and would be the sharpest 12-month increase since 1981, when retail food prices rose 7.9 percent. `` Consumer demand will pull up food prices in 1989,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. `` While growth in the general economy is slowing, growth in real disposable personal income is still likely to be 2 percent to 3 percent this year, after rising 2.9 percent last year.'' The report said the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s consumer price index for food increased at an annual rate of 8.6 percent in the first three months of 1989, well above the rate expected last fall. `` Additional upward adjustments are likely for the rest of this year, based primarily on the strength of consumer demand and the impact of higher petroleum prices,'' the report said. Much of the sharp rise in the first quarter was blamed on cold weather in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> which cut supplies of fresh vegetables. Retail prices, which had been expected to decline during the quarter, rose an average of 5.7 percent. Other price increases in the first quarter resulted from lingering effects of last summer's drought. `` Processed vegetable prices continued to rise because of smaller supplies of canned sweet corn, green peas, snap beans and dry beans, all victims of the drought,'' the report said. `` Smaller supplies of canned vegetables forced frozen vegetable prices higher as well.'' Retail egg prices rose 29.5 percent compared to a year earlier. Production was cut back because of high, drought-related feed costs, the report said. Food price increases are expected to be more moderate in the remainder of 1989. Prices for meats, poultry and fish `` will remain reasonably stable for the rest of the year,'' the report said. Egg prices are expected to fluctuate but should remain well above year-earlier levels.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says private exporters have sold <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> an additional 150,000 metric tons of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat for delivery in the marketing year that will begin June 1. No selling prices or the names of the companies involved were announced. Wheat sales to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in the current 1988-89 marketing year total almost 8.3 million tons, officials said Thursday. A metric ton is about 2,205 pounds and is equal to 36.7 bushels of wheat. The 150,000 tons would be about 5.5 million bushels and, at recent prices of about $ 4.03 per bushel, would have a farm value of around $ 22 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MissingTorah     05-26 0507</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Missing Torah,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Desperately Seeking Scroll: Schumer Asks State Department Help</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KIM I. MILLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> needs to know more if it's going to help find a sacred Jewish scroll that was being smuggled from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> when it was allegedly seized by officials in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION>. `` Without more information, there's no way that the department, which wants to be helpful, can be,'' a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said Thursday, speaking on condition that his name not be used. `` There just does n't appear to be anywhere else to turn.'' Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, has asked the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to help recover the 150-year-old Persian Torah, which had been destined for a new Persian synagogue in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION>, N.Y. But the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has been unable to locate the holy book, the man who was transporting it or the official who allegedly confiscated the scroll in the tiny <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> emirate of <PERSON> Ras </PERSON> <PERSON> Alkheimeh </PERSON>. A spokesman for the Embassy of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION> did not return several phone calls Thursday. The Torah's owner, an <LOCATION> Iranian </LOCATION> woman, asked a friend of her husband in November 1988 to smuggle the sacred scroll to <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION>. Iranian law prohibits exporting a Torah, according to <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>. The woman was sending the Torah to her brother in <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, who was planning to donate it to synagogue <PERSON> Beit </PERSON> <PERSON> Knesset </PERSON> <PERSON> Omid </PERSON>. `` We were going to have a grand opening at the synagogue and I was expecting to put this Torah at the grand opening,'' the brother said in an interview from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He spoke on condition that his name not be used for fear that the Iranian government might retaliate against his family. The brother said the scroll had been in his family for generations. `` The value of this Torah, if you are Jewish, is priceless,'' he said. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> put its price in the tens of thousands of dollars if it is indeed 150 years old. The smuggler took the scroll by boat from a port in southern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION>, where he planned to mail it to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said. But in <PERSON> Ras </PERSON> <PERSON> Alkheimeh </PERSON>, the courier was stopped by government officials and the scroll was confiscated, <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said. In a letter to Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said he has learned that the person who seized the Torah was <PERSON> Javad </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadad </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice-Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> provided a phone number for <PERSON> Hadad </PERSON>, but there was no answer there Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consul in <LOCATION> Dubai </LOCATION> had tried to chase down <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>'s leads to no avail. `` That name has been given before but they have not been able to track him down, as much as they've tried,'' the spokesman said. `` We're really at a stone wall right now.'' <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> blamed the Torah's alleged confiscation on Arab anti-Semitism. `` It's a human rights issue,'' he said. `` I think they can be embarrassed because this is the most vulgar kind of anti-Semitism that could exist.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CrystalBall Bjt   05-26 0666</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crystal Ball, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>World Affairs Are Getting Very Hard To Predict</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Throw away your crystal ball. It's a topsy-turvy world. Events do n't turn out the way you might have supposed. Predictions are n't worth very much. Just look around. West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, a conservative, is in the vanguard of West Europeans seeking disarmament and an accommodation with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He's resisted the blandishments of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and disrupted the script for the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit meeting to be held Monday and Tuesday in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> by demanding a negotiated reduction in short-range nuclear missiles. Brave <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> talk of a Western alliance able to withstand tensions can not obscure the fact that the usually reliable West Germans _ and not the independent <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> or a smaller left-leaning ally _ have opened a rift that challenges <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s very reason for being. If the time has come to negotiate the elimination of battlefield nuclear missiles in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> because the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> threat has receded, then <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION>'s purpose is due for a reassessment. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was going to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to celebrate the 40th anniversary of the alliance. There still will be wall-to-wall photo-ops in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, but behind the scenes, diplomats will be up late trying to paper over the U.S.-West German split with smiles and ambiguity. All in all, a strange turn of events. But not the only surprise on the world stage. Down in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, despite hopeful <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> predictions and a unanimous indictment by the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> that he was responsible for `` grave events and abuses,'' Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> clings to power, defying all efforts to dislodge him. More than a year ago, <PERSON> Elliott </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, then the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs, said <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was `` hanging by fingertips.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> regarded ousted <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Arturo </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON> as the legitimate authority. However, <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>'s government ceased to exist 15 months ago, and <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is in effective control of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. He evidently still can depend on the military for support. Without the assistance of the generals, apparently there is no way for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to force <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s ouster. He is still there, defying the odds and the predictions. In <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON>, scorned by the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administrations as <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s inept puppet, is still in power without a single <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> soldier standing behind him. Rebels armed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> were supposed to move in for the kill right after the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> withdrew. The troops left in mid-February, but <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> remains in charge in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Could any seer have predicted only a few months ago the turmoil sweeping <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, the open defiance of generals ordered to move against student protesters, the democratic slogans from a people staggering under Marxist rule? That <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> would come to terms with the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>? That <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> would have a stock exchange? That the <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> would retain his grip on <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> well into his 80s? That <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> would end weapons shipments to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>? The Soviet leader, of course, has turned out to be the biggest surprise of all. He is not what the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had come to expect from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Some 30 years ago <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, in a flurry of reform and showmanship, upset the West's balance. Since his downfall in 1964, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and its allies could count on a certain amount of predictability. Until <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came along. He has kept the West off balance constantly. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who had dismissed the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as an `` evil empire,'' wound up having five summit meetings with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and signing a landmark treaty to eliminate an entire category of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear missiles. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> apparently is still trying to figure out <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> response to Soviet arms control initiatives has been cautious. After all, there is no way of predicting what might happen next.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> covers foreign affairs for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-China-Chronology     05-26 0558</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-China-Chronology,0584</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chronology of Events in China</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Key events in student demonstrations: April 15 _ Former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON> dies. <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students put up posters praising him and indirectly criticizing opponents who forced his resignation after student demonstrations in 1986_87. April 17 _ Thousands of students march in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, shouting `` Long live <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>! Long live democracy!'' April 27 _ More than 150,000 students, with wide support from people on the street, surge past police lines and fill <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, chanting slogans for democracy and freedom. April 29 _ Officials meet with student leaders, but independent student groups are not satisfied and continue a class boycott at 41 universities. April 30 _ <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief, <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, meets with student representatives. May 4 _ About 100,000 students and supporters march on <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to celebrate the 70th anniversary of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first student movement. Demonstrations are held in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nanjing </LOCATION> and other cities. About 300 journalists protest outside the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. May 9 _ Journalists petition the government for press freedom. May 10 _ Thousands of students bicycle to major media offices in a press freedom demonstration. Another protest is held in the provincial capital of <LOCATION> Taiyuan </LOCATION>. May 13 _ About 2,000 students begin a hunger strike in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. May 14 _ Thousands flock to the square to back the students. The number fasting rises to 3,000. May 15 _ The government deadline for students to leave the square passes. Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s welcoming ceremony planned near the square must be moved to the airport. May 16 _ Hundreds of thousands occupy the square. Journalists and intellectuals join the protest. May 17 _ <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> pleas for students to leave. Students reject his appeal and hold marches that generate 1 million supporters in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. May 18 _ About 1 million people, including many workers, again take to the streets to show their support for the hunger strikers. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> issues a stern lecture to student leaders and refuses to discuss their demands. May 19 _ A tearful <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> visits weakened hunger strikers. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> also visits the students briefly. The students later decide to end the hunger strike. May 20 _ Martial law is declared in parts of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> reportedly resigns after failing to persuade <PERSON> Li </PERSON> and other hardliners to compromise. Students resume their hunger strike, then abandon it, saying they will need their strength for the struggle ahead. May 21 _ Students claim to reject an order by <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> to leave the <LOCATION> Tiananman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> or face military action. Defying martial law, hundreds of thousands of people remain in the square or block intersections to prevent troops from reaching it. May 22 _ Hundreds of thousands of people again block major roads and senior military leaders say they are resisting orders to order their troops on the protesters. At least one military convoy is reported to withdraw. May 23 _ One million people take to the streets to demonstrate for democracy. May 25 _ <PERSON> Li </PERSON> makes his first appearance since declaring martial law. State-run radio says 27 of 29 provinces support martial law, and military units announce they support martial law. May 26 _ Sources say <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> and another leading liberal, <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, head of the legislature, are under house arrest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pierce-HUDProbe     05-26 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pierce-HUD Probe,Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Panel Blasts Pierce for Housing Subsidy Program</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> provoked anger and disbelief among members of a congressional panel that questioned him about a housing subsidy program which investigators say was riddled with favoritism. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, who is now a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> lawyer, told congressional investigators Thursday that he was n't directly involved in deciding which projects received grants under the program. He said a committee of his subordinates at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> selected the winners, and his approval was a rubber stamp. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he was n't influenced by well-connected Republicans and former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials who obtained a large portion of the multimillion dollar subsidy projects, acting as consultants or developers. `` Perhaps we should have watched the program closer than we did,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said, in the closest he came to acknowledging any blame. `` But we've got a whole department -LRB- to run -RRB- ...'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s appearance before a House Government Operations subcommittee marked his first public comment since an investigative report sharply criticized the management of a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> program that provided indirect subsidies for rehabilitation of privately owned low-income housing projects. Current <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> has suspended further awards under the program pending a review. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, who headed <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for eight years under former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, testified that he recommended <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> kill the so-called mod-rehab program. But his remarks stirred strong reaction among members of the subcommittee, which questioned him for more than two hours. When <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> suggested that Democrats had also profited from the program, a near-shouting match erupted with Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat charged that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> was trying to `` deflect some of the blame'' by making `` irresponsible statements'' he could not back up. At one point during their exchange, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said, `` I do n't think ...'' and did not complete his sentence. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> shot back, `` Well, that has been clearer and clearer.'' Subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., told <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> the suggestion that the Republican-appointed inspector general was protecting Democrats was `` difficult to fathom. Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, D-Conn., told <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> that despite eight years in the Cabinet job, his remarks suggested `` you do n't really today understand how this program works. `` I did not have hands on,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> responded. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said an audit he conducted found a pattern in which former department officials and other well-connected Republicans received an inordinately large share of project awards. Among those cited was former <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>, who was reported receiving a $ 300,000 consulting fee on a <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> project. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> acknowledged that department officials used their own discretion in awarding subsidies, but said that was because <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 waived requirements specifying fair-share allocation procedures. Subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., read from a memo that he said the inspector general sent <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> in 1988 warning him of problems in the program <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said by then he had altered the selection process. He said he did not respond to the inspector general's suggestion because those changes needed time to work. `` The inspector general is not God,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. Rep. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Roukema </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.J. </LOCATION>, and the subcommittee's chairman, Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., expressed surprise at <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s reaction to <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' memo _ which <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> called `` a very, very dramatic recommendation. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> responded that he did not remember the memo, and added, `` Well, there were a lot of fights going on.'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he met with <PERSON> Watt </PERSON> on the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> project but referred him to the appropriate office at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> and told him that `` we'd look very carefully at his project.'' `` No promises were made to him,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrightProbe Bjt   05-26 0796</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright Probe, Bjt,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Want To Be Ready To Move Foley Into Wright's Job Quickly</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Democrats, anticipating a historic resignation next week of Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, are making plans for quickly promoting Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to the powerful speaker's post. But intrigue is brewing for filling in the rest of the party leadership slots as some Democrats worry that Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s likely successor, could hurt the party because of questions about his own financial dealings. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, talking with reporters Thursday in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, said he spoke to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> earlier in the day and the speaker `` repeated his desire to have an opportunity to state his case, his side of the case, to the widest possible audience, and he's determined to take that opportunity at the first time that seems appropriate.'' `` I assume that will be with either next week or shortly thereafter,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. Leadership sources in the Capitol said arrangements were being made for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to make a resignation address to the House next Wednesday, but the speaker himself had not yet decided on his precise course of action. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, remained secluded in his office Thursday, but he released a statement making clear he no longer was seeking any `` plea bargain'' with the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee. One of the most serious charges made by the ethics committee was that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, was given a no-work job by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s friend and business partner, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> House rules prohibit gifts from people with interest in legislation, and the committee said it believed <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> developer, had an interest. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who has vowed to clear his wife's name, dispatched his attorneys on Wednesday in search of a deal that would accomplish that, according to sources who said the lawyers offered his resignation in exchange for the panel dropping at least the charges that involve his wife. But the deal fell through as Republicans and at least one Democrat on the panel resisted. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> on Thursday distanced himself from the effort and indicated it was over. `` There is no deal now. There will be no deal in the future,'' he said in the statement, insisting he had never personally engaged in the discussions. It remained unclear whether <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, if he resigned his speakership, would at the same time resign his seat in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> or if that would happen soon thereafter. The ethics committee would be forced to abandon its case only if <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> left the House. If <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> resigns his speakership, his party would quickly caucus to fill his post and the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> presumably would elect the popular <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, the No. 2 House Democrat. If <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> moved up to speaker, his post of majority leader would become vacant. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif., would be next in line However, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> recently admitted that he failed to include on his financial disclosure forms a $ 50,000 bank loan that he used toward purchasing junk bonds. On Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is conducting a preliminary criminal investigation of whether <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> received favors from <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lambert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the firm that issued the junk bond. After the troubles surrounding <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, some lawmakers were privately promoting Rep. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, D-Mo., for the majority leader's post <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> are political allies, but the <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> Democrat did not rule out such a run. <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> press spokesman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON> said her boss is `` waiting to see what the speaker is going to do. He's listening to people and at this time he just has n't made a decision.'' Rep. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, D-Ga., also was being mentioned for a leadership spot Contenders lining up for <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s No. 3 whip's spot, should he try to move up, included Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., the current chief deputy whip, and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> Chairman Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, The politicking was taking place quietly. `` There's a certain amount of inappropriateness in mounting a campaign before the funeral,'' quipped Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Mont. Some Democrats were distressed at the turn of events, with the speaker seemingly being forced out before the ethics committee even moved into the phase of its proceedings during which <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> could testify and make his case. `` My heart is so heavy that this could happen to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, who in 1986 ran unsuccessfully for whip. <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON> said he was especially bothered by those members who have called for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s resignation because he is embarrassing the House. `` I was outraged because, hell, there's nothing wrong with embarrassing other members of the damned <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said heatedly. `` I just ca n't think how you'd ask someone to damage the office and walk away from it without fighting like hell.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--China-Rabies     05-26 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--China-Rabies,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>80 People In Eastern Province Die Of Rabies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eighty people died from rabies in the eastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> province of <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION> during the first three months of this year, an official daily said today. The <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> quoted a local health official as saying 539 people in the province died from rabies last year. The official said there are now 6 million dogs in <LOCATION> Shandong </LOCATION> despite a ban on keeping dogs in its urban areas. He said anti-rabies vaccine is scarce in many rural areas where dogs are allowed, and many bite victims can not receive treatment in time. There are no national figures for rabies victims. Health officials in southern <LOCATION> Guangdong </LOCATION> province earlier reported 566 deaths from rabies in 1987 and 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FusionWorkshop     05-26 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fusion Workshop,0612</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fusion Workshop Concludes Without Conclusions</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUE MAJOR HOLMES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA FE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Nobel laureate said Thursday that none of the scientists who spent three days discussing experiments on room-temperature fusion believes the research is a key to creating energy. However, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schrieffer </PERSON> said, chemists and physicists are finally talking to each other and are forming collaborations to work together on various cold fusion projects. The Workshop on Cold Fusion Phenomenon, attended by 440 researchers from 14 nations, concluded Thursday without reaching a consensus other than that researchers have a lot of work to do. Physicists, chemists, engineers and other scientists wrangled over the conclusions reached in numerous experiments performed in the two months since <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> researchers announced they had produced nuclear fusion in a jar. The debate centers over the phenomenon of excess heat reported by the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> researchers and the subsequent discovery of nuclear fusion indicators, such as neutrons, reported by other scientists trying to verify the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> work. No one has reported both heat and nuclear particles, leading some to conclude that the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> experiment did not produce cold fusion. <PERSON> Schrieffer </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, said he believes the presence of heat without observed nuclear particles is a `` smoking gun'' in the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> experiments. `` I personally do not believe the heat was from anything but a chemical process,'' he said at a news conference after the session ended. However, he also said he believes experiments that found evidence of a low level of neutrons or gamma rays indicated energy was coming from a fusion source, and those hold promise for scientific study. Fusion has long been touted as the possible energy source of the future. It would be clean because it produces virtually none of the radioactive waste associated with the fission reaction of nuclear power plants, and would be plentiful because the basic fuel would come from water. But <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Hackerman </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> member who co-chaired the conference, told the final session, `` Few of us, if any, look upon this source as a viable source of power.'' <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> researcher whose cold fusion experiments have measured low rates of neutrons, also said he does not believe cold fusion will be a power source. `` It's a rose, not a tree,'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> said. `` It's not going to give us energy, but it is beautiful.'' The cold fusion concept announced by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> chemist <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and British colleague <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> on March 23 stirred the scientific world with its very simplicity. The researchers said they produced a fusion reaction in a simple apparatus. They ran electrical current through electrodes of palladium and platinum in a jar of heavy water, which is made with an isotope of hydrogen called deuterium. <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> reported the release of heat which they attributed to nuclear fusion. They backed down from original claims they measured gamma rays, but have claimed subsequent experiments yielded up to 10 times more energy than was consumed. The two researchers did not attend this week's conference. Papers presented by researchers at <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> A & amp; M <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alamos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> and others reported measuring neutrons or gamma rays or the presence of tritium, but no excess heat. One group led by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Huggins </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> reported heat, but did not test for the presence of nuclear byproducts. Others, such as <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION>, found no indications of heat or nuclear processes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright'sHouse Bjt   05-26 0794</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright's House, Bjt,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Freshmen Reflect: This Isn't What They Came Here For</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON>, owner of five motels and three restaurants in central <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON>, veteran of the internecine battles of the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> legislature. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, ex-Peace Corpsman, son of a congressman, fighter of civic corruption in <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION>, N.Y. They came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in January marching to their own agendas and now find themselves freshmen in a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> preoccupied with its own troubles. `` Self-flagellation'' is what one of them calls it. Another deplores the `` stick it to you'' partisanship he finds here while the people's business waits. <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON> wanted to restore a `` citizens <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' He has a constitutional amendment to limit people to 12 years' service in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, `` then let them have a year to find out again what it is like to get a parking ticket.'' <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> came here to make certain the farmers of upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> had some representation. Nobody from the Empire State had been on the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> for a long time. He wangled a place on it. `` We have lots of dairy farmers,'' he says. Sangmeister ticks off his issues: education, the need to adjust <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s defense posture in view of fresh winds blowing from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, the environment. `` We used to joke about the idea of ` global warming,' but we do n't laugh anymore,'' he says. They talked Thursday about their initiation into a <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that seems obsessed with itself, its pay, its speaker, its ethics. Two months went into maneuvering over whether to take a 51 percent pay raise. Then came the rejected nomination, amid charges of booze and womanizing, of former <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> to be secretary of defense. There was the shabbiness of the <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> affair, the resignation of `` the most powerful aide on the Hill,'' the `` 436th congressman'' after a woman he brutally attacked years ago pointed a finger at him. And now what appears to be the inexorable removal of a speaker of the House for violating an ethics code that did n't exist when he came to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> 34 years ago. At the Capitol on a glorious morning it seemed obvious why <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> would be reluctant to give up his role as king of the Hill. It has been a wet, lush spring. The azaleas and tulips have faded but the magnolias _ white blooms as big as a soup bowls _ are just opening. On the steps of the Capitol, Rep. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mineta </PERSON>, D-Calif., marks time with his feet while the Emerald Regime Marching Band and Color Guard from <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, in gold, green and black, perform a concert for the benefit of anyone happening by For just this moment, the bandsmen lugged their gold, green and black uniforms and their instruments all the way from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Youngsters in baseball caps, their fellow Americans here on class trips, applaud, take snapshots, chew gum. `` What I'm seeing as a new member is a lot more partisanship that I'd have thought,'' says Democrat Sangmeister, inside. `` Almost as though there's a ` Well, it's our turn to stick it to you' atmosphere. `` It started with the Tower matter. Then the <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> affair. Now the Democrats going after -LRB- Newt -RRB- <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> -LRB- new House Republican whip, accused of ethics violations. -RRB- `` The election's over; we ought to be getting on with the people's business,'' <PERSON> Sangmeister </PERSON> said. Republican <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, hurrying to a meeting, pauses in the Speaker's Lobby It is hung with oil portraits of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speakers, the famous and the forgotten. `` Speakers of the House of Representatives of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' says a plaque. `` Chosen by the people, honored by the preferment of their associates.'' <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, whose own father, <PERSON> William </PERSON>, served in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from 1973-79, says he wonders about <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' `` self-flagellation.'' He says he speaks as one who helped send a mayor of <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> to prison, but worries that the image <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is giving itself is destructive in the long run. `` We're good people,'' he says of his colleagues, `` but the people of the country need assurance of that.'' <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON>, the `` citizen congressman,'' the only <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> to win an open Democratic seat last fall, admits he ran using <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> as a symbol of what was wrong in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Now he says he thinks higher of the institution than he might have guessed. He got on the Banking Committee, which immediately plunged into the savings and loan crisis. `` We were there working on that bill day after day. It was n't partisan Everyone came together to honestly solve this problem. The chairman -LRB- Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON> -RRB- was fair, I've got to admit that. He let everyone speak. When we were done, it was after midnight. We gave the chairman a standing ovation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TapDay     05-26 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tap Day,0560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tap Dancing Not Tapped Out Yet</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY McGRATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The rhythmic art of tap dancing, which nearly became extinct during the 1950s, is n't tapped out just yet, a joyful chorus line of dancers proved as they shim-sham-shimmied across the Golden Gate Bridge. `` There is a happiness there when I tap dance,'' said veteran hoofer <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Winston </PERSON>. `` There are very few ways that comes out of my body. It's a natural happiness that comes out of me. I have to tap to live.'' Although wind and salt air threatened to blow off their hats and sandblasters drowned out much of the performance, about 30 dancers hoofed it across the bridge Thursday to celebrate National Tap Dance Day. The national celebration coincided with the birthday of legendary staircase tapper <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> `` Bojangles'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, who was born on May 25, 1878, and died in 1949. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Sandman </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Sims </PERSON> popularized the dance in muscial extravaganzas of the 1930s and 40s, and it later gained respectability on the stage at <LOCATION> Carnegie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>. `` In the 1950s, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> choreographers made the decision not to put tap in Broadway musicals because it got more and more superficial, like a joke, with the big funky moves,'' said <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON>, of <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON> <PERSON> Radiator </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> Supertappers, who helped resuscitate the form during the past two decades after it faded in the'50s. The troupe, led by <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON> in her red flared skirt, white tuxedo vest and sailor hat, is in the Guinness Book of World Records for longest tap dance _ a 7.3-mile performance. Tap, which blends African dance with the Irish jig and lively English clog, originated among black dancers performing on street corners and in saloons. Unlike ballet dancers, tap dancers hold their body limp like a rag doll and use the natural movements to belt out rhythms with their feet. `` It's the way kids move before their mother tells them to stop scraping their feet,'' said <PERSON> Rosie </PERSON>, describing the art of making music with your feet. `` The foot is like a musical instrument and today we are playing the bridge.'' Against a backdrop of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> skyscrapers and a vast expanse of water below, the tappers made their way across the six-land bridge, from <LOCATION> Marin </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> side, where they received a City Hall proclamation. `` Tap dancing is widely recognized as <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s only-original form of dance, yet for years it has been in danger of becoming a lost art,'' said Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich., whose resolution was passed by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday declaring May 25 `` National Tap Dance Day. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approval is expected, he said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <PERSON> D.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, who admitted being a `` frustrated tap dancer'' soon to begin lessons, said former Bojangles dance partner <ORGANIZATION> Lloyd </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Story </ORGANIZATION>, 65, tried to tap on the floor of the House but was barred by the parliamentarian, who said it violated rules against demonstrations. On the bridge, <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelehey </PERSON>, an escalator mechanic who practices on broken escalators in her cowgirl costume, passed the gold-sequined `` torch of tap'' during the single-file relay watched by wide-eyed drivers. `` I do n't care if I'm overweight and pushing 40. I feel like a star,'' she said, thrusting her arms out like <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Merman </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MomentofSilence     05-26 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Moment of Silence,0205</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commercial Radio Stations Plan Moment of Silence Friday</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of commercial radio stations across the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> will go silent for 30 seconds Friday morning as part of a campaign to show the importance of radio in daily life. `` The day the radio stopped'' will mark the beginning of a $ 100 million campaign with the theme: `` Radio. What would life be without it.'' At 7:42 a.m. local time, the booming voice of actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> will tell listeners that `` for the next 30 seconds this station and others would like you to imagine your life without radio. Imagine if all your days sounded like this. ...'' Following the 30 seconds of dead air, <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> will say: `` Thirty seconds seems like a long time, does n't it? Now think how radio fills that silence for you.'' About 8,000 stations, about 80 percent of the nation's commercial stations, will participate, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> The simultaneous promotion will be the largest in the history of radio, said bureau spokesman <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Flamberg </PERSON>. The biggest previous event was in 1986, when 2,000 radio stations simultaneously broadcast `` We Are The World'' to promote hunger relief.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DroughtRelief     05-26 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Relief,0556</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0417 to fix category code.</HEAD>
<HEAD>House Panel Passes Emergency Relief for Drought-Stricken Farmers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has approved emergency relief legislation to help farmers cope with drought devastation to their crops. The bill passed Thursday was originally intended to apply only to winter wheat crops, but numerous amendments offered by congressman in non-wheat states expanded it to include feed grains, cotton, rice, soybeans, peanuts, sugar beets, sugar cane and tobacco. Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., chairman of the Agriculture subcommittee on wheat, soybeans and feed grains and chief architect of the legislation, said the inclusion of the other crops, which either have been affected by dry weather or are susceptible to future drought, was a `` political accommodation. `` We felt if we were going to come with a disaster program, we had only one bite of the apple,'' he said, recognizing that producers of crops other than wheat needed help but acknowledging that a multitude of legislation was not feasible. Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> told the committee in a letter to <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> that he would not recommend that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sign the bill unless it was `` budget neutral.'' In that case, it would have to apply only to 1989 crops affected by drought and be accompanied by a promise that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would agree to use crop insurance as the sole vehicle for disaster assistance after this year. `` I think we are in the ballpark,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Kika </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, after the vote. The concern about crop insurance remains a stumbling block because farmers consider the current program unsatisfactory. `` I hope the secretary wo n't hold this bill hostage in order to pass crop insurance,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. He said the current system, which requires farmers to pay insurance premiums to protect against the effects of bad weather, does n't work <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> la </PERSON> <PERSON> Garza </PERSON> pointed out that <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> improvements to the crop insurance bill would not be completed in time for action on this bill. But he said the progress <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is making should indicate that continued emergency relief such as this legislation will not be needed in the future. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, deputy agriculture secretary in charge of commodities, appeared before the committee to explain <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s concerns After the vote, he said the secretary's first question would be, `` How much will it cost?'' De la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON> estimated that the bill would cost about $ 1 billion, an amount close to what the government will save in price support payments to farmers. An amendment to the bill offered by Rep. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, prohibits disaster relief from exceeding the amount saved in price supports. Since the drought caused a shortage in commodities supply _ primarily wheat _ prices should rise, alleviating the need for government subsidies. The money that had been set aside for the price supports would therefore be used to pay the farmers who lost their crops to drought. The administration wants farmers to purchase crop insurance rather than depend on the government to bail them out when bad weather causes crop failures. The bill would require farmers to have insurance after this year to cope with bad weather or other natural disasters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0045EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BleacherCollapse     05-26 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bleacher Collapse,0144</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bleachers Collapse, Injuring 12 During Graduation Ceremonies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FOWLER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bleachers collapsed Thursday night at a high school gymnasium, injuring at least a dozen people watching graduation ceremonies, a fire official said. At least six people suffered major injuries and six were injured slightly in the accident around 9 p.m. at <ORGANIZATION> Fowler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, said Assistant Fire Chief <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundy </PERSON>. The accident happened as graduation ceremonies for about 30 seniors were ending, <PERSON> Lundy </PERSON> said. `` They were starting the processional and the spectators stood up and it collapsed,'' he said. Rescuers had to lift bleachers off some victims. <PERSON> Lundy </PERSON> said rescuers had to lift the bleachers off some of the victims. He said some of the injured were adults and some were children. The injured were taken to hospitals in <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION> about 30 miles to the northwest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FishStory     05-26 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fish Story,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Angler Rescues Girl From River</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Montagna </PERSON> says a 15-pound salmon was small fry compared to the 9-year-old girl he saved from drowning. <PERSON> Montagna </PERSON>, 43, had landed the fish Sunday at the <LOCATION> Deschutes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> when he saw little Amber <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON> slip from a rock ledge into a treacherous sinkhole. `` I jumped in where I thought she'd be and went down too,'' <PERSON> Montagna </PERSON> said. When he surfaced from the 30-foot-deep river, the girl was nowhere to be seen. `` It was the sickest moment of my life. She could have been inches from my fingers.'' Moments later the girl popped out of the water about 12 feet away. <PERSON> Montagna </PERSON>, an ironworker, grabbed the girl and pulled her out of the water with the help of others on shore. Amber was n't breathing, but her heart was still beating, and she was revived, said her mother, <PERSON> Lola </PERSON> <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON>. `` There are no thanks big enough for this gentleman,'' <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON> said. `` Very few people come out alive because of the rocks. The river is so mean; it just boils.'' `` I was in the right place at the right time,'' <PERSON> Montagna </PERSON> said. The Deschutes runs through Bend in central <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, about 160 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890526-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-26-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w PM-IowaExplosion     05-26 0754</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iowa Explosion,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Probe Relationship Between Two Shipmates in USS Iowa
blast</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NORMAN BLACK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
