<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-EpiscopalConference     06-03 0395</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Episcopal Conference,0404</SECOND>
<HEAD>Episcopal Clergy Convene To Establish Traditionalists Group</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT WORTH, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> bishop has called for recognition of a `` church within a church'' as a haven for conservative Episcopalians opposed to such so-called liberal trends as the ordination of women. `` Let us firmly declare and commit ourselves to the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> and to the provinces of the <ORGANIZATION> Anglican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communion </ORGANIZATION> that it is our will to be the church within the church,'' the Rt. Rev. <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said Thursday. <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>, bishop of the Diocese of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> and president of the Evangelical and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION>, addressed nearly 1,200 delegates at the opening session of the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Synod </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> on Thursday. <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> is president of the Evangelical and <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION>, and he and other bishops in the mission called the synod last year after the Rev. <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> was consecrated as the first female bishop in the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. The bishops called Ms. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>' election `` the final crisis.'' <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> and other speakers contended that segments of the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> are abandoning the biblical faith through decisions to ordain female priests and bishops and efforts to relax moral teachings on sexuality and marriage. `` We must do all we can to remain within this church and do all we can to transform this church,'' said the Rt. Rev. <PERSON> John-David </PERSON> <PERSON> Schofield </PERSON> of the Diocese of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joachin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` If it will not be permitted, then we will have to take the next step when it comes.'' <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>'s laws do not prevent the traditionalists from forming a voluntary association, and he called for the acceptance of the new organization as a way for traditionalists to stay within the church. `` We seek nothing more and nothing less than to provide a way to maintain and propagate the gospel of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> through the unchanged tradition of the historic church. ... Society, we believe, is hungry for this kind of church and gospel _ neither of which is subject to the shifting sands of this present age,'' <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>'s proposal would create a voluntary organization that would allow traditionalist bishops and priests to visit parishes. Traditionalist bishops, a small minority in the 2.9 million-member <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, say the church has lost 1 million members in the past two decades because of liberal changes, including the ordination of women.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StringfellowToxics     06-03 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Stringfellow Toxics,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury: California Must Share Cost of Stringfellow Cleanup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> should share the huge cost of cleaning up the Stringfellow toxic waste site, a project with a potential price tag of up to $ 740 million, a jury decided Friday. The six-member federal jury did not determine how much the state should contribute to the cleanup of the <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> hazardous waste site, leaving that decision to <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ideman </PERSON>. The decision came after less than a day of deliberations. The Stringfellow site opened in 1956 and received an estimated 34 million gallons of acids, pesticides and other toxic materials before it was closed in 1972. The panel ruled the state was liable because it supervised construction of the toxic landfill, delayed cleanup activities and allowed a dangerous condition to exist on public property. The jurors also found the state liable for maintaining a nuisance and breaching its duty to deal with toxic contamination, but ruled the state was not negligent in choosing or designing the site in the early 1950s, or for failing to remedy the toxic contamination. The decision pleased lawyers for <PERSON> J.B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, owner of the quarry that contained the dump and 14 users of the landfill who were all found liable to share cleanup costs by <PERSON> Ideman </PERSON>. `` We believe the implications of today's ruling is that the state will bear the lion's share,'' said attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kahn </PERSON>. <PERSON> Stringfellow </PERSON>, 62, of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> said he was delighted with the jury's decision. `` I feel better,'' he said. `` It's the first time anyone had heard my story.'' Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said the verdict favored the state because it rejected the plaintiffs' claims the state was negligent in choosing and designing the dumpsite, and that it allegedly failed to remedy problems that became apparent in the 1970s. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> hinted that an appeal was possible, saying that he felt the jury would not have found the state liable at all if retired judge <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Peetris </PERSON>, who presided over the fact-finding hearing, had not refused to instruct the jury on several legal defenses possibly applicable to the state. `` It is the opinion of the attorney general's office that these defenses would have barred any finding of liability against the state on the portion of the verdict that dealt with those theories,'' <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said. During the two-month proceeding, Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Noble </PERSON> told the jury operators of the Stringfellow site were to blame because they allegedly failed to follow design specifications in a key area of the dump site. The alleged error allowed toxic materials to overflow barriers and spread into groundwater supplies, she said. Stringfellow attorney <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Bisgaard </PERSON> said his client initially balked at the idea of putting the toxic dump on his property but relented after state officials allegedly promised to help build and operate the dump. <PERSON> Bisgaard </PERSON> said state geologists erroneously determined in 1955 that the quarry was located above an impermeable granite bedrock suitable for safe dumping. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goode </PERSON>, attorney for <ORGANIZATION> Rohr </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION>, one of the companies that dumped chemicals at the Stringfellow site, said the jury decision shifted blame from companies that merely accepted state assurances the site was safe. `` We were found liable without having done anything wrong,'' <PERSON> Goode </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PlaneCrash-Tape     06-03 0494</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plane Crash-Tape,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Hears Cockpit Tape of Final Moments Before Fatal Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An audio tape played in a courtroom Friday featured a copilot saying `` That's a gun,'' following the sounds of shots fired aboard a commuter jetliner that crashed in 1987, killing all 43 people aboard. Jurors heard the pilot and copilot groan loudly after apparent gunfire in the final moments preceding the crash of the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> flight blamed on a gun-toting former airline employee bent on revenge after he was fired for on-the-job theft. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>, 35, of <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> is alleged to have smuggled a .44 - caliber Magnum aboard Flight 1771 on Dec. 7, 1987 by flashing his employee badge at a security gate and bypassing metal Relatives of eight passengers and two crew members are suing <ORGANIZATION> PSA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airports </ORGANIZATION> and a security company, contending they were negligent in allowing <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> to board the jet bound for <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> with a loaded gun. The airline, airport agency and <ORGANIZATION> Ogden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> contend <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> was solely responsible for the fatal crash. <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> was an employee of <ORGANIZATION> USAir </ORGANIZATION>, the parent company of <ORGANIZATION> PSA </ORGANIZATION>, until he was fired by a man he allegedly shot in the passenger section of the plane before he entered the cockpit and fired on the flight crew. <PERSON> Julian </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a pilot and former air traffic controller, testified as an expert witness for the plaintiffs using a recording of the cockpit crew's conversation with an air traffic controller in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. The tape began with the sound of a possible gunshot. Pilot: `` My God!'' -LRB- Sound of second shot. -RRB- Copilot: `` That's a gun.'' Pilot: `` Yeah, I know. Tell'em we got a problem.'' Copilot: -LRB- Sending distress signal. -RRB- Unknown crew member: `` We've got a problem. We've had a gun fired. Are they on board the aircraft?'' Air Controller: `` I beg your pardon.'' Crew member: `` ... and we've had a gun fired on board the aircraft.'' Air Controller: `` OK. Do you want to go to <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> Can you make it, sir?'' -LRB- Sound of door opening. -RRB- Unknown female: `` Hi, Captain.'' Pilot: `` What kind of problem ...'' -LRB- Loud crashing noise. -RRB- Pilot and copilot: `` Ohh.'' -LRB- Loud groan. -RRB- -LRB- Tinkle of breaking glass. Soft banging sound, possibly of the cockpit door banging shut. -RRB- The plane crashed minutes later in central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Special Agent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Varley </PERSON> told the jury a .44 - caliber pistol with six spent cartridges was found in the It was traced to an <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> man who said he loaned it to <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>. <PERSON> Varley </PERSON> said a note _ in <PERSON> Burke </PERSON>'s handwriting and addressed to his former supervisor _ was found that read: `` I think it's sort of ironical we end up like this. I asked for some leniency for my family ... Well, I got none and you'll get none.'' <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Wecht </PERSON>, attorney for the plaintiffs, said <PERSON> Burke </PERSON> bought about $ 350,000 in flight insurance from a terminal vending machine before boarding the airliner.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     06-03 0108</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Correspondent Appointed in Cleveland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kristi </PERSON> <PERSON> Umbreit </PERSON>, correspondent in charge of the <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been appointed correspondent in charge at <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. Columbus Chief of Bureau <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Booher </PERSON> announced the appointment Friday. It is effective June 19. Ms. <PERSON> Umbreit </PERSON>, 36, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in July 1984 as a news clerk in <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>. She became a newswoman in <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> in June 1985 and was promoted to <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> correspondent in October 1987 A native of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, she earned a bachelor's degree in journalism at <ORGANIZATION> Memphis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1984. She began her journalism career with The Memphis Press-Scimitar.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-03 0560</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LUBBOCK, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While some city slickers may think real cowboys are an endangered species, cowboy poets know better. Sixteen cowboy poets participated in Friday's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symposium </ORGANIZATION> and Celebration, reciting verses about bull riding, the cowboy's changing way of life and the barren land they try to tame. `` As long as there are cows and people eat hamburgers, there will be cowboys and my audience will exist,'' said <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, who quit his work as a cattleman and veterinarian in the early 1980s to become a full-time cowboy poet. The poems were melancholy and humorous; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Underwood </PERSON>'s had plenty of whimsy. One verse was about a dream of a scientifically enhanced steer with `` eyes a big a truck headlights, each horn weighed a thousand pounds.'' `` Cowboy poetry is looking at our flaws and foible and laughing at ourselves,'' said <PERSON> Black </PERSON>. `` I try to nudge that fine line between good taste and throwing up in your hat.'' Black recites his poems, which run as long as 10 minutes, from memory almost effortlessly. However, on a recent appearance on the <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> show, he was so nervous he considered using a TelePrompTer. `` But I decided, no, that's not the cowboy way,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SPRINGDALE, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON> will soon return to his watch outside a spinach warehouse. Pranksters stole the 7-foot, 200-pound fiberglass statue last month, but an anonymous tip a few days later led police to <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON>. He was in a ditch. A note, stuck in the sailor's mouth, said: `` We deeply regret the absence of your friend <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON>. We are returning him because he just did n't seem happy with us. He would n't eat his spinich -LRB- sic -RRB- so we figured something was wrong. Help <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON> find his real home.'' The note was signed by a fraternity from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said he doubts that the fraternity took <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Allen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has since repainted the statue. The company also is working on a way to re-erect the monument to spinach vitality `` that we think will be pretty secure,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, spokesman for the family-owned business, said Friday. He said the company is n't looking for the Popeye thieves. `` We're just glad to have <PERSON> Popeye </PERSON> back in the family,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With one flush, <PERSON> Trish </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> saw her wedding go down the toilet. A day before she was to tie the knot, the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> woman accidentally flushed a $ 5,000 engagement ring down her toilet. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, preoccupied with prewedding arrangements, forgot she had wrapped the ring in toilet paper to protect it. After she wiped the sink dry with some other toilet paper, she flushed the whole clump. `` I just about hyperventilated on the floor. I said, ` This is the beginning of the end of my marriage.''' Enter a team of Roto-Rooter employees. The workers tore up the front lawn, built a special dam and flushed gallons of water into a sewer main. And they found it. `` I gave them all the champagne out of my refrigerator,'' said <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION>, a 27-year-old flight attendant. `` I was just passing it out in the street.'' `` It was a real long shot,'' said <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Williamson </PERSON>, a Roto-Rooter employee. `` I did n't think myself that we'd ever get it.'' <PERSON> Trish </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> were married on schedule, May 20.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0721EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PierogiPolka     06-03 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pierogi Polka,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Polka Entrepreneur Appeals To Pierogi Lovers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fitness entrepreneur <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> LoRusso </PERSON> says he wrote `` The Pierogi Diet: 101 Fun Ways to Use and Enjoy Pierogis'' to help flatten the tummies of dance lovers as well as make them laugh. `` A lot of times when I dance at polka festivals, I see people dancing polka and drinking beer, and the one food they buy is dozens of pierogis,'' <PERSON> LoRusso </PERSON>, who sells `` PolkAerobics'' videotapes, said Friday. `` I want to reach these people.'' The book, which sells for $ 2.95, details ways to cut calories and enjoy pierogis, which are flour shells usually stuffed with potatoes, cheese or onions. It suggests topping pierogis with low-fat yogurt instead of sour cream and boiling the pasta pockets rather than frying them. It also suggests using the treats for less orthodox purposes. `` They can take the pierogi and stuff it in their clothes for shoulder pads or make a change purse out of one,'' <PERSON> LaRusso </PERSON> said. When promoting his book, <PERSON> LoRusso </PERSON> plays a kazoo and sings his latest song, `` The <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pierogi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Polka </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ErteSale     06-03 0526</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Erte Sale,0545</SECOND>
<HEAD>Artist Erte Sells Works In Atlantic City Casino</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOYCE A. VENEZIA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Noted artist <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> will collect big money in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, but not by gambling. `` I am bored by gambling,'' the master of art deco design said. Instead, <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> will exhibit and sell some of his private collection in a casino ballroom tonight. In his suite at <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Castle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> and Casino this week, the 96-year-old artist was signing special exhibit books for high rollers who are invited to see and bid on Erte's special exhibit. On Sunday, the exhibit will be open to the public and available for purchase. The collection includes 50 original watercolors, some up to 80 years old. It will also feature some of Erte's distinctive sculptures and jewelry and a costume recently designed by the artist for the new Broadway musical `` Stardust.'' Born <PERSON> Romain </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Tirtoff </PERSON>, the artist took the name Erte from his initials. Today, the tiny white-haired man, who designs his own suits and chunky jewelry, smiled when asked if he has any favorites among his pieces. `` They are all my children and I am their father,'' he said. But he admitted to some affection for one abstract sculpture in his <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> flat, titled `` Autumn.'' `` I will never give it away because it is the center of my decorations,'' he said. The artist said he has created almost 20,000 designs, mostly of women bedecked in elaborate outfits. And Erte's mind and paintbrushes keep flowing. `` Retirement is to die, and I do n't want to die,'' he said. `` I will retire when I die.'' Erte, who is building a new home in <LOCATION> Majorca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, has spent most of his years in a <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> apartment, said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Estorick </PERSON>, managing director of the <LOCATION> Grosvenor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gallery </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Erte </PERSON>'s exclusive world agent `` There have been five different owners of his flat who spent years waiting for him to die,'' <PERSON> Estorick </PERSON> said, chuckling. <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> keeps living a full life, traveling around the world to exhibits and designing costumes and scenery for upcoming theater productions. `` I always make the complete package for a show,'' he said. `` I hate to make costumes for someone else's setting. If one painter makes the background and one the costumes, it's not art, it's an accommodation.'' The end results are richly colored costumes and headpieces melding with spectacular background effects. <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> said he first started drawing at age 3. At 6, he drew an evening dress that his mother later had a dressmaker copy for her to wear. Years later, from 1915 to 1937, he created covers and illustrations for <PERSON> Harper </PERSON>'s Bazaar. He never married, yet he has created thousands of dreamlike images of women, with inspiration that he said comes from heaven. <PERSON> Estorick </PERSON> said <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> `` is not only a meticulous creator, but unlike fashion designers, he is a basic designer and an artist. Other designers have to bring in artists to flesh out their ideas.'' Even with `` the foibles of old age _ rheumatic problems and old teeth _ the fact is that <PERSON> Erte </PERSON> is a discipline machine. He always is a no-nonsense, hard-working artist,'' <PERSON> Estorick </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0708EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PensionRisk Bjt   06-03 0731</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pension Risk, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official Says $1.6 Trillion in Pension Funds Potentially at Risk</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A government watchdog says $ 1.6 trillion in private pension funds are subject to potential fraud and abuse because of loose regulations and lax enforcement of federal pension laws. Labor Department Inspector General <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said in a report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Friday that the problems that leave the pension system open to abuse are much like those that triggered the savings and loan crisis. Unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> acts quickly to strengthen the laws and require the government to improve oversight of pension funds the potential exists for a `` nightmare'' that would dwarf the S & amp; L crisis, <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said in the report. `` As, unfortunately, has been demonstrated by the recent savings and loan crisis, government regulation of an industry does not ensure that invested assets are protected,'' he said. The report drew immediate criticism, however, from a research group that follows employee benefit programs and from the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> itself, which said the pension laws have been strengthened in recent years and are under constant review. `` I think he is very dramatically overstating any problems,'' said <PERSON> Dallas </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Salisbury </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Employee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. He said that as a result of the 1974 law governing pensions, `` the funded status of the private pension system has improved dramatically in each of the last 15 years.'' Also, a spokeswoman for the federal agency that insures private pension funds said <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> appeared to be exaggerating the government's _ and taxpayer's _ potential liability in the event of a major pension funding crisis, the likelihood of which she said was `` remoter than remote.'' But <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON>, while not alleging any specific abuses, said existing laws and regulations allow employers and pension fund managers to hide abuses from the government. He said understaffing at the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> leaves the government little chance to catch offenders. The department, <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said, has just 300 people to monitor and enforce the nation's central pension law and lacks a system to detect when reports pension funds are required to file are delinquent. Permissive regulations allow fund administrators and their accountants to omit from reports information that could alert the government to fraud, abuse and mismanagement, said the inspector general. <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said his and other reviews of enforcement of the 1974 Employee Retirement Income Security Act have found `` a striking number of parallels'' to the current savings and loan crisis, particularly in the failure of managers and private accountants to pinpoint and report significant management and operations problems. The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> attacked that assertion, saying: `` The analogy between the S & amp; L crisis and <ORGANIZATION> ERISA </ORGANIZATION> is a faulty one. On the one hand over recent years S & amp; Ls were largely deregulated while pension rules have become more stringent.'' But <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said the $ 100 billion the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> estimates it will cost <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> taxpayers to rescue savings and loans would appear a bargain should a similar crisis wrack a significant number of the nation's 870,350 private pension funds and a sizable portion of their $ 1.6 trillion in assets _ $ 7,000 for every man, woman and child in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` The burden of insuring and protecting failed benefit plans will fall upon all taxpayers, not just plan beneficiaries and parties, since the <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guarantee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is the final insurer of these plan assets,'' <PERSON> Hyland </PERSON> said. `` Unless steps are taken now, today's <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L bailout may become tomorrow's ERISA nightmare.'' <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoden </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the pension guaranty corporation, said the agency believed the protections of ERISA, while not abuse-free, were strong enough to prevent a crisis in the private pension system. `` Most pension plans are well managed and well funded,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hoden </PERSON> said. `` The likelihood of something like that happening is remoter than remote.'' In the unlikely event of a total or near-total collapse of the private pension system, PGBC would be liable for its assets plus its line of credit with the federal <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, now $ 100 million, Ms. <PERSON> Hoden </PERSON> said. The agency's assets now total $ 2.6 billion and are expected to top $ 10 billion in the next decade, she said. The government is not bound to back the agency beyond the limits of the credit line _ unlike its responsibility to cover all insured bank deposits if the government agencies that insure them run short of cash, Ms. <PERSON> Hoden </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0709EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DroughtAssistance     06-03 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drought Assistance,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Allows Haying, Grazing on Conservation Set-Aside Land</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is opening up millions of acres of erosion-prone land for hay cutting and livestock grazing to help farmers in drought-stricken areas. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> announced the assistance on Friday, saying producers in more than 500 counties in 16 states currently could be eligible. `` Livestock producers have exhausted stocks of hay that were carried into winter, and they are now faced with another dry spring,'' Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` So they're out of hay and short of grass. The land being made available is part of a conservation reserve program that pays people to take their most erosion-prone land out of production for at least 10 years and improve it by planting grasses and trees. The haying assistance would be authorized county by county in states where a livestock emergency has been declared, currently 16 states, mostly in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION>, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. Tighter restrictions would be placed on livestock grazing on the so-called CRP acres. It would be allowed only after a visual inspection of the land by the <ORGANIZATION> Soil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to ensure it would not suffer any damage. The 16 states are: <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>. County offices of the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stabilization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> must seek authority for the haying and grazing privileges. <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipp </PERSON>, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s press secretary, said about 570 counties in the 16 states were eligible currently to apply for the CRP-related assistance because they had received livestock emergency declarations. Additional counties and states could become eligible later. As of last year, 28 million acres nationwide _ 19 million of those in the 16 states _ had been enrolled in the conservation reserve program, which was established by the 1985 farm law as a way to reduce erosion and trim overproduction on marginal land. The government paid $ 1.4 billion in yearly rental payments to producers participating in the program. Friday's announcement is the latest federal aid made available to farmers facing crop and livestock losses from lingering drought conditions. It followed <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> earlier this week and earlier visits to <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> last month authorized livestock grazing and hay cutting on land taken out of production under this year's commodity programs, but put off a decision on conservation reserve acreage. In addition, livestock and poultry producers have been allowed to buy surplus government-owned grain at discount prices. These restrictions will apply to the <ORGANIZATION> CRP </ORGANIZATION> assistance: _ Rental payments to producers next year will be cut 50 percent for those who cut hay or graze livestock Nationwide, annual payments averaged $ 48 an acre last year. _ No <ORGANIZATION> CRP </ORGANIZATION> land with grasses planted after July 1, 1987, will be eligible _ Only one hay cutting will be allowed, and none permitted after July 15 At least three inches of stubble must be left, and a one-fourth of each field must be left untouched to provide cover for wildlife. _ Local <ORGANIZATION> ASCS </ORGANIZATION> operations will determine how long grazing will be permitted on <ORGANIZATION> CRP </ORGANIZATION> land as well as the number of livestock No grazing will be allowed after Aug. 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0709EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-VAMortgageRates     06-03 0195</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-VA Mortgage Rates,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>VA Cuts Rate to 10 Percent</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Veterans Affairs Department is reducing its home mortgage interest rates by half a percentage point, a move that could save purchasers more than $ 300 a year on a typical <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> loan of $ 75,000. Effective Monday, the maximum interest rate for the federally backed loans will drop to 10 percent. It is the first change in the VA rate since Dec. 19, when the rate rose from 10 percent to 10.5 percent. VA home loans may be used to purchase, improve or refinance a home or condominium and to purchase or refinance a manufactured home. Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> said the action `` reflects continued investor confidence in the economy as well as current financial market conditions in which investors are willing to accept lower yields on long-term investments.'' The department said that effective Monday, a variety of other mortgage rates also will fall by a half-point. The maximum rate for graduated-payment mortgages will fall to 10.25 percent; home improvement loans, 11.5 percent; manufactured home loans, 12.5 percent; manufactured home lot-only loans, 12 percent; and manufactured home and lot loans, 12 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0710EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls-CapitalRequirements     06-03 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls-Capital Requirements,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>S&amp;L Capital Requirements to Rise, But Rules Likely to Change</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most savings and loan associations will have to increase the amount of capital they keep in reserve, the government says. The increase is required by current regulations that tie the capital standards to the industry's annual profitability. As a result, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that minimum requirements for most savings and loans will rise from the current 3.44 percent of liabilities to 3.75 percent at the start of next year. The regulations would gradually increase capital requirements to 6 percent. The rules, however, are likely to be superseded by legislation under consideration in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that would overhaul S & amp; L regulations and require thrift operators to put more of their own money at risk to stay in business. The tougher capital requirements proposed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as part of his S & amp; L bailout package have been the subject of intense debate on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, with differences between <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> proposals likely to be ironed out by a joint conference committee. Under the changes announced Friday by the bank board, <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls in the standard group _ which includes healthy thrifts and covers about 80 percent of the industry _ would see their capital requirements rise to 3.60 percent on July 1 and to 3.75 percent next January. Capital requirements vary case by case for <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls in the lower group _ made up of thrifts experiencing financial difficulty or under federal supervision _ but their required capital would rise by 0.19 percent on July 1 and another 0.18 percent next January.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0710EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JudicialSelection     06-03 0573</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Judicial Selection,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dispute With Bar Over Judicial Selection Settled, Thornburgh Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> may have too much influence in the selection of federal judges, a position that puts him in partial agreement with conservative critics. `` In some respects, the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>'s standing committee has become larger than life,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said Friday at a hearing of his committee. He was referring to the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>'s Standing Committee on Federal Judiciary. `` Surely the -LRB- Judiciary -RRB- committee has over the years, given the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> standing committee an exalted status,'' he said. But <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> also said that the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>'s opinion on judges was sought in the past because `` cronyism and not competence was all too often the reason for choosing a nominee.'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> spoke the same day that Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> told reporters he considered his dispute with the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> over judicial selection to be settled. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> told reporters he regarded an agreement reached with the bar group last month `` to be dispositive of this issue.'' Conservative senators have been smoldering ever since four of the standing committee's 15 members voted to find then-Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> unqualified for a seat on the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Joined by a number of other lawmakers, conservative senators have been calling for an overhaul or even an end to the process under which the committee meets behind closed doors and does not explain how it arrives at its conclusions or how the individual committee members voted. The system, Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, `` is a moldering, corrupted, malodorous old relic which should be given a quick burial for the sake of public health.'' Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> it `` is no longer appropriate that this one private organization be granted a status not accorded to any other group.'' `` It exercises a virtual veto over judicial nominees,'' <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON> said. But Sen. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, scoffed at what he called conservative concerns over the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>'s liberal focus. He said he had been an <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> member for decades and `` there's no question about it _ I would put the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> on the conservative side.'' `` Who are you kidding?'' <PERSON> Metzenbaum </PERSON> said. `` This is the hierarchy of all the big corporate law firms in the country.'' Under the new agreement with the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>, the group promised to drop a disputed paragraph from a brochure outlining its methods of reviewing potential nominees for the federal bench. The paragraph to be erased says: `` Political or ideological philosophy are not considered, except to the extent that they may bear upon other factors.'' Far from barring consideration of politics, critics say, the paragraph specifically opens the door to such inquiries. <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> officials also promised to refrain from weighing the ideology and political philosophy of potential candidates for judge whose names are sent to it for review by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. The officials, however, made a point of adding they had never considered those factors in their evaluations. Names of potential federal judges are sent to the president by senators and other influential officials. Before they are nominated by the president, they are evaluated by the administration and investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>. Since 1953, the government also has maintained an arrangement under which potential candidates are screened by the <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION>, the major professional association of the nation's lawyers, before the president sends their names to Capitol Hill for confirmation by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-03 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLESLEY, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON>, former <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> presidential campaign manager, told graduates at the 111th <ORGANIZATION> Wellesley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> commencement to take precautions against crime but not to be ruled by fear. She said Friday that the recent beating and rape in Central Park of a <LOCATION> Wellesley </LOCATION> graduate brought memories of a tragedy that occurred to her in 1974, two days before she graduated from <LOCATION> Wellesley </LOCATION>. `` On my way home from a rehearsal right here, in the parking lot of my new <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> apartment, I was raped,'' she said. `` I can not tell you why black teen-agers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> would abuse and beat a jogger, or why white teen-agers in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> would sexually abuse a mentally impaired girl they had gone to school with all their lives,'' <PERSON> Estrich </PERSON> told the 511 graduates of the all-women college. `` And you do not need me to remind you about locking doors, and traveling in twos and, not taking unnecessary risks. I can only tell you that after you have done all that, fear can harm you more than crime.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, on her first trip back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> since President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took office, told friends and reporters that her memoirs will be a page-turner. `` I'm going to say everything I could n't say for eight years,'' she said Friday at a tea party. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to address a Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> symposium on first ladies' memoirs. She assured about 100 people at the party that she and the former president love their <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> life. But she said at times she misses being first lady. With a mischevious grin, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> confessed to a group of reporters, `` I even miss you.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PASO ROBLES, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The King of <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> claims he's overtaxed <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> Hassan </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> is appealing a recent property tax assessment on his sprawling central <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> ranch 175 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The monarch owns more than 16,000 acres of ranchland with an assessed value of nearly $ 3.7 million. But the king's lawyer said Thursday the property was only worth about half that much. The difference in the tax bill is about $ 20,000 a year, said attorney <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Baggett </PERSON>. He said he believes a compromise can be reached without a formal appeals hearing.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The class of ` 69 had its dreams, and it seems many of them came true. Among the graduates expected at <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flora </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>'s 20th reunion this weekend were <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Ussery </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION>; Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Califf </PERSON>, cardiologist at <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Tompkins </PERSON>, Gov. <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>'s chief of staff. `` It's a very unique class,'' said graduate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinkins </PERSON>, who enjoys his own bit of fame in the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> area as owner of <PERSON> Bullwinkle </PERSON>'s club. `` There are a lot more successful people in our class than probably should have been expected.'' But <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said even in high school there was a feeling the class was special. `` It really was an enchanted period of my life _ it was a <LOCATION> Camelot </LOCATION> atmosphere,'' <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON> said. `` I do think many of us were very conscious that it was a group of the best and the brightest. I felt very fortunate growing up where I did and going to school where I did.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RHINEBECK, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One week after meeting with about 200 recovering drug addicts, millionaire businessman <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> donated $ 25,000 to <LOCATION> Day-Top </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, a rehabilitation center. <PERSON> Day-Top </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON> said Thursday the money may be used toward building a new center for adolescents. When he visited <PERSON> Day-Top </PERSON>, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> shared the story of his brother <PERSON> Fred </PERSON>, who died from alcoholism at age 43.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tour of the musical version of `` Our Town'' was canceled after actress <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> pulled out for medical reasons, according to a published report. The 76-year-old <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, who starred in Broadway's `` <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>'' and `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Pan </PERSON>,'' was to appear in `` Grovers Corners.'' `` It's a major disappointment because she's one of the few who can still build a huge ticket advance on her name alone,'' <PERSON> Price </PERSON> <PERSON> Berkley </PERSON>, who publishes the Theatrical Index trade newsletter, told the <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. The nature of Miss <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>'s medical problem was not disclosed in the newspaper's report Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NuclearDump     06-03 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Dump,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Re-examining Possible Geological Fault at Nevada Site</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is taking a second look at the possibility of a geological fault near the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> site where the nation's first permanent dump for high-level nuclear waste is planned. The department, which previously had concluded there was no such fault, sent a team of scientists to <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> last month to review existing data on the question `` to make sure we did n't overlook something,'' department spokeswoman Ginger King said Friday. The review was prompted by the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which raised questions about the department's decision to dismiss a 1982 study that reported the possible fault, said <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON>, manager of the <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> project, the name for the planned dump. `` There does n't appear to be a fault,'' <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON> said in a telephone interview, but it's not possible to know for sure until the department begins actual digging work. That work ca n't start until <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> grants certain permits, he said. The site borders the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Test Site, where underground nuclear tests are conducted. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, which must approve a license for the waste repository, also recommended more extensive study on whether the site contains significant amounts of gold, <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON> said. Any gold mining activity could disrupt the repository, but <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON> said preliminary <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> studies indicated no significant amounts of any valuable minerals at the site, which is about 100 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. He said additional studies were planned, but that the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> wanted even more. The dump is intended to entomb 70,000 tons of highly radioactive waste from commercial nuclear reactors and from the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s nuclear weapons plants. Numerous sites were under consideration early in the decade, but in 1987 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> decreed that the search would be limited to <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> state government strongly objects to the project and has accused the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> of disregarding the 1982 study that said there may be an uncharted fault parallel to the Ghost Dance Fault, which cuts through the site. In a letter to <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON> on Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Nevada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said the 1982 report contains `` strong evidence'' of a fault intersecting the area where two exploratory shafts would be drilled. Earthquakes could destabilize the holes. The state contends that if the additional fault were confirmed it would disqualify <LOCATION> Yucca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> as a waste dump because the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s site criteria rule out sites with underground facilities closer than 100 feet from a fault. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> raised a similar point, according to <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagner </PERSON>, a commission spokeswoman. She said the department was told in a meeting in early May that `` it looks like they may be violating their own criteria.'' She said the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> would publish a lengthy analysis of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s preliminary site study in July. <PERSON> Gertz </PERSON> said a team of researchers would spend the next two months reviewing all the existing scientific data on the possible existence of an uncharted fault, but that the key to ending the debate was getting started with exploratory drilling. `` Rather than rehash all their old data we want to get on the mountain,'' he said. King said Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> had begun reviewing the project plans and schedules in light of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>'s objections and a series of delays in the program that have drawn the ire of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the nuclear utility industry. She said <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> had not yet come to any conclusions about possible changes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Fauntroy     06-03 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fauntroy,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>DC Delegate to Congress Says He's Violated No Laws</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The District of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s non-voting congressional delegate, whose office personnel practices are under preliminary investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, says he has done nothing to violate the law or the rules of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. In a statement Friday to reporters, <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> complained about <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> leaks concerning the probe and said he is `` cooperating fully'' with authorities. He also said The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> has `` consistently'' filed misleading stories over the past six months. In declaring his innocence, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> also said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has `` subpoenaed personnel records that are not in my possession nor mine to give.'' <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>, a non-voting Democratic delegate to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, said Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> `` simply must get control of his agency.'' He urged <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to appoint an independent counsel to look into the news leaks that have provided the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> with material for some of its stories. The AP reported last November that <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, the son of Rep. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill., was on <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON>'s payroll from Sept. 8, 1987, to June 13, 1988, and that for a portion of that time he also was campaigning for election to the <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> also reported that in his election petition, <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> said he resided in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. In his statement, <PERSON> Fauntroy </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> had failed to report that <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> was placed on an unpaid leave of absence for the 10 weeks `` that he was in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> campaigning for a state office.'' AP's original story on Nov. 29, 1988, reported that <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> records showed <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> had been on an unpaid leave of absence for six weeks during that period. House records that could resolve the discrepancy were unavailable late Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0254EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Urban     06-03 0547</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Urban,0566</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Man `Poles Love to Hate' Running for Parliament</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 His television campaign ridicules his prominent ears as `` disquieting, even fatal.'' Known as the man Poles love to hate, polls show he is trailing his Solidarity-backed candidate by a 7-1 margin in the race for a seat in parliament in Sunday's balloting. He is <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Urban </PERSON>, the loyal government spokesman for <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s communist authorities since 1981 Urban was the point man for seven years in the government's campaign against the Solidarity union movement And he was among the first government officials to announce his candidacy in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s first democratic elections since World War II. In his usually provocative manner Urban, who is now information minister, is running as an independent. The Sejm, or parliament, has 460 seats and 161 are open to opposition candidates, including independents. The other seats are reserved for members of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and its allies. As government spokesman, Urban gave his first news conference in December 1981 on the day the government imposed martial law and suppressed Solidarity. The independent union movement subsequently was outlawed but was legalized again in April following negotiations that also set the framework for Sunday's elections. Over the years Urban belittled Solidarity founder <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> as the `` former head of a former union.'' Now he is running for a <ORGANIZATION> Sejm </ORGANIZATION> seat in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s center-city district against <PERSON> Andrzej </PERSON> <PERSON> Lapicki </PERSON>, a Soviet-endorsed actor. Opposition polls show Urban to be a heavy underdog. But the results could be affected by the large number of ballots expected to be cast by Poles abroad. The district has about 140,000 eligible voters, but some 600,000 Poles abroad, including many embassy and government contract workers, also will have their ballots counted in the district. Urban was promoted to information minister on April 17, the day Solidarity became legal again. As government spokesman he conducted weekly news conference that were televised and gave him a national audience. He frequently would mention polling data showing more than half of the population disapproved of him, but his news conferences were the highest rated weekly show on television. In the first few days of the campaign the opposition newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Gazeta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyborcza </ORGANIZATION> had so many articles concerning Urban that one letter writer told the editors to avoid `` Urbanophobia.'' <PERSON> Ryszard </PERSON> <PERSON> Straus </PERSON>, an Urban aide, said of the polls: `` Urban is in a better situation than other candidates because he is a well-known person and does not have to introduce himself to the public like the others, so it is a big advantage. Ninety-six percent of people questioned said they knew who Urban was.'' Urban is a journalist and satirist who was associated with Prime Minister <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> weekly Polityka. He mocks his distinctive appearance _ a small man with a circular bald pate and large ears. In a program on state television, controlled by Urban as information minister, a singer sang, `` Strange ears had he, strange hears had he,'' while Urban was shown as a child, teen-ager and young man. Video-writing drew circles around his ears to make them look even larger. In a country where many politicians are rigid and humorless, Urban recently told a campaign rally, `` Everyone knows who I am.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0713EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SwissArmy Bjt   06-03 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Swiss Army, Bjt,0687</SECOND>
<HEAD>Socialists, Split Over Zero Army Proposal, Hold Crucial Meeting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TRUDY STUDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERN, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A divided <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> gathered today to discuss an extraordinary proposal: disbanding this neutral nation's 625,000-member army. About 1,000 delegates were to decide the party's official stand in a Nov. 26 national referendum on dismantling the army. The proposal for unlateral disarmament is given no chance at the polls, but the Socialists' position on it could have an impact on the country's 30-year-old coalition government. The proposal has drawn fierce reactions from the Socialists' three center-right partners in a governing alliance often cited as a prime factor in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>'s political stability A leader of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Christoph </PERSON> <PERSON> Blocher </PERSON>, has said an anti-army decision by the <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION> should spell the end of the government coalition. <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>'s army has not fought a foreign war for five centuries but Western military experts have rated it as one of the world's best-trained and most highly motivated forces. The Socialists' right wing and trade union leaders were seeking a resolution to keep the army. The left wing was inclined toward dismantling the army. Party President <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Hubacher </PERSON> predicted that the meeting, which was to open in <LOCATION> Bern </LOCATION> today, would decide not to issue a recommendation. That, too, would provoke criticism from the center-right. The anti-army proposal was authored by socialists and religious pacifists. They collected 113,000 signatures backing a proposed amendment to the federal constitution saying `` <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> has no army'' and deleting all references to defense needs. Under the system of direct democracy in this nation of 4.2 million voters, the signatures were enough to force a nationwide vote. Even supporters admit the proposal has no chance of winning and was mainly meant as a pro-disarmament demonstration. But it has posed a predicament for the Socialists, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>'s second-largest political party, ever since being officially submitted three years ago In its platform, the party endorses <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>'s armed neutrality but it has a record of being critical about the defense budget and procurement plans. <PERSON> Hubacher </PERSON>, 63, a former infantry private, urged unsuccessfully a clear position against the proposal, which he called `` a rotten egg.'' `` It is an illusion to think we should set an example and disarm,'' he said in an interview. `` It is not we who are a threat to the world but the big powers.'' The two Socialist members of the seven-member federal executive, Foreign Minister <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Felber </PERSON> and Finance Minister <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Stich </PERSON>, also have spoken against the proposal. Senior party members warned that supporting the proposal would boost conservative groups that split from the main party in recent years. But warnings have not stemmed a surprisingly strong pacifist groundswell in the party, particularly among the young and in urban regions. At the special congress, the party's future defense concept is the only point on the agenda. Recent public opinion polls suggest that about one of four voters might sympathize with the `` zero option.'' Women appear to oppose disbanding the army more than men, though feminist groups favor the proposal. Polls are not always reliable in multilingual, multicultural <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. But even the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Neue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zuercher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeitung </ORGANIZATION> newspaper in a recent editorial conceded a `` declining trend'' in popular support of the army. Protests have been growing against low-flying combat planes, projects to expand army exercise grounds, and noise from mandatory regular target practice by militia members at the country's 2,500 shooting ranges. But most Swiss remain opposed to a farewell to arms in the country where the military has a long tradition. `` I understand every voting citizen who may be tempted to use this occasion for venting personal anger at the army or the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>,'' Defense Minister <PERSON> Kaspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Villiger </PERSON> was quoted as telling the independent <PERSON> Basler </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeitung </PERSON> newspaper. `` But this time, we are closely watched from abroad. And therefore it is particularly important to make plain as firmly as possible that we remain committed to armed neutrality and to the defense of our country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0713EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Foley Bjt   06-03 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foley, Bjt,0474</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foley Says He Will Try to Repair Broken Bonds in Congress</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELISABETH DUNHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man likely to succeed <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker believes both parties are tired of partisan mudslinging and is pledging to use his ties to Democrats and Republicans to improve the atmosphere in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., spoke critically Friday of the ethics war sweeping <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in recent months But <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, known as a consensus builder, also praised the work of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which comprises six Democrats and six Republicans. `` The committee has won a broad degree of public respect in the manner in which it's handled the difficult issues before it,'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said. `` What we are talking about is the use of ethics issues as a tool or instrument of recrimination, partisanship. `` It's not the ethics committee, it's the members on either side who are trying to come up with some concept of abusive charges.'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority leader, said members of both parties are guilty of using ethics issues for recrimination and partisanship. `` I think the vast majority of members on both sides of the aisle are tired of that sort of tactic,'' he told reporters at the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> headquarters following a private luncheon with <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democrats. The 60-year-old <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said he hopes to restore the public's confidence and mutual respect in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> `` We have to reach out on both sides of the aisle to try and change the mood of bitterness, which exists to some degree, and hard feelings, which exist to some degree in both parties, and get back to a mood of mutual respect and conciliation which can, and must be, the basis of any effective parliamentary body,'' he said. First elected to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1964, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> has been described by colleagues in both parties as the ideal leader to bring a bipartisan spirit back to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in the wake of resignations by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, D-Calif. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> provided no specifics on how he plans to fight resentments and abuses in both parties But he said he hopes to create a task force to examine issues like the code of conduct, ethical standards and whether to limit or abolish fees representatives receive for speeches and appearances. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> recently acknowledged that he failed to report a loan from a savings and loan whose chief executive helped set him up in a junk bond deal. He said last week he is quitting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rather than endure an ethics investigation like the one that felled <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> resigned Wednesday following a yearlong, $ 1.5 million investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee that led to charges he violated <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules in 69 instances.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Glance     06-03 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Glance,0275</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>A Look at Poland Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are facts and figures on <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s parliamentary and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> elections Sunday:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 WHAT'S AT STAKE _ Of 460 seats in the Sejm, or parliament, 161 _ or 35 percent _ are open to opposition candidates. The remaining 299 are set aside for members of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> or its allies. All the seats are contested, except for a `` national list'' of 35 positions for which the communist coalition selected unopposed candidates. There are 1,745 candidates nationwide for the 425 contested seats. In the newly created <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, all 100 seats are freely contested, making it the first fully democratically picked legislative chamber in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. There are 553 candidates nationwide for those seats.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 VOTING _ The polls will be open from 6 a.m. to 10 p.m. There will be 22,411 polling places in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and about 205 abroad, mainly at Polish diplomatic posts and construction projects. There are 27,211,188 eligible voters, according to the government. Voters must be 18. If they live abroad, they must provide proof of Polish citizenship. Voters cast ballots by crossing out all names on the ballot except that of the chosen candidate.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 VICTORY MARGIN _ Candidates must receive more than half of the votes. If none does, the two candidates receiving the most ballots will participate in run-off elections June 18. The candidates on the `` national list'' in the uncontested races also must receive more than 50 percent of the votes. If they do not, the seat will not be filled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0343EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IowaInvestigation     06-03 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iowa Investigation,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iowa Crewman's Friend Recalls Talk of Suicide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sailor who survived the USS Iowa explosion says he heard his friend and crewmate talk of suicide but never of blowing up a ship. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported earlier Friday that investigators of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> explosion are focusing on <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>, who was one of the 47 sailors to die in the blast April 19. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> was often despondent and aloof, and that he reportedly told a witness, `` If you've got to go, go in a blast. You go quick. You go painless.'' But <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s friend, Gunner's Mate 3rd Class <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, said on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Nightline'' that he did n't take <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s talk of suicide seriously. `` The way he described, you know, killing himself would have been just simply -LRB- to -RRB- walk off the ship,'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said. `` He never talked about an explosion.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said he remembered that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> `` was a little down, but it was over a year and a half ago. He had at one point -LRB- talked about suicide -RRB- but it was n't very serious. ... I think we all talk about suicide at least once in our life, and at the time the divisions were razzing him about how close friends we were.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>, 25, was the last man to touch the gunpowder that exploded in the ship's second turret on April 19. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> reported a witness told investigators that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> showed off a $ 15 timer available in hobby stores and said that if it were rigged to a battery it could set off the ship's gunpowder and start a chain of explosions. But <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, said on `` Nightline'' that he believed the explosion may have been caused by an inexperienced crew working with gunpowder that he contended was unstable because it was stored improperly. Last week, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigators said the gunpowder had been stored at unusually high temperatures at one point. But they also said that would not have affected its stability. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> also said he had talked to an <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> crewman who remembered hearing someone say shortly before the blast, `` Tell them we're not ready yet.'' <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Baumann </PERSON> said he could not comment on the network report, and expressed regret that leaks about the investigation were distressing relatives and ship's crew. <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> could have inserted a homemade detonator between bags of gunpowder in the breech of the turret's center 16-inch gun, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> explosive experts have successfully tested a similar timing device in a simulation, the network added. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> also reported that a witness told investigators that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> had shown him a timing device and said words to the effect that he could blow the ship up. The network said no remnants of a timer were found, but firefighting may have washed them away. Investigators reportedly said such a device could have given off smoke or made a noise that could have served as a warning to other sailors. It had been known earlier that the last words of sailor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, spoken into a internal ship telephone, were, `` We've got a problem in here.'' A different voice was heard saying something that sounded like `` smoke smoke smoke, help help,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said. Many sailors' bodies were found in defensive positions, hunched over with their arms covering their heads, the network said. In addition, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said investigators found that <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> had written letters that spoke of his death and the destruction of the second turret. The network quoted sources as saying they believed <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> lived in a fantasy world and told relatives of an upcoming transfer to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> that the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said he had not been given. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> was heard by two other sailors as saying immediately after the blast, `` I ca n't believe he actually did it.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said on `` Nightline'' that he did not recall making such a statement and added, `` He -LRB- <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> -RRB- never talked about blowing up a ship or anything.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> has asked the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> for an apology for linking his name to the criminal investigation of the explosion. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said Friday at a news conference, `` If the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> wants to reveal it they will, and they're going to; he's going to be cleared.'' Responding to <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>'s comments, <PERSON> Baumann </PERSON> said Friday night, `` How can we clear him? We have n't accused him of anything.'' He read from a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> statement that said: `` The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> recognizes with regret the additional anguish press reports from some unidentified sources have placed on the families of deceased <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> shipmates as well as the crew itself. `` We wish to assure these families the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> remains committed to a thorough and complete investigation and hopes that a responsible public understands the need for discretion until all the factors can be amassed and evaluated.'' <PERSON> Baumann </PERSON> said <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>'s comments were `` the gist of why we're putting this out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0348EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HondurasAid     06-03 0517</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Honduras Aid,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Department Official Backs Away From Testimony on Honduras Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURIE ASSEO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official is backtracking from his denial that a plan was carried out to link aid to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> with help to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels, and a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee chairman says he will ask more questions about the plan. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON>, assistant secretary of state for inter-American affairs, testified on April 25 that the `` plan was disapproved, at the objection of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, on the grounds that conditionality _ linkage between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance and any -LRB- Honduran -RRB- assistance to the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- resistance _ was contrary to <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. policy.'' `` The whole proposed linkage that was included in -LRB- the -RRB- plan was disapproved, was not made, there was no ` discreet emissary,''' <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations subcommittee on foreign operations chaired by Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>. But in a letter to Obey this week, <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> said, `` I certainly did not intend to imply by these statements, however, that decisions to provide assistance to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> on an expedited basis were not thereafter made or carried out.'' <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> had testified that an admission of facts agreed to by both sides and used in former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial was misleading. Among other trial documents was a Feb. 1985 memo initialed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and approving a plan to link more than $ 110 million in extra aid to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>' support for the Contra rebels. Then-Vice President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> traveled to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and met with President <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordova </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he did not discuss any possible quid pro quo with <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON>. After examining the secret documents used to draw up the admission of facts, <PERSON> Obey </PERSON> wrote <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> that his testimony did not seem to jibe with the documents. Obey said Friday that <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> wrote back to say, `` Because I am responding from the perspective of the department and my own personal knowledge, I can not speak to documents from other agencies or the thoughts and actions of persons other than myself.'' A separate letter to Obey from Assistant Secretary <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON> said, `` Information about non-departmental personnel and activities should be sought from other, appropriate sources'' which she did not specify. Obey said <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON>'s letter to him `` seemed to indicate that his original testimony left the wrong impression.'' `` His letter, without specifically reversing that, simply said, ` I'm sorry if we left the impression that the plan was not carried out,''' Obey said. Obey said he believed `` there's absolutely no question that it was carried out. The documents laid out the plan ... the additional assistance we know did arrive.'' <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON>'s letter will lead to more questions that will be addressed both to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the White House, including questions about aid to other Central American countries, Obey said. Last month, Obey threatened to hold up $ 700 million in aid for <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> unless administration officials concede they misled lawmakers about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts to win third-country help for the Nicaraguan rebels. <PERSON> Kozak </PERSON> did not return a message left at his home phone Friday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     06-03 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Won't Let PLO Reopen Washington Office</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has turned down a request to let the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> reopen the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration shut down in 1987. The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> representative of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, Ambassador <PERSON> Clovis </PERSON> <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>, told reporters earlier Friday that he had asked the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to permit the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to reopen the office. <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON> said it was `` mind-boggling'' for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to maintain a dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, begun last December, while refusing the organization permission to reopen its office here. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, responding to press inquiries about <PERSON> Maksoud </PERSON>'s statement, said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 prohibited the establishment of any <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> office in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Byrd Urges Open Cambodian Policy</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, is urging the administration to seek an open <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> rather than trying to secretly arm non-communist guerrillas `` There is much at stake here and it seems inadvisable to engage in secret deals, secret policy, secret aid, and repeat the mistakes of the very recent past,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Friday. `` If we are to re-engage in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> let us do so,'' said <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, the former majority leader who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` But let us do so only after thorough, open debate, with discussions of options and the careful formulation of a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in concert with other nations that wish to bring long-term peace and stability to <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> announced last April 1 that it will end its 10-year occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and withdraw all of its military forces by next Sept. 30.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Harris Corp. Pleads No Contest</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> company has agreed to pay $ 200,000 in fines and $ 300,000 to settle civil claims by the government arising from an investigation of fraud involving weapons sales to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which is based in <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, pleaded no contest Friday to a criminal charge it aided and abetted the filing of a false statement by a Filipino businessman convicted of defrauding the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The company entered the no-contest plea in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in nearby <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>. The action was announced by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> admitted that its Farinon Division agreed to falsely inflate to $ 3.38 million the value of a $ 2.4 million subcontract it obtained from businessman <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> to sell electronic equipment to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> military under the program, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said. <PERSON> Harris-Farinon </PERSON> agreed to kick back $ 1.03 million of the $ 3.38 million to a <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> shell corporation operated by <PERSON> Moreno </PERSON> in the guise of a marketing fee, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 4thLd-Writethru   06-03 0939</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0782,0968</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Chinese Troops Fire Tear Gas, Beat Student Protesters</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with troops firing tear gas on
crowds in Tiananmen Square, details. Picks up graf 3 pvs, `Troops on ...'
TRIMS thereafter to shorten and conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese riot police fired tear gas Saturday on crowds near <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in a renewed attack against pro-democracy students occupying the central square. Witnesses also reported at least 30 people were beaten by police outside the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Hotel. About 700 to 800 riot police used tear gas to clear an area around the entrance to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headquarters at <LOCATION> Zhongnanhai </LOCATION>, just west of the square. They also attacked students and others with truncheons. About 5,000 troops, meanwhile, confronted and were quickly surrounded by crowds outside the Great Hall of the People who were defying martial law restrictions imposed last month by Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. The troop advance came hours after larger contingents of soldiers were driven back by throngs of people who implored the soldiers not to crush the student-led movement for democractic reform that began in mid-April. On the west side of the Great Hall, opposite from the square, crowds quickly grew into the thousands and blocked the troops from advancing onto <LOCATION> Changan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, the main street running past the square. A city bus was moved in front of the troops to impede their advance. Large crowds stood on top of the bus and inside it. About a half-mile to the west, near <LOCATION> Zhongnanhai </LOCATION>, students and others were throwing rocks at riot police, who were armed with truncheons and knives. One man, his chest bloodied, said he had been beaten by police. Chinese witnesses said riot police also battled crowds shortly after noon outside the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, to the east of the square. They said about 30 people have been beaten by police carrying truncheons before the police had left the area and headed toward the north, away from the square. Meanwhile, an official report said three people were killed when struck by a police car in an accident Friday night. Students linked the deaths to their demonstrations and called for a general strike in protest. Troops on Saturday moved against students whose defiance of martial law and occupation of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s vast square for weeks have spurred a power struggle among <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s rulers. The military advances began about midnight and ended in disarray. More than eight hours later, soldiers still straggled away from the city center to the outskirts, where about 200,000 soldiers were reportedly camped. Soldiers advanced down <LOCATION> Changan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, the capital's main road, but thousands of students and residents used trucks, buses and their bodies to stop them in front of the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION>, several hundred yards east of the square. Other troop convoys coming from other directions also were halted. The middle of the square remained calm, with the `` Ode to Joy'' from <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s Ninth Symphony blaring over student loudspeakers. More than 2,000 people surrounded two unmarked buses, one carrying about 40 soldiers and the other supplies including automatic rifles, 1.2 miles west of <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION>. Some of the people broke into the supply vehicle and removed several automatic rifles, one equipped with a bayonet, and displayed the weapons on a table set up on top of the bus. A banner draped on the bus read, `` These are the angels of peace sent by <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> government to protect the people of the capital.'' The crowd alternately cheered and jeered the soldiers as they moved away from the square. Shouts of `` What do you think you're doing? and `` Are you of the people?'' filled the balmy night. Said one soldier: `` If I'm going to die I want to die on the battlefield, not on Changan Avenue.'' Earlier, about 3,000 student bicyclists headed from the square to protest an incident in which a police vehicle ran into a crowd. The bicyclists turned back when they heard that advancing troops were seen on the other side of the square. Government-run <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday that three people were killed in the accident. The official <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> newspaper said Saturday that two people were killed and two were seriously injured. The newspaper said the police car was traveling too fast on wet pavement but gave no other details. Witnesses said the accident occurred at about 11 p.m. Friday. They were not the first deaths linked to the demonstrations. It was reported about two weeks ago that a soldier was killed in a traffic accident involving troop movements connected to the protests. The <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, in an announcement on the square, called for a general strike and a demonstration later Saturday to protest the deaths. About 300,000 people crowded into <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> on Friday evening when <PERSON> Ho </PERSON> <PERSON> Te-chien </PERSON>, a singer from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> who defected to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1983, and three others began a hunger strike atop the martyrs' monument in support of the students' 6-week campaign for democratic reforms. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> declared martial law on May 20 to quell the burgeoning student-led protest movement, but the declaration only triggered greater support for the students. The number of student protests inside the square had declined dramatically in the past week, with about 10,000 maintaining a round-the-clock vigil. But Friday evening, huge masses again converged on the plaza, the symbolic heart of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The students, who have gained considerable support from ordinary citizens, are demanding more democracy, an end to official corruption. <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, a reformer who advocated concessions to the students, has reportedly lost his post and is under house arrest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890603-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-03-89 0405EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EarthFirst! Bjt   06-03 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Earth First!, Bjt,0719</SECOND>
<HEAD>Radical Environmental Group Has Uncompromising Philosophy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARTHUR H. ROTSTEIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TUCSON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
