<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 2327EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GreenRiver     07-13 0618</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Green River,0638</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Former Law Student Called `Viable Suspect' in Green River Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVE BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former law student is a `` viable suspect'' in the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> slayings, the nation's worst serial murder case, according to court documents released Thursday. The Green River case involves the deaths of 41 women and the disappearance of at least eight others in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> in 1982-85. Most of the victims were young and almost all were linked to prostitution. Former law student <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, 38, was named in an affidavit made public Thursday. The affidavit was filed to support a search warrant for two of <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' residences in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, 290 miles east of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>. The searches Wednesday yielded a truckload of crime reports, maps, credit card receipts, 1,800 videotapes, 14 police badges and two <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> police uniform shirts, other court documents showed. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> is serving a one-year term in the King County Jail for the burglary of a police equipment supply store in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> in 1979. Police say <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> walked away from a work-release program in 1981 and was not located until last December, when he was in his final year at the <ORGANIZATION> Gonzaga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law school in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>. He was arrested and returned to jail Jan. 9. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> has not been charged in the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> investigation. His father, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, when reached by telephone in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> on Thursday, said, `` I've been advised by my attorney not to answer any questions.'' The <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> case takes its name from the river south of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> where the bodies of the first five victims were found. Most of the bodies were found in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> area. Four were found in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, Ore. The tip to <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' whereabouts came in a call from <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, after a television program last December about the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> killings, police said. The search warrant for a house rented by <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> and for his parents' house said there was `` probable cause to believe that the crime of murder has been committed.'' <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> investigators have long theorized that the victims might have been lured into the killer's car by someone posing as a police officer or otherwise in a position of trust. `` One of the things that was speculated ... the killer could be a cop or someone posing as a cop,'' King County Police Capt. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, commander of the multi-agency <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> River </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. Before <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> was arrested in January, <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> police determined that he owned a former <LOCATION> Everett </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, police car which had been equipped and made to appear like a real police car, the affidavit said. The police car had been falsely registered by <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who had represented himself as the police chief of Spangle, a town 15 miles south of <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>. Part of the investigation includes a time line which traces his travels from <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, and to <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>. The 405 entries on the 1981-88 time-line `` tended to place <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> in the area during the time space of a <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> victim's disappearance,'' the affidavit said `` None of the documented contacts, telephone records or credit card charges served to eliminate <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> as a suspect in any of the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> cases,'' the affidavit said. `` Instead, interviews and records have produced the following facts that tend to establish that <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> is a viable suspect in the <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> homicides,'' the document said. Other material taken in the searches included boxes of 1982 newspapers, <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> sex crime reports and <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION> police crime synopses from 1983. The affidavit said task force files contained several tips suggesting <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> might have been linked to the killings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WanderingPlane 3rdLd-Writethru a0779 07-13 0970</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wandering Plane, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0779,0992</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stricken Pilot Rescued After Plane on Autopilot Crashes into Atlantic</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf with 6 grafs to UPDATE with quotes from tape of
conversation between Root and controllers; picks up 9th graf, ``There was
...''</HEAD>
<HEAD>LasePhotos WX26, MH1,2,4, LaserGraphic NY29</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN SEWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A small plane with a stricken pilot flew hundreds of miles down the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> on autopilot shadowed by military jets Thursday, finally running out of gas and spiraling into the ocean. The pilot then emerged from the wreckage and swam toward his startled rescuers, authorities said. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON>, a 36-year-old lawyer from <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, was pulled from Bahamian waters by <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> parachutists four hours after he had first radioed he was in trouble. He was first taken to <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION> and a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> helicopter then flew him to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. `` For him to survive a crash like that, it just sent us all into shock,'' said Petty Officer <PERSON> Veronica </PERSON> <PERSON> Cady </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. `` We did n't expect this story to have a happy ending.'' Coast Guard Capt. Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON> said Root may have passed out from carbon monoxide poisoning in the cockpit of his single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> and that water splashing in his face apparently roused him. Root was taken to Memorial Hospital in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, where he underwent three-hours of exploratory surgery for possible internal injuries. After the operation, his condition was upgraded from critical to stable, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Wine </PERSON>. Root's family requested no information be released on his injuries, she said. Root's wife, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>, 35, told reporters from the porch of the family home that her husband had been awake and talking to doctors. She said she told hospital officials to send her husband the following message: `` Root, you really did it this time.'' The drama began about 8:30 a.m. when Root, who had taken off from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> about 6:30 a.m. for <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, radioed air traffic controllers in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. `` Yessir, we're having a little problem up here,'' <PERSON> Root </PERSON> told controllers, according to a tape of the conversation played by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> television station <ORGANIZATION> WRC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. `` Seem to have a little trouble breathing,'' said Root, who also reported chest pain. `` How far am I to Rocky Mount now?'' `` You're about 17 minutes from <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION>,'' replied an unidentified controller. `` Uh,'' said the pilot. `` Niner niner one three <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION>, do you hear?'' said the controller, calling the plane's number. There was no further radio contact, and military pilots who tailed the plane reported he was slumped behind the controls as his plane flew south off the coast, occasionally getting within 100 miles of the shore. Military pilots and rescuers trained to parachute into the ocean to save ditched pilots could only watch helplessly as their aircraft tracked the plane until it ran out of gas. After more than 3 -LCB- hours of radio silence, the plane spiraled into the water and Root was rescued, 800 miles from his original destination in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and 250 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` The words you keep hearing are, ` You're kidding,''' said Ms. <PERSON> Cady </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said the plane went down about 15 miles east of the island of <LOCATION> Eleuthera </LOCATION>. `` It spiraled into the water, so it did n't make the best of all possible landings,'' said Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Parris </PERSON> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lt </ORGANIZATION>. Commander <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Poll </PERSON>, who was at the scene in a jet when <PERSON> Root </PERSON> crashed, said the plane was at about 7,000 feet when it began spiraling in like a corkscrew and spinning down at about 2,000 feet per minute. Poll said the nose and left wing hit the water at the same time and the plane swiveled on its belly on a 360-degree spin. He said it stayed afloat for several minutes and started to sink. Air Force Sgt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, one of four <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technicians </ORGANIZATION> who parachuted into the water, said <PERSON> Root </PERSON> was first spotted swimming away from the wreckage dressed only in pants and socks. Root was pulled onto a raft and given first aid, said <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, based at the <ORGANIZATION> 301st </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rescue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recovery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Homestead </LOCATION>, about 20 miles south of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` He told us his abdomen is hurting a lot and we could see he was bleeding,'' said <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>. `` It was incredible. He had a sense of humor about it.'' <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>, the doctor who treated Root in <LOCATION> Nassau </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Root </PERSON> was alert and could speak well but seemed to be in shock and had abdominal injuries and fractured ribs. <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON> said there was no indication of a heart attack and Root had no history of heart trouble. `` It's definitely a miracle he's alive. He's a little confused by it all,'' the doctor said. After its distress call, the plane was intercepted by two <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> F-A-18 jet fighters when it entered <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> Naval Station airspace at 8:45 a.m., said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. The pilots of the intercepting planes tried unsuccessfully to contact the pilot by radio, he said. The Cessna 210 Centurion can seat four to six people, counting the pilot, and cruises at about 190 mph. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierman </PERSON>, shift supervisor in the air traffic control tower at <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> Raleigh </ORGANIZATION> radio station <ORGANIZATION> WPTF </ORGANIZATION> that the autopilot was set on a heading that would have sent the plane toward <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. `` Put an airplane on automatic pilot and it's going to continue just exactly on the course that the automatic pilot is set for,'' he said. At time of crash, <PERSON> Root </PERSON> was followed by a C-130 cargo plane from <ORGANIZATION> Homestead </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and an HH3 helicopter from <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, also on <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanek </PERSON> of Homestead. A flight surgeon was part of the rescue teams, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-US-SovietSpaceAds     07-13 0312</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Soviet Space Ads,0320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Plan to Launch Ads Into Space, Newspaper Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has hired a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> advertising company to sell broadcast rights and corporate sponsorships for the first British-Soviet space mission, scheduled for 1991, a newspaper reported Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said the Soviets have hired the <PERSON> Saatchi </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Saatchi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, the world's largest advertising and marketing conglomerate, to exploit the commercial opportunities of the Juno mission. The mission, which will carry <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s first astronaut into orbit from a launching pad in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, will be financed entirely by the sale of commercial opportunities, the newspaper said. That includes the sale of space aboard the Soviets' Mir space station for scientific payloads. The Times reported that more than 10,000 men and woman responded to an advertisement <PERSON> Saatchi </PERSON> placed in several British newspapers in late June that carried the headline: `` Astronaut wanted. No experience necessary.'' If the Soviets are successful in this and other commerical ventures, a soft drink or cheesburger may be advertised on the side of a Soviet Soyuz rocket, while commericals to promote a sneaker as the official athletic footwear of the space product, the newspaper said. The Soviet space agency, Glavkosmos, two weeks ago gave <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the exclusive right to market its goods and services in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Glavkosmos has signed commerical agreements with several Western companies. In March, a Japanese televison network paid the agency 12 million <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollars for the right to send a correspondent into space in 1991. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, which administers the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space program, does not accept advertising or payment from private citizens for flights. In the past, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space shuttles have carried some projects for a fee, but that practice was canceled after the Challenger explosion in 1986 that killed seven astronauts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment-Texas     07-13 0101</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment-Texas,0104</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Correspondent Named in San Antonio</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN ANTONIO, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, a newswoman in the <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> bureau of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, has been named correspondent in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Wednesday by <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumpkin </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>, 26, succeeds <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedeno </PERSON>, who recently was promoted to correspondent in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> bureau. Ms. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> worked for the Palestine -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Press and the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> News-Press </PERSON> before joining the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> last year. She is a native of <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> and a graduate of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0011EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment-Wisconsin     07-13 0085</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment-Wisconsin,0087</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP Correspondent Named in Wausau, Wisconsin</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WAUSAU, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Imrie </PERSON>, a statehouse reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, has been named correspondent in <LOCATION> Wausau </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Wednesday by <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chief </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Spratling </PERSON>. <PERSON> Imrie </PERSON>, 37, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pierre </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, in 1985 and transferred to Bismarck the next year. He previously worked for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Journal. <PERSON> Imrie </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dakota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Village     07-13 0893</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Village,0921</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army, Activists Battle for Control of `Liberated' Village</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NICOLAS B. TATRO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SALFIT, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For nearly a year, this was a `` liberated'' village. Outlawed <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> flags fluttered from light poles, activists patrolled the streets, slogans covered the walls, and popular committees did the work of city hall. No longer. At dawn on July 5, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers stormed the village of 5,000 people, and reopened army-run government offices, which had been attacked and burned by rioters in January. `` This is a test case. We went in because <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> had been portrayed as a main center of the intefadeh,'' or Palestinian uprising, said Col. <PERSON> Udi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sagey </PERSON>. He referred to Palistinian statements that the village had been `` liberated'' from <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation. Of the 420 villages in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>, several dozen like <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> have declared themselves `` liberated.'' <PERSON> Sagey </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> army </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> unit in the area, said he planned to reopen its medical center, reconnect the telephones, restore postal and agricultural extension services, and resume construction of a new road. `` The first goal of the intefadeh leaders has been to cut the ties between the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities and the people,'' he said. `` If the economic support to these people is greater, maybe they will be less radical towards Israeli authorities.'' He said he hoped if normal life was restored in <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION>, it would have an impact on neighboring villages that depend on <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> for services. Since the start of the 19-month Palestinian uprising, <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> was largely ignored by the army because it is isolated at the end of a single-lane road. The village is only 18 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, but it is in rocky hills far from main highways and Jewish settlements. In January, Palestinian rioters forced the closure of all government offices and activists bedecked <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> with symbols of independence: red, black, white and green <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> flags and a map of the would-be <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state on a wall in the town center. Popular committees made up of activists aligned with the <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> faction and communist groups organized underground schools, medical services, street cleaning and agriculture. In short, <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> became a microcosm for the independent state that Palestinians hope they can achieve if <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 21-year occupation is ended. `` There is no higher voice than the voice of the intefadeh,'' declared graffiti, freshly painted on a wall where the army had covered over previous slogans. <PERSON> Rafaat </PERSON>, 29, a blacksmith talking with friends at a shop on the village's main <LOCATION> Gamal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Abdel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nasser </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, said there has been little resistance to the army takeover because about 200 activists fled into the countryside to avoid arrest. `` We were liberated for a few months. But now there is more tension because at any moment a soldier can stop you or arrest you,'' said <PERSON> Rafaat </PERSON>, who declined to give his full name for fear of reprisal. The streets still bear the evidence of past protests: the remains of burned tires and scorched stones blocking part of one entrance to the village. <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON>, a 25-year-old grocer, said soldiers patrol frequently, but there were some small acts of defiance. He said youths had hung about 100 flags the previous night. This was disputed by a soldier standing guard outside the new military encampment that sported an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> flag. He said there had been only two flags. `` The town is so quiet now that we go on patrol with just our berets and no helmets,'' he added. About a dozen Palestinians gathered at the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> offices. One man said he wanted an entry permit to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> for a relative who lives in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>; another said he wanted a travel document to return to his job in the <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION>. Yet another, wearing a bandage to cover a head wound he said was inflicted by soldiers, had come to get his ID card that had been taken during a search-and-arrest raid. All were kept waiting several hours even though a reporter who entered the encampment found two army offices sitting alone in their offices. `` Let them wait for awhile,'' said the guard with a shrug. <PERSON> Bassam </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Maadi </PERSON>, a doctor who lives in a spacious villa on the edge of town, said <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> activists and the army were watching each other carefully to see what would happen next. `` It will not stop in <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> as long as the intefadeh continues elsewhere in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. It will not stop until there is some hope offered for the future,'' said <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Maadi </PERSON>, 37. During the course of the uprising, he said, three Palestinians from <LOCATION> Salfit </LOCATION> had been shot to death and about 50 wounded. About 250 had been detained at one point or another. <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Maadi </PERSON> said arbitrary actions and collective punishments had left a feeling of resentment toward <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. He said that after a Jewish settler was killed in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> in June, soldiers came to his house, broke the porch lights and smashed a front window. `` I came downstairs and opened the door. An officer hit me in the face without warning or comment. He then ordered me to go to the school where everyone was being rounded up,'' <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Maadi </PERSON> said. `` If I do something wrong, I will accept punishment. But this is punishing everyone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0013EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TurbanedTrooper     07-13 0145</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Turbaned Trooper,0148</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sikh's Turban Causes Headache for Norwegian Military</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OSLO, Norway (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Norwegian defense officials have added turbans to the military dress code after a year-long battle by a Sikh immigrant who demanded the right to keep his traditional dress during military service. <PERSON> Harvinder </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, 25, became the first Norwegian soldier ever allowed to wear a turban on duty, the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Verdens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gang </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, who came from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in 1978, was called up in July for a year of compulsory military training. He wanted to serve but refused to remove his turban, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was sent home while military officials mulled over the problem. The supreme command decided that <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION> must adapt to recruits from various cultures and ordered that standard issue turbans be prepared to fit the military dress code, defense spokesman <PERSON> Erik </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinstad </PERSON> told the newspaper.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Navy     07-13 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Navy,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviets Display Pacific Fleet, But Fog Obscures Show of Glasnost</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ABOARD THE SOVIET CRUISER TALLINN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet navy sought a high seas show of glasnost, but dense fog obscured much of the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>'s two-day maneuvers and hampered its planned display of firepower. It invited reporters from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, who went aboard the anti-submarine vessel <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION> to watch the exercises in the Sea of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Also on board were officials from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> rejected an invitation but dispatched the frigate USS Holt and at least one helicopter to keep an eye on the maneuvers, Soviet officials said. The fog, which rolled in Monday evening and remained for the next two days, made much of the observation of the ships, planes and helicopters impossible. The navy was forced to alter its plans for mock battles and conduct a short-range demonstration of anti-ship missiles, depth charges, anti-aircraft guns and rocket-launched torpedos. The Soviets also arranged a tour of a destroyer at fleet headquarters in <LOCATION> Vladivostok </LOCATION> and a launch ride to view the task force at anchor. They allowed reporters to wander about the ships to which they were assigned. Inquiries about specific weapons and plans were ignored, however, and a request to visit the <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Combat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, the nerve center of a modern naval vessel, was politely rejected with the explanation that the captain was too busy. Observers did see two ships ready for inspection. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> paint, some of it fresh, covered most surfaces on the <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION> and the destroyer Stoiki. Brass name plates were polished. The portraits of President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and Soviet founder <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON> were in place along the gangways. In the sailors' quarters, personal belongings were put away and all bunks were made. No space was wasted. Each ordinary sailor, practically all of whom are drafted, gets one-third of the space beneath the bottom bunk for uniforms, a cubbyhole for toiletries, and a cabinet large enough to hold about three books for personal belongings. Asked how he liked maritime life, a 17-year-old sailor standing watch for the visitors replied with a shrug. `` Service is service,'' he said. One officer said only 10 percent of the conscripts re-enlist after their three-year stint. The exercises were designed to demonstrate the Soviet navy's defensive posture and its ability to protect a convoy from attack, but the traditionally secretive navy also tried to score some political points The fleet commander, Adm. <PERSON> Gennady </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khvatov </PERSON>, called the tour an example of the `` new political thinking'' supported by <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Others emphasized the ethnic diversity of the sailors from a country with searing ethnic disputes. Capt. <PERSON> Viktor </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Obraztsov </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s political department for the task force, said members from 29 of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s more than 100 nationalities make up the <LOCATION> Tallinn </LOCATION>'s 321-man Western naval specialists say most Soviet officers come from the Slavic republics of the <LOCATION> Ukraine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Byelorussia </LOCATION> and the Russian federation. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> refused to send observers to watch the exercises partly in solidarity with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which considered them a provocation because they were held near islands that the Soviets seized in the closing days of World War II. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> have never signed a peace treaty ending the war, largely because of the dispute over possession of the Kuril islands, known as the Northern Territories in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Western naval experts, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> encouraged its <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> allies to stay away because it does not want to feel obligated to invite Soviet officers aboard ship during annual exercises by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 3rd Fleet.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--BirdBirth     07-13 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bird Birth,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Artificially Propagates Crested Ibis</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> zoo has become the world's first to artificially breed a crested ibis, a long-billed wading bird that is near extinction, the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Daily said today. The 2-ounce bird was born Monday, ending a three-year effort by the zoo to find a way to artificially propagate the species, the official daily said. It said the 4-year-old mother delivered two eggs in mid-June, but pecked one of the babies to death. The other was removed to a breeding box for special care. The crested ibis was once found in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> peninsula </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> as well as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but its population has declined dramatically because of destruction to its environment, the daily said. It said only about 48 of the species survive, two in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the rest in <LOCATION> Yangxian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> of central <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Shaanxi </LOCATION> province.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IAPAAwards     07-13 0422</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-IAPA Awards,0439</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP, Time Among IAPA Award Winners</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, Time magazine and nine journalists from other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> publications are among winners of the 1989 awards competition of the <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The awards, recognizing excellence in coverage of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hemisphere </LOCATION> news, will be presented at <ORGANIZATION> IAPA </ORGANIZATION>'s general assembly Oct. 9-12 in <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Latin American winners include journalists and publications in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> won the IAPA-Tom Wallace Award for an extensive series, written by 23 reporters, on the plight of abandoned children in the hemisphere. The association said the articles showed the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s `` overall commitment to Latin American coverage.'' <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> was the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president of <ORGANIZATION> IAPA </ORGANIZATION>. Other winners, announced Wednesday, are: _ IAPA-La Nacion of <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> Award: Time magazine for cover stories on drug problems _ IAPA-Tom Wallace Award for Illustration: <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> of The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> for photographs of disturbances in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> _ IAPA <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> Award for Investigative Reporting: <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Chardy </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Oppenheimer </PERSON>, all of The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>, for a series on the Panamanian military's control of that country's _ Spot News: <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boudreaux </PERSON> and <PERSON> Marjorie </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times for coverage of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> _ Feature Reporting: <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> of The Wall Street Journal for his article on `` train-surfing'' children in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION> _ Interpretive Commentary: <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Zakarian </PERSON> of The <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Courant for interpretive commentary for his series on Central America _ IAPA-Jamaica Daily Gleaner Award for editorial writing: <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> of The <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> Inquirer for an editorial on <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ IAPA-Pedro <PERSON> Joaquin </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> Award for Freedom of the Press: Collectively to the journalists of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> for condemning drug cartels and for having `` suffered so much for their courage and convictions. _ IAPA-Pedro <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beltran </PERSON> Top Publication Award in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: La Nueva Provincia of <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Blanca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, for support of the handicapped in the workplace _ IAPA-Harmodio Arias award for human rights: <PERSON> Mariela </PERSON> <PERSON> Balbi </PERSON> of La Republica of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, for articles on violence against innocent civilians Also cited in the <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON> competition were: <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> news agency in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> for a photograph of violence during an uprising at a military base; <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Norte </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, for coverage of toxic waste and electoral corruption; <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Nacion </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, for coverage of Hurricane Juana; and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, for editorials against drug cartels. The winners were announced by <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Fabricio </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News @ Sun-Sentinel, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> IAPA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Awards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BlindCowboy     07-13 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Blind Cowboy,0530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Blind Cowboy Depends on Horses for Independence</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ARTESIA, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A horse that knows when it's safe to cross intersections allows a blind former cowboy to keep his independence, but the city says the man must clean up after the animal or lose the privilege. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>, 69, who retains about 1 percent of his sight in one eye, has a year to persuade the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to let him keep two horses, Blue Rocky and Buck, in his back yard. When <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> rides Blue Rocky through town, the horse stops at intersections and does n't move until traffic is flowing in the direction the horse is supposed to go. In 1981, the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> granted <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> a lifetime zoning variance allowing him to keep the horses in town. But inspectors reported in 1987 that <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> was n't cleaning up after the horses and was bothering neighbors with the smell. The variance was revoked and a judge fined <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> $ 100. The fine was thrown out on appeal. Last month, a judge gave <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> a year to change the council's mind or move the horses `` Now, hopefully, what we're doing is right,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. `` As far as being unfair, he's the one who's being unfair to his neighbors.'' <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> said the neighbor behind the complaints is <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON>, who wanted to sell his house next door but was afraid <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>'s horses would lower property values. <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> is not on speaking terms with <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> nor with reporters. `` I do n't want to say nothing about that crap. No, bye,'' he said, hanging up. <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON>, who likes to smoke hand-rolled cigarettes and reminisce about the days when he worked as a cowboy in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, had to stop working in 1964 because of retinitis pigmentosa, a hereditary degenerative eye disease. But <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> likes to ride Blue Rocky the two miles to downtown <LOCATION> Artesia </LOCATION>, across six intersections with stoplights. He could see better about 10 years ago, when he got Blue Rocky and started leading the horse on his walks into town. When <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> heard traffic going in the direction he was walking, that meant the light had turned green and he would cross the intersection. Now the horse decides when it's time to cross. `` He automatically stops anyhow at any intersection,'' <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> said. `` I guarantee you he wo n't go unless the traffic is going my way. Whether he can read the light is the $ 64 question.'' Other times, <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> rides his horse into the hills west of his house. `` You know, I can get kind of down and out because I ca n't work, and get on that old horse and ride five or six miles and, hey, I got a different outlook on life all of a sudden,'' <PERSON> Bradford </PERSON> said. `` I'm completely independent. He shudders at the thought of losing his horses. `` Oh, I suppose somebody could take me places, but you have to go back when they want to go back _ you know, you're not independent.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Olivier'sHeirs Bjt   07-13 0747</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Olivier's Heirs, Bjt,0769</SECOND>
<HEAD>Olivier's Death: The End of An Era?</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT WOLF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> is gone. Will the theater world ever see his like again? Said critic <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, who wrote in <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> died Tuesday: `` No one will replace the splendor that he gave his native land with his genius.'' Other critics say that while another <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> may be in the wings, they feel today's entertainment industry makes it doubtful. Primarily a man of the stage, <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> became a superstar in all media. The sheer quantity of his work is among the most noteworthy aspects of a career that ended with his death at age 82, at his country home south of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> was also the consummate actor-manager _ a passionate theater advocate as important behind the scenes as a director and organizer as he was on stage as a performer. Few theater observers would dispute that first-rate <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> actors continue to abound. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Redgrave </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Glenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> McKellen </PERSON> are just some of the generation after <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> who have been widely and often acclaimed. Then there's a still younger generation less known abroad but already staring greatness in the eye: <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>, <PERSON> Antony </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON>, <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevenson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fiona </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. And although <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s death is being called the end of an era, he is survived by such stalwart knights and dames of stage as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gielgud </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mills </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rex </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alec </PERSON> <PERSON> Guinness </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiller </PERSON> and <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashcroft </PERSON>. But it's <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s level of commitment to the art form he cherished that may be in shorter supply. `` Will anyone ever again go on for so long, play so many great parts, run so many companies?'' asked <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Coveney </PERSON> in The Financial Times. `` Will they want to enough? We must doubt it until they do.'' <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulman </PERSON> in The Evening Standard also feared such dedication was dying. `` The likes of <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>, nurtured on greasepaint, the footlights, and the effrontery of daring an audience to like you, are fast becoming an endangered species.'' The stage instead, he wrote, is `` fast becoming the casting kindergarten for film and TV.'' The trend is increasing in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> as talented young theater actors opt for the greater financial rewards of film and TV. <PERSON> Natasha </PERSON> <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilby </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Amanda </PERSON> <PERSON> Donohoe </PERSON> are just some of the classically schooled young English talents who work mostly on screen. Among the older generation, none has matched the initiative of <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>, who in 1963 realized an old dream of establishing a National Theater of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. `` The quality of work we do here is mostly due to him,'' veteran actor <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> told Tuesday night's audience at the National's production of `` The Voysey Inheritance. Some feel <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s death ends a kind of theatrical majesty that transcends issues of talent. In an editorial entitled `` Stage Colossus,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> wrote: `` He was the undisputed leader of his profession, its spokesman, and the brightest jewel in its crown. We shall not look upon his like again.'' <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> wrote: `` What we have lost with <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> is glory. ... You could practically see it growing around him like a nimbus.'' <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Quilley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s co-star in a celebrated <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> production of <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>'s `` Long Day's Journey Into Night,'' said in an interview, `` There are people today -LRB- like <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> -RRB- but not on the same scale.'' Would-be inheritors most frequently mentioned are men like <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON> and the protean <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>, <PERSON> Guy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pringle </PERSON> in the TV series `` Fortunes of War,'' who combine thespian dynamism with a team spirit. Both have started theater companies _ <PERSON> Pennington </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> English </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shakespeare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, which finished a world tour in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> this spring, and <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Renaissance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Theater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, which had a sell-out <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> season on the West End last fall. <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>, 28, tempted further comparisons to <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> by starring on stage and screen as <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> V </PERSON>, one of <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s most celebrated achievements. <PERSON> Branagh </PERSON>'s film is due out in the fall. <PERSON> Antony </PERSON> <PERSON> Sher </PERSON>'s 1984 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> also was likened to <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON>'s. But South African-born Sher, 40, has forsaken the spotlight to focus on writing. <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rigg </PERSON>, who appeared with <PERSON> Olivier </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Stratford-upon-Avon </LOCATION> and in his 1983 TV `` King <PERSON> Lear </PERSON>,'' says the case is n't closed on greatness. `` It's impossible to say you'll never see the likes of him again,'' she said in an interview. `` The profession is full of incredibly talented people, some in the cradle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ChannelGlide     07-13 0414</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Channel Glide,0426</SECOND>
<UNK>Briton Claims Record As First Woman To Cross English Channel By Hang
Glider</UNK>
<DATELINE>DOVER, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Briton has claimed a place in the record books as the first woman to cross the English Channel by hang glider, making the 21-mile trip to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in 22 minutes. Strapped into her frail craft, 29-year-old <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Leden </PERSON> was first lifted to 13,500 feet over <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> by a hot air balloon Wednesday morning. The balloon's pilot, <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON>, then cut the rope on which the hang glider was suspended 30 feet below his craft, sending the glider into a spinning 200-foot nose dive before it leveled out and began its downward glide. Miss <PERSON> Leden </PERSON> came down on a beach at Le Chatelet midway between the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> north coast ports of <LOCATION> Calais </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Boulogne </LOCATION>. After landing, she admitted to being scared at the start of the flight: `` It was the highest I had ever been with a hang glider so I was going into the unknown. `` I am not frightened very easily but I was terrified for a short time. Because of the thinness of the air at 13,000 feet I went to at least 110 degrees and was rotating very fast, which is the way the hang glider recovers and begins to fly. `` I kept my nerve ... but once that horrible moment was over I had a lovely smooth glide over to <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.'' Preparations for the flight, which was sponsored by an auto company, were dogged by technical problems for a year. But Miss <PERSON> Leden </PERSON> said Wednesday's crossing was `` incredibly smooth, without any serious complications.'' Miss Leden, from <LOCATION> Derbyshire </LOCATION> in northern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, holds the women's world open distance hang gliding record of 145.34 miles. That flight, listed in the Guinness Book of Records, was between <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> over <LOCATION> Owens </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> on July 13, 1983. She was honored by Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> this year by being made a Member of the Order of the British Empire in recognition of her services to the sport. British news reports said the only other hang glider pilot to fly across the English Channel was Briton <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Messenger </PERSON> in 1977. He suffered frostbite because of cold at the high altitude from which he started. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement after <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Leden </PERSON>'s crossing Wednesday that for safety reasons it will not allow any further hang gliding attempts across the English Channel. The skies above the Channel are a major commercial air route.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Unions     07-13 0761</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Unions,0783</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite Commuter Misery, Strikes Win Some Sympathy</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAUREEN JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Britons are witnessing something that has become unusual in the past decade of union-curbing Thatcherism: a striking blue-collar union is enjoying a measure of public sympathy. Wednesday saw the fourth one-day strike in a month of the national rail network and <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> subways. Yet the union leaders, while hardly popular national figures, appear as people with a real grievance. `` They're enjoying a remarkable amount of public support considering how hard the public is hit directly,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Railway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>, a independent monthly. He attributes this to a general sense that <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION> is underpaying its staff as Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> cuts the state-owned company's subsidies to the lowest in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. The goal, in line with the free-market philosophy of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, is to make British Rail self-financing. But what the public mostly sees is higher fares, demoralized staff and falling service standards. A Gallup poll shows 69 percent of Britons favor more subsidies, not less. With unfortunate timing, <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION> announced in the middle of the pay dispute that its profits were a record $ 492 million last year, largely from real estate sales. Meanwhile, the media are focusing on recent hefty pay increases for top executives, such as the 86.5 percent raise for <PERSON> Lord </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, chairman of Cable and Wireless, who now earns $ 630,780 a year. With overtime, train drivers average $ 24,840 a year and they want a 10 percent raise to beat the 8.3 percent inflation rate. A poll Wednesday in the usually pro-Thatcher Daily Mail showed that of 2,770 rail passengers questioned, only 23 percent placed sole blame on the unions. It said 33 percent blamed management, 20 percent blamed the government, and 14 percent thought all sides were guilty. Ten percent had no opinion. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s last big battle against organized labor ended with a crushing defeat for the coal miners in 1985, and widespread applause for the prime minister's tough stand. But <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON>, head of the 75,000 member <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Railwaymen </ORGANIZATION>, is a benign figure, when compared to <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Scargill </PERSON>, the Marxist miners' leader who led surging crowds of pickets in pitched battles with police. A gruff man with tufts of snow-white hair, <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> sticks to a simple unpolitical message: that <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION>'s 7 percent pay raise offer is below inflation, and that it wants to break up the union and weaken its collective bargaining power. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> says the strikers are selfish and dominated by left-wing extremists, but in the image war, <PERSON> Knapp </PERSON> puts up a credible challenge. It has been some time since a British union boss was described in print as `` cuddly.'' Transport Minister <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Channon </PERSON>'s well-publicized walks to work on strike days were dismissed by the conservative <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> as `` embarrassingly unconvincing.'' And British Rail apparently miscalculated when, instead of waiting for the result of an arbitration effort, it asked the courts to ban the strike. The courts refused, and the public's sense of fair play was offended because the union had scrupulously obeyed Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s union-curbing laws by balloting its members and obtaining the necessary 55 percent majority for a strike There are no mass pickets at train stations, just silence. Columnist <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, in the liberal Observer newspaper, wonders what `` has happened to all those gentlemen, usually wearing bowler hats, who would enliven any railway dispute by assaulting station staff with their umbrellas?'' The transport strikes are part of a wave of industrial unrest also hitting the docks, the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> and local government services. Coupled with resurgent inflation and rising interest rates, they have pushed Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> to 10 points behind the socialist <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in opinion polls. Ironically, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s own success in taming organized labor may now be working against her. Britons elected her in 1979 because they wanted a tough response to unions that were perceived as too left-wing and powerful. That perception has since waned. `` A decade ago, 80 percent of people thought the trade unions were too powerful. Now it's down to three in 10,'' says <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Worcester </PERSON>, head of Market and <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>. `` A decade ago, 53 percent said most trade unions were controlled by extremists and militants, now it's only 20 percent.'' `` In a sense, the ballot has given strikes a spurious sense of legitimacy,'' said <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Mather </PERSON> of the right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>. He wants the government to implement its threat to ban strikes in essential services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Fires-Cat     07-13 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fires-Cat,0266</SECOND>
<HEAD>House in Ashes, but Cat Survives</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Fires Rdp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOULDER, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A newlywed couple looking through the ashes of what had been their home found most of their belongings destroyed by a wildfire. Their dog found a stray cat _ singed but alive _ inside the refrigerator. `` We lost everything. I do n't even have proof of who I am,'' said <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Voit-Perry </PERSON>. <PERSON> Voit-Perry </PERSON> said she and her husband, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> football player, were married June 24 and were on a honeymoon until July 5, four days before the fire broke out. The blaze, which started Sunday, burned 2,000 acres in the <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION>, and destroyed 37 homes and numerous other structures. Officials expected to bring it under control today. The couple fled as fire engulfed the ridgetop house where they had planned to begin married life. <PERSON> Voit-Perry </PERSON>, 29, said among the items lost in the blaze were wedding gifts, including cash, a gas barbecue and handmade quilts from friends. `` I would say, ` I'm going to take a picture of the property,''' <PERSON> Voit-Perry </PERSON> said after looking over the damage Tuesday. `` <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> would say, ` We do n't have a camera any more' ... the realization is setting in.'' But her dog, <PERSON> Zack </PERSON>, sniffed at the refrigerator, which the cat somehow managed to use as a shelter. The 3-year-old, 9 -LCB- - pound female cat was taken to the All Pets Clinic in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION> where it was treated for injuries to its paws and a high fever Dr. <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Gurule </PERSON> said it should survive.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     07-13 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0050</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 01; 08; 13; 14; 19; 26.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 01; 04; 09; 16; 24; 32. Supplementary 26.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 4-8-9; 6-0-2-8; 5-7-1-6-8; 3-8-9-7-3-7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-MisterI'mNot     07-13 0177</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mister I'm Not,0178</SECOND>
<UNK>Call Me Madam, Not Mister, Deputy Speaker Tells Legislator</UNK>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Upsetting a time-honored tradition of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>, Deputy Speaker <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Boothroyd </PERSON> told a legislator to stop calling her Mr. and start calling her Madam. In accordance with usual practice, legislator <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Winterton </PERSON> of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday referred to <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Boothroyd </PERSON> as `` Mr. Deputy Speaker'' during a late-night debate in the absence of Speaker <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Weatherill </PERSON>. But Miss <PERSON> Boothroyd </PERSON> told her: `` I long to be a female. Vive la difference. I am Madam Deputy Speaker.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Winterton </PERSON> replied: `` I am a traditionalist and I hope you will not mind, Mr. Deputy Speaker, if I refer to you as Mr.'' But Miss <PERSON> Boothroyd </PERSON> did. `` While I am in the chair, I am to be addressed as Madam Deputy Speaker,'' she ruled. The Commons clings to a variety of strange customs and rituals inherited from the past. The `` Mr. Deputy Speaker'' tag dates back to the all-male days before 1919, when <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Astor </PERSON> became the first woman legislator.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vietnam-Crash     07-13 0126</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Crash,0129</SECOND>
<HEAD>Twenty Reported Dead as Plane Carrying Soviets Crashes in Vietnam</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 20 people were killed when a Soviet military plane carrying Soviet and Vietnamese officials crashed in central <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said in a report seen today. The Japanese news agency's report from <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> quoted `` reliable sources'' as saying that a 20-member Soviet military delegation and several Vietnamese officers were killed in the crash Saturday. The sources quoted by <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> said the plane had taken off either from <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> or from the central coast city of <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Nang </PERSON>. Neither the Soviet Embassy in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> nor the Vietnamese government had reported the incident, the report said. The report, filed from <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> on Wednesday, included no other details.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w TestTestTest.     07-13 0013</FIRST>
<SECOND>Test Test Test.</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 This is a test. AP-Washington.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-King'sTreatment     07-13 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-King's Treatment,0225</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saudi King Due at Cleveland Clinic for Exam</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s King Fahd, accompanied by an entourage of up to 200, including his wives, plans to enter the <ORGANIZATION> Cleveland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> for a physical examination and possible knee surgery, a hospital spokesman said. Twenty rooms are being refurbished for security reasons and to suit the 67-year-old monarch's tastes, said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON>, a clinic spokesman. The exam will coincide with <PERSON> Fahd </PERSON>'s official state visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON> said Wednesday night. Fahd is to meet with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on July 27. A spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Saudi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arabian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> would neither confirm nor deny <PERSON> Fahd </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. Such a trip would be announced once he arrived in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the spokesman said. <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON> said he did not know when the king would arrive. An advance team scouted hospitals in four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities and chose the clinic because of its expertise in orthopedic surgery, and because the king's half-brother, <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, had heart surgery there twice, <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Khaled </PERSON>, who preceded Fahd as <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>'s king, died in 1982 Extensive remodeling of the <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION>, which had been scheduled this year, has been speeded up in preparation for the visit, <PERSON> Weiland </PERSON> said. Some of the entourage will stay at other hotels.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     07-13 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0964</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Princess of <LOCATION> Wales </LOCATION> reportedly has decided against plastic surgery on her nose because of fears the results could be worse. The Ladies' Home Journal reports in its August issue that <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>'s doctor advised her against surgery on her `` conk'' _ British slang for the proboscis `` I could n't go around with my nose in bandages for days,'' <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> reportedly said during one of the women-only evenings the Journal said she holds at <LOCATION> Kensington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palace </LOCATION> for her friends. `` Also, things go wrong, and it would be terrible if it looked worse afterward,'' <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> said of her nose, which she described as `` too big.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moving on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CASTRO VALLEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> slugger who has more speeding citations than major league hits this season, had another brush with the law. <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> got his latest ticket Tuesday while driving his new white Porsche home to watch the All-Star game. He was ticketed for driving 51 mph in a 35 mph zone, said <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrol </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Verhoek </PERSON>. The officer who stopped him believed he was going over 65 mph on winding <LOCATION> Crow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> but could n't get a radar reading, <PERSON> Verhoek </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> was ticketed on the same road a few months ago. `` I got stopped for going 13 miles over the speed limit. Can you believe that?'' <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> asked at a workout Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coliseum </ORGANIZATION>. When asked if he got a ticket, <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> said, `` Me? Not get a ticket?'' <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> was voted the American League's Most Valuable Player last year, but he has n't played in major league games this year because of a wrist injury. In February, <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> was ticketed in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> for driving 125 mph in his $ 75,000 red <ORGANIZATION> Jaguar </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Canseco </PERSON> said later he was doing only 120 mph. In March, he was ticketed again in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A libel suit against pop rocker <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> has been dismissed by a judge who ruled the plaintiff was `` forum shopping'' when he filed the lawsuit in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> noted neither Hall nor the plaintiff, fellow entertainment figure <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Madera </PERSON>, had any <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> connections. <PERSON> Madera </PERSON> claimed he was libeled in an interview given by Hall to Music Connection magazine for its November-December 1986 issue. <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> described the deterioration of his relationship with <PERSON> Madera </PERSON> in the interview. He was quoted as saying, `` He had his day in the sun. But he was pretty much a small-time kind of guy.'' <PERSON> Madera </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>'s statements damaged his reputation in the entertainment industry. The judge noted that <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, whose hits include `` Private Eyes'' and `` Rich Girl,'' lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and the magazine was based in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Madera </PERSON> tried to sue before in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, but the cases exceeded the statute of limitations in those states, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said. He sued in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> in May 1988, about 18 months after the alleged offense. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> has a two-year statute of limitations.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich., suffered a cut on his forehead when his car struck a security barrier in the Capitol parking lot <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Operations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, was treated at <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and released, a hospital spokesman said. <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON> and the driver, <PERSON> Cedric </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> were thrown into the windshield, which shattered, said Capitol police spokesman <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>. At the time, the congressman was headed to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor for a vote. <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> was admitted to the hospital, which did not have a report on his condition. <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> said Wednesday's accident was under investigation.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> admits she slapped a police officer, but says he deserved it. `` The policeman is an empty-headed, gorgeous man,'' she said. Then, in a stream of denunciations, compared him to Nazi soldiers in her native <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. `` But the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> were smarter; they had the sense to mistreat women in private,'' said Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> said she hit Officer <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> in self-defense because he threatened to break her arm. She pleaded innocent Wednesday to several misdemeanor charges. Municipal Judge <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> granted Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON>'s request for an Aug. 2 pretrial hearing, and set her jury trial for Sept. 11. When arriving for Wednesday's arraignment, she was met at the courthouse by a crowd of reporters and several relatives, who held signs that said `` Free <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON>.'' Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> was arrested June 14 after <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> pulled over her <ORGANIZATION> Rolls-Royce </ORGANIZATION> for an expired registration. She drove off as <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> was checking for other infractions, then slapped him when he got her to stop two blocks later.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WHEELING, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of country music fans will head for the hills this weekend to see <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>, <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, The <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> <PERSON> Band </PERSON> and other stars at one of the nation's largest outdoor country concerts. At least 60,000 people are expected at the 13th Annual Jamboree in the <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, said concert spokeswoman <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>. More than 20 recording artists and bands will perform during the 19-hour festival, scheduled to begin at 11 a.m. Saturday with an appearance by <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandrell </PERSON>. One of the regular performers is <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, who has missed only one of the outdoor jamborees. `` It's kind of like a homecoming for me,'' <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said. Other stars scheduled are The <ORGANIZATION> Bellamy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Patty </PERSON> <PERSON> Loveless </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> McDaniel </PERSON>, Highway 101, Restless Heart, K.D. <PERSON> Lang </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillis </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     07-13 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MICHIGAN CITY, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Marines were battling for every inch of beachhead and met no resistance from about 2,000 spectators. Four amphibious landing craft from the USS Boulder bounded ashore Wednesday and disgorged 90 Marines in full battle gear. Instead of charging deadly pillboxes and lethal snipers, the leathernecks directed blank fire toward toward a pop stand, three port-a-johns and a festively colored tent where a six-piece <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> band had been playing. With bases concentrated on ocean coasts, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> rarely get to show their stuff to Midwesterners, said <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Knox </PERSON>. Spectators on the <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> beach broke into applause as the blank automatic weapons fire finally ceased. `` It was really cool,'' said 13-year-old <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> Huff </PERSON>. Mayor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Behler </PERSON>, an ex-Marine, rode in the assault wave carrying a fantasy instead of a rifle. `` I wanted to dress like -LRB- Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> MacArthur </ORGANIZATION> and just stand on the beach with my corncob pipe and glasses,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man climbed into a hot tub with a joke and planned to keep up the routine for three days to set a new mark for hot tub humor. `` It's great. Surf's up,'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said about a half-hour into his marathon Wednesday. He plans to stay there for at least 73 hours, until Saturday morning. He started out with some elephant jokes. `` Why do elephants have flat feet?'' he asked. `` It's obviously because they jump out of trees.'' `` Most of the jokes are off the top of my head and are jokes I've collected from 19 years in the radio business,'' said <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, 36 `` Of course, after 27 hours or so you begin to hallucinate, so fortunately the Guinness people allow me to use cue cards.'' The 1989 edition of the <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Book </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> lists him as the record-holder for time spent telling jokes in a hot tub with a 52-hour effort, but someone in <LOCATION> Portugal </LOCATION> has topped that mark. The effort to regain the title has its risks. `` I've got to keep the temperature of the water between 85 and 90 degrees,'' <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said. `` Any lower than 85 and hypothermia sets in without me knowing it. I can go numb, nod off. Any higher than 90, and I can boil myself without knowing it.'' Wrinkled feet are another hazard, said <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, who has survived four tub-joking marathons. He plans to solve the problem by keeping his feet out of the water much of the time. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> has a penchant for spending long periods in odd places. `` I once sat in spaghetti for three days,'' he said. Unfortunately, <ORGANIZATION> Guinness </ORGANIZATION> lists no record for spaghetti-sitting.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-B-2Bomber Bjt   07-13 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-B-2 Bomber, Bjt,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Republicans, Democrats Joining Forces Against Stealth Plane</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Cheney scheduled to testify at 10 a.m. EDT; pre-noon top planned</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Republicans and Democrats are forecasting a rocky congressional ride for the stealth bomber despite the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> assessment that the half-billion-dollar aircraft is key to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> strategic forces. `` The B-2 program is in a lot of trouble,'' Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials who pleaded their case Wednesday. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> was to present his argument for the bomber today before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel. Air Force Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> and Chief of Staff <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> met with stiff resistance from lawmakers Wednesday as they urged members at <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sessions to continue spending for the $ 70 billion program. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> and <PERSON> Welch </PERSON> told the committee that stretching out the B-2 program would increase the cost significantly. Current estimates put the pricetag of a single bomber between $ 500 million and $ 750 million, making it the most expensive plane in history. Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said extending the program could raise the price of a single bomber to $ 1 billion `` If you make the annual cost acceptable, the sticker price becomes unacceptable,'' <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON> said. `` If you make the sticker price acceptable, the annual cost becomes unacceptable. I do n't know how to fix it.'' Moments after <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>'s comments, <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> put it more bluntly to the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials. `` When the chairman tells you you're not going to get it politically, you can put it in your pocket and take it to the bank,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. Rep. <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., added: `` I want to put my head down and cry You made a compelling case but I do n't know where to get the money to pay for it.'' Two committee Republicans _ Reps. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> _ have joined forces with liberal Democrat <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON> of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on an amendment to shut down production of the B-2 after the manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, produced 13 planes. The amendment, which the lawmakers said they will introduce on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor, would allow the 13 planes to be developed and tested and then a decision would be made on whether to continue the program. `` It's a reasonable, moderate position,'' said <PERSON> Rowland </PERSON>, who believes the coalition can win support from members stunned by the cost of the radar-evading aircraft. But the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> argues the B-2 outpaces improvements in Soviet air defenses, is important to nuclear deterrence and can be used in a conventional role. Despite the sticker shock, the B-2 `` comes down as the only candidate for some categories of things we want to do,'' <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0158EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BastilleDay-Texas     07-13 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bastille Day-Texas,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Paris, Texas, Celebrates</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parisians here see oil derricks instead of the Eiffel Tower and favor crape myrtles over crepes, but do n't expect them to call July 14 anything other than Bastille Day When Parisians in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> toast the 200th anniversary of their revolution on Friday, their namesakes here will, too _ Texas-style. The fete will include a barbecue, quilting contests, music, plays and `` Tour de Paris'' bike races expected to draw up to 1,500 entrants to this town of 27,000 people 200 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. City leaders and businesses started the Bastille Day celebrations 10 years ago thinking, `` Why not?'' said <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>, program coordinator of the <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` It started out as a downtown merchants' promotion, a sidewalk sale, real small and kind of quaint,'' she said. But as word of the festival grew, `` We just thought we'd take advantage of it.'' <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> have fraternal ties, she said. `` <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> was one of the first to recognize <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> as an independent -LRB- republic -RRB- ... and the French flag was one of the six that flew over <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>,'' Ms. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> said. As part of the celebration, about 20 high school girls will compete for the title of Crape Myrtle Queen, with the winner receiving a bouquet from the flowering trees. Hungry revelers can feast on pastries from `` Marie A.'s Cake Company,'' named for <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Antoinette </PERSON>, the haughty monarch known for saying `` Let them eat cake.'' The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> even has a commemorative cancellation mark for July 14 letters. `` It's got a little Eiffel Tower on one side and an oil derrick on the other,'' Ms. <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON> said. `` Our logo, on little pins, is a little Eiffel Tower with a cowboy hat on top. ... They're a real big hit.'' The only thing missing will be a French dignitary, she said. `` But, they've got their own birthday party.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     07-13 0028</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0028</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Stocks Close Down 70 Points</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed Thursday at 33,631.16, down 70.36 points on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     07-13 0924</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Encouraged by Wheat Harvest Estimates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1989 wheat crop is turning out better than many believe possible a few months ago, but it still is far short in many areas where last year's drought lingered on. New Agriculture Department estimates put the harvest at 2.12 billion bushels, a 17 percent increase from last year's 1.81 billion bushels and the most since 1985 when farmers produced 2.43 billion bushels. For the first time this season, the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimates issued Wednesday included durum and `` other'' spring-planted wheat, in addition to winter wheat planted last fall. <PERSON> Reggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyckoff </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Growers </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> estimate was `` a little higher'' than he had expected and that there will be adequate supplies through the 1989-90 marketing year if the current projections are correct. `` But it also shows evidence that there is disaster in many areas'' where wheat yields have tumbled, <PERSON> Wyckoff </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. `` It's pretty rough in hard, red winter wheat areas.'' The department's <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said the average yield, based on indications as of July 1, was estimated at 33.4 bushels per acre, down from 34.1 bushels last year. But farmers are expected to have about 63.5 million acres of wheat for harvest this year, up from 53.2 million in 1988, the board said in its report. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s first official estimate of 1989 production of corn, soybeans and some other major spring-planted crops will be issued on Aug. 10, along with revised figures for wheat. However, the July report did show new figures for 1989 plantings of major crops. Corn plantings were estimated at 65.8 million acres for harvest, up from 58.2 million acres in 1988, and soybeans, 60.2 million acres, up from 57.4 million. Cotton plantings were estimated at 10.5 million acres, down 16 percent from 1988. That was also 5 percent below a preliminary forecast in March. Winter wheat production was estimated at 1.46 billion bushels, down 6 percent from 1988, reduced sharply in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> and some other parts of the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> by lingering effects of last year's drought It makes up about three-fourths of total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat production. The <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> wheat crop estimate, however, was boosted slightly to 211.2 million bushels from the June forecast of 202.4 million. Even so, it was down by more than a third from last year. Winter wheat fared better in 1988 because most was harvested or had matured before the full impact of heat and drought was felt. Durum wheat production was estimated at 111.3 million bushels, up from 44.8 million in 1988, and `` other'' spring wheat was indicated at 544.1 million bushels, compared with 205.5 million last year. Department economists say the decline in wheat supplies since last year's reduced harvest is having only slight effect on consumer food prices, which are expected to rise an average of 4 percent to 7 percent, compared with a 4.1 percent gain in 1988. A related supply-and-demand report showed that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wheat inventories may total 592 million bushels by the end of the current marketing year next May 31, down from 694 million bushels this June 1. Last month, when the crop was thought to be smaller, analysts projected inventories could decline to 500 million bushels next spring. The report showed wheat prices could average $ 3.75 to $ 4.10 per bushel in 1989-90, down from the range of $ 3.80 to $ 4.20 projected in June but still above the $ 3.72 average for last season. Wheat exports were projected at around 1.23 billion bushels, down from 1.44 billion bushels in 1988-89. Corn production, based on past trends and the current outlook, was projected at 7.45 billion bushels, up from last year's drought-shriveled 4.92 billion bushels But the July corn outlook was down from June's projection of 7.85 billion bushels, due partly to late plantings in the eastern Corn Belt and `` continued limited moisture'' conditions in the west. The soybean crop was projected at 1.95 billion bushels, unchanged from the June forecast and up sharply from 1988 output of 1.54 billion bushels. The price outlook also was unchanged at $ 4.75 to $ 6.25 per bushel, compared with an average of $ 7.35 in 1988-89.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has proposed a technical measure designed to speed the reduction of barriers to trade in farm products. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Trade Representative <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> says the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration wants other nations to convert non-tariff import barriers, such as quotas and restrictive licenses, to tariffs. `` By converting to tariffs, barriers would be more transparent and uniform, making it easier to negotiate worldwide reductions in agriculture support and protection,'' she said Wednesday in a statement. The proposal was made in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in trade negotiations with 100 other nations under the auspices of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, which regulates world trade treaties and settles commerce disputes. The current series of talks, known as the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round, began in 1986 and are scheduled to run through next year. In April, <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> negotiators achieved a breakthrough in the talks, which had been deadlocked since December, reaching broad agreement in four key areas, including a compromise on a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> demand to do away with all trade-distorting agricultural subsidies. The talks since then have been aimed at nailing down specifics of how to achieve the goals of the larger compromise. <PERSON> Hills </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> `` tariffication'' proposal must be part of a more comprehensive package including fundamental reforms in domestic farm subsidies, export subsidies and sanitary rules.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SovietLasers     07-13 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet Lasers,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Says Film of Soviet Laser Confirms its Threat to US</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> disagrees with American scientists who say their visit to a long-secret Soviet laser research center convinces them the facility is not a threat to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> satellites. A <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official said Wednesday that videotape taken by the scientists of the Sary-Shagan laser facility in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> `` only firms up'' the department's view that the laser facility is capable of incapacitating <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> satellites. The scientists, however, said Wednesday their inspection of the facility last week convinced them it poses no military threat. They said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> had greatly exaggerated the facility's importance. `` This facility really has n't had large resources devoted to it since the 1970s,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Hippel </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, one of the scientists who visited the site as part of a broader inspection program sanctioned by the Soviet government. The scientists showed the videotapes at a news conference Wednesday. No <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government officials were included in the visit. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official, who asked that he not be identified, said the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> still believes that while the Sary-Shagan laser center may be unable to knock a satellite out of space, it can do enough damage to `` negate our satellite capabilities.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scientists </ORGANIZATION> told reporters the Sary-Shagan laser is not powerful enough to shoot down satellites or ballistic missiles. He said it was 100 to 1,000 times less powerful than an American power laser at <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sands </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, that he called only marginally capable of shooting down satellites. <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> was not on the tour but described for reporters his analysis of the photographic and other evidence gathered by the tour group, which also visited a <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear weapons production center and conducted radiation experiments on a nuclear-armed <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> cruiser in the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>. He noted the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, beginning in 1984, had described the laser center as the heart of an ominous Soviet anti-satellite program with ground-based lasers that could shoot down satellites and in the future might be able to destroy ballistic missiles. `` It is clear that the threat posed by this facility has been wildly exaggerated over the last several years,'' <PERSON> Pike </PERSON> said, adding the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> claims represented either a major intelligence failure or a deliberate effort to mislead the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> public. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cochran </PERSON>, a staff scientist with the <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the tour group, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials were invited to go along but declined. Rep. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, D-Mich., who participated in the tour, said Soviet willingness to allow Americans to inspect the previously secret laser facility and other military installations was clear evidence of `` extraordinary steps'' being taken by Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to promote the arms control process <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> said Soviet officials told him during the tour that legislation was being prepared to permit more public disclosures about <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear weapons production.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890713-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-13-89 0231EST</FILEID>
