<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DC-10Landing     08-09 0359</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC-10 Landing,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>Engine Failure Forces DC-10 To Make Emergency Landing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 made an emergency landing Wednesday after the tri-motor jet's No. 2 engine apparently began breaking up and the pilot shut it down, officials said. Flight 308, carrying 256 people from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, landed without incident at <ORGANIZATION> Stapleton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday about 6:30 p.m., according to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boulware </PERSON>, a spokesman at the airport. `` They experienced a severe vibration from the No. 2 engine, -LRB- and -RRB- as a precautionary measure, they elected to make an unscheduled landing,'' said <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Whalen </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION>, Minn.-based airline. The No. 2 engine of a DC-10 also is the focus of an investigation into the crash of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 232 last month in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, killing 111 of the nearly 300 people aboard. Flight 232's No. 2 engine apparently disintegrated, shooting shrapnel that apparently severed hydraulic lines in the jet, causing almost complete loss of control and forcing the crash-landing at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s airport. The investigation into the cause of that disaster is continuing. <PERSON> Boulware </PERSON>, who observed the damage to the aircraft after it landed Wednesday night, said there were `` multiple shrapnel-like holes in the outer cowling'' of the No. 2 engine, which on a DC-10 is mounted in the vertical stabilizer at the tail of the aircraft. The other two engines are mounted under the wings. `` One of the holes was big enough I could have stuck by hand through,'' he said. He said the holes were along the upper side of the engine cowling. `` Whatever exited, exited upward,'' he said. He also said a service door on the tail about eight inches square had been blown open, but remained attached to its hinges. <PERSON> Whalen </PERSON> said the landing was normal in terms of controlling the airplane, and the 245 passengers were being placed on alternate flights to <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>. There were 11 crew members on board, he said. <PERSON> Whalen </PERSON> said the airline's mechanics will take a close look at the engine, and since <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> does n't have a maintenance base in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, the jet might have to be shuttled to <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Divorce-Embryos     08-09 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Divorce-Embryos,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Divorcing Couple Take Witness Stand in Battle for Embryos</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SHARP</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARYVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman battling for control of seven microscopic embryos said she worried about frozen storage `` killing them,'' but her husband said bringing them to life was a mistake. The couple, <PERSON> Junior </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, drew a portrait of themselves Tuesday as a couple who tried desperately for nine years to have a child. Their marriage has collapsed into a battle for custody _ or ownership _ of seven frozen `` pre-embryos'' that have been in cryogenic storage since December. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 30, sued for divorce in February, and wants the embryos to remain in storage until the couple decide together what to do with them. `` I oppose the use of the pre-embryos by <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> or any donor because I do not wish to be raped of my reproductive rights,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> says she has the right to have the embryos implanted in her womb regardless of her husband's feelings. `` I do n't feel it abuses his rights,'' she testified. `` He consented to be a father and I'm willing to let him.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said she objects strongly to leaving the embryos in cold storage, where according to some testimony they could not last for more than two years. `` I believe that would be killing them,'' she said. `` I am the mother of these embryos. They are the beginning of life. They are more than just cells that mean nothing.'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> acknowledged his wife has gone through physical and emotional trauma during their six attempts at conception in the in vitro program, which they entered in 1985. `` But I ca n't see where that's enough to bring a child into this world where the child will have more pain than it cost us to achieve it,'' he said. `` I do n't want my child in a single-parent home,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> told <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Blount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge hearing the case. `` I was raised in a broken home and I do n't want that for my child.'' Both <PERSON> Junior </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, 28, come from families of six children. Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' attorney, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Christenberry </PERSON>, contends the embryos should be considered `` pre-born children'' and allowed to come to term in Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' body. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON>, attorney for <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, said there have been tremendous advances in helping infertile women such as Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. He contends that because she could reasonably expect to become pegnant with another man after her divorce, it is unnecessary to use these particular seven embryos. Under his questioning, zoologist <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Shivers </PERSON> said the success rate of in vitro programs `` will definitely go up'' in coming years. Testimony Monday indicated the national average for successful implantations is 18 percent. The <PERSON> Davises </PERSON> said they met in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> while in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and married nine years ago. Mrs. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> suffered five tubal pregnancies, one of which she said nearly killed her. The couple tried adoption, only to be told they had little chance of becoming parents that way. They joined the <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> program, taking a child under their wing until its mother `` started using us sort of as a baby-sitting service,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. The trial, which began Monday, recessed until Thursday. Young is expected to rule within a month. The embroyos are in cryogenic storage at minus 180 degrees Centigrade. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said he does not want the embryos destroyed, just left alone. `` Three years down the road I might have a change of heart,'' he said. In vitro fertilization produces so-called `` test-tube babies'' because the fertilization takes place outside the womb. The process was pioneered in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, where the first successful birth was recorded in 1978. The embryos in the <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> case were less than two days old when they were frozen, and consist of four to eight undifferentiated cells each, according to testimony. It is 12 to 14 days after fertilization before the cells start to take on different characteristics and technically are considered embryos, scientists testified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     08-09 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0368</SECOND>
<HEAD>ABC's `Roseanne' Takes First in Television Ratings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Summer reruns, topped by the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> comedy hit `` Roseanne,'' beat out original programming in the latest Nielsen ratings. Two other <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> shows _ `` Wonder Years'' and `` Who's the Boss'' _ were next in the ratings for the week ended Aug. 6, but the network remained in third place. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> each finished the week with four shows in the Top 10, but it was <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> which gained a 59th consecutive victory. `` Roseanne,'' snubbed last week in the Emmy nominations, supplanted <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers'' in the top spot. The <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> barroom antics fell to fourth place, tying with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Coach.'' Original programming fared poorly in the ratings, despite coming amid summer doldrums. The <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> program `` Yesterday, Today & amp; Tomorrow'' made its debut in a tie for 19th place with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Full House.'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s much-touted `` PrimeTime Live'' was in 37th place The NBC summer series `` 13 East'' dropped from 10th place last week to 35th. Another NBC summer show, `` Knight & amp; <PERSON> Daye </PERSON>,'' remained in the middle of the ratings in a four-way tie for 50th place. <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s summertime jump in the ratings has apparently bottomed out. `` Married ... With Children'' dropped to 38th place, `` Totally Hidden Video'' was 46th and `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted'' in the four-way tie for 50th place. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> survey with an average of 10.5. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was second with 9.4 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> third with 9.2. For the season to date, from Sept. 19, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had 14.7, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.8 and CBS 11.7. The ratings are the percentage of the 90.4 million homes with televisions in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The share is the percentage of sets in use. Here are the Top 10: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers `` and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Coach'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>: The Case of the Lost Love'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Murder, She Wrote'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` Designing Women'' tied. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> claimed first place among the nightly news shows. The ratings: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 9.4, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 9.1, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 8.6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     08-09 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of July 31-Aug. 6 Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.8, 17.0 million homes. 2. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.7, 15.1 million homes. 3. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5, 14.0 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 4. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 6. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9, 13.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6, 13.2 million homes. 7. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>: Case of the Lost Love'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.6, 13.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 9. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 11. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4, 13.0 million homes. 12. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9, 12.6 million homes. 13. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.5 million homes. 14. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.6, 12.3 million homes. 15. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5, 12.2 million homes. 16. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4, 12.1 million homes. 17. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0, 11.7 million homes. 18. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2, 11.0 million homes. 19. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0, 10.8 million homes. 19. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` NBC News Magazine: Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0, 10.8 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 22. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 23. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 24. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 24. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> McKenna </PERSON> Story'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 11.5. 24. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 27. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Hot Prospects,'' CBS, 11.3. 27. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 29. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 30. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Outback Bound'' _ `` CBS Special Movie-Thursday,'' 10.9. 31. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 32. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 33. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 10.4. 34. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 35. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` 13 East,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 36. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Billionaire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 10.1. 37. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` PrimeTime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0. 38. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 39. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` Deadly Deception,'' `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 9.5. 39. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 41. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Out of Mind,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 41. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 43. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 9.0. 43. -LRB- S -RRB- `` <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 45. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 46. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 46. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Sins,'' Part 3, _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 8.6. 48. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 49. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 50. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 50. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Take My Daughters, Please'' _ `` Movie of the Week-Friday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 50. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 50. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Knight & amp; <PERSON> Daye </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 54. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 55. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Bad Medicine'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 7.6. 56. -LRB- 88 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 57. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` 20,000 Leagues Under the Sea'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Night Movie,'' 7.3. 58. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 59. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 7.1. 59. -LRB- 100 -RRB- `` Highway To Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 61. -LRB- 100 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.9. 62. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` The Apple Dumpling Gang'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 62. -LRB- X -RRB- `` NBC Major League Baseball,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 64. -LRB- 106 -RRB- `` <ORGANIZATION> Smothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> _ Fun & amp; Games,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 65. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 66. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 67. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 5.9. 68. -LRB- X -RRB- `` NBC Major League Pre-Game,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 69. -LRB- 96 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 5.5. 69. -LRB- 120 -RRB- `` Corn People'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Summer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Playhouse </ORGANIZATION>,'' CBS, 5.5. 71. -LRB- 100 -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 72. -LRB- S -RRB- `` Protect and Surf,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 74. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 75. -LRB- S -RRB- `` Chain Letter,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 75. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0102EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APME-FOI     08-09 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME-FOI,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>FOI Award Finalists Announced</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six newspapers have been selected as finalists in the annual Freedom of Information Award competition sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors Association. The finalists were announced Tuesday by <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawpe </PERSON> of The Courier-Journal of <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. They are: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southtown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION>, for successful efforts to force release of presentencing letters and reports that a judge said influenced him in sentencing the <LOCATION> Willow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, police chief. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, for successful efforts to document a city redevelopment project that cost the taxpayers $ 40 million. _ The <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Dispatch, for successful efforts to open juvenile records in the case of the late <PERSON> Rakie </PERSON> <PERSON> Cloyd </PERSON>. _ The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Mercury News, for efforts to open legislators' driving records and for revealing secret meetings of the state Legislature. _ The Spokesman-Review and <ORGANIZATION> Spokane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, for efforts to obtain records illustrating the problem of sexual abuse of students by teachers. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, for an examination of the way in which corporations and institutions use court secrecy to prevent disclosure of critical information relating to health and safety issues. The winning entry will be announced at the APME convention in October in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Analysis     08-09 0748</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Analysis,0773</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kaifu's `Clean Start' Follows False Start by Uno</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Japan, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After a two-month false start, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s governing party is on another `` clean start'' to reform itself. The false start was under <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>, who became prime minister June 2 with pledges of political reform but soon was pursued by allegations of having kept paid mistresses. Now another veteran legislator with no personal power base has been pulled up to lead the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. There was an eerie sense of deja vu in <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>'s acceptance remarks If he had Uno's glasses and streak of white hair, it would have been hard to discern that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> had a new leader. Uno was clear of involvement in the Recruit influence-buying scandal that caused his predecessor, <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, to leave office prematurely. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> bears the minor taint of receiving the equivalent of $ 110,000 in donations from <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> over five years, but he did not receive profits from cut-price stock deals, as did most of the party leaders now sidelined. That scandal, <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> said on June 2, `` has had a dramatic effect on our party. I would like to take this opportunity to reflect on this development so we can make a clean start in politics and regain the confidence of our people.'' <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> said Tuesday, after winning the party presidency, that it was `` a crucial time.'' He called for debate through which `` we can gain the people's understanding of our policies.'' `` I want to carry out reforms and pass reform legislation based on our deep self-reflection,'' he said. `` We must carry out political reforms and shed our old skin.'' Like Uno and <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, and almost everyone else in his conservative party, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> said the Liberal Democrats were in a crisis. The crisis appears deeper than ever, and the calendar is moving steadily toward the next encounter with the electorate. In elections July 23, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> lost constrol of Parliament's upper house for the first time in the party's 34-year history. Elections for all seats in the lower house must be called by July 1990, but the Socialist-led opposition in the upper chamber will try to create a legislative deadlock to make the government hold them sooner. So low is the Liberal Democrats' popularity that analysts expect they would lose their majority in the lower house. The reasons are many, and not easy to overcome. Despite a pledge not to impose a new major tax, the governing party bulldozed a 3 percent sales tax through <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. When it was coupled with reductions in personal income and inheritance taxes, the net effect was a reduction in the average household's tax burden, but the sales tax remains unpopular. It also produces 10 percent of government revenue, which makes abolishing it expensive. Although the Recruit scandal ended officially in April with the indictment of two legislators on bribe-taking charges, it lives on in the minds of many who feel party leaders should not have escaped prosecution. Among those who did was <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, who preceded <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> as prime minister. The easy money politicians reaped from the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> was spread so widely that nearly all top Liberal Democratic figures were tainted, making it impossible for them to succeed <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> or Uno. They remain powerful, however, and voters know many hope for future high office. To the sales tax and Recruit scandal, which created an image of arrogance and unaccountability, was added the insult to women of Uno's alleged affairs. The result was the thrashing the Liberal Democrats took in the July 23 election. <PERSON> Takako </PERSON> <PERSON> Doi </PERSON>, the first woman to lead a party in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, is popular and has been able to fuzz over her <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s policy of an unarmed, neutral <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, which is not the majority opinion. She attacks the sales tax and the governing party's image. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> is new and untried. He is 58, still boyish-looking, young enough in Japanese politics to suggest a new generation and has reform credentials from service under <PERSON> Takeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Miki </PERSON>, a `` Mr. Clean'' prime minister of the 1970s. He has until October, when the party votes again on its president, to show he has made a good start on rescuing the deeply troubled party. If he does n't, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> could be looking for its fourth prime minister of 1989.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorson </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> news editor of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NavyPlaneCrash     08-09 0162</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Navy Plane Crash,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Crewmen Die in Navy Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WHIDBEY ISLAND NAVAL AIR STATION, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The two crewmen aboard a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> A-6 Intruder aircraft were killed Tuesday when the attack jet crashed while practicing for an air show here. The pilot was identified Tuesday night as Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruces </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, and the bombardier-navigator was Marine Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, 31, of <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, said base spokeswoman <PERSON> Mariana </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. Both officers were assigned to <ORGANIZATION> Attack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 128 </ORGANIZATION>, known as the `` Golden Intruders.'' The squadron is based at <LOCATION> Whidbey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. The cause of the crash is under investigation, Ms. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. Since 1980, 12 of the Whidbey-based A-6s have crashed, resulting in 14 fatalities, she said. The aircraft was completing a turn over the field Tuesday when it lost altitude and hit the ground, Ms. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. The airfield, about 45 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, was closed for approximately two hours after the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0132EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-09 0858</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0896</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Berke </PERSON> Breathed, whose pen illustrated the comic strip `` <LOCATION> Bloom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>,'' plans to go a little overboard as a contributing editor at Boating magazine. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, editor in chief of Boating, said Tuesday that Breathed, an avid boater who has homes in <LOCATION> Evergreen </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, will write a monthly humor column. Breathed, who owns four boats, said his column, titled `` Overboard,'' will reflect his consuming interest in the sport. `` Boating looks at equipment in the way I want to look at equipment _ what's coming out, and why we silly boaters think that a new-style helm station is exciting,'' Breathed said. The last `` Bloom County'' comic strip appeared in papers last weekend. Breathed, who won a Pulitzer Prize for cartooning in 1987, plans to begin work on a new strip called `` Outland'' that will begin Sept. 3. `` Outland'' features a black ghetto child who was a `` Bloom County'' regular.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 CBS is firmly behind the `` The <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON> Show'' as the late-night talkfest struggles against reigning king <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> and his `` Tonight Show,'' the show's producer said. `` CBS has just told me, ` Do what it takes to make it work, and we'll stick by you,''' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said in a recent interview. The show, featuring <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON> of `` Wheel of Fortune'' fame, debuted with good ratings seven months ago but has since dropped to third place. <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said the show has been revamped. The blue couch is gone, replaced by a beige one. Only four guests will now appear nightly, instead of five, a change <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said was made `` to allow <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> time to sink his teeth into an interview.'' Most significantly, <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON>'s monologue will run in the middle of the show or not at all. `` We figure it does n't make sense to compete against <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> with his act,'' <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CULVER CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Reggae singer <PERSON> Ziggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> says if his audiences notice he's smiling a great deal, it's because he loves the music he makes. `` I feel good. I feel like everything is goin' alright and I love our music,'' said <PERSON> Marley </PERSON>, 20, at a news conference Tuesday. <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> and his band, The Melodymakers, began a world tour and showed reporters their new video for the single `` Look Who's Dancing,'' from the album `` One Bright Day'' Brother <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> and sisters <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> <PERSON> Prendergast </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cedella </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> also perform in The Melodymakers The four are the children of the late reggae great, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ziggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> said his father once told him: `` On your way up please take me up. On your way down do n't let me down.'' Reggae music is based on themes of peace and unity, <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> and The Melodymakers will tour the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, then <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> and the band won a Grammy for best reggae recording last year and an <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> Image award.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Running <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> is n't child's play, but sometimes it makes Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> wish he was a kid again. <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, better known for his brash, outspoken style, revealed a yearning for the simpler life of a child Tuesday during a tour of a new day-care center at police headquarters in lower <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. `` It's marvelous,'' the mayor said as he was shown the playroom and a second room where the 35 children in the program take a nap after lunch. `` Sometime about 3 o'clock in the afternoon I feel like I want to come over and be loved,'' <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> told Police Commissioner <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who led the tour. `` Come over between one and two o'clock,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> replied.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LARAMIE, Wyo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>, the drummer with <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s E Street Band, plans to tell college freshmen about how he found success working in a rock' n' roll band. <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> will be the featured speaker at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wyoming </ORGANIZATION>'s fourth annual President's Welcome Assembly for Freshmen on Aug. 28. His speech, `` Growing Up on E Street,'' will cover motivation, goal-setting, overcoming career obstacles and achieving success, said university officials. `` Working toward success in a rock' n' roll band is really no different than working toward success in any other endeavor,'' <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said. `` You have to be disciplined, professional and, most importantly, you have to believe in yourself and your goals.'' <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>'s address also will include film footage of his 14 years as the band's drummer.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Princess Nori, the only daughter of Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and Empress <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON>, plans to visit Belgian King and <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Baudouin </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> next week, a palace official said. Princess Nori, a sophomore majoring in literature at <ORGANIZATION> Gakushuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, is to stay with the Belgian royal couple at their summer house in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> for about 10 days beginning Aug. 16, an <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> official said. The princess has traveled in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> twice in the past, but this is her first visit to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, said the palace official. The Crown Prince <PERSON> Hironomiya </PERSON>, the first son of the emperor and empress, spent two summers with the Belgian couple, in 1976 and 1985, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0215EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PieFight     08-09 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pie Fight,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Owners of Restaurant Fight for Slice of Pie Business</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LR1 of Aug. 8.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY FREEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOT SPRINGS, Ark. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pies lining the two shelves behind the counter at the Club Cafe have always been in demand. Now, they're in court. When <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON> bought 51 percent of the cafe in May, he thought he was buying the restaurant's award-winning recipes, too. But then the baker _ <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, a former part-owner who had the recipes in her head _ quit and <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON> sued to get the recipes back. `` They're not written down someplace,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> `` The recipes are something my client has developed over many years.'' Attorneys still are taking depositions and will request a final hearing in a month or so in chancery court to determine ownership of the recipes, <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> said. In the meantime, the 45-year-old Club Cafe still offers, for $ 1 a slice, 14 varieties of pies: peanut butter, chocolate, coconut, banana, lemon, pineapple, egg custard, pecan, apple, Dutch apple, cherry, blueberry, banana split and strawberry. And four cheesecakes. <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON> says the pies these days are every bit as good as Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>'s, and his baker, <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, a 14-year veteran at the restaurant, agrees. `` The pies, we have it down to an art,'' <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON> said. `` Just right after she quit, we had it down pretty close.'' The customers? `` They ca n't tell the difference,'' <PERSON> West </PERSON> said. But some say they can. `` My opinion is that the crust is n't as good,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, an administrative assistant for a judge who's been a regular at the cafe for about five years. `` If you've had the way the pies used to be, you know what's genuine and what's imitation,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said `` We true Hot Springs natives could brag that we had the best pies in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>.'' Businessman <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Horner </PERSON> has been indulging in Club Cafe pies since he was a teen-ager 30 years ago, when he was known as the `` Dutch Apple Kid.'' <PERSON> Horner </PERSON> said he could n't quite put his finger on the difference. `` It seems like it's not quite up to what it used to be,'' he said. `` But they're still good pies.'' <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, 19, who used to help out at the restaurant when her mother worked there, said she ca n't taste any difference and she's sampled everything on the pie menu. `` They taste the same to me. The meringue has a different texture, but the fillings are the same,'' she said. <PERSON> West </PERSON> said he cranks out 50 to 70 pies a day, a job he calls more stressful than his old duty of cooking the main meals. The chocolate pie, one of several crowned with 3 inches of meringue, is his customers' favorite, with coconut next, he said. Under a temporary restraining order issued in May, Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> has been barred from the Club Cafe premises and is working as a waitress at a local Oriental restaurant. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> said there are no orders preventing her from baking elsewhere. Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> filed a counterclaim in June asking that the sale of the 51 percent share to <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON> be rescinded because of a dispute over payment on a $ 40,000 banknote for her mother and aunt, who each owned a 20 percent share in the cafe. Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> had owned the remaining 11 percent sold to <PERSON> McNanna </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, still owns 29 percent of the restaurant and <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> owns the remaining 20 percent. <PERSON> Monty </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Monty </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pawn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shop </ORGANIZATION>, said he's gone into the cafe just about every day since 1954 and has seen a lot of changes, though the same faded red-and-white `` Club Cafe'' sign still hangs over the door. `` Five to six years ago, you could come here for lunch and there'd be a line out the door,'' <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said. But until the last couple of months, that was n't the case anymore, he said. `` There are lots of new faces,'' <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said. `` More tourists seem to be coming in here.'' `` It's kind of funny, getting all the publicity,'' <PERSON> West </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Bush-Hostages     08-09 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Hostages,0375</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper: Bush Says Hostage Crisis Resolution May Not Come Soon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would be willing to negotiate for the release of American hostages held in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> if it could be done without endangering others, according to a published interview. `` I have no problem with that ... if I can talk to somebody and get the release of an American hostage and do it without, in my view or in the view of the experts, putting others at risk'' of being taken hostage, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in an interview appearing in Wednesday's editions of The <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>. `` I have no reason to say that I can see in the short run a total resolution of the American hostage problem. I wish I could,'' he said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would continue using quiet diplomacy rather than military force to resolve the crisis. `` I have tried to keep from escalating matters by making a lot of loud threats,'' he said. `` I have had to take certain prudent actions ... We are trying to handle this where diplomacy can be most effective.'' But the president played down the possibility of imminent freedom for the eight American hostages held in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration Tuesday rejected the idea of swapping the captives in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> for $ 2 billion in Iranian assets frozen nearly ago decade ago. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> dismissed the possibility of such an exchange. `` The questions of the assets have no connection or linkage whatsoever with the hostage issue,'' he said. The president said he was `` satisfied'' that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence network in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> had improved in recent years `` but we still do n't have the intelligence that I would like to have. If we had better intelligence, we might be able to surgically extract the Americans that are still held hostage.'' White House officials said later that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representatives would debrief <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Marrack </PERSON> <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> Wednesday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> about his weeklong tour of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Goulding </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on Monday after a series of meetings with Israeli, Moslem and <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> leaders that `` circumstances may be more conducive'' to a resolution than in recent months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ScotusNotebook Bjt   08-09 0530</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotus Notebook, Bjt,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Supreme Court Justices Travel Internationally This Summer</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD CARELLI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Summertime at the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> is always restful, offering the justices a relaxed pace until a new term starts the first Monday in October. But after a particularly tiring June this year, five of the court's nine members sought renewal overseas. Chief Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> taught a course on <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> history in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> for three weeks, and is lecturing in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. Justice <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON> has a similar gig in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, and Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> have concluded teaching appearances in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, respectively. Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> traveled in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. Justice <PERSON> Antonin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> was to teach in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, but the opportunity fell victim to that country's political unrest. <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON> this week is in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, along with <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> and Justice <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, for speaking engagements at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Justices <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> apparently have no plans to travel outside the continental <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> during the summer recess.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Several Law Clerks Pass Up Lucrative Law Firm Jobs</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Meanwhile, back at the stately edifice on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, the annual ebb and flow of law clerks has seen those who served the justices last term depart, replaced by those already preparing for the coming term. Most of last term's 34 law clerks, each of whom earned an annual salary of $ 34,580, have joined high-powered law firms where their starting salaries likely top $ 80,000 a year. But there are some exceptions. Two of <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>'s law clerks, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Engelmayer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jonathon </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, have become assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Stromseth </PERSON>, a law clerk for <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, has joined the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s legal office, and <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> <PERSON> Findlay </PERSON>, who clerked for <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON>, has become a special assistant to Secretary of Transportation <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON>. Two <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> law clerks have gone into public interest law. <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> has taken a job with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinzerling </PERSON> will work for a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> group known as Business and Professional People for the Public Interest.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Marshall Sets the Record Straight</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Legal Times columnist <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> recently referred to a Time magazine article of some years ago in stating that <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> `` spends his afternoons chuckling over episodes'' of the popular television show, `` The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> contacted <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> to tell him that's not so. `` That's an awful program,'' the 81-year-old justice reportedly told <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>___</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Judge Wapner: the People's Choice</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Speaking of `` The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>,'' did you know that 54 percent of the American public knows that Judge <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON> presides over that TV courtroom and only 9 percent know that Chief Justice <PERSON> Rehnquist </PERSON> sits atop the federal judiciary? According to a recent <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> survey, the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s best known member is <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON> _ 23 percent of those polled could name her. No other justice registered double-digit recognition: <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 7 percent; <PERSON> Scalia </PERSON>, 5 percent; <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, 5 percent; <PERSON> Blackmun </PERSON>, 3 percent; <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> and <PERSON> White </PERSON>, 3 percent; and <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> a lowly 1 percent. The survey-takers said only two of 1,005 people comprising the national sample could name all nine members.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0253EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OceanPollution Bjt   08-09 0626</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ocean Pollution, Bjt,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beach-goers Face Another Summer of Pollution</HEAD>
<HEAD>For Release noon EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Beach-goers ready to frolic in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> coastal waters should be prepared to encounter contamination from toxic chemicals, sewage discharge and medical waste, a private environmental group said today. `` Few regions of the country have escaped the effects of coastal pollution,'' the Washington-based <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said in a report released today. The report, which examined a variety of ocean pollutants, suggested the trend toward growing coastal contamination can be reversed over the next decade, but only through strict pollution control measures and curbs in development along coastal areas. `` Each year our factories dump no less than 5 trillion gallons of wastewater into coastal waters,'' the report said. `` We flush another 2.3 trillion gallons of sewage into them. And every time it rains or snows, massive amounts of poisonous substances, including gasoline and pesticides, are carried into the sea as runoff from our city streets and farms.'' Half of the nation's population lives within 50 miles of coastal waters, including the Great Lakes system, the report said, noting that the population in many coastal regions is expected to increase sharply over the next decade. The report cited as examples of the coastal pollution problem: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>'s designation of three locations in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Puget Sound as priority toxic cleanup sites under the federal Superfund law because of sediment contamination _ The closing of parts of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Casco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> in recent years to clam and mussel digging because of bacterial pollution from inadequately treated sewage that was allowed into the waters Sediments in the bay also were found to be contaminated with heavy metals, PCBs and an assortment of pesticides. _ Continued high levels of the toxic pesticide DDT in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> 20 years after it was dumped into the water by industry The pesticide was banned in 1972. _ The forced closing of at least 40 beaches in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> during the first three weeks of this summer because of sewage contamination _ The oil industry's routine dumping into offshore waters of thousands of tons of waste material, including `` drilling mud'' that contains toxic chemicals Medical waste on beaches, which attracted widespread attention last summer, continues to be a problem, the report said. Such wastes have been reported on beaches in 17 states this summer. `` Even supposedly clean beaches are far from safe,'' said the report, entitled `` Ebb Tide for Pollution.'' About one-fourth of all sewage wastewater `` is dumped directly into coastal waters'' and much more is released into rivers that eventually reaches the ocean, the report said. Pollution from a variety of sources increasingly is showing up in fish and shellfish in many parts of the country, it said. Even the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> contributes to the problem, the report said. Of up to 700 million cubic yards of material dredged by the Corps from harbors and channels each year, as much as 35 million cubic yards are highly contaminated from pesticides, heavy metals, PCBs and oil, according to the study. Much of the dredged material is dumped in the ocean. The environmental group called for tighter controls on toxic industrial pollutants as well as runoff pollutants from agriculture and other sources, a ban on all discharges of raw sewage into waters and more effective treatment programs and tighter land-use and zoning requirements to curb coastal development. It also urged a halt of ocean dumping of medical wastes or the discharge of plastics from vessels, sewers or other sources, and a comprehensive program to protect coastal waters from oil spills including a tightening of restrictions on offshore drilling and tanker shipments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-UrbanLeague-Drugs Bjt   08-09 0572</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Urban League-Drugs, Bjt,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>Drug Abuse Not a `Black Problem,' Urban League Leader Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drug abuse is not merely a `` black problem'' but a national dilemma that will require major resources to solve, say leaders attending the national Urban League convention. `` We ca n't talk about the future we want to see for urban America without talking about the No. 1 threat in our inner cities today: illegal drugs,'' President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the league Tuesday, as the drug issue received heavy attention from the largely black organization. Urban League President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, in an interview Tuesday, said, `` We believe the federal government ought to ... mobilize this nation to a realization that this is not a black problem but a national problem that will require national resources.'' But <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> and others attending the meeting called for efforts to protect the innocent during crackdowns in housing projects. The league today concludes its four-day convention, which included a puppet show at a forum on drug abuse. <PERSON> Lottie </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcoholism </ORGANIZATION> and Other Dependencies, on Tuesday showed off the puppets her Detroit-based group uses to teach families the dangers of drug abuse. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Pogue </PERSON>, senior vice president of <ORGANIZATION> CompDrugs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, told the drug forum: `` What sells in this country right now is the notion that the drug problem is primarily a minority problem. `` It is much easier for this country to buy into the notion that it is a minority problem because then there is no compelling urge to do anything about it,'' <PERSON> Pogue </PERSON> said. However, <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> contended the drug issue has not been swept under the rug. `` I think that the whole issue of dealing with drugs is intimidating,'' he said. `` It has required that our community become consciously more aggressive in attacking that problem, because it is not an easy problem to attack, nor is it a safe one to become involved with. `` Now we are talking about our community developing relationships with the police and authorities that will ultimately lead to people getting locked up,'' <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> said. `` That is contrary to the gentle nature of African-Americans toward each other and is really inconsistent with the value system that we have had about the extended family concept.'' Now, <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON> said, blacks are seeing that `` the entire family must be more important than those persons who would violate the trust of the family.'' Secretary of Housing and Urban Development <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> brought up the subject of fairness, telling delegates Tuesday, `` We are going to be tough on drugs, but we are going to be tough for due process, too.'' <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, asked if due process protections were a major concern for the black community, said, `` I think it is a major concern that people do not be penalized because of someone in their families that might be using drugs that they had no control over. `` We do n't want to create a climate in which people just run roughshod through the -LRB- housing -RRB- projects eliminating people because they just look like they use drugs,'' he said. But <PERSON> Jacob </PERSON>, asked whether tight budgetary restrictions might harm the war against drugs, said: `` I do n't think it will be as tough for drugs as it will be for a lot of things. There are white Americans who are just as scared about what's happening with drugs as the black community.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StatisticiansConvention     08-09 0515</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Statisticians Convention,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lies, Damned Lies and T-Shirts</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Nirmal in 15th graf is cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the quirkier statistics presented at a convention of statisticians here indicates that men should get married, have children and get divorced if they want to be promoted on a university faculty. Another statistic concerned the sale of T-shirts, but it was less precise. Among more than 1,000 scholarly papers being presented at the joint meetings of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Biometrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> and the Institution of Mathematical Statisticians was one by <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON> <PERSON> Billard </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION>, who studied promotion rates on college faculties. Here's what she found about the path of advancement from assistant to associate professor: _ Among those who were married but childless, 51 percent of the men and 41 percent of the women were promoted _ Among those who had spouses and children, 66 percent of the men and 51 percent of the women were promoted _ Among those who were single, divorced or widowed and childless, 53 percent of the men and 37 percent of the women were promoted _ Among those who were unmarried and had children, 80 percent of the men and 33 percent of the women were promoted Ms. <PERSON> Billard </PERSON>, in a paper reflecting the jargon of her industry -LRB- `` the standardized regression coefficients in the prediction equations for men and women'' -RRB-, drew no conclusions although the moral was clear: For male assistant professors, the way to get ahead is to get married, have children and get divorced. For women, that path leads to stagnation. As for T-shirts, vendor <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuzzucoli </PERSON> said statisticians seemed to snap them up. A couple of hundred arrived at her table at 7:40 a.m. Tuesday and by 9 a.m. they were all sold, she said. They bore this legend: `` I'm Statistically Significant.'' Bumper stickers using a play on the statistical term `` moment,'' moved more slowly. `` Statisticians May Be Dull ... But We Have Our Moments.'' The annual August meeting filled two <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotels and brought together 4,215 statisticians to observe the 150th year of the ASA, which was founded in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and whose membership has included <ORGANIZATION> Florence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nightingale </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Carnegie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Buren </PERSON>. The meeting's youngest presenter of a paper was 16-year-old <PERSON> Nirmal </PERSON> <PERSON> D.C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON>, a junior at the <ORGANIZATION> Mahrishi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fairfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. His topic was `` Multivariate vs. Univariate Time Series Forecasts of Weather Variables.'' He's an old hand at delivering papers, having previously done so before the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Neuroscience </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>. Outgoing ASA President <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Norwood </PERSON>, who heads the government's <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION>, noted in a speech that her bureau used to draw moral conclusions from the numbers it gathered For example, she said, in 1888, studying the conditions of women workers, the bureau found that those living in rooming houses had to receive guests in their rooms because there was no other place. It concluded: `` Such a condition tends either in the direction of crushing out social intercourse, especially between the sexes, or of carrying it beyond the limit of prudence.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North-Drugs     08-09 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North-Drugs,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oliver North Begins Community Service in Anti-Drug Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> is beginning his service as a draftee in the war against narcotics by helping reformed drug dealers and other underworld figures to repay their crimes. The national security aide who directed some of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's boldest covert ventures abroad now will be plotting forays much nearer the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> as five men calling themselves the `` New Pied Pipers'' attempt to clean up their old neighborhoods in the capital. North will `` most definitely'' be given a tour of the worst drug neighborhoods, but he wo n't be active on the streets, program coordinator <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` He's not a street-wise individual _ we know that. His element is administration.'' North, conscripted into the drug battle by the judge who sentenced him in the Iran-Contra trial, began his orientation Monday as a management adviser to Save Our Youth, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a private umbrella group for several anti-drug projects. He will focus, to start with, on the `` Pipers'' initiative. Under an arrangement with the court, <PERSON> North </PERSON> will work in the program about 16 hours a week for 75 weeks. Early last month, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> sentenced North to two years' probation, a $ 150,000 fine and 1,200 hours of community service for his conviction on three felony counts in the Iran-Contra case North is appealing his conviction, but told the court he was eager to begin the community work. North, in a two-hour get-acquainted meeting with program organizers, was `` very excited about his involvement,'' coordinator <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` He wanted to get to work right away.'' North initially was scheduled to return to the program's offices at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday afternoon, but <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said the second session was postponed to avoid the glare of media attention. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> assigned <PERSON> North </PERSON> to the Save Our Youth program after the judge learned of the `` Pipers'' effort. The five men, all well-known in the drug community, will try to dissuade youngsters from using drugs and also will seek out dealers in efforts to give them legal employment, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Roach </PERSON>'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, a member of the Pipers who met with <PERSON> North </PERSON> on Monday, said he has no qualms about working with the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide. `` He's interesting ... and I think he was interested in us,'' said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>. `` I think he will use his mind to help us develop solutions.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Staggers </PERSON>, chairman of Save Our Youth, said <PERSON> North </PERSON> `` represents one of the best minds in the nation when it comes to strategizing on how to attack problems.'' As a deputy on <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> staff, <PERSON> North </PERSON> not only was a key figure in the secret sale of arms to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> _ and diversion of profits to the Nicaraguan rebels _ but played a major role in planning the invasion of <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>, the retaliatory bombing of <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> and the interception of an Egyptian airliner carrying the hijackers of the <PERSON> Achille </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> cruise ship. Staggers and <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> acknowledged that <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s political image is a far cry from that favored by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s black community. But `` we're creating a marriage of two extremes,'' said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. `` The focus is not on our differences. The focus is on changing what is happening on our streets and to our young people. The young black man is self-destructive; he's becoming an endangered species,'' <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. Under terms dictated by <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, <PERSON> North </PERSON> can not act as a fundraiser, can not counsel young people, and can not give speeches or act as a spokesman for the group. Thus, <PERSON> North </PERSON> will `` serve as a advisor in the management and administration of SOY's activities,'' with his initial focus on the Pipers, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> said. `` He will stay in his element, and we'll stay in ours.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrightInvestigation     08-09 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright Investigation,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Groups Say Staff Wanted Books Purchased in Lieu of Speaking Fees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal grand jury wants to examine documents from at least three groups that bought hundreds of copies of a book by former <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> instead of paying him a speaking fee, the groups say. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> refused Tuesday to discuss the grand jury probe. But lawyers for <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Realtors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> confirmed they received subpoenas requesting documents related to the book. A spokesman for Ocean Spray, a cranberry and citrus growers cooperative in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, said the grand jury also was seeking documents from his group. Company spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> would n't discuss details of the subpoena, but he did say the group bought $ 2,000 worth of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s book for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s use <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> resigned this summer after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee accused him of trying to evade <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> limits on outside income through bulk sales of `` Reflections of a Public Man.'' He earned royalties of 55 percent on the book's sales. The House limits members' earnings from speaking engagements to 30 percent of the congressional salary, but royalties are exempt. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> said the investigation appeared to be `` very routine.'' <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said the agency's inquiry is continuing `` I ca n't comment on any aspect of the investigation, except I will confirm that it is ongoing,'' he said. <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> spoke to Ocean Spray growers and management employees in November 1985. He said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s staff suggested that instead of giving the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> speaker an honorarium, the cooperative could use the money to buy the books. `` As far as we were concerned, it was an honorarium in the form of a book purchase in place of a cash honorarium,'' <PERSON> Lawlor </PERSON> said. `` How he was to use them -LRB- the books -RRB- was for him to determine.'' <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Fly </PERSON>, a lawyer for <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said the school received a subpoena for documents relating to <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s 1984 speech there and the subsequent purchase of $ 3,000 worth of books Fly said the university had agreed to pay <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> $ 3,000. However, a <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> aide called after the speech to say the speaker had reached his limit on outside income and asked if he could use the money to buy copies of his book for the university, Fly said. `` We received about 504 copies of that book,'' Fly said. <PERSON> Laurene </PERSON> <PERSON> Janik </PERSON>, general counsel for the Realtors organization, said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> spoke to the group in April 1985. A $ 2,000 check was issued and voided, and the money was to be used to buy <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s book, she said However, the Realtors have no record of receiving copies of the book, Ms. <PERSON> Janik </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Politics     08-09 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Politics,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Bush Hitting the Campaign Trail</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, never one to sit still for long, is traveling to his vacation home in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> next week by way of <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. `` It's a fairly common route,'' jokes spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 2,000 miles of backtracking en route to <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION> is a political detour that <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> says will be just one of many upcoming campaign appearances by the president. In the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> instance, it's all in the family. The president will campaign for <PERSON> Ileana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ros-Lehtinen </PERSON>, the Republican nominee for the seat left vacant with the death in May of Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepper </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON>, a 36-year-old <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> real estate executive who has long been active in <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> politics, is the candidate's campaign manager. The president's appearance comes in advance of an Aug. 29 special election. Actually, there has been considerable political maneuvering lately in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s family _ both his official one and his personal one. But most of the movement entails declarations of non-candidacies. <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, for instance, is sending out signals that he's not interested in running for elective office after a stint as <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s secretary of commerce _ preferring instead to spend time developing his business. And <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s oldest son, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 43, an oilman and part owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rangers </ORGANIZATION> baseball team, announced he was more interested in the American League pennant race than running for <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> governor in 1990. He had been widely viewed as a likely contender before last week's announcement. About the same time, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Card </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, deputy to White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, announced he is abandoning the notion of a gubernatorial bid in his home state of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> and will devote his time to his White House post. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> earlier took himself out of the 1990 <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> race for the seat being vacated by the retiring Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, R-N. He said he hopes to serve <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for at least four years, preferably eight. But speculation continues to swirl around persistent rumors that <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, may challenge Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, next year. The Sununus and <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> have been on less than friendly terms recently. Meanwhile, presidential aide <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Studdert </PERSON>, who has served three <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> presidents, announced recently that he was resigning _ to return home to <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, spend more time with his family and serve as a political consultant. And what about reports that he may run for governor of <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>? `` No plans at this time to run,'' <PERSON> Studdert </PERSON> says. However, he does n't hesitate to note that `` there are major economic structural challenges that face <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>'' and to outline how he would approach them. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, meanwhile, appears ready for his vacation, which starts a week from today and will last until Sept. 5. On Monday night, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was preparing to speak via telephone hookup to a town meeting in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and was chatting with the local host, Rep. <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., about their travel plans The preliminary conversation was piped into the White House press briefing room, and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> that first lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was already in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>. `` We're going up next week,'' the president said enthusiastically. A case of the pre-vacation sillies may be setting at the White House. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the other day jokingly told a group of photographers in the Oval Office: `` Do n't anybody take the ashtrays.'' And on Tuesday, he rushed into the White House press room brandishing a gag photo depicting him as an invisible leader _ and jokingly threatened to fire the top aides who sent it to him as a practical joke. The photo showed aides seated around <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s desk at the Oval Office, with his seat empty. It read: `` To President Skippy. From the gang that sees through you.'' It was a reference to the comic strip `` Doonesbury,'' and creator G.B. <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>'s frequent depiction of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as invisible and references to an imaginary `` evil twin'' whom <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> named Skippy. `` This is a vicious assault on my presidency,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made no secret that he's no fan of <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>, who was excluded from the invitation list when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> invited cartoonists to lunch last spring.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-09 0847</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sugar Industry Stockpiling Ammunition for Quota Debate</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s sugar industry is stockpiling statistics to throw into the fight to maintain import quotas that ward off foreign sugar and boost consumer prices at home. An industry study unveiled Tuesday said the sugar and allied corn-sweetener industries directly create 144,442 full-time jobs nationwide and pump almost $ 7.4 billion a year into the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economy. `` It shows there is a lot more to this industry than the attacks that say it only benefits a handful of growers,'' <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sugar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Luther </PERSON> <PERSON> Markwart </PERSON> said in making the study public. <PERSON> Markwart </PERSON> cited findings that, counting indirect effects, sugar and sweetener production generate $ 18.5 billion in wages and revenues, plus 361,000 jobs annually in 42 states. If there is a move to lift quotas as part of the 1990 farm bill, the survey is guaranteed to be used by the industry to offset claims that it represents only a narrow special interest. Because of the quotas, a pound of raw sugar that sells for 14 cents in world markets goes for about 24 cents in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. That difference is passed on to consumers after the sugar is processed, packaged and sent to the grocery shelf. Consumer groups and industries such as soft drink and candy makers complain about the high cost of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sugar. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Agriculture Committees, however, have left the quotas intact. The two panels include members from major sugar-growing states and lawmakers reap hefty campaign contributions from growers. The survey also takes into account jobs and earnings generated by the corn-sweetener industry. Its products, used widely in soft drinks and various foods, trail sugar in price and the two industries are often allies. Lifting quotas would eventually scuttle not only beet and cane growers but sweetener manufacturing in this country, <PERSON> Markwart </PERSON> said. The survey said annual sugar and sweetener output totaling more than $ 7.3 billion a year is spread over many states. It said that the combined value topped $ 100 million in 17 states. The major corn states of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> headed the list of 17. Those two states, plus <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, were the leading corn-sweetener producers. Major cane states were <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> made the list principally as a refining site. Also among the 17 were the sugarbeet producing states of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. Among states on the list, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> was notable for its diversified production. In employment, the agricultural side of the two industries contributes 115,268 jobs and the processing side 29,173, according to the study. It cited seven states with substantially higher employment totals than others: <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, 11,057; <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, 10,513; <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 9,929; <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, 9,890; <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, 9,731; <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, 8,907; and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, 8,889. The total includes farm workers involved in growing corn, even though economists are n't sure just what would happen to those jobs if sweetener production in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> halted. But the study said that, leaving out corn production, overall employment in the industries would total `` a highly creditable 75,411 full-time positions.'' Agricultural wages for corn and sugar totaled more than $ 1.2 billion nationwide, according to the study. Cane states had the highest overall payrolls, $ 159 million for <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and $ 82.7 million for <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>. On the processing side, wages came to more than $ 811 million. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> led the way with $ 118.5 million. Overall wages for growing and processing nationwide were just over $ 2 billion, the survey said. It said that sugar and sweetener business generates wages of $ 100 million a year or more in eight states: <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>. Sugar industry critics are quick to point out not only the impact of quotas on the wallets of consumers but the other side of the employment story. `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> workers also do not escape the adverse effects of this program,'' Sen. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> recently. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, the program's leading <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> critic, noted that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> refineries have been closing their doors and laying off workers because of high sugar prices. He said those costs are also hurting other industries. `` The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> food and beverage manufacturing industries employ hundreds of thousands of people,'' he said. `` The chocolate and confectionary industries alone employ more than 60,000 people. These jobs are threatened by competition from foreign manufacturers who have access to sugar at world market prices, not <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s inflated price.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farm machinery sales are expected to rise for the third year in a row, increasing from $ 6 billion in 1988 to as much as $ 6.7 billion in 1989, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Higher net cash incomes, lower real interest rates, rising farmland values and lowered agricultural debt are all trends that are contributing to expectations for a better year in tractor sales, <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> said. It said demand for the more powerful tractors is especially strong thus far in 1989. Sales of 139-plus horsepower, two-wheel drive and four-wheel drive tractors are expected to climb 23 percent and 65 percent respectively.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDProbe     08-09 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Probe,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>HUD Officials Can't Find Files of Former Assistant Secretary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> says it ca n't locate the files of a former housing official whose conduct is under scrutiny in the influence-peddling probe, but the former official says he does n't have them. `` I do n't even know where they are kept, much less take them with me,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> said Tuesday, adding that he took no files when he left <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> last year. `` I do n't have them.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafferty </PERSON>, deputy assistant secretary for public affairs at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, said, `` He may have taken them with him _ we do n't have them here.'' However, he said the department has no evidence that <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> took the files. `` They could be someplace that we do n't now know about but they are not in the typical places that you would look for them,'' <PERSON> Lafferty </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials realized the files were missing after receiving a Freedom of Information Act request for access to them. The files of two other former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials _ Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and his top aide <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> _ have provided dramatic insight into their activities at the agency. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in May that he had no direct role in funding decisions. Since then, however, a number of news accounts have detailed <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s personal intervention in several <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> projects, and his files offer further evidence that he was more involved in some decisions than he indicated in his congressional testimony. Ms. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s files show that she was often contacted by developers and consultants seeking <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> approval for projects and often gave proposals her endorsement although her job carried no official funding authority. For two years <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> was <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant secretary for housing, a powerful position that has jurisdiction over many of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s subsidy programs The report that sparked the congressional and internal investigations of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> focused heavily on <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>'s conduct. That report, by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general, questioned the selection process used to award lucrative rehabilitation subsidies and said many of those who benefited were contributors to a charity <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> helped establish. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Inspector General <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> concluded that <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> committed no criminal offenses but said that prominent Republicans and former agency officials appeared to get special treatment from <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which reviewed the report to determine whether <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> violated <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s standards of conduct, said last month it would not prosecute him. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> also was in charge of another program that was the subject of a critical audit by the inspector general. That report said <PERSON> Demery </PERSON> awarded emergency <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> funding to a number of projects that were n't eligible. Several qualified projects that did n't receive funding later went under and were taken over by the government, the report said. An <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> review of the program found that developers of projects that got emergency funding although auditors said they did n't qualify included a former business associate and several donors to his pet charity. <PERSON> Demery </PERSON>, in a recent interview, said he made the awards `` on the merits'' and questioned the audit's assertion that many of the projects were n't eligible.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SchoolBuses     08-09 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-School Buses,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Safety Board Trying to Increase Safety of Small School Buses</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> wants to find the best way to protect children who ride in small school buses that do n't have to meet standards set for larger buses. The board Tuesday sent a report on school bus safety back to its staff for revisions after failing to resolve issues involving the use of seat belts and the design of front-seat barriers in buses that carry 10 to 24 passengers. The staff wanted to conduct crash tests, but the four board members at the meeting refused to adopt that recommendation. Acting chairman <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said the small number of fatalities in small school buses _ an average of two or three a year with 41,000 buses on the road _ did n't justify the testing. `` I think the parents of this country can be reassured that their children are by and large safe on these small school buses,'' <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said after the board spent three hours discussing the proposals it eventually declined to adopt. The recommendations, drawn from a study of 24 bus crashes, called for tougher rollover standards, improved joint design, more secure door latches and strengthened windshields. <PERSON> Suzanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Stack </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> safety specialist, said federal standards for seat spacing, barrier padding and other safety features required for large buses do n't apply to the smallest school buses. Use of the small buses has increased in urban areas, where they often serve handicapped or specialized students, she said. <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> said he hopes to call another board meeting within a few weeks to adopt the report and resolve the issues of front-seat barriers and lap belts. <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON> characterized all the safety recommendations as `` relatively minor'' and said school buses remain one of the safest forms of transportation. Large buses are somewhat safer than small ones, he said. The report follows an <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> study two years ago on larger school buses that concluded the vehicles generally are safe. It recommended against installation of seat belts because federal standards require that seats be designed to form a padded compartment around young riders. All small Type A buses, which include vans converted to carry pupils, already have lap belts for each passenger but do n't follow rules for compartmentalizing the youngsters. The draft report recommended crash tests to determine the safety of various barrier designs with both restrained and unbelted passengers in Type A buses. Barriers in front of the first row of seats in small school buses generally were inferior to those in large buses, the report said. In several cases studied, the report said, passengers were thrown into the front of the bus where they were injured. In one instance, two children sitting in a front seat were killed _ one who wore a lap belt rammed his head into the barrier, and the other who was not wearing a belt was thrown through the barrier. The report said restraining barriers sometimes came loose during crashes, moving into the passenger area and exposing sharp edges that caused injuries. The draft also called for a study of the possibility of requiring lap-shoulder belts or other restraining systems for all passengers in Type A buses. Board member <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, who was not at the meeting, said he favored adopting the staff report as drafted. In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said that although school buses provide a highly safe form of transportation, `` the security of schoolchildren remains a major public safety concern.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890809-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-09-89 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Nicaragua     08-09 0687</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Nicaragua,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Contra Legacy Sized Up as Extinction Looms</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
