<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PeachTrees     02-17 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Peach Trees,0311</SECOND>
<HEAD>Peach Trees Will Return to Peachtree Street</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELLIOTT MINOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FORT VALLEY, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>'s famous Peachtree Street will be turning peachy soon. Members of the <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, a grower-financed group that promotes the state's peach crop, will donate 20 trees next month during a ceremony in downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. `` During the national Democratic Convention in July, visitors wondered why there were no peach trees,'' said spokeswoman <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>. `` I thought the <ORGANIZATION> Peach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> should do something to remedy that.'' Ms. <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> said she contacted <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> officials and learned that the peach trees that once lined the street were not replaced when they died because they created a nuisance. `` The fruit attracts bugs and the trees are n't very tolerant of auto pollution,'' she said during a recent interview at a meeting of peach growers in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. She said city officials were skeptical about planting peach trees along the street until she discovered a variety that produces beautiful blooms, but no fruit. `` That's what we're going to plant,'' she said. <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> began in the 1840s as the terminus of the Western and <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Railroad </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Peachtree </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, running northward along a line of ridges, quickly became an important commercial and residential thoroughfare in the growing city. Beginning near <LOCATION> Woodruff </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> downtown, the street runs through office, hotel and business complexes. Further north, <LOCATION> Peachtree </LOCATION> is lined with stately homes built early in the century. The road ends more than 40 miles from downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> in rural northeast <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Peach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s trees will be planted in <LOCATION> Woodruff </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> during a ceremony tentatively set for March 23, said Ms. <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>, who hopes the tree planting will encourage others to plant peach trees along the street. `` It restores some meaning to the name of <LOCATION> Peachtree </LOCATION>,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-CentralAmerica Bjt   02-17 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Central America, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: The Valentine's Day Love-in in El Salvador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The five Central American presidents showed more interest in making love than war last Tuesday, an appropriate activity for Valentine's Day, but the question now is whether anybody is going to cheat. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he's wary of the promises Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> made to hold a free and fair election because he believes the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> leader has been unfaithful in the past after making similar pledges. But the four other leaders _ all friendly to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ who assembled with <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> at a beachside resort in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> believed <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s promises were heartfelt enough to give him the benefit of the doubt. The result was unanimous agreement on a lengthy communique designed to lay the groundwork for two objectives all sides say they want: peace and democracy in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, D-Mich., felt <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s stated commitment in the communique to democracy was so convincing that the Nicaraguan Contras should declare victory `` I think this is what the Contra forces in essence have been asking,'' said <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, long a Contra antagonist. `` I think it presents a unique opportunity for them to take advantage.'' But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was more skeptical. `` What's troubling me is that ... claims like this have been made at one time, only to see those claims repudiated,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday. In return for his promises of democratic reform, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> got his colleagues from <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> to agree to draw up a plan within 90 days that will lead to the demobilization of the Contras. That has been <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s highest priority for years. A year ago, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> granted his wish to suspend military aid to the rebels; now, his neighbors are agreeing to their demobilization. Meanwhile, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has been playing the unaccustomed role of bystander to events in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has yet to make some key appointments, including some at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, and has been occupied with other issues, leaving a vacuum in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> which the five countries decided to fill this week. The administration's hand in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> seems to get weaker by the day. Two years ago, some in the administration had high hopes that the Contras would be able to topple the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. A year ago, the goal was reduced to just getting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve humanitarian aid for the rebels. Now, the administration wants to find a way to head off the planned Contra demobilization, hoping that their continued existence _ if only as a potential military menace _ will induce <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> to keep his word. At a minimum, this has been an interesting week for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> doctrine, the grand design of the former president to assist the Contras and anti-communist rebels elsewhere who are fighting pro-Soviet regimes. The Contras were once the centerpiece of that doctrine but they are now reduced to what amounts to welfare recipients: huddled in austere camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> near the Nicaraguan border, living off U.S.-donated food, facing the specter of demobilization, and praying that the political winds in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> will some day favor them again. In contrast to the Contras, the news was somewhat better this week for another pet rebel group of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s _ the <LOCATION> Afghan </LOCATION> resistance. The day after the Central American presidents called for the demobilization of the Contras, the last Soviet soldier withdrew from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in a major triumph both for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy and for the anti-Soviet resistance. But the Soviet-backed regime is still in power and peace still seems distant in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> as the two sides, both heavily-armed by their respective superpower patrons, continue their struggle with the Soviet Army on the sidelines for the first time in nine years. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> pressed the Soviets to withdraw for years but, now that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> has complied, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is escalating its objectives. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said it would not be fair for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to cut off aid to the rebels after the departing Soviet soldiers left behind all those fighter aircraft, helicopters, tanks, howitzers and other equipment. So in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the somewhat incongruous Valentine's Week prospect is for a lot more warmaking than lovemaking.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Gedda </PERSON> has covered foreign affairs for the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1968.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BushRdp Bjt   02-17 0594</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush Rdp, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Worried About Weapons Soviets Left in Afghanistan</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MERRILL HARTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he will continue helping rebel groups in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> after the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s withdrawal, and fully intends to support the Contras in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> when their current aid expires next month. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday he preferred a peaceful reconciliation in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> but was concerned that departing Soviet forces may have stockpiled weapons for the Marxist government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. `` It would not be fair to have a tremendous amount of lethal supplies left behind and then cut off support for the resistance and thus leave an uacceptable imbalance,'' he said in a session with reporters in the Oval Office. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s remarks came a day after Soviet troops completed their withdrawal. Their departure has caused widespread fears that a struggle for control by competing guerrilla groups could throw <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> into a civil war. `` The time for recrimination is over,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` The time for bloodbaths is over and I would like to see the various factions get together and come up with recommendations that would lead to a peaceful <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> with no more bloodbaths.'' Turning to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and the rebels fighting the leftist Sandinista government, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` I have every intention of seeing that these people receive humanitarian support. But how that comes about, we'll just have to wait and see.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made the statement even though administration officials acknowledge that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has gained the upper hand on the question of giving assistance to the rebels. The current aid program expires March 31. New questions have been raised about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> as a result of the agreement by the presidents of five Central American nations, including <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, to a peace plan that would produce free elections by February 1990 in exchange for dismantling the Contra fighting force. On other matters, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: _ He would `` strongly oppose'' any attempt to outlaw all semiautomatic weapons if that would mean outlawing all pistols and rifles that could be fired continuously by repeatedly pulling the trigger The weapons are popular among drug gangs and one was used to kill five children in a <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, schoolyard last month. _ The tedious pace of making personnel appointments has him fustrated But <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said that `` I do n't think it's hurting the government.'' _ He hopes his campaign for high ethical standards in government has not `` created something that just carries things too far. He expressed sympathy for <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, his nominee as secretary of health and human services, who gave up accumulated sabbatical pay to join the government. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also said that Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> had `` made the right decision'' to sell stocks in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bank holding company that holds Third World loans. While applauding the Soviet withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> as `` a new chapter in the history'' of that country, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he does not accept the Soviet call for a cease-fire and arms embargo. During a Soviet Embassy news conference, Minister-Counselor <PERSON> Yevgeny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kutovoy </PERSON>, the second-ranking official, said `` the question at stake at the present time is this: either restoration of peace on the Afghan soil or continuation of senseless bloodshed.'' But <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Redman </PERSON> said there has been massive stockpiling by the Soviets in recent months. Supplies provided to the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> regime reportedly include numerous fighter aircraft and helicopters, dozens of medium tanks, infantry fighting vehicles, armored personnel carriers, more than 200 howitzers and scores of other artillery pieces and hundreds of transport vehicles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Analysis     02-17 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Analysis,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Christian Power Struggle Will Affect Lebanon's Future</HEAD>
<HEAD>AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Friday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FAROUK NASSAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The battle for control of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s Christian heartland will have a profound impact on efforts to hold this fractured country together The power struggle appears to be finely balanced between army commander <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> and <PERSON> Samir </PERSON> <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>, head of the Lebanese Forces, the main Christian militia. But political figures say <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> must crush <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>'s heavily armed fighters quickly if he is to have any chance of victory. Should <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> come out on top, he likely will emerge as <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s next president, filling a vacuum caused when <PERSON> Amin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>'s term expired Sept. 22 No successor has been elected because Christians opposed the Syrian-backed candidates. If <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> wins, a senior Moslem official said, `` It'll be the final divorce, the irrevocable partition of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> ... and possibly a new round of civil war fighting.'' Electing <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> would make accommodation of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its Lebanese Moslem and leftist allies possible and avert the threatened formalization of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s partition into sectarian cantons. Removing <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>, fiercely anti-Syrian and anti-Moslem, has long been a key demand of <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its <LOCATION> Lebanese </LOCATION> allies, who allege the militia commander has close ties with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> says the 40,000 Syrian troops in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> under a 1976 <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping mandate are an occupation force, and he demands their unconditional withdrawal as a precondition for a Christian-Moslem settlement. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> appears to be aiming to drive <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> out of east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, isolating him north of the city, so that the capital can be reunited and <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> convened to elect him president on a platform of reunifying the country. Minutes before <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON> stepped down, he named <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> prime minister of a caretaker military government until a successor could be elected. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> sought to strengthen his presidential chances by forging a hasty and uneasy alliance with <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>. That outraged <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its allies. They rejected <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> and supported the predominantly Moslem Cabinet of acting Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON> that had governed under <PERSON> Gemayel </PERSON>. The split fractured the 42,000-man army, long plagued by sectarian divisions, and deepened prospects of formal partition. Western diplomats in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> doubt <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s troops will be able to swiftly dislodge the Lebanese Forces from their strongholds along 25 miles of the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coast north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` The army has superior armor and firepower. But there's the issue of loyalty,'' said one diplomat, who requested anonymity. `` Its questionable how long <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s troops and officers will be willing to press the campaign against their coreligionists in the Lebanese Forces.'' Most of the fighters on both sides are Maronites, and pressure for a cease-fire is escalating from the sect's spiritual and political leaders. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> counts mainly on three brigades trained by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Green </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Berets </ORGANIZATION>, as well as three battalions of commandos and military police. These units total about 12,000 men, with 98 U.S.-supplied M-48 battle tanks and 50 French-built AMX-13 light tanks. <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON>'s militia has 6,000 hard-core fighters with thousands more reservists. <PERSON> Geagea </PERSON> has 12 M-48s plus 60 T-54 tanks. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> is the main power broker in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, but its peace efforts have bogged down in the country's unending violence and the complex puzzle of its politics. <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s alliance with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has also been strained by a challenge from the Tehran-backed <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> for supremacy of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 1 million Shiite Moslems, the country's largest sect. <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, the mirror image of the Lebanese Forces on the Moslem side, seeks to create an <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Its power has been weakened by <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s main surrogate, the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amal </ORGANIZATION> militia, in fighting aimed at eliminating <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>'s Moslem extremists. That would make a Christian-Moslem settlement easier.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Farouk </PERSON> <PERSON> Nassar </PERSON> has covered <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> events for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> for more than 20 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BSOStrike     02-17 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BSO Strike,0239</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tentative Settlement Reached</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> announced a tentative settlement of the 22-week <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Symphony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orchestra </ORGANIZATION> strike late Thursday night, but released no details of the agreement. The settlement ends the walk-out that began last September, and concludes the longest running symphony strike in American orchestral history. `` For all intents and purposes, the strike is over,'' <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said at an 11 p.m. news conference. The 96 members of the orchestra must still ratify the agreement, which <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> said could occur by this weekend. The next <ORGANIZATION> BSO </ORGANIZATION> concerts are scheduled for next Thursday and Friday nights. If the strike had not been settled by Monday, the orchestra would have been forced to cancel its East Coast tour scheduled for next month. Last November, the players proposed a four-year contract that would have brought their salaries to $ 1,050 a week in the last six months of the 1991-1992 season. Management countered by offering a contract that would have paid the players a minimum of $ 1,030 a week in the last three months of that season, including guarantees for broadcast and recording work. Under the contract that expired in September, the players had earned a minimum of $ 770 a week. Thursday's negotiating session at the State Office Building was the first between the two sides since mediated contract talks broke off nearly a month ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TombRobbers     02-17 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tomb Robbers,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tomb Robber Given Suspended Death Sentence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court in western <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has given a suspended death sentence to the leader of a gang of tomb robbers, the official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said today. The <LOCATION> Xinjiang </LOCATION> Uygur Autonomous Region court upheld a lower court death sentence for <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Xionglin </PERSON> for encouraging peasants in the <LOCATION> Turfan </LOCATION> area to rob 86 tombs from the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period -LRB- 770-221 B.C. -RRB- But the high court said the sentence would be converted to life imprisonment as long as the prisoner demonstrated repentance over the next two years. <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> said the peasants sold 90 stolen cultural relics to <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> for $ 116. The relics individually command prices of thousands of dollars when smuggled to antique markets in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and other foreign countries. The Chinese government in recent years has tried to crack down on lucrative smuggling operations in antiques and other cultural treasures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0228EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MedicaidReform     02-17 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Medicaid Reform,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>$13.2 Billion to Give Medicaid Coverage to All Below Poverty Line</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government and the states would have to spend at least $ 13.2 billion more to expand the Medicaid program to cover all Americans who live in poverty, according to a coalition led by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The coalition proposed such a plan Thursday to cover the estimated 11 million people whose incomes are below the federal poverty level but who do not now qualify for the health assistance program. `` Medicaid simply does not work adequately in its current form,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, majority leader of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the coalition's committee on Medicaid. `` We call for a system that truly cares for the needs of the poor.'' Though Medicaid was established as a federal-state program to serve the medical needs of the poor, fewer than half of the 33 million Americans below the poverty line are covered by the program, the coalition said. Eligibility varies from state to state, and as health-care costs have soared, states have trimmed growth in their Medicaid costs by restricting eligibility. As a result, the average income threshold for eligibility in 1988 was $ 4,792 gross annual income for a family of three _ 49 percent of the federal poverty level of $ 9,690, the report said. In <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, the state with the lowest income threshold, a family of three can earn no more than $ 1,416 a year to qualify for Medicaid. The coalition, called the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agenda </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, said its plan to expand the Medicaid program and improve benefits would cost $ 13.2 billion to $ 28 billion above current Medicaid expenditures, with most of the additional cost borne by the federal government. `` We are placing before the people a tough statement that there is an unmet need; it is well documented; the program is falling substantially short _ it covers fewer than half the poor in the country _ and that's going to have to fall to government,'' <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON> said. `` New resources have to be made available because we have a system that's crumbling.'' In fiscal 1988, the federal government spent about $ 30.5 billion and the states spent about $ 20.5 billion on Medicaid. The coalition proposes to: _ Establish a standard benefits package states would be required to provide That would add $ 6.5 billion for a `` median'' package and up to $ 21.5 billion for a package that included more services. _ Set income eligibility for the program at no less than the federal poverty level, and require eligibility for those with incomes above the poverty level who have extraordinary medical costs _ Raise reimbursement rates for physicians and hospitals at least to the level of Medicare rates, which would cost an additional $ 4.4 billion Reimbursement rates have dropped so low that at least a quarter of the nation's physicians do n't treat Medicaid patients. Raising rates would `` encourage greater participation by health-care providers and more frequent, appropriate visits by patients to physicians' offices for preventive care,'' the group said. The report by the coalition, which represents both business and labor interests, stayed away from any recommendations on requiring employers to provide health insurance to their employees. Without such a requirement, some employers who now provide insurance coverage for employees who would be covered by the expanded Medicaid program might drop the private coverage, potentially adding more than $ 5 billion to the cost of the expanded program. However, the coalition noted that requiring employer-based health insurance for all employees and their dependents would provide coverage to 5.6 million uninsured workers below the poverty line. That would reduce the cost of the expanded program by an estimated $ 4.6 billion, the group said. Currently, some 35 million Americans have no health insurance. The Health Policy Agenda for the American People was organized in 1982 by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> AMA </ORGANIZATION> pays for most of the work of the coalition, which is composed of 172 groups representing business, labor, consumers, the elderly, children and health-care providers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     02-17 0866</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yeutter on USDA Recruiting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> says he's looking for men and women who are n't afraid of hard work and have good sense <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> told rank-and-file <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employees Thursday that he has interviewed `` a lot of outstanding people in the last 30 days'' for jobs in the federal agencies he oversees. `` I feel good about the quality level, talent level that we're going to be able to assemble here,'' he said `` If we can just get cleared through the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s office of personnel, we may eventually get them on board.'' Appointments to scores of high-level posts within the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration are being held up for clearances and other paperwork associated with the changeover from the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> years. The No. 2 job in <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>, for example, is still being performed by Deputy Secretary <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>. `` One of the questions I have asked every one of these people is how hard they're prepared to work, because if they come, they're going to work awfully hard, probably a lot harder then they've ever worked before,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said He added: `` I also want them to work smart. Working hard is one thing, working smart is another, and we're going to try to find people who will work smart, too.'' Only a few minutes before his brief remarks to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> employees, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> got his marching orders from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> during a formal swearing-in ceremony. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he expected <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> to help `` make sure our objectives in agriculture are achieved'' as the new administration pursues the longtime <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal of reducing world trade barriers. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s name `` rhymes with fighter'' and that he is `` tough as nails, knowledgeable _ that's why I picked him. And I know he's going to fight hard for farming, for fair trade and for all the other important responsibilities for this department.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, 58, who holds degrees in law and economics, is a farm native of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and has held many public and private posts, including <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> service in the early 1970s and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercantile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> from 1978 to 1985. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> had an `` outstanding tenure'' for 3 -LCB- years as President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s trade representative. He said <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> will work closely with <PERSON> Carla </PERSON> <PERSON> Hills </PERSON>, the new trade representative, to help protect the interests of American farmers during multinational trade talks. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> was confirmed unanimously by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on Feb. 8 and was officially sworn in as secretary without ceremony later the same day at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. In Thursday's ceremonial event, which included a color guard, Marine band and family members, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>'s repeated oath of office was administered by <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, who also had sworn him in as trade representative in 1985. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> `` is about to make an enduring commitment to this department, and then told a story about a farmer making a breakfast of eggs and bacon to show the difference between involvement and commitment. `` The chicken is involved, but the pig is committed,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New estimates by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> show the number of cattle being fed for the slaughter market as of Feb. 1 in the seven major beef states totaled 7.7 million head, down 2 percent from a year ago but 5 percent more than inventories of two years ago. The placement of new cattle and calves in fattening pens last month was reported at 1.71 million head, up 3 percent from a year ago but 8 percent more than two years ago. Officials said Thursday it was the largest January feedlot placement since 1974. Marketings of `` fed'' cattle in January totaled 1.67 million head, down 5 percent from a year ago and down 7 percent from two years ago. As of Feb. 1, feedlot inventories were smaller than a year earlier in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. But <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> showed an increases. The seven states produce about three-fourths of the nation's beef. State feedlot cattle inventories are listed here for the seven states. The first number is the number of cattle, in thousands, as of Feb. 1, and the second number is the percentage of a year earlier.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> 260 77 <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> 425 102 <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> 825 95 <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> 675 103 Kansas 1,535 110 <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> 1,920 96 <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> 2,060 93
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says the nation's potato stockpile was about 144.6 million hundredweight as of Feb. 1, down 13 percent from a year ago According to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> records, that was the smallest Feb. 1 inventory since 1983 and compared with 166.7 million hundredweight a year ago. The estimates were for potatoes harvested last fall in the major producing states. Fall potato production in those states, many of them hit by drought, declined to a five-year low of 299.3 million hundredweight from 333.1 million in 1987, the report said Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Peru-Crash     02-17 0089</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Peru-Crash,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>10 Killed When Truck Plunges Off Andean Cliff</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LIMA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten people were killed when a truck hauling eucalyptus branches plunged off a 330-foot cliff in the Peruvian Andes, the government said. The state news agency <ORGANIZATION> Andina </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that the crash occurred near the northcentral town of <LOCATION> Otuzco </LOCATION>, 340 miles from <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. No other vehicles were involved in the crash, which police blamed on recent torrential rains that washed out sections of the crude dirt and gravel highways in the mountains, <ORGANIZATION> Andina </ORGANIZATION> reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SportVehicles     02-17 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sport Vehicles,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Critics Say Treasury Caved in to Pressure from Abroad</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NANCY BENAC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration flunked its first world trade test by caving in to pressure from abroad and cutting back on duty levels for imported sport utility vehicles and vans, critics say. At issue was a decision Thursday in which the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> scaled back a <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> ruling and said only some foreign-made sport utility vehicles and vans will be reclassified as trucks. The <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in January had said it would classify all the vehicles as trucks, upon which a 25 percent duty is imposed, rather than as cars, subject to a 2.5 percent duty. After Thursday's reversal, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> carmakers and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from auto-making states said the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration let itself be swayed by foreign lobbyists. `` The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration clearly caved in to pressure from the Japanese,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON>, D-Mich. `` This decision hurts <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ it costs us money and jobs. <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s other senator, Democrat <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, saw it the same way: `` In its first major action on trade, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has put the wrong foot forward.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which represents domestic carmakers, said the original ruling to boost duties had been the correct one. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> ought to decide <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade practices, not foreign manufacturers,'' the association said. Foreign automakers were more conciliatory, but said none of the affected vehicles should be subject to 25 percent duties, which they characterized as a new tax by the `` no-new-taxes'' president. They also raised the specter of higher sticker prices on both imported and domestic sport utility vehicles and vans. Toyota Motor Sales <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> congratulated <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> `` for courage in the face of massive political pressure from <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'' but said none of the vehicles should be classified as trucks. <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartsch </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> ruling `` reduces but does not eliminate the economic harm brought by the tax.'' <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Segall </PERSON>, speaking for <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suzuki </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, said the ruling `` probably will mean overall more expensive sport-utility vehicles being imported, which will be followed by more expensive domestic sport-utility vehicles.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, characterized its decision as a technical matter based on `` legal classification issues'' rather than a reflection of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade policy. Under past policy, the vehicles sometimes were considered cars and sometimes were classified as trucks, depending on whether they were fitted with back seats and other amenities. Forty-four percent of the 239,000 affected vehicles imported last year were classified as trucks. Under the plan announced Thursday, four-door sport-utility vehicles will be classified as cars and two-door models will be considered trucks. Vans will be considered cars if they feature rear seats, rear windows and rear doors. <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> officials said that had the same policy been in effect last year, 66 percent of affected vehicles would have been classified as trucks, bringing in another $ 83 million in duties.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ACURatings     02-17 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ACU Ratings,290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservatives, Liberals Each Claim Congress Leans Their Way</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> congressional delegation showed its liberal colors and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> was the most conservative state in 1988, according to a survey by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. A lawmaker with a rating of 100 percent is one who voted in accordance with the position of the conservative group in all instances. In <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> the average score was just 3.69. In <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, it was 97.3. Based on its selection of 22 key votes in the two chambers, some of which the group gave double weight, the <ORGANIZATION> ACU </ORGANIZATION> said both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted more conservatively in 1988 than in 1987. The average House rating went from 37 percent to 44 percent, while the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> average went from 40 percent to 43 percent. In both chambers, however, the move to the right was made easier by a lack of confrontation over tough budget issues last year, due to the 1987 budget summit, the group said. Last month, the Americans for Democratic Action, a liberal group, released a similar survey and declared that the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had become more liberal. The differences occur because the two groups base their surveys on different vote lists. However, the surveys do highlight the ideological differences between the parties. The <ORGANIZATION> ACU </ORGANIZATION> said four senators and 38 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, all Republicans, scored 100 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> ADA </ORGANIZATION> last month gave two senators and two dozen <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members, all Democrats, 100 percent ratings. The conservative group in its rating gave double weight to votes on three issues: aid to the Nicaraguan Contra rebels, the override of President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto of the Grove City civil rights extension bill, and a vote on shifting $ 100 million away from the Star Wars missile defense system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RefugeeDetention     02-17 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Refugee Detention,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Plans To Detain Refugees In Tent City</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER DIXON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plans to detain Central American refugees in a `` tent city'' on isolated <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> brushland while their applications for political asylum are processed, congressional officials say. Immigration and <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Duke </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> said Thursday that there had been `` no public disclosure'' of the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's plans for handling the flood of refugees and that the issue was still under review. But Capitol Hill officials disclosed the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plan to pitch tents on land adjacent to a minimum-security federal detention center now being used to process the refugees' applications Rep. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, said in a statement that the tent camp would meet basic human necessities of adequate housing, food and sanitary conditions. More than 2,000 refugees from <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> are crossing into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> illegally every week, most of them coming across the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> at <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, officials say. Treatment of the refugees by <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> has sparked a lawsuit. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Filemon </PERSON> <PERSON> Vela </PERSON> on Jan. 9 blocked an <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> policy that had barred asylum-seekers from traveling beyond the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> while their applications were pending. Under the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> policy, many of the refugees had been relegated to squalid squatters' camps lacking basic sanitation and other amenities. A congressional aide, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> hopes word of the tent-city detention center quickly reaches <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and discourages more amnesty-seekers from coming to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> officials contend that many are seeking only to better themselves economically and are not actually fleeing political repression. Advocates for the refugees say many INS decisions have been politically skewed because the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government is unwilling to admit the extent of repression by Central American governments allied with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> plans to keep the refugees in tents near the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Isabel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Processing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, about 15 miles north of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, the congressional officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Arabs-UnityPacts Bjt   02-17 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arabs-Unity Pacts, Bjt,0611</SECOND>
<HEAD>Arab World Takes Economic Road To Unity, Using Common Market Model</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>AMMAN, Jordan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two new Arab economic pacts being forged this week show a shift from the grandiose unity plans that once sowed hope, suspicion and conflict throughout the Arab world. The <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> born Thursday in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maghreb </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Countries </ORGANIZATION> under discussion in <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> reflect modern economic concerns, including reduced trade barriers and the opening of internal markets. Their model is closer to the European Common Market than the ill-fated <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> that joined <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> as a single nation from 1958 to 1961. Dozens of <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> unity proposals have been born and died since the region gained its independence from European powers after World War II, frustrated by the borders dividing people with a common language and common culture. Many tried in a stroke to sweep away the frontiers, physically unite armed forces or unify foreign policy. Virtually all efforts failed, victims of internal rivalry, external interference or shifting political tides. But like the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>, the new groupings have a political impact. They have divided the Arab world into three main economic blocs: the six-nation <ORGANIZATION> Gulf </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION> Arabian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>, the five-country Maghreb Union stretching from <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iraq </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yemen </LOCATION>. If successful, the new groupings will give their members access to wider markets that should make their farms and industries more efficient and enhance their bargaining power in the world economy. It might also be easier for the three blocs to reach effective agreements on economic cooperation than it has been for the 21 individual Arab countries. The Gulf Cooperation Council, formed in 1981, evolved into a military and olitical alliance under the threat of the Iran-Iraq war. While the leaders of the new <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> deny plans to form a military bloc or a political alliance, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> already cooperate militarily in some ways. They also include two of the Arab world's strongest military forces _ <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> _ as well as one of the best trained, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. Several of the leaders have acknowledged their economic cooperation has political implications. Their charter said they acted in part to enhance `` pan-Arab security against current or future threats.'' But while they have left the door open to other states, the union will arouse apprehension in other quarters. Syrian leaders can not enjoy watching Jordanian TV reach into Syrian homes with celebratory broadcasts of singers lauding <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> as `` <PERSON> Saddam </PERSON> the Joy.'' They remain deeply at odds with both <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, which have tightened their embrace of a Syrian friend, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. The union adds to <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s isolation, already aggravated by <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> support for <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> war, where fighting was halted Aug. 20 under a U.N.-sponsored cease-fire, and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s reintegration into the Arab fold after years of estrangement following its 1979 peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The new council also helps cement <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s return to the Arab world. But the political clout of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> will be limited by economic difficulties faced by all four countries, as well as by outside interests all still maintain. <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> particularly look to <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> for economic aid and can ill afford to alienate it. The new agreement ties <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> countries lying to the west, but <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> is counting on money from its southern gulf neighbors to help finance post-war reconstruction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-17 0863</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0903</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> has decided to return to CBS next year for a sixth season as a crime-solving mystery writer on `` Murder, She Wrote.'' `` <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> as <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Fletcher </PERSON> is one of the most beloved characters on television,'' said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> LeMasters </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are delighted that we will be bringing her back for one more season.'' The agreement was signed earlier this week with <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>. The actress had said previously this would be her last season on `` Murder, She Wrote,'' CBS' highest-rated program, but added she would consider reviving the role in an occasional television movie. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> threw a lavish party for <PERSON> Lansbury </PERSON> on Sunday to celebrate the show's 100th episode.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>'s new staging of `` Swan Lake'' will be the opening night attraction of the American Ballet Theater season at the Metropolitan Opera House. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> announced the lineup for the May 8-July 1 season on Thursday. It includes <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> premieres of three works choreographed by artistic associate <PERSON> Twyla </PERSON> <PERSON> Tharp </PERSON>: `` The Bum's Rush,'' to music by <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hyman </PERSON>; `` Everlast,'' to music by <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Kern </PERSON>; and `` Quartet,'' to music by <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON>. It also features company premieres of two more dances by <PERSON> Tharp </PERSON>, `` The Fugue'' and `` In the Upper Room.'' The new `` Swan Lake'' was first performed in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, in December. Other ballets scheduled for the Met engagement are `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Quixote </PERSON>,'' `` <PERSON> Romeo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Juliet </PERSON>'' and `` La Sylphide.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SUNDANCE, Utah (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A burglar stole an antique clock and more than $ 1,500 worth of ski equipment from <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>'s office at his Sundance Ski Resort, police said. Stolen early Tuesday were the clock, four pairs of skis, a pair of poles, gloves and some boots. The burglar `` went through a closet and took only the best skis and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Redford </PERSON>'s ski poles,'' then left through the front door, according to a statement from the <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. No arrests had been made by Thursday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainer <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> is suing an <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> radio station for invasion of privacy because of an unexpected, on-the-air wake-up call. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> for an October concert when WHTQ-AM telephoned her at her hotel between 6 a.m. and 7 a.m., the lawsuit said. The station and its owner, <ORGANIZATION> TK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fort </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lauderdale </ORGANIZATION>, have a celebrity wake-up feature in which well-known people are roused `` from a deep sleep, without their knowledge, to see what embarrassing or confusing things might be said,'' according to the lawsuit. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' lawsuit, filed Wednesday, also claims that WHTQ should have arranged for a commercial fee to be paid to her since the station informed its listeners in advance that it would be phoning the former star of television's `` The Partridge Family.'' <ORGANIZATION> WHTQ </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> TK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> were unavailable for comment Thursday night.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>APPLETON, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Miss America <PERSON> Gretchen </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> says the public often expects beauty queens to be knowledgable on world issues and that she wants to be remembered for addressing the importance of family and education. `` There are a lot of issues that <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is asked to address and people think you are an expert on every world problem,'' Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> said during an appearance Wednesday. `` I would like to say that I am, but I am not,'' she said. `` So you have to pick and choose. So those are the two that I have decided upon.'' Miss <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Anoka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, said problems related to drugs, violence or teen-age sex are `` a manifestation of the breakdown of the family and the discipline within our society.'' She attributed that breakdown to homes where both parents work, adding that much of what she has achieved was done with her family's help `` Family provides strength and guidance when you are trying to achieve goals,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 First lady <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> helped volunteers fill orders at a food bank warehouse and told the group its work does not go unnoticed. `` I am proud to be a small part of this wonderful organization,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Thursday. `` It gives and helps bring food to so many people. You should be very proud.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and her son, <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, went up and down the aisles of the warehouse, filling an order for a <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> agency that feeds the needy. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also accepted the honorary chairmanship of Second Harvest, the Chicago-based national food bank network that operates the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> to visit her 11th grandchild, <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, born Feb. 7 to <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Longer version of following item moved on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>MILAN, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McEnroe </PERSON> celebrated his 30th birthday by advancing to the quarterfinals in the <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Artois </PERSON> indoor tennis championships. <PERSON> McEnroe </PERSON> received applause Thursday from the sellout crowd of 8,000 at the <LOCATION> Palatrussari </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arena </LOCATION> and a cake with 30 candles from the organizers. `` I feel good, not old,'' <PERSON> McEnroe </PERSON> said. `` I am happy with what I have done.'' <PERSON> McEnroe </PERSON>, a three-time Wimbledon champion, defeated <PERSON> Michiel </PERSON> <PERSON> Schapers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> 6-2, 6-3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PollutionIncrease Bjt   02-17 0572</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pollution Increase, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cities with Polluted Air up 41 Percent</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Air pollution last summer was the worst of the decade and the number of cities where ozone exceeded federally approved levels jumped 41 percent, according to preliminary federal figures. `` This new information shows the clear fallacy in industry arguments that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s air pollution problems are solving themselves,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., who made the figures public on Thursday A year ago the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> listed 68 cities that had recorded peak ozone levels considered unsafe under federal standards. Last summer the number jumped to 96 metropolitan areas plus two areas considered to be rural. The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and environment, chaired by <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, had requested the data from the federal agency. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials said the data were only preliminary and had not been thoroughly analyzed. But they acknowledged the findings indicate a significant increase in urban pollution in 1988 and suggested that when the final numbers are evaluated from all monitoring points the number of cities where pollution exceeds federal standards could exceed 100. The preliminary data submitted to <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s subcommittee show peak daily ozone pollution levels last summer were on average 5 percent higher than in 1983, which had been widely regarded as having the worst ozone pollution this decade. Last summer's levels of ozone, a key component of smog, were on average 14 percent greater than those in 1987. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> called the data startling enough to affect the congressional debate on how to strengthen federal air pollution laws. `` I expect this data to give a strong boost to congressional efforts to establish long overdue new pollution control requirements for the automobiles, factories, power plants and other pollution sources which contribute to the urban smog that now afflicts almost every American city,'' said <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>. <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s subcommittee has scheduled a hearing later this month on the health impact of the air pollution. He said the latest <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> data indicate that more than 100 million Americans now live in cities with levels of ozone or carbon monoxide pollution than exceed what the federal government considers safe. Ozone pollution, caused by a variety of emissions from cars and trucks as well as industrial plants and factories, causes coughing and chest pains and has been linked by some scientists to permanent lung damage. According to the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> findings, two-thirds of the agency's 323 monitoring sites reported higher ozone pollution levels last summer than in any other summer this decade. The information, which was collected by the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> from state and local air pollution control agencies, covered the period from April through October, 1988. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> suggested that the hot summer contributed to the ozone problem. The additional areas that were classified in 1988 as exceeding federal ozone pollution levels were: <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Falls </PERSON> and adjacent <LOCATION> Essex </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Poughkeepsie </LOCATION>, all in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> state; <LOCATION> Sussex </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Del </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Altoona </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Erie </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Johnstown </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>, Reading, <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, all in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greenbrier </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Greensboro </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> and adjacent <LOCATION> Cherokee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>.; <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Toledo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Youngstown </LOCATION>, all in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION>, La.; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Mo </PERSON>.; and <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. An area is considered to have exceeded the federal levels if it has a daily peak ozone level of more than 0.12 parts per million of pollutant.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0301EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-AuctionDoll     02-17 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Auction Doll,0232</SECOND>
<HEAD>Record Price For 1909 German Porcelain Doll</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 80-year-old porcelain doll that lay forgotten in a nurse's attic was sold for a record $ 159,000, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s auction house said. The 21-inch German-made bisque doll _ a red-haired, blue-eyed girl in a pale blue dress _ is one of only 10 of its type made by <PERSON> Kammer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reinhardt </PERSON>, the auction house said Thursday. The buyer was described only as a Madame <PERSON> Vierny </PERSON>, a Frenchwoman planning to open a museum of childhood in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. The same woman bought the previous record-making doll, a 17th century wooden doll that fetched $ 107,000 in March 1987. The unidentified owner is a nurse from <ORGANIZATION> Sussex </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, who <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s said had played regularly, and rather roughly, with the doll through her childhood, even pushing it around in a doll carriage with her dog. Just before Christmas, the nurse cleared it out of her attic with other dolls she had collected and took it to be valued, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said The auction house had estimated its pre-sale price at $ 26,550 to $ 35,400. Another toy, a clockwork battleship, also sold Thursday for $ 70,092, a record for a tinplate toy. The hand-painted model was made in 1904 by a German firm, <PERSON> Marklin </PERSON>. The previous record was $ 49,649 paid at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s in 1984 for a tinplate train, also made by <PERSON> Marklin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0303EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Maritime-Defense     02-17 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Maritime-Defense,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: US Lacks Merchant Ships to Support War Effort</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government should spend $ 13 billion over the next decade to provide enough commercial ships for massive troop and equipment movements should war break out, a special maritime commission says. Despite that figure, the real cost to the government would be about $ 5.7 billion because of the tax revenues generated by the new ships and facilities, the <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Merchant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> said. The commission presented its proposals for legislative and private action to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday, but its chairman, former <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> Sen. <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> Denton </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> made no commitment to seek the funds. The commission's proposals include a package of legislation aimed at adding 244 ships that could be used to meet military needs. Some of the ships would be built abroad to allow shippers to become more quickly competitive internationally, the report said. Another commission member, retired <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Adm. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, said the country probably has only 70 percent to 80 percent of the commercial ships that might be needed in an emergency. `` If a crisis erupted someplace around the world, we do not have enough ships under the American flag to support a planned operation,'' <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Holloway </PERSON> said the maritime defense issue has not been critical in the past because it was assumed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> allies could provide ships if necessary. But he said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> may have to `` go it alone,'' such as it did for a time in protecting <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> shipping. Troops and supplies likely would be available, he said, `` but we do n't have the sealift to move them.'' In addition to increased ship building, the commission recommends adding 8,208 mariners, improving ship repair yards, countering unfair foreign trade tactics against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> maritime industry and making several reforms in laws affecting the industry.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0244EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a Lites     02-17 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>Lites,0449</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Efforts by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> to get a trademark on the name have commissioners in this south <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> city seeing stars. `` We do n't believe we should have to get their permission to use our own city's name,'' Mayor <PERSON> Mara </PERSON> <PERSON> Giulianti </PERSON> said. `` We are a duly incorporated city, and they are n't even a city.'' If the movie capital on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> gets the trademark, all other Hollywoods would have to pay to use the city name. An exception would be made for the area within the city limits of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. But City Manager <PERSON> Irv </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenbaum </PERSON> says that's not good enough. `` We market tourism nationally,'' he said. `` We're the eighth-largest city in the state. We should be able to use our name wherever.'' At least seven other Hollywoods _ in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> _ would face the same problem, <PERSON> Giulianti </PERSON> said. The Chamber of Commerce of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, actually a district of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, filed for the trademark on its name Jan. 17. The <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> city had only until Feb. 17 to file its objection, but has asked for a 30-day extension from the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Trademarks Office.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wires on Feb. 15.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The winner and still heavyweight champion of the world after the legendary `` long count'' is ... <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON>. There were no knockdowns in the courtroom, but <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON> won a clear verdict over <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Dempsey </PERSON> from a historical judge on Wednesday. The unofficial ruling somewhat vindicated a controversial decision by a referee 62 years ago. In front of chuckling onlookers at `` ringside'' at the mock <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, Municipal Judge <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Choppelas </PERSON> declared the long-count controversy `` null and void.'' `` <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON> deserves full credit for the victory,'' the judge said. Almost all the evidence was in <LOCATION> Tunney </LOCATION>'s corner. <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON>'s son, former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON>, said the long count, in which his father lay on the canvas for nine of the slowest counts in the history of boxing, was `` the luckiest thing that ever happened'' to either fighter. `` It kept their names in the public forum and gave added luster to both their careers,'' <PERSON> Tunney </PERSON> said. If the controversy over the famous 1927 title fight was heated, Wednesday's session was not. But that's not unusual for the <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>. The just-for-fun court, which convenes over lunch, has previously settled such weighty issues as the origin of the martini -LRB- <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- and whether <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> is real -LRB- You bet -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UN-Namibia Bjt   02-17 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Namibia, Bjt,0487</SECOND>
<HEAD>First U.N. Peacekeeping Official Expected In Namibia Today</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping forces are due in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> this weekend to begin overseeing the nation's transition to independence after 74 years of South African rule. Commissioner <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Fanning </PERSON>, head of a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> police unit that will monitor <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s national police force, was to arrive today in that country, said <PERSON> Martti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON>, the special <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> representative for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. Fanning is to hold weekend talks with Namibian police officials, <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> said Thursday. Namibian police, which includes some South African officers, will remain responsible for civil order but will be supervised by 500 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> police officers. The <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> move into <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> follows the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s unanimous adoption of a resolution Thursday authorizing <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s independence <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has ruled <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, also known as <LOCATION> South-West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, since it captured the territory from <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> during World War I. Early next week, Gen. <PERSON> Dewan </PERSON> <PERSON> Prem </PERSON> <PERSON> Chand </PERSON>, the commander of the military peacekeeping contingent, will arrive with more administrators, said <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> set April 1 was set as the date to begin the one-year plan for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s transition to an independent, black majority-ruled nation. They also approved a report by Secretary-General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> that calls for sending 4,650 <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> military peacekeepers, 500 police supervisors and at least 1,000 civilian election monitors to <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials have not yet worked out which countries will provide personnel for the peacekeeping force, but for the first time <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has offered to send up to 20 election monitors, said an <LOCATION> Asian </LOCATION> diplomat. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuellar </PERSON> has estimated the effort will cost $ 416 million in its first year, making it the biggest <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping mission since the Belgian <LOCATION> Congo </LOCATION> operation of 1960-64, which cost more than $ 400 million and involved 19,828 soldiers at its peak. The General Assembly on Thursday approved funds for a 70-man team of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> military observers who will monitor the withdrawal of 50,000 Cuban troops from <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> as neighboring <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> becomes independent. That group was budgeted at $ 9.2 million for this year, and a total of $ 19.4 million during its entire 31-month mandate of overseeing the Cuban withdrawal. In December, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> signed accords at <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> headquarters pledging their cooperation with a southwest African peace plan that includes the Cuban pullout and Namibian independence. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> refused to relinquish control of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> without the withdrawal of the Cuban troops, saying their presence just over <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s northern border could intimidate voters during the independence process. All Cuban troops are to be out of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> by July 1991. Cuban troops have been in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> at that country's request since 1975 to defend it from attacks by South African troops and the U.S.-backed rebels of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for the Total Liberation of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugReport     02-17 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Report,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Urges International Cooperation in Drug Fight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> narcotics committee's report on drug use says the problem will become even graver without greater international cooperation. Citing an increase in cocaine-related deaths last year, the report said, `` With the continued influx of cocaine into this country, the prospects for any change in this situation in the near future are not promising.'' The report by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Narcotics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> added that current estimates of the scope of drug abuse may understate the problem. `` Without a concerted international commitment, including a hemispheric drug summit, and without increased resources at home, the future picture is bleak,'' Chairman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said Thursday. The report said indicators showed an increase last year in coca and cocaine production and trafficking as well as greater opium and marijuana cultivation, despite reports of stepped up eradication efforts in some countries. The report catalogued a substantial haul of narcotics intercepted by federal agencies on their way into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> but noted official estimates that the amount intercepted represents no more than 5 percent to 15 percent of what comes across the border. `` Despite the best efforts ... drugs continue to flood our borders because of bumper crops in producing countries,'' the report said. It said that `` the influx of drugs places a significant burden on federal, state and local law enforcement efforts.'' The panel also estimated that 6 million to 6.5 million Americans need drug abuse treatment and said there are 1.1 million to 1.3 million intravenous drug abusers. Currently, however, there are only about 250,000 treatment slots, according to the committee. It said about 148,000 are for intravenous abusers. `` Long waiting lists are common in many areas,'' it said. `` Moreover, there is no measure of those who are discouraged from even applying.'' The panel said hospital emergency rooms recorded 1,696 cocaine-related deaths last year, up from 604 such cases in 1984.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-High-RiseCats     02-17 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-High-Rise Cats,0325</SECOND>
<HEAD>High-Rise Cats Survive Falls From Condos</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One small step for a cat can turn into a giant leap when the feline lives in a high-rise, but a surprising number of the animals survive such falls, veterinarians say. <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON>'s fluffy brown Himalayan two years ago took the plunge _ a 300-foot fall down 24 floors at a condominium in the <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> area _ and today is alive and well. <PERSON> Baily </PERSON> suffered no fractures, according to <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Tenzer </PERSON>, who treated the feline for an internal injury. <PERSON> Sheldon </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinmetz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> veterinarian, said split palates and broken jaws are common because the cats land on their feet and as their bodies hit, chins hit the ground. Their survival also seems to have a lot to do with heavy landscaping and the `` terminal velocity'' factor. Because of their weight and shape, cats fall at a top speed of 60 miles per hour. Humans fall as fast as 120 mph. `` They're pretty incredible creatures,'' <PERSON> Steinmetz </PERSON> said. Veterinarian <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Marks </PERSON> says the cats often take a leap because of taunting by birds. `` The cat's out on the terrace,'' he said. `` There are birds out on the terrace. The cat leaps at the bird. The bird flies away. The cat keeps going. `` The cats are not that stupid,'' he added in their defense, `` but they are instinctive hunters.'' Studies have been done on cats with High Rise Syndrome. In a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> study of 132 fallings cats, a mixed breed named <PERSON> Sabrina </PERSON> took the record by surviving a 32-story fall to a concrete sidewalk. She chipped a tooth. <PERSON> Baily </PERSON>, who may have the local record in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, apparently was cushioned by trees when she fell. She was conscious and dazed, but quite alive, when her owner rushed downstairs. `` We decided the cat really may know how to fly,'' Ms. <PERSON> Greenberg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0316EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AT&amp;T-Allen     02-17 0512</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AT&amp;T-Allen,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>AT&amp;T Chief Urges Curbs on Regional Bell Companies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal regulators should `` unleash'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> telecommunications companies in the world marketplace but keep a tight rein on the regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies, the chairman of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> says. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said Thursday that the Bell companies that were created in the 1984 breakup of <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T are monopolies and should be regulated as such. To allow them into the long-distance and manufacturing arenas, as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the courts are considering, would turn back the clock on the post-1984 gains such as lower equipment prices, lower long-distance rates and more widespread use of telephones, he said. The Bell companies could potentially `` do a lot of damage to competitors'' in markets currently protected by the 1984 consent decree, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said at a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` If that happens,'' he said, `` the force of antitrust law will be blunted. Competition may wane and consumers may suffer.'' He said that under the decree, which prevented the regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies from manufacturing equipment or providing long-distance or information services, `` suppliers have flourished, spurred by the knowledge that the -LRB- regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies -RRB- have no ` inside' manufacturer with an ` inside' track. Allowing them to manufacture would not improve the nation's trade deficit or create new jobs, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. The regional companies would be inclined to go overseas to buy critical switches for phone equipment because of the high costs of developing their own, <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said. `` To get into this business would mean alliances between the -LRB- regional <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> companies -RRB- and switching companies in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>,'' he said. He said that while the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> debates the regulation issue, foreign competitors are racing ahead, thanks to government subsidies. He said he was n't calling for subsidies but for the government to `` unleash the competitive information industry in this country.'' `` Regulators need to act, where they are clearly free to do so, to enhance rather than hinder the competitiveness of American business,'' he said. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, who assumed the <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T chairmanship last April, said there should be less regulation in competitive marketplaces such as long-distance calling, where about 500 companies, including <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sprint </ORGANIZATION>, are battling <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T. `` In the competitive part of the industry, regulators have been slow to remove restraints. This has denied the nation the full benefit of all competitors being able to compete flat out. And this, in turn, penalizes <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> when it needs the very best technology to succeed in a time of intense international competition,'' he said. `` Divestiture worked,'' he said of the <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T breakup. `` It promised protection of consumers by driving a clean wedge between the monopoly markets and the competitive markets.'' He said <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T now was just one of many communications networks in the nation. He said it was unfair that it be regulated in a competitive marketplace while leaders in other industries, such as computers, are not. `` One is overly restrained ... the other is not restrained at all,'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-UnauthorizedHaircuts     02-17 0206</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unauthorized Haircuts,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Father Who Threatened Suit Over Disciplinary School Haircut Arrested</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ELYRIA, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 News reports about a man who threatened to sue a teacher for cutting his son's hair got the attention of police who arrested him for failing to complete a court sentence on an unrelated matter. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kotnik </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Elyria </LOCATION>, was arrested Wednesday on a bench warrant issued by Municipal Court Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> in January 1988 for allegedly failing to attend classes as part of a drunken driving sentence. The arrest came after news reports about <PERSON> Kotnik </PERSON>'s 7-year-old son and a first-grade classmate who had their `` tails'' _ a long lock of hair hanging from the nape of the neck _ cut last week by their teacher, <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Abba </PERSON>. The teacher has been suspended pending an investigation. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimble </PERSON>, the mother of the other boy whose hair was cut, said Thursday that she and her husband had decided to press assault charges against the teacher, claiming the youngster was bruised while being held down to have his hair cut. Ms. <PERSON> Abba </PERSON> initially that she had cut the students' hair as a disciplinary measure but later declined comment on the matter. Calls to her home Thursday went unanswered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0246EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AirbrushedFirefighter     02-17 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Airbrushed Firefighter,0373</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Can Sue Union for Emotional Distress</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A black firefighter who was airbrushed out of a photograph in a union's newsletter can sue the group for emotional distress, a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge has ruled. The omission of <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> from the August 1987 photo did not amount to a statement that was libelous or portrayed him in a false light, said Judge <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollak </PERSON>, dismissing those two counts of <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s suit. But in the ruling Wednesday, <PERSON> Pollak </PERSON> said <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> could sue Firefighters Local 798 and two members involved in the newsletter for intentional infliction of emotional distress, which requires proof of `` outrageous'' conduct. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was one of several <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> firefighters honored for a rescue effort. The photograph in the union's newsletter, Mainline, was altered to remove <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, the only black and only non-union member in the group. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> belongs to the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firefighters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, a separate organization. In his suit, he said the omission caused him humiliation and stress that kept him off the job. The incident happened within a few months of the discovery of a swastika in an office used by two minority firefighters, and the manhandling by whites of an officer involved in a department training program for women and minorities. Those episodes were cited by a federal judge who pronounced the Fire Department `` out of control'' in January 1988. Shortly afterward, Chief <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Phipps </PERSON> resigned and was succeeded by <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> Postel </PERSON>. The union apologized to <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> over the photograph but said he was omitted only because he was not a member of the union, which has some minority members. `` I have a hard time accepting the idea that a union or any other organization has a duty to publish pictures of non-members,'' said <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, a lawyer for Local 798. `` Even if the person does feel left out, there should be a privilege that says the organization is free to grant publicity to its members.'' He said the union would make another attempt to dismiss the emotional distress claim before trial. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s lawyer, said the suit would be redrafted to try to reinstate the libel and `` false light'' claims.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Captan-EPA     02-17 0470</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Captan-EPA,340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fungicide Forbidden on 42 Fruits and Vegetables</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is forbidding use of the fungicide Captan on lemons, potatoes, soybeans and 39 other crops, but other favorites such as apples, grapes and onions are among the two-dozen foods exempt from the new rule. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said in its announcement Thursday that it decided against an outright ban, such as it had proposed in 1985, because `` the benefits of some uses of Captan outweigh the risk from dietary exposure.'' Where it may continue to be used, the risk of a person getting cancer from such exposure is less than one in 1 million, the agency said. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> estimates that about 10 million pounds of the chemical is used each year. Captan was classified by the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> as probably causing cancer because exposure to the chemical had caused laboratory mice and rates to develop tumors. Some environmental groups have urged the government to ban the chemical altogether and expressed disappointment in the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> decision. `` We are now telling people to wash their fruit and write your congressman,'' said <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hind </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> began looking into the possible dangers of <LOCATION> Captan </LOCATION> in 1980 and suggested four years ago that the risk of cancer is significant enough that a ban might be warranted, But <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s acting deputy administrator, said Thursday that studies since 1985 have shown the health risk to be considerably less than once thought. `` We are looking at theoretical lifetime cancer risks that are 100 to 1,000 times lower than we previously projected,'' he said in a statement. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said the agency's decision to allow continued use of <LOCATION> Captan </LOCATION> on some food products `` is based on data which are a more realistic reflection of the actual residues of this pesticide found in the diet.'' Officials said the exposure estimates used four years ago were based on an assumption that 100 percent of each crop received maximum exposure to the chemical. Since then actual field data have shown the exposure estimates to be much lower, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> says Captan may no longer be used on: avocados, beans, beets, broccoli, <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> sprouts, culp onions, cabbage, carrots, cantaloupes, cauliflower, celery, collards, cotton, crab apple, cranberries, cucumber, eggplant, grapefruit, honeydew, kale, leeks, lemons, limes, muskmelon, mustard greens, oranges, pears, peas, pineapples, potatoes, pumpkins, quince, rhubarb, rutabaga, shallots, soybeans, squash, sweet corn, tangerines, tomatoes, turnips and watermelon. The chemical may continue to be used, although in some cases at lower doses, on: almonds, apples, apricots, blackberries, blueberries, celery -LRB- plant-bed only -RRB-, cherries, dewberries, eggplant -LRB- plant-bed only -RRB-, grapes, green onions, lettuce, mangoes, nectarines, peaches, pears -LRB- post harvest only -RRB-, peppers, pimientos, plums, raspberries, spinach, strawberries, taro, and tomatoes -LRB- plant-bed only -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890217-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-17-89 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sweden-Submarines     02-17 0262</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sweden-Submarines,0269</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Sub Intrusions Continue Off Sweden</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
