<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--Poland-Potatoes     12-15 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Poland-Potatoes,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Idahoans Sending Potato Farming Equipment to Poland</HEAD>
<DATELINE>IDAHO FALLS, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Idahoans are sending potato farming gear to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in a gesture of support for the democratic movement in eastern <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, a congressman said. About 30 pieces of equipment, including potato diggers and planters, will be sent initially, Democratic Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said, noting the spud is as central to Polish agriculture as it is to farming in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, the nation's biggest potato grower. `` We are witnessing events in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> of historic proportions, and they started in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said at a news conference Friday. `` We want to see these events succeed. `` Folks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> are scratching their heads trying to decide how best to respond ... In the meantime, Idahoans are moving ahead with practical solutions.'' <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Knudsen </PERSON>, a Boise-based engineering, mining and construction company, agreed to ship the equipment to the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION>, where charitable organizations will ship it to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Vietnam-Refugees     12-15 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-Refugees,0293</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Protests Forced Repatriation of Boat People</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> told <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> that it rejects the forced repatriation of refugees from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and reserved the right to send them back to the British colony, official Vietnamese media reported Friday. A Foreign Ministry official handed a note on the issue to <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> <PERSON> Emrys </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, said a <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> report in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. A group of 51 Vietnamese were flown from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> on Tuesday in the first repatriation of boat people against their will. However, Vietnamese authorities accepted the group back and the official media said without clear explanation that the repatriation was `` part of the framework'' of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s policy of rejecting forced repatriation. According to the <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> note strongly affirmed the policy of rejecting forced repatriation and `` and only accepting those who volunteer to return or who are not opposed to the repatriation.'' It said the ministry official cautioned <PERSON> Davies </PERSON> that `` any violation of these principles may hamper and even completely disrupt the process of cooperation to resolve this problem step by step'' as agreed to at the multilateral conference on Indochinese refugees held in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> in June. The agency said the ministry official stressed that `` if <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> discovers any case of ` forced repatriation,' it reserves the right to return them to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>.'' Many of the 44,000 Vietnamese who have sailed into <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> since June 1988 are considered illegal `` economic migrants'' unless they can prove they fled their Communist homeland fearing persecution. Thousands have held demonstrations to protest the decision by <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> its colony to force the return of the refugees, a decision condemned by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FossilFind Bjt   12-15 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fossil Find, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scientists Find 225-Million-Year-Old Fossil Bed in Virginia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists excavating an ancient lake shore in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> say a concentration of fossils there dates from a time when the area was a lush tropical forest and creatures resembling armored monsters roamed the Earth. <PERSON> Hans-Dieter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sues </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> paleobiologist, said Thursday that the rich collection of fossil remains are from a variety of animals that lived 225 million years ago and some are of a type never before found. `` Many of these are not known because rocks from this particular chunk of time are not found anywhere else in the world,'' said Sues in an interview. `` This is the first time that we've got a really diverse group of land animals from this part of geologic time.'' Sues said the largest assembled fossil includes the body, but not the head, of a five-foot-long reptile resembling an armor-plated crocodile. `` This creature had two rows on its back of this very massive bony plate and huge spines sticking out on the side,'' said Sues. `` It's like something from a Japanese monster movie. It is a funny-looking creature and an entirely new type of animal.'' Sues said the Triassic period fossils were found in a formation of stone called mudrock about 15 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>. The assemblage includes many fossils from a group of animals called cynodonts, the closest reptile ancestors of the mammal. Sues said the fossils include parts for a cynodont about the size of a small dog, and other parts from a mammal-like reptile measuring 5 to 10 inches long. Sues said fragments of fossils of this type have been found in the northern hemisphere, but never in such a large group. Individual cynodont fossils also have been found in <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> and in southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` This is further evidence for the super continent of <LOCATION> Pangaea </LOCATION>, when all of the continents were one large giant land mass,'' he said, because fossils from the same species and the same era can be found on continents that now are separated. It is thought that during the geologic period called Triassic, between 240 to 205 million years ago, all of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>'s land area was connected in one large mass called <LOCATION> Pangaea </LOCATION>. The land mass slowly split apart, as massive plates drifted away from each other over millions of years, and the continents and islands eventually arranged themselves in their present positions. Sues said that when the cynodonts and other creatures lived in what is now <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, the area was near the equator and the climate was tropical and humid, with lush vegetation. `` You had these huge fresh water lakes and rivers throughout the whole area,'' he said. `` You had an incredible variety of animals. There were plant eaters and a whole variety of meat eaters.'' Sues said the cynodont fossils found in the assemblage include five very small jaw bones, apparently from hatchlings, six larger jaw bones, and the back bone and head from a still-larger animal. `` The cynodonts were creatures that were the precursors for true mammals,'' he said. `` They are not mammals themselves, but were species that gave rise to mammals.'' One of the small jaw fossils is attached to a detailed mold of the brain, and <PERSON> Sues </PERSON> said this may enable scientists to learn more about how the mammalian brain developed. Most of the Triassic period reptiles died out as dinosaurs began to evolve into the dominant animal, around the time the first mammal is thought to have evolved. `` This find gives further evidence that mammals and dinosaurs probably evolved at the same time,'' Sues said. `` The dinosaur became very successful and remained successful for the next 140 million years and mammals were sort of pushed over the side and only became important and successful after the dinosaurs went extinct.'' Dinosaurs became extinct, for reasons still not understood, about 65 million years ago, and mammals, such as mankind, evolved into the dominant animal. The fossil deposit was found by <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsen </PERSON>, a geologist with the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lamont-Doherty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Observatory </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Olsen </PERSON> was conducting a survey in the area in 1985, Sues said, and chanced onto a small fossil. Sues identified it as a cynodont part and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> supported further exploration leading to the discovery of the large fossil deposit.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HealthDiscrimination Bjt   12-15 0610</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Health Discrimination, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Seek Study on Men-Only Medical Tests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> want to know if the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> are making good on a promise to stop testing only men when seeking cures to diseases that also affect women. Reps. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, D-Calif., on Thursday asked the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> to investigate a policy adopted in 1987 after a report from the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> showed sex discrimination at <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> clinical `` The gender bias in medical research is n't confined to the lab; it filters down to the health care that women receive,'' said <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>. `` If a woman wants to know if she should take an aspirin every other day to help prevent heart disease or take a cholesterol-lowering drug to bring down her cholesterol level, her doctor wo n't have the answer. All of the research in this area has been done on men,'' said the congresswoman. She was referring to two studies that were highly criticized for excluding women _ the <ORGANIZATION> Multiple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Risk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Factor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intervention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trials </ORGANIZATION>, which studied coronary disease risk factors, and the Physician's Health Study, which inspected use of aspirin as preventive therapy for coronary disease Both studies were started before 1987. <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> said she feared the treatments developed from these men-only studies might be useless or even harmful when applied to women. `` The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> are aware of this problem, but we want to know what success they've had in including more women in medical research,'' said <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>. `` After all, you do n't test apples to see what happens to oranges. The institutes, which together have a $ 7.68 billion budget, are funding hundreds of studies on their <LOCATION> Bethesda </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, campus and through grants to universities and private companies throughout the country. They comprise the nation's largest medical research agency. Dr. <PERSON> Millicent </PERSON> <PERSON> Higgins </PERSON>, who helps decide who will do research for the National Heart, Lung and <ORGANIZATION> Blood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION>, said observational studies were including women all along. The problem was in experimentation. `` The studies started recently include women,'' she said. But she said the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> audit will determine the degree to which women are involved in clinical testing. The policy established by <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 did not have any target date or quotas for increasing women in clinical tests. A research official in another institute at <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> said she did n't think women were being excluded intentionally `` It was like everything else in our society,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Florence </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazeltine </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Population </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> within the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. `` Women are second-class citizens so they are thought of second.'' <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> said that because men dominate medical research they often study problems related to themselves. `` We've heard this for several years,'' said <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, of the American <ORGANIZATION> Heart </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` I think the people making the decisions are getting the message.'' <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON> said they want the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> report by April, before <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on health and the environment begins authorization hearings of the <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> budget for the next fiscal year. Among the questions asked by the members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> are: _ Has <ORGANIZATION> NIH </ORGANIZATION> refused to issue any grants because the applications did not comply with the policy to include women _ Have any grants been given waivers _ What is the cost of including women in clinical tests What are the cost implications of continuing to exclude them? _ What are the gender, race, ethnic origin and age of the people used in clinical trials Which studies used predominantly one gender, race, ethnic group or age group?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Marcos-Murders     12-15 0637</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos-Murders,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Knew of Conspiracy That Led to Murders, Lawyer Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RORY MARSHALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> had `` full knowledge'' of an intelligence conspiracy that led to the 1981 murders of two anti-Marcos activists in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, a lawyer told jurors Thursday. But a defense attorney said that although it's easy to see the late <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> dictator as `` the personification of excess and evil,'' no evidence indicates the deaths of Silme Domingo and <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON> were caused by anything other than a local union dispute. The lawyers' comments came during closing arguments in a civil lawsuit accusing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, his widow, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, and others of running an intelligence network that harassed and intimidated anti-Marcos elements in this country. Plaintiffs claim defendant Dr. <PERSON> Leonilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Malabed </PERSON> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> ran an intelligence slush fund for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> that paid for the murders, and that the payoff was delivered to the killers by defendant <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Baruso </PERSON>, who was president of the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cannery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON>, who were reformist officers of the union, were shot in its offices on June 1, 1981. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' intelligence network `` ran amok'' and <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> did nothing to stop it, plaintiffs' attorney <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> `` had full knowledge of the conspiracy and not only foresaw but condoned acts of harassment and physical violence'' against his opponents in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> court </ORGANIZATION> jury that is hearing the case against the <ORGANIZATION> Marcoses </ORGANIZATION>. Judge <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothstein </PERSON> will judge the liability of five other defendants in the lawsuit, which seeks millions of dollars in damages for the victims' survivors. <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> said the murders were `` made to look like a union dispute _ hot-headed Filipinos shooting it out, vicious thuggery.'' But evidence clearly showed <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> headed an extensive intelligence network not only in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> but in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, he said. `` We're talking about so many spy agencies you ca n't even count them all,'' <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> said. At the start of the trial Thanksgiving week, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> defense lawyer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hibey </PERSON> had painted <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON> as small fry in the anti-Marcos movement, laboring in `` a smaller vineyard'' than more prominent activists. But <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> noted <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON> had traveled to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> to meet with `` the largest and most threatening labor organization <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> had ever encountered,'' and that both men had sponsored a resolution critical of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> at a <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> labor convention. `` Mr. <PERSON> Hibey </PERSON> may have thought the vineyard was small, but <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> knew better,'' <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> said. Three men linked to a Filipino gang were convicted of murder on the theory that <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON> were victims of an internal union dispute over work assignments and gambling in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> fish canneries. `` There was turmoil in this union. There were bribes, there was violence, there were gangs, there was murder,'' <PERSON> Hibey </PERSON> said. `` Sure, it's easy to look upon <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> and <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> as the personification of excess and evil. That's what the case panders to,'' he said. `` Do n't be so blinded by it to seize on the target of two incredibly unpopular people and hold them accountable for that which is not theirs to account.'' But <PERSON> Withey </PERSON> said evidence did n't support that explanation. `` The evidence establishes that <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Viernes </PERSON> were far more than anti-Marcos activists who happened to be killed in an unrelated dispute,'' he said. `` They were very active and effective anti-Marcos activists.'' The jurors must decide whether the Marcoses were part of a conspiracy that led to the murders and whether they were negligent in exercising control over their intelligence network. <PERSON> Rothstein </PERSON> on Thursday granted a motion by the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> government to be dismissed from the suit. In a videotaped deposition made before his death last September, <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who was overthrown in February 1986, took the Fifth Amendment privilege against self-incrimination when asked about his connections with <PERSON> Malabed </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     12-15 0830</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>USDA Predicts 1990 Will be a Better Year for Farmers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A survey of bankers shows them to be in basic agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> experts that 1990 will be a brighter year for farmers and the rural economy. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> projects some improvement in net cash income of farmers, perhaps to around $ 54 billion or so, compared with an estimated $ 53 billion this year. Net cash income is the money farmers have left over from gross cash earnings after paying cash expenses. Department economists also predict 1990 increases in farmland prices, farm assets and equity values, which are important indicators of financial condition. `` Overall, the financial condition of farmers is stronger now than at any other time in the last several years,'' says the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is largely due to cautious investment behavior, effective cost control, increased cash financing, and continued restructuring and write-offs of outstanding debt.'' The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said its survey of 60 bankers at the group's annual conference last month in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, indicated optimism for the rural economy in 1990. Sixty percent said they were optimistic about the outlook for the rural economy. Eight percent said it would worsen. In general, the bankers said they believe farmers next year `` will plant more acreage, use fewer chemicals, sell more products to foreign markets, sign up for more crop insurance and increase their use of computers'' for their records. About 48 percent of the bankers responding to the survey said competition from other banks and the Farm Credit System would be the biggest issue for them in 1990. Rural development was second with 28 percent. The bankers were not so optimistic about the use of the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s guaranteed loan program. Half said they expect to make fewer FmHA-guaranteed loans next year, while 25 percent said they expected an increase and 25 percent no change. `` The results apparently reflect the bankers' concerns over what they consider to be the burdensome paperwork involved in the program,'' the association said. But when it comes to ending federal subsidies to farmers, 67 percent of the bankers said they were opposed to scrapping the payments. `` Nearly all of the bankers surveyed -LRB- 95 percent -RRB- said, so far, they have not had to pay for cleanup costs on environmentally contaminated collateral or property,'' the association reported. `` Likewise, a majority -LRB- 93 percent -RRB- of the bankers said animal rights laws have not affected whether they would make a loan.'' The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bankers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> calls itself `` the national trade and professional association for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s commercial banks of all sizes. Assets of <ORGANIZATION> ABA </ORGANIZATION> member banks are about 95 percent of the industry total.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Republic of <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> has produced its first litter of test-tube pigs, a step the island nation hopes will lead to a supply of genetically superior swine for <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. A report by the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s trade officer in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> said the potential market for such breeder pigs is estimated at 1.8 million sows, or $ 270 million, in <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> alone. `` Companies in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have expressed a keen interest in using <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> as an agrotechnology service base,'' the report said. <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> is eliminating traditional methods of pork production, which require extensive land use and create pollution. `` The birth of the piglets marks the beginning of efforts to modernize production and to create a stock of elite, genetically superior breeding pigs, which can be built up for mass production throughout the region,'' the report said. Veterinary surgeons implanted a surrogate sow with donated embryos last spring, resulting in the birth of seven offspring in September. The report said the surrogate mother can be adapted to local conditions, allowing her to pass on antibodies to local diseases to her young. Because the risk of disease is reduced, the chance of survival is increased. Also, the cost of transporting embryos is less expensive than live animals, and disease transmission is minimized.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> bought <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> poultry meat this year for the first time in a decade, but <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> analysts say the future potential of the Soviet market is uncertain. Sale of 33 million pounds of broiler `` leg quarters'' this fall was the first since 1980, and that one was halted by the partial embargo ordered by then-President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> in retaliation for the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Thus, said the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, there had not been actual shipments of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> poultry meat to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> since 1977. `` Broader Soviet policies toward providing consumer goods and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> prices relative to <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> broiler prices will be among the factors influencing future sales,'' the agency said. `` <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> traditionally imports poultry meat from Eastern European countries, primarily <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, and is expected to continue such arrangements.'' In 1988, <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> exported almost 70 percent of the estimated 395 million pounds of poultry imported by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Gingrich-Ethics     12-15 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gingrich-Ethics,320</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gingrich Asking Campaign Contributors to Help Pay $125,000 in Legal
Fees</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID PACE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 House Republican Whip <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> is appealing to his past campaign contributors to help pay more than $ 125,000 in legal fees for preparing his defense against ethics charges. <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Galen </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> congressman, said Thursday that <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> sent an urgent fundraising letter last week to some 12,000 previous contributors seeking help with his legal bills. Two <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorneys, former <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Bethune </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Swillinger </PERSON>, have been preparing a defense so <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> will be ready if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee decides to launch a formal investigation of two complaints filed against him by Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Galen </PERSON> said `` It's like buying insurance,'' the spokesman said. `` You hope you do n't have to use it.'' The ethics committee has taken no formal action on either complaint. The first alleges that <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> violated <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> rules and federal campaign finance laws by getting 21 investors to put up $ 5,000 each to promote his 1984 book, `` Window of Opportunity.'' An outside counsel hired to evaluate that complaint concluded in October that there were not sufficient grounds for the panel to investigate <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, who was elected <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> whip after filing the ethics complaint that led to the resignation last June of former Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. After the outside counsel made its recommendation, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> filed another complaint, along with 670 pages of supporting documents, accusing <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of ethics and campaign finance violations in seven new areas. <PERSON> Galen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> sent out the fundraising appeal because he does not have enough money in his campaign account to pay the attorneys' bills. <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> reported to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on June 30 that he had $ 35,847 in leftover debts from his 1988 re-election campaign and a cash balance in his 1990 campaign account of $ 50,297.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-15 0955</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0998</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SCRANTON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A veterans group is suing country singer <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> for refusing to perform at a concert when the group refused to pay in cash upfront. The federal suit, filed Wednesday by the Veterans of the Vietnam War, says <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> was hired in April to perform at a concert in <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, on Aug. 18. He received an $ 11,250 check and was to get the balance on the day of the concert. On that day, <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> allegedly demanded the balance in cash, despite the contract's provision for payment by check, and refused to perform. The suit claims he also failed to provide sound and lighting equipment, preventing other bands from performing. The veterans group lost about $ 228,000 as a result of his actions, the suit claims. <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> disputed the allegations Thursday, saying the group had promised him a 30-day promissory note, not a check.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Author <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> says his writing skills were unleashed in a chance encounter with a salty-tongued teacher when he was a struggling, 13-year-old refugee. <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> writes in the Dec. 17 issue of Parade magazine how as a seventh-grader he met <PERSON> Marjorie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabidou </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Worcester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. Told to choose a hobby, <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> said he `` decided to follow the prettiest girl in my class _ the blue-eyed daughter of the local Lutheran minister.'' `` She led me through the door marked ` <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>' and into the presence of Miss <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON>, the newspaper adviser and English teacher who would become my mentor and my muse.'' <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> wrote an essay for the school paper about his mother, who was killed by Communists during the Greek civil war. <PERSON> Hurd </PERSON> sent it to the Freedoms Foundation in <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Forge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, where it won a medal. <PERSON> Gage </PERSON> was a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and later recorded his mother's life and death in the book `` <PERSON> Eleni </PERSON>,'' and his father's story in `` A Place for Us.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Olympic gymnastics champion <PERSON> Olga </PERSON> <PERSON> Korbut </PERSON> has been campaigning to raise money for a group bringing young leukemia victims from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The first of the Soviet children, 5-year-old <PERSON> Irina </PERSON> <PERSON> Chechkovsky </PERSON>, is expected to arrive in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> within two weeks, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> Children's Hospital. <PERSON> Irina </PERSON> became sick apparently because of exposure to high levels of radiation from the 1986 accident at the <LOCATION> Chernobyl </LOCATION> nuclear power plant. She may undergo a bone marrow transplant, <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Korbut </PERSON> lives in <LOCATION> Minsk </LOCATION>, the Soviet city where the girl is from. Winner of three gold medals during the 1972 Olympics, <PERSON> Korbut </PERSON> made more than a dozen public appearances over several days to appeal for donations to the <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, created in July to locate and help children around the world suffering from grave ailments. Twelve Soviet children slated to visit <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> in the coming months will be the first to benefit from the organization's efforts, <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> said
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>'s lawyer has warned impersonator <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Edenetti </PERSON> that his one-man show violates a <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> trademark. `` The whole thing is bogus. I've never heard of vocal qualities being trademarks,'' <PERSON> Edenetti </PERSON> said Wednesday, adding he will ignore the legal threat and continue his Las Palmas Theater performances. <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> publicist <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> would n't comment on the lawsuit Thursday. But in a stunt to advertise Tuesday's opening of `` <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Edenetti </PERSON> <PERSON> Stars </PERSON> as <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>,'' the impersonator's publicist distributed at the threater a `` cease and desist'' letter from <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> attorney <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Finkelstein </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Having traveled to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle during a 14-month sabbatical, cartoonist <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> should have even more loopy animals with which to draw his popular cartoon `` The Far Side.'' The Universal Press Syndicate, which carries <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>'s strip, kept busy during his absence, adding newspapers for a total of more than 900 that run the cartoon. Under his new schedule, <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> will produce five original panels a week, with reissues of old cartoons for the other two days. He said he had mixed feelings about being back at work; the first new cartoons will be published Jan. 1. `` I currently feel fresh and recharged, and a reduced workload I'm sure will play a big role in maintaining that feeling,'' <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> said. `` But, as I'm sure anyone who has had an opportunity to take a full year off will agree, that first Monday morning back to work is quite a sobering experience.'' <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> _ whose off-beat, bizarre humor features animated puns, animals that act like humans and vice versa _ took a break starting in October 1988. <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> and his wife traveled extensively and spent four months in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where he studied jazz guitar. Their home is in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and his wife were received by Emperor <PERSON> Akihiko </PERSON> and Empress <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> was decorated for his contribution to strengthening ties between <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Following the audience Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> Akaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palace </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, had lunch with the royal couple and their son, Crown Prince <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> later met with Prime Minister <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> and received the Grand Cordon of the Order of the Rising Sun, <PERSON> Paulownia </PERSON> <PERSON> Flowers </PERSON>, a foreign ministry official said. The Shultzes arrived in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> on Wednesday for a five-day visit.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BLOOMINGTON, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Today'' anchorwoman <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON> will deliver the commencement address May 5 at <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, school officials announced. <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, born in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> and a graduate of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, began her broadcast career in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> in 1972 as a reporter for WISH-TV. She joined <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' in 1976. <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Norville </PERSON> is replacing her on the show next year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Ex-DAIndicted     12-15 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ex-DA Indicted,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Berks County DA and Reading Mayoral Candidate Indicted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former <LOCATION> Berks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney and a onetime candidate for mayor in Reading were indicted Thursday on federal charges of supplying chemicals to three Reading-area drug operations. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>, who served as <LOCATION> Berks </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> district attorney from 1976-80, and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> are charged with conspiracy to manufacture methamphetamine and phenyl-2-propanone, or P2P, a key ingredient in methamphetamine. The indictment says <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>, a practicing attorney, and <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> delivered chemicals, laboratory equipment and recipes for methamphetamine or P2P to drug manufacturers from June 1985 to February 1986. Three others named in the indictment were not charged. <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Emmanuel </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dimitriu </PERSON>, refused to comment on the indictment. <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernhart </PERSON>, did not return telephone calls for comment. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Vaira </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> described <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON> as a `` broker.'' According to the indictment, in June 1985, <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON> delivered phenyl acetic acid, an ingredient of P2P, to <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Auchenbach </PERSON>, who was charged separately Thursday with manufacturing P2P. <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> and two others not charged delivered about 200 pounds of phenyl acetic acid in December 1985 to a farm in <LOCATION> Bethel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, according to the indictment. <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> also provided drug manufacturers with the telephone numbers of individuals supplying P2P to <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>, the indictment says. The indictment also charges <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON>, 51, of <LOCATION> Myerstown </LOCATION> with one count of aiding and abetting the manufacture of P2P. <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> also is charged with distributing one quart of P2P. If convicted on all counts, <PERSON> Morrissey </PERSON> faces a maximum penalty of 60 years imprisonment and a fine of $ 500,000; <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON>, 65, of West Reading faces a maximum penalty of 30 years and a $ 250,000 fine; and <PERSON> Auchenbach </PERSON> faces a maximum penalty of 20 years and a $ 1 million fine. <PERSON> Marrissey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pastore </PERSON> were scheduled for arraignment Friday in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> before Magistrate <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobkin </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Jobs-Graduates     12-15 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Jobs-Graduates,0452</SECOND>
<HEAD>Job Market Survey Shows Good Growth for College Grads Next Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SARAH NORDGREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 College graduates in 1990 can look forward to a job market much like 1989's _ a year of good growth _ with engineering students pulling in the highest starting salaries, according to an annual survey released Thursday. But the author of the survey said the 260 businesses surveyed were more cautious in their economic outlook than they were a year ago, with 44 percent saying they expected business to be about the same and 6 percent predicting a decline. Fifty percent said they expected a slightly better business climate in 1990. `` This is a rather unusual balance _ a decidedly mixed outlook,'' said <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Lindquist </PERSON>, author of the <ORGANIZATION> Northwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> Lindquist-Endicott Report of 1990. `` Although there appears to be economic stability with limited growth, there is vulnerability in the marketplace,'' said <PERSON> Lindquist </PERSON>, associate dean and director of placement at the school. `` If a decline in business becomes pronounced and widespread, there will be an immediate and sudden drop in job opportunities for college graduates.'' The 44th annual Lindquist-Endicott report surveyed medium to large businesses and industrial companies. Among those surveyed were major employers in banking, finance, merchandising, electronics and public utilities. <PERSON> Lindquist </PERSON> said there is `` a rather good match'' this year between the number of students entering the job market and the jobs available. But he predicted by 1992 there will be more jobs than students, because of a declining pool of students. He said that on average, starting salaries for this spring's graduates would be up 3.9 percent over last spring, lagging slightly behind inflation But he noted a new trend in which 24 percent of businesses offered signing bonuses of about $ 3,000 on average to students who actually accept jobs. Students with engineering degrees can expect to earn an average $ 32,304 starting salary, the highest among their peers, the report said. Those majoring in computer sciences and chemistry are not far behind, with average starting salaries of $ 29,100 and $ 29,088, respectively. <PERSON> Linquist </PERSON> said the outlook should continue to be strong for computer science majors. Accounting majors got the biggest percentage salary increase, up 5.8 percent over last year's figure to an average of $ 27,408, while starting salaries in sales-marketing showed the smallest increase, up .2 percent to $ 27,828. <PERSON> Lindquist </PERSON> said companies are spending more money recruiting at colleges and universities and noted `` a little bit of craziness'' in which some companies hold college receptions complete with `` caviar, shrimp and exotic pates.'' But he said companies continue to seek the old standbys: good grades and extra-curricular activities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0055EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PECOSettlement     12-15 0441</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PECO Settlement,0456</SECOND>
<HEAD>PECO Fined for Improperly Cutting Off Electricity to Customers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRY MUTCHLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARRISBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utility </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> Thursday fined <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> $ 50,000 for improperly cutting off electricity to customers, including a family who resorted to using candles that started a fatal fire. The <ORGANIZATION> PUC </ORGANIZATION> said the utility also must contribute $ 400,000 to an energy assistance fund for needy families as part of a settlement regarding customer service violations over a two-year period. The most publicized case was last April, when <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> cut off electricity to a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> family who used candles to light their home. Eleven days later, a fire started in their row home in the city's <LOCATION> Fairmount </LOCATION> section and killed seven-year-old <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackwell </PERSON>. His five-year-old brother <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackwell </PERSON> received third-degree burns over 35 percent of his body. An <ORGANIZATION> PUC </ORGANIZATION> investigation determined <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> did not alert a `` responsible adult'' in the family that service would be terminated but instead told a neighbor. The commission said the utility also did not provide a 48-hour termination notice and would not agree to payment plan offered twice by the family to clear up the delinquent bill. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, chief of the <ORGANIZATION> PUC </ORGANIZATION>'s consumer research, said the <ORGANIZATION> Blackwells </ORGANIZATION> owed $ 738.01. <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> terminated service and wanted $ 338 to reconnect the electricity and asked the family to pay $ 20 a month afterwards. The <ORGANIZATION> Blackwells </ORGANIZATION> received state assistance and could not afford the amount, <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> would not accept any other payment arrangements. `` They treated this family like they were <ORGANIZATION> Mellon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>,'' Commissioner <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> said. `` They did n't take into consideration, as required by law, -LRB- the <PERSON> Blackwell </PERSON>'s -RRB- ability to pay.'' After reading the <ORGANIZATION> PUC </ORGANIZATION>'s report, <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> said he concluded `` <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION>'s violations of regulations directly and significantly contributed to the death of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackwell </PERSON> and the maiming of <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackwell </PERSON>.'' <ORGANIZATION> PUC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> said he believes the utility's violations and sloppy administration contributed to the fatal fire He said <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> had been fined $ 50,000 for similar violations in 1987. <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> was also forced to pay $ 150,000 to an energy assistance fund. <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said the fatal fire can not be linked to the company's termination of service. <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> said it is `` quite disturbing'' that <ORGANIZATION> PECO </ORGANIZATION> did not modify its behavior after the 1987 fines. `` I think a $ 400,000 fine has good possibilities for behavior modification,'' <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> said, noting that the greatest driving force for change `` is the death.'' `` Without question, if you look at the report of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> in this case, the company has made substantial progress from where it was two years ago,'' <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RuralHousing     12-15 0449</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rural Housing,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rural America Has Low-Income Housing Crisis, Report Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly three of every four rural households pay more for housing than the government considers affordable, with about a quarter of all rural residents living in substandard dwellings, says a new report. `` To many Americans, the low-income housing crisis is primarily an urban problem, calling up visions of homeless men and women sleeping on steam grates and of families in city welfare hotels,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON>, director of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities. `` Yet in rural <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, too, there is a crisis in housing for low-income people,'' <PERSON> Greenstein </PERSON> said. His organization and the <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> coauthored the report released Thursday. Sen. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.C. </LOCATION>, said the report demonstrates the need for his rural housing legislation. <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON> has introduced a bill that would increase funding for <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> rural housing programs by $ 500 million over two years, targeting rural communities that traditionally do not get much help from the federal government. `` In my home state of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 12 rural counties have poverty rates over 20 percent and occupied substandard housing rates over 10 percent,'' said <PERSON> Sanford </PERSON>. `` Some 100,000 <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> households still use outhouses.'' The report found that 42 percent of rural poor households spent at least half of their income on housing in 1985, the most recent year for which data is available. It said 26 percent spent 70 percent or more for housing. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> has standards that say housing is not considered affordable unless it is 30 percent or less of a family's income. While an earlier <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> study showed it's more expensive to live in urban areas, the study released by the two organizations Thursday says more rural residents live in substandard housing than city dwellers According to the report, the worst rural housing is in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. The study showed that 83 percent of all rural housing units with rats were in the South, as were 79 percent of the homes with inadequate waste disposal, 73 percent with holes in the floor, 61 percent with inadequate heating, 53 percent with cracks in the walls and 52 percent with inadequate water supplies. The study was based on data released in February 1989 by the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in a study called the American Housing Survey of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1985. The Center for Budget and Policy Priorities is an independent research organization that specializes in issues affecting low - and moderate-income groups The Housing Assistance Council promotes development of low-income rural housing through seed-money loans, technical assistance, research and information.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ImpoundedPets     12-15 0226</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Impounded Pets,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dog and Cat Returned To Owner In Rent Dispute</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A landlord's lawyer plans to appeal the release of Iris the dog and <PERSON> Whitehill </PERSON> the cat, who had been impounded in a dispute over back rent. Civil Court Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Early </PERSON> signed an order this week releasing the animals, seized Dec. 6 with <PERSON> Lynell </PERSON> <PERSON> Zelenka </PERSON>'s car as security for the money. `` The nightmare is over,'' said <PERSON> Zelenka </PERSON>, hugging her 7-year-old <PERSON> Saluki </PERSON>, and her 11-year-old mixed-breed cat. Landlord <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chambers </PERSON> said she owes him $ 12,000 in rent, which he agreed to let go unpaid while her lawsuit over a back injury was pending. He claims she settled the injury suit recently and failed to tell him. But <PERSON> Zelenka </PERSON>, who admits owing Chambers $ 6,000, ended up with only $ 750 after paying attorney fees and medical expenses, Early was told Tuesday. The judge said he has yet to decide how much rent <PERSON> Zelenka </PERSON> owes. But he ruled <PERSON> Zelenka </PERSON>'s pets have value only to her and, unlike a cow or a horse, would bring no money if put up for sale. `` This is a form of hostage, so to speak, to take the dog and the cat ... Why should the dog and the cat be pulled into the middle of this thing and deprived of the love of their master?'' Early said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Czechoslovakia     12-15 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Czechoslovakia,0497</SECOND>
<HEAD>Havel Wins More Backing for Presidency</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SYDNEY RUBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PRAGUE, Czechoslovakia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opposition leader-playwright <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> has gained more support for the presidency, with 40,000 supporters cheering him in the streets and the nation's <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> primate joining his chorus of backers The opposition and Communist leaders planned to resume negotiations toward selecting the new president. Communist hard-liner <PERSON> Gustav </PERSON> <PERSON> Husak </PERSON> resigned Sunday after swearing in the first government here since 1948 not dominated by Communists. Opposition spokesman <PERSON> Lubos </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobrovsky </PERSON> told a news conference Thursday night that negotiations would resume soon but did not say when. He said negotiators were exhausted after intense discussions that lasted until late Wednesday and decided to take Thursday night off. About 40,000 people poured into <LOCATION> Wenceslas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> on Thursday to show their support for <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>. The rally was called by students who were the vanguard of the pro-democracy movement. Police action on Nov. 17 against peaceful student demonstrators left 143 injured and launched the peaceful revolution that forced the Communists to relinquish their monopoly on power. `` Havel for president!'' and `` We want <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>!'' chanted the crowd Thursday. The voice of Czechoslovak Primate Cardinal <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomasek </PERSON> on Thursday joined others supporting <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, according to the state news agency <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION>. `` My choice for the function of the country's president is Mr. <PERSON> Vaclav </PERSON> <PERSON> Havel </PERSON>, fighter for the right, justice and truth, not only for himself, but for all of us,'' wrote the popular, 91-year-old cardinal in a statement of support carried by <ORGANIZATION> CTK </ORGANIZATION>. The talks Wednesday night at first seemed to have produced agreement in how a new president would be named. Under the constitution, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> has two weeks after the resignation to elect a new head of state and avoid a constitutional crisis. Opposition leaders thought they reached an understanding with the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in earlier negotiations that <PERSON> Havel </PERSON> would be named president until free elections next year. But the 350-member, Communist-dominated parliament has resisted electing the former dissident, who spent years in jail for fighting Communist rule and defending human rights. In parliamentary sessions Tuesday and Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> deputies introduced a proposal to hold a referendum to choose the new head of state. Negotiators met until late Wednesday and concluded by issuing a joint statement saying the deadline would be extended by a constitutional amendment to give <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> 45 days to select the president. <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Hora </PERSON> said the party would make its decision on the issue at a special congress set for Dec. 20-21. The party's shifts indicated a split in party ranks between reform-minded members and those associated with the old, discredited regime of hard-liners. Also suggesting divisions within <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> ranks was the announcement that Slovak party boss <PERSON> Ignac </PERSON> <PERSON> Janak </PERSON> stepped down Thursday from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Frantisek </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanus </PERSON> resigned from the party secretariat.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LookingGlass     12-15 0211</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Looking Glass,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon to Halt Round-the-Clock Flights of Airborne Command Post</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon has proposed halting round-the-clock flights of an airborne command post that since 1961 has had orders to take charge of nuclear forces if the president and other leaders were killed, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday. According to <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is instead proposing that the planes be changed to `` continuous ground alert with specified number of sorties per week.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> recommendation, made amid growing defense budgetary restraints and the belief the threat of a surprise <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear attack is diminishing, needs President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s authorization. One official told the Times the plan has not drawn strong objections from within the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, where some preliminary defense budget recommendations were reversed after debate. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> maintains on a rotating basis a fleet of planes collectively known as `` Looking Glass'' that has been under the command of the <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, Neb. In the event <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leaders were killed during nuclear war, a SAC general would assume command of nuclear forces. The proposal, which originated at <ORGANIZATION> SAC </ORGANIZATION>, would save about $ 20 million in fiscal 1990. The plan is one of several recommendations to change defense planning and spending.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC-SmokingSurvey Bjt   12-15 0455</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC-Smoking Survey, Bjt,0467</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study Urges Targeting Anti-Smoking Effort to Least-Educated</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOSEPH B. FRAZIER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Younger people with limited educations are more likely than anyone to light up and should be the target of campaigns against cigarettes, a study released by the federal <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> concluded. A 1988 survey of about 20,000 people in 36 states and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> found that less-educated people, who also tend to be of a lower social and economic status, are more likely to be smokers. `` There has been progress in reducing cigarette smoking. But the study shows most of the progress is limited to the well-educated,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobedo </PERSON> of the Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>, who analyzed aspects of the survey released Thursday. `` The emphasis must become more targeted,'' he said. `` Some of that already is being done through substance abuse programs. Tobacco is an addictive substance.'' <PERSON> Escobedo </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> has a program in inner-city schools working to reduce the odds of children becoming regular smokers, as do private institutes and some state health departments. The random telephone survey sought people 18 or older. Results showed that for people older than 35 the likelihood of being a current smoker increased with each decrease in the level of education. But for those ages 18 to 34, the chance of being a current smoker decreased substantially only for those with more than a high school education, while smoking rates for high school dropouts and those with high school diplomas were more nearly equal. The study said cultural factors, such as the high Mormon population in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, also may affect who smokes. <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> had the lowest rate of smokers in its over-18 population -LRB- 18.1 percent -RRB- and former smokers -LRB- 9.1 percent -RRB-. <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> had the highest percentage of current smokers -LRB- 37.9 percent -RRB-. The highest percentage of former smokers was in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> -LRB- 20.3 percent -RRB-. The median figure for current smokers was 26.2 percent, meaning half the states were above that figure and half below. The median figure for former smokers was 15.1 percent. The study said other factors affecting who smokes include smoking prevention activities such as school programs, state cigarette taxes and the intensity of promotional events and advertising by the tobacco industry. The study found that 41 percent of the 18-to-34 group with less than a high school education are smokers. The figure dropped to about 34 percent for those with a high school education and 19 percent to those with more than a high school education. In older age groups the education difference between smokers and non-smokers was much less pronounced. The survey is part of a continuing study done annually since 1980 with more states participating each year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0156EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Philippines-Radio Bjt   12-15 0757</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Philippines-Radio, Bjt,0781</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wild Radio: Reporters on the Coup Beat Thrill Listeners</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The told listeners where the snipers were hiding, where the bombs were falling. They filled the airwaves with information, some of it frenetic, some of it wrong, all of it thrilling. `` I'm hit,'' screamed a woman reporter over the air when a shell landed nearby. She continued to broadcast as her van rushed her to the hospital, where doctors found she was suffering only from shock. Such was the wild, free-wheeling style of radio reporting here during the eight-day uprising launched by mutinous soldiers on Dec. 1 in an unsuccessful effort to topple President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. Filipinos listened to the rebellion on the radio, absorbed by round-the-clock running coverage by what is the major medium for news and information here. `` We got threats from all kinds of people almost every day,'' said <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sison </PERSON>, managing editor of <ORGANIZATION> DZRH </ORGANIZATION> radio. `` We tried to balance our reporting, and the threats from both sides made us think we did have a balanced programming.'' Differences in reporting style showed the slant of individual stations. Reporters and anchormen for <ORGANIZATION> DZMM </ORGANIZATION> screamed at colleagues from rival stations for airing `` tactical information,'' such as positions of government forces and the types of firearms and vehicles used. `` You are traitors to our country,'' a reporter lectured on the air. As tension mounted, the government warned it would strictly enforce existing guidelines giving it authority to close stations that broadcast hostile propaganda or `` disinformation.'' Newspapers are exempt from such controls. Publishers say they received no directives from the government on what to print. Individual reporters claim, however, they have been lectured by military and civilian officials angry at stories perceived as favorable to the rebels. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> closed <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> radio station <ORGANIZATION> DZEC </ORGANIZATION> after it erroneously reported that Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> fled the palace at the height of the coup attempt. The station has been the chief outlet of supporters of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who died in <LOCATION> Hawaiian </LOCATION> exile this year after being ousted as president in February 1986. The commission also shut down <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION> radio station <ORGANIZATION> DYLA </ORGANIZATION> after it broadcast a taped interview of rebel leader Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Edgardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Abenina </PERSON>. A week later, the commission reopened the station at the request of church leaders. So far, the government has issued no formal warnings against other stations. It did not prevent the stations from interviewing rebels after they gave up strongholds in the <LOCATION> Makati </LOCATION> financial district on Dec. 7, despite the `` ban'' on rebel propaganda. But stations that adopted a more balanced editorial policy faced another problem _ fending off threats from both government officials and the rebels. <PERSON> Sison </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> DZRH </ORGANIZATION> said the staff received frequent calls from <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramos </PERSON> and military officials demanding that the station omit detailed reports of rebel attacks on military camps. Rebels also demanded that reporters covering the street fighting broadcast their propaganda. Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Florendo </PERSON>, chief of the military-civil relations office, complained at one point that such detailed reporting was helping rebel soldiers correct their aim during air and artillery attacks at the armed forces headquarters at Camp Aguinaldo. Stations also received threats from mutineers who demanded that they transmit only rebel propaganda. One reporter, who spoke on condition that his name and station not be mentioned, said rebels threatened him after management refused to broadcast his interview with them. Television stations reacted more cautiously. All but one of the five <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> stations, including the government station, went off the air on the first day of the coup attempt. Technicians at the four stations removed essential transmitter parts to keep rebel soldiers from seizing their facilities and telecasting propaganda. In 1987, rebel forces loyal to <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> took over private radio-television station GMA-7 and broadcast statements. GMA officials said they learned from that experience and decided to resume operations days later, when it looked like the conflict was over. As the coup attempt unfolded, stations exercised a degree of self-censorship by bowing to government demands that they avoid detailed reports of tactical operations. Several continued broadcasting reports of shelling at Camp Aguinaldo and elsewhere, for example, but would not state precisely where the rounds were falling. Government officers complained the rebels were monitoring the reports and adjusting their aim accordingly. Stations still reported movements of government forces but without detailing exactly how many troops were deployed. At least 113 people died in the coup, the most serious attempt yet to topple Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-SakharovSketch 1stLd-Writethru a0424 12-15 1116</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sakharov Sketch, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0424,1142</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sakharov, the Conscience of Mankind</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS graf 9 `Born in' to INSERT birthdate; SUBS graf 16 `The
Soviets' with two grafs to UPDATE with details of his banishment to Gorky.
Picks up 17th pvs, `In an ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With Obit-Sakharov</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ANDREW KATELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 From national hero to shunned exile to popular lawmaker, <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s remarkable journey of conscience made him perhaps the world's most celebrated dissident. His life was a great irony: the physicist who developed the Soviet hydrogen bomb went on to become his nation's greatest advocate of human rights at a time when the world lived under the shadow of nuclear war. He spoke out for democracy when many others were silent. He kept speaking out when it became fashionable under the reforms of President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. Hours before he died at age 68, he stood on the floor of the Soviet <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> and demanded that the squabbling opposition form an alternative party to the ruling Communists. `` We can not take on ourselves responsibility for what the leadership is doing now,'' he said, speaking in an official forum the type of words that sent him into internal exile for six years, that won him a Nobel Peace Prize. Selfless, brave and determined, the stooped, disheveled dean of Soviet dissent lived to see many of his dreams come true. His own people began to acknowledge his greatness, as the rest of the world had done earlier. But <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> was never satisfied, saluting reforms but faulting their inadequacy. He constantly challenged even the man who turned many of his dreams into reality and set him free after nearly seven years in exile. `` I personally respect <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Sergeyevich </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> very much, but it is dangerous to give so much power even to the initiator of perestroika,'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> boldly told the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in June after it added the presidency to <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s job as <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> general secretary. Born the son of a physicist on May 21, 1921, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s early fame was not as a political activist but as a brilliant scientist. He was inducted into the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> in 1953 at age 32, the hallowed hall's youngest member ever. In 1948, he joined physicist <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamm </PERSON> in developing the hydrogen bomb and for the next 20 years lived and worked in secrecy, with privileges that included a good apartment, a driver, a high salary and a government awards. But, like <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Einstein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> began to worry about the morality of developing weapons of mass destruction. He had his first major brush with top Soviet officials in 1961, when he appealed to Premier <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> to stop nuclear weapons tests. <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> responded that scientists should n't meddle in politics. Two years later, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> agreed to such limits in a treaty with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, horrified at Soviet society's mistreatment of its own citizens, once said his `` social and political views underwent a major evolution.'' He risked his prestigious position and began using his influence for victims of human rights abuses in 1966, speaking out for those who suffered under dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s repressions The authorities showed their rage in 1968, when <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s `` Progress, Coexistence and Intellectual Freedom'' was published abroad It called for Soviet-American detente well before the concept became part of Soviet foreign policy, saying progress in disarmament is impossible without human rights and political changes in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. He was banned from work on secret projects. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> called the essay `` a turning point in my life'' and two years later, he helped found the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. In 1971, after the death of his first wife, he married <PERSON> Yelena </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> doctor and human rights activist who was to become his constant, feisty companion. In 1975, he won even greater world recognition and was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. The Soviets, on the other hand, condemned his strong criticism of the 1979 Soviet invasion of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. First they stripped him of his awards and then on Jan. 22, 1980, he was pickup up on a <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> street and banished to internal exile in <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION>, a closed city 200 miles east. In an autobiographical statement written in 1981, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> reflected on his approach to human rights. `` Moral criteria, in combination with unrestricted inquiry, provide the only possible compass for these complex and contradictory problems. ... Today, as always, I believe in the power of reason and the human spirit,'' <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> wrote. Western governments, scientific and human rights groups pressed the Soviets to release him. In December 1986, a phone was suddenly installed in <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s Gorky apartment, and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> called to say he could return to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, suppressing his joy at the news to show his concern for others, told <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to free all political prisoners. Two months after <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s release, scores of political prisoners were freed and he threw his support behind <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. He gradually was rehabilitated, getting his old job back at the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION>, speaking at official conferences and giving interviews to the Soviet press. In November 1988, he was allowed to travel abroad for the first time, even though <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> himself had said earlier <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> could not travel to other countries because he had access to state secrets. Although he professed not to aspire to politics, <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> was elected to represent the Academy in the new <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Academy leaders had initially rejected him, but had to reverse the decision after a popular outcry. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>'s rumpled figure and high-pitched voice became familiar to millions of Soviets watching his televised appearances at the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and fellow parliamentarian <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON> called him `` the nation's conscience.'' Age and poor health curtailed his human rights activities _ he looked far older than his years _ but when he felt he had to speak out, he did, such as his condemnation of the crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrators in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in June 1989 and constant complaints that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s economic and political reforms did not go far enough. Even though he was a poor speaker _ with a slight stutter and high-pitched voice _ the public had come to know and like <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> so much that an unscientific poll by a Soviet newspaper in October 1989 indicated he was the most popular parliamentarian, outscoring even <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and the maverick Communist <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeltsin </PERSON>. In a February 1989 tribute to <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, the weekly magazine <ORGANIZATION> Ogonyok </ORGANIZATION> `` praised a person who had earlier been cursed'' and published his long-suppressed essays and letters. The Soviet press had come a long way from the pre-glasnost days when it branded him a traitor and `` utterly ignorant person'' who `` groveled before the capitalist order.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Durenberger-Ethics     12-15 0680</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Durenberger-Ethics,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Durenberger Made 40 Trips to Earn $100,000</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHILIP BRASHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn., made at least 40 expense-paid speaking appearances to earn $ 100,000 through a book contract he's accused of using to launder honoraria, records show His <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> publisher said Thursday the speaking fees enabled him to show a profit on <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>'s two books on health and defense policy and allowed the senator to record the earnings as salary. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which has hired a special counsel to determine whether <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> used the book deal to circumvent <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> honoraria limits, has subpoenaed records from organizations that paid the fees as well as from publisher <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON>. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> amended his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> financial disclosure statements in recent months to list the 40 expense-paid speaking appearances, many of them in such locales as <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The speaking appearances include an engagement with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Podiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in 1986 where `` there was not even a mention of the book or books,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Carson </PERSON>, director of government affairs for the group. <PERSON> Carson </PERSON> said a $ 2,000 check was sent to <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Piranha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, but he considered it `` from day one up to the current moment as a fee for the purpose of the senator making a speech to our audience.'' <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, who says he cleared the book deal through the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, contends he broke no <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rules. Aides said he would not respond to questions about the deals now under investigation. The book deal is one of three plans <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> had for boosting his income at a time he was having financial and marital difficulties. Two of the arrangements are being looked at by the <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> _ the book matter and allegations that <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> arranged speeches in 1985 and 1986 to coincide with appointments he and his wife had with a marriage counselor in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. The committee also could be asked to look at payments the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> made to <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> for his rental of a <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> condominium in which he owned an interest. <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> says it was his idea, not <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>'s, to have <ORGANIZATION> Diamond </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Piranha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> division publish the two books _ `` Neither Madmen Nor Messiahs'' and `` Prescription for Change.'' But it was the senator's idea to use <ORGANIZATION> Piranha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> as a speaker's bureau to make money for both men from <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>'s appearances, <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said He sold 13,000 copies of his books, not enough to cover the cost of printing them, <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said. The $ 200,000 earned from the senator's speaking appearances enabled the publisher to net a $ 50,000 profit, said Diamond. `` That was not the intent. At the time we went into it we thought most of the money would be from the sales, but it just did n't work out that way. I thought we would sell more than we did,'' <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. Diamond estimates special interest groups paid <ORGANIZATION> Piranha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> about $ 200,000 to hear <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> speak over the two-year period. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> ended the contract because of the criticism he received, although the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> concluded that payments from his publisher would constitute a stipend rather than speaking fees, he said. `` I believe I made a good faith effort to comply with the law by contacting the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> and seeking its opinion in advance of any work I did under the agreement,'' <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> said in a statement his office issued recently. The complaint before the Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> contends <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> misrepresented the deal to the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> lists 23 appearances in 1985 in connection with the books, including trips to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Head </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, and four cities in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. His 17 engagements in 1986 took him to <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> twice and <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, once each. <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON> filed the amendments to his financial disclosure statements as a result of discussions between his aides and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Ethics Committee staff, said his press secretary, <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>. The Ethics <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> staff has refused to comment on the investigation, but the senator's office confirmed the panel subpoenaed records about the speaking engagements.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Christmas     12-15 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Christmas,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Hails Bells of Freedom for Holidays</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, calling this year's holiday `` the Christmas we've awaited for 50 years,'' is urging Americans to celebrate by reaching out to someone in need. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, with an assist from his 3-year-old granddaughter <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, threw a switch to light the National Christmas Tree on Thursday night, carrying on a tradition that <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> started in 1923. He used the ceremony before about 12,000 people opening the Pageant of Peace on the Ellipse both to celebrate `` the bells of freedom'' ringing across <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and to nudge Americans once again to aid the less fortunate. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> even got into the shopping spirit earlier Thursday, making a personal expedition to a local <ORGANIZATION> Sears </ORGANIZATION> store to buy presents _ clothing, not toys _ for his 11 grandchildren. He came prepared with a list and paid cash. Unlike his predecessor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who used to light the National Christmas Tree from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> went to the Ellipse to light the 35-foot living blue spruce, decorated this winter to symbolize <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s `` thousand points of light.'' Describing the dramatic strides toward democracy that have unfolded in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared, `` This is the Christmas that we've awaited for 50 years.'' Now, he said, `` 1989 is ending bright with the prospect of a far better Christmas time than <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> has ever known; a far better future the world dared to imagine.'' With the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> wall tumbling down and `` spring'' returned to <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, he said, `` The glad sound you hear is not only the bells of Christmas, but also the bells of freedom.'' Turning his thoughts toward home, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` We've worked hard this year, all of us, all of you, to help build a better <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, to help make this a kinder and gentler nation.'' But `` there remains a world of need all around us. In this holiday season, reach out to someone right where you live,'' he said. `` From now on in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, ` there's no room at the inn,' that's simply not an acceptable answer,'' said the president The National Christmas Tree is a living blue spruce transplanted to its permanent spot on the Ellipse in 1978. The ceremony, which kicked off the 1989 Pageant of Peace on the Ellipse, took place despite some star-crossed microphones. When singer <PERSON> Loretta </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> tried to belt out `` A Good Old Country Christmas,'' her cordless microphone flickered on and off. A stagehand gave her another mike. It was dead. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> corralled master of ceremonies <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, dressed in a <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> suit, and began singing into the mike beneath his beard. `` I'm glad I had one beard to give for my country,'' quipped the jocular weatherman. Later, singer <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoo </PERSON> found herself without amplification, and pageant president <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON> could n't be heard introducing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Some speakers cut off in mid-ceremony for the president. Before retreating to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> leaned over and intoned into <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>'s beard _ site of the only reliable microphone _ `` <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION>, you did a fine job.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Stocks     12-15 0024</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Stocks,0023</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nikkei Up</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Nikkei Stock Average closed at 38,271.04, up 90.34 points, on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Scandal     12-15 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Scandal,0578</SECOND>
<HEAD>Founder of Company at Heart of Scandal Denies Bribery Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hiromasa </PERSON> <PERSON> Ezoe </PERSON>, the head of a company that brought down a government by plying it with favors, said in court today that the gifts he gave to politicians were not meant as bribes. The 53-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> chief told Judge <PERSON> Tadatsugu </PERSON> <PERSON> Watanabe </PERSON> that he accepted the prosecution's allegations that he provided gifts and bargain-priced stock to influential figures. `` These events did occur, but I do not agree with the substance of the charges,'' <PERSON> Ezoe </PERSON> said. `` I had absolutely no intention of committing bribery. ... I apologize for causing social disorder.'' Also denying bribery charges were Recruit executive <PERSON> Toshiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Ono </PERSON> and two politicians: former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> Minister <PERSON> Takao </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON> and <PERSON> Katsuya </PERSON> <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON> of the opposition Clean Government party. If convicted, the defendants could be sentenced to five years in prison. Their trial is the last of five that began Nov. 22 in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION>. More than just legal proceedings, the court actions are examinations of the cozy relationship between Japanese government and business. The Recruit scandal began in summer 1988 and brought down Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, who resigned last spring after acknowledging he received large donations from the giant information services conglomerate. Other key figures in the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> have been sidelined by the scandal and the honesty of ranking bureaucrats has been questioned because of gifts they accepted from Recruit. Like the other three defendants, <PERSON> Ezoe </PERSON> accused prosecutors of mistreating him. `` The prosecutors questioned me from morning to night. When I tried to close my eyes they forced me to keep them open to the point that they hurt so bad that tears were flowing,'' he said. <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON>, 56, was chief <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> secretary under Prime Minister <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON>, <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s predecessor. He is accused of receiving the equivalent of $ 140,000 and 10,000 shares in <LOCATION> Recruit-Cosmos </LOCATION>, a subsidiary whose stock was offered to influential people at a reduced price before it was sold publicly. Prosecutors say he put pressure on the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> not to change the traditional season for recruiting college graduates, which would have hurt Recruit's sales of job-placement magazines. <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON> denied the allegations. <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON> said he had been unaware of both the political donations from Recruit and the share-dealing, which was done by an aide. <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON>, 52, is charged with receiving $ 14,000 for himself, $ 35,000 for his wife and 5,000 shares in Recruit-Cosmos for his brother. According to prosecutors, he gave pro-Recruit speeches in Parliament in return. <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON> resigned his seat; <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON> remained in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, but resigned from his party. <PERSON> Ono </PERSON>, a 39-year-old former company department head who faces two counts of giving bribes, denied the allegation. The other trials involve six bureaucrats and two other Recruit executives. Prosecutors must show the point at which a gift becomes a bribe. Japanese law says bribery occurs when a public official or politician receives money or valuables from people or companies the official is in a position to supervise. Recruit offered millions of discount shares in Recruit-Cosmos to hundreds of politicians, bureaucrats and businessmen before the stock was available to the general public. When it was offered on the over-the-counter market, the price of the stock shot up and the insiders made large profits. <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON>'s shares were said to have gained him $ 215,000
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891215-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-15-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LeukemiaDrug     12-15 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leukemia Drug,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>FDA Examining Possible Problems on Generic Drug for Leukemia</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
