<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0107EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Vincennes-Drugs     05-27 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vincennes-Drugs,0421</SECOND>
<HEAD>15 Vincennes Sailors Disciplined for Drug Use</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday that 15 crew members of the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vincennes </ORGANIZATION>, the cruiser that shot down an Iranian jetliner in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> last summer, will be disciplined for drug abuse. `` There is no connection now to the July 3 incident in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> to what has happened on board the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON>, spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Surface </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> headquarters. The <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>, meanwhile, will be shifted to <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shipyard </LOCATION> within five weeks for modifications to correct deficiencies in the Aegis electronic combat control system, The -LRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> reported Friday. Aegis, which would enable a ship like the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> to make computer-recommended battle decisions for entire fleets, was found flawed in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> confrontation. According to Pentagon analysts, split-second decisions were affected by the inability of radar-scope interpreters to immediately match the plane's `` blip'' with digital direction, altitude and speed information displayed on another screen. Those problems are one reason the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> will undergo modernization, an unidentified source told The <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. None of the sailors involved in the drug sweep were in positions that may have influenced the decision by Capt. <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> to fire two anti-aircraft missiles at the jetliner, <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. All 290 aboard the plane died. Of the 15 sailors, six are being processed for discharge from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, while six others have been given warnings, <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> said. `` Three are petty officers who are being investigated for possible court-martial in connection with drug sales,'' he said. <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> noted that the 15 sailors represent 3.9 percent of the 384 sailors on board. `` That is less than the 5.4 percent average for the entire <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. The announcement came as preparations were under way at the <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> for Saturday's change of command aboard the <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> will be rotated to a new assignment at the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> The new <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION> commander is Capt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON>, who had been stationed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and is assuming his fifth sea command. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, have been under guard by the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> since a pipe bomb exploded under the family van Mrs. <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> was driving to her teaching job March 10 in <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jolla </LOCATION>. She escaped injury. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is investigating the attack as possible terrorist retaliation for the airliner's destruction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Wright 4thLd-Writethru a0757 05-27 0952</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wright, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0757,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coelho to Quit, Scramble on for House Leadership Posts</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: To update with confirmation, subs lead and adds 2 new grafs
after 7th graf previous, ``If I can't''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> plans to announce his resignation from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday, Democratic sources said Friday, throwing the party's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership into even more turmoil with the expected resignation next week of Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, his career in shambles as a result of ethics charges, disappeared for a long holiday weekend _ after first handing out roses from his garden to television reporters camped outside his door. Hours later, sources who spoke only on condition of anonymity said <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, the Californian who was third-ranking Democrat in the party's <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> leadership, also plans to quit because some of his business dealings are under scrutiny. Popular Majority Leader <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is likely to be elevated to speaker without a hint of discord, but <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> had expected to be a contender for <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s current job in what was expected to be a nasty battle. But <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> he plans to resign his leadership position as soon as a successor is picked and will quit the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> on June 15, his 47th birthday. `` I do n't intend to put this institution through more turmoil. And more importantly, I do n't intend to put my family through more turmoil,'' the Times quoted him as saying. `` If I ca n't be leader and if I ca n't be whip, it's time to try a new and different challenge. Therefore, June 15, which is my 47th birthday, will be my last day in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> told the Times. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s decision will be announced Saturday at the Capitol, said one source, who explained. `` he does n't want his attention or abilities distracted in this fashion.'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> `` has been told by his attorneys that he has no legal difficulties. But he just thinks enough is enough,'' the source said. `` He does not want to put his party through it.'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> was facing questions about a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> bank executive's purchase of a high-yield junk bond for <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> in 1986, when <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> found himself unable to finance the transaction The bond was sold to <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> by the executive a month later at the initial offering price, saving <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> about $ 4,000 compared to the bond's market price at the time. The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported this week that the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> was opening a criminal investigation of whether <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> received favored treatment from <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> said the story was wrong. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> was expected to face other contenders for the majority leader's spot, including <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>. Likely candidates for the whip position, the post now held by <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, include <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, Chief Deputy Whip <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> and perhaps <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> _ though <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> let it be known he wo n't try for the No. 2 majority leader's position against <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, who helped in his unsuccessful presidential campaign. Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> Democrat who made an impression as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iran-Contra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, might also jump into the majority leader's race. Spokeswoman <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Binder </PERSON> said he has been urged by colleagues to run but has made no decision. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> faced a difficult fight to move up to the no. 2 spot as Democrats were leery of perpetuating the image problems they have had to deal with as <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has fought ethics committee charges of financial impropriety. One lawmaker, a <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> ally, said, `` there are a good many of us'' trying to persuade <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> to step aside, thus freeing <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> to run. Common Cause, the private group that joined in the complaint that brought the ethics commission investigation of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, said Friday it was asking the panel to open a formal inquiry of <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>. A source close to <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> Democrat `` will be a candidate for the position when the speaker resigns.'' And <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON> apparently will have support from the powerful chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowsk </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. The sources, aware of the sensitive nature of the situation with <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> still in his job, commented only on condition they not be named. While the succession struggle swirled about him, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> went on a weekend getaway with his wife, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON>, to an undisclosed location, his aides said. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> awoke Friday morning to find television crews encamped in his front yard. He came outside, cut a bouquet of roses from his garden, and handed them to a network news producer, but declined to answer questions. `` I'll have a statement to make at some time, and when I do, I'll welcome you,'' he said. Earlier this week, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s lawyers and representatives of the ethics panel talked over a possible arrangement under which <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> would give up his position _ which makes him the nation's highest elected Democrat _ in exchange for the dropping of at least one of the major charges against him. In particular, he is said to be interested in wiping out an allegation that his wife <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> was given a no-work job by <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s friend and business partner, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON> House rules prohibit gifts from people with a diret interest in legislation, a description the committee says applies to <PERSON> Mallick </PERSON>. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, meanwhile, told a news conference in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> that `` there is no vacancy'' for the speaker's job and `` I have no knowledge on his part of plans to resign.'' <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> had not asked him to schedule time for <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> to address the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to defend himself against <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee charges he committed 69 rules violations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FieldTripRobbery     05-27 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Field Trip Robbery,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police: 6th Graders Steal $10,100 In Bank Field Trip</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JAY, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two sixth-graders have been charged with helping themselves to more than $ 10,000 in cash during a class tour of a bank vault. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Elementary </PERSON> <PERSON> School </PERSON> <PERSON> Principal </PERSON> <PERSON> Elton </PERSON> <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> said he dropped about 30 students off at <ORGANIZATION> NCNB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> Thursday morning and returned to pick them up about an hour later. Hours later, the bank manager called to report $ 10,100 was missing. <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> said he called <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON>, a resource officer at <ORGANIZATION> Jay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, to ask students about the reported theft. <PERSON> Whatley </PERSON> and another deputy questioned the students who went on the field trip one at a time. <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> said the boys did n't try to hide the theft but apparently did n't say why they helped themselves to the cash. The two allegedly stuffed their clothes with $ 100 bills. Deputies recovered all of the missing money. Sheriff's Capt. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said the boys were picked up by the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. They were charged with grand theft and taken to the <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> said the two, who had recently transferred to his school, are n't representative of its students. `` Our kids are good kids, basically. We normally do n't have problems,'' he said. Later, <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> gathered all the sixth-graders for a lecture on `` finance.'' `` I think -LRB- the incident -RRB- may have seemed kind of funny to start out with, but when I got there it ceased being funny,'' he said. The principal said he had not had a chance to apologize to the bank manager, `` but I do n't think this will affect our ability to tour the bank as in years past.'' <PERSON> Nowling </PERSON> said the boys have been suspended from school for the remainder of the year. Bank officials refused to discuss the incident Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Time-Warner     05-27 0510</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Time-Warner,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Time-Warner Merger Now Needs Only Shareholder Approval</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shareholders meetings next month are the last big hurdle to the $ 18 billion merger of <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> following action by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> on Friday granted a temporary waiver of its cross-ownership restrictions, which was the final regulatory approval needed in the creation of the world's largest entertainment and media conglomerate. The commission had to review the transaction because a <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary _ <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> _ operates cable television systems in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, areas, which overlap with the viewership of television stations owned by <ORGANIZATION> Chris-Craft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a company that controls a 15.5 percent block of <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> stock and would hold about 12 percent of the combined conglomerate. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s waiver gave the companies 18 months to comply with federal cross-ownership rules that generally prohibit one company from owning multiple media outlets in one area. There are at least four ways the companies can comply: <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> could sell the affected cable systems; <ORGANIZATION> Chris-Craft </ORGANIZATION> could sell its TV subsidiary; or it could reduce its stake in the combined <ORGANIZATION> Time-Warner </ORGANIZATION> to below 5 percent; or <ORGANIZATION> Time-Warner </ORGANIZATION> could apply and receive a permanent waiver from the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>. `` We perceive no public interest benefit in removing cable service to the many communities involved in this matter until a buyer or buyers can be found,'' the commission wrote in its opinion. `` The alternative would be to hold up a major transaction of which the cable systems constitute but a very small part.'' The chairmen of both companies, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Munro </PERSON> of Time and <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION>, said in a joint statement: `` We are delighted to have successfully completed the federal review process necessary for our merger. ... We are confident that the nation's policy makers will not be disappointed in the pro-competitive, pro-American and pro-consumer impact of the merger. Seven weeks ago, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ruled that the merger would not violate antitrust laws. On Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> approved proxy materials for separate Time and <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> shareholders meetings scheduled June 23 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. A majority of shareholders of record on May 1 must approve the merger, which was announced on March 3. The transaction also must be approved by several local cable franchising authorities. Time owns systems with about 4 million subscribers while <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> has about 1.5 million cable subscribers. The proposed conglomerate, <ORGANIZATION> Time-Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, would surpass <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Australia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> as the world's biggest media and entertainment concern. Time publishes Time, People and Sports Illustrated magazines and owns <ORGANIZATION> Time-Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Books </ORGANIZATION> and the Book-of-the-Month Club. <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> operates the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION> movie and television studios as well as <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recording </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> owns cable systems or has a stake in cable systems serving Canyon Country, <PERSON> Orange </PERSON>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Marino </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gardena </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Torrance </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. A wholly owned <ORGANIZATION> Chris-Craft </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary, <ORGANIZATION> BHC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, owns <ORGANIZATION> KMOL-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> KCOP-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Fisher     05-27 0372</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Fisher,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>McCarthy Target Who Helped Shift Public Opinion Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, who as a young lawyer became a target of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> but whose boss' spirited defense of him helped turn the tables on the senator, has died of a heart attack. He was 68. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> died Thursday while attending a lecture sponsored by the Israeli bar in <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION>. He was a senior partner in the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> firm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Dorr </PERSON>, which he joined shortly after his graduation from <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. He recently had moved to <LOCATION> Sagamore </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> played an inadvertant part in the dramatic 1954 Army-McCarthy hearings that grew out of a dispute between the senator and <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officials, whom <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> had accused of `` coddling Fifth Amendment communists.'' <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Republican, accused a number of public officials, military officers and prominent private citizens in the early 1950s of having Communist affiliations. A special counsel for the Army at the hearings before <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>'s investigations subcommittee was <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, a partner in <ORGANIZATION> Hale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Dorr </PERSON>, in which <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> was then an associate <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> of having been a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> `` long after it had been exposed as the legal arm of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Welch </PERSON>, near tears, responded: `` Until this moment, Senator, I think I never really gauged your cruelty or your recklessness. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> is starting what looks to be a brilliant career with us. I fear he shall always bear a scar, needlessly inflicted by you.'' `` Have you no decency, sir?'' he said to <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON>. The exchange on national television was considered a pivotal point in turning public opinion against the senator, who subsequently was censured by his colleagues. <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> later became a partner at the firm in 1958 and organized its commercial law department. He also served as president of the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and as chairman of many committees of the American and <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> bar associations. He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Talia </PERSON>; two sons, <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> 3d, of <LOCATION> Shropshire </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Natick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>; a daughter, <PERSON> Genevieve </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>.; two brothers, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Haywood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Champe </PERSON> of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION> and four grandchildren.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0728 05-27 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0728,0321</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Keogh; No separates moved for the AMs cycle.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Charles Lykes</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkhill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lykes </PERSON>, chairman of a Tampa-based cattle, citrus and meatpacking empire and patriarch of one of the state's most prominent families, has died at age 72. <PERSON> Lykes </PERSON>, who died Thursday, was chairman of the board and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Lykes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a 79-year-old company with 350,000 acres devoted to citrus, cattle and sugar cane; a <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> orange-juice processing plant; a Plant City meatpacking plant; and real estate in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Clearwater </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> He was also president of the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cattlemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in 1968 and was inducted into the Agricultural Hall of Fame in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> on Feb. 14. <PERSON> Lykes </PERSON> also was chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Lykes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which owns Tampa-based Peoples Gas System, the state's largest natural gas utility, and <ORGANIZATION> Shore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the majority owner of <ORGANIZATION> Lykes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steamship </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans-based </LOCATION> company begun in the early 1900s to move cattle to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Eugene Keogh</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keogh </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> congressman who fashioned pension-plan legislation that bears his name, died Friday of pneumonia at age 81. <PERSON> Keogh </PERSON> was elected to the first of his 15 terms in 1936. He became a member of the influential <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and was active in the effort to pass Medicare legislation. The Keogh Plan, enacted in 1962, allowed self-employed people like doctors, lawyers, salesman and freelance lawyers, salesmen and freelance writers to invest part of their income in a fund that is exempt from federal taxes until the money is withdrawn at retirement. After retiring from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, he resumed full-time practice with the law firm of <PERSON> Halpin </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Keogh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; St. <PERSON> John </PERSON> until the early 1970s. He served as counsel to the firm of <PERSON> Abberley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Kooiman </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Marcellino </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Clay until early last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Strikes Bjt   05-27 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Strikes, Bjt,0634</SECOND>
<HEAD>Britain Hit By Rash of Strikes</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By COTTEN TIMBERLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has been hit by a series of strikes in recent months recalling the pre-Thatcher days of national walkouts that helped bring down a <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> government. But experts say the scenario is very different from the `` Winter of Discontent'' of 1978-79 when public service workers paralyzed much of the country. Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ousted the socialists in May 1979 on a wave of anti-union sentiment Experts predict the strikes will eventually subside after a current round of wage negotiations. Although there are concerns the walkouts could lead to higher wages and prices, their impact will be limited by Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s union-curbing laws, they say. Repeated one-day walkouts by subway workers and bus drivers have forced millions of Londoners to walk to work. The <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has canceled or cut live television and radio programs because of brief strikes by employees for higher pay. Dockworkers are voting on whether to strike at <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s 40 ports over the government's plans to abolish a job-guarantee plan. Engineers and university and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> workers are also restive. `` When times were very hard in the 1980s, we took a back seat,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Mowat </PERSON>, an official with the <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s largest union. `` We negotiated wage decreases. Now Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> is telling us that <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s economy is booming so we think ... we should be partial beneficiaries of that boom.'' The strikes have been spurred by high wage demands stemming from resurging inflation and interest rates. Changes in work practices sought by new managers to control costs and raise efficiency are also a factor, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, a lecturer at the <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION>. However, <PERSON> Gavyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, an economist with <ORGANIZATION> Goldman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sachs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, said the economic effect of the renewed industrial strife `` is much less because the economy has moved to be more service-oriented, more small firm-oriented and more female labor, and in each of those areas there is less incidence of union membership.'' <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, an official with the employers' Confederation of British Industry said: `` Our view is that it is a short-lived period of industrial disputes ... There is no widespead fear of an upswing in union militancy.'' Workers are demanding raises as high as 15 percent, pointing to the rising inflation, which largely is blamed on a credit-fueled consumer spending boom. April's 8 percent annual inflation rate was more than double the 3.9 percent rate a year earlier. The government has tried to curb inflation by raising interest rates 10 times in the past year _ from 7.5 percent to 14 percent. But the subsequent higher mortgage rates have boosted pay requests. Employees of the soon-to-be-privatized electricity industry recently won a 9.2 percent pay raise, higher than the inflation rate. The settlement averted a walkout. It has been difficult for companies to reject wage demands as their profits have soared _ they were up 12 percent in 1988 and are expected to be healthy this year. In addition, many employers have difficulty recruiting labor. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s national unemployment rate has nearly halved to 6.5 percent. And lower birth rates of the 1970s are going to translate into fewer workers in the 1990s. `` Unions are in quite a strong bargaining position,'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. However, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has curbed union power with laws banning sympathy strikes and mass picketing and forcing secret ballots on whether to strike. Union membership has declined to 8.8 million from a peak of 12.2 million in 1979. Last year, 3.02 million work days were lost to strikes, compared with 30 million in 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SubmarineFire     05-27 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Submarine Fire,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Disables Sub Off Southern California Coast</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN DIEGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An engine room fire forced an attack submarine to surface off the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> coast, and the diesel-powered sub was towed to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> on Friday, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials said. None of the 73 crew members aboard the USS Blueback were injured in the Thursday afternoon fire, the second accident in two days involving a San Diego-based submarine. Another ship was towing the <LOCATION> Blueback </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, said Lt. <PERSON> Sonya </PERSON> <PERSON> Hedley </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the Naval Submarine Base here. Officers initially had hoped the sub could make the trip under its own power. `` They experienced a minor electrical fire in their propulsion system,'' <PERSON> Hedley </PERSON> said. The sub, which carries a crew of 65 enlisted and eight officers, was on general training operations, she said. In the other incident, the attack submarine Gurnard was freed after being stuck on a reef for about four hours. The ship was submerged when it hit the reef, Ms. <PERSON> Hedley </PERSON> said, correcting earlier reports it was on the surface. No injuries were reported among the Gurnard's 135-man crew, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman said, and the grounding was under investigation by Rear Admiral <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>, who is commander of the San Diego-based Submarine Group Five.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LATeachers 1stLd-Writethru a0724 05-27 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-LA Teachers, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0724,0463</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teachers Go Back to School After Strike Settlement</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 9th graf, `Attendance figures...,' with 2 grafs to UPDATE
with attendance figures on students and teachers. Picks up 10th graf pvs,
`On Thursday...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROGERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teachers and students returned to peaceful campuses Friday after settlement of a nearly two-week strike, but the atmosphere was more social than academic, some said. `` People have n't seen each other in two weeks and they want to talk to each other and welcome each other back,'' said 10th Street Elementary School Assistant Principal <PERSON> Evelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON>. Throughout the 700-square-mile district, teachers at nearly 600 schools were greeted with flowers, balloons and hugs from students. But numerous absences indicated the Memorial Day weekend may have tempted many students to stay away. Students who reported to class during the strike were subjected to auditorium assemblies, educational films and lengthy study periods overseen by substitute teachers. Thousands of others stayed away from school. `` I do n't think we knew how much our teachers provided us with motivation to learn,'' said <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Hollywood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` Everything is back to normal now,'' said a smiling <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Montoya </PERSON>, a 10th grader at <ORGANIZATION> Belmont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have our teachers back and now we can get back to our studies.'' Special education teacher <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ung </PERSON> said the mood among the teachers was upbeat at Belmont High. `` It seems to be getting back to normal. From everyone I've talked to, the mood is good, the attitude is excellent,'' he said. But he noticed that classes seemed thin. `` Some may be taking advantage of the long weekend,'' he said. There were 365,137 students in class in the nation's second largest school district, hardly a dramatic lift from the 305,650 attending Thursday, the last day of the strike that began May 15. Teachers did return nearly in force, with 24,569 regularly assigned teachers out of a possible 26,250 returning Friday, with 1,447 substitutes bringing the number to 26,016, `` pretty close to full strength,'' said school district spokeswoman <PERSON> Eva </PERSON> <PERSON> Hain </PERSON>. On Thursday, members of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers-Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> approved by voice vote a $ 600 million, three-year contract giving them a 24 percent raise over three years and a bigger voice in the control of their schools. The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unified </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION>'s seven-member board approved the pact during a closed door meeting the same day, with arguments centering on the $ 120 million in cuts the school board staff says will have to be made elsewhere to provide the teacher salary increases. The contract, 16 months in the making, is retroactive to July. The union represents 22,000 of the district's 32,000 teachers, counselors, nurses and librarians.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Apollo11     05-27 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Apollo 11,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Neil Armstrong Took `Small Step' Himself</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HARRY F. ROSENTHAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 For nearly 20 years, space buffs have wondered who composed the words `` That's one small step for a man'' which <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said when he stepped on the moon. Now, with the one-score anniversary coming up July 20, <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> says that not only were those words his own, but that he composed them on the spot. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, commander of the Apollo 11 moon mission, was reunited with his two crew mates for a news conference Friday to satisfy requests for interviews in connection with celebrations planned across the world to mark the event. He was asked when exactly he decided on the words `` That's one small step for a man, one giant leap for mankind,'' which he said after climbing down the ladder on the lunar lander. `` It was a statement that was natural in the sense of the time,'' <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said. `` I thought about it after we got there.'' With that he destroyed longstanding rumors in space circles that some anonymous public relations genius, not <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, created those words for history. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, along with lunar module pilot <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> `` Buzz'' <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON> and command module pilot <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, fielded questions from reporters with humor and self-deprecation for the niche they carved in the annals of exploration. Here are some <ORGANIZATION> Armstrong </ORGANIZATION> comments: _ On the use of robots to explore space _ a technique favored by many scientists: `` Man can be amused and amazed, and a robot can be neither. _ On leaving footprints on the moon that will remain undisturbed for millennia: `` I had hoped that somebody goes up there some day and cleans them up. _ On how their lives were changed by their adventure: `` Before 1969, press conferences were much smaller. _ On whether the Apollo moon program was a stunt of little value: `` Even if it was a bad idea, I'm glad we did it. All three were asked what moment of their mission they would choose to relive. <PERSON> Aldrin </PERSON>, who just published a book on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s space program, answered it would be the last 10 seconds before they touched down on the lunar surface and the first 10 seconds afterward. <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> said, `` I would pick a moment when I could look out the window and see a full Earth.'' And <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said it would be the moment when he saw the lunar module returning from the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION>'s surface against the background of the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> floating in the black of space. In his view, he said, were both the Earth with three billion people and the moon ship with only two.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MarijuanaRally     05-27 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Marijuana Rally,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pro-Marijuana Group Agrees to Parking Lot Rally Without Rock Music</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They ca n't play rock music, and they have to use a parking lot, instead of a ballfield. But a pro-marijuana group has won a judge's permission to hold a rally over the Memorial Day weekend. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON> on Friday ordered the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cannabis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reform </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> to refrain from selling T-shirts or playing amplified music at the rally Sunday in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Adams </LOCATION>, a small industrial city in the <LOCATION> Berkshires </LOCATION>. A rock concert would not be in keeping with the `` solemnity of Memorial Day, when we acknowledge those who died representing their country,'' the judge said. He also pointed out that `` the Constitution protects expressions of thought, not profit-making activities.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, an attorney for the group, said it was willing to use the parking lot, rather than a ballfield as it had originally hoped. `` It's a disappointment, but we'll have speeches, acoustic music and distribute literature,'' said <PERSON> Curt </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON>, one of the organizers, after the hearing in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. On Wednesday, the judge told both sides to find a suitable place for the rally. Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who opposes legalization, suggested the city landfill. `` This group has a right to express its feelings whether we agree with them or not,'' <PERSON> Freedman </PERSON> said Friday, noting that the coalition's request had been before the city Recreation Commission for four months. <PERSON> Mansfield </PERSON> said the group initially wanted to march in the city's Memorial Day Parade, but a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans group opposed the idea `` They wanted no part of it,'' he said. `` So we came up the idea of having a gathering in the park.'' Said <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>: `` We recognize that reform of the marijuana laws is a very controversial subject. And we were hesitant to inject it into the Memorial Day Parade because of the solemnity of the observance.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0332EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HemingwayStamp     05-27 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hemingway Stamp,0194</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key West Gets First Issue of Hemingway Stamp</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KEY WEST, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This island city will be honored with the first issue of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> postage stamp paying tribute to Nobel Prize-winning author <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON>. The commemorative 25-cent stamp, featuring the bearded <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> in his signature turtle-neck sweater against a background of a golden African plain, was taken from the classic <PERSON> Yousuf </PERSON> <PERSON> Karsh </PERSON> photo of the author. The stamp will go on sale July 17, a day before it's available in the rest of the nation. The issue date coincides with the ninth annual Hemingway Days Festival, when Key West celebrates the author's time on the island, where he wrote some of his most popular and critically acclaimed books. The <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Postal Service usually picks the city most identified with a the honored person to first issue a stamp. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has a long tradition of remembering distinguished Americans on its postage,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` We thought the Hemingway Days Festival would be the appropriate venue to issue a stamp in honor of this great author and adventurer.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Seabrook     05-27 0576</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seabrook,0596</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seabrook Operators Prepare for First Atomic Reaction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL MOKRZYCKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEABROOK, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Engineer <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was part of the team overseeing the startup of a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> reactor that 30 years ago helped usher in the age of commercial nuclear power. Today, he is preparing to lead the start of atomic fission at the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> nuclear power plant, a symbol for the anti-nuclear movement and bellwether for utility industry officials worldwide who hope to promote a new, safer generation of nuclear reactors. The $ 6 billion Seabrook reactor, which was originally planned for commercial operation in 1979 and completed but idle for three years because of evacuation-planning and financial problems, won a low-power testing license Friday. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission granted the license a day after a federal appeals court declined to delay the tests. The testing process is expected to start this weekend, leading to the first fission reaction in <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION>'s fuel core in seven to 10 days, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hampshire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION>, which operates the plant, recalled his days as a `` dark-haired young engineer'' conducting environmental monitoring at <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>' <ORGANIZATION> Yankee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rowe </ORGANIZATION> when the reactor started its atomic tests in 1960. It was the nation's second commercial nuclear power plant. `` It's a different ball game now,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said in an interview in his office. In contrast to <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s tumultuous history, the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> plant was built in three years for $ 45 million. It produces only 189 megawatts of electricity. <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> is supposed to produce six times as much. `` A lot more is at stake with this one,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said, arguing that <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> is vital for meeting the region's energy needs. <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s opponents agree that much is at stake, but for different reasons. They say stopping the plant is crucial for the health and safety of tens of thousands of people who live nearby. The low-power license does not settle disputes over evacuation planning for crowded beaches and coastal communities within 10 miles of <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> _ the key issue blocking commercial operation. <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> officials hope to receive a commercial license in the fall, but <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and other foes have promised to fight it even if it means going to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Nuclear industry officials around the world also see high stakes involved with the <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION> plant, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` We're aware the rest of the industry is watching us, but we're not out there fighting the industry's battles,'' he said Two weeks ago, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> attended a conference in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> of nuclear plant operators from 31 countries, and he said there was `` tremendous interest'' in <LOCATION> Seabrook </LOCATION>'s progress. `` When I came back I told the folks here that it really dawned on me for the first time _ there are people who perceive <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON> as the bellwether,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` But I do n't. My objective is to get it running.'' When <PERSON> Seabrook </PERSON>'s tests start, valves will be opened and water will be pumped through the reactor coolant system. Friction from the rapid circulation would heat the reactor from 150 degrees to its operating temperature of 557 degrees. Then, operators would set the stage for a nuclear chain reaction by withdrawing neutron-absorbing control rods from the reactor fuel core and reducing the amount of neutron-absorbing boron in the coolant water, eventually letting uranium atoms start the fission process. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> estimated the plant would achieve initial `` criticality'' _ its first self-sustained fission reaction _ within seven to 10 days.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-Clark     05-27 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Clark,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastside Principal Joe Clark to Have Open-Heart Surgery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Bat-and-bullhorn-wielding high school principal <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who gained national attention because of his disciplinary tactics, is scheduled to undergo open-heart surgery. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, principal of <ORGANIZATION> Eastside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Paterson </LOCATION> and the subject of the movie `` Lean On Me,'' was admitted Wednesday to <ORGANIZATION> Beth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON>, his personal manager. `` He's been run-down,'' <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON> said Friday. `` He had pneumonia a couple of weeks ago. He was out of school for five or six days.'' The principal, who made the cover of <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> because of the renown and criticism he received for his `` no-nonsense'' educational approach, said from his fifth-floor hospital bed that he entered the hospital to `` ascertain for a very high temperature and to diagnose heart irregularities.'' `` I am in good spirits,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. Neither hospital spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON> knew the specifics of the surgery or when it would be performed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ClarkHospitalized 1stLd-Writethru a0408 05-27 0198</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Clark Hospitalized, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0408,0198</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastside Principal Joe Clark to Have Open-Heart Surgery</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, `Clark, subject...,' to CORRECT title of movie
to `Lean on Me' sted `Stand and Deliver'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEWARK, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the high school principal known for his bat-and-bullhorn disciplinary tactics, was hospitalized and scheduled to undergo open-heart surgery, a spokesman said Friday. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, principal of <PERSON> Paterson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Eastside </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, was admitted Wednesday to <ORGANIZATION> Beth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Israel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON>, his personal manager. `` He's been run-down,'' <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON> said. `` He had pneumonia a couple of weeks ago. He was out of school for five or six days.'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, subject of the recent movie `` Lean on Me,'' said in a statement from his fifth-floor hospital bed that he entered the hospital to `` ascertain for a very high temperature and to diagnose heart irregularities,'' said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>. `` I am in good spirits,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said in the statement. Neither <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Fusco </PERSON> knew the specifics of the surgery or when it would be performed. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> was supposed to speak Monday to students at <ORGANIZATION> Valdosta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Valdosta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, but canceled at the last minute, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 2ndLd-Writethru a0753 05-27 0769</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0753,0794</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede FORT AMADOR</HEAD>
<HEAD>Noriega Says Solution Up To Political Parties</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 6-7, `Earlier Friday...told reporters' with 3 grafs
to UPDATE with quote from mission. Pick up 8th pvs, `The OAS...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD HERZFELDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mission from the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> has failed to make any progress toward a solution of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s political crisis, an opposition leader said Friday. `` Unfortunately there has been no progress for the good of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> in the talks,'' said opposition presidential candidate <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> after meeting with the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> delegation. The mission, made up of the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> and </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tobago </LOCATION>, also met Friday with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s de facto leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> and first vice presidential candidate <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> said the sticking point had been <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s refusal to negotiate with the opposition. <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> said he would not take power if <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> remained as commander of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, but <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> called questions about his possible retirement `` stupid.'' Earlier Friday, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> told reporters that the military would not be drawn into negotiations and that a solution to the political crisis should come from talks between the opposition and pro-government parties. `` They both claim they won,'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> told reporters. Ecuadoran Foreign Minister <PERSON> Diego </PERSON> <PERSON> Cordovez </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mission had succeeded in giving <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and the opposition each other's point of view, but that a solution `` will require an enormous effort from the <LOCATION> Panamanian </LOCATION> people. The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> delegation seeks to end the impasse created when the government nullified the May 7 presidential election. The opposition, led by <PERSON> Endara </PERSON>, won the elections over pro-government candidate <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON> by a 3-1 margin, according to international observers. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s troops seized the vote tallies and the election was nullified three days later. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said Friday: `` The key to the problem lies with the contending political parties. The opposition has declined to talk to Duque. `` If the opposition remains intransigent, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> are not going to slip on a banana peel'' and be drawn into the dispute. `` The two sides have to start talking.'' Opposition leaders say they will not negotiate with civilians because the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> commands, hold the real power in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` Nothing positive can come out of a negotiation between <LOCATION> Duque </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> because <ORGANIZATION> Duque </ORGANIZATION> does n't have a single drop of power,'' <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> said Friday in a telephone interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are willing to talk to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> about an institutional solution, but for this it is vital that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> retire.'' When asked to say who had won, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> said, `` That's up to the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribunal </ORGANIZATION>,'' which nullified the vote. `` I'm just another Panamanian among 2,394,000.'' <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> noted that, in a resolution passed before the mission was sent, the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> called for `` a transfer of power as soon as possible.'' `` They did n't talk about the presidency, but about power,'' <PERSON> Endara </PERSON> said. `` That power that is now in military hands.'' The <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> mission came to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s offices at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Amador </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and waited 15 minutes before the general came strolling down the street with a half-dozen staff officers, munching on a mango. `` Panamanian mango,'' he remarked, taking a bite. `` You should try it.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s offices back onto a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval station and are cater-corner from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION>'s logistics and personnel offices. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who also spent 2 -LCB- hours with the delegation Wednesday, said he repeated that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s problems were caused by the `` interfering hands'' of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Since President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent 1,900 more troops to augment security at <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION> installations, he said, `` Panamanian troops have been instructed not to get trapped into a provocation. We also ask Panamanian citizens not to do anything provocative.'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has been indicted on drug trafficking charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which he describes as part of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plot to renege on treaties that cede the canal to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at the end of 1999. He said the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> had made some proposals, but he would not reveal them. `` There are 100,000 formulas,'' he said. When asked if he would step down, he replied: `` Do n't ask stupid questions.'' At Wednesday's meeting, the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION> was told <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s retirement was a matter for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> to consider, not the opposition or the <ORGANIZATION> OAS </ORGANIZATION>. On Friday, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> called the international press `` disinformers'' and agents of imperialism. `` You are the ones who have made me out to be a dictator,'' he said to an unruly crowd of reporters, photographers and television cameramen. `` You say it's a dictatorship, but right here we have anarchy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0208EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TobaccoBan     05-27 0163</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tobacco Ban,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dutch City to Ban Tobacco Ads</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Bellm is CQ</HEAD>
<DATELINE>THE HAGUE, Netherlands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tobacco ads will be banned from public billboards in this city of 450,000 in a bid to combat tobacco-related diseases, a municipal official said. `` We think tobacco is such a threat to public health that steps should be taken quickly,'' spokesman <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bellm </PERSON> said Friday. Under a city plan, the ads will be banned from The Hague's 250 advertising billboards after renewal of their annual lease contracts, he said. <PERSON> Bellm </PERSON> said the tobacco ads, on about two-thirds of the public advertising space, bring in $ 90,000 a year. He noted that in 1986, about 800 people in the city of 450,000 succumbed to tobacco-related diseases such as lung cancer, heart attacks and respiratory problems. That was the latest year for which figures are available. The Dutch government is considering extending a nationwide ban on tobacco promotion on radio and television to a more comprehensive one.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Factions     05-27 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Factions,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>Power Struggle Exposes Rifts with Deng</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BIERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Although <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> has been <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s supreme ruler for more than a decade, his differing approaches to economic and political change have not met with universal approval. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s market-oriented economic reforms have achieved remarkable results since 1978 and received a resounding vote of confidence at the 13th <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1987. Under his policies, millions of Chinese have seen their living standards increase dramatically. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, who was named <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief at the <ORGANIZATION> congress </ORGANIZATION>, was considered <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s top protege and heir apparent because of his enthusiastic support for economic liberalism and opening up to the outside world. But <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s sympathy with student demands for free government and democratic reform apparently proved unacceptable to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, an 84-year-old revolutionary with little tolerance for dissent. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s moderate attitude toward the students resulted in his loss of power this week to conservative Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, an engineer trained in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, opposed the rapid pace of economic decentralization that was the result of <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s policies He instead prefered the status quo. But <PERSON> Li </PERSON> apparently was acting on <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s behalf May 20 when he decreed martial law for <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, where students and more than 1 million supporters have been demonstrating for political liberalization. At least temporarily, supporters of <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s conservative views on political change have won out over supporters of his far-reaching economic reforms. Among other leaders: President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON> _ The former general has close ties to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> and has been viewed as a supporter of economic reform. <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> apparently shares <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s aversion to political pluralism, however, and announced May 19 that troops were being sent to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to restore order. <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Li </PERSON> _ The head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is a firm supporter of the market-oriented economic reform, but may not approve <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s crackdown. During a recent trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, he praised the students as leading a patriotic movement and urged a peaceful resolution to the uprising. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Yun </PERSON> _ The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> long has been viewed as a staunch conservative opposed to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s economic reform. But he made clear in a speech Friday he supports the hard-line stance against the pro-democracy movement. Joining <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> on the party's policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> are <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Qili </PERSON>, <PERSON> Yao </PERSON> <PERSON> Yilin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Shi </PERSON>. Their support of <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s economic and political policies is difficult to gauge, particularly because all of their meetings are in private.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Scotland-Church     05-27 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Scotland-Church,0791</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lord Chancellor Runs Afoul of Reformation-Style Hostility</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report. ^By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The passions of the 16th century, burning fiercely in the Highlands of <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, have driven the Lord High Chancellor from his church. Lord <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> of Clashfern, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s chief legal officer, said Friday that he would leave the Free Presbyterian Church of <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> rather than promise not to attend Roman Catholic funeral Mass, as he had done twice in honor of fellow peers. `` I have no intention of giving any such undertaking as that for which the synod has asked,'' <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> said in a statement issued from his office in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Like a 16th century chancellor, Sir <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> More </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> was forced to choose between private conscience and public duty in a land where the church as well as the state derives its authority from the crown. More, a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, was beheaded in 1535 after refusing to recognize <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> VIII </PERSON>'s supremacy over the newly formed <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION>, and the rhetoric of the Reformation echoed in the church at <LOCATION> Inverness </LOCATION> where the `` Wee Frees'' held their annual synod this week. `` I find it very difficult to believe that the lord chancellor of a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> country, with a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> queen on a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> throne, has any obligation by reason of state to go to a Popish Mass,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLean </PERSON>, clerk of the <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Presbytery </LOCATION>. Lord <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> of </PERSON> <PERSON> Fawsley </PERSON>, a prominent Roman Catholic and former <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> officer, put the issue this way: `` What is the lord chancellor of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, who is the head of the judiciary, doing belonging to such an intolerant organization?'' The struggle for the lord chancellor's soul was waged amid scenes of stout women weeping, solemn men stomping their feet in protest and the church's moderator, the Rev. <PERSON> Aaron </PERSON> <PERSON> Ndebele </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bulawayo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, banging his fist on the table for order. <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON>, an elder of his church in <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>, had been suspended last year following a complaint about his attendance at the funeral of Lord <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Killowan </LOCATION> at Westminster Cathedral in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. He had attended another Catholic funeral in 1986. Speaking to the Lord Chancellor's opponents, the Rev. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> of <PERSON> Tain </PERSON> warned the synod that it `` will make the name of this church stink in the <LOCATION> Highland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION> and wherever it is known.'' `` May God have mercy upon us as a church,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinclair </PERSON> of <PERSON> Wick </PERSON>, at 90 the oldest clergyman in the church. `` Lord <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> is a man whose conscience is clear before God.'' The Rev. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> of Laide, convenor of the church's committee on religion and morals, noted that the synod had easily mustered a unanimous vote some years ago to rebuke Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> for attending a Mass. `` Yet when one of our own goes to Mass there is a big hullabaloo when he is disciplined for it,'' <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> said. The vote upholding <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON>'s suspension, by 33-27, signaled a new schism in a 6,000-member denomination born in protest in 1893. The Rev. <PERSON> Calum </PERSON> <PERSON> MacInnes </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Toronto </LOCATION>, who had once been threatened with discipline for refusing to wear a clerical collar, filed a formal protest and walked out. Besides the <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> case, <PERSON> MacInnes </PERSON> complained of a 1987 decision to refuse membership to a man whose golf club was open on Sundays, and another last year to suspend a minister who had invited a <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> priest to pray at an education committee meeting. Appointed lord chancellor by Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> in 1987, the 61-year-old <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> presides over the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lords </ORGANIZATION>, the unelected upper house of Parliament. His tenure has been controversial because of his proposals for sweeping reform of the ancient privileges and powers of the English bar, proposals which some lawyers have resented as coming from an outsider. <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON>, with his twinkling eyes and soft smile, appears an unlikely object of controversy. The son of a railway porter, he attended <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Heriot </PERSON>'s School -LRB- `` for the improvement of the children of poor but deserving folk'' -RRB- in <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION> and then took a degree in mathematics and natural philosophy in <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>. After lecturing for a time at <ORGANIZATION> Trinity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, he turned to law in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION> and eventually became Lord Advocate, the top law officer in <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. In an interview with author <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mortimer </PERSON>, published in The <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> in February, <PERSON> Mackay </PERSON> had defended his church from accusations of intolerance. `` It depends what you mean by intolerance,'' he said. `` If you believe something strongly, if that is your faith, the testimony you have received, you seek change in others by way of persuasion.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     05-27 0766</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music singer <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Paycheck </PERSON> will perform for his fellow inmates at an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> prison next month, and ex-convict <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Haggard </PERSON> will join him. Paycheck and <PERSON> Haggard </PERSON> will perform two concerts June 13 at the <ORGANIZATION> Chillicothe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, said warden <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` We're excited about the opportunity to put on something like this,'' <PERSON> Tate </PERSON> said. `` This has the makings of something really big.'' Paycheck, 50, is serving a seven - to 9 -LCB- - year sentence for shooting a man in a southern <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> bar in Paycheck is best known for his 1978 hit song, `` Take This Job and Shove It.'' <PERSON> Haggard </PERSON>, one of country music's top singers for the past 25 years, spent three years in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION> for burglarizing a cafe. He was paroled in 1960 and pardoned in 1972 by then-California Gov. <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The prison concert will be recorded for release as an album, tentatively called `` Behind the Walls,'' <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, Paycheck's record producer in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, said Friday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROGERSVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>'s younger sister, singer-actress <PERSON> Stella </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>, says people always ask her what it's like to be in the shadows of a country music legend `` I do n't know what to compare it to,'' she said. `` I've always been her sister since the day I was born.'' Miss <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>, 40, prefers to focus on her own career, which includes spending 200 days on the road each year. She runs her own record and production companies from <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>. She began singing with her sisters at age 7, but she has yet to score a big hit. `` I'm not one to wince at a challenge,'' Miss <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> said. `` My recording career has been slow to take off at times, but I found I was quite good at doing other things and I also enjoyed it.'' Miss <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> appeared in the television show `` The Dukes of Hazzard'' and on stage in `` The Best Little Whorehouse in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>'' and `` Pump Boys and Dinettes.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LITCHFIELD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> will not pay any money to the estate of a woman who accidentally died on the actor's estate in 1986 A settlement was reached Thursday in a lawsuit against <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> and three other defendants that stemmed from the drowning of <PERSON> Sheila </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruse </PERSON> <PERSON> Fionda </PERSON>. `` The amount will not be disclosed but the settlement does not involve any money from Mr. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. The case was to go to trial Thursday. The lawsuit, filed by <PERSON> Fionda </PERSON>'s former husband on behalf of their son, concerned claims of wrongful death and negligence in <LOCATION> Fionda </LOCATION>'s Aug. 24, 1986, drowning <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> was not at the estate at the time. <PERSON> Fionda </PERSON>, 43, a teacher, was found about 6 a.m. in the hot tub portion of a swimming pool on <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Roxbury </LOCATION> estate. An autopsy showed her blood-alcohol count was three times the legal limit for drunken driving in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Miss America <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON>'s boyfriend has left the <LOCATION> Allenwood </LOCATION> federal prison in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> for a halfway house in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to finish serving his sentence for tax evasion. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>, 47, owner of a sewer construction company, is due for release June 26 after completing two years of a three-year sentence. Inmates awaiting release live in the halfway house, but go to work during the day and may receive weekend passes. <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON> was jailed in 1987 after pleading guilty to evading nearly $ 1.5 million in taxes. Miss <PERSON> Myerson </PERSON> later was forced to leave her post as the city's cultural affairs commissioner after taking the Fifth Amendment before the grand jury that investigated <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON> Later, she was accused of having used her city job to try to influence a judge handling <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s divorce case. She was acquitted of charges that she gave the judge's daughter a job in return for rulings that reduced <PERSON> Capasso </PERSON>'s support and child care payments.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, D-Ariz., has been released from the hospital where he had been treated since May 9 for pneumonia and symptoms associated with <PERSON> Parkinson </PERSON>'s disease, an aide said <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, 66, has had Parkinson's disease for about 10 years and periodically goes into the hospital to have his medication adjusted. During a visit this month, doctors discovered he had pneumonia, said his chief of staff, <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>. <PERSON> James </PERSON> said <PERSON> Udall </PERSON> is fully recovered from the pneumonia but is supposed to rest at his home in <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, next week. <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, a 15-term congressman, is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Insular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra     05-27 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Delays Trial After Iran-Contra Defendant Accuses Prosecution</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The trial of a former <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent in the Iran-Contra arms and money affair is being delayed for two weeks over allegations the prosecution is using the defendant's testimony to a congressional panel. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> on Friday moved the starting date to July 24 after ex-CIA agent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> said the prosecution's case has been tainted by his immunized congressional testimony. In a related case, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> on Friday rejected a motion by former <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> for a post-trial hearing. North, convicted May 4 of three felonies stemming from the Iran-Contra affair, had contended that the evidence against him was prejudiced by his testimony before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> during televised hearings in 1987. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s lawyers raised no new issues to warrant another hearing or dismissal of the charges. The judge concluded in a June 16, 1988, ruling that <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s congressional testimony `` was not submitted to the grand jury in any form.'' In the <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> case, <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> denied a motion to dismiss the case, but the judge said he will look further into what steps the prosecution took to insulate itself from <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>' testimony. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>'s former station chief in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, is accused of obstructing and lying to the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's office and the presidential Tower commission He allegedly told investigators that a secret airstrip in <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> built as part of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s secret resupply network for the Nicaraguan Contra rebels was an initiative of the Costa Rican government. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> allegedly told the Tower panel he did not know for a fact that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was assisting the resupply effort, which was prohibited by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Under immunity from prosecution, <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> later told congressional investigators the airstrip was tied into the resupply effort and that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was part of it. <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON> lawyer <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said two <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> employees, <ORGANIZATION> Cole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Dupart </PERSON>, were familiar with <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>' immunized testimony, yet were questioned extensively by prosecutors. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Black </PERSON> maintained he was unable to `` ferret out'' what he learned from <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>' immunized testimony and what he learned from non-immunized testimony. Prosecutor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Longstreth </PERSON> disputed <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s contention, saying prosecutors' questions to <PERSON> Black </PERSON> were framed narrowly and that none of his answers was based on <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>' immunized testimony. A <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling bars prosecutors from making any use of someone's immunized testimony in prosecuting the person. The office of independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, which is prosecuting <PERSON> Fernandez </PERSON>, has gone to extreme lengths to wall itself off from such testimony, <PERSON> Longstreth </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s office will supply the court with information on the steps it has taken to remain free from the taint of immunized testimony, the judge said at the end of a hearing. The trial is expected to last about three weeks. Prosecutor <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> Shtasel </PERSON> said the government will call 15 to 18 witnesses and take five to seven days to present its case. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the defense will take a `` similar amount of time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Argentina     05-27 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Argentina,0481</SECOND>
<HEAD>Argentines Loot Supermarkets; Police Deployed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED McCULLOUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Supermarkets in at least four cities were looted and one was set afire in unrest prompted by high inflation. No injuries were reported, but more than 90 people were arrested. Police in central <LOCATION> Cordoba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s second-biggest city, were deployed at public buildings and radio and TV stations as well as supermarkets to ward off incidents, police and Argentine media reported. They said authorities seized firebombs. In <LOCATION> Mendoza </LOCATION>, 620 miles west of <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>, a supermarket was set ablaze Friday by firebombs, the news agencies <ORGANIZATION> Diario </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> y </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Noticias </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Noticias </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Argentinas </ORGANIZATION> reported. In the working class towns of Quilmes to the south and <LOCATION> Mataderos </LOCATION> to the west, food stores and delivery trucks were robbed, the news agencies said. Police and the news agencies reported 60 arrests in <LOCATION> Cordoba </LOCATION>, about 25 in <LOCATION> Mataderos </LOCATION> and six in Quilmes. In <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION> on Friday night, about 300 women demanding wage increases and an end to recent price rises banged pots and pans outside Government House. Inflation is projected to top 70 percent this month, wages have shrunk by more than 30 percent this year and people are hungry across this country that exports huge quantities of grain and beef. `` What I spent to buy five bottles of cooking oil last month wo n't buy even one now,'' said <PERSON> Elsa </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, a housewife at the rally in <LOCATION> Buenos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aires </LOCATION>. `` My husband works two jobs and earns about 5,000 australs'' a month, or about $ 25, she said. `` It's humiliating. It makes me sick.'' President <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON>'s governing <ORGANIZATION> Radical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> lost elections May 14 to the <ORGANIZATION> Peronist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in large part because of the deteriorating economy. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> offered to step down before scheduled on Dec. 10; President-elect <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> declined to take office early. The Argentine currency has been devalued by 90 percent against the dollar since February. Bus and commuter train, gas, electricity, telephone and other public utility rates were increased sharply last week. Exchange houses were closed since Monday in an effort to reduce speculation against the austral. Banks, which fear a run on deposits, were closed Monday and Tuesday but resumed some transactions Wednesday. The limit for withdrawals is 20,000 australs every two days, or about $ 100. Looting of supermarkets, butcher shops, food stores and delivery trucks _ and clashes with police, who have fired tear gas and rubber bullets _ began Tuesday. Some hungry looters have eaten food on the spot. The government attributes the incidents to agitators that so far it has refused to identify. `` There is no doubt'' that the looters are organized, said <PERSON> Facundo </PERSON> <PERSON> Suarez </PERSON>, chief of the state intelligence agency. <PERSON> Alfonsin </PERSON> reportedly was set to address the nation Sunday to announce details of a new anti-inflation program.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Korea 1stLd-Writethru a0593 05-27 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0593,0592</SECOND>
<HEAD>South Korean Students Copy Chinese Hunger Protest</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to CORRECT that protest outside sted inside
cathedral, protests not increasingly violent; pickup 5th graf, `South Korean...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 300 radical students went on a hunger strike outside a Roman Catholic cathedral on Friday in a protest they said was inspired by the student-led demonstrations in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The students gathered at <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>'s Myongdong Cathedral to call for the overthrow of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s government and an investigation into the death of student leader <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Chol-gyu </PERSON>. `` Overthrow the murder regime!'' and `` Down with <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo!'' protesters chanted as riot police watched but made no move to intervene. The peaceful protest strike was called amid growing pressure on students to end their violent protests. South Korean newspapers have praised the Chinese student protesters in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for their peaceful tactics in calling for freedom and democracy. About 3,000 students went on a hunger strike in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on May 13 to dramatize their demands. That hunger strike was lifted a week later. South Korean student leaders said Friday they were using the same tactics as Chinese students. Some students claimed they would fast to the death if their demands were not met. `` We are more determined than the students fasting in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' one student said. About 100 students chanted slogans at the cathedral's main gate. Others rested in the cathedral compound or took part in discussion groups, taking water but no food. Students stayed out of the cathedral itself and administration buildings. The Korean students are pro-leftist and anti-Western, rejecting Western democracy as unsuitable for Korean conditions and calling for an ill-defined `` workers and farmers state.'' The Chinese students are demonstrating for a freer society and an end to official corruption, but are not calling for an overthrow of the communist system. Radical students in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> lack popular support because of their extreme views and violent tactics. Some student groups have been trying to switch tactics after six riot police officers were killed May 3 in a clash in the southern city of <LOCATION> Pusan </LOCATION>. A seventh trooper injured in the clash died Thursday night, police said. Radical students and dissidents claim <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> was tortured and killed by police and are demanding the government admit there has been a cover up. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s body was found May 10 in a reservoir near the southern city of <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>. Dissident groups called for a major demonstration in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> on Saturday to protest <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s death, but police banned the rally. Officials deny involvement in <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s death, although police tried to detain him at a roadblock just before he disappeared. The government says an autopsy proves <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> was not tortured and officials speculate he fell into the reservoir. Posters with color pictures of <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s bloated body were put up Friday by students in the cathedral compound. Crowds of up to 100,000 people marched in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> last week to demand the government admit police killed <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>. The demonstrations also called for <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s fall for the bloody suppression of a 1980 uprising in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION>. The hunger strikers in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> said Friday they also were demanding <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>'s ouster for the <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> uprising. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> was a senior general during the uprising. Protesters also chanted anti-U.S. slogans Friday. They claim the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was involved in <LOCATION> Kwangju </LOCATION> and are demanding expulsion of the 43,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops based in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890527-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-27-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>b w AM-Coelho 6thLd-Writethru a0440 05-27 0998</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coelho, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0440,1000</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coelho Reportedly Plans to Resign</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS to attribute to Foley; EDITS to conform throughout</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
