<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 2358EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Duncan     05-28 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Duncan,0203</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jeff Duncan, Dance Company Founder, Dies at 59</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, who founded dance companies in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, has died of acquired immune deficiency syndrome. He was 59. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> died with friends at his side on Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Don </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miller </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> home that provides care for people with AIDS, said <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartzell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>'s friend. In the mid-1960s, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> founded the Dance Theater Workshop, now based at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for the Performing Arts, and directed it for more than 10 years before moving to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> in the late 1970s. At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> formed the resident <ORGANIZATION> Impetus </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>. He also performed and choreographed works for the Baltimore Theater Project. Born in <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> studied with such dancers as <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Joffrey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Limon </PERSON>, <PERSON> Anna </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> and <PERSON> Alwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Nickolais </PERSON>. He performed with the Juilliard Dance Ensemble as Ms. <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>'s assistant, appeared in <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> shows and joined the New Dance Group with Ms. <PERSON> Sokolow </PERSON> in the mid-1950s before starting on his own. <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> is survived by his mother, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, and a sister, <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--MafiaAttack     05-28 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Mafia Attack,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed In Attack on House; Stolen Car Link</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AGRIGENTO, Sicily (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen with pistols and sawed-off shotguns attacked four auto mechanics suspected of involvement in a Mafia-linked stolen car ring, killing three, the Italian news agency <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> reported. The fourth man was serious wounded in the Sunday's attack, <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said. The report quoted police as saying the victims were suspected of roles in a stolen car ring in which BMWs and Mercedes were stolen in northern <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and taken to <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION>, where they were refitted, given new registrations and sold. <ORGANIZATION> ANSA </ORGANIZATION> said the men, all Italians, traveled back and forth between <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> and the northern Italian region of <LOCATION> Lombardy </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The victims were just about to emerge from a house in the countryside in the province of <LOCATION> Agrigento </LOCATION> before dawn when four or five killers struck and then fled in two cars, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-ElPasoMayor 2ndLd-Writethru a0655 05-28 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-El Paso Mayor, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0655,0415</SECOND>
<HEAD>El Pasoans Elect Woman Mayor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to UPDATE with Azar victory and quotes. Picks
up 3rd graf pvs., `The successor ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EL PASO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Suzie </PERSON> <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> became the first woman mayor in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> history Saturday with a landslide victory over fellow city council member <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> in a runoff election. `` I'm thrilled to death. I'm ready to go to work,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> said. `` One hundred seventeen years is a long time for <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paso </ORGANIZATION> to wait, and I'm glad they waited for me.'' The final, but unofficial totals showed that Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> captured 65 percent of the votes, or 29,961, to only 35 percent, or 16,218, for <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>. `` When you get a margin like 65 percent, that's a mandate from the people that they're willing to work with you,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> said. The successor to Mayor <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON>, who by law had to step down after four consecutive two-year terms, will face problems posed by widespread poverty and rapid growth. Unlike most <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> cities, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> has a strong-mayor form of government with no city manager.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The new mayor is expected to grapple with a high car-theft and house burglary rate, a growing youth gang problem, shockingly high rates of hepatitis and tuberculosis in outlying areas, double-digit unemployment and a steady influx of Mexicans, many of whom work illegally for low wages. Nonetheless, the runoff was almost devoid of issues until two weeks ago, when <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> brought up the matter of Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON>'s finances. Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON>'s husband, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON>, leases business property from the city-owned airport, and <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> said he wanted to know how much the Azars made from businesses on the property. At <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>'s prodding, Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> released a statement showing that she and her husband had a net worth of about $ 3.7 million. <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON>, owner of a medical supply business, has a net worth of about a tenth as much. The two city council members defeated four other candidates in the May 6 general election to make it to Saturday's showdown. Before the May 6 election, the six-candidate campaign focused on taxes, police protection and economic development. But <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> held similar views, and <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> chose to stress personal wealth as a campaign issue. El Paso's elections are non-partisan and there are no party primaries. <PERSON> Elsey </PERSON> is a Republican and Mrs. <PERSON> Azar </PERSON> is a Democrat.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0635 05-28 0537</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0635,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: AMs separates moved as a0631 on Shepard, a0647 on Newborn, a0665
on Anderson.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Allan Shepard</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOISE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Idaho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> died Saturday of complications following a heart attack two days before. He was 66. Last week, <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> stepped down as chief justice, but remained on the court. He cited his heavy work load as a reason for giving up his post. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> joined the five-member <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1969. He suffered a heart attack in late 1987 that kept him off the bench for six weeks. He also was hospitalized early this year with chest pains. <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> served two terms as a Republican state legislator and held the state attorney general's post for six years.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Phineas Newborn Jr.</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jazz pianist <PERSON> Phineas </PERSON> <PERSON> Newborn </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was found dead Friday at his home. He was 57. The cause of death was not released. <PERSON> Irvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Salky </PERSON>, <PERSON> Newborn </PERSON>'s agent, said X-rays six weeks ago showed a growth on one of <PERSON> Newborn </PERSON>'s lungs but that <PERSON> Newborn </PERSON> skipped appointments for tests because he did not want to be hospitalized `` In his prime, he was one of the three greatest jazz pianists of all time, right up there with <PERSON> Bud </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Tatum </PERSON>,'' said jazz critic <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Feather </PERSON>, a columnist for <ORGANIZATION> Downbeat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. His albums included `` A World of Piano,'' `` The Newborn Touch,'' `` The Great Piano of Phineas'' and `` Piano Artistry of <PERSON> Phineas </PERSON> <PERSON> Newborn </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Johnnie L. McHaynes</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. LOUIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Johnnie </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> McHaynes </PERSON>, half of the hefty comedy duo of <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zack </PERSON>, died Thursday. He was 42. The cause of death was not been determined. McHynes teamed with <PERSON> Zachary </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> in the act that also was known at The Fat Boys from <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, prior to <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>'s death two years ago. Together, they weighed more than 750 pounds. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zack </PERSON> made its television debut on the last episode of the `` Redd Foxx Comedy Show'' and later played hospital orderlies in the feature movie `` Nice Girls Do n't Explode,'' in 1987.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Jerry Anderson</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MURFREESBORO, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> player <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> drowned Saturday after pulling two boys out of a rain-swollen river. He was 36. `` Mr. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> jumped in the water and managed to get the little boys out, but witnesses said he went under two or three times and about the fourth time, he did n't come back up,'' police Capt. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> said rescue workers pulled <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> from the lake and took him to a local medical center, but efforts to revive him failed. Five years ago, <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> helped <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION>, residents who were trapped in buildings and cars during a flood. He was honored by the city for his heroic actions. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, 36, grew up in <LOCATION> Murfreesboro </LOCATION> and attended <ORGANIZATION> Northeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> A </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; M <ORGANIZATION> Junior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, where he played football for two years before transferring to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oklahoma </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> was a cornerback on the <ORGANIZATION> Sooners </ORGANIZATION>' 1975 national championship team. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> played briefly in the <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> for <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. He also played in the Canadian <ORGANIZATION> Football </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> before his career was ended by a knee operation in 1982.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 3rdLd-Writethru a0666 05-28 0938</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0666,0968</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students March Again in Beijing; Government Expands Purge</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with residents lining march route,
comments on why workers staying away; EDITS throughout to tighten.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BEJ9,12,13</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of students formed a huge procession Sunday and left <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to march through central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to press their demands for democratic reforms. March leaders said students from up to 300 schools and institutes would join the march at various points around the capital. One student from <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said the goal of the march is `` to have Chinese from throughout the world unite'' in demanding that the government grant greater political freedom. Many carried signs demanding the resignations of Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>, who declared martial law in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on May 20, and senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>. Authorities did not try to stop the marchers as they set out. Unlike demonstrations last week that drew up to a million people to sprawling Tiananmen square, including thousands of workers, there appeared to be few people who were not students in Sunday's procession Student leaders said workers would probably stay away. `` Factories are now taking economic measures against workers who participate,'' one student leader said. Some, he said, have had their pay docked. However, thousands of people lined the streets and crowded onto overpasses to cheer on the marchers. `` Do n't stop,'' some in the crowd yelled. `` We wo n't let you down,'' students shouted back. On Saturday, student leaders proposed that demonstrators hold a climactic rally Tuesday to `` celebrate our great victory'' and then end their historic two-week occupation of Tiananmen Square. The call came as hardliners expanded their purge of moderates, whose sympathy for the students triggered the fiercest power struggle since the leftist ideological purges of the Cultural Revolution. Student leaders said it was time to change tactics in their push for greater freedom and an end to official corruption. But they said protesters in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, whose numbers had fallen sharply to about 10,000, would have the final say on ending the sit-in. Top student leaders <PERSON> Wu'er </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaixi </PERSON>, <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chai </PERSON> <PERSON> Ling </PERSON> held a news conference at the square and called for a city-wide march Tuesday to culminate the protest movement that began April 15. Also Saturday, President <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiannian </PERSON> made the first public acknowledgement that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was experiencing a power struggle, accusing some <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leaders of plotting to create confusion in the country. Sources said officials in the media, the party and the army suspected of participating in the protest movement were being told to write `` reports'' detailing their activities. The reports could be used against them, the sources said, speaking on condition of anonymity. The developments came two days after <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON> was reportedly stripped of power and placed under house arrest. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s fall signaled a victory for the 84-year-old <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> and other leaders who oppose political reform. <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s ouster must be confirmed by a meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which is expected soon. Party officials from provinces and cities were gathering in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to prepare for the meeting, sources said. Sources said <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> has been accused of heading an anti-party clique. One diplomat referred to the clique as a `` new Gang of Four,'' a reference to ultra-leftist radicals who ruled <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> during the last years of the Cultural Revolution of 1966-76. They were purged by <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> when he took power in 1978. Included with <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> are Politburo member <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Qili </PERSON>, Vice Premier <PERSON> Tian </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiyun </PERSON> and Defense Minister <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> <PERSON> Jiwei </PERSON>, Chinese sources said. Chinese and diplomatic sources said <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> used his influence to keep troops in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> from enforcing martial law. Millions of people have taken to the streets in defiance of martial law, and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents put up blockades to prevent troops from entering the city. Students waiting Saturday at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> railroad station to go home said they would bring their message out to the countryside. `` We have to tell the people to arise, including peasants, workers, intellectuals and others from every walk of life,'' said a 24-year-old student from <LOCATION> Wuhan </LOCATION> who asked not to be identified. Tens of thousands of students have occupied <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> since May 13, when they began a hunger strike. But over the past week, thousands have returned to their schools in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and elsewhere and the capital has returned to normal. `` We just feel the movement is ready to take a new form,'' said one student. `` We are ready to print newspapers and conduct speeches.'' The student leaders called for April 27 to be made into a holiday commemorating their movement. On that day, hundreds of thousands marched in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to protest a People's Daily editorial denouncing the student movement. In the first public acknowledgement of a power struggle, former President <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiannian </PERSON> accused `` certain people in the leadership of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'' of creating confusion in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, an apparent reference to <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>. `` These people have an organization, a plan and a plot,'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON> was quoted as saying on television news. `` If they succeed, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> will be thrown into a deep disaster.'' In another blow to <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s faction, state-run media said <PERSON> Wan </PERSON> <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, chairman of the standing committee of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, had thrown his support to conservatives During a visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last week, Wan made statements expressing sympathy for the students. `` After I had time to study the situation,'' Wan was quoted as saying in a letter, `` I realized that a small minority was behind a plot to cause turmoil in society.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PipelineExplosion 2ndLd-Writethru a0653 05-28 0852</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pipeline Explosion, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0653,0869</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigators Look for Cause as Hundreds Remain Displaced</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 11 grafs to update with response from pipeline owner
and NTSB investigator, picks up 13th graf pvs, `The area ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Twin Trauma, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUINN LOTA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly 300 people were kept from their homes Saturday while investigators tried to find out why an underground gasoline pipeline blew up in the same spot where a train derailed two weeks earlier. Two people, and possibly a third, were killed in the explosion, which enveloped a suburban neighborhood in a cauldron of gas-fed flames Thursday morning. `` We are still searching, still investigating the area,'' said police spokeswoman <PERSON> Bernita </PERSON> <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON>. An angry city official, meanwhile, said the owner of the pipeline had proposed to move the rebuilt line closer to homes that survived the rupture and explosion, rather than farther away as the city has urged. `` This has to be one of the most callous examples of corporate greed in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' City Attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said. `` After killing those people they are going to move the pipeline closer to the survivors.'' <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> said <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> officials decided that the city's proposal to move the 14-inch pressurized fuel line to the far side of the railroad tracks, about a mile away from any homes, `` is going to cost them too much money.'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON>, an attorney representing <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON>, said the company wants to move the pressurized fuel pipeline only about 3 feet east of its existing route `` to obviate any safety concerns whatsoever to the existing pipe.'' Although the city's proposal for relocating the pipeline was discussed, <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said, `` I told him that he lives in a hopelessly unrealistic world, and that every major regulatory agency agrees that the pipeline should remain where it is.'' <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> also planned to ask a federal judge to issue an order prohibiting <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> and other city officials from interfering with <LOCATION> Calnev </LOCATION> employees working in the area. <PERSON> Penman </PERSON> allegedly threatened to order <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> police to shoot <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> employees if they try to dig a new trench, <PERSON> Diamond </PERSON> said. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Pugh </PERSON>, an investigator from the federal <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, declined to comment on the dispute at a news conference Saturday evening. Ten homes were destroyed and five were damaged in the eight-hour fire. Seventy homes were evacuated, and Ms. <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> said it was unclear when the 270 displaced people would be be allowed to return home. The area was barricaded to keep out the curious and there was a round-the-clock watch. `` At this point, there is no danger of fire or explosion,'' Ms. <PERSON> Joyner </PERSON> said. The death toll from official sources has fluctuated, rising to three, then reduced to two. On Saturday the city police spokeswoman said there were three dead: a woman, another adult and a child. But Deputy Coroner <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sedgwick </PERSON> said as far as he knew the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> coroner's office had received two bodies. The explosion occurred just days after experts assured city officials and residents that <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON>'s underground pipeline had escaped damage from the May 12 train wreck. The <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> freight train flew off curving tracks atop an embankment and smashed a row of homes on Duffy Street. Two trainmen and two boys in a home were killed. The train fell atop the ground where the pipe is buried. The cause of the blast remained under investigation, but <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> manager <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Seal </PERSON> has said the pipe might have been damaged by the wreck. After the blast, pieces of metal were found in the ground near the pipe and were identified as pieces of a locomotive and a brake assembly from one of the runaway train's cars, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolstad </PERSON>, acting chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION>. What ignited the fuel also remained unknown. A train passed over the tracks 10 minutes before the blast but no connection was immediately drawn. The city and an attorney for more than 100 residents announced plans to file lawsuits against the pipeline company. The residents also plan to sue the city and the rail line, <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> provided vouchers for food, clothing and lodging to the evacuees. `` The residents are still in the motels and they will remain there until they get with <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> and decide what they will do,'' said <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. The pipeline carried gasoline, diesel and jet fuel from a tank farm in <LOCATION> Colton </LOCATION>, several miles from the blaze site, to southern <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, supplying the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> with 90 percent of its fuel. The flow of fuel through the pipeline was shut off when an automatic alarm signaled a drop in pressure, said <PERSON> Jed </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Calnev </PERSON> general manager in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>. However, up to 12,000 gallons of gasoline burned. The explosion was expected to cause a five-cent increase in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> gasoline prices over the Memorial Day weekend, suppliers reported. The price hike was prompted by the cost of having to ship gasoline and diesel fuel by tanker truck rather than the pipeline.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-AT&amp;TTalks 8thLd-Writethru a0667 05-28 1018</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AT&amp;T Talks, 8th Ld-Writethru, a0667,930</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>AT&amp;T, Unions Near Agreement On Three-Year Contracts</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 1-3 to add language dispute; pickup graf 4 pvs,bgng,
``In the ...; SUBS graf 9 to update with joint news conference tentatively
set for Sunday afternoon</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T and unions representing about 160,000 workers were near agreement on new contracts early Sunday, resolving disputes over medical benefits and wages in a frenetic day of bargaining Saturday and working through the night on a few remaining details. Disputes over certain job-classification titles and exact contract language covering some areas of agreement blocked a settlement. But, believing an agreement was at hand, the two unions agreed to bargain overnight and terms of contracts due to expire just before midnight Saturday were extended until further notice. `` It's a speck we expect to work out,'' a company official said of the final dispute. `` We think we'll have it done by daybreak -LRB- Sunday -RRB-,'' a union official said. In the overall agreement being worked out by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> and the unions was a wage and profit-sharing package that should bring workers raises of more than 10 percent over three years, a source said. It is the first time <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T has offered profit sharing to its union workers. The source, speaking on the condition of anonymity, said the unions had fought off <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>'s demand that workers pay more up front for health care costs, the issue that dominated the talks from their outset in March. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> won concessions allowing it to amend certain job titles and thereby expand the duties of certain workers, the source said. Also included was a package of parental, family and elder-care leave provisions. The family and elder-care provisions would allow workers to take six months off to care for a sick parent, spouse or child without losing seniority, the source said. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T would continue health insurance during the leave, the source said. And, in a proposal <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> offered on the final day in hopes of brokering a settlement, the company agreed to create a fund to support new and existing child care centers. The company-union fund reportedly would total $ 5 million. If the remaining disputes are resolved, union and company officials plan a joint news conference Sunday afternoon. An agreement would avert a possible holiday weekend strike by <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>'s union workers, although the unions had not been expected to immediately call a strike even if there were not an agreement Saturday. The new contracts would be subject to rank-and-file ratification and would replace contracts with the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> that expired at 11:59 p.m. EDT Saturday. It appeared as late as Saturday afternoon that no agreement would be reached by the deadline as sources on both sides reported little movement on the health insurance fight. But by early evening there was renewed optimism, spawned by progress made in a series of private meetings between <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's top negotiator and two ranking union officials. Those sessions led to progress at the formal bargaining sessions, and as the existing contracts entered their final hours both sides said an agreement before the deadline was possible. But both sides girded for a possible walkout nonetheless. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T had several thousand managers on alert, their bags packed in case they were dispatched around the country to replace strikers. The unions used computer networks with locals across the nation to update members on the status of the talks and plans for implementing a nationwide labor boycott of <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T long distance had union leaders _ in the event no agreement was reached _ picked that strategy instead of an immediate strike. A strike would have been the third against <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T in nine years. <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> workers did not honor <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION>'s 1986 strike, allowing <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> to keep half its manufacturing plants open. The two unions negotiated jointly for the first time this year. The talks, the largest single-employer collective bargaining session this year, took on added significance because they will affect negotiations later this year for nearly 500,000 union workers at regional phone companies. Also, major corporations seeking to curb soaring health care costs were eager to see whether <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T could pass some of the bill to workers. The unions were determined to prevent the company from slicing its $ 1 billion annual medical bill at the union workers' expense, and from the start of the talks demanded expanded benefits while promising to work with <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T on cost-control measures they said would save millions of dollars. Job security was the third major issue behind health insurance and wages, and <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T made a significant concession in that area on Friday by offering to limit its use of temporary workers. That and other developments brought the first reports of significant progress with little more than 24 hours remaining in the existing contracts. Negotiators returned to the bargaining table at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel Saturday after just a few hours of sleep. Overshadowing their work were periodic private meetings among <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Bahr </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickman </PERSON>, a top aide to <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, and <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's top negotiator, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the company's vice president for labor relations. Those sessions were the key to breaking the impasse over health insurance. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's initial wage package, presented formally on Monday, included base wage increases and lump sum payments for both operating and manufacturing employees and the company's first profit-sharing plan for union workers. Included in that proposal was the company's demand that employees be required to pay 20 percent of doctors and hospital bills _ up to $ 1,000 a year in addition to deductibles _ and 25 percent of the premiums for dependent care. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T employees do not currently pay for dependent care and pay only annual deductibles ranging from $ 150 to $ 300 for medical care. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> said it needed the increased worker contribution to cut an annual medical bill of $ 1 billion. According to company estimates, the negotiations affected about 21,500 long-distance operators, 35,500 in-house and field technicians, 37,000 manufacturing employees and 54,000 other personnel in clerical, administrative, sales and other positions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0309EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Taiwan-China     05-28 0208</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Taiwan-China,0215</SECOND>
<HEAD>Taiwanese Demonstrate To Support Beijing Students</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An estimated 20,000 people demonstrated in <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s two largest cities Sunday to support the student-led democracy movement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. About 10,000 students, movie stars and retired servicemen marched in a park in downtown <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION> and carried banners proclaiming `` Inseparable Blood Relationship'' and `` Long Live Freedom and Democracy.'' `` The students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> are fighting for the future of all Chinese,'' veteran actor <PERSON> Sun </PERSON> <PERSON> Yueh </PERSON> told the gathering in a speech. `` They have our full support.'' Organizers said the rally was in response to a request from the mainland students for international demonstrations Sunday to support their fight for greater freedom and an end to official corruption. In <LOCATION> Kaohsiung </LOCATION>, 230 miles south of <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>, about 10,000 students and faculty members from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yat-sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> marched, police said. <PERSON> Yu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuang-chung </PERSON>, a literature professor, read a poem he composed, `` Tiananmen, We Are Coming,'' during the rally. Tiananmen is a massive square in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> where the Chinese students have been camping during their 15-day protest. The Nationalist government, which lost a civil war to the Communists in 1949, continues to claim it is the legitimate ruler of all <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The Nationalists and Communists are technically still at war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0539EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Bush-Protesters 1stLd-Writethru a0679 05-28 0301</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush-Protesters, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0679,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesters Block Bush Motorcade Briefly</HEAD>
<UNK>Eds: SUBS pvs 5th graf bgng, A few, with 2 new grafs to CORRECT spelling
of Nazionale and identify the organization.</UNK>
<DATELINE>NETTUNO, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two dozen right-wing demonstrators vaulted barricades and briefly halted President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s motorcade Sunday as he traveled to a Roman Catholic Mass in this seacoast city south of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. Some protesters standing along the president's route tossed handbills headlined `` <LOCATION> Anzio </LOCATION> 1945: Were They Liberators or Invaders?'' at <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s motorcade while others formed a human pyramid in the road. The motorcade was stopped for about three minutes until the protesters were removed by police. The demonstrators made no attempt to reach the president's limousine, and <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Snow </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was never in danger `` The president was well back, he was never involved and never in danger,'' Snow said. `` He was never threatened.'' A few of the demonstrators, who said they belonged to a group known as <ORGANIZATION> Destra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nazionale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MSI </ORGANIZATION>, were arrested. <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmonds </PERSON> was injured slightly when a plainclothes officer hit him in the face with <PERSON> Edmonds </PERSON>' camera. <ORGANIZATION> Destra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nazionale </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MSI </ORGANIZATION> stands for <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Right </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Italian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, a neo-fascist political party. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was on his way to attend Mass in <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> before he spoke at a cemetery for nearly 8,000 Americans slain in World War II. The cemetery is situated near the site of a British-American amphibious landing in 1944. The demonstrators' handbills, objecting to the ceremony, said `` the American President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> decided to give an emphasis and a propagandistic depiction that has nothing to do with an obligatory remembrance of the soldiers fallen in combat.'' The brochures said: `` Americans would like to continue to present themselves as the only wall of defense of democratic liberties.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 0952EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Bush 4thLd-Writethru a0686 05-28 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bush, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0686,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Pays Tribute To War Veterans</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS new 5th graf bgng, The president, with Bush departure
for Brussels.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WALTER R. MEARS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Special Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NETTUNO, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> paid tribute Sunday to Americans slain in World War II and said their sacrifices demonstrate that the West needs `` a strong military deterrent'' to preserve freedom and democracy. On the eve of a <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit threatened by discord over nuclear weapons policy, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> appealed to the postwar generation of <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> and Europeans to remain vigilant against military threats. He spoke at a Memorial Day weekend ceremony in a grassy cemetery on <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s west coast, where nearly 8,000 Americans are buried from World War II, and then paid a surprise visit to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft carrier <LOCATION> Guadalcanal </LOCATION> which was anchored in nearby waters. `` We only had 10 minutes, we wanted to show the flag,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told Capt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McKay </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, as he arrived aboard the carrier by helicopter. The president returned to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> and flew to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, at midday for the two-day summit of Western allies which begins Monday. Seeing him off were Italian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> and outgoing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> <PERSON> Rabb </PERSON>. Accompanied by his wife <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON>, the president flew here by helicopter from <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> to lay a wreath and attend Mass at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which has only six pews seating about 70 people. On his way to the church, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s motorcade was halted briefly by right-wing demonstrators who threw handbills and formed a human pyramid in the road. The road was quickly cleared by police, and a <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said the president was never in danger. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who arrived in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> late Friday night, planned to travel to <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> later in the day for Monday's opening of the 16-nation <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit. In remarks prepared for delivery at the cemetery, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the white crosses and Stars of <PERSON> David </PERSON> marking the graves here and around the world were `` a silent tribute to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s battles for freedom in this century.'' `` As I reflect on this scene and anticipate the dynamic and forward-looking <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> of the 1990s, I think of generations of young people on both sides of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> who have grown up in peace and prosperity. `` With no experience of the horror and destruction of war,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` it may be difficult for them to understand why we need to keep a strong military deterrent to prevent war and to preserve freedom and democracy. `` The answer is here, among the quiet of the graves,'' the president said. The remarks echoed the sentiment he voiced last Sunday in a speech at <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> when he said he was concerned about `` a growing complacency'' throughout the West. `` As we gather today,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` it is dawn in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, Memorial Day weekend. `` And as the sun rises and the summer begins, the images both here and at home are of countries that are prosperous and secure, countries confident of their place in the world and aware of the responsibility that comes with that place,'' he said. Meanwhile, in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> leaders already have started gathering for Monday's summit. The atmosphere of the meeting has been marred by a dispute largely between <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> on one side and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> on the other. Amid a tide of disarmament sentiment, West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> has demanded that the West open negotiations soon with the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> to reduce short-range nuclear missiles in central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Most of the weapons are based in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and, if used, would fall on German soil. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> also is resisting plans to modernize the missiles to make them faster and increase their range. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has opposed negotiations about the missiles, arguing they are needed to offset the big advantage in conventional forces by the Soviet-led <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pact </ORGANIZATION>. There also are fears in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that any negotiations to reduce the number of missiles would create public pressure to eliminate them entirely.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-AT&amp;TContract     05-28 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-AT&amp;T Contract,210</SECOND>
<HEAD>AT&amp;T, Unions Agree On Three-Year Contracts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T and unions representing about 160,000 employees reached agreement early Sunday on new three-year national contracts that include the company's first profit-sharing plan for union workers. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> officials and the unions were to release details of the settlement Sunday afternoon but sources familiar with it said a compromise reached on the thorny issue of health insurance would not require workers to pay more up front for coverage. That demand, made by <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION>, had threatened to block agreement. Also in the contract, according to sources, are annual wage increases for both operating and manufacturing employees. And the company included a package of `` family issues'' benefits that include an improved policy for parental leave, a new one allowing family leave to care for a sick family member and a new joint <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T-union fund to support child care. The two sides reached agreement on the framework for a national contract before midnight Saturday but still had a few remaining disputes over local issues and contract language. The unions agreed to extend terms of existing contracts _ which were to expire at 11:59 p.m. Saturday _ and bargaining continued into the early morning hours.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Vietnam-Storm     05-28 0122</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam-Storm,0125</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Kills 52 People in Central Vietnam</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tropical storm tore through <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s central <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> <PERSON> Nam-Danang </PERSON> province, killing 52 people, injuring 37 and leaving 100,000 homeless, according to radio reports Sunday The storm razed 36,000 houses and sank or damaged 700 vessels in the province on Wednesday and Thursday, the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> radio said in a broadcast monitored in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. Torrential rains in <LOCATION> Nghe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tinh </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Binh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tri </PERSON> <PERSON> Thien </PERSON> provinces north of <PERSON> Quang </PERSON> <PERSON> Nam-Danang </PERSON> caused heavy damage on Friday and Saturday, the radio said. Floods ruined 84,600 acres of rice and 49,400 acres of other crops, the <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said earlier. The storm dumped heavy rains on <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> after leaving <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-SiameseTwins     05-28 0141</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Siamese Twins,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>Siamese Twins Separated in Malaysia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Siamese twins who were joined at the chest and abdomen and shared a liver were successfully separated at the Government Hospital on Sunday, officials said. The 7-month-old girls were in stable condition in an intensive care unit following an eight-hour operation conducted by a team of 40 people. Dr. <PERSON> Goon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hong </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooi </PERSON>, one of two team leaders, told reporters the operation left each girl with a liver that should function normally. He said the doctors used new equipment during the procedure. One device, an ultrasonic dissector, reduced bleeding during the separation of the liver by allowing the doctors to break its cells without damaging important blood vessels. The second device, a tissue expander, was used to stretch the tissues, providing additional skin to cover the girls' wounds.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1121EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Iran-Earthquakes     05-28 0180</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Iran-Earthquakes,0184</SECOND>
<HEAD>17 Iranians Hurt, Several Houses Destroyed In Earthquakes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A strong earthquake and several mild tremors struck southern <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> late Saturday and early Sunday, injuring 17 people, destroying several homes and killing 100 head of cattle, the official news agency said. The cattle were killed in <LOCATION> Fars </LOCATION> province, where the quake was felt just before midnight in the cities of <LOCATION> Mamasani </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Shiraz </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Karzeroun </PERSON>, according to the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> geophysics center said the quake measured 5.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale and was centered 375 miles south of <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. Eight mild tremors hit <PERSON> Kohkiluyeh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Boyer </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> province, resulting in the injuries and the damage to the homes, said <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. In the cities of <LOCATION> Boushehr </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Gonaveh </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Borazjan </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Boushehr </LOCATION> province, frightened residents rushed into the streets during a series of mild tremors. The Richter scale is a gauge of the energy released by an earthquake, as measured by the ground motion recorded on a seismograph. A quake measuring 6 on the scale can cause severe damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghanistan     05-28 0442</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan,0457</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Launch New Offensive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYAN WILDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Moslem rebels have launched a new offensive to capture the embattled eastern Afghan city of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, but there were conflicting reports Sunday of their success. Rebel sources said the mujahedeen, or Islamic `` holy warriors,'' began attacking communist government positions from all four sides Saturday. They claimed to have captured several government military posts and killed or wounded at least 70 communist troops. Rebels losses were put at about 10 dead. However, official Radio <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, monitored in <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>, said government forces repulsed the attack and gained new territory around the city. It said 55 `` enemy elements'' were killed and 46 were wounded. Both sides of the Afghan civil war often make exaggerated claims that contradict each other and usually can not be verified independently. The mujahedeen, backed primarily by <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, have fought unsuccessfully for <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> since March 6. The battle began about three weeks after Soviet troops pulled the last of their troops from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, ending nine years of military support for the Marxist government. Afghan forces still hold the country's major cities but the guerrillas reportedly control more than 90 percent of the countryside. Communist troops have withstood relentless rebel rocket and artillery attacks on <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, where they still control the city center and the military airport to the east. Guerrilla leaders earlier predicted that the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government would fall within weeks or months of the Soviet troop withdrawal. However, President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> has said his forces' tenacious defense of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION> proves the guerrills can not win a military victory in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. He has made repeated overtures for peace talks with the insurgents, but they have refused. <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> leaders blame the ruling <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION> for inviting the Soviet military intervention. They demand a complete capitulation of the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government and the establishment of an Islamic republic of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Fighting since the Soviet pullout has concentrated on <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, 42 miles west of the <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> border, and most recently <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION>, a garrison town to the south. Rebel commanders also say they are preparing an all-out assault on <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. Guerrilas during the weekend claimed to have overrun at least three government posts around <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION>, killing 50 soldiers and capturing four officers since Thursday. They said 18 rebels were killed. Radio <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>, however, claimed Saturday night that 173 mujahedeen were killed and 32 were wounded. Foreign observers estimate that some 1.5 million Afghans have died in the past 11 years of civil war. More than 5 million Afghans, about one-third of the country's pre-war population of 15 million, live as refugees in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Thailand-AIDS     05-28 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Thailand-AIDS,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teams to Search for AIDS Victims in Thailand</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Teams of medics and social workers will tour <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> to look for people with the deadly disease AIDS, <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Thailand </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. Up to 30 teams have been set up to test blood from people in high-risk groups in major provinces, the state-run radio said. Testing will concentrate on prostitutes and drug addicts. Some estimates put the number of prostitutes in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> at 1 million. The <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> says more than 6,000 people in the country have AIDS and that most of those afflicted are drug addicts. But the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which monitors the AIDS epidemic worldwide, says the figure in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> is actually about 25,000. Acquired immune deficiency syndrome is an affliction in which a virus attacks the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to a wide variety of infections and cancers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BusPlunge     05-28 0096</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bus Plunge,0096</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nine Killed, 43 Hurt When Bus Plunges Into Lake</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nine Pakistanis were killed and 43 were injured when a speeding bus went out of control, hit a fence and plunged into a lake in central <LOCATION> Punjab </LOCATION> province, officials said Sunday. Police said a broken steering tie rod apparently caused the accident on Saturday, but the driver fled the scene before he could be questioned. Hospital officials said 10 of the injured were treated at area hospitals and released. The accident occurred near <LOCATION> Phalia </LOCATION>, 100 miles south of <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Iran-Drugs     05-28 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Iran-Drugs,0172</SECOND>
<HEAD>23 Drug Smugglers Hanged in Tehran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty-three convicted drug traffickers were hanged Sunday in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>, the official <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. Twenty-one men were hanged in public, and two women were hanged at a prison, the agency said in a report monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>. The hangings raised the number of drug-related executions in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> to 151 in the past two weeks. <ORGANIZATION> IRNA </ORGANIZATION> quoted an Islamic revolutionary court statement as saying the drug traffickers were longtime smugglers who also were involved in running brothels. Two of those hanged were Turkish nationals. Both were bus drivers who smuggled more than 220 pounds of hashish and heroin into <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on several occasions, the agency said. It said several of those executed had previous narcotics convictions and that one couple had resumed trafficking when they were pardoned and freed while serving a life sentence. The hangings brought the number of drug-related executions to 709 since <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> launched a nationwide anti-narcotics crackdown in December.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-Teachers     05-28 0132</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Teachers,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Block Formation of Korea's First Teachers' Union</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hundreds of police stormed a university Sunday to prevent 1,000 teachers from organizing <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s first teachers' union. Authorities said 250 teachers were arrested. About 700 riot police marched into <ORGANIZATION> Hanyang </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to block a rally by the elementary, middle and high school teachers. After they were prevented from entering the university, the teachers held the rally at a nearby high school, where they shouted anti-government slogans. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION>, which claims a membership of 70,000, wants to form a union in defiance of the government, which says the law forbids teachers from forming a union because they are public servants. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> has 300,000 primary, middle and high school teachers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Turkey-Kurds     05-28 0143</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Turkey-Kurds,0147</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed in Coffee House Raid Blamed on Kurd Separatists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NIZIP, Turkey (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Suspected Kurdish separatists opened fire in a coffee house, and three people were reported killed and eight wounded. The semi-official <ORGANIZATION> Anatolia </ORGANIZATION> news agency said four men armed with automatic weapons fled in a car after the attack late Saturday. The agency quoted witnesses as saying the gunmen shouted they were firing in the name of the <ORGANIZATION> Kurdish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, an outlawed group that seeks to set up a Marxist state in parts of eastern and southeastern <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. Last week, 22 Kurdish guerrillas and 10 soldiers were killed in three separate clashes. More than 900 civilians and security personnel and about as many Kurdish insurgents have been killed since the guerrilla campaign began in 1984. Ethnic Kurds make up about one-fifth of <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>'s population of 55 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Burma-China     05-28 0533</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Burma-China,0546</SECOND>
<HEAD>Burmese Students Boosted by China's Pro-democracy Campaign</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRUNNSTROM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The people of <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, who saw their own dreams of democracy brutally crushed last year, are gaining inspiration from the student uprising in neighboring <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Defying an army ban on demonstrations, 12 students rallied outside the <ORGANIZATION> Rangoon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus one day last week and shouted slogans supporting the students in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> diplomat reported. Tin Oo, chairman of the main opposition party, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday that authorities detained six activists who pasted posters on trees in the capital proclaiming support for the Chinese students. He said the activists sought legal advice from him. Millions in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> last year followed university students and marched in the streets shouting for an end to decades of repression. They forced the resignation of three presidents and ended the one-party system, but today they still live under a military-run government. The Burmese government's response to the protests was much harsher than <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s _ troops shot to death thousands of peaceful demonstrators, and in September the military reestablished control and banned protests. `` At least the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government has some respect for the students,'' said <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> <PERSON> Thi </PERSON> <PERSON> Zun </PERSON>, a 24-year-old student leader who fled to the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> border to escape arrest for organizing demonstrations. `` In <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>, the students were just shot down in the streets.'' Before fleeing, he was head of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for a <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the main student-led political party in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>. At rallies this month, <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, the other leader of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION>, contrasted the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government's attitude with the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> leaders' adamant refusal to make any contact at all with dissidents She was campaigning in the central city of <LOCATION> Mandalay </LOCATION> for a general election that the government has promised for May 1990. `` We started with a students' movement, so everyone has strong feelings for what is happening in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' said Tin Oo, reached by telephone in the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> capital, <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION>. He was refering to the country's tradition of student activism, beginning with the campaign that led to <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s independence from <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1948. <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s state-run press has carried nothing on the events in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the government has made no official comment. But people have been following developments on the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. The uprising in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has boosted the morale of some of the 3,000 students who remain along the border with <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> after fleeing last year's military crackdown in the cities. They are living in harsh conditions in the malarial jungles, where ethnic groups are fighting a 40-year-old war for greater autonomy. `` It makes them realize they are not alone,'' <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> <PERSON> Thi </PERSON> <PERSON> Zun </PERSON> said. `` They can see there are people like them struggling for democracy.'' But he said many students are upset that the world press that once ran the <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> uprising on its front pages now gives it little coverage. `` It is particularly sad as the students in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> went through even greater hardships than those in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Now it is not worthy of page one, even though there are many still suffering.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Poland-Election Bjt   05-28 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Poland-Election, Bjt,0852</SECOND>
<HEAD>Communists Run on Their Record in Poland's Strange New Experiment</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DANISZEWSKI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a land where people must wait decades for an apartment or telephone and pay inflated prices for scarce goods, how does a party in power for nearly half a century run on its record? Such is the dilemma facing the <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> as it prepares for the June 4 elections to parliament, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s first somewhat democratic balloting since World War II. The communists are being challenged by a well-organized, emotionally driven opposition led by the newly legalized Solidarity labor movement. Solidarity, with the luster of novelty and the aura of idealism, is awash in campaign contributions and volunteers. At a converted coffee house in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s Constitution Square, the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, workers almost trip over each other to get out campaign literature, deliver placards, sign up poll watchers and instruct citizens on voting procedures. A few blocks away, in a state-owned department store, the party-led coalition's campaign headquarters is almost empty. One campaign workers is on duty, his piles of leaflets sitting idle and unread. Polish leader Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>, who ordered the crackdown that led to Solidarity's suppression in 1981 and initiated the conciliation that resulted in its legalization this year, has said the communist party must be prepared to face the electoral test. Party spokesman <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bisztyga </PERSON> said despite <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s dire economic problems, the party can point to some achievements during its 45 years in power. `` We had 45 years of peace. ... At all our borders, we had friends. It means something,'' he said. `` We changed the classes in our country. We had a majority of peasants.'' Now, a majority has moved to an urban life, and `` we have a huge intelligentsia.'' All this took `` tremendous economic, social and political effort,'' he said. `` So it is very unjust to enter the political campaign looking for errors and defeats.'' More important than the past is the future, he said. The party is campaigning on the premise that it is the best bet for ensuring political and economic reform. Of all the political forces in the country, he said, the party is in the strongest position to guarantee that reforms actually will be carried out. `` To say that the reforms just started now _ it is not true,'' he said. `` Always in our party, the <ORGANIZATION> communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> party </ORGANIZATION>, it was a trend to adopt our policy to the actual situation in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>.'' The party pitches itself as pragmatic and practical, implying Solidarity is not. Banners around <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> say: `` With us, it's surer,'' and `` We have a realistic program. Missing is any reference to the communist party itself. Instead of the party's Polish initials, PZPR, posters bear a logo with a red mermaid, a city symbol used by the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> `` coalition'' of party candidates and those of allied groups. At stake in all of this are 460 seats in the existing parliament, the Sejm, and 100 seats in the newly created <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The opposition is allotted only 161 seats in the Sejm, with the rest reserved for the communists. But the race for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is wide open. The new system was one of the agreements that came out of two months of talks between the government and the Solidarity-led opposition. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s regime agreed to the talks after a series of crippling labor strikes last year. It is seeking Solidarity's help in putting in place unpopular measures to overhaul the nation's sickly economy In return, among other things, Solidarity was made legal again and elections were made freer. The <ORGANIZATION> Solidarity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citizens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has named just one candidate for each of the parliament races it can enter. The party's slate is less clearly defined. For example, there are more than 30 candidates on the ballot for three <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats from <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>. Three represent Solidarity, but the party has never clearly announced which of the others it supports. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Szymborski </PERSON>, a party propaganda department employee manning the coalition's <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> campaign center, says that is because the party wanted to let the people decide. Some opposition leaders have suggested the party's strategy includes trying to confuse voters. Candidate names are to appear on lengthy and complicated ballots with no indication of affiliation. Although the party has been in power since the reestablishment of a Polish government after World War II and claims a membership of 2 million -LRB- about 5 percent of the population -RRB-, it has been trailing the opposition in opening campaign offices, announcing a platform and putting up posters. `` If you are talking about visual propaganda, for certain we were behind the Solidarity side,'' <PERSON> Szymborski </PERSON> conceded, saying the party was slower to pick its candidates. But he said the party is dealing more specifically with the issues. `` Solidarity first of all is basing its campaign on its name and its sign, and our campaign is more complicated and wider,'' he grumbled.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-ThenandNow Bjt   05-28 0786</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Then and Now, Bjt,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissent 10 Years Ago Smaller, But Presaged Current Upheaval</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR ` S NOTE _ The writer reported from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> between April 1979 and November 1984 and was The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> bureau chief. She is now the chief correspondent at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> UNITED </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NATIONS </ORGANIZATION> _ A decade ago, police scrubbed down <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Democracy Wall and stifled the calls for political reform that sowed the seeds of today's protests for greater freedom in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Democracy Wall, so named because it was laden with posters calling for democratic reform, came to represent the early political dissent that was crushed by <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s supreme leader The political tremors of 10 years ago presaged the current upheaval by millions of student-led protesters, but there are major differences between the so-called <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Spring of 1979 and that of 1989. The movement then was mostly underground and disorganized and involved a few thousand people, mostly working-class men. It was far more strident and revolutionary than the past six weeks of jubilant demonstrations in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Then, there were no live television interviews with loquacious, hopeful demonstrators in Western clothes. There were no rock concerts. In December, 1978 the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> restored diplomatic relations. The next year witnessed the flowering and the end of the Democracy Wall, in the same central square where today's students have centered their protests Ten years ago, the movement was fierce in rhetoric, more negative than positive. Many dissidents likened Communism to fascism and denounced <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> as a modern emperor and tyrant. They did n't know exactly what they wanted, or how to get it, but they knew they did n't want the status quo. `` We do n't want Communism, socialism, capitalism or any other ` ism' _ we want nationalism and the best for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' dissidents said. They were branded as counterrevolutionaries out to wreck Chinese modernization. In 1979 it took a special courage to stand up to the powerful state machinery that did not tolerate criticism. Ordinary citizens were afraid to speak out in support of the demonstrators, poster writers, artists and poets who clamored for change. Many were afraid to speak to foreigners, because they might be interrogated by police. In demonstrations, police did not hesitate to disperse crowds using force. Some who dared speak out were beaten and jailed, some lost their jobs. One editor of an underground magazine, <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingsheng </PERSON>, was tried and convicted as a traitor in 1979. He was sentenced to 15 years in a labor camp, where some say he went mad and died. But all that was before sweeping economic reforms gave people greater independence and confidence, before glasnost and greater freedom began to sweep the Communist world. Now, millions of people nationwide have defied the government and martial law with marches and demands for democracy, party reform and an end to endemic official corruption. Demonstrators have demanded the ouster of <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> and his hard-line protege, Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON>. They have shouted, chanted, and they blocked army tanks when <PERSON> Li </PERSON> declared martial law. About 3,000 went on a hunger strike. Though today's protest leaders face danger, there is official recognition of legitimate demands for greater freedom. The men and women today are disciplined and organized, and more important, they are backed by ordinary citizens. Their strength lies in numbers, mass support, reasonable demands for reform and a clean Communist government. They do n't demand revolution. Even the government calls most of them patriots. The student demands have been treated sympathetically by the official Chinese press, which has even joined the protests. Democracy Wall, a gray stone barricade between a bus yard and central Tiananmen Square, was the focus of the movement 10 years ago, when <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was emerging from the Cultural Revolution and beginning to open to the outside world. The wall, 200 yards long and three yards high, became a billboard for big character posters, a staging ground for activism, a gallery for dissident artists, and a marketplace for ideas and unofficial magazines. It made headlines in November 1978 when <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> exploited it to discredit political opponents who banished him during the Cultural Revolution. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> himself reportedly named it `` Democracy Wall.'' `` Wall posters are not forbidden ... they are a constitutional right and if the masses feel some anger, we must let them express it,'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> said in late 1978. But he also said the masses sometimes were confused. Then, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, the architect of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s economic reforms and open door, decided that free speech had gone too far. On Dec. 7, 1979, big character posters were prohibited. Workers used scrapers, shovels, rakes, brooms, spatulas, steel wool and eradicated the offending posters _ but not the ideas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Soviet-Georgia     05-28 0514</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Georgia,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Official Report Says Soviet Troops Planned Massacre in Georgia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers planned to massacre people during a pro-independence rally last month in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and used clubs to beat the injured and the elderly, an official report says. The report, issued by a Georgian commission that looked into the April 9 clash that left 19 dead, was circulated among deputies to the new Soviet parliament, which met during the weekend. The report calls for the parliament, the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, to condemn the incident and determine who exactly was responsible `` Otherwise,'' the report said, `` a shadow will be laid across the Soviet government as a whole.'' The report gives a horrifying account of troops' behavior in the 4 a.m. clash with protesters. It also supports claims of <LOCATION> Georgian </LOCATION> activists who accused soldiers of extreme brutality. Soldiers `` blocked crossings, surrounded citizens and beat them with clubs and shovels. They did not spare hunger strikers, girls, old women, doctors and <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> workers. They pursued people who were running away and beat the wounded even more, tearing them from the hands of medical personnel,'' the report says. `` We come to the conclusion that the action taken ... carries the signs of a punitive operation _ a planned mass massacre, committed with special cruelty,'' the commission reported. The panel, sponsored by the Georgian parliament, also said Georgian television announced a curfew the day after the clash only four minutes before it went into effect, so many residents were caught on the streets unaware. One young man was shot and killed for violating the curfew. It said the Soviet media distorted coverage of the clash and its aftermath and it blamed local leaders for `` complete isolation from the people.'' A medical subcommittee's findings repeated widespread criticism of the Defense and Interior Ministries for not telling doctors for several days exactly what sort of gas was used to control protesters. Western doctors who conducted autopsies have said the gases, described as suffocants, caused some of the deaths. Also, more than 4,000 people have required treatment, mainly for poisoning, and diagnosis and treatment would have been much easier if authorities had acknowledged earlier that they used a chemical agent, the report said. A Soviet magazine recently carried an interview with Georgian chief Prosecutor <PERSON> Vakhtang </PERSON> <PERSON> Razmadze </PERSON>, who said representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the government and the military attended the meeting at which the decision was made to use troops to break up the demonstration. They included Georgian party chief <PERSON> Zhumber </PERSON> <PERSON> Patiashvili </PERSON>, who later resigned, General <PERSON> Igor </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodionov </PERSON>, the regional military commander, who is now a deputy at the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, and a deputy national defense minister. The account was consistent with a claim made Thursday by President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He said he and other Politburo members found out about the decision to bring in troops only hours after the damage was done. Protests began in <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>'s capital, in early April in response to demands by the Abkhazian minority in <LOCATION> northwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> to have their area transferred to the Russian republic.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Anti-DrugAds Bjt   05-28 1055</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Anti-Drug Ads, Bjt,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>Are Public Service Spots Effective? The Reviews Are Mixed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fried egg sizzles and burns on the television screen as an ominous voice intones: `` This is your brain on drugs.'' Another ad depicts a medical machine recording the active brain waves of a typical 14-year-old followed by the somewhat deadened brain waves of a 14-year-old after smoking marijuana. The advertisements are brought to the screen by advertisers who have voluntarily collaborated on the efforts, and by TV networks that have provided millions of dollars worth of free air time. But do they work? Some _ including the Media-Advertising Partnership for a <LOCATION> Drug-Free </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and its sister organization, The Advertising Council _ maintain they are effective in changing public attitudes about drug use. That position is supported by <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, director of the federal Office of National Drug Control Policy. Others say the ads are a waste of money. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Des </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarlais </PERSON>, an epidemiologist who works with heroin and cocaine addicts in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said when the addicts do refer to the ads, it's `` derisively.'' `` They're not aimed at addicts,'' he said. `` They're aimed at people not using or casual users. The preliminary data I've seen indicate they do change some attitudes, but in terms of actually changing drug use, that remains to be seen.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Condry </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor who has spent the past year at the <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> on the Influences of Television on Children at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION>, said television is delivering too many mixed messages for the ads to have an impact. <PERSON> Condry </PERSON> said he has found that the ratio of pro-drug to anti-drug messages on television was 8-to-1, including programs and advertisements showing people smoking, drinking or taking medicines. Even legitimate ads for such things as over-the-counter pain medications send the wrong message, he contended. `` While it's not illegal, what they are saying is if you do n't like the state you're in, if you have a headache, you take a drug ... take some sort of substance to change how you feel,'' Condry said `` For a child, it's not clear there's a distinction between one drug and another _ a pill's a pill,'' he said. <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Charren </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, said the money spent to make and broadcast the public service ads could be better spent on education. The `` Just Say No'' ad effort promoted by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> `` seems to me the kind of campaign that kids who are dealing in drugs laugh at,'' she said. `` It's not that I think these -LRB- advertisements -RRB- are damaging,'' <PERSON> Charren </PERSON> said. `` What's damaging about it is that it makes the society feel we're doing something. It makes the ad industry feel it's OK to advertise the products of their clients in programs that glamorize crime in the streets, violence against women and the culture that gives rise to drug dealing. `` It's conscience money for a society that is not taking care of that part of the population that's most likely to get involved in drugs,'' she said. But <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, program director for the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>, praised the effectiveness of the advertising campaigns. <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, co-director of the 1988 national survey of high school seniors that indicated a decrease in illicit drug use credited the ads with having a substantial impact. `` I personally believe the partnership's efforts played an important role in helping to bring about these changes, and the young people we survey seem to believe it as well,'' <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> wrote to the Partnership for a Drug-Free <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. `` They report a very high level of recalled exposure to the anti-drug advertising, a high degree of credibility in the content, and most important, a high judged impact on their own drug-using behaviors and attitudes.'' The annual <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> survey is backed by the federal government and has won acceptance over the years as the best measure of high school drug use. But it makes no pretense of measuring drug use among the 15 percent who drop out of school and are more prone to drug use. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Clemm </PERSON>, chief operating officer of the polling firm of <ORGANIZATION> Gordon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> _ hired by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agencies </ORGANIZATION> to survey the anti-drug ads' impact _ said the survey found they were effective when they got a lot of air time. `` In the areas where we were able to get more exposure, we were having an impact,'' <PERSON> Clemm </PERSON> said. `` Among key groups, we were seeing changing attitudes and perceptions, changes in drug use.'' The partnership has been responsible for some 70 different TV commercials, and <PERSON> Clemm </PERSON> noted that different ads affect different groups. `` There is n't one single message that will work with every group,'' he said. Younger children, ages 9 and up, respond more to ads questioning whether the drug pushers and drug users are really such cool characters, `` the big men on campus, the people you want to be friends with,'' <PERSON> Clemm </PERSON> said, basing his remarks on interviews over two years with some 14,000 people. Older teens and college students responded to `` concern over what their younger brothers and sisters might do because of their actions'' and adults were affected by depictions of the possible impacts on their work performance, whether they might endanger others as well as themselves by taking drugs, <PERSON> Clemm </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> cited the <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> study when he said in an interview that the advertising `` does work. It works not for the hard-core addict, but it does work for a person who's a casual user.'' In addition, he said, it helps prevent people from starting to use drugs, `` if you get the right ad.'' <PERSON> Theresa </PERSON> <PERSON> Venet </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> of the Partnership for a Drug-Free <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> rejected <PERSON> Charren </PERSON>'s contention that the commercials represent `` conscience money.'' `` I think these ads work,'' she said. `` I think there's a changing tone in the entire entertainment industry'' that eliminates qualms advertisers might have in supporting programs while also participating in anti-drug efforts. Among the shows she cited as making a `` conscious effort to deglamorize drug use'' were `` 21 Jump Street,'' `` Growing Pains'' and `` Family Ties.'' `` To say the industry does n't care, that's just as irresponsible as saying that we do n't have a problem,'' <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890528-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-28-89 1202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Thatcher-Bush     05-28 0579</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Thatcher-Bush,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Analysts Predict U.S.-British Relationship Will Thrive Under Bush</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Summit Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
