<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HurricaneErin 2ndLd-Writethru a0724 08-26 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Erin, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0724,0245</SECOND>
<HEAD>Erin's Winds Easingd, Storm's Weakening Forecast</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with 10:30 p.m. EDT position; picks
up 4th graf pvs: `The storm ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Erin continued its northward trek into cooler mid-Atlantic waters Friday with winds falling to 85 mph and forecasters predicting a gradual weakening over the weekend. `` It's only a threat to marine interests,'' said National Hurricane Center forecaster <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimberlain </PERSON>. `` Our forecast track is between <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.'' At 10:30 p.m. EDT, <PERSON> Erin </PERSON>'s center was near 43.0 north latitude and 35.4 west longitude, or about 310 miles west-northwest of the westernmost <LOCATION> Azores </LOCATION>. The system was moving northeast at about 25 mph and was expected to weaken gradually over the next 24 hours. The storm will probably lose its tropical characteristics over the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, but that does n't mean it will be harmless, <PERSON> Kimberlain </PERSON> said. The storm will probably lose what forecasters call its tropical characteristics over the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>, but that does n't mean it will be harmless, <PERSON> Kimberlain </PERSON> said. A similar storm lashed <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> two years ago, causing substantial damage. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> became a named storm Sunday night when sustained winds reached 39 mph. It reached the 74 mph threshold for a hurricane Tuesday. There have been seven tropical depressions in the 1989 <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season, which runs from June 1 to Nov. 30. <PERSON> Erin </PERSON> is the fifth named storm and the third hurricane of the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-`Starsky-Hutch'AIDS     08-26 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-`Starsky-Hutch' AIDS,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Starksy And Hutch' Star's Family Infected With AIDS Virus</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA10</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wife and son of `` Starsky and Hutch'' star <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> are infected with the virus which causes AIDS, and the couple's daughter has already died from the disease. Although <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> and her 5-year-old son have not developed AIDS, the couple's first child, daughter <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON>, died of AIDS complications last year at age 7. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>, the former star of the cop show `` Starsky and <PERSON> Hutch </PERSON>,'' is the only family member not infected. `` Lesser men would have walked,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>, who has taken the anti-AIDS drug AZT for the past 18 months. `` He never made us feel we were anything but a family.'' <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> said the family had no choice. `` We have grown up a hell of a lot. It was either grow up or perish,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Glasers </ORGANIZATION> have strived to keep their family life as normal as possible, but they anticipate that will change, they told the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in a story in Friday's editions. They said they decided to go public with their pain after they learned the National Enquirer was planning a story on them. The tabloid declined to comment. `` We begged them not to run the story but they said it was newsworthy,'' said <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>, who is now a film director. `` Our fear is the greatest for our son,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> said. `` It is our right to tell him when he is strong enough and old enough to handle the information. Now, we may not have that choice.'' <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>, who played the streetwise plainclothes detective <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Starsky </PERSON> in the police action series that ran from September 1975 to August 1979, acknowledged it is not easy for him to talk about the tragedy he faces. `` This has to be a story about how we rise above our fears, how we all have to be stronger than we ever thought we could be,'' he said. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>'s former co-star <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Soul </PERSON> said he had been unaware of the family's situation and encouraged the public to support the <ORGANIZATION> Glasers </ORGANIZATION> by helping to fight the deadly disease. `` I have been deeply saddened to learn of the events of these past several years and of the profound loss which <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> and <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> have suffered,'' Soul said. `` But I am also inspired by the strength of their commitment to each other and to their children.'' The family's nightmare began in 1981 when Mrs. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> contracted HIV after receiving seven pints of blood. She had been rushed to a hospital for the transfusions when she began hemorrhaging in her ninth month of carrying Ariel. Four years later, her daughter was hospitalized with a stubborn illness. Tests confirmed it was AIDS. The <ORGANIZATION> Glasers </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> contracted the virus from her mother through eight months of breastfeeding. The boy contracted it in the womb. After her daughter's death last year, Mrs. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON>, former exhibit director for the local Children's Museum, turned much of her attention to raising money for pediatric AIDS research. She has collected more than $ 5 million. Her efforts have drawn the support of many celebrities and politicians including former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>. Her story also moved <PERSON> Kitty </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, the wife of the former Democratic presidential candidate, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>. `` Nobody in that short of time has touched me so,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>. `` I have never been with anybody who could rise above their own pain to help so many other people.'' As of Aug. 1, AIDS had been diagnosed in 102,621 Americans, of whom more than half, or 59,391, have died, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION>. No one is known to have recovered from AIDS. AIDS, or acquired immune deficiency syndrome, is caused by the human immunodeficiency virus, which damages the body's immune system, leaving victims susceptible to death from infections and cancer. It is spread through sexual contact, needles or syringes shared by drug abusers, transfusions of infected blood or blood products, or from an infected mother to her baby before or during birth. However, screening procedures not available when Mrs. <PERSON> Glaser </PERSON> had her transfusions have greatly reduced the risk of acquiring the virus through tainted blood.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0057EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-B-2-DefectivePart     08-26 0447</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-B-2-Defective Part,0462</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abbreviated Test Flight Blamed On Defective Part</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EDWARDS AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The second test flight of the B-2 stealth bomber was scrubbed in midflight because of a crack in a part provided by a defense contractor once fined for billing fraud, <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> officials said. A hairline crack in a casing of an accessory drive, which powers the $ 530 million high-tech jet's generators and controls, caused oil pressure to drop during the Aug. 16 test flight, Air Force Capt. <PERSON> Tess </PERSON> <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said Thursday. `` It was n't anything critical that would have caused the plane to crash,'' she said. `` It was a minor problem.'' The flight of the bat-wing bomber designed to pass through enemy radar undetected was scheduled to last up to four hours, but was halted after about one hour. The casing for the aircraft's No. 1 accessory drive was made by <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, which <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials indefinitely suspended last year from doing business with the government. <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION> was fined $ 115 million in October for overcharging the government for parts, billing the Pentagon for baby-sitting costs, country club dues and executive servants. The suspension did not affect contracts the company already had, including the one for the B-2 casings. <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> said he would not comment on the flaw. The part was redesigned to make it thicker after laboratory tests indicated the casing would work better if strengthened, Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said. `` There's absolutely nothing wrong with the part as originally designed,'' she said. `` Things break, OK?'' Officials for <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which builds the B-2, said the thinner casings, measuring four feet long, one foot wide and five inches thick, were examined and cleared as airworthy. `` We would n't put anything in there that we thought was potentially defective,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION>'s B-2 spokesman <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cantafio </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> engineers continue to work with designers from <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Sundstrand </ORGANIZATION> and other subcontractors throughout the B-2 construction process and were fully aware of the modifications made to thicken the casing, Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cantafio </PERSON> and Ms. <PERSON> Taft </PERSON> both said they were unaware of any plan to replace the thinner parts before the B-2's next test flight. The government has spent about $ 22.4 billion in the B-2 program, which is 18 months behind schedule, and <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has balked at the thought of paying more than $ 500 million apiece for 132 bombers. Shrouded in secrecy for 10 years, <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> last month began an intensive campaign to surmount stealth foes. The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> wants $ 4.7 billion for the bomber in the coming fiscal year, and it may need $ 8 billion in each of the three years of peak production, 1992 to 1994.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SchoolClosings     08-26 0199</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-School Closings,0205</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Rules Boston Can Close Five Schools</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state appeals court ruled Friday that five <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> public schools at the heart of a fierce dispute over budget-cutting can be closed. Schools Superintendent <PERSON> Laval </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the five schools will be closed as planned and affected parents will receive new school assignments for their children. On July 25, the city's school committee voted to close the schools to meet Mayor <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>'s $ 362 million target budget and to ease a projected $ 2.6 million deficit going into the school year. The three-judge <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> panel ruled that the school committee's vote was valid, even though it erred when a required public hearing was delayed until Aug. 7. Parents who had fought the closings said they did not expect to appeal Friday's decision, which overturned a <LOCATION> Suffolk </LOCATION> Superior Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roseman </PERSON>'s decision Tuesday to block the closing plan. <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> member <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Cappucci </PERSON> said he preferred saving money by closing the schools rather than putting special programs like athletics `` on the chopping block.'' `` I would rather close buildings than programs,'' said <PERSON> Cappucci </PERSON>. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said the committee has made $ 3 million in administrative staff cuts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     08-26 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 11; 19; 24; 25; 38.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0208EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     08-26 0082</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0089</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 07; 11; 19; 24; 25; 38.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0166.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 07; 15; 19; 20; 26; 30.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 11; 12; 24; 38; 40; 41. Bonus: 48105.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 02; 14; 18; 20; 39; 46. Supplementary 16.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0225.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 1-1-1; 2-6-5-3; 2-0-7-6-2; 6-6-6-3-4-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Florida-Crackdown 1stLd-Writethru a0715 08-26 0337</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Florida-Crackdown, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0715,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hundreds Arrested In Second Statewide Anti-Crack Push</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 4 grafs to UPDATE with arrest, seizure totals; picks
up 5th graf: `The 48-hour ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK REYNA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s second sweep of drug users and dealers netted more than 1,400 arrests by Friday evening as authorities combined reverse sting and `` Trojan Horse'' operations with search warrants and highway surveillance. `` I think the idea is to just get as much crack off the street as we can, and to once again send a message to people that are buying and selling crack that it's not going to be tolerated,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Liljedal </PERSON>, spokesman for the <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's office. By 11:00 p.m. Friday, the roundup produced 6,683 crack cocaine rocks, 2.6 pounds of cocaine powder, 10.44 pounds of marijuana, 52 firearms, 209 vehicles and $ 54,667 in cash. A total of 1,465 arrests had been made by Friday evening in the operation, staffed by an estimated 1,200 officers in all of the state's 67 counties. The 48-hour crackdown, dubbed Operation Rock Pile II, was launched at 12:01 a.m. Thursday and was coordinated by the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriffs </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. A total of 2,076 arrests were made in the first Operation Rock Pile, begun June 31. It also netted 3,510 crack cocaine rocks, 10 pounds of cocaine powder, 3 pounds of marijuana, 327 vehicles, 50 firearms and $ 55,107 cash. Crack, a derivative of cocaine, is sold in small chunks called rocks. `` The only thing that surprised us intially was what seemed to be an unsually high amount of marijuana,'' <PERSON> Liljedal </PERSON> said at the operation's command post in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>. In reverse stings, officers pose as drug sellers and bust customers. In Trojan Horse operations, several deputies ride hidden in the back of a truck and jump out to make arrests when the driver is offered crack for sale by street corner dealers. `` Nothing seems to deter these people when they're looking for crack or looking to sell it,'' said <PERSON> Liljedal </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0055EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SnowmobileShooting     08-26 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Snowmobile Shooting,0417</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cameron Kocher, 10, Arraigned On Homicide Charge</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAN BLAKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STROUDSBURG, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 10-year-old boy pleaded innocent Friday to adult charges of criminal homicide in the March shooting of a 7-year-old girl who was riding a snowmobile in a lot adjacent to his home. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> <PERSON> Kocher </PERSON> was 9 years old when, police said, he loaded his father's .35 - caliber rifle, pointed it out his parent's bedroom window and shot <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> of <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> in the He has been free on $ 50,000 bail. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> stood silently next to his attorney as Monroe County Judge <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Vican </PERSON>, addressing the boy as `` Mr. <PERSON> Kocher </PERSON>,'' explained the charges of criminal homicide, aggravated assault and recklessly endangerment. Defense attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON> signed documents indicating <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON>'s plea while the boy looked on, and told the judge he had instructed the boy to stay quiet. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> stood before the judge with his arms folded, occasionally looking at the ceiling and let out a heavy sigh as he turned to his parents after the proceedings ended. <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> was riding on the back of a snowmobile March 6 in <LOCATION> Kresgeville </LOCATION> with her friend and <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON>'s next-door neighbor, <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ratti </PERSON>, 13, when she was shot. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> was arrested two days later after police found the rifle with a telescopic sight, a cut on the boy's forehead and blood splattered in the room. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> said the rifle cut him when its recoil jammed the scope's eyepiece into his face. In June, <PERSON> Vican </PERSON> refused to transfer <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON>'s case to juvenile court, saying the shooting was deliberate. <PERSON> Vican </PERSON>'s decision followed four days of testimony from psychologists hired by the Kochers and the state. <PERSON> Vican </PERSON> wrote in June that all four psychotherapists who examined <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> agreed he did not have any mental or emotional problems at the time of the shooting. The psychologists disagreed, however, on whether <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> could understand the proceedings and participate in his defense. The also disagreed on whether he could form the intent to kill. <PERSON> Cameron </PERSON> faced a pre-arraignment shortly after his arrest in March, when bail was set at $ 50,000. He has been free on bond since then. Assistant District Attorney <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Pazuhanich </PERSON> said in an interview he has ruled out seeking the death penalty. He said if the boy is convicted, punishment could range from probation in conjunction with psychiatric treatment, to life imprisonment. The defense has 30 days to file pre-trial motions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Colombia-DrugLords     08-26 0601</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Colombia-Drug Lords,0619</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Medieval-Style Castle Shows Drug Lords' Fast-Lane Philosophy</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Colombia, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHIA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Why waltz when you can rock' n' roll?'' wrote a visitor in the guest book at the medieval-style castle of reputed cocaine trafficker <PERSON> Camilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>. The question reflects the fast-lane philosophy obviously embraced by <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s wealthy drug lords, and was revealed in the public confiscation of hundreds of their properties nationwide in an anti-narcotics crackdown. The sandstone castle, ringed by formal gardens, dominates a 200-acre compound of 10 buildings, a dozen thoroughbred horses as well as goats, ducks, dogs and even a couple of flamingos. Visible from a nearby highway, it has long been a landmark in <LOCATION> Chia </LOCATION>, a suburb 13 miles north of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. It was seized by the army this week, and shown off to reporters on Friday. European and Oriential antiques filled the castle's richly appointed rooms, lined with paintings, statues and ceramic figurines. Beds were framed with crystal and bronze, or four towering posters with marble bedside tables filled with electronics to open and shut doors and control video equipment. A guest book provided a peek at the peculiar variety of people who visited the estate. It is just one of many believed to have been owned by <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>, even though he is considered a kind of second-string smuggler, lacking the household-name stature of reputed cartel bosses such as <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jorge </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochoa </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON>. The visitor who endorsed rock' n' roll signed his message, apparently in jest, `` M-19 power.'' M-19 is the name accorded to a leftist guerrilla group operating in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, although the traffickers are much more closely associated with right-wing death squads. Another visitor, calling himself <PERSON> Mad </PERSON> <PERSON> Max </PERSON>, wrote: `` Living by chance, loving by choice and killing by profession.'' An Oct. 10, 1988, visitor named <PERSON> Tuti </PERSON> wrote in a feminine hand: `` Happy birthday. Tomorrow they'll kill me and it'll be your fault.'' Many women left their phone numbers after their signatures. <PERSON> Margarita </PERSON> <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON>, identified by army officials on the estate as <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON>'s sister, was much more solemn: `` May God and the Virgin bless all of this and those who inhabit it.'' The book also was signed by two men who identified themselves as local police station commanders, two army lieutenants and an army captain. Two local mayors also signed, one of them declaring, `` Few people can truly appreciate the history of this property.'' A group of women from several embassies, including <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> signed the book, as did a tour from a religious society. Next door to the estate is a religious boarding school run by nuns. In a garage and sprawling servants' quarters attached to the castle were two new Mercedes automobiles, also confiscated. There were also stables, where an office wall was lined with ribbons and trophies; an indoor swimming pool and gym, tennis courts, horse exercise trails and a modern thatch-roofed cottage of many rooms. There was a chapel as well, dedicated to <PERSON> St. </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Assisi </LOCATION>, with stained glass windows, antique religious statues and pews for about 30 people. Studiously ignoring the dozens of soldiers who guarded the place were 10 groundskeepers who watered the well-kept lawns and acres of gardens, trimmed the hundreds of yards of hedges and tended to the animals. They gave contradicting statements about <PERSON> Zapata </PERSON> <PERSON> Vasquez </PERSON>: he never came to stay, he came regularly, he just left a couple of weeks ago. They all agreed on one thing: they were underpaid, receiving the minimum legal wage _ about $ 80 a month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Austria-Refugees Bjt   08-26 0714</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Austria-Refugees, Bjt,0742</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Europeans Get Help, but Pose Problems for Austria</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TEDDIE WEYR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOERBISCH, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hospitality extended for 40 years by this haven for Soviet bloc refugees is being strained as more East Europeans take advantage of reforms and emigrate to the West. While East Germans flooding across the Austro-Hungarian border this summer have enjoyed heartfelt welcomes, other East European refugees find state support withering away. Women in the border town of <LOCATION> Moerbisch </LOCATION> have spent days sorting old clothes, cooking and giving hugs to exhausted East Germans who stumble in after a grueling journey to freedom through the borderland brush. `` You just have to help. Anyone with a sense of humanity has to,'' said one woman, her eyes filling with tears as she surveyed the large hall where tables were piled high with clothes and dazed East Germans sat over sausages and bread. `` I remember in 1956, my husband drove down to the border day and night with his truck to pick up the refugees,'' she said on condition of anonymity, recalling the mass exodus of Hungarians after Soviet tanks crushed <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s anti-Stalinist uprising. In 1968, <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> sheltered streams of Czechoslovaks after other <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact countries crushed the `` Prague Spring'' reforms. And when martial law was declared in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> in 1981, at least 35,000 Poles sought asylum here. <PERSON> Ilse </PERSON> <PERSON> Tremmel </PERSON>, chief organizer of <PERSON> Moerbisch </PERSON>'s relief program, is full of energy, seeing that volunteers get rest and giving a mother's firm hug to a 17-year-old boy who left his childhood and his parents on the other side of the East-West divide. `` The help has come from everywhere,'' she says. `` Private individuals, companies, stores. Everyone is helping.'' The East Germans spend only days in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> before going to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. But thousands of Poles and Hungarians want to remain, and because of that they feel less welcome. Their asylum applications now are rejected on grounds they are not politically persecuted but seek only to improve their economic situation. Refugee <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mojzer </PERSON> does n't see the distinction. `` You ca n't separate the two,'' he says `` If the -LRB- communist -RRB- party regulates everything, then you ca n't live or work freely.'' Many Austrians believe the Hungarians and Poles sponge off the state, receiving free room and board plus meager monthly allowances while they wait years for applications to be processed. But in July and August, 3,800 Hungarians and Poles stopped receiving the allowances and were turned out of government-rented hotels and boarding houses. They came to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> before May 1988, when the Austrian government began rejecting most asylum applications. Interior Minister <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Loeschnak </PERSON>, under fire from left-wingers who argue this violates <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s policy of sheltering all refugees, insisted the Poles and Hungarians were informed months in advance. But many said they were given only days' notice. About 800 jobs and language training for some Poles and Hungarians was arranged to end the furor. But <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, and the West in general, still faces the dilemma of absorbing tens of thousands of East Europeans expected to cross increasingly open borders. <PERSON> Pius </PERSON> <PERSON> Strobl </PERSON>, a leader of the small opposition Green-Alternative party, noted that 10 percent of <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s population of 7.4 million are former refugees. <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>'s declining population should encourage authorities to integrate new arrivals who are anxious to work, he said. Two million refugees have come here since World War II ended and 613,000 remain, officials say. Last year, 16,000 applications for asylum were submitted, double the number for 1986. Hungarians who refuse to return home and depend on charitable organizations complain they are trapped in a Catch-22 situation _ needing a work permit to secure a residence permit, and a permanent place of residence to acquire a work permit. `` Who can guarantee that the reforms in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> will continue,'' asked <PERSON> Ferenc </PERSON> <PERSON> Briski </PERSON>, who came to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in 1987. <PERSON> Briski </PERSON>'s family is among several that found lodging in eastern <LOCATION> Burgenland </LOCATION> province with help from the Greens and charity groups. Some live without electricity or heating. Hungarian-born <PERSON> Wilma </PERSON> <PERSON> Csoknyai </PERSON> recalls when she came to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> after World War II and how impressed she was with the hospitality. `` After the war, when nobody had anything, it was apparently easier to be a refugee,'' she said. `` Now people ca n't imagine how it is to have nothing.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-26 0863</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> took his crusade to help the homeless to <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>'s Walk of Fame while accepting a star in his honor there. `` The sidewalks of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> are known all over the world as the Walk of Fame, but many sidewalks in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> could be known a the ` Walk of Shame' because of the 4 million homeless people residing on them full time,'' <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> said Friday. In his role as honorary mayor of <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION>, the 49-year-old <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> recently declared the wealthy beach community a sanctuary for the homeless. The actor, flanked by his wife, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON>, and sons <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Estevez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON>, asked the crowd to pray with him for 400,000 homeless children. <PERSON> Sheen </PERSON> made his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stage debut in 1959 in `` The Connection'' and his movies include `` Apocalypse Now,'' and `` Wall Street.'' He was the 1,897 th recipient of the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> star
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BETHLEHEM, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, who has led the Solidarity movement to form the first non-Communist government in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> since just after World War II, forgot to tell his son his new telephone number. <PERSON> Lech </PERSON>'s 17-year-old son, <PERSON> Slawek </PERSON>, who has been touring the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> with a polka band for two months, tried to call his father Thursday but found the number no longer functioned because of changes in the Polish phone service. <PERSON> Slawek </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> said he did n't have his father's new number. The younger <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, who is returning to <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> on Monday to finish his last year of high school, said he thought his father would be more effective heading Solidarity than being prime minister. <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazoviecki </PERSON>, a longtime Solidarity activist, was selected by <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> to head the government and was elected by the assembly as prime minister Thursday. <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> has said he preferred to remain as Solidarity's chief rather than taking the reins of government.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former first lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be honorary chairwoman for the 3rd annual Royal Chase steeplechase, organizers of the event said. But Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> probably will not attend the Nov. 3 event, its chairwoman <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Peterson </PERSON> said this week. Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>, who attended the previous two chases and won a race in last year's event, also has said she will be unable to attend Proceeds from the event will benefit <ORGANIZATION> Recovery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Residence </ORGANIZATION>, a center for drug and alcohol treatment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Before he got into hard rock, The Who's <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Daltry </PERSON> worked on heavy metal _ at a metalworking factory. And <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> may have met `` Maybellene'' when he did her hair. <PERSON> Daltry </PERSON>'s experience as a metalworker and <PERSON> Berry </PERSON>'s as a hairdresser are some of the humble beginnings portrayed in a Labor Day weekend broadcast of `` Cruisin' <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' a <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> radio program featuring disc jockey <PERSON> Cousin </PERSON> <PERSON> Brucie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> used to dig graves for a living, and <PERSON> Chubby </PERSON> <PERSON> Checker </PERSON> was once a chicken plucker, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement promoting the program. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> -LRB- of the <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> Five -RRB- may have learned his stage acrobatics as a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> stuntman. The Troggs were bricklayers before they wrote `` Wild Thing,'' and <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuinn </PERSON> of The Byrds pumped gas. Some of the other performers featured in the Labor Day weekend program are former disc jockey Sly Stone, <PERSON> Donovan </PERSON> -LRB- once a waiter -RRB-, Fats Domino -LRB- who worked in a bed spring factory -RRB- and former truck driver <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> of the pop group <PERSON> Duran </PERSON> <PERSON> Duran </PERSON> said his new baby daughter has his eyes, but an awful voice. The 6-pound, 5-ounce girl born Friday to <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Yasmin </PERSON>, has the mother's legs, nose and mouth, <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON> said. `` Thank God everything went well at the birth of our little girl. We never knew nine months could take so long,'' he said. <PERSON> Yasmin </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Bon </PERSON>, a 24-year-old fashion model, has suffered two miscarriages. The singer was with his wife when she gave birth at a private clinic in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. A friend said: `` It was a completely natural birth and the couple are absolutely delighted.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, the second son of Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and Empress <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON>, has decided to marry the 22-year-old daughter of a university professor, according to news reports today. The reports, quoting palace and government officials it did not name, followed months of speculation that the prince and <PERSON> Kiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawashima </PERSON>, a graduate student at <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Gakushuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, were making marriage plans. The reports were carried by the mass-circulation <ORGANIZATION> Asahi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and on the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s morning news <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, 23, is a student of zoology at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, and is home in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for a short vacation. He is to return to <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> Sept. 20. <PERSON> Aya </PERSON> is second in line to the throne, which his father assumed Jan. 7 after the death of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. The engagement must still be approved by the 10-member <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, headed by Prime Minister <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>. Plans for <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>'s marriage could be delayed because his elder brother, Crown Prince <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>, has yet to settle on a bride. <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>, 29, reportedly hopes to marry within the next year or so.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-NewtonKilled 3rdLd-Writethru a0768 08-26 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Newton Killed, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0768,0807</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest Suspect in Newton Killing</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 12 grafs to UPDATE with ballistic tests pending on
9mm pistol; additional quote on alleged motive; arraignment set for Tuesday;
CORRECTS spelling of Guerrilla; background on Robinson's acquaintance with
Newton; picks up 9th graf pvs: `Police said Newton crossed ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER McNULTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man described by police as a drug dealer was arrested for investigation of murder in the death of <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>, but claimed self-defense in killing the Black Panther founder, police said Friday. <PERSON> Tyrone </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, 25, of <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> was arrested on a weapons charge around 7 p.m. Tuesday, hours after <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s predawn murder on a west <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> sidewalk, and Investigators believe they recovered the 9mm pistol used in <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>'s killing, police said, but ballistics tests are still pending. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> `` considered the murder a means to advance'' in the Black Guerrilla Family, a narcotics distribution gang, said Sgt. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> at a early evening news conference at the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION>. `` He wanted to be a high-mucky-muck,'' <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said later in an interview. `` He was a foot soldier and he wanted to be a shot caller. He figured we already knew. We felt we had him and he new it.'' The Black Guerrilla Family is a prison-based gang that operates in the state's maximum-security prisons, including <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> served time, authorities said. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, currently on parole for a robbery conviction, admitted to the killing early Friday and is scheduled for arraignment Tuesday, <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> have known each other for two years. <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> argued with <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> over a cocaine deal and that <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> then shot the 47-year-old former leader of the black militancy movement in the 1960s. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> contended <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> pulled a gun when the two met at a street corner in the drug-torn neighborhood, but investigators said they found no evidence <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> had been armed. The killing occurred in a neighborhood where <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>, as minister of defense for the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panthers </ORGANIZATION>, once tried to set up social programs to help destitue blacks. Police said <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> told them <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> demanded drugs and that he refused to sell them to him. Police said the two argued for about a minute. Police said <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> had `` crossed'' the Black Guerilla Family several times in the past. Investigators believe <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> stole drugs from the gang, including an instance earlier this summer when, <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said, he was robbed by <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> of 14 crack cocaine rocks valued at $ 160. <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said a man accompanying <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> witnessed the shooting, but police did not divulge whether the man, arrested Friday for investigation of auto theft, backed up <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s claim of self-defense. Police said they had located several other witnesses who disputed <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>'s account of the killing. There have been no other arrests in the case, <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> was arrested Tuesday for investigation of felony possession of a firearm about a block from the crime scene. He was questioned about <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s murder, but was not considered a prime suspect until Thursday. Two other men were arrested at the same time on weapons violations, but are not considered suspects in the case, <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON> said. Police denied a report published Thursday that three men had been linked to the killing, but acknowledged for the first time that the men were arrested on weapons charges one block from where <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> was slain about 12 hours earlier. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s slaying prompted a noontime protest march Friday that started in the neighborhood where he was slain. About 40 members of <ORGANIZATION> Uhuru </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> waved banners, carried placards with his photo and chanted, `` Who killed <PERSON> Huey </PERSON>? Do n't you tell no lie, it was the government, the government, the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> infiltration of the <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Panther </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> had contributed to its gradual disintegration as the group, founded more than 20 years ago, drifted from operating ghetto social programs into violence and its members were killed. Officials in the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> office did not immediately return a telephone message Friday afternoon. The protesters marched two miles to City Hall and the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Courthouse </LOCATION>, where supporters had chanted `` Free Huey'' during <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>'s 1968 trial for the death of an <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> police officer. Marchers refused to speak to reporters, blaming them for media accounts that included descriptions of <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION> as a gangster. Family members continued to prepare for <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s funeral Monday in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. Organizers expect up to 2,000 mourners, including Black Panther co-founder <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Seale </PERSON>. `` This is for members of the community and Panthers and neighborhood supporters,'' said <PERSON> Barbarette </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>, the victim's sister-in-law `` People who knew <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> in the past and present need to express some things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Voyager-Quayle     08-26 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voyager-Quayle,0438</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quayle Signals Interest in Space Program With Visit to NASA Lab</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Voyager-Neptune, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> visited <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION>'s Jet Propulsion Laboratory to congratulate Voyager scientists and underscore his new interest in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space program `` I am exceedingly delighted to be here on this very historic day for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s space program,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told a receptive crowd of perhaps 1,000 laboratory employees. The crowd cheered as <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said that unmanned missions _ the <ORGANIZATION> Jet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Propulsion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>'s specialty _ will continue to be an important part of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> space program. `` We are seeing a beginning of a new era where we'll see a recommitment to space,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said, echoing comments he has made in recent months as he works hard to adopt the space program as his issue. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s visit Friday morning followed Voyager 2's close encounter with <LOCATION> Neptune </LOCATION> that capped a 12-year, 4.4 billion-mile flight that took the two Voyager spacecraft to Jupiter in 1979, <ORGANIZATION> Saturn </ORGANIZATION> in 1980 and 1981, and Uranus in 1986. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who had shown little interest in the space program before becoming vice president, has now seized upon it as an issue he can use to improve his political fortunes. `` It's a great opportunity for him, because ordinarily vice presidents have limited duties,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Beckwith </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s press secretary The issue was handed to <LOCATION> Quayle </LOCATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which established the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> at the end of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration and designated the vice president as its head. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> is hoping to convince <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the public that expenditures on space are worthwhile, even in the face of continuing federal budget deficits. On July 20, the 20-year anniversary of the landing of a man on the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called for the permanent settlement of space, by first returning to the <LOCATION> moon </LOCATION> and then sending a manned mission to <LOCATION> Mars </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> charged <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, as head of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, with developing a plan to carry out those goals. The plan is supposed to be delivered to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in October. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s visit to the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, which included a briefing with laboratory officials and a tour of the Voyager control center, was patterned after a successful visit last month to the General Dynamics Space systems division is <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> gave the same stump speech in both places, contending that space exploration furthers scientific understanding, provides jobs, leads to new technology and inspires young people to seek careers in science or engineering.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-26 0335</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0349</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EAST LANSING, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Cara </PERSON> and <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> were excited about getting a new baby brother, but sitting in a hospital waiting for him to come was n't a fun way to spend their birthday. A little assurance from <PERSON> Dad </PERSON> helped ease the conflict of having a third <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> born Aug. 22. `` We've always been careful about keeping the birthdays individual,'' said the children's father, <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>. `` From now on, it'll be three cakes at our house every August 22nd.'' <PERSON> Cara </PERSON> turned 10 Tuesday and <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> turned 7. And <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> was born. `` I've been taking a lot of ribbing at work,'' their father said. `` They're asking me if we're going for a world record.'' To do that, <PERSON> Rod </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON>, will have to come up with three more children born on Aug. 22. The Guinness Book of World Records, under the category `` Coincidental Birth Dates,'' reports that <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummins </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Clintwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, gave birth to five children on five different Feb. 20ths from 1952 through 1966. Still, the odds against coming up with a triple birthday, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> statistician, are 100,000 to one. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> came three days late and weighed 9 -LCB- pounds.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>GLEN ELLYN, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Now, for the parents with everything _ Rent-A-Stork. The $ 50, 6-foot wooden bird can perch outside the front door with a pink or blue bundle in its beak _ just the thing to announce a new birth to your neighbors. Rent-A-Stork, along with computerized fairy tales, children's compact discs and diaper delivery services that also deliver meals, was among about 75 exhibits at the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baby </LOCATION> and Kids Expo this week <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Doessel </PERSON> of <PERSON> Diane </PERSON>'s Personalized Children's Books was printing up stories by computer on the spot, exchanging the names of children who stepped up to her exhibit booth for those of the stories' heroes. `` Kids love to be the star of their own stories,'' she said. The books cost $ 8.95.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0247EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush Bjt   08-26 0694</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Urges Other Nations to Support Colombia</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XKNE1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, appealing to other nations to rally behind Colombian officials `` on the front line of the war against drugs,'' is sending President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>'s government a $ 65 million package to combat narcotics trafficking The aid announced Friday by the summer <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> consists primarily of aircraft _ mostly helicopters _ and a variety of other equipment and supplies, but no <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops. However, presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said some <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> advisers would be sent to show Colombians how to use and maintain the equipment. He said they would number fewer than `` dozens'' but did not have a precise figure. `` We will provide only material support and training,'' the vacationing president said in a statement. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has complete confidence in the capability of the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> police and military to deal with this situation. `` It is time for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other countries of the world to stand with President <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> during his courageous challenge to these insidious forces that threaten the very fabric of Colombian society.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vowed `` to assist the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> officials who are on the front line of the war against drugs.'' <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> has been rocked by recent drug-related violence, including the assassination last week of the leading presidential candidate and this week's bombings of homes and offices of government and political leaders. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said eight <PERSON> Huey </PERSON> transport helicopters would be sent to <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> next week, and another 12 would be sent later along with a <ORGANIZATION> Blackhawk </ORGANIZATION> helicopter for medical evacuation. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> C-5 transport plane brought in two Bell 212 helicopters Friday that were delivered to Colombian authorities. The helicopters, which add to six of the same type Colombian police already had, represent `` an immediate, tangible response of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government to President <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>'s stepped-up war on the narcotics traffic,'' the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the eight Hueys would be used mainly `` for carrying troops and policemen into rural areas'' and for locating drug activity. In addition, another 20 helicopters previously bought by <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, and not part of the new package, will also be shipped over the next few months, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. The package includes another $ 8.6 million for light aircraft, but the type and number has yet to be determined, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. Also in the package are machine guns and other small arms, grenade launchers, mortars, aircraft ammunition, radios, jeeps, ambulances, field gear, anti-tank weapons, field trucks, utility boats, 18-man `` assault boats'' that carry machine guns, medical supplies, tools and spare parts. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s statement reiterated the administration's vow to work with Colombian legal officials in extraditing drug traffickers wanted in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the overall package `` represents a conclusion that we have a responsibility and an interest in helping them to the maximum degree possible.'' The aircraft and supplies will help <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> `` launch a major effort'' against the drug cartel, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. The money comes from a special foreign aid fund and is separate from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s new $ 8 billion anti-drug program to be unveiled by the president in a nationally televised address Sept. 5. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the drug at plan will also contain additional funds for <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and other Latin American countries. The money is also separate from a $ 2 million program announced earlier in the week to help <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> set up security for public officials. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will meet with Cabinet members involved in drug policy and drug-policy coordinator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> here next week. The president is midway through a three-week vacation that runs through Labor Day. Evangelist <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> was spending the weekend with the first family. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Friday followed what has been his usual pattern of athletic activities, including golf, boating and horseshoes. At one point, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ran his 28-foot speedboat, <ORGANIZATION> Fidelity </ORGANIZATION>, into a hard submerged object _ either a rock or piece of wood _ forcing him to abandon a morning of boating. However, the mishap, which damaged the housing of one of his propellers, was quickly repaired by a local marina and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was back on the water by late afternoon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FemaleCondom Bjt   08-26 0541</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Female Condom, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Company Urges Quick Approval of Claimed AIDS Protection Device</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> is beginning to draw up guidelines to market a female condom, which its manufacturer says can help protect women from the AIDS virus and other sexually transmitted diseases. <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollard </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> member of the panel that heard testimony on the device Friday, estimated that it will take <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmacal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> at least 18 months to conduct the study, receive <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> approval and market the female condom. `` It will take us quite a while to just get the study going,'' <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, company said after the hearing. `` The results -LRB- of the hearing -RRB- are about as good as we could expect.'' <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON>, in a presentation at the hearing, said the female condom is the only method that a woman can herself control to protect against infection from the AIDS virus and from other sexually transmitted diseases. `` Today, if a woman asks a man to wear the male condom and he says no, her choices are to take the risk or to get out of bed,'' <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> told the panel. `` A difficult decision in the heat of the moment.'' The device displayed by <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> resembled a sock made of polyurethane, a tough, clear, flexible plastic. There are soft, flexible rings at both ends. <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> said the ring at the closed end is to aid insertion. When properly used, she said, a sheath barrier is created within the vagina. The ring at the open end of the device remains outside and protects the labia. The female condom would cost about $ 1.50, <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> said, and is designed for one use. <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> Pharmacal proposed to market the condom solely as a device to protect against the spread of sexually transmitted diseases. But the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> advisory panel decided that before receiving approval such a barrier device should be tested on an unspecified number of women for long enough to prove that it is at least as effective as the male condom as a contraceptive. The panel concluded that there was no ethical way to test the female condom for its ability to protect against disease, but that investigating how well it prevents pregnancy would act as a `` surrogate'' test for how well it prevents disease. Requiring tests against disease directly is unethical, the panel said, because it would require exposing some women to the risk of sexually transmitted diseases. Proposed guidelines were revised during the hearing and panel chairwoman Dr. <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Connell </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> staff will draw up formal regulations. <PERSON> Connell </PERSON> said the advisory panel would meet again to consider the final guidelines, but she said no date has been set. In her presentation, <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> asked that the condom be approved for marketing only as a disease-prevention device, and medical experts from <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> and from private medical organizations spoke in favor of this approach. <PERSON> Leeper </PERSON> said the female condom, which the company is calling WPC-333, has been successfully tested on research equipment at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> and is less likely to fail than the male condom.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pentagon-Colombia     08-26 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pentagon-Colombia,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Equipment Suited For Colombia's Drug War</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The helicopters, weapons and supplies the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military is providing <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> will help that nation take its anti-drug battle into the remote regions where drug traffickers hide. `` Our military equipment is well-suited for that purpose. It is durable and designed to operate in rough terrain,'' Army Maj. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Super </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said Friday. While the exact numbers and types of equipment have not been completely worked out, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has decided to send some $ 65 million worth of material to help stem the flow of illegal drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and help <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> battle drug dealers. No <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> combat personnel will be sent to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, officials stressed, but a small number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> advisers will train Colombians in the use of the equipment. There are 112 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government employees in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, including 36 military personnel, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said. The initial $ 20 million package <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has designated for <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> includes some of the rough-and-tumble type of equipment that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces used in the jungles of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, such as the eight UH-1 `` Huey'' troop transport helicopters. The choppers, which also may be used for ground surveillance, can be modified to carry two .50 - caliber machine `` They are fast, versatile and reliable, and can be used to great effect to speed up transportation when the roads are bad,'' <PERSON> Super </PERSON> said of the choppers. Under past Foreign Military Sales agreements, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has sold <ORGANIZATION> Colombia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Huey </ORGANIZATION> choppers, as well as the updated Blackhawk version, which must be flown by Colombian pilots. The Colombians can put most of the transportation, communications and small weapons to work if they carry out raids against the ranch headquarters and cocaine processing plants scattered about that country's rough, mountainous territory. Included in the first package destined for <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> are machine guns, mortars, ammunition, 4-wheel drive vehicles, ambulances, communications equipment and anti-tank guns, said <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. The anti-tank weapons could be used to blow up entire buildings, if necessary. The Colombians are also in line to get 12 more Hueys, a Blackhawk medical evacuation helicopter, assault boats, trucks, medical supplies and airplanes, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. Although he did not identify which type of fixed-wing aircraft might be sent the Colombians, a good candidate would be an A-37, a small two-person attack jet that can carry small rockets or bombs. The Colombians already have 18 similar aircraft in their own air force and have pilots familiar with such a craft. The Blackhawk helicopter, which can be transformed into a medical evacuation chopper, is the larger, modernized version of the older <PERSON> Huey </PERSON>, and can carry twice the payload. Super noted the type of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trainers that will be sent to help will depend on the final type of equipment that is shipped to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. `` They may need help maintaining the equipment _ with mechanics _ or they may request training in tactics, map reading, or first aid _ any number of things that we could provide,'' <PERSON> Super </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0301EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LeningradLibrary     08-26 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Leningrad Library,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>For release at noon EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Library of Congress to Combat Damage in Leningrad's Great Collection</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> said today it has received $ 135,000 to help restore fire - and water-damaged books in a <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> institution where one of the worst library disasters in history occurred The gift from Reader's Digest will help experts counter the damage at the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION>, whose collection of 20 million books, manuscripts and periodicals was begun in 1714 by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> the Great. Four million books were damaged or destroyed in a 19-hour fire in February 1988. The Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is a leader in developing techniques to rescue books threatened by decay or disaster. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Billington </PERSON>, librarian of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and a <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> expert, went to <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> after the fire to assess the damage and arranged for a protocol, signed by the two institutions, agreeing to preserve damaged materials and replace destroyed books. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Waters </PERSON>, a Library of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> expert on the conservation of damaged book collections, went to <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> within six weeks of the fire. <PERSON> Billington </PERSON> welcomed the gift, saying in a statement that it underscored the principle that library collections `` are truly international resources for humanity which all of us must support whenever one of them is threatened by destruction.'' The library said the Reader's Digest grant will finance equipment, supplies and technical consultation to return to use many of the 200,000 rare volumes that were frozen in an effort to arrest deterioration after the fire. The <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> institution is one of the world's largest research libraries, although not nearly as large as the <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which holds 86 million items. The Academy Library is a major exchange partner for most <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research libraries that collect Russian and Soviet materials. Every year, several hundred <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> specialists in <LOCATION> Russians </LOCATION> affairs visit there to do research. A few months after the fire, Soviet historian and cultural activist <PERSON> Dmitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Likhachev </PERSON> said the disaster could have been prevented if officials had heeded warnings about the dilapidated condition of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s most prestigious book collections. He said it pained him to see how rare books and art treasures that were spirited away by residents of <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> to protect them from Nazis who occupied the city in World War II had been destroyed through negligence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0303EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Congressman-Prostitute Bjt   08-26 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congressman-Prostitute, Bjt,0715</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barney Frank Says Disclosure He Hired Prostitute Won't Cripple Career</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BX1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL BEEGAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEWTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> says his political career is intact but he made a big mistake in hiring a paroled male prostitute to do personal chores at his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> home. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, who disclosed his homosexuality in May 1987, befriended and employed the man four years ago after paying him for sex. The <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat fired his employee in August 1987 when he suspected the man was selling sex from <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s apartment. `` Certainly if I were a voter, I would not ask my advice on how to rehabilitate someone,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, 49, said during a news conference Friday at his office in this <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> suburb. `` I think I have had much better judgment in my public life.'' The state <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> called on <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> to resign, but the congressman, up for re-election in 1990, said the incident would not affect his political career or plans. `` I do n't think I'm going to be heavily penalized by the voters for being suckered by a guy I was trying to help,'' he said. Some of his colleagues agreed. House Speaker <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, a Democrat, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> `` has provided outstanding service to his constituency and the nation, and I am absolutely confident he will continue to do so long after this matter has been forgotten.'' The only other member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to acknowledge being homosexual, Rep. <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, D-Mass., easily won re-election after being censured by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1983 for an affair 10 years earlier with a 17-year-old House page After revealing his homosexuality, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> won election to his fifth term in 1988 with 70 percent of the vote in the state's 4th District, which encompasses some <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> suburbs and parts of southeastern <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>. `` Barney <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> is on virtually everyone's list as one of the 10 ablest members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Studds </PERSON> said. `` I suspect he will remain on that list for a very long time to come.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>'s hiring of the male prostitute was first detailed in Friday's editions of The <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Times. The newspaper said the man was named <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said his real name is <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>. No telephone number was listed for a <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> or its suburbs. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said he met the man in 1985, and estimated his age at 26 or 27. The congressman admitted paying for sex with the man once, but said the relationship quickly became one of friendship. He said he paid <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> to do household chores, driving and other errands from his own money, not congressional or campaign funds. The total compensation amounted to about $ 20,000 a year, including cash and payment of lawyer and other bills. In an interview on <ORGANIZATION> WUSA-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, a man identifying himself as <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> repeated charges that <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> was aware of the sexual activities at the apartment. `` He knew what was taking place. He knew there were clients coming to his house. As long as the clients were n't there when he was there, that was no problem,'' <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> called the man's allegations that he was aware of the activity `` absolutely untrue.'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Tennant </PERSON>, executive director of the state <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> should resign because there are laws against patronizing prostitutes. `` This is simply a question of a congressman who had the public's trust and violated this trust by engaging in illegal activity,'' <PERSON> Tennant </PERSON> said `` <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> revealed today that he paid for sex.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said his only other contact with <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON>, after the firing in August 1987, came in December of that year when <PERSON> Gobie </PERSON> called to say he was having problems and needed help. At the hourlong news conference, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> refused to answer most questions about his sex life. But he did say the temptation to pay for sex was `` one of the things that led me to acknowledge being gay. ... It was one of the reasons I was vulnerable to being preyed on.'' He told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> that he has now been in a monogamous relationship for about two years with `` a very sensible person and a steadying influence.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0304EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SoybeanCorner Bjt   08-26 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soybean Corner, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agency Sees No Conflict in CBOT Soybean Emergency; Senator Skeptical</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: RETRANSMITTING to add budget designator.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN M. DOYLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> says a report by federal regulators raises conflict-of-interest questions regarding the activities of <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> officials during last month's soybean emergency. The <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Futures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which oversees the nation's futures markets, said Friday that an initial review of the emergency liquidation in the soybean futures market found no examples of self-dealing. But Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, noted the report raised possible conflict-of-interest questions about several of the officials who voted for the forced reduction of holdings in July soybean futures contracts. `` The <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION> must question those <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> directors participating in the July soybean decision whose affiliated firms held net short positions in the July soybean contract in house or customer accounts,'' said <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt., in a statement issued by his office Futures contracts are agreements to deliver a quantity of goods at a specified price at a certain time in the future. `` Credibility is paramount for exchanges in carrying out their self-regulatory functions. The public will not tolerate self-dealing or conflict of interest by exchange directors or insiders,'' <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> said. The Board of Trade, the world's largest commodity exchange, issued an emergency order last month requiring traders to reduce their holdings in soybean futures contracts. That decision touched off wild swings in soybean prices and sparked sharp criticism by farm groups, and traders saw the value of their futures holdings drop. Those who had sold borrowed soybean futures on speculation the price would fall, in what's known as a short position, stood to gain from the emergency order because it resulted in a steep drop in soybean prices. The Board of Trade has said it took the action after consulting with the <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION>, because a subsidiary of Italian grain merchant <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finanziaria </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S.P.A. </ORGANIZATION>, failed to voluntarily reduce its large holdings in the July soybean market. <ORGANIZATION> CBOT </ORGANIZATION> officials have said the exchange was worried that soybean supplies were insufficient for meeting large holdings of contracts for July delivery of soybeans in the final days of trading in that contract. The July 11 order requiring traders to reduce their positions in the July soybean market to 1 million bushels was widely perceived as a move to prevent <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> from cornering the soybean market, which <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> has denied. <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> also has bitterly criticized the CBOT action. `` We continue to believe that is was totally unnecessary for the board to take its emergency action,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, an executive with <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> subsidiary. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Ferruzzi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> supports Sen. <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>'s call for further investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION> into the matter,'' said <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, also chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION>'s preliminary report was contained in a 36-page letter to <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON> from <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION> Chairwoman <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>. Among the preliminary findings, the <ORGANIZATION> CFTC </ORGANIZATION>'s review disclosed no <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> governing member appeared to trade for the purpose of profiting personally, or through an affiliated company, from prior knowledge of the July 11 order. `` Our position is that even though a firm held a position -LRB- in the July soybean market -RRB- a director would not be influenced,'' said <ORGANIZATION> BOT </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Oakes </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0306EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Watkins-Fernald     08-26 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Watkins-Fernald,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Watkins Balks at Judge's Request For Testimony in Nuclear Pollution
Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is balking at a request by a federal judge that he testify on what the government agreed to in settling a class-action lawsuit over pollution from a nuclear weapons plant. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> did n't explicitly say he would refuse to appear in the court of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>, but indicated he would try to avoid it. `` My lawyers tell me that it's not essential, that I am not bound by law to comply with that thing,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said in a meeting Friday with reporters in his office. `` It's very difficult for me to be put in that position _ to demand my presence under these circumstances.'' The suit was brought by 14,000 people who live near the <LOCATION> Fernald </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, weapons plant. The residents allege they suffered emotional distress and diminished property values as a result of uranium dust releases from the plant. They contend they still have the right to sue for contamination cleanup costs, but the department, which owns the plant, says the proposed settlement is intended to preclude any further suits over cleanup. The plant, known as the Feed Materials Production Center, is 18 miles from <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON>, who must approve the proposed settlement, said Wednesday he wanted <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to testify under oath on his understanding of what the settlement entailed. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Chesley </PERSON>, lawyer for the residents, said <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> was running the risk of being formally ordered to testify. `` Adm. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is picking a fight with the wrong judge,'' <PERSON> Chesley </PERSON> said. In a related matter, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said he would present to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> within two weeks a plan for restoring the nation's capability to produce a gas needed to make nuclear warheads. The plan will include a recommendation that three active but idled military reactors in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> be restarted and run for another 15 years to ensure a supply of tritium, a radioactive gas used to boost warheads' explosive power. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> provided no details of the plan, but he has said he would like the first of the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reactors, near <LOCATION> Aiken </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, to be operating by early next year. All three have been under repair for more than one year, leaving the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> with a diminishing stockpile of materials for warhead production. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> also said he would tell <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reactors should not be operated beyond 2005 because of uncertainty about aging problems. `` Not one of us would sign on a piece of paper that it's smart to take those aging reactors beyond that point,'' he said. `` There are just too many unknowns.'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should move quickly to approve the financing for development and construction of two new tritium-producing reactors _ one at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and one in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> _ to ensure a continued supply beyond the 1990s. The department has said the plants can be built in 10 years for $ 6.8 billion. `` The fragility of the antique reactors at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> is going to be hanging over our heads like the Sword of Damocles until the year 2005,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0307EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SevenWonders     08-26 0376</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Seven Wonders,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Seven Underwater Wonders of World' Are Named</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of marine experts says the `` seven underwater wonders of the world'' could be lost without a global effort to protect the world's oceans and seas. `` We're killing the oceans,'' said former astronaut <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>, one of a panel of experts who named the sites Friday to focus public attention on the world's underwater environment. <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Sammon </PERSON>, president of the sponsoring organization, CEDAM International, said the selection was the start of an educational campaign aimed at preserving `` the world's beautiful but very fragile marine environment.'' `` If a concerted effort is not undertaken soon to protect and preserve our underwater wonders, they _ like the classic Seven Wonders of the World _ could be lost forever through carelessness, negligence or deliberate mistreatment,'' he said. The seven underwater wonders, selected by the 14-member panel of marine scientists, conservationists and explorers, are: <PERSON> Palau </PERSON>, an island group in <LOCATION> Micronesia </LOCATION>; the northern <LOCATION> Red </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION>; the Great Barrier Reef of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>; the waters of the <LOCATION> Galapagos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> off the coast of <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Baikal </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>; the <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION> Barrier Reef; and the deep ocean vents in the middle of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> oceans. An honorable mention went to whales as one of the great living wonders of the seas. CEDAM International is a non-profit group of 1,000 mostly marine scientists and conservationists based at <LOCATION> Croton-on-Hudson </LOCATION>, N.Y. The educational campaign will include collecting data and publishing information packets about the seven sites, a documentary series, a touring exhibit of underwater photographs, school curricula on marine conservation and an art-quality photo book. <PERSON> Carpenter </PERSON>, an environmental consultant from <LOCATION> Vail </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, blamed the world's runaway population for the declining health of the oceans and marine life. `` We've got to stop population growth and we've got to eliminate our ignorance,'' he said. `` The ocean is a very delicate entity and people do n't realize that. Without healthy oceans, a healthy planet is impossible.'' The 13 other panelists included representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aquarium </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION>, the federal <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CSIRO </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s largest scientific and industrial research organization.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IvyLeagueTrial     08-26 0500</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ivy League Trial,0513</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ex-Harvard Student Sentenced for Armed Robberies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LYNN ELBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SANTA ANA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A young man from a poor, Hispanic neighborhood who went on to attend <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> was sentenced to 10 years in prison for six armed robberies committed during school breaks. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Razo </PERSON>, 22, was convicted in June of six robberies and attempting to escape police after his 1987 arrest in <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. He was found innocent of four other robberies. `` He's earned his way to <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>, but he also earned his way to prison,'' Deputy District Attorney <PERSON> Ravi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON> told the court before sentencing. `` Mr. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> needs to pay his dues to society now. Mr. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> needs to be punished for what he's done.'' <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> also faces trial in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, where he is charged with three counts of robbery and six of assault with a deadly weapon. `` I have not disregarded the good things I have learned about you, Mr. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Rheinheimer </PERSON> said before she sentenced <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> on Friday. `` This is not a happy sentencing for this court.'' Rheinheimer, who could have given him a maximum 15-year term, was asked by the defense to consider <PERSON> Razo </PERSON>'s achievements as a star athlete and scholar who gave time to charity. `` I do n't know how it is that a boy such as <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> stands before this court facing 15 years in state prison,'' said attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barnett </PERSON>. `` Perhaps the gap between the barrio of <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Habra </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> was just too wide for him to pass.'' But <PERSON> Rheinheimer </PERSON> said she could not ignore the fact the crimes were premeditated and occurred over a two-year period, showing what she called a `` pattern of conduct dangerous to society.'' Each of the 10 store robberies, committed between December 1985 and June 1987, occurred during school breaks while he attended <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> for two years. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> sat expressionless Friday as the sentence was read. His tearful parents refused to comment. `` What can we say?'' <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Barnett </PERSON> said he planned an appeal. He called the sentence too severe, but added, `` The judge gave her honest opinion of what the crimes were worth and what the defendant was worth.'' With credit for time served and for good behavior, <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> could be eligible for release in about three years, <PERSON> Mehta </PERSON> said outside court. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> will then face three years on parole. A $ 500 fine also was imposed. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> was a former high school football star, <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> `` Boy of the Year'' and outstanding student at <ORGANIZATION> Servite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Anaheim </LOCATION>. The prosecution's case relied heavily on a videotaped confession in which <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> recounted with vivid detail the crimes, each committed by a gunman wearing a ski mask. The holdups at fast-food restaurants, grocery and drug stores, netted the gunman $ 27,000. <PERSON> Razo </PERSON> later retracted the confession, saying he was in a drug-induced stupor. He claimed he was describing crimes actually committed by a friend.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0313EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AsianBases     08-26 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Asian Bases,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Schroeder Says Philippines Shouldn't Expect Large Sums of U.S. Aid</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RUTH SINAI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> Democrat who heads the panel that funds <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases, says the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> will have `` a long wait coming'' if they expect large sums of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid. Her comments came as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> prepare to start negotiations on renewing six military base leases that expire in 1991. Many Filipino lawmakers are demanding far higher <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid in return, or a phased withdrawal of American forces. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, just back from a 16-day trip to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, said the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> wants $ 2 billion each year. `` I told them that if they are waiting for foreign aid to more than double, they have a long wait coming,'' she said in a statement Friday. Her sentiments have been echoed in recent weeks by other lawmakers visiting the region over the summer recess. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> agreed to pay the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> some $ 960 million until 1991, but <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> said she would introduce a bill to sever the link between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign aid for the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> base rights there. `` Either a base is necessary for mutual defense or it is not,'' she said. <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> also issued a report she commissioned from the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, the watchdog agency of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> could save the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> $ 600 million annually by assuming payments in Japanese yen for such things as utility bills and salaries of Japanese workers on the bases. The report also disputed <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s claim that it can not increase support for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces without renegotiating the 1960 agreement for the stationing of American troops there. `` The Japanese are hiding behind this document, and our government lets them get away with it,'' <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON> said. The study praised <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for increasing its share of funding for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces from 24 percent in 1981 to 31 percent or $ 1.7 billion in 1987. But it said much of the gain resulted from the fact that the stronger yen now buys more dollars. `` Although the increase in Japanese support from 1981 to 1987 is impressive when measured in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollars, much of it can be attributed to the decline of the dollar's value against the yen,'' the report said. When measured in dollars, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s cash contributions rose 137 percent, but because of the strengthening of the yen, the actual increase was 44 percent, the study found.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890826-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-26-89 0314EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BasqueMonument     08-26 0555</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Basque Monument,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>22-Foot Tall, 5-Ton Sculpture in Reno Honors Basque Shepherders</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA MYERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
