<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TwoForks     04-11 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Two Forks,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Forks Veto Threat Puts Water Providers At Crossroads</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SANDY SHORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Work to Start At Once on Two Forks Reservoir,'' proclaimed a headline in The <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> 61 years ago, touting a project that would free the city from worry about future water supplies. That 1928 report proved to be a bit optimistic. Not an ounce of concrete has been poured at the proposed dam site on the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Platte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> 25 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. And now the federal <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> may be about to scuttle the dam, whose cost has ballooned from $ 6 million in 1928 to current estimates of $ 500 million to $ 1 billion. In an unusual move, <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> began the veto process on the 1.1 million acre-foot dam project March 24. He said it simply was too costly environmentally: It would inundate a gold-medal trout stream and possibly damage a <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> wildlife habitat. Dam supporters can make a final appeal to save the project. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Lathrop </PERSON> said the review process could continue through December. Although the city has adequate supplies at least through the next quarter century, its leaders have n't decided where to turn for water beyond that if Two Forks is defeated. `` We planned well and there's no crisis,'' said <PERSON> Monte </PERSON> <PERSON> Pascoe </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, which spent decades developing the proposal. `` We're trying to plan equally well for the next 25 years, and we're being told we ca n't do that. The city currently diverts mountain water across the Continental Divide from the <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION>' Western Slope. The dam has been touted by supporters as the best solution to the area's future water needs. Opponents, such as <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Berle </PERSON>, have called the dam an `` environmental and economic monstrosity'' that would destroy scenic Cheesman Canyon in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. They also say it would alter the <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Platte </ORGANIZATION>'s flow downstream into <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> and affect fragile habitat for 240 species of migrating birds, including the endangered whooping crane and the sandhill crane. Two Forks, just downstream from the confluence of the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Platte </LOCATION> and its <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fork </LOCATION>, would stand 615 feet _ about half the height of the Empire State Building _ and would be 1,700 feet long, and from 160 to 467 feet thick. By comparison, <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON>, one of the highest concrete dams in the world, is 726 feet tall astride the <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and 1,244 feet long with a 660-foot thick concrete base. <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> <PERSON> Dam </PERSON>'s reservoir, <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mead </LOCATION>, on the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona-Nevada </ORGANIZATION> border, stores about 29.7 million acre-feet of water _ one acre-foot is enough water to cover one acre to a depth of one foot _ and covers about 255 square miles. Two Forks, however, would store only 1.1 million acre-feet. It would cover 13.28 square miles and the small community of Deckers. <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> leaders have considered a dam on the river since 1896 and the city began acquiring land for the project in 1923. The most recent attempt to build a dam intensified in 1981 when the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> asked the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> to study the dam's potential environmental impact. In 1986, the board and the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Providers </ORGANIZATION>, a group of 42 suburban water suppliers, formally applied for a construction permit. The Corps issued a draft environmental impact assessment in 1987 that identified Two Forks as the most environmentally damaging of seven proposed dams on the river, but it also said Two Forks was the most cost-effective way to meet the area's water needs into the 21st century. Metropolitan officials are making contingency plans in addition to continuing the fight for Two Forks, and the <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> last week formalized water restrictions. Under the new policy, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> may decide each September whether to restrict additional water connections outside city limits, and may implement rate increases in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> and the suburbs to which it sells water. Most of the cities in the metropolitan area purchase water from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pascoe </PERSON> said the board has an adequate supply to meet needs in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> in the immediate future but `` there's no room for error.'' `` We honestly do n't think other supplies for water will be very easy to find,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lead-TanksList     04-11 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lead-Tanks List,0317</SECOND>
<UNK>With PM-Lead-Schools</UNK>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are school water coolers by model number that contain some lead components or lead-lined tanks, according to the Environmental Protection Agency:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Halsey Taylor Co.</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Coolers manufactured by <PERSON> Halsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> from 1978 through late 1987 using lead solder: Models WMA-1; SWA-1; S3 @ 5 @ 10 C & amp; D; S300 @ 500 @ 1000D; SCWT @ SCWT-A; <ORGANIZATION> DC </ORGANIZATION> @ DHC-1; HWC7 @ HWC7-D; BFC-4F @ 7F @ 4FS @ 7FS; 5656 FTN; 5800 FTN; 8880 FTN. Coolers manufactured by <PERSON> Halsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> with lead-lined tanks: Models WM8A; WT8A; GC10ACR; GC10A; GC5A; RWM13A.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>Sunroc Corp.</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Bottled water coolers manufactured by <ORGANIZATION> Sunroc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, with some coolers having lead solder as secondary seal, produced from 1978 through 1981: Models USB-1; USB-3; T6 Size 3; BCH.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>EBCO Manufacturing Co.</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Manufacturer provided four categories of drinking water coolers that it said included lead solder joints: Category I. Pressure bubbler water coolers shipped from 1962 through 1977. No model numbers available. Category II. Pressure bubbler coolers produced from 1978 through 1981. The models are: CP3; CP3-50; CP3H; CP3M; CP5; CP5M; CP10; CP10-50. C10E. 7P; 13P; 13PL. DP20; DP20-50; DP3R; DP3RH; DP8A; DP8AH; DP13A; DP13A-50; DP14A-50-60; DP10X; DP12N; DP15W; DP5M; DP7M; DP7MH; DPM8; DPM8H; DP13M; DP13M-60; DP14M; DP15M; DP16M; DP15MW; DP5S; DP7S; DP13S; DP14S; DP7SM; DP13SM; DP7WM; DP7WMD; DP5F; DP10F. WEEC03; WEEC05; WEEC07; WEEC10; WEEC13; WEEH03; WEFC03; WEFC08; WEFC10; WEFC13; WEFC15; WEFC20; WEFC13-OX; WEFC20-OX; WEKC05-OX; WEFH03; WEFH08; WEKC03; WEKC05; WELC05; WELC07; WELC08; WELC13; WELC14; WELC15; WELC16; WELH07; WEMC07; WEMC13; WW07T; WEPC05; WERC05; WERC07; WERC13; WETC05; WETC10; WEWC07; WEEC03-OX; WEEC10-OX; WFE10; WTC10. EP5F; EP10F. PX-10. Category III. Bottled water coolers with a lead solder joint shipped from 1962 through 1977. Models CBI -LRB- H -RRB- and DB1R -LRB- H -RRB-. Category IV. Bottled water coolers with a lead solder joint shipped between 1978 and 1981. Models DB2 and DB1R -LRB- H -RRB-.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0112EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan-King     04-11 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan-King,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>Memories Of The Past, New Hope, For Once And Future King</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a padlocked shed near the old royal palace, the limousine of the last Afghan king waits in the dust. The black Daimler's tires are flat, but the silver royal crest on the door is untarnished. The car is an apt symbol for <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>, the 74-year-old exile whose return is talked about by Afghans across the political spectrum as a way of ending the decade-old civil war between an authoritarian government and Moslem fundamentalists. Sixteen years after he was deposed, the ex-king remains a symbol of better days _ of a time when Afghans were not slaughtering each other in horrific numbers. The problem is finding a way for him to return. `` The car is ready for him. It would be good if he came back,'' said a man who knew the whereabouts of <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Daimler </ORGANIZATION>. Then, looking around even though no one else was within hearing distance, the slender university graduate added: `` Please do n't write my name. Others are less fearful. `` If King <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> wants to work for his country, he can have a positive role in bringing peace,'' said <PERSON> Wadir </PERSON> <PERSON> Safi </PERSON>, dean of law and political science at <ORGANIZATION> Kabul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` Even if he did n't do much for the progress of our country, he did n't kill anybody,'' said <PERSON> Safi </PERSON>, who studied at <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Charles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> About a month ago, <PERSON> Safi </PERSON>'s views were published in a new weekly newspaper, the Akbar-e-Hafta. The article was accompanied by the first photograph of the former king that <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> residents can remember seeing published in the government-supervised media since <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> was overthrown in 1973. The issue quickly sold out, although its price of 20 cents is four or five times that of other newspapers. Even illiterate people scrambled for copies. `` All the people like <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>,'' a shopkeeper said on condition of anonymity. `` In <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s time there was not killing of people,'' the father of 10 added. Even President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>, a former secret police chief, has said talks with the ex-king could be useful. In mid-February, <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said he had sent emissaries to <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s exile home in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. A spokesman for the aging ex-monarch promptly denied any contacts with <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s Soviet-style regime. U.S.-backed Moslem fundamentalist guerrillas, operating from headquarters across the border in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, are divided about reinstating the monarchy. Any future role in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> has been rejected by hard-liners among the rebels, such as <PERSON> Rasul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayyaf </PERSON>, leader of one of the seven parties in the Pakistan-based guerrilla alliance. Some moderate leaders, such as <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Gailani </PERSON> who once served as the king's religious adviser, say they would accept his return as a constitutional monarch, a sort of living flag to help unite the Afghan people. The king himself seems amenable. In early February, as the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> was withdrawing its last soldiers from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and ending nine years of combat support for the <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> government, <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> said: `` I am prepared to render without any claim or precondition any service to my country which would reflect the will of the majority of my compatriots.'' The sticky question is how to reconcile the poles-apart politics of <PERSON> Najib </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Afghanistan </ORGANIZATION>, the rebels' Islamic fundamentalism and a monarchy The rebels refuse to deal with the party, whose communist beginnings never took root among the fervently capitalist Afghans. The party, whose leadership changes have come only through coup, assassination or purge, says it is willing to `` share'' power but will never step aside completely. In four decades on the throne, <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> himself proved a less than dynamic leader. He was only 19 in 1933 when he became king upon the assassination of his father, <PERSON> Nadir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>. For the next 20 years his uncles ran the country. In 1953, his cousin, <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON>, became prime minister and tried to push a feudalistic, tribal nation toward the 20th century by such means as freeing women of their all-enveloping robes. In 1963, <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> finally exerted himself. <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> resigned, waited a decade, and overthrew his cousin the king. Five years later, in 1978, <PERSON> Daoud </PERSON> was assassinated in a coup that brought the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> to power with a succession of leaders. Since then about 1 million Afghans have been killed in the war. Another 5 million have fled to neighboring <LOCATION> Paistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, leaving <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> with a population of 10 million. Throughout the war, <PERSON> Zahir </PERSON> <PERSON> Shah </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Daimler </ORGANIZATION>, a car that is somehow sleek and bulky at the same time, has been unscathed. Periodically it is dusted by a man with only childhood memories of the monarchy, a man who does not want to give his name and hopes the car remains safe until the king returns. The Daimler waits, along with five other royal automobiles, in a simple white-washed structure behind the national museum, abou 300 yards from the early 20th century Darulaman Palace which now houses the defense ministry.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChevronFire     04-11 0284</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chevron Fire,0292</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire, Explosion At Chevron Plant; 6 Injured</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire erupted Monday at a <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> oil refinery plant, injuring at least seven workers and sending 100-foot flames shooting into the sky. The fire apparently started at 12:46 p.m. when an explosion shook a 100-foot-tall column in a refinery processing plant where gasoline is manufactured, said <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Holt </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. Thick black smoke and flames rose into the sky as about 40 firefighters from <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> and the city of <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> battled the blaze, which was declared under control about four hours later, <PERSON> Holt </PERSON> said. `` The fire is still burning and we have not been able to get in to assess the cause or the totality of damage,'' said <PERSON> Holt </PERSON>, who refused to estimate a damage amount. Three Chevron operators were flown to <LOCATION> Brookside </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pablo </LOCATION> where a hospital spokesman said they were in stable condition with second degree burns. One man suffered burns over 70 percent of his body and the other two had burns over 20 percent to 30 percent of their bodies. Another Chevron operator was taken to <LOCATION> Doctor </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Pinole </LOCATION>, where he was reported in stable condition after being treated for smoke inhalation, according to the nursing supervisor. <ORGANIZATION> Alta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> reported that one <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> fire marshal was admitted with second degree burns on his face, ears and neck and was having respiratory difficulties, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>. At least two other people were reported injured but there was no immediate word on the extent of their injuries. The facility is <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION>'s second largest refinery on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> and produces about 265,000 barrels of crude oil daily.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     04-11 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0451</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Major League' Leads Off In First Place</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Major League,'' the story of a big-league baseball team inherited by a showgirl, hit a home run in its first time at bat at the nation's box offices. The Paramount movie starring <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Berenger </PERSON> as a washed-up catcher on the team took in $ 8 million last weekend to finish at the top of the box office rankings by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Three other new releases finished among the top six movies last weekend Universal's `` The <ORGANIZATION> Dream </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Team </ORGANIZATION>,'' a comedy about four mental patients in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, debutted in second place with $ 5.7 million. `` Rain Man,'' winner of four top Oscars, continued its strong post Academy Awards-showing by gathering $ 4.1 million to finish in third place. Another newcomer, `` Cyborg,'' starring <PERSON> Jean-Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Damme </PERSON> as `` the first hero of the 21st century,'' finished fourth on receipts of $ 3.1 million. `` Fletch Lives,'' a comedy sequel featuring <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, landed in fifth with $ 2.6 million. Next was `` Dead Calm,'' a new thriller set on a sailboat, with sales of $ 2.4 million. In seventh was the re-release of `` The Rescuers,'' with $ 1.7 million. `` Lean on Me,'' the dramatization of the life of high school principal <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, finished in eighth with $ 1.5 million. Completing the top 10 were the comedy `` Bill and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>'s Excellent Adventure,'' with $ 1.4 million and the bedroom drama `` Dangerous Liaisons,'' with $ 1.1 million. Here are the top movies for last weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Major League,'' Paramount, $ 8.8 million, 1,541 screens, $ 5,734 per screen, $ 8.8 million, one week. 2. `` Dream Team,'' Universal, $ 5.7 million, 1,316 screens, $ 4,335 per screen, $ 5.7 million, one week. 3. `` Rain Man,'' <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Artists </ORGANIZATION>, $ 4.1 million, 1,580 screens, $ 2,604 per screen, $ 148.6 million, 16 weeks. 4. `` Cyborg,'' Cannon, $ 3.1 million, 830 screens, $ 3,831 per screen, $ 3.1 million, one week. 5. `` Fletch Lives,'' Universal, $ 2.6 million, 1,473 screens, $ 1,770 per screen, $ 27.2 million, three weeks. 6. `` Dead Calm,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.4 million, 959 screens, $ 2,569 per screen, $ 2.4 million, one week. 7. `` The Rescuers,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.7 million, 1,463 screens, $ 1,172 per screen, $ 16.2 million, four weeks. 8. `` Lean on Me,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 904 screens, $ 1,703 per screen, $ 25.9 million, five weeks. 9. `` Bill and <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>'s Excellent Adventure,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.4 million, 1,201 screens, $ 1,171 per screen, $ 33.7 million, seven weeks. 10. `` Dangerous Liaisons,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.1 million, 622 screens, $ 1,788 per screen, $ 29.2 million, 15 weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-DrugBoss     04-11 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-Drug Boss,0583</SECOND>
<HEAD>Praise arrest of Mexican drug kingpin</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN WRIGHT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opposition politicians and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials praised <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> authorities for the capture of a drug czar believed to control more than half of the cocaine shipped through <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Authorities seized some of <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Angel </PERSON> <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>'s assets Monday, including a hotel, pharmacy, real-estate company, bank accounts and various properties. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>, 43, was arrested Saturday night in <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION>. No value was placed on the assets confiscated Monday, but <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>'s net worth is estimated to exceed $ 500 million, including at least 50 houses and 200 ranches. Attorney General <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Castillo </PERSON>, at a news conference Monday, called <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> `` the No. 1 drug trafficker in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>.'' He said that others arrested in the weekend raids included three of <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>'s aides as well as the chief federal anti-drug official and five other ranking police officers in <LOCATION> Sinaloa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>'s home state. `` We congratulate the judicial police for the apprehension of the drug czar and we praise the role of the military in <LOCATION> Sinaloa </LOCATION>, where they detained police involved in drug trafficking,'' <PERSON> Alberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Noyola </PERSON>, spokesman for the conservative <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, told the government news agency <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Yanez </PERSON>, a leader of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> Notimex </ORGANIZATION>: `` We hope that this not only affects the circulation of drugs but that it attacks the problem starting with production,'' <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> noted that President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, who took office in January, has vowed to stop drug dealing and corruption. The raids were the third dramatic example of <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON>' determination In January he put the corrupt leader of the oil workers' union behind bars and in February a leading stockbroker went to jail. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, told reporters, `` The message ... is that President <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> means business.'' `` To pull this thing off the way it was done is a tribute'' to Mexican authorities, he added. `` The impact it has on the drug market, we can say, is extremely significant.'' <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>, thought to head a ring that smuggled up to 4 tons of cocaine a month into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, had been sought for years but `` obtained protection from diverse authorities,'' <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> said <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> `` was as important as any major trafficker in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'' and `` has been operating almost with impunity in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> because of the protection he received.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities believe <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> was involved in the 1985 slaying of American drug agent <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> <PERSON> Salazar </PERSON>. But <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> said <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> opposed killing <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> and that his office had no evidence linking him directly to the killing. <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> added, however, that <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> was the `` intellectual author'' of the organization that killed <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON>. <PERSON> Camarena </PERSON> was kidnapped outside the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consulate in <LOCATION> Guadalajara </LOCATION> in 1985 and tortured and killed. While Federal judicial police were arresting <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> in the western state of <LOCATION> Jalisco </LOCATION> soldiers detained every police officer on the 80-member force in <LOCATION> Culiacan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallard </PERSON>'s hometown and the capital of <LOCATION> Sinaloa </LOCATION> state in northwest <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Alvarez </PERSON> said federal authorities did not trust the police in <LOCATION> Sinaloa </LOCATION> and wanted to avoid a shootout. Most of the officers were quickly released, he said. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> purportedly had an alliance with <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Medellin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cartel </ORGANIZATION> to move cocaine into the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Abortion-Women'sGroups Bjt   04-11 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion-Women's Groups, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Issue Revitalizing Women's Movement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The threat to legalized abortion has infused the women's movement with a passion and purpose unmatched since the determined but losing campaign to ratify the equal rights amendment. Women are turning out, joining up and writing checks in what one organizer called `` a torrent of activity'' provoked by the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to re-examine <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON>, its 1973 ruling that legalized abortion. `` It's like spontaneous combustion or a prairie fire,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, D-Colo., co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caucus </ORGANIZATION> on Women's Issues The throngs that turned out for Sunday's abortion rights march were only the most visible aspect of an energized movement. March organizers report their contributions have risen 50 percent in recent months. One group, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abortion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, raised $ 600,000 in March 1989 _ five times as much as the previous March. New members in February and March amounted to double the entire number of people who joined <ORGANIZATION> NARAL </ORGANIZATION> throughout 1988. Another major beneficiary has been the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> for Women. Once the undisputed leader of the women's movement, NOW after the 1982 ERA defeat was just one of many groups with separate interests. Its membership fell, its finances suffered and its activist, grassroots tactics were spurned in favor of an insiders' strategy of `` playing the game. But NOW has gained 18,000 members in the past few months, said president <PERSON> Molly </PERSON> <PERSON> Yard </PERSON>. Its fiscal health has improved dramatically as a result of the abortion rights mobilization. And the march, initially scheduled to kick off a new NOW campaign for ERA, has raised its profile considerably. Many feminists acknowledge their movement had been in a slump, successful through the 1980s only in staving off threats to ground they had thought was secure. For example, women's groups were part of the broader coalition that helped defeat <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Bork </PERSON> and pass the Civil Rights Restoration Act over then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s veto. But for the most part, women's groups in the post-ERA movement went their separate ways. Some raised money for feminist candidates, some lobbied for family or economic bills on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NARAL </ORGANIZATION> continued its abortion rights campaign, NOW its pursuit of the ERA. Until the threat to abortion rights, `` there was n't that kind of eye on the prize that a movement needs,'' said <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissling </PERSON>, president of Catholics for a Free Choice. While acknowledging the backhanded contribution the conservative <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administrations have made to their movement, feminist leaders say they do n't consider the <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> threat a boon or a necessity. `` It has mobilized both human resources and money. It's providing energy and fuel to the movement,'' said <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Lichtman </PERSON>, president of the Women's Legal Defense Fund `` But it was n't a dying movement. It's an extraordinarily diverse movement with quite powerful leadership. We did n't need an attack on <PERSON> Roe </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> to be a strong movement.'' NOW's moment in the spotlight cast by the massive abortion march may pass, but feminist leaders say the energy activated by the abortion threat will continue on that front and spill over to others. `` It will certainly revive the reproductive freedom movement and it will go well beyond where it's been before,'' said <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> NARAL </ORGANIZATION>. Noting the new involvement of labor unions, doctors, civil rights groups and religious groups, she said `` the coalition to preserve this right is much bigger and broader than ever before in the'70s and'80s.'' Many leaders spoke optimistically of the college students from some 450 campuses who came to the march. `` This is going to be the issue that brings them into the political process,'' said <PERSON> Michelman </PERSON>. `` It's going to galvanize them to care about public policy and legal rights and civil rights. It will have a spinoff effect.'' The women also cited a renewed resolve to hold politicians accountable on a wide range of women's concerns. `` People were here for abortion because there's an immediate threat,'' said <PERSON> Lichtman </PERSON>. `` But they lobbied on Monday not just on abortion but on child care, family leave and the minimum wage. They're going to use their political chits with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' Most groups are likely to continue the present focus on abortion and family issues such as child care, which concern women on an intensely personal level. But NOW intends to renew its quest for the ERA, despite the difficulties of building steam for what is perceived as a losing issue. Yard said NOW does n't need a lot of people to build a solid legislative record at congressional hearings, the first phase of what she sees as a 10-year effort. And she said congressional passage can wait until more women are elected to the state legislatures that must ratify the amendment. While some women consider legal abortion the fundamental right women need to participate fully in society, <ORGANIZATION> Yard </ORGANIZATION> said NOW members believe the bottom line is the ERA. `` We're never going to let the ERA go,'' she said. `` We're very concerned about other issues, but at rock bottom, you have to have the equal rights amendment to protect the rights you win.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PoliceShooting     04-11 0229</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Police Shooting,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Kill Disturbed Man On Crowded Street</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An emotionally disturbed man screaming `` I'm going to kill you'' swung a machete at pedestrians and police on a crowded midtown <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> street before an officer shot and killed him Monday, police said Four police officers and a sergeant tried to stop the man by spraying mace and shooting him with a stun gun but both failed to slow him down, said police Inspector <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McCabe </PERSON>. `` They all did cartwheels to prevent having to shoot him,'' said Officer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> of the Patrolmen's <ORGANIZATION> Benevolent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. `` The guy just wanted to die and nothing was going to stop him.'' `` He kept screaming, `` You're going to have to kill me or I'm going to kill you,'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> said The man, whose identity was not known, was shot at 2:30 p.m. by 26-year-old Officer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Masucci </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> when he lunged at the officer from a distance of three feet with the 18-inch long machete, <PERSON> McCabe </PERSON> said. The victim, shot once in the upper chest and once above the navel, staggered across the street and collapsed. He died an hour later at <LOCATION> Bellevue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said police spokesman Detective <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>. `` We did everything humanly possible to contain him,'' <PERSON> McCabe </PERSON> said. `` Every time police asked him to drop the knife he said he would not drop it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Soviets-BandFlap     04-11 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviets-Band Flap,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Department Reverses Itself, OKs Coast Guard Band's Soviet Appearance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CALLAHAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a policy reversal, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has agreed to let the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> perform this June at a <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> concert commemorating last year's U.S.-Soviet arms treaty. Earlier this year, the <ORGANIZATION> Leningrad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> invited the Connecticut-based military band to play with the <ORGANIZATION> Leningrad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> in a joint concert June 22 in honor of the first anniversary of the treaty banning intermediate-range nuclear missiles. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> embraced the idea, according to Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., but higher-level officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> rejected it without explanation <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> and officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, protested the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> decision to scuttle the trip. In a letter last month to <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON>, the department's legislative liaison, <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> said he could not understand `` what reason could possibly exist for refusing this gracious and generous invitation during this period of excellent relations. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> on Monday that the trip was back on. `` The band shows the best of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' the congressman said. `` The <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> people will love it.'' One source said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials feared the trip would interfere with a concurrent visit by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officials and were uneasy about the idea of having an American military unit performing in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. But <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> said he believes the reluctance stems from the problems Americans have with responding to glasnost, the Soviets' new policy of openness `` It's just symbolic of the difficulty of the new opportunities in the relationship with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Even the simplest and smallest symbol that they're willing to try ... was a major hurdle to get across,'' <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Mullins </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials for Soviet affairs could not be reached for comment following <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>'s announcement, which came late Monday afternoon <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> officials are paying for the band's hotel, meals and local transportation, <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has to supply air travel to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     04-11 0728</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>Yeutter Defends Trade Agreement with Europeans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> says <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators held the line during trade talks in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> last week, regardless of how the final agreement is worded. Moreover, he said, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export subsidy program _ which provides reduced prices for selected commodities in certain overseas markets _ was a key factor in putting leverage into the negotiations, particularly in getting approval from the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> had balked at the earlier <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> insistence that all trade-distorting agricultural subsidies be eliminated over the long haul. The agreement reached in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> by more than 100 countries calls for a `` substantial progressive reduction'' in such subsidies. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, in an interview Monday with a group of reporters, said the Europeans objected to earlier language calling for the `` elimination'' of the subsidies and later to a modified `` ratcheting'' down of them. Asked if the final language represented backtracking on the part of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in its quest to do away with trade-distorting subsidies and other practices, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> replied: `` I do n't consider it backtracking at all.'' He maintained that there is no practical difference between `` elimination'' or `` ratcheting'' or the accepted `` substantial progressive reduction'' of subsidies, regardless of what some European leaders may feel. `` They may have their own reasons for articulating the outcome of the meeting as they have,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` Obviously, everyone will go home and, to some degree, at least, articulate their own interpretation in a way that fits their own particular needs.'' The accord reached in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> provides a framework for further discussions under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, a four-year effort called the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Round </LOCATION> of talks to liberalize global trade. The current <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> round will conclude at the end of 1990. As part of the <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> agreement, participants agreed to an overall freeze on farm supports and import barriers through 1990. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goal is to gain long-term accord on the future of agricultural trade and that the short-term agreement reached in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, while acceptable, was no big challenge for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators. Some American farm leaders, including <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleckner </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, had urged <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to proceed writing a new general farm bill on an assumption that little progress could be expected under the <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> talks. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said he had no objection to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> proceeding with a new farm bill to replace the 1985 law that will expire next year. And <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> denied that he had favored going slow on legislation until it was clearer how the <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> talks would shape up. `` Somehow that got misinterpreted ... because that's not really what I meant at all,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. `` Assuming that -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> GATT </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- negotiations are a success, the 1990 farm legislation will have to be modified accordingly in 1991,'' he said. `` But I never meant to indicate that we should n't have full-scale farm legislation in 1990.'' On the matter of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> export subsidies used in the Export Enhancement Program, or <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said it is `` our view that we are not constrained on <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> expenditures.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said further that he still favors <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> removing the lid on <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> spending so that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can match the unrestrained export subsidies of the Europeans. The program, he said, was a major factor in reaching the agreement in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> last week, along with aggressive negotiating and general leverage. `` In the absence of this combination of leverage _ with the <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> program providing a great deal of that leverage _ we very likely would not have an agreed framework in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> today,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. In a written statement later, <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> repeated his earlier insistence that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` will continue to aggressively seek elimination of trade-distorting measures'' during the remainder of the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round. A background sheet said that in the short-term the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` in a general way'' is committed not to increase price support and protection for American farmers. Specifically, it said, `` We are committed not to intensify market access barriers or raise support prices to producers, subject to the condition that the commitment be consistent with existing legislation.'' The paper added: `` Our assessment is that this will not require us to do anything differently from what we are now doing. For 1990, our 1985 farm legislation requires cuts in some support prices.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Drugs-Housing     04-11 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drugs-Housing,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Kemp Plans Effort to Evict Drug Dealers from Public Housing Projects</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Housing and Urban Development Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> says his proposals to get drugs out of <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> housing projects can be followed in the rest of the nation, too. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> on Monday proposed actions against drugs in the federally supported housing projects of the nation's capital, including more police patrols, installing security fences and guarded entrances, and requiring photo identification cards for residents. He announced the moves as part of the federal government's drug crackdown in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, but said the proposals `` are appropriate and will be suggested'' to every public housing authority in the nation. `` I'm asking today the <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> police chief and the public housing authority of <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, along with public housing authorities around the country, to engage in those type of operations that can clear out and secure public housing projects from drug users and abusers and dealers,'' <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said. In the nation's capital, <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said he would waive <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> grievance hearing requirements that can delay evictions from public housing for months. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> took steps recently to remove those requirements in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> outlined his plan at a news conference where national drug policy director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> and Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> announced a major new effort to combat drugs in the nation's capital. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said local police and public housing authorities should issue photo identification cards to residents of federally supported housing projects so that legitimate residents can be distinguished from outsiders. He said security guards would be trained and `` a better presence of public housing and city police'' would be provided. A part of the effort would be a general cleanup of projects, including removal of graffiti. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> acknowledged that many of the steps are things <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> should be doing anyway, and said many of the proposals were based on successful tests by local housing authorities at projects in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> and elsewhere. He said he would finance the anti-drug effort with existing money appropriated for public housing rehabilitation and operating subsidies. He put no price tag on the effort. `` If it's not enough, I'll ask <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for a supplemental'' appropriation, he said. <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assisted </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION>, which operates the city's public housing projects, said city housing officials were discussing <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s proposal and had no immediate response. But she said the district is already issuing photo cards to residents of high-rise projects for senior citizens. Most units for other residents are apartments or town houses, she said, and use of the cards is `` a much different issue'' for families. She said the district already has asked <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> for more money to pay for 100 additional housing guards and for more security fences. <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> also will: _ Ask <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorneys to seize the apartments of drug dealers and return them to the public housing authorities _ Seek ways to terminate federal housing subsidies, such as <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> vouchers and housing certificates, for anyone convicted of using or selling drugs _ Attempt to reclaim vacant units sometimes used by drug dealers and abusers, and enforce housing codes and standards _ Encourage resident management of public housing projects _ Establish an anti-drug hotline to encourage residents to make confidential reports on drug-related crimes _ Encourage youth sports leagues in the projects to steer youngsters away from drugs
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Arias-Figueres     04-11 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Arias-Figueres,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Interrupts North American Trip to Visit Ailing Ex-President</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARLOS A. SANDI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> interrupted his North American trip to visit his ailing mentor, former President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Figueres </PERSON>. `` I come to see my friend, one of the greatest leaders that <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has ever had,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> told reporters Monday as he entered <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dios </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in the nation's capital `` When his health failed, we realized how much <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON> meant to us,'' said the president, who was to later resume his trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Figueres </PERSON>, 83, has been hospitalized since Friday with a heart ailment. Although doctors initially said they feared his death was imminent, by Monday they said he had improved considerably. All day long, hundreds of people called the hospital to ask about the health of the former president affectionately known as <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON>. <PERSON> Figueres </PERSON> was president of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> three times and in 1948 abolished the army. At a recent public event <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> confessed that `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON> is like my second father and has been my political guide.'' Both men belong to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which <PERSON> Figueres </PERSON> founded in 1953. `` I want to tell all of you that I am glad to find <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON> so well and I think he is recovering quickly,'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> told reporters. `` He always has encountered force against adversity in his life and that force has come from God.'' <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> refused to comment to journalists on his tour of <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and his debt talks with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Canadian officials.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Lead-Schools     04-11 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lead-Schools,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lead Found in Same Model Water Coolers Used by Schools</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Lead-Tanks List</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Water fountains with excessive levels of lead because of tanks lined with the toxic metal are being used at elementary and secondary schools, and more than 100 models have unhealthy levels, the government says. The exact number of coolers with the lead-lined tanks is not known, but the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> did say that more than a million other coolers are in use that have lead soldering or lead in some other form. Although the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> lacks the authority to order lead testing in schools, a law enacted last year requires states to begin a program to assist school districts in testing for lead in drinking water. Many such programs are under way. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials also said Monday they would soon issue a detailed guide for school officials on how to testfor unhealthy lead levels, and the agency listed more than 100 manufacturers' model numbers for fountains in which lead levels were found to be of concern. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said Monday it discovered the lead-lined tanks while inspecting 22 coolers provided by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. The nine with lead-lined tanks were all models like those used in schools. Those coolers, all made by <ORGANIZATION> Halsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taylor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, mostly had lead levels of more than several hundred parts per billion, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. In some cases, when long-standing water was tested, the level was more than 1,000 parts per billion, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> considers a lead level of 20 parts per billion in water to pose health risks especially if a child is exposed to lead poisoning from other sources as well. Lead is a toxic metal that is harmful to health even at low levels of exposure and poses increased risks to children. It can cause damage to the brain and nervous system and lead to learning disabilities, hearing impairment, and interference in the formation of red blood cells, according to the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>. `` There are a few hundred thousand children who have enough lead from other sources so when lead from drinking water is added at levels of 20 parts per billion there will be some adverse health impact,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Cook </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> water contamination office, in an interview. The agency also said that three major manufacturers of school water coolers have acknowleged that more than a million coolers have some lead components _ usually lead soldering at joints. Two other companies did not reply to the inquiries and another said it manufactured no coolers with lead soldering. The agency gave no specific levels of lead in water from all the coolers cited by model numbers, but said the coolers were singled out only after levels were found to be in the unhealthy range. After the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> issues a final list of coolers with lead-lined tanks later this year, the <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> intends to seek their recall by the manufacturer, said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmeltzer </PERSON>, director of compliance at the commission. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials said that school water fountains likely account for only a `` very small'' part of the lead exposure that faces youngsters. In some cases it's uncertain whether the high lead levels in some model coolers was from the coolers or water pipes that feed the coolers. In addition to the nine lead-lined coolers from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> received two additional coolers with lead-lined tanks from school officials in <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Cook </PERSON> said. The law that was passed last year also requires the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to issued detailed guidelines on how to detect lead contamination in school water systems and sets a timetable for replacing or fixing coolers that pose a health hazard because of lead contamination. The coolers cited by model number were manufactured by three companies _ <ORGANIZATION> Halsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taylor </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> EBCO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Sunroc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> said two other companies have yet to reply to inquiries on lead content in their coolers and a third said it produced no coolers with lead components.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Whistleblowers     04-11 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Whistleblowers,240</SECOND>
<UNK>Bush Signs Whistleblower Protection Bill</UNK>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> signed a bill to protect federal whistleblowers who report government waste and fraud, calling it a `` significant improvement'' over a version vetoed by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. The bill signed by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday gives more job protection to federal employees who disclose misdeeds and mismanagement in their agencies. `` The true whistleblower is a public servant of the highest order,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said at a bill-signing ceremony in the Old Executive Office Building attended by the measure's congressional sponsors. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> vetoed a similar measure last fall. Stripped from the new version _ which was approved unanimously in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and by a voice vote in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> _ is a provision opposed by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> that would have permitted the Office of Special Counsel to go to court on behalf of whistleblowers. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> protested this would have resulted in federal agencies fighting court battles against each other. The new version `` addresses the chief constitutional concerns raised by earlier versions of this legislation,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` The bill I am signing today is a significant improvement over legislation enacted by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last year.'' Under the new act, employees fighting for their jobs would face less stringent standards of proof that their firing or demotion came as the result of whistleblowing. The Office of the Special Counsel, established eight years ago to investigate civil service abuses, would become an independent agency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PLO-Israel     04-11 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-PLO-Israel,0494</SECOND>
<HEAD>PLO Rejects Israeli Plan For Elections In Occupied Territories</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TUNIS, Tunisia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> has rejected an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> proposal to hold elections among Palestinians in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Wafa </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> news agency, said the proposal by <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> is `` nothing but a reactivation of the self-autonomy scheme of the Camp David accord, which the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> and our entire <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> people already have rejected.'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Habash </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION>, said in a statement issued in <LOCATION> Damascus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>: `` We will not allow the <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> plan to pass. We will not allow elections to be held under enemy army bayonets. We will not allow the creation of a substitute leadership whatever their name or color might be.'' <PERSON> Habash </PERSON>'s Marxist organization is the second-largest group in the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fatah </ORGANIZATION>, the main Palestinian fighting force. Under <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s plan, proposed last week in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> would choose representatives for negotiations about an interim settlement in the territories. An Israeli government official in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> quoted <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> on Monday as saying he was willing to discuss participation in proposed elections by Palestinians from outside the territories. The official said those elected also might consult during negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, with which <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> refuses to deal, because `` no one can think the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> is an element you can totally ignore.'' In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> should `` explore practical ways to advance the peace process.'' He declined to say whether the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was asking the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to endorse <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s plan, which received President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s qualified support The Wafa report, quoting a <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman it did not identify, said elections in the occupied lands should be held under international supervision after <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> withdraws. `` The idea of elections is totally unacceptable in the shadow of <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> occupation and this proposal is nothing but a maneuver aimed at undermining efforts undertaken by several world powers to achieve a just settlement in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>,'' the report said. In the U.S-mediated Camp David accords that lead to the 1979 peace treaty, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> agreed to limited autonomy for Palestinians in the territories that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> captured from <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in 1967. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> should turn over the territories to a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> supervisory force for a transition period during which elections would be held. On Friday, <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> said <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON>'s proposal was `` inappropriate, as usual.'' Monday's <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> statement reiterated calls for an international peace conference on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> involving all parties concerned, `` including the Palestinian state'' proclaimed Nov. 15 by the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which acts as the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> legislature. It is the first <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> mention of the Palestinian state as the representative of Palestinians at an international forum. Previous references have been to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> itself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FuelEconomy     04-11 0462</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Fuel Economy,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Car Average Mileage of 33 mpg Possible by 1995, Congress Told</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM BOVEE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cars could average 33 miles per gallon by 1995, but automakers are unlikely to make the necessary engineering changes on their own, the congressional <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION> says. The higher average, about 5 mpg above the present one for new cars, could be reached if automakers began immediately to move available fuel-conservation technology into their cars at a more rapid pace, an analyst with the office told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on Monday. Those changes include better tires, more aerodynamic body design and engine improvements, said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON>, senior associate with the office. `` We calculate that this level of efficiency could be obtained without a performance loss or the need to move to smaller vehicles, at a cost that would be compensated for by fuel savings,'' <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> told the oversight and investigations subcommttee, chaired by Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich. But the office `` doubts that the industry will pursue this course without a further economic or regulatory incentive to do so,'' <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> have said high fuel-economy standards are difficult to reach because of the public's demand for larger, high-powered cars. The OTA analysis struck a middle course between the positions of advocates of tighter fuel-economy standards and the major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automakers. Energy conservation groups have proposed a 45 mpg fuel-economy goal for cars by 2000, a level <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said was `` virtually impossible'' to reach. Neither <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> nor <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> could provide estimates of attainable fuel efficiency for 1995. `` We have n't gone out that far in our prognostications, largely because there are just too many variables to deal with, the largest of which is fuel cost,'' said <ORGANIZATION> GM </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> Terry </PERSON>. The office's analysis assumed a $ 1.10 per gallon price for gasoline, <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said. The corporate average fuel economy standard requires the mix of 1989 cars sold by each automaker to average 26.5 mpg or better. The average fuel-efficiency for all new passenger cars in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1987 was 28 mpg and <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said the present level is about the same. Among the presently available technologies whose adoption could improve fuel efficiency are more aerodynamic styling, improved tire composition and design and improved pumps and other components, <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said. Greater use of front-wheel drive, four-speed automatic shift, four-cylinder and four-valve engines and low-friction rings and pistons would also help increase the average fuel efficiency of cars in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said. The goal likely could n't be reached if present trends toward greater performance and luxury continued, or if the industry had to comply with stricter pollution-control standards that required technologies that reduce fuel efficiency, <PERSON> Plotkin </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CountryAwards-List     04-11 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Country Awards-List,0134</SECOND>
<HEAD>Winners of the 24th Annual Academy of Country Music Awards</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Country Awards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BURBANK, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the winners Monday at the 24th Annual Academy of Country Music Awards presentation at <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION>. ENTERTAINER OF THE DECADE: <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. ENTERTAINER OF THE YEAR: <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>. MALE VOCALIST: <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Strait </PERSON>. FEMALE VOCALIST: K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON>. NEW MALE VOCALIST: <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowell </PERSON>. NEW FEMALE VOCALIST: <PERSON> Suzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogguss </PERSON>. VOCAL GROUP: Highway 101. VOCAL DUET: The <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION>. RECORD OF THE YEAR: `` Eighteen Wheels and a Dozen Roses,'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>. SONG OF THE YEAR: `` Eighteen Wheels and a Dozen Roses,'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattea </PERSON>. ALBUM OF THE YEAR: `` This Woman,'' <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON>. MUSIC VIDEO: `` Young Country,'' <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0203EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SocialSecurity     04-11 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Social Security,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chaos Overwhelms Special Line to Social Security Office, Witnesses
Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 People who called an expanded toll-free telephone service offered by the <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> met with busy signals, endless waits on hold and misinformation when they did get through, witnesses told a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel. <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, told the the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Special </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Aging that she was put on hold three times for 20 minutes, then told she would have to wait 30 days for the answer to a question on moving her mother's checks into a new account. A phone representative neglected to tell <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Lippert </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> that she needed to file a claim to get a widow's benefit, and she said it took five months to wade through red tape before the problem was solved `` I would like to point out that for the past five months, I have only received my own Social Security check, which is $ 70 less than my rent alone,'' she told the panel on Monday. The administration began the 800-number service last October, hoping to improve convenience and accessibility to the public by making phone representatives available for 12 hours per day, instead of eight. The system, in which calls to local Social Security offices are routed to any of 37 national `` teleservice'' centers, has been implemented so far in 60 percent of the nation and received 22 million calls. The service was touted in two mailings to a total of 36 million beneficiaries in December and February. Lawmakers began hearing about the system after national busy signal rates reached 43 percent in January, followed by 35 percent in February. The rate dipped to 9 percent in March, but only after calls dropped from 4.8 million in March to 3.4 million in February, and after <ORGANIZATION> SSA </ORGANIZATION> brought in staff members in from other offices to answer calls, a <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> official testified. `` While the reassignment of staff contributed to the reduction of this busy signal rate for March, it raises questions about the impact on the operations of the field facilities,'' <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Delfico </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>'s Human Resources Division said in a prepared statement. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sturdivant </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employees </ORGANIZATION>, told the panel that <ORGANIZATION> SSA </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Dorcas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> `` has created sweatshop conditions for teleservice employees.'' `` She is pressuring employees to complete calls in an average of 200 seconds,'' he said, adding that the employees are being denied sick leave. <ORGANIZATION> SSA </ORGANIZATION> said it reduced the busy signal rate in March partly through the use of a system to reroute calls during peak calling times. `` As we have identified problems and gained experience with the system, we have been able to modify our procedures along the way in order to improve our performance,'' <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> told the panel. `` This will be the largest 800-number in the world,'' she said in a prepared text. `` I want it to be the best.'' A survey conducted by <ORGANIZATION> SSA </ORGANIZATION> in February found that 84 percent of callers interviewed were satisfied with the phone service and 98 percent thought they had been treated courteously, the administration said. <PERSON> Hardy </PERSON> said the latest survey placed the system-wide accuracy rate at 94 percent. But <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Delfico </PERSON> said that an <ORGANIZATION> SSA </ORGANIZATION> study last December found that the number of incorrect 800-number responses ranged from 2.5 percent for a question on disability benefits to 22.9 percent for a question on the annual earnings test for people 70 years old and over. The service handled 22 million calls during its first six months.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Spill-Race     04-11 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spill-Race,0450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oily `Response Team' Dawdled, Lost Race Against Clock</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Tanker Spill, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Allyeska-Exxxon in 2nd graf, Wendie in 14th graf cq</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JUNEAU, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It lacked the proper equipment and dawdled when it should have been racing against the clock, but the oil-smeared `` response team'' promised to revise its contingency plan and do better next time. The Allyeska-Exxxon Response Team was the last of the 103 teams to cross the finish line in the 14th-annual Ski-to-Sea Relay near <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>. `` We were well-prepared. We had a good plan. But, darn, the thing just was n't adequate,'' team member <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON> said Monday. <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON> said his team was neither sanctioned nor supported by <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> nor <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the companies blamed for the slow response to the Valdez oil spill. It was just coincidence that team members had crude oil on their faces and clothes, he said. In fact, all but one of the team members work for the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>, which is no stranger to oil companies. Each team included a downhill skier, who began the relay at the top of the <ORGANIZATION> Eaglecrest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ski </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> and passed the baton to a cross-country skier, two runners and a bicyclist. <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON>, a legislative aide, noted his bicycle was not designed for the job. `` We thought it was a state-of-the-art bike. It actually was a little small. It was n't large enough to deal with the size of the race,'' he said. `` Well, it basically was a little kid's bike.'' The downhill skier in <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON>'s team missed all the gates, `` and unfortunately there's a penalty each time you do that,'' he said. `` I think she skied part of the way backwards.'' Things got worse when the team's cross-country skier took over. `` He's our lawyer and he was dressed up in a suit and tie, smoking a cigar,'' <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON> recalled. `` After the start he realized his cigar went out so he stopped and took the time to light it. `` He figured there just was n't much of a hurry. Things were under control. He had The Wall Street Journal with him and he read that.'' <PERSON> Wendie </PERSON> <PERSON> Marriott </PERSON>, who organized the weekend race as the city's recreation supervisor, said she heard that the team's runners actually ran _ backward `` The team was purposely trying to come in last, which it did,'' she observed. `` The idea was to clean up the mess at the end of the race.'' <PERSON> Nordlund </PERSON> said the team learned a lot from the experience. `` We'll do it better next time,'' he said. `` You can trust us.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DCDrugWar-Glance     04-11 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC Drug War-Glance,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Major Components of New U.S. Drug Program in D.C.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-DC Drug War Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are some of the major components of the federal effort to curb drugs and drug-related violence in the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> proposed by national drug control policy director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. _ JAIL AND PRISON SPACE: Some 250 inmates now housed at the local jail will be moved to federal prisons The administration will find excess federal land for construction of a 500-bed pretrial detention facility to be built within one year. The federal <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prisons </ORGANIZATION> will build within two years a 700-bed correctional institution for the <LOCATION> Washington-Baltimore </LOCATION> area. _ LAW ENFORCEMENT: Expansion of the current task force which combines federal, state and local law enforcement officials to include 57 more people including 25 <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents, 11 <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents and five intelligence analysts from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> In addition, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> will assign 10 military lawyers to augment the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's staff and the local <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> will help the task force in an as-yet-undetermined way. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> will provide access to its own information and its laboratory as well as perform forensic examinations of firearms and other evidence found during drug-related murder investigations. _ PUBLIC HOUSING: The Housing and <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will ease regulations covering eviction of drug offenders from federally funded housing projects <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, with help from the local police, will try to revitalize local housing projects by such actions as the issuance of photo identification cards to legitimate tenants, erection of security fences around projects, establishment of guarded entrances and refurbishment of projects. _ TREATMENT PROGRAMS: <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will authorize the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abuse </ORGANIZATION> to establish three model outpatient clinics that will provide at least 300 new treatment slots by 1990 In addition, <ORGANIZATION> NIDA </ORGANIZATION> will provide immediate technical assistance in the district's current treatment programs. _ JOBS: The <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will expand its local summer training and education program, work with private employers to recruit more young people for job-training programs, and grant $ 100,000 to establish employee assistance programs for drug abuse in small - and medium-sized _ EDUCATION: <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, which by law must increase funds for drug prevention programs in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by 50 percent to $ 1.4 million, also will expedite applications for additional funds and programs to help the drug education effort
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Reagan     04-11 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Reagan,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former President Nixon Asks No Reagan-Bashing in Bush White House</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> did n't like hearing that former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was the object of criticism by some members of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s White House. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> fired off a letter to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> saying as much. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> issued a decree that any such bad-mouthing was to cease. And the whole matter came to the attention of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who wrote <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> a note on the subject, according to <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s spokesman. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> sounded off during a recent senior staff meeting, after a <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> story quoted several current <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> officials anonymously as comparing <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> unfavorably with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. The comparisons focused on <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s active work shedule and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s reputation for leaving detail to aides and keeping short hours. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> would not say whether the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> complaint caused <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>'s order that aides refrain from criticizing the former president. He said that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> speak frequently on the phone and that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has the `` highest respect'' for the man who made him vice president. `` Most of us owe our careers'' to the former president, he said, noting that he and others, including Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, had worked in the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> White House. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Saddle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, confirmed that <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> had written <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> complaining about the story. `` As a matter of fact, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> dropped President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> a note last week,'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> said. In a March 23 story, <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullmann </PERSON> quoted several top-level aides to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, including some who had worked for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, as saying such things as that <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would still have been asleep at 7 a.m. _ the hour <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> usually arrives at the Oval Office. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> dressed down <PERSON> Ullmann </PERSON> during Monday's <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> news briefing, accusing the reporter of making up quotes. Later in the morning, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> apologized for the personal attack on <PERSON> Ullmann </PERSON>, but did n't discuss any further the merits of the story. At the briefing, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said that `` I do n't know anybody who has been bad-mouthing former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said that <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> told staff aides, `` Do n't get caught, you know, making jokes or being lighthearted or anything about the past.'' He quoted <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> as saying, `` I do n't know whether this is true or not, but if it is, do n't let it happen.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-JunkParts     04-11 0458</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Junk Parts,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Audit: Military Stuck with Millions Worth of Useless Parts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHERINE RIZZO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The military has a multimillion-dollar stockpile of useless spare parts because contractors fail to follow specifications and the government neglects to check the shipments, a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> auditor told <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. A two-year audit conducted at the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> concluded an estimated $ 104 million worth of parts failed to conform `` to essential or critical operational characteristics,'' according to a report released Monday to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. The report detailed problems both with the way government contractors ship out parts and the way the military accepts and pays for parts without making sure they meet rigidly drawn specifications. `` Obviously we have a lot of material out there that is not combat-ready,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, told a hearing of the committee, which he chairs. `` I want to know why we are accepting substandard parts.'' Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> he would order spot inspections of parts as they're delivered. And Brig. Gen. <PERSON> M.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> has started to equip its depots with equipment to test parts as they come in. `` It's obvious we need to do more checking,'' <PERSON> Pepe </PERSON> said. `` We had n't been doing enough checking.'' In addition, since July 1988 competitive contracts have included a one-year warranty requiring replacement or refund of substandard parts, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaaf </PERSON>, deputy inspector general for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, said the audit covered spare parts chosen randomly from the <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Robins </ORGANIZATION> warehouse. About 58 percent, or $ 12.9 millon worth, of the gun parts tested in the study were unusable. Only 8 percent of examined gun parts, with such functions as feeding ammunition into 20mm and 30mm aircraft-mounted guns, conformed to specifications, the audit report said. Tests of mounted bearings, which are used in aircraft landing gears and wing flaps and on helicopter main rotor heads, indicated 38 percent conformed to specifications and 30 percent were unusable. Below-standard parts routinely were accepted and used, though the failure to conform to specifications meant they did n't last as long as they would have if they met the standards, the report said. <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaaf </PERSON> said auditors found numerous examples of contractors who shipped defective parts to one branch of the service, but other branches were n't told of the problems and gave the same contractor orders for identical or similar parts. In one case, `` one part of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> gave new work to a contractor while another part of the same <ORGANIZATION> Logistics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> hauled $ 1.5 million worth of the same contractor's parts to the scrap yard,'' <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaaf </PERSON> testified.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     04-11 0525</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beetle Bellies May Hold Key to Safer Food Supplies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A natural yeast found in a beetle's stomach can neutralize deadly farm chemicals and natural toxins that sometimes are found in the nation's food supply, according two government scientists. Entomologists <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON> and <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shen </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said that if preliminary tests are borne out in further experiments, the yeast could be used to remove potentially harmful toxins from livestock feed and to clean up the environment. `` Although we're not yet sure of its full range of detoxifying ability, the implication we see here is for the environmental cleanup situations, like toxic waste dumps,'' <PERSON> Shen </PERSON> said. If the yeast can be developed properly, it could be mass-produced to detoxify a wide variety of plant and chemical toxins in the environment, he said in a report issued by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> agency.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Coast Guard to Ease Seizure Rules in Drug Cases</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> is making permanent its decision not to seize vessels when only small quantities of drugs are found on board. The agency announced Monday a rulemaking that would subject the owners of commercial fishing vessels to a summons in cases when personal-use quantities of illegal drugs are found on their ships. The issuing of summonses in such cases was instituted on an interim basis Feb. 16 and the rulemaking would make that permanent, the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> said. Before that, vessels had been subject to immediate seizure when any quantity of drugs was found. The new regulation covers commercial fishing, fish processing and fish tender vessels. Separate laws extend similar protection to ferry boats, cruise ships and other commercial vessels in cases in which a passenger brings small quantities of drugs on board. However, these vessels remain subject to seizure if there is evidence that the master or operator of the vessel was aware of the violation.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>New Search for MIA Remains Set This Week</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pentagon is sending investigators to <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> this week for 2 -LCB- weeks to search for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen missing from the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. In addition, the Vietnamese government has informed the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> it intends `` to repatriate 21 remains, which may be those of Americans, on April 27,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement on Monday. The investigative teams will arrive in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> on Wednesday for what will be the fifth such joint mission working with Vietnamese officials in the field. The three teams _ two comprised of investigators and one consisting of forensic scientists _ have been told they can remain in the country until April 30, making this the longest such mission ever, the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> added. Previous U.S.-Vietnamese field missions were limited to 10 days each. The teams concentrate their efforts primarily on investigating geographic areas near the last known position of so-called `` discrepancy'' cases. A discrepancy case is one in which the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has reason to believe an American serviceman survived an airplane crash or hostile fire. The joint teams also attempt to investigate live-sighting reports and other claims about the fate of missing servicemen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890411-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-11-89 0210EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     04-11 0954</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0997</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Rodney </PERSON> <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> went to court to stop a hotel chain from using his voice in its commercials because he `` ca n't get no respect'' elsewhere. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Dickran </PERSON> <PERSON> Tevrizian </PERSON> scheduled a pretrial hearing Sept. 11 and trial Oct. 17 unless <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> can settle their differences. <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> alleges an impersonator illegally mimicked his voice on a radio commercial. `` The case poses the question of whether someone can do a satire of a famous person and get the benefit of something someone has spent their whole life developing,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lavely </PERSON>, the entertainer's lawyer. <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON>, he said, has spent a lifetime developing a unique voice, style and remarks such as, `` I ca n't get no respect.'' Attorneys for Park Inns argue they have the right to satirize famous people. They also said the commercial, which has been discontinued, contained a disclaimer that celebrity voices were impersonated. <PERSON> Dangerfield </PERSON> was not in court Monday, but his complaint said the disclaimer was insufficient.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CULVER CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
