<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-UN-Iran 1stLd-Writethru a0779 09-29 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UN-Iran, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0779,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Blames Iraq for Cease-fire Stalemate, Threatens Force</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: 2 grafs SUB for 4th graf, `On Friday ... with BACKGROUND on
Iraq blaming Iran for talks stalemate. Picks up 5th graf, ``Iraq has ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICTORIA GRAHAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> blamed <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> Friday for the stalemate in their year-old peace talks and said if <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> does not withdraw from captured territory `` within a reasonable time'' <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> must consider other, forceful action. Iranian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> that after more than one year and 15 rounds of U.N.-sponsored talks, virtually no progress has been made since establishment of a cease-fire. He called on the international community and the <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to put pressure on <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> to withdraw immediately to international borders and release all prisoners of war, as demanded in a <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> resolution. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, he said, is ready to comply fully with all obligations. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, in turn, has repeatedly accused <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of bogging down peace talks. At a summit conference of the non-aligned movement in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>, on Sept. 5, <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Tariq </PERSON> <PERSON> Aziz </PERSON> charged in remarks made to reporters that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> rejects peace talks with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Friday renewed the mandate of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeeping group in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> for six more months and called upon both countries to implement the council's peace plan. `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has refused to take the very first step in fulfillment of its obligations ... namely, withdrawal from the territory of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> said. `` <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> has tried to take advantage of illegal occupation of the territory of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> for realization of illegitimate and expansionist ambitions for which it launched a war of aggression.'' He said that <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> `` must realize that peace is to the benefit of the two countries and the region. Continuation of the present no-peace-no-war situation can gradually move the region toward resumption of tension,'' <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> said. He said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> welcomes the forthcoming visit of special <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> envoy <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Elliason </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> ambassador of <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>, to both capitals and will continue to cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> secretary-general. `` But if these efforts do not lead within a reasonable time to a change in <LOCATION> iraq </LOCATION>'s stance, other measures must be contemplated,'' <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> said. Earlier Friday he told a news conference that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would use force to recapture its territory if <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> does not withdraw. He was repeating a statement by Iranian President <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> several weeks ago. In his speech Friday <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> also condemned <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>'s use of chemical weapons in their war and said any international ban on such weapons, as proposed by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and others, must include strong punitive measures. Earlier Friday, <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> said his government was ready to help seek the release of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> releases billions of dollars of Iranian assets frozen since the storming of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> by Iranian radicals in 1979. `` If we can do anything to help any country -LRB- win release of its hostages -RRB-, we do not hesitate,'' <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> said in answer to a question. `` But I hope the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> also will take some measures in releasing our frozen assets.'' <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>, asked about the relationship between hostages and assets, said: `` It is not our duty to talk about hostages who are kept in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, which is another country. Some countries ask us to help about hostages and that is based on reciprocity.'' Sixteen foreign hostages, including eight Americans, are being held in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> by pro-Iranian Islamic fundamentalist groups and <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is believed to wield influence with them. Longest held is <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, who was abducted 4 -LCB- years ago. <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON> emphasized the new Iranian government, believed more pragmatic and intent on economic reconstruction, `` is against any hostage-taking and holding innocent persons hostage.'' For several years, he said, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has exerted considerable effort to help some countries with hostages in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Velayati </PERSON>, asked about prospects for better relations with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said that from the beginning of the Iranian revolution in the late 1970s the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> `` has had hostility against us and still continues the same policies.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Mecham     09-29 0316</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mecham,0324</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court Lets Mecham Impeachment Stand</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Friday rejected former Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s lawsuit seeking reinstatement and more than $ 600,000 in back pay and expenses. The court said it no power to overrule the state <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> which removed the first-term Republican from office last year when it convicted him on civil impeachment charges he misused money in a state protocol fund and tried to obstruct an investigation. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> told a news conference the decision `` invited legislative anarchy.'' He said he might appeal to federal courts but only if he could raise $ 150,000. Otherwise, he said, he'll take his case back to the people in running again for governor next year. `` Justice in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> today can only be found with the people at large, certainly not with the justice system,'' he said, adding, `` This is a war, not a battle.'' Some of the money issues raised in <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> case are also the subject of a lower court lawsuit, and the justices said <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> could continue to pursue them there or in the Legislature which can authorize payments itself. His lawyer argued that the protocol fund statute was drafted unconstitutionally and that senators were allowed to vote on the charges without having heard all the evidence or agreeing on what the exact charges were. But the justices said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was free to impeach <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> for his general course of conduct whether or not the conduct violated any particular statute and whether or not the statute was unconstitutional. Because impeachment trials are political in nature, courts have no right to interfere as long as lawmakers follow the few rules for impeachment set forth in the <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> Constitution, they added. Aides to Democratic Gov. Rose Mofford, the elected Secretary of State who assumed office after <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON>'s ouster on April l4, 1988.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ShuttleAssignments 1stLd-Writethru a0794thestatethroughmid-1989
09-29 0437</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle Assignments, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0794,0440</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Black Woman Named to a Space Flight</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS third graf, `Dr. Jemison...', to CORRECT birthplace to
Decatur, Ala., sted Decatur, Ill.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> on Friday named astronaut crews for five space shuttle missions, including the first black woman selected for space flight. Dr. <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jemison </PERSON>, 32, a physician, was assigned as a mission specialist to a June 1991 flight aboard shuttle Discovery. The mission is to conduct life sciences and materials processing experiments. Dr. <PERSON> Jemison </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Decatur </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION>, but considers <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where her parents live, to be her hometown. She received a bachelor of science degree in chemical engineering from <ORGANIZATION> Stanford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1977 and a doctorate in medicine degree from <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in 1981. She was working with <ORGANIZATION> CIGNA </ORGANIZATION> Health Plans of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and as a general practicioner in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> when selected for the astronaut program in 1985. Named to fly with Dr. <PERSON> Jemison </PERSON> were <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> and <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. Other crew members will be picked later. Astronauts were named for flights in late 1990 and early 1991. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> will command an October 1990 Atlantis mission which will dispatch the Ulysses spacecraft to study the sun. The others are Marine Lt. Col. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cabana </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepherd </PERSON>, Coast Guard Cmdr. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Melnick </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Akers </PERSON>. <PERSON> Melnick </PERSON> is the first <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> astronaut picked for a flight. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Coats </PERSON> will command the crew of Discovery on an unclassified <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> mission set for November 1990. The others are <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Harbaugh </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> McMonagle </PERSON>. Previously assigned to this mission were <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> Guion </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bluford </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hieb </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacy </PERSON> <PERSON> Veach </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Foale </PERSON> were named to a March 1991 flight aboard <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> which is to study the sun and Earth's atmosphere Picked earlier for this flight were <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lampton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lichtenberg </PERSON>. Others will be named later. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> will command Atlantis on a May 1991 flight which will deploy and then retrieve a package of science instruments developed by the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicollier </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> astronaut, will be a crew member, as will <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> astronauts <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Chang-Diaz </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> who has made one shuttle flight and is training for another set for launch next month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     09-29 0129</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chief of Bureau Named in West Virginia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattiace </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> since 1982, has been named chief of bureau in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION> The appointment was announced Thursday by <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>. <PERSON> Mattiace </PERSON>, 38, will direct <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> operations in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, succeeding <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinney </PERSON>, who will take a new assignment. <PERSON> Mattiace </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in 1976 in <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, and later that year was named correspondent in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where he worked until assigned to <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mattiace </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, and a graduate of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peter </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. He worked for The Dispatch in <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; The <LOCATION> News-Virginian </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Waynesboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and The Press in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, before joining the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0033EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-DeadFish     09-29 0608</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Dead Fish,0627</SECOND>
<HEAD>Syrian Shellings Killed Millions of Fish off Christian Enclave</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOUNIEH, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six months of Syrian shellings have killed millions of fish in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> off this Christian enclave near <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and threatened one of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s few natural resources, a government ecologist says. The shellings stopped with the recent cease-fire in the battle for <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> but damage to the fish population and the livelihoods of local fishermen remain critical. `` Our sea is dying,'' ecologist <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Malichev </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said in an interview. `` It's become rotten and polluted. Our marine life is nearing its end and we have no fish for next year.'' He estimated that along with the millions of fish killed, billions of their eggs also perished. <PERSON> Malichev </PERSON> said fish not killed by the hundreds of exploding 130mm howitzer shells and salvoes of rockets were poisoned by tetryl, one of the explosive elements in the shells that is released into the water. The shellings also forced most of the enclave's 500 fishermen to remain ashore. But about 75 of them risked going out after dark to gather the thousands of fish that would float up dead on the surface after each shelling. `` After a heavy round of shelling, the dead fish float like a carpet on the surface,'' fishermen <PERSON> Sirop </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornakian </PERSON> said before the cease-fire took effect. `` We usually wait a bit and then head for the carpet. Most times I collect about 25 kilograms -LRB- 55 pounds -RRB- of fish every trip.'' The Syrians shelled the 28-mile coastal enclave and its waters to keep cargo ships and tankers from running a blockade with supplies for the Christian forces of Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> in the battle of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. `` The shelling has killed our season,'' said <PERSON> Kivork </PERSON> <PERSON> Manoukian </PERSON>, a fisherman for more than 40 years. `` Usually this time of the year is the best for us, when we make some money. But this year's been catastrophic.'' His friend, <PERSON> Arten </PERSON> <PERSON> Khishkhishian </PERSON>, said he gave up fishing because his nets were torn by twisted rocket casings and lumps of shrapnel littering the shallow waters off <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> and the ancient port of <LOCATION> Byblos </LOCATION> a few miles north. `` I've had to repair my net three times and that cost more than 100,000 pounds -LRB- $ 200 -RRB-,'' he said. `` I decided to stop this ` shrapnel fishing' until there's lasting peace.'' But the others risked their lives and their boats, 15-foot craft powered by outboard motors, to haul in the dead fish. Sometimes a Syrian barrage would come unexpectedly. Police said several fishermen were wounded. <PERSON> Kevork </PERSON> <PERSON> Manoukian </PERSON> said that on one night `` it looked quiet so I dropped my net.'' `` Then the next minute a shell hit about 100 meters away from my boat,'' he said. `` I ditched my net and made it for the shore in panic as more shells exploded around me.'' Ornakian and other fishermen went out regularly for catches not much bigger than those they were netting before the fighting. With fish in short supply in the enclave, the price has doubled to the equivalent of about $ 4.50 a pound. Ornakian and the others reckon that the money they made from each trip _ the equivalent in Lebanese pounds of about $ 250 _ was worth the chance. Moslem fishermen are banned from the waters off <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, where the Syrians deployed batteries of long-range artillery along the waterfront to shell the Christian coastline. But the Moslems are able to fish south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> for 50 miles down the coast to the ancient port of Tyre, where the biggest danger they face is an occasional Israeli gunboat.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-NorthernIreland     09-29 0774</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Northern Ireland,0795</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leaked Files Causing Uproar in Northern Ireland</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A mysterious rash of leaked security files has led to new accusations that <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s embattled security forces are cooperating with <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> murder squads The British government is embarrassed, the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> government is expressing dismay, and the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is enjoying a propaganda windfall in its war to rid <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> of British rule. Desperate to build credibility with the deeply suspicious <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> minority, the police force has taken the drastic step of calling in 19 detectives from <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> to conduct an independent inquiry into the source of the leaks. The affair began Aug. 29, when <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> reporter <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> was taken blindfolded to meet four masked men who had files and a videotape to show. The men claimed to belong to the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighters </ORGANIZATION>, a shadowy Protestant organization that specializes in killing Catholics. Four days earlier the group had killed <PERSON> Loughlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Maginn </PERSON>, a 38-year-old Catholic father of four. The masked men said they wanted to convince the reporter that <PERSON> Maginn </PERSON> was on file as an <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> suspect and was not an innocent victim. If, as the <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> group claimed, the files came from the security forces, then how did they fall into the hands of an illegal and murderous organization? The furor has worsened in the ensuing weeks as at least eight more security files have surfaced. The files consist mainly of sheets of photos with names and addresses of <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> suspects. In the hands of the police or army, the files are routine anti-terrorism documents. In the hands of the <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> group, they are death lists. `` This is an intolerable situation,'' said <PERSON> Seamus </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallon </PERSON>, a leading politician in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> who, while consistently critical of the security forces, has in the past urged fellow Catholics to cooperate with police investigations of <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> outrages. <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>'s political wing, has long claimed that collusion exists between the security forces and <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> groups. <PERSON> Mallon </PERSON>, who belongs to the more moderate Social Democratic and <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, says the fact that files are leaking out of security bases all over the province points to a widespread problem. The Royal Ulster Constabulary, the province's police force, has published a statement by its chief constable, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Annesley </PERSON>, in all <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>'s daily newspapers. `` The RUC -LRB- police -RRB- will not tolerate wrongdoing, should it be uncovered in its own ranks, or flinch from tackling it in any other branch of the security forces, or anywhere in society,'' the statement said. Some lists have come to <PERSON> Mallon </PERSON>, others have gone straight to the media. At least two disappeared from police stations, and two more from bases of the locally recruited <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regiment </ORGANIZATION>. In most cases they have been mailed without explanation, but one, sent to a Scottish newspaper, came from a former soldier who said he wanted to show how easy it was to obtain such documents. Another, sent anonymously to a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> newspaper, The Independent, included the names of 25 people living in the <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>. This added a fresh dimension to the controversy because it suggests that intelligence collected by <LOCATION> Irish </LOCATION> police and shared with colleagues across the border may also be available to the murder squads. Deputy Chief Constable <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, the English policeman leading investigations of the leaks, said Thursday that a British soldier serving in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was returned to his former posting in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> after being questioned about leaked intelligence. Details were not available. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> also announced his inquiry team of 15 was strengthened to 19. Critics say some of those listed are simply victims of mistaken identity. `` One is a well-known businessman with no connection with subversive activity, and at least six of the addresses published are wrong, which puts the lives of innocent people in jeopardy,'' <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Sinn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fein </ORGANIZATION> told a news conference. The affair reflects the blurred line between law and lawlessness in a province where 20 years of conflict have spawned an array of illegal `` paramilitary'' outfits of <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> republicans and Protestants loyal to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. The Royal Ulster Constabulary knows it can isolate the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> only with the cooperation of Catholics, and it has made strenuous efforts to shed its old sectarian image. Its statistics show that last year, more Protestants than Catholics were charged with murder, even though <ORGANIZATION> Catholics </ORGANIZATION> committed three times more murders. Indeed, one theory holds that the Protestants have chosen to publicize their alleged links with the security forces in retaliation for the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ulster </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>'s crackdown on their racketeering activities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HokeyMen     09-29 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hokey Men,0733</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pushcart Street Cleaners Pick Up Where Machines Leave Off</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER BRANDLON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BALTIMORE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They no longer wear white uniforms with roses in their lapels, but every litter bit still counts to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>'s pushcart street sweepers, who pick up where mechanical street sweepers leave off So popular are the 110 men and women who sweep, shovel and spiff up the city's sidewalks and gutters that when one of them takes a vacation or sick leave, it's not unusual for residents to call the city and ask where they are. The city calls them `` hokey men'' _ regardless of their sex _ because of their compact `` hokey carts'' stocked with cleaning tools and paper trash bags. No one seems to remember how the carts got their name. Their job is to tidy the corners and crevices that the street sweepers ca n't reach. They bag autumn leaves, shovel snow and harvest the summer's crop of used Popsicle sticks and other trash. They sweep between parked cars and scoop cigarette butts out of the cracks in the sidewalk. <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, which was incorporated in 1796, is by no means spotless, and its age shows in many places. Nevertheless, public works officials in other Eastern cities are envious of <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>'s cleanliness and the attention lavished on its public spaces by the hokey cart operators, said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Kapplin </PERSON>, executive director of the city's Public Works Museum `` It seems in the 20th century that it's a very antique way to do things,'' <PERSON> Kapplin </PERSON> said. `` But it's really the only way to keep the city clean, if you want to do the total job.'' Nowadays, they fill out civil service applications and don fluorescent orange T-shirts or overalls before setting out to erase the evidence of urban carelessness. But a century ago, men had to earn their way into an elite street cleaning corps known formally as the White Wings and informally as the Beauty Squad. `` From the days we were settled and through the 18th century, roving bands of pigs and dogs cleaned the streets. There were n't any government services,'' said <PERSON> Kapplin </PERSON> That was changed by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Waring </PERSON>, who became <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s commissioner of street cleaning in 1885 and transformed a menial task into an honorable calling by forming the first refuse patrols, according to museum officials Inspired by <PERSON> Waring </PERSON>'s initiative, <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>'s White Wings were organized about the turn of the century. Each man on the Beauty Squad wore white duck trousers, a white jacket studded with brass buttons and a cork helmet. The $ 5 cost of the uniform came out of the men's $ 10 weekly salaries, according to museum officials. Some men added a natty touch by wearing a rose boutonniere. Sadly, <PERSON> Kapplin </PERSON> said, respect for the elite squad declined around 1920, after the special uniforms wore out and were replaced by drab gray outfits. But the hokey men who evolved carry on the same tradition, he said. `` They're very proud. They're career people.'' Actually, the job is considered an entry-level position, paying a starting wage of $ 7.46 to $ 8.89 an hour. But some of the hokey men like the work so much they never leave it. `` I'm the type of person who likes to work outside. I get to meet people,'' said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdock </PERSON>, a 16-year hokey veteran. `` To me it's a great job.'' <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Goods </PERSON> has belonged to the group only since last December, but he's already got a pet peeve: `` It bothers me when one car parks with its front end all the way over the sidewalk and you ca n't clean the space. Then when they leave, it spoils the whole area, makes it look like an eyesore.'' Nine hokey carts are detailed to the downtown area. The rest are sprinkled along heavily traveled streets and in neighborhoods throughout the city. The street cleaners develop a sense of belonging in the neighborhoods they patrol, and the feeling is often mutual, said <PERSON> Orville </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Swafford </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waste </ORGANIZATION>. `` If a hokey man is sick, we get loads of calls from people saying, ` Where is our hokey man?''' <PERSON> Swafford </PERSON> said. `` Also, there was one who works on Baltimore Street who came back on his vacation to make sure his ` customers' were being served.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RequestDenied     09-29 0665</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Request Denied,0684</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Force Refuses Dying Employee's Request for Flight Home</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DIAMOND</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A civilian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> employee dying of cancer in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> wants to spend his last days in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> where he grew up. But the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, despite pressure from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and a White House aide, refuses to provide an air ambulance ride home. Even if regulations permitted the flight, the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> says, someone would have to pay for it, and it could cost more than a civilian air ambulance. <PERSON> Avram </PERSON> <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> was in and out of a coma Thursday at his home in <LOCATION> Palmdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, about 45 miles north of downtown <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The 25-year-old native of <PERSON> Norwood </PERSON> learned he had an inoperable brain tumor a year ago, just weeks before he was married. He was a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> computer operator for three years, working on such projects as the B-2 stealth bomber at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. In July, doctors estimated he had a few weeks to live. <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> wants to die in his home state where most of his friends and relatives live. But the latest estimate from a private air ambulance company is that it would cost $ 29,000 to fly him coast to coast. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>, citing regulations, refuses to take on the job. `` I understand their position, that they just ca n't pick up and take anybody,'' <PERSON> Brody </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Amy </PERSON>, said in a telephone interview. `` But by the same token he worked for them. He worked for his country, defending his country and they're not helping him in his time of need.'' Not for lack of influential help have the <ORGANIZATION> Brodys </ORGANIZATION> failed to move the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> off its position. Rep. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, D-Mass., on the powerful Rules Committee, and Rep. <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mavroulas </PERSON>, D-Mass., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, have made Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., has been contacted <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Card </PERSON>, a native of <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> and a top aide to White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON>, has his staff working on the case. But the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> is firm. <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Maj. <PERSON> Fran </PERSON> <PERSON> Tunstall </PERSON>, a press spokesman based in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> might qualify for an airlift home if his illness were caused by his government work, if the trip were necessary to receive some special medical treatment, or if there were some chance for survival. But even if <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> met those criteria, he would have to pay for the flight and <PERSON> Tunstall </PERSON> estimated the cost at $ 30,000, since it would involve a special trip for a plane stationed in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>. Only if <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> were a uniformed officer whose medical situation was a life-or-death emergency could <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> be eligible for a free flight, he said. <PERSON> Tunstall </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> was sensitive to <PERSON> Brody </PERSON>'s plight but had to draw the line somewhere on transporting government employees _ particularly when the flight involved costly medical preparations. `` This is n't a greed factor,'' he said. `` It just seems so cold and heartless,'' said state Rep. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, who has been trying to help the <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> family. Mrs. <PERSON> Brody </PERSON>, 25, said her husband's medical problems began to crop up a few months before they were married, but they went ahead with the ceremony. `` We had planned on getting married and we did n't want to disrupt the event,'' she said. Going to <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> also would make her life easier. <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> would be able to stay in a hospital for the terminally ill not far from his mother's home. Now, he is bedridden at home and Mrs. <PERSON> Brody </PERSON> has had to stop working to care for him. One of the public officials working on the case is <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON>, a client advocate for the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Office of Handicapped Affairs. `` His wife is having to cope with the ultimate horror of seeing their joint future destroyed by a cruel death,'' <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON> said. `` The question I would raise is this: Is elementary compassion too much to ask?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-OverdueBenefits     09-29 0200</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Overdue Benefits,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman Gets Social Security Benefits 17 Years Overdue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BISMARCK, N.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A woman whose Social Security files got lost in a bureaucratic shuffle finally got a check for $ 19,000 in back benefits for the past 17 years. <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON>, 86, of <LOCATION> Mandan </LOCATION>, said after getting the check Thursday she was n't sure exactly how she would spend the money. `` I have n't any idea,'' she said. `` But I have eight grandchildren and two sons, and I'm sure I can find some place for it.'' Mrs. <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> was getting monthly Social Security check based on the earnings of her late husband when she remarried in 1972. Under a law passed two years later, her benefits should have been raised to reflect the higher earnings of her second husband, said <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Haugen </PERSON>, an aide to Rep. <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>, `` Social Security searched for people eligible, but she fell through the cracks,'' <PERSON> Haugen </PERSON> said. `` There turned out to be a couple of snags in the application, and her Social Security file was lost.'' Mrs. <PERSON> O'Neil </PERSON> heard she might be eligible for more money and contacted the congressman's office in July, which got Social Security to recalculate her benefits, <PERSON> Haugen </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     09-29 0993</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1033</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Talk-show host <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> is about to be married for the third time, but he does n't consider himself a two-time loser _ the losers are those who marry only once, he says. `` We are shocked when people marry several times, but if society would admit it, the truth is that many couples who've been married 50 years probably met other people and were afraid to move on,'' King, 55, writes in the Sept. 29-Oct. 1 issue of `` USA Weekend. King is confident his marriage to <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, 41, who runs a lawyer-recruitment firm in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, will last. `` What <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> and I both know _ and this is what experience gives you _ is there can never be anything after this, or anything as strong,'' he said. <PERSON> King </PERSON> says he married his first wife, <PERSON> Alene </PERSON>, `` because in'61 you got married if you wanted a family.'' They divorced after having one daughter, <PERSON> King </PERSON> said, because `` we really never understood each other.'' He married his second wife, <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON>, in 1976. That marriage did n't work, he said, because they competed for attention. His relationship with <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, who is once-divorced, is different, King says. `` This will be the first time I'm walking down the aisle with not only someone I love but also someone I adore and who is my friend,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brando </PERSON>'s performance as a trial lawyer battling <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s apartheid system in `` A Dry White Season'' won a thumbs-up from the man considered to be the inspiration for the role. `` He's a great actor, and I was truly moved,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bizos </PERSON>, a lawyer who has handled some of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most famous political cases, said Thursday. <PERSON> Bizos </PERSON> represented <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> in 1963 when the nationalist leader was sentenced to life in prison, and was involved in the inquiry into the death of black activist <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Biko </PERSON> in 1976. <PERSON> Bizos </PERSON>, who was attending a conference this week examining a post-apartheid constitution for <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, said the film portrays `` a compressed reality'' of life in the country. `` It's improbable that all those things happened to just two families,'' he said, `` but all the events in the film have happened to South Africans.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s is holding its first horse auction this weekend, putting 98 of entertainer <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s prized Arabian horses on the block. The sale Saturday evening at <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>'s plush <ORGANIZATION> Casa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shenandoah </ORGANIZATION> ranch, on the city's southwest side, should bring in about $ 750,000, said <PERSON> Sealy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodger </PERSON>, a Sotheby's spokesman. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> has been breeding Arabian horses for 25 years and is raising a herd of more than 250 on his ranch at <LOCATION> Logandale </LOCATION>, northwest of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s `` Aramus'' herd, named after a favorite Polish national champion stallion owned by the entertainer, is considered one of the top five Arabian herds in the world.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, whose country has some impressive large structures of its own, was astonished by the heights of the World Trade Center nonetheless. `` They are such huge buildings that I could see from the windows here, the other big buildings look like small villas in comparison,'' <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> said during a visit Thursday. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>, in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to push President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to support an <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> plan for bringing peace to the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>, stopped here as part of an Egyptian fashion exhibit at the 110-story building.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RENO, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had to cancel his first scheduled appearance since undergoing skull surgery, so his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, will stand in for him. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was to have spoken at the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grocers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> annual conference here Monday. `` To be on the safe side, his physicians have recommended he not travel away from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> until the second week in October,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said Thursday. <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s recuperation `` continues to go well and his physicians in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> are fully satisfied with his progress.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> underwent surgery Sept. 8 at the <ORGANIZATION> Mayo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, to drain fluid that had accumulated on his brain after he was thrown from a horse July 4.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>FOXBORO, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Rolling Stones wo n't solve this town's budget crunch with a three-day stand at <LOCATION> Sullivan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>, but revenue from the shows will help save some programs The town receives 66 cents on each ticket sold in return for giving the stadium a tax exemption. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON>, clerk of the town <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Selectmen </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday the three sold-out concerts today, Sunday and Tuesday would bring Foxboro $ 108,000. Despite the cash rolling in with the Stones, another $ 200,000 has to be cut from various town departments. `` When you consider our total budget is $ 22 million, it's not a huge amount percentage-wise,'' <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON> said of the Stones windfall. `` But it helps, you bet.'' About 55,000 people are expected to attend each performance.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> made no secret of his admiration for <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> during filming of a television version of <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Williams </ORGANIZATION>' `` Sweet Bird of Youth.'' `` I'm a tremendous fan of hers, and I told her that right from the beginning,'' <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> said. `` I think she was having fun, too. I think she's always wanted to play <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Lago </PERSON>,'' a fading movie queen who hooks up with a gigolo played by <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>. An actor's goal should be to reach a level where you can `` work with the great people and say the great words,'' <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON> said, adding he got the chance to do that working opposite <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> in the TV drama, which will air Sunday on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Harmon </PERSON>, 38, said he deliberately seeks parts that play against his clean-cut good looks to avoid being typecast in lighter roles. `` People in this business love to find a niche for you. But I need the challenges and I need to do different things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PrisonBreak-In     09-29 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Prison Break-In,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Men Break Into, Er, San Quentin?</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN QUENTIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two suspected burglars got to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION> a lot faster than most after unwittingly breaking into the state prison while running from the police. `` It's more than funny; it's a scream,'' <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Zimmermann </PERSON>, a police spokesman for the neighboring cities of <LOCATION> Larkspur </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Corte </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Madera </ORGANIZATION>, said of the incident. The strange chain of events began when three men tried to break into a parked pickup truck Wednesday afternoon in <LOCATION> Larkspur </LOCATION>, which is near <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION>. The truck's owner arrived on the scene, began to chase the men and then hailed a police car. Two of the three fugutives climbed a fence onto prison property, said prison Lt. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. The third man was still missing Thursday night. Two outsiders were caught on prison grounds Wednesday, a 16-year-old boy and <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON>, 18, of <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. Both were booked for investigation of auto burglary and trespassing on a state prison. `` Nothing like this has ever happended here before,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Cal </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Quentin </LOCATION>. `` People just do n't break into prison every day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0137EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Congress-Schools Bjt   09-29 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Schools, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign School Aid Program Has Grown Into `Pork Barrel,' Congressmen
Say</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Several key members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> say it's time to overhaul a $ 35 million grant program which is supposed to help American-sponsored schools and hospitals abroad, but now is a `` foreign affairs pork barrel.'' Their assertion is backed up by internal <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> records that show that administration officials routinely bend the rules in the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Schools </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospitals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Abroad </ORGANIZATION> program in response to pressure from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` My interest is in getting people to rethink the program,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, D-Ind., chairman of the Foreign Affairs subcommittee on the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, the region where many of the program abuses are occurring `` It's become a kind of foreign affairs pork barrel.'' <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Obey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Wis </LOCATION>., showed their displeasure with the 28-year-old program by ordering the <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, which runs it, to withdraw a $ 1.5 million grant intended for an ultra-orthodox Israeli school that trains teachers for other religious schools Rep. <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, has acknowledged he intervened to help an Israeli school get a grant, but said he now believes the process is out of hand `` The competition has become too fierce,'' he said. `` We now have the undignified prospect of individuals approaching senators and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>'' to lobby for their schools. `` We did not envision this kind of political competition.'' Most of the complaints about political interference involve schools with heavily religious orientations, particularly Jewish institutions. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> filed a lawsuit last year alleging that the program violated the constitutional separation of church and state. The lawsuit names 20 Roman Catholic and Jewish schools that received grants, most of them because of political pressure. Most ASHA grants remain in line with the program's aim, which is to showcase <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> achievements in education and medicine overseas. The <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beirut </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Hadassah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, recipients of continuing aid, are often cited as success stories. But the rules for awarding grants state that `` assistance may not be used to train persons for religious pursuits or to construct buildings or other facilities intended for worship or religious instruction.'' Obey, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Appropriations foreign operations subcommittee, and <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> ordered AID earlier this month to scotch a $ 1.5 million grant for <ORGANIZATION> Sha'Alvim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and redirect the money to other institutions by Saturday, the end of the fiscal year. The aim of the college, an ultra-orthodox Jewish institution, is to train rabbis and teachers who would work in settlements in areas such as the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. Such a goal would be at odds with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy, which opposes <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s settlement policy in the occupied lands. Despite its apparent ineligibility, the school was put on the `` approved'' grant list after intervention by Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, R-Wis., according to <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> records and congressional sources In another case, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Belz </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> had been turned down for grants almost annually from 1980 through 1984, its request ranked near the bottom of the merit list by independent reviewers. But in 1985, AID administrator <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> McPherson </PERSON> awarded the school a $ 500,000 grant `` without reference to the results of the FY 1985 review process,'' according to an admission the department filed in the <ORGANIZATION> ACLU </ORGANIZATION> lawsuit. `` The grant was made because Sen. -LRB- <PERSON> Alfonse </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON> strongly expressed the view that the grant should be made and exerted pressure on AID to get it to make the grant,'' the document stated. The grant was approved even though the application had been filed a full year after the deadline, the department said. <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.Y. </LOCATION>, is on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which approves money for AID programs, a fact that `` influenced Mr. <PERSON> McPherson </PERSON>,'' the department said. Telephone calls to <PERSON> D'Amato </PERSON>'s office were not immediately returned. A spokesman for <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Sims </PERSON>, said the senator was not alone in backing the Sha'Alvim school and said it was unfair to single him out. `` To my knowledge, there was no opposition in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. And he contended <PERSON> Kasten </PERSON> was simply supporting the AID administrator's action, rather than influencing it. The program receives requests for as much as three times the amount of aid its budget allows. When projects near the bottom of the list are made eligible through exercise of political might, institutions higher on the list lose out. Among other lawmakers named in the documents as applying pressure to make institutions eligible are Sens. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boschwitz </PERSON>, R-Minn.; <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON>, D-Tenn.; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sasser </PERSON>, D-Tenn.; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Hawaii </LOCATION>; and Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, D-Ill. <PERSON> Inouye </PERSON> was criticized two years ago when it was revealed he sought to funnel $ 8 million to a French school He was forced to rescind the grant after it generated public controversy. In a letter to <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON>, acting AID administrator, Obey and <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON> warned they planned to closely monitor the program. `` We ... may well object if changes are not made in the coming year,'' they wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0123EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitalGains Bjt   09-29 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capital Gains, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Capital Gains Tax Cut Fight Heads to Senate</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fight over President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s cut in the capital gains tax moves quickly to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and into electoral politics following the president's hard-fought victory in the House. A high-profile <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> effort to derail the tax break, which party leaders called a giveaway to the rich, was beaten 239-190 on Thursday. The Democratic alternative contained a tax increase on the wealthy, and 64 Democrats defected to the president's side. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> victory `` was n't unexpected'' but that he would try to buck <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with an alternative of his own when his committee meets next week. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, a longtime supporter of special tax treatment for capital gains earnings, says the nation ca n't afford to give away too many new tax breaks with federal deficits running at $ 130 billion a year. However, others in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> were certain to push for the capital gains cut. The <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> plan would restore universally deductible Individual Retirement Accounts, an idea the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democrats' proposal also embraced. But his plan does n't include their proposal to raise income taxes on the wealthy, who now pay a lower marginal rate than the upper middle class. Setting a lower tax rate for capital gains, which <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> promised in his presidential campaign, would reverse what was considered a major achievement of the 1986 tax overhaul supported by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> _ taxing earned and unearned income at the same rate. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> plan approved Thursday as part of a huge, 2,000-page budget bill would reduce the maximum tax rate on capital gains from 33 percent to 19.6 percent for the next 27 months. After that, the rate would rise to 28 percent, but taxes would not be paid on earnings attributable to inflation. `` A lower capital gains rate will reduce the cost of capital and create incentives for investment in the long-term productive capacity of American industry,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in hailing Thursday's vote Majority Leader <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mo </LOCATION>., called the plan `` a $ 25,000-a-year tax cut on average to 375,000 <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> families _ the wealthiest families in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> _ for some decision they already made'' and not for new investment House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>, D-Wash., said the Democrats took the correct position even though they lost and he would continue the fight `` This is not the end of the process. It is the beginning,'' he said. In the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, the capital gains fight was just one of many in the bill, which will continue to occupy the chamber most of next week. Other, less partisan battles are expected then on whether to repeal the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> catastrophic illness insurance plan, and on new federal support for child care. Regardless of the eventual fate of the bill, the political implications of the vote will linger. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s campaign organization, said his telephone facsimile machines were humming with press releases tagging any Democrats who supported their party as voting for a tax increase and against jobs and prosperity. `` This is one of those votes that you lie awake waiting for, and we got it,'' he said, adding that it would be brought up again for the 1990 elections. Rep. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ohio </LOCATION>, said Democrats also gained issues _ the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>, the federal deficit and the economy. `` Both parties right now are plowing, fertilizing and seeding the fields'' for next year, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HomelessRally-Celebrities     09-29 0224</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Homeless Rally-Celebrities,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Celebrities, Homeless Come Together in Housing Rally</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON>, <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> and other <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> stars joined the homeless in a rally to press for affordable housing. `` It's a shame to see what's happening to our own people,'' <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON> told a crowd of more than 300 gathered Thursday at a new 20-unit, low-priced rental property near downtown. `` Poverty is black, it's white, it's brown, it's red and it's painful, and we're here to do something about it,'' said radio show host <PERSON> Casey </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasem </PERSON>, who recently established his hotel penthouse as a command center in the battle against homelessness The rally was to drum up support for an Oct. 7 homeless rights march on the nation's capital. Other celebrities on hand were actresses <PERSON> Rosana </PERSON> <PERSON> Desoto </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Alicia </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eileen </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Kazan </PERSON>; comedian <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>; radio announcer <PERSON> Shadoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Stephens </PERSON>; and actors <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Saget </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Spano </PERSON>. `` There are people in the street, people who are hungry, babies who take showers in fountains in the park,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Desoto </PERSON>, who co-starred in the movie `` La Bamba.'' `` We're going to turn it around and we're going to start today,'' she said. After the rally, a bus carrying 47 people set off for <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where the travelers are expected to join a caravan going to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, march.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0216EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitalGains-Leadership     09-29 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capital Gains-Leadership,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Vote Raises Questions on Democratic Leadership</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Capital Gains, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s powerful victory on the capital gains tax calls into question whether <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> and his Democratic leadership team can marshal something more important than personal popularity _ votes. On an issue where the Democrats themselves drew the line in the sand, calling the president's position a gift to his rich friends, 64 of their own members crossed over to the other side. The Democrats gave <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> the votes he needed for his 239-190 win on Thursday. `` It puts a big dent in the leadership's new car,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, D-Mont. `` And you remember that first dent the longest.'' The defections cast doubt on whether <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> and his team, who took over just three months ago from their scandal-plagued predecessors, chose the right issue on which to confront <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, since many Democrats were already supporting a capital gains tax cut as a boon to the economy. The vote also raised questions of political lethargy _ whether the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> could have headed off the loss. The process of putting together a Democratic alternative was agonizingly slow and public, completed less than a week before the decisive vote. The alternate proposal to expand <ORGANIZATION> Individual </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retirement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounts </ORGANIZATION> included a tax increase. Democrats argued that it applied only to the nation's 600,000 wealthiest taxpayers, but it still was the political equivalent of taping a `` kick me'' sign on Democratic members' backs. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Finance Committee <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, steered clear of that one when he raised the idea of reviving universal IRAs as an alternative to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s tax cut. <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s panel begins working on the tax issue next week. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> brushed aside the problems as he met with reporters to analyze the vote, saying he was `` comfortable'' with the outcome. `` I think it is a proud day. I am satisfied we took a correct position,'' he said. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s Democratic opponents on the vote were quick to express their admiration of him and discomfort with having to go against their leadership. `` I regret it. I've not enjoyed this at all,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, who was one of the six Democrats who started the ball rolling by supporting <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the Ways and Means Committee. `` I do n't think you can just blame the leadership.'' <PERSON> Andrews </PERSON> and other Democrats said there was little resemblance in this vote to 1981, when <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> held news conferences to decry their leadership and vote with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Any analogy to 1981, when the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s economic plan with the help of renegade Democratic `` boll weevils,'' has some major weaknesses. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was riding high in the polls then, as <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is now, but seemed to have a greater ability to appeal directly to Americans on teleision. `` I do n't think this is -LRB- because of -RRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif., vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Democratic Caucus `` Compared to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, this is not a guy who brings sweat to a brow of a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. ... this is nothing like that.'' But Democrats have to worry, as Republicans were all but gloating over the possibility that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will enjoy a kinder and gentler version of the politics that led to <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s big victories. Republican <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, the minority whip, was plenty comfortable with that scenario. He declared that the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> now has a working majority in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, because the Democratic leadership was representing a liberal wing out of step with most Americans. White House budget director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, bubbling after the vote, said that `` if we conduct ourselves well, there's an opportunity to use some elements of the same coalition on other issues.'' Democrats tried to play down that scenario, saying capital gains was an issue where many Democrats had long-fixed feelings that a lower capital gains rate would help boost the economy. But there was almost no evidence that the Democratic leadership had `` gently persuaded,'' in <PERSON> Foley </PERSON>'s words, any significant number to change their minds and back the party. The complex politics of the Capitol can always produce a silver lining, though. Although <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> fell short, one top <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> aide chuckled that the leadership forced <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to deliver pork-barrel goodies to many Democrats in order to keep their votes. `` He had to help our guys get re-elected in exchange for his legislative victory,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUDProbe     09-29 0727</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD Probe,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>FHA Losses Combine Worst of S&amp;L, HUD Cases</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Massive losses in the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> insurance fund appear to combine the worst of the savings and loan crisis and the federal housing scandal, and taxpayers again may wind up footing the bill, congressional investigators say. The <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> losses _ half of them attributed to fraud and mismanagement _ have swelled the cost of the scandal at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> almost overnight from $ 2.2 billion to $ 6.9 billion, officials said Thursday. The new estimate results from the disclosure that the department's <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> mortgage insurance program lost $ 4.2 billion in 1988 alone. `` With the S & amp; Ls, the farm credit system and now <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION>, it seems to me there was almost a government meltdown in the 1980s,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, head of a special <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> task force on potential fiscal crises, said at a hearing Thursday. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, whose panel is examining taxpayer exposure to abuses in several supposedly fee-based, self-financed government insurance programs, said the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> losses `` combine the worst of the S & amp; L fiasco and the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> scandals.'' `` The <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people again may be left holding the bag for billions of dollars of waste, mismanagement, fraud and abuse,'' he said. <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said the loss figure was a conservative estimate. `` It sounds like a reasonable estimate to me,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s inspector general, told the panel. Comptroller General <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON> told the panel the chief causes of the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> mortgage insurance losses totaling $ 4.2 billion last year were the same as those that set off the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; L crisis that will cost taxpayers a minimum of $ 157 billion under a bill passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> last month. Some of the shortfall stemmed from homeowners in economically strapped areas of the country being unable to make their house payments, <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON> said. But he said at least half of it was due to mismanagement at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>, plus fraud and undercapitalization by private insurers who started writing <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> coverage in 1983 under the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's efforts to privatize the program `` You have to monitor what's happening in the private sector when you delegate to the private sector,'' <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON> said. `` It's just like the <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls. `` We do n't know what's happening with the programs,'' he said. `` Our budgeting and accounting systems are on a cash basis. So no one has to report a problem until they have to write a check. There's a culture of not bringing up bad news.'' Not that some officials did n't try. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> had written several reports on abuses of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> programs before one last spring grabbed the attention of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee and subsequently the media. Only since 1986, <PERSON> Bowsher </PERSON> said, has <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> modernized its accounting systems enough for the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> that he heads to even perform an audit of <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> programs. Without that modernization, it would have been at least another two years before the $ 4.2 billion losses in 1988 would have surfaced. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said a dozen ongoing audits by his office and more than 600 active investigations into <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> activities `` confirm that many abuses are continuing.'' Despite several changes ordered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1987, such as requiring higher down payments and more creditworthiness reviews, he said, `` We continue to uncover schemes to defraud the program.'' About $ 960 million of the <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> loss was attributed to the so-called co-insurance program initiated by <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. Basically, it allows private lenders to write <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> insurance coverage for 80 percent of a mortgage, assuming only 20 percent of the risk themselves but collecting large fees up front in the form of points. But because many private lenders have little or no money of their own at risk as capital in the enterprises, the government often gets stuck for the full tab if the borrower defaults. House investigators cited instances of companies writing federally insured mortgages totaling $ 300 million with as little capital as $ 1 million. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> is now investigating two of those companies _ <ORGANIZATION> DRG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Funding </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Benton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> _ with losses in the tens of millions of dollars. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> said he attempted several times to convince former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> officials to establish capital requirements for writers of <ORGANIZATION> FHA </ORGANIZATION> mortgage insurance but was always rebuffed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ToxicSites-List 2Takes   09-29 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Toxic Sites-List, 2 Takes,950-1,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>With PM-Toxic Sites</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the hazardous waste sites added to and deleted from the national priority list for cleanup under the federal Superfund cleanup law, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Additions:</HEAD>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Motorola </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, 52nd Street Plant, <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Bryant </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Arvin </PERSON>. Fairchild Semiconduct, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. Fresno Municipal Sanitary Landfill, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>. J.H. <ORGANIZATION> Baxter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, Weed. <ORGANIZATION> Jasco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> View </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Lorentz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barrel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Drum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Montrose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Torrance </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION>, Fillmore. <ORGANIZATION> Synertek </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, Building 1, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Barkhamsted-New <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Landfill </LOCATION>, Barkhamsted. <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Meadows </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Durham </LOCATION>. Gallup's Quarry, <LOCATION> Plainfield </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Precision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plating </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Dover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Sussex </ORGANIZATION> County Landfill No. 5, <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Agrico </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Chemform </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pompano </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bumper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Hialeah </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> Mine Sludge Ponds, <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Wingate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Incinerator-Dump </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Firestone Tire, <LOCATION> Albany </LOCATION>. Marzone Inc.-Chevron <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Tifcon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Electro-Coatings, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Cedar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapids </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION>, Soda Springs.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Ilada </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Girardeau </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Lenz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Lemont </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION> Municipal Landfill, <LOCATION> Woodstock </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Prestolite Battery Division, <LOCATION> Vincennes </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>LOUISIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 D.L. Mud, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Abbeville </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAINE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hope </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Albion-Sheridan Landfill, <LOCATION> Albion </LOCATION>. Barrels, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Kysor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cadillac </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSOURI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Kem-pest Laboratories, <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Girardeau </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport-HIS-Fut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coatings </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Wheeling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disposal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Amazonia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Benfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Hazelwood </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Geigy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Aberdeen </LOCATION>. JFD Electronics-Channel Master, <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Starch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Salisbury </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Lindsay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lindsay </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Brook Industrial park, <LOCATION> Bound </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clothing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Minotola </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Witco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW MEXICO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Cimarron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Carrizozo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pagano </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvage </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lunas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW YORK</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Tri-Cities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barrel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crane </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A.I.W. <PERSON> Frank-Mid-County </PERSON> <PERSON> Mustang </PERSON>, Excon. <ORGANIZATION> AMP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rock </PERSON>. Bell Landfill, <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Township </PERSON>. Berks Landfill, Spring Township. <ORGANIZATION> Commodore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Semiconductor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, Lower Providence Township. CryoChem, <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Worman </PERSON>. Eastern Diversified Metals, Hometown. <ORGANIZATION> Jacks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Creek-Sickin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Smelting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Refining, <PERSON> Maitland </PERSON>. North <LOCATION> Penn </LOCATION> - Area 2, <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Novak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sanitary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Landfill </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Whitehall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>. Occidental Chem-Firestone Tire, Lower Pottsgrove Township. <ORGANIZATION> Publicker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Raymark </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Hatboro </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Recticon-Allied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, East Coventry Township. <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Landfill-Waste </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Hermitage </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Tonolli </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, Nesquehoning.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0220EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ToxicSites-List 1stAdd   09-29 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Toxic Sites-List, 1st Add,880</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Tonolli Corp., Nesquehoning.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>RHODE ISLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Rose Hill Regional Landfill, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingstown </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Landfill </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Cayce </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> Property, Travelers Rest.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TENNESSEE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Mallory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capacitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Waynesboro </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TEXAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Dixie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Processors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Friendswood </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>UTAH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Light-American Barrel, <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Buckingham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Landfill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Buckingham </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Culpeper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Culpeper </LOCATION>. Dixie Caverns County Landfill, <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Saunders </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supply </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Chuckatuck </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VERMONT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> BFI </ORGANIZATION> Sanitary Landfill, <LOCATION> Rockingham </LOCATION>. Darling Hill Dump, <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Tansitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Bennington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crossarm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Conduit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Chebalis </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Spokane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shop </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Sauk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Landfill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Excelsior </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FEDERAL FACILITIES</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Rocky Plats Plant, <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>. Aberdeen Proving Grounds-Michaelsville, <ORGANIZATION> Aberdeen </ORGANIZATION>, Md Camp Lejeune Military Reservation, <LOCATION> Onslow </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wright-Patterson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Dayton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, eight areas, <LOCATION> Warminster </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa </LOCATION>. Naval Security Group Activity, <LOCATION> Sabana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. Hanford 100-Area <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Hanford 1100-Area <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Hanford 200-Area <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Hanford 300-Area <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> county </LOCATION> Naval Undersea Warfare Station, four areas, <LOCATION> Keyport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Deletions:</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 These are active hazardaous waste treatment, storage or disposal sites where cleanup is being handled under a different program.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> FMC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Hewlett-Packard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marley </PERSON> Co0oling <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Rhone-Poulenc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc.-Zoecon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Signetics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sunnyvale </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Roseville </LOCATION>. Van Waters & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Kaiser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fontana </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Marietta </PERSON> Corp.-Denver Aerospace, Waterton.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Pratt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Whitney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft-United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Olin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 A.Y. <ORGANIZATION> McDonald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Deere </PERSON> <PERSON> Dubuque </PERSON> <PERSON> Works </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Dubuque </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Frit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humboldt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plant </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Humboldt </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Nameplate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vernon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Sheffield </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Firestone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Noblesville </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Furley </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Montague </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Lacks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, Grand Rapids.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Monroe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Equipment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cozad </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Matlack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Woolwich </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OHIO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Coshocton </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Rohm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Haas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> landfill, <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> IBM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION> plant spill; <LOCATION> Manassas </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WEST VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Mobey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Martinsville </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 These sites are being dropped because they now rank below the cutoff for federal aid according to <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s scoring system for environmental and health threats.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> GBF </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> dump, <LOCATION> Antioch </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Pigeon Point Landfill, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Castle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Stauffer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Heights </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON>'s Bald Knob Landfill, Mt. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890929-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-29-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b w AM-ObsceneArt     09-29 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obscene Art,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Senate Signals Support@Opposition to Helms' Obscene Art Amendment</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: A roll call is planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
