<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Iowa-Investigation 1stLd-Writethru   10-04 0577</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iowa-Investigation, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0812,480</SECOND>
<HEAD>Captain, 3 Others Charged With Dereliction</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 14-15: ``Kathy Kubicina,'' with comment of Hartwig's
sister</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The captain of the USS Iowa and three subordinates were charged with dereliction of duty for violating administrative procedures aboard the battleship on which 47 men were killed in an explosion, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said Wednesday. The actions against the four men, ranging from `` administrative corrective measures to punitive letters of admonition,'' resulted from admiral's mast hearings conducted earlier this week on board the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> by Vice Adm. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Donnell </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. None of the men was relieved of his duties. `` Each person was charged with a dereliction of duty under the Uniform Code of <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> as a result of administrative deficiencies found in the <LOCATION> USS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> investigation,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. Despite violations of procedure, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said, `` None of the discrepancies resulted in or contributed to the explosion'' on April 19. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> investigation concluded that gunner's mate <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> `` most likely'' caused the explosion in the battleship's No 2 gun turret by inserting a detonator between two powder bags. The report, which has come under congressional scrutiny, turned up numerous lax procedures, including experimentation with extra-strength gunpower and projectile loads, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. Those allegations prompted the admiral's mast hearings. As a result of the hearings, Capt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON>, commander of the battleship and the only man publicly identified by the service, and his operations officer, Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Finney </PERSON>, were subject to `` administrative corrective measures,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sources identified <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> and the other two men cited in hearings. A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> source, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> and <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> will not have letters that affect their potential promotions placed in their files, although they will be given the letters. However, the source said their annual fitness reports will reflect the problems on the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> and their careers are likely to be damaged. Stiffer disciplinary action was given to the weapons officer and the fire control gunner, who were given punitive letters of admonition. The weapons officer was fined $ 2,000 and the gunner $ 1,000, but the fines were forgiven. The weapons control officer has been identified as Cmdr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>, while the gunner was Master Chief Petty Officer <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Skelly </PERSON>. The service said the action against <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> was less severe because `` subordinates were held accountable for deficiencies in their specifically assigned duties.'' <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Kubicina </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>'s sister, said she was not surprised by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> action. `` They got merely a slap on the wrists. If they would have gotten something harsher, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> would have had to admit their own guilt. I was prepared for this, which is absolutely nothing,'' she said. <PERSON> Donnell </PERSON> based his punishment on what he concluded was appropriate for each person, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said, insisting that the administrative deficiencies had nothing to do with the explosion. `` It should be stressed that although deficiencies in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s training documentation, weapons handling requirements and adherence to safety procedures were found within the weapons department, the investigation determined that these shortcomings did not cause or contribute to the explosion,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said in a statement In deciding on the punishments, <PERSON> Donnell </PERSON> was `` required to separate the larger tragedy from the process of determining accountability for administrative training, safety and ordnance-handling deficiencies,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. All four men can appeal for a review of the actions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CocaineCache     10-04 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cocaine Cache,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Law Officers Seize Nine-Ton Cocaine Cache</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HARLINGEN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities seized almost 18,000 pounds of cocaine Wednesday in what could be the second-largest amount in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history and arrested five people, officials said. `` We think it's the second-largest cocaine seizure in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, second only to the 40,000 pounds seized last week in -LRB- <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, a spokesman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>. The 17,950 pounds of cocaine _ nearly nine tons _ were seized and the five were arrested fat a rural residence just west of <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION>, said DPS Sgt. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>. Seven men were arrested last week in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> after a record 20-ton cocaine seizure connected to the <LOCATION> Mexican </LOCATION> leg of a major smuggling operation that brought the drug from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. Federal investigators have linked a warehouse in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> and three homes across the border in <LOCATION> Ciudad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juarez </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> cocaine stash. Drug agents said the cocaine apparently came into the country via <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION> and was then shipped to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Salmonella     10-04 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Salmonella,0233</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salmonella That Killed Seven Came From Food</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Health officials are blaming contaminated food for an outbreak of salmonella poisoning that killed seven residents of a geriatric hospital and sickened 160 others. The preliminary findings released Wednesday by <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>'s public hospital authority indicated food preparation at the <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Richet </PERSON> hospital in suburban Cergy <LOCATION> Pontoise </LOCATION> was not the cause of the outbreak. Salmonella poisoning struck nearly one quarter of the hospital's 670 patients shortly after a Sept. 28 dinner of a soup including ground beef, followed by an omelette, with rice pudding for dessert Since Friday, two women and five men aged 85 to 93 have died from food poisoning. The remaining 160 infected patients are not in life-threatening danger, the health authority said in a statement. Residents at the hospital are long-term patients suffering serious illness or handicaps, the health authority said. An investigation conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Pasteur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> will attempt to pinpoint the exact cause of the poisoning, the health authority said. The results will not be known for several days. The mass poisoning is the second in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in three months. Nine patients at a retirement home at <LOCATION> La </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rochelle </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> died over a one-month period after eating salmonella-infected rice pudding July 9. There were 6,000 reported cases of salmonella poisoning in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> during 1988, health officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--QuiteAJug     10-04 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Quite A Jug,0152</SECOND>
<HEAD>Churchill Head Jug He Disliked Sold For $26,400</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHESTER, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A rare pottery character jug modeled after <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, which the World War II leader disliked so much that production was stopped, sold for $ 26,400 at auction, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s says. <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> dealer <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Power </PERSON> bought the 7 -LCB- - inch tall jug of <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>'s head against competing bids from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> telephoned to the sale room this northwestern town <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Proudlove </PERSON>, the auction house spokesman, said only three of the jugs are known to exist. `` Royal <PERSON> Doulton </PERSON> made a few in 1940 before production was stopped when <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON> said he did n't like the way his features were portrayed. The jugs were meant as a tribute to his leadership during the Battle of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> but none was sold,'' he said. The sellers were an unidentified English couple who did not say how they obtained the jug.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AbortionBombing     10-04 0433</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abortion Bombing,0447</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Bomber Released from Prison, Second Set for November</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BILL KACZOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PENSACOLA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of two men who bombed three abortion facilities here on Christmas Day 1984 is free and the other is scheduled to be paroled next month, federal officials said Wednesday. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldsby </PERSON>, both 26 and from the Cantonment community north of <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION>, have served about half of the 10-year prison sentences they received for the Christmas Day bombings. The bombings in this <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION> city, followed by three more in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, area the next week, refocused national attention on the abortion issue. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON> was transferred from the <ORGANIZATION> Tallahassee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> to a work-release program in <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> a couple months ago. He was released from there 59 days early on Sept. 25 under the federal curfew parole program, said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON>, regional administrator for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parole </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Although free, he must observe a curfew until his regular parole date of Nov. 28, <PERSON> Kowalski </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Goldsby </PERSON> is scheduled for release Nov. 21. His initial release date was May 21, 1990, but <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Rast </PERSON>, the regional parole commissioner, moved it up two years ago because <PERSON> Goldsby </PERSON> was credited with superior program achievement, which could include good conduct, work performance and educational advancement. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>, a glass company employee, and <PERSON> Goldsby </PERSON>, a construction worker, were convicted of planting homemade pipe bombs at a clinic and two doctors' offices where abortions were performed. The building in which one office was located was demolished by the explosion and ensuing fire and the other office was seriously damaged. Damage at the clinic, The Ladies Center, was less severe and it soon reopened, becoming the target of numerous anti-abortion demonstrations. One doctor at the bombed-out clinic retired and the other discontinued abortions because insurance companies refused to cover his new office, fearing it also might be attacked as long as he continued that part of his practice. <PERSON> Simmons </PERSON>' wife, <PERSON> Kathren </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Goldsby </PERSON>'s former fiance, <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiggins </PERSON>, were convicted on conspiracy charges and placed on probation. All four had attended the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> God </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> and said the two men were driven by religious conviction. Feminist leaders criticized the sentences are being too lenient to begin with. The terms were the shortest given to people convicted of bombing or torching abortion clinics up to that time. The case drew wide public attention when it went to trial in April 1985 with defense lawyers portraying their clients as idealistic `` knights in shining armor'' or `` <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Huck </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PostPoll     10-04 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Post Poll,130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Approval Still High</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s approval rating remains high, although a majority feel his administration is lagging in the war on drugs, the budget deficit and pollution, according to a <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> poll. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s approval rating as president stood at 76 percent among the 1,535 adults interviewed at random for the survey, which was conducted between Sept. 28 and Oct. 3 and reported on in Thursday editions of the newspaper. Other recent polls have show similar high approval ratings for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. In the war on drugs, 56 percent said the administration is not doing all it can, 68 percent held a similar view on the budget deficit and 71 percent said not enough was being done to combat pollution. However, 61 percent approved of the way <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is dealing with the nation's environmental problems and 72 percent approved of his handling of foreign affairs. The poll has a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bulgaria-Turks     10-04 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bulgaria-Turks,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bulgarian Turks Caught Between Assimilation at Home, Hardship in
Turkey</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROLAND PRINZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOFIA, Bulgaria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of ethnic Turks line up daily at the Turkish Embassy in <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION>, besieging officials for visas to enter <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. But about 20,000 who got visas in past months have come back, unable to find good jobs or housing in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. The Turks have been fleeing a sometimes-violent campaign by Bulgarian authorities, going back to 1984, to force them to use Bulgarian names, curtail their Moslem religious rites and stop speaking Turkish in public. Diplomats in <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> say many of the Turks who have returned face prosecution, although they have no details of such cases. They also say the Turks often are forbidden to return to their previous jobs and homes, partly due to an acute labor shortage in some areas that has prompted authorities to shift manual labor to crucial construction projects and industries. The official Bulgarian news agency, <ORGANIZATION> BTA </ORGANIZATION>, has reported the return rate at 500 to 1,000 a day. A Turkish diplomat in <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> said, however, that ethnic <PERSON> Turks </PERSON> `` still want to leave <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> as vigorously as before.'' `` You can see for yourself. There are some 2,000 people waiting around our consulate every day,'' he said. About 320,000 of <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>'s 1.5 million ethnic Turks began in mid-year to leave for <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> deported some of them. Others emigrated under new liberalized passport regulations. Many had their possessions seized before leaving, and their arrival strained Turkish abilities to absorb them. On Aug. 22, Premier <PERSON> Turgut </PERSON> <PERSON> Ozal </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> closed the border to the ethnic Turks, requiring them to obtain regular visas. His move, part of an attempt to persuade <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> to safeguard the property of those seeking to settle in <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, was widely seen as a diplomatic victory for <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>'s Communist government over <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, which had asserted at one point that it would welcome any Bulgarian Turk facing persecution. Now that <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> is no longer absorbing large new groups of ethnic Turks, the situation of people wanting to emigrate has become even more precarious. About 25,000 would-be emigrants are stranded in <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. Most have sold their houses and other belongings. A Turkish diplomat said his mission now is to issue visas only for family reunification and other urgent case. `` In all, we are interviewing about 800 people a day,'' he said. Only a handful, perhaps a dozen or so, receive visas each day. `` With the numbers we have given out for visa applicants, we are already in the mid-1990s,'' he said of a waiting list for interviews. Long lines reportedly also have formed outside the Turkish consulates in <LOCATION> Varna </LOCATION> on the <LOCATION> Black </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and the southern industrial town of <LOCATION> Plovdiv </LOCATION>. Several diplomats in <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION> asserted that 500,000 more ethnic Turks may want to emigrate to <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. But <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> continues to balk at a new emigration accord with <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> that would set out in detail such things as property rights and social security claims. `` Such a new immigration agreement would limit the free movement of our people under the <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> accords'' on human rights, said <PERSON> Chavdar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mladenov </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> has come under heavy Western criticism over the issue. Officially, <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION> has stopped referring to a Turkish minority in the country. Officials and newspapers now invariably speak of `` Bulgarian Moslems.'' <PERSON> Maldenov </PERSON> asserted flatly that there are no Turks in <LOCATION> Bulgaria </LOCATION>. Turks indeed have left some of the villages in the <LOCATION> Razgrad </LOCATION> area, 270 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Sofia </LOCATION>. `` Of 400 families, 300 left'' for <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>, said one of the handful of farmers in one village. In <LOCATION> Mortagonovo </LOCATION>, another predominantly Turkish village, a frail man in his late 70s sat on a bench, his prayer beads gliding through his fingers. He was asked if he planned to leave. `` I was waiting in a camp down south for 15 days. Then they closed the border,'' he said in halting Bulgarian. `` I sold my house before I left. Now I'm staying with my son.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Politics     10-04 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Politics,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Season Under Way, with Thatcher in Full Cry</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was asked over lunch with foreign journalists how she'd run a political campaign against <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>. Her reply: `` I would n't. I'd vote for her.'' This instant response on Wednesday showed the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister in full, combative cry as she goes into the 1989-90 political season, with three consecutive election victories behind her and every indication she will go for a fourth. Autumn in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> means the annual party conventions, where political leaders take stock of the year and promise victory next time. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s Conservatives convene next week. The opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is halfway through its convention, buoyed by opinion poll leads and a conviction that after a decade of Thatcherism, the British are ready for a change. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> obviously disagrees, but she does so with the zeal and enthusiasm of a first-time candidate rather than a senior stateswoman who turns 64 this month and is the longest-serving leader of a Western democracy. She has been to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and talked to farmers who ca n't get permits for equipment to grow crops. Last month she was in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, watching Soviets selling vodka to her press party, strictly for hard currency. She had her sixth meeting with <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and was struck once again, she says, by the enormous risks of switching rapidly from communism to a free market. Her conclusion is characteristically simple: `` There is no revision, refashioning or reform of socialism that is possible. There's only rejection of it.'' This unwavering conviction that she is right is a Thatcher hallmark, and any suggestion of second thoughts is quickly slapped down. Lately, attempts are being made to penetrate the <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> mystique through long-distance psychoanalysis. <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Abse </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> lawmaker, has just published a 288-page book whose central thesis is that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> suffers from narcissism caused by an unloving mother. On Wednesday, The Independent newspaper said Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> plans to block her official residence with 10-foot-high railings. It said psychiatrists believed it was a sign of the stress caused by 10 years at the helm. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> probably would scoff at such notions. She believes she simply represents basic human instincts. `` Thatcherism is a lot older than me,'' she said. Referring to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s bumpy passage into the brotherhood of European nations, she said she merely wanted to make sure the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> followed Thatcherite principles, namely not to tie free enterprise down in bureaucracy. `` Because we approached the whole of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in the same way as we do at home, we do n't wish it to be tied up with unnecessary regulations,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> likes to illustrate her points with mundane examples, like the Polish farmers last year. She had asked them why they could n't grow enough food. They told her it was because of the difficulty in obtaining farming equipment from officials. `` And then it suddenly dawned on me,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said, `` that it is the whole network of intricate controls which will stop people from being able to make maximum use of their property.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CrippledBomber 3rdLd-Writethru a0820 10-04 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Crippled Bomber, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0820,0819</SECOND>
<HEAD>B-1B Lands Safely After Jammed Nose Gear Forces Transcontinental
Flight</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 15th graf, `The crippled ..., with 2 grafs to UPDATE with
crew IDs, CORRECT that Edwards AFB is 1,200, sted 2,000, miles from Dyess.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ABI1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL FLEEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>EDWARDS AIR FORCE BASE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A B-1B bomber with crippled landing gear flew halfway across the continent Wednesday and made a successful touchdown on the <LOCATION> Mojave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> lake bed where the space shuttle lands. The $ 280 million aircraft, with its four-member crew unable to unlock its nose landing gear, refueled in the air and landed at 6:15 p.m. after 11 -LCB- hours in the air that began as a training flight in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The big bomber trailed a plume of dust as it rolled down the 12-mile-long runway after touchdown, slowly lowering onto its nose. `` There were no injuries,'' said Tech. Sgt. <PERSON> Donn </PERSON> <PERSON> Clarius </PERSON>, a spokesman at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>. `` The flight crew came out just fine. `` There was no fire or explosion or anything.'' He said the bomber suffered some damage, which was being assessed by ground crews as darkness fell. <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Punter </PERSON>, an aerospace buff who monitors military frequencies from his home in <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, listened to radio traffic between the pilots and controllers. Just before touching down the pilot said, `` It's been a great day for flying, except for a few glitches,'' Punter reported. Just after the landing, <PERSON> Punter </PERSON> said he heard the pilot say, `` It was real nice. Structure looking good.'' During the landing, the massive bomber skidded on its nose for more than half a minute, yet it did not break up. No flames were seen. `` It's one of the safest areas to land,'' said base spokeswoman <PERSON> Dottie </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegelberg </PERSON>, adding that the hard clay surface means there are no sparks and minimizes the chance of explosion or fire. The aircraft, flying out of <ORGANIZATION> Dyess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, was n't carrying bombs. `` There are no nuclear weapons,'' said Lt. <PERSON> Anu </PERSON> <PERSON> Sjaardema </PERSON>, an <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> public affairs spokeswoman. An 18-unit disaster preparedness team was mobilized at <LOCATION> Edwards </LOCATION>, including explosives experts, a mortuary services officer, an environmental officer and fire department personnel, the lieutenant said. `` They route a lot of emergencies to our lake bed, both military and civilian. We have a team to respond to that all the time,'' said <PERSON> Sjaardema </PERSON>. The flight crew was Capt. <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Beene </PERSON>, 30, aircraft commander, of the 337th <ORGANIZATION> Bombardment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION>; Capt. <PERSON> Vernon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Benton </PERSON>, 30, co-pilot; Capt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON>, 31, offensive systems officer and Lt. Col. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>, 38, an instructor and offensive systems officer with the 338th <ORGANIZATION> Combat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crew </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Training </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squadron </ORGANIZATION>. The crippled plane was refueled by a tanker plane before flying to <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, about 1,200 miles away. The B-1B, with a maximum speed of 1,000 mph and range of more than 7,000 miles, is 147 feet long and 137 feet wide when its swing-wings are extended. It weighs 477,000 pounds when fully fueled and armed. Maj. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Beth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilgore </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Dyess </ORGANIZATION> said the plane started circling <ORGANIZATION> Dyess </ORGANIZATION> at about 9:30 a.m. PDT. It left for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> five hours later. Mechanics from <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION> and the plane's manufacturer, <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, worked with the plane's crew to try get the nose gear down. The plane's rear wheels were down while it circled <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION>, located at the western edge of <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION>, a city of 100,000 in west <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The plane took off from <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION> at 6:38 a.m. PDT on a training mission. The plane was originally tested at <ORGANIZATION> Edwards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AFB </ORGANIZATION> and Ms. <PERSON> Kilgore </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION> officials believed someone there could figure out the problem. <LOCATION> Dyess </LOCATION> is one of four bases in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> where B-1 bombers are stationed. In March 1986, the variable-sweep wings became stuck on the second production model of the B-1B during a training flight out of <ORGANIZATION> Dyess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AFB </ORGANIZATION>. The pilots successfully made a high-speed landing at <LOCATION> Edwards </LOCATION> when the wings were swept back. The plane stopped after using 13,000 feet of runway. There have been three B-1B crashes and the crash of a B-1 prototype. The most recent crash was in November 1988 at <ORGANIZATION> Ellsworth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>. All four crew members ejected safely. The three crashes left the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> with 97 of the B1-B planes, the first bomber added to <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in about 25 years. Production has been completed, for $ 20.5 billion. The plane was killed by President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> in 1977 and resurrected by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1981. In February, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said problems persist in performance of the plane _ range and payload _ and fuel leaks probably could not be corrected. Fixes could cost $ 400 million per aircraft if the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> decided to do them all, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-BogotaNewspaper     10-04 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bogota Newspaper,180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bombed El Espectador Now Losing Money, Newspaper President Says</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> newspaper that was bombed bcause of its coverage of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s drug trade is now losing money and may have to close, its president is quoted as saying. A car bomb that exploded near the offices of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espectador </LOCATION> on Sept. 2 did $ 2.5 million worth of damage, according to the president, <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, in remarks at a luncheon with editors and reporters of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. A report on the luncheon appeared in Thursday editions of the Post. Advertisers have been threatened, and some smaller ones have left the newspaper, <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said. But among employees, `` no one abandoned the paper,'' he said. `` If we do n't receive some support, we can not continue,'' <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> was quoted as saying. <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> said his company, which employs about 1,000 people and publishes the second-largest daily in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> with a circulation of 200,000, is seeking a long-term, low-interest loan from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s central bank. He is touring the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, in part to seek support from news organizations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Wood     10-04 0365</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Wood,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grand Ole Opry's Ragtime Pianist Dies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VICKI BROWN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Del </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>, The Grand Ole Opry's ragtime pianist whose 1951 recording of `` Down Yonder'' sold more than 3 million copies, died Tuesday at a <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> hospital following a stroke. She was 69. Miss <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> became a member of the Opry in 1953 and was the only person regularly featured at the Grand Ole Opry keyboard. <PERSON> Minnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON> is the only woman who has been on the famous country music show longer than Miss Wood, said Opry spokesman <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Strobel </PERSON>. Miss <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> suffered a stroke last week and was in intensive care at <LOCATION> Baptist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> until her death Tuesday night, said <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, a family friend. Known as `` The Queen of the Ivories,'' her real name was <PERSON> Adelaide </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>. In an interview with the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, she said she still practiced about three hours a week. `` I'd never go on the Opry without first doing a run-through. If I live to be 100, I'm going to do the best I can,'' she said. Grand Ole Opry star <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON> said Miss <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> was a fine pianist. `` I do n't know of any we've had on the Opry better on the piano than she was. She made a very fine reputation for herself in country music,'' he said. Miss <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>'s parents gave her a piano on her fifth birthday and she was schooled in classical music until ragtime _ a jazz-influenced style of pop music _ became her passion as a teen-ager. `` Ragtime has so much get-up-and-go that it's infectious; it's part of our heritage,'' she said After graduating from high school in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>, she worked playing sheet music for customers at a dime store and as a payroll clerk for the state Health Department while pursuing her music career on weekends and at night. She cut a record featuring `` Mine All Mine,'' for RCA and with `` Down Yonder'' on the flip side. `` Down Yonder'' was second on the pop charts for 27 weeks and was also a country hit. Miss <PERSON> Wood </PERSON> also played five songs in the movie `` Rhinestone,'' which starred <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APME-APAwards     10-04 0639</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME-AP Awards,0657</SECOND>
<HEAD>Top Performance Awards From APME</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The annual Top Performance awards of the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors association have been presented to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> bureau, National Writer <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayles </PERSON>, Science Writer <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Q. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haney </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> photographers <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Widener </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Heung </PERSON> <PERSON> Shing </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Applewhite </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The organization also named <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> newswoman <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfous </PERSON> winner of the ninth annual <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON> award for excellence by a young AP writer. The Top Performance awards recognize outstanding work by AP reporters and photographers in the previous 12 months in two reporting categories _ writing on deadline and feature writing _ and two photography categories _ spot news and feature photography. The winners were awarded $ 1,500 and a plaque at the APME convention here Tuesday. The AP <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> bureau was honored for coverage of the suppression of the student-led democracy movement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Those specifically cited were <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilhelm </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Pomfret </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Terril </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Biers </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Biers </PERSON> were on assignment in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bayles </PERSON> and <PERSON> Haney </PERSON>, both of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> bureau, were chosen for a three-part series, `` Six Miles Up and Sleepy,'' about the risks caused by fatigue among airline pilots. <ORGANIZATION> Widener </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> were selected co-winners for their photo coverage of the student demonstrations and subsequent government crackdown in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Applewhite </PERSON> was singled out for a photo of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwater </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, mugging while accompanying a band during the presidential inauguration. The <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON> award is named for a former <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> leader and managing editor of the <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, newspapers who had an abiding interest in good writing and helped young writers improve their skills. He died in 1980. Ms. <PERSON> Dreyfous </PERSON> received a $ 1,000 cash award and a plaque. Additional awards for excellence in the Top Performance reporting competition went to: _ <PERSON> Maureen </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Earleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Herbaugh </PERSON>, both of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>, for coverage of the Soviet troop withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> and its aftermath; _ <PERSON> John-Thor </PERSON> <PERSON> Dahlburg </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Katell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Porubcansky </PERSON>, all of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Sydney </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, for coverage of the catastrophic earthquake in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>; _ <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Shulins </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newsfeatures </ORGANIZATION>, for her story `` Lost Innocence,'' about two elderly <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> brothers whose peaceful lives were shattered by a violent robbery; _ AP <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> staff members <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Noblet </PERSON>, <PERSON> Monte </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Todd </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> McFarren </PERSON>, <PERSON> Susana </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmos </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eduardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Handler </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> McCullough </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Genasci </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Foreign Desk, for their periodic series, `` Continent in Crisis,'' about the economic, political and social turbulence in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>; _ <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>, <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Tad </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bartimus </LOCATION>, all AP regional reporters, and <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Olympia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, for `` Course of Doom,'' an examination of the years of errors that made the Exxon Valdez oil-spill disaster inevitable. Awards for excellence in photography were given to: _ <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Yurchenko </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> for his work in the aftermath of the Armenian earthquake and for a photo of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> checking his watch while <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> spoke in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> in April; _ <PERSON> Katsumi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kashahara </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> for a picture of <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Louganis </PERSON> hitting his head on the diving board at the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> Olympics; _ <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, for a closeup of an oil-covered bird after the <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> spill and for a photo of native Alaskans tending to a gray whale trapped in the ice; _ <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sancetta </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> for her photo series documenting the progress of a young Armenian boy undergoing surgery and therapy for injuries incurred in the Armenian earthquake. The <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> comprises managing editors and other news executives of the 1,478 member newspapers of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, the world's oldest and largest newsgathering organization.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0024EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMECitations 3Takes   10-04 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Citations, 3 Takes,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>APME Salutes Newspaper, Broadcast Contributors</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-APME-AP Awards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Associated Press Managing Editors association has awarded 301 citations to newspapers and broadcast stations for outstanding contributions to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> report. The awards were presented Tuesday by <PERSON> Bennie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivory </PERSON>, managing editor of the Jackson -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Clarion-Ledger and vice chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Citations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, at the annual APME convention. The <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> comprises managing editors and other news executives of the 1,478 member newspapers of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>, the world's oldest and largest newsgathering organization. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> is a cooperative agency whose members provide coverage of news in their areas for distribution through AP bureaus in their states. The citations are in three categories _ news, newsphoto and news-newsphoto. Newspapers and broadcast stations cited in each category were:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>News Citations</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Aiken </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Standard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KXRA AM @ FM Alice -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Echo-News Avon -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- KZYR-FM <LOCATION> Bakersfield </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Californian </PERSON> <PERSON> Barre </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Argus <LOCATION> Batesville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Guard <PERSON> Beatrice </PERSON> -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Daily Sun Beaufort -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette Beaver -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Times </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Belleville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Democrat <LOCATION> Bethlehem </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Globe-Times Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KBLG-AM Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KGHL-KIDX Radio Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KTVQ-TV Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KULR-TV <LOCATION> Bradenton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald Bryan-College Station -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Butte -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Standard Cadillac -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WWTV-TV <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Repository Celina -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Standard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chambersburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Public Opinion <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Observer <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Enquirer <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Post Claremore -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Progress Clarksdale -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Press Register Cleveland -LRB- Miss. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Bolivar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbus </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Republic Columbus -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Dispatch Conway -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Log Cabin Democrat <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KRLD </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WCXI-AM <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KDAL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Duluth </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> WEBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dorado </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- News-Times Enid -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News & amp; <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Times Erie -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning News <LOCATION> Escanaba </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WDBC-AM Fargo -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- WDAY-Radio -LRB- 2 -RRB- <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> KAFF </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Radio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Sentinel and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Telegram <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Bee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun Gallup -LRB- <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KGAK </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gary </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Post-Tribune Gillette -LRB- <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. -RRB- Radio Station KIML Grand Forks -LRB- <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION> -RRB- KFJM Radio Grand Rapids -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WOOD-AM <LOCATION> Grass </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Union <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hamilton </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Journal-News </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Times <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON> -LRB- La. -RRB- Daily Star <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- KGBT-Television <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Daily Times <PERSON> Hazleton </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Standard-Speaker Hot Springs -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Sentinel-Record International Falls -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Journal Jackson -LRB- Miss. -RRB- WJDX-AM <LOCATION> Jeffersonville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Evening News <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Gazette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kalispell </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- KOFI-AM-FM <PERSON> Killeen </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Herald <LOCATION> Kingman </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> KAAA </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Radio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Havasu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- City Herald Lansing -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- State Journal Laurel -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Leader-Call <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News Little Rock -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Democrat Little Rock -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Gazette <LOCATION> Lompoc </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lufkin </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News Manassas -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal Messenger Mansfield -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News Journal Marion -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Marquette -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WLUC-TV <LOCATION> Massillon </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Evening Independent Meridian -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Star <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Record <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Herald-Record <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- KARE-TV <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Missoulian Monroe -LRB- La. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KNOE </ORGANIZATION> and KNOE-TV Mountain Home -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Baxter Bulletin Mountain Home -LRB- Ark. -RRB- Radio Station KTLO <LOCATION> Muskogee </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> & amp; Times-Democrat <LOCATION> Natchez </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Democrat <ORGANIZATION> Newport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Times-Herald North Platte -LRB- Neb. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KODY </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norwalk </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Reflector <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Banner <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal Record Omaha -LRB- Neb. -RRB- KMTV <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Report Oswego -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Palladium-Times <LOCATION> Oxnard </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press-Courier <LOCATION> Palo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alto </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Tribune <LOCATION> Pascagoula </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Press <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -LRB- Ariz. -RRB- KFYI Radio <LOCATION> Phoenixville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Evening <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Plano </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Courier <LOCATION> Plattsburgh </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WIRY <LOCATION> Ponca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rapid </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> KTOQ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redding </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record Searchlight <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Democrat & amp; <LOCATION> Chronicle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rockford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- Register Star Rolla -LRB- Mo. -RRB- Daily News
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0025EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMECitations-1stAdd     10-04 0413</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Citations - 1st Add,0537</SECOND>
<HEAD>DES MOINES: Daily News.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Saginaw </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- WSGW-AM <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Times </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sentinel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Progress <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Seneca </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WSFW <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- KWKH Sidney -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- S.D. -RRB- KDLT-TV St. Albans -LRB- <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION> -RRB- Messenger St. Cloud -LRB- Minn. -RRB- WJON @ <ORGANIZATION> WWJO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spectrum </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stephenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Empire-Tribune </PERSON> <PERSON> Strasburg </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WHEN @ WRHP Syracuse -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WSTM <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- WSYR <LOCATION> Tallahassee </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Democrat Thibodaux -LRB- La. -RRB- Daily Comet Toledo -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Blade Torrance -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Breeze Troy -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- KNST Radio <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Citizen <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- World <LOCATION> Urbana </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Citizen <LOCATION> Vacaville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Reporter <LOCATION> Visalia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Times-Delta </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Walnut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Costa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warren </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Warrensburg </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Mo. -RRB- Daily Star-Journal <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Post </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- KFDX-TV <LOCATION> Williamsport </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <PERSON> Sun-Gazette </PERSON> <PERSON> Willoughby </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Herald Wooster -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Record Youngstown -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Vindicator </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Newsphoto Citations</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Independent-Mail <LOCATION> Carbondale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Illinoisan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Champaign-Urbana </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Gazette <LOCATION> Cheyenne </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. -RRB- <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Eagle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning News <LOCATION> Duluth </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Tribune <LOCATION> Easton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Express <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gallup </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION> -RRB- Independent <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Helena -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Independent Record Honolulu -LRB- <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -RRB- Advertiser <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Bulletin <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle <PERSON> Kearney </PERSON> -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Daily Hub <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Mankato </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Press <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Herald </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Tribune North Platte -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Telegraph <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Desert </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Herald <LOCATION> Peoria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal-Star <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pottstown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Mercury Providence -LRB- <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal-Bulletin Reno -LRB- <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette-Journal <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rochester </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Springfield </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Union News St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Pioneer Press Dispatch <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Star </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily
</TEXT>
<NOTE>News and Newsphoto Citations</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Abilene </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Reporter-News <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Beacon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Journal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Daily Town Talk Allentown -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Morning Call Ardmore -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Ardmoreite Augusta -LRB- <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Augusta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Times <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Morning Advocate and State Times Billings -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Gazette Biloxi-Gulfport -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Sun <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> -RRB- Statesman <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Daily Chronicle Bloomsburg -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press-Enterprise <LOCATION> Brainerd </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Dispatch <LOCATION> Bristol </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Courier </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brownsville </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-News <LOCATION> Burlington </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Press <LOCATION> Carson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> -RRB- Appeal <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News and <PERSON> Courier </PERSON> and The Evening Post <LOCATION> Charlottesville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Progress Chillicothe -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Gazette Cleveland -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMECitations-2ndAdd     10-04 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Citations - 2nd Add,0457</SECOND>
<HEAD>DES MOINES: Plain Dealer.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Dayton -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Daytona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Journal <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Press <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Douglas -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Dispatch <LOCATION> Durango </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elyria </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle-Telegram <LOCATION> Evansville </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Courier Fort Myers -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> News-Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- <LOCATION> Journal-Gazette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> News-Sentinel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fostoria </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Review Times <LOCATION> Fredericksburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Free Lance-Star Grand Rapids -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press Great Falls -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Piedmont </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hattiesburg </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- American Idaho Falls -LRB- <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> -RRB- Post-Register <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- News <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Star Jackson -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Clarion-Ledger <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Times-Union </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Johnstown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune-Democrat <LOCATION> Kalispell </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lafayette </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Journal and Courier Lakeland -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Ledger </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION> -RRB- Review-Journal <LOCATION> Lawton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Constitution <LOCATION> Lorain </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal <LOCATION> Lynchburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- News & amp; <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marquette </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Mining Journal <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Today </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Middletown </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION> -LRB- Mont. -RRB- Missoulian <LOCATION> Modesto </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Bee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald <LOCATION> Muskegon </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Chronicle <LOCATION> Myrtle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Times-Picayune <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Ledger-Star <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Virginian-Pilot <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Transcript <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Ogdensburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oklahoman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sentinel <LOCATION> Ottawa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Herald </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pensacola </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Journal <LOCATION> Petaluma </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Argus-Carrier <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Post-Gazette <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press <LOCATION> Pontiac </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Press </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pottsville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Republican Rapid City -LRB- S.D. -RRB- Journal Richmond -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- News Leader <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Dispatch <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <LOCATION> World-News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald <LOCATION> Saginaw </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Deseret </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rosa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press Democrat <LOCATION> Sarasota </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Tribune Scottsbluff -LRB- Neb. -RRB- Star-Herald <LOCATION> Shreveport </LOCATION> -LRB- La. -RRB- Journal Shreveport -LRB- La. -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vista </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal South Bend -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Tribune St. Johnsbury -LRB- <LOCATION> Vt. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Caledonian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Record </LOCATION> <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lawrence </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Courier-Observer <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times <LOCATION> Stillwater </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- NewsPress <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record Sumter -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Item Sunbury -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Item </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News-Sun <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Journal <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Post-Standard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Traverse </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- Record-Eagle <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Okla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Tribune <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION> -LRB- Miss. -RRB- Evening Post Vincennes -LRB- Ind. -RRB- Sun-Commercial <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Record News <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Leader <PERSON> Winchester </PERSON> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Star Woodbridge -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- <LOCATION> Potomac </LOCATION> <LOCATION> News </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yuma </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily Sun
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Pope-Moslems     10-04 0819</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pope-Moslems,0844</SECOND>
<HEAD>Despite Difficulties, Pope Strives for Better Relations with Moslems</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>By VICTOR L. SIMPSON</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VATICAN CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With his travels to <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, his peace initiatives and calls to forget the painful past, Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> has made unprecedented openings to the Moslem world. But the road to dialogue is dotted with obstacles, and the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> is keeping a wary eye on challenges to the church in Islamic countries. Over the past two decades, and especially during <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s 11-year pontificate, the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> has sought to erase the image of medieval crusades fought in the name of faith `` Moslems and Christians have generally understood each other badly and sometimes, in the past, have exhausted each other in polemics and wars,'' he said in <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> four years ago as the first pontiff to set foot on Arab soil as an official state guest. He said dialogue was essential between the Catholic church and Islam, the two largest religious groups in the world. But the spread of Moslem fundamentalism has raised alarm, especially for isolated minority communities of Christians. The danger of Moslem-Christian rivalries has been dramatized by the bloodshed in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The pope's concern over the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> fighting recently led him to make the first direct appeal by a pontiff to the Islamic world, saying there can be no winners in such a struggle. He also repeated his desire to visit the country torn by 14 years of civil war, despite threats against him from Moslem extremists. On Oct. 9, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> begins a visit to <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, the world's largest Moslem country with an estimated 140 million Moslems and a tiny <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> minority of 5 million He will be there until Oct. 14. The pope has previously stopped in such predominantly Islamic countries as <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bangladesh </LOCATION> as well as several African countries with large Moslem populations. The era of dialogue was spurred by the <ORGANIZATION> Second </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, which also opened the way to improved relations between Catholics and Jews. `` Upon the Moslems, too, the church looks with esteem,'' said the 1965 declaration Nostra Aetate. `` They adore one God, living and enduring, merciful, and all powerful, maker of heaven and earth and speaker to men.'' <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials are pleased that its efforts have led to stepped-up exchanges of visits between church representatives and Moslem theologians. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> also maintains diplomatic relations with a number of predominantly Islamic countries, including <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON>'s calls for a homeland for the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> have won him appreciation in the Moslem world while his meetings with <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> drew protests from <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, a country with which the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has refused to establish formal diplomatic relations. The church has generally been cautious to avoid offending Moslem sensibilities. Officials note that on Islamic issues, it often has to deal with governments, not religious leaders. `` It's something like the church in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, where diplomacy is the best method. We like to do things quietly,'' said a <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> official speaking on the usual rule of anonymity. During the height of the fury earlier this year over <PERSON> Salman </PERSON> <PERSON> Rushdie </PERSON>'s novel `` The Satanic Verses,'' the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s newspaper said millions of Moslems had found the novel offensive. It condemned `` whatever is irreverent and blasphemous'' in the book but said the author should not be killed, as the late Iranian leader, <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, demanded. According to church surveys, the amount of religious liberty and pluralism varies considerably in the Moslem world. In some cases, the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> minorities `` live in a state of tension and of concern at the possibility of new restrictions,'' said Fides, a press service at the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION>'s missionary office. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> is worried about the spread of Moslem fundamentalism in countries such as <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> ad in <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, where rivalries between Christians and Moslems led to the burning of churches and mosques in the northern part of the country in 1987. In an unusual public criticism, the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> in a major document on racism issued in February condemned the imposition of the <LOCATION> Sharia </LOCATION>, or Islamic law, on non-Moslems. Catholicism's fastest growing church is in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, but it is subject to special pressures. During a visit to <LOCATION> Rwanda </LOCATION> in 1982, <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader Col. <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> declared `` Africa is not Christian'' and called for a holy war to help spread Islam on the continent. <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> officials consider <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> a generally tolerant country, but <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> <PERSON> Catholics </PERSON> say they are worried about a government bill presented to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that would give legal recognition to several hundred Islamic courts. Religion and politics are also intertwined on <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Timor </LOCATION>, a former <LOCATION> Portuguese </LOCATION> colony with a large Catholic population forcibly annexed by <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> in 1976. Church officials report that a number of Moslems have been converting to Catholicism as a political statement of their opposition to <LOCATION> Indonesian </LOCATION> rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     10-04 0726</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0815</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Sept. 25-Oct .1 Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 27.0, 24.4 million homes. 2. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.1, 22.7 million homes. 3. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.3, 22.0 million homes. 4. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.4, 21.2 million homes. 5. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.4, 20.2 million homes. 6. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 22.1, 20.0 million homes. 7. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.4, 19.3 million homes. 8. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Living Dolls Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.4 million homes. 9. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.3, 18.4 million homes. 10. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.2, 18.3 million homes. 11. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Chicken Soup,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.6, 17.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 17.2 million homes. 13. -LRB- X -RRB- `` <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Walters </PERSON> Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 13. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 15. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 16.3 million homes. 16. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> vs <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.5 million homes. 17. -LRB- X -RRB- `` TV Bloopers Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 15.2 million homes. 17. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 15.2 million homes. 19. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 15.0 million homes. 19. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 15.0 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Night Walk'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 16.3. 22. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 16.1. 22. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jones </LOCATION> & amp; The <ORGANIZATION> Temple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Doom </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 16.1. 22. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` My Boyfriend's Back'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 16.1. 25. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.9. 26. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 15.8. 27. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6. 28. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 15.5. 29. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Hardball 2nd Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 30. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 31. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.6. 32. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 32. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 34. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` The Famous Teddy Z,'' CBS, 14.1. 35. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 35. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 37. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` The People Next Door,'' CBS, 13.4. 38. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.3. 39. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 40. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Sweet Bird of Youth'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 13.0. 41. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 41. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 43. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 43. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` The <ORGANIZATION> Nutt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 45. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Prime Target'' _ `` Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 45. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 12.6. 47. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 48. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.4. 49. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.3. 49. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 51. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Rescue 911,'' CBS, 11.8. 52. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 53. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 54. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Island Son,'' CBS, 11.1. 55. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 56. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` The Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 57. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 57. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.7. 57. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Top of the Hill,'' CBS, 10.7. 60. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: The Tarnised Years,'' CBS, 10.5. 61. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.4. 62. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 62. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 62. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 65. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` Peaceable Kingdom,'' CBS, 9.4. 66. -LRB- 69 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 67. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Snoops,'' CBS, 9.1. 68. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.9. 69. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 70. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 70. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Free Spirit,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 72. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 72. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` PrimeTime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 74. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 8.1. 75. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 76. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Saturday Night with <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.9. 77. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` Brand New Life'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 78. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` B.L. Stryker'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 7.7. 78. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 80. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Homeroom,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 81. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 82. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 82. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 84. -LRB- 79 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 85. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 86. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 87. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.6. 88. -LRB- 85 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d e BC-Dance     10-04 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0297</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baryshnikov Dances at Martha Graham Gala</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> gave an exciting performance in `` American Document'' at the opening night gala of the <ORGANIZATION> Martha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Graham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> danced as though born to the <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> technique, although his training is in ballet, which is much different. <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, a student at the <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> school and daughter of actor <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, narrated the dance, a celebration of democracy which Miss <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> choreographed originally in 1938 and revised this year. The 95-year-old choreographer took bows with the company after the performance Tuesday night at the City Center, and the audience responded with a standing ovation. <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maxine </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> danced the roles of an `` everyman'' couple who move through the history of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Both were modest but eager, stalwart and optimistic. Their duets _ from embattled through proud to beautifully romantic _ were a high point of `` American Document.'' In the original production, the parts were danced by <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> and <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>. <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Herring </PERSON>, in red, danced the counterpart to the narrator. In revising the dance, Miss <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> changed the chorus from the original all women to nine women and eight men. She also integrated the speaking and dancing more smoothly and she changed the music `` American Document'' is danced to from a score by <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> to `` Concerto for Oboe and Orchestra'' by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Corigliano </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucarelli </PERSON> was oboe soloist and <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Sussman </PERSON> conducted. The evening began with `` Night Chant'' from 1988 and ended with `` The Rite of Spring'' from 1984, both choreographed by <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>. The company will dance at the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> through Oct. 22.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-LastTemptation     10-04 0539</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Last Temptation,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Last Temptation' Controversial for Cable Too</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 The uproar that surrounded `` The Last Temptation of Christ'' at the box office was renewed when it hit cable television this week, with some groups vowing to cancel subscriptions and others protesting local blackouts of the film. Several cable companies around the country refused to show the movie, transmitted on the <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION> pay cable network, prompting outcries of censorship, while others broadcast disclaimers beforehand. The movie portrays the life of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> and includes scenes of a fantasy <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> entertains in the movie about being married to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Magdalen </PERSON>. Its box-office opening last year was followed by protests nationwide, with some theaters canceling showings because of bomb threats. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, about 300 members of eight churches vowed to cancel their cable television subscriptions for six months after the movie was shown Monday night on <PERSON> Cinemax </PERSON>. `` We know there are many other forms of what we would call sinful viewing, but we feel the line must be drawn somewhere,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hair </PERSON>, pastor of <ORGANIZATION> Calvary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` We know that people are free to watch what they want, and by the same token we're free to make an appeal. We believe the message of <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> is being blasphemed.'' Cable companies across the country, including at least three in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> and two in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, were blacking out the movie to their subscribers, but the manager of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cablevision </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> said he refused to. `` One, we believe we're not allowed to censor the programming under our contract with <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION>; and, two, a basic First Amendment reason _ we might not agree with what the movie has to say, but we're not going to censor it because one element of the community asks us to.'' Officials Home Box Office, the parent company of <ORGANIZATION> Cinemax </ORGANIZATION>, said they would have no comment on the controversy. Some of the protests were against the cable companies' decision not to show the movie. In <LOCATION> Jonesboro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, more than 30 people carried signs that `` Stand Up Against Censorship'' as they marched outside <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cablevision </ORGANIZATION>. man confused over his identity and purpose, and subject to sexual temptation. In <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> displayed a message on a blue screen: `` The management of <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> have decided not carry this film because of strong content objections voiced by various groups when the movie was initially released to theaters. We do not believe it is responsible to offer a movie, even on a paid channel, which was not generally shown in general theaters because of sensitive content.'' `` I went to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to fight against this kind of thing,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Tattersall </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION>. `` I came home and was taking my boots off to go to bed when I switched on the TV. I do n't even want to watch the thing; I'm just angry they're censoring it.'' A 73-year-old <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> man has sued <ORGANIZATION> Multimedia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cablevision </ORGANIZATION> for $ 1 million for allegedly violating his constitutional rights by pre-empting the movie. `` I'm a World War II veteran, and I treasure our Constitution and all the provisions of it, and I say if we do n't protect it then we deserve to lose it,'' <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Olim </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0048EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Alexander     10-04 0265</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Alexander,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>H.G. Alexander, Intermediary for British-Indian Talks, Dies at 100</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Horace </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, a Quaker who served as an intermediary between <PERSON> Mahatma </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and the British government during <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s struggle for freedom, has died. He was 100. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> died of natural causes Saturday at Crosslands Retirement Community in <LOCATION> Kennett </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, a suburb of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, said his stepdaughter, <PERSON> Cecilia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradbeer </PERSON> <PERSON> Sibinga </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> once described <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> as `` British in nationality but Indian in heart.'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> was with <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> Aug. 15, 1947, when <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> gained its freedom from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>. In 1984, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> honored <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> for his contribution by awarding him one of the country's highest decorations, the <PERSON> Padma </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhushan </PERSON> <PERSON> Award </PERSON>, roughly translated as `` outstanding human being.'' Two years after his first wife, <PERSON> Olive </PERSON> <PERSON> Garaham </PERSON>, died in 1943, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> made his first visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He moved to <LOCATION> Swarthmore </LOCATION> with his second wife, <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradbeer </PERSON>, in 1969. In a 1984 interview, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said he continued to believe in the non-violent principles of <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. `` I try to be hopeful about the future, but it is rather difficult, is n't it? But there are a lot of people in the world who are trying to take non-violence seriously, so maybe in the course of time, it will begin to affect national policy,'' he said. `` People have a great capacity for good things as well as evil things, and I suppose each of us has to go on doing the little bit he can.'' In addition to his stepdaughter and second wife, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> is survived by a son, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Biddle </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradbeer </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891004-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-04-89 0116EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     10-04 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0444</SECOND>
<HEAD>Different Cast, But `Different World' Premieres in Top 10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
