<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StormKaren 1stLd-Writethru a0716 12-02 0241</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Storm Karen, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0716,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weather Service Lifts Tropical Storm Warnings for Cuba</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS penultimate graf to UPDATE with later position.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical Storm <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> moved southwest away from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> on Friday after dumping heavy rain on the island. Tropical storm warnings for <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> were lifted by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. The storm, moving in a clockwise loop, could make a complete circle in the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> if it stays together long enough to meet with a big funnel trough located in the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, forecaster <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Case </PERSON> said. `` That could cause the storm to move to the northeast in a big circle,'' Case said. But, there is a 50-50 chance the storm will dissipate before then, he said. `` We do n't see any major dramatic effect on land areas,'' he said. The system surprised forecasters by achieving tropical storm strength Thursday when its winds hit 39 mph. Rainfall reports Thursday from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> included more than 14 inches at <ORGANIZATION> Punta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> del </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Este </ORGANIZATION> on the Isle of Youth, more than seven inches in <LOCATION> Matanzas </LOCATION> and nearly five inches in <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>. At 10:30 p.m. EST Friday, the center of the storm was located near latitude 17.8 north, longitude 85.2 west, or about 175 miles east of <LOCATION> Belize </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Karen </PERSON>'s highest sustained winds were near 40 mph. The hurricane season begins June 1 and ends Nov. 30. However, hurricanes have been recorded in every month but April.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AbductedNun     12-02 0209</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Abducted Nun,0213</SECOND>
<UNK>Senator Urges Investigation Into Abduction of Nun in Guatemala</UNK>
<DATELINE>ALBUQUERQUE, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON> called on Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> on Friday to order an investigation into the abduction and torture of a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> nun in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> last month. Sister <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> of Grants, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, was abducted Nov. 2 from a retreat house in <LOCATION> Antigua </LOCATION>, about 30 miles from <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and released a day later. In his letter to <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> dated Friday, <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.M. </LOCATION>, said Ms. <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> was `` subjected to a 24-hour interrogation that included both physical and sexual abuse.'' `` There are indications that a man with a North American accent who finally stepped in to stop the physical abuse may have been associated with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Bingaman </PERSON>'s letter said. This possibility `` warrants an expeditious but thorough investigation,'' the letter said, without giving further details. A <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> duty officer said nobody would be available for comment until Saturday. In his letter, the senator also enclosed press reports indicating a man wearing a Guatemalan police uniform participated in the abduction. Sister <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> had been a school teacher in rural <LOCATION> Huehuetenango </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION> prior to her abduction. Her order, the Ursuline Sisters, has indicated she will not return to <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     12-02 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0089</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 21; 30; 35; 42; 44.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 1-3-2-3.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 09; 10; 11; 13; 23; 35.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 16; 23; 26; 30; 34; 44. Bonus: 89378.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 02; 03; 31; 32; 35; 46. Supplementary 23.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 9-9-3-0
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 6-4-0; 8-6-7-6; 0-2-7-6-7; 9-2-0-6-5-0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     12-02 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0026</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 01; 21; 30; 35; 42; 44.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0250EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-VoterRegistration     12-02 0213</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Voter Registration,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iowa Puts Voter Registration Forms in Phone Books</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> is distributing voter registration forms inside each copy of the new telephone book, and officials hope the process catches on in other states. `` In every election, fewer and fewer people vote in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' Secretary of State <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> said Friday. `` We're making <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> the leader in convenient voter registration procedures.'' Telephone books currently being distributed by <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION>, the Denver-based regional phone company, include voter registration forms at the bottom of one of the instruction pages. The form can be clipped and mailed in an envelope to the county auditor. State income tax booklets that will be sent out at the end of the year also will include voter registration forms, under legislation enacted this year. <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Mix </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> US </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> vice president, said <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> is the first state in which the forms will be included in telephone books. He predicted other states would follow suit. `` I hope that this becomes a model for the voter registration process,'' he said. <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> distributes nearly 2.2 million telephone books in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, Mix said. There are more than 1.5 million registered voters in <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and an estimated 500,000 eligible voters who are not registered, Ms. <PERSON> Baxter </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Fusion-Pons     12-02 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fusion-Pons,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>Utah Officials Say Japanese Fusion Work Spawning Patent Concerns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SALT LAKE CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Japanese researchers have duplicated recent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> `` cold'' fusion experiments and are reaching for the lead in the emerging technology, one of the scientists who touched off the furor complained Friday. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> panel recently refused to back a national nuclear fusion program based on discoveries by <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utah </ORGANIZATION> electrochemist <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and a British colleague, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON>. Physicists contend the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> research has been largely discredited because other experimenters have failed to fully duplicate <PERSON> Pons </PERSON>' and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON>'s results. But <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> said Friday that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> are making major investments in nuclear fusion research and development that could wrest leadership in the field away from the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. In March, <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> said they had achieved room temperature, or `` cold'' fusion, by immersing in deuterium-rich heavy water rods of palladium inside electrically charged platinum coils. The two said the reaction yield heat equivalent to 100 times the energy needed to produce the reaction. `` They've been duplicating our experiments since late March,'' <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> said. `` The Japanese and Indians are doing just what's obvious They're doing the research needed to find out if it's feasible or not, and they're finding it is. A bitter <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> said if the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> does lose its lead in nuclear fusion research, the blame should rest squarely on the shoulders of the <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The board recently concluded there is no conclusive evidence that <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> actually produced fusion. `` We've tried to tell the country that research money is the only way to cover these -LRB- developments -RRB- properly, and its pretty obvious that's not going to get done,'' <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> said. `` We certainly ca n't match the scope of the work that the Japanese ... are doing.'' Japanese physicists at <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Nagoya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> said in the November issue of the English-language Japanese Journal of Applied Physics that fusion had occurred spontaneously between two palladium electrodes in a flask filled with deuterium gas. The Japanese said the major difference between their work and that of <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> was the use of deuterium gas instead of heavy water. However, <PERSON> Pons </PERSON> he and <PERSON> Fleischmann </PERSON> already have carried out the same experiment as the Japanese, and have applied for a patent on the procedure. Japanese researchers point out their own experiments yielded a high level of neutron emissions _ up to 20,000 times the normal background level. That is one possible indicator of a fusion reaction. Topping that, another group of researchers at <ORGANIZATION> Osaka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> this week reported detecting neutron levels 2.5 million times normal levels in a cold-fusion experiment using platinum electrodes in heavy water. In addition to the Japanese and <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, fusion research also reportedly is under way in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     12-02 0896</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names ,0938</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> stole the show with his jokes and his new look at a fund-raiser for the gubernatorial campaign of Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>. The guests at the Century Plaza Hotel on Wednesday night were all abuzz over <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s undyed gray hair. `` The Prez looks like a <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> justice all of a sudden _ very distinguished,'' said <PERSON> Joyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> fund-raiser who put together the event, which was attended by 700 people and raised $ 700,000 for <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s campaign. Actors <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON> also attended. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> fell out of favor with <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in 1976, when he backed <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> at the GOP presidential primary. But there were no hard feelings Wednesday. `` <PERSON> Pete </PERSON>'s not one for raising taxes,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said to the roars of the crowd, `` unlike the Democrats, who look at your paychecks the way Colonel <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> looks at chickens.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Judge <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, who has dispensed his own brand of justice on `` The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'' for nine years, said the syndicated television show has helped viewers make sense of the court system. The program set off a flurry of small claims cases when it began airing in 1981. But that was the show's intent, <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON> said Friday in an address to the eighth biennial Bench-Bar-News Media conference. Before `` The People's Court,'' many people did n't know there was a small claims court, where to find it or how to use it, he said. `` We're trying to educate people. Judges should try to demystify the judicial system,'' he said. <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, 69, explains every decision after he rules on a case. He said the same practice should be followed by most judges. `` The litigants are entitled to know why you're deciding the case the way you are,'' he said. `` Those three steps to the bench do n't make you a god. You're appointed, but not annointed.'' <PERSON> Wapner </PERSON>, who has been nominated for four Emmys, turned to electronic justice after retiring from the bench in 1979 after serving 20 years as a judge in the <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> courts of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> is n't exactly petite, but a Saturday morning cartoon based on her character has tentatively been titled `` Little Roseanne.'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> is negotiating with <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>'s representatives for an animated show based on the highly popular `` Roseanne'' comedy series, an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> spokesperson said Friday. `` Little Roseanne'' would make its debut next fall if an agreement is reached. `` We are discussing it but no commitment has been made,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> spokesperson who asked for anonymity. `` Roseanne,'' now in its second season, is <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s highest-rated prime time show and has frequently been first in the Nielsen ratings. In the show, Miss <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> plays a <LOCATION> Midwestern </LOCATION> housewife and mother, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> plays her husband.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Rolling </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stones </ORGANIZATION> plan a rousing end to their four-month <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wheels </ORGANIZATION> tour that will include several other rock' n' rollers in a live broadcast. The Dec. 19 show will be shown over a pay-per-view cable television station from the <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. Joining the group will be <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Clapton </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Hooker </PERSON> and Guns' N Roses stars <PERSON> Axl </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> and <PERSON> Izzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stradlin </PERSON>. The tour's final performance will be Dec. 20 at the Convention Center. Guitarist <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Richards </PERSON> said he's in favor of the live broadcast. `` I like the diceyness of live TV and I like the possibilities,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Assemblyman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> say their split after 16 years of marriage was amicable. They filed separate divorce petitions on Friday after reaching agreements on financial and property matters. Details were n't disclosed because of a privacy pact, their attorneys said The divorce would be final in six months. The couple separated in December 1988; the court papers did n't give a reason for the split They will share custody of their 16-year-old son, Troy, their spokesman, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>, said. Attorneys said it was unusual for both parties in a divorce case to file separate petitions. `` They just wanted to make it very clear that neither side was initiating this,'' said <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> Miss <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, 52, won best actress Oscars for the 1971 film `` Klute'' and in 1978 for `` Coming Home.'' <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, 50, the one-time <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seven </ORGANIZATION> anti-war activist, represents <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Monica </PERSON> as a Democrat in the state Assembly.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Jamaica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>'s wife <PERSON> Beverley </PERSON> filed for divorce on the grounds that their 17-year marriage `` has broken down irretrievably.'' <PERSON> Beverley </PERSON> <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>, 48, the prime minister's fourth wife, said in documents filed Friday in the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> that there was no likelihood of reconciliation between the two, who have been separated for more than two years. In the court petition she requested joint access to the couple's two children, <PERSON> David </PERSON>, 8, and <PERSON> Natasha </PERSON>, 15, who live with their father <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> has three other children from previous marriages. <PERSON> Manley </PERSON>'s first two marriages ended in divorce and his third wife died four years before his 1972 marriage to <PERSON> Beverley </PERSON> <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, a former radio and television announcer. In February, a landslide electoral victory over former rightist Prime Minister <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Seaga </PERSON> brought the 64-year-old leader's center-left <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> back to power <PERSON> Manley </PERSON> previously governed from 1972-1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-SalvadorProtest     12-02 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador Protest,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Daniel Berrigan, 22 Others Arrested in Salvador Protest</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Salvador</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHEVEL JOHNSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshals arrested 23 people, including activist <PERSON> Jesuit </PERSON> priest <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Berrigan </PERSON>, who blocked elevators in a federal building Friday to protest government support for <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The arrests followed a confrontation between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Volz </PERSON> and the Rev. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Fagin </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Province </ORGANIZATION> of Jesuits. <PERSON> Fagin </PERSON> was not arrested but said he supported the protest. `` I'm a Catholic and I'm sympathetic to your cause, but I ca n't allow you to break the law,'' <PERSON> Volz </PERSON> told the demonstrators just before ordering their arrest `` We are upholding our civil disobedience rights,'' said <PERSON> Fagin </PERSON>. Prior to being arrested, <PERSON> Berrigan </PERSON> defended the protest to reporters. `` This is a protest salvaging our own humanity,'' he said. The protests coincided with the second day of a two-day memorial held by Jesuit-run <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> for six Jesuit priests murdered recently in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. There was no violence by the 80 or so protesters. Fifteen men and eight women were handcuffed and arrested later, then were arraigned on misdemeanor obstruction charges and released without having to post bail. The demonstration at the 13-story building's eight elevators began about 12:45 p.m., capping a day of prayer, song and protest joined by numerous Jesuit leaders, nuns and local high school and college students. Among them were students from <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, where <PERSON> Berrigan </PERSON>, who began his social activism with his brother during the 1960s, is teaching sociology this semester. Protesters blocked access to elevators by sitting in the doorways, preventing doors from closing. Power to the elevators appeared to have been shut off shortly after the protest began and workers in the building headed for the stairs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Santa-Sex     12-02 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Santa-Sex,0191</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accused Sex Offender Santa Claus Arrested</HEAD>
<DATELINE>El CENTRO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Santa Claus who worked at a shopping center booth was arrested after police found out he was a sex offender who had violated his parole. Police were tipped off to the identity of the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> and arrested him after a computer check. He had worked only one shift at the mall, police said. `` The condition of his parole requires that he stay away from unsupervised contact with children. In this case, he had actual physical contact with children,'' Police Sgt. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON> <PERSON> Blankenship </PERSON> said. `` <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> sent us a couple of applications and we picked this individual because he had that <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Claus </LOCATION> look,'' said <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Plaza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shopping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` He came highly recommended and we had every reason to believe he was OK.'' <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Capt <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> said he knew the man was on parole but had no idea of the nature of his offense. `` I did n't want to pry. We look toward the future not backwards to the past,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-China-Students Bjt   12-02 0568</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Students, Bjt,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chinese Students Hope Bush Keeps Promise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEPHANIE SCHOROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese students are dismayed at President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto of a bill to let them remain here after their visas expire, saying he seems to be exempting <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> from the human rights standards held for other Socialist countries But several students expressed faith in <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s promise that he would help those who fear returning to their homeland through other means. <PERSON> Pei </PERSON> <PERSON> Min </PERSON> <PERSON> Xin </PERSON>, a graduate student in government at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a pro-democracy leader, said Friday that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> caved into pressure from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, calling the fierce Chinese government opposition to the bill a `` bluff.'' `` People like us have come to this country not only to study but to learn how democracy operates. We have found that this single case is rather discouraging,'' <PERSON> Pei </PERSON> said. `` When it comes down to a choice between human rights and geopolitical interests, the leading democracy did not hesitate to choose the latter.'' Said <ORGANIZATION> Brandeis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON> Shen </PERSON> <PERSON> Tong </PERSON>: `` The basic signal to me from the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> government is that the government still holds different standards about human rights in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and other countries.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday vetoed the bill, which had been passed without opposition in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The president said it was unnecesssary in light of other administrative proposals. The bill affects about 40,000 Chinese students and scholars in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The Chinese government has attacked the bill and has threatened to cut off all foreign exchange programs with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> if it passes. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he was directing Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to take steps to administratively extend visa benefits to Chinese students. In a statement, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the administrative steps will provide `` the same benefits'' and `` accomplish the laudable objectives of the Congress ... while preserving my ability to manage foreign relations.'' Chinese students are particularly concerned about a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> requirement that they return to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> for two years before reapplying after their visas expire. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s directions to <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> include waivers of the two-year requirement. <PERSON> Wu'er </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaixi </PERSON>, a prominent Chinese student activist who escaped to this country after the Chinese crushed demonstrations in and around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, believed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would help students. `` Of course we hoped very much to have the bill pass, but we were also glad and thankful to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that he did, in fact, try to help <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> students,'' <PERSON> Wu'er </PERSON> said through a translator. `` I hope <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will do what he promised.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may have been playing a diplomatic game _ supporting the democracy movement in fact while ostensibly following the wishes of the Chinese government, said <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Maddox </PERSON>, associate director of <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Fairbank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> for East Asian research and a frequent vistor to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Maddox </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also may be assuming that the bill will be overridden by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which would give `` a good plug to his Chinese friends'' while letting the bill take effect. <PERSON> Pei </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> students are reluctant to seek political asylum in this country because they eventually wish to return to their homeland. `` I am a patriot living abroad, waiting to go back to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' he said. <PERSON> Pei </PERSON>, who has studied in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for five years, said he has learned his name is on a blacklist of pro-democracy students. If he returned home now, <PERSON> Pei </PERSON> said, `` I would face at least life in prison or execution right away.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0306EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Summit-Trade     12-02 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Summit-Trade,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Czarist Bonds, Damage by US Troops Are Issues With Soviets</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CARL HARTMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If Presidents <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> run out of issues at their seaborne summit they could try to settle stubborn disputes about bonds issued under the czar and damage claims against <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> troops in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> 70 years ago. The seemingly arcane bond issue is in fact a serious obstacle to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s hopes of borrowing money in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` We've got a pile of obstacles that high,'' said <PERSON> Valery </PERSON> <PERSON> Sorokin </PERSON>, economic counselor at the Soviet embassy, holding his hand about two feet above a coffee table. <PERSON> Sorokin </PERSON> has compiled a 33-page summary of problems that slow trade between the two countries. Negotiators have worked for over a year on the issue of bonds that the Soviets repudiated when they took power after the overthrow of the czar. <PERSON> Sorokin </PERSON> said there has been little progress. The Soviets have made agreements with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> to redeem such bonds held by citizens there for a few cents on the dollar. One Soviet official, speaking anonymously, estimated the bonds' face value as high as $ 300 million They were issued by railroads and other privately owned business under the czar. `` We get letters from Americans every once in a while, asking us what to do with them,'' <PERSON> Sorokin </PERSON> said in an interview. A few dealers have been willing to buy them for small sums. Collectors have admired the certificates for their elaborate engraving. They were not considered to have any other value, so some were destroyed because they were creased or discolored. The government that ruled <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> just before the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> takeover in 1917 was allied with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> against <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> in World War I. It got $ 192.6 million worth of loans from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The Soviets repudiated those loans too and made their own peace with <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Woodrow </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> sent <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops to <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION> in a combined action with <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. The Soviet government under <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> and his successors diligently kept the memory of that brief conflict alive, though it has been forgotten by most Americans. `` We have our claims, too,'' <PERSON> Sorokin </PERSON> said. With accumulated interest, the wartime loan claim now amounts to almost $ 1 billion. As long as it is not settled, a law passed in 1934 bars the Soviets from floating commercial loans in this country. On Thursday, members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> asked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to make a priority issue of waiving another obstacle to commerce between the superpowers, the Jackson-Vanik amendment. That law keeps tariffs high against Soviet exports because of Soviet restrictions on emigration, now considerably eased. Trade between the two nations faces other restrictions as well. One <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law says no government agency can help the Soviets get loans of more than $ 300 million _ not a large sum in world finance. It makes an exception only for the <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corporation </ORGANIZATION>, which lends to purchasers of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> farm products. But because of the more far-reaching Jackson-Vanik amendment, the Soviets have never been able to use that exception for their huge purchases of American grain. A 1986 law bans gold imports from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as a sanction against race segregation laws, and also includes the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in the ban. Those are the world's two biggest producers of gold. A spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> MTB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which opens an exhibit of coins in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> next week, said it will show Soviet silver and palladium coins but no gold ones. `` They would n't let us bring in any samples,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON>, `` not even a collection of historic coins from the Hermitage Museum in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Salvador-American     12-02 0469</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador-American,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Salvadoran Officials Have Softer Words for Arrested American</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two Salvadoran officials are questioning whether an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> woman who was arrested in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> after weapons and explosives were found in the back yard of the home she rented was willfully helping rebels. <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdivieso </PERSON>, the Salvadoran undersecretary of foreign affairs, suggested Friday at a news conference that <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Casolo </PERSON> may be `` a naive person who has been used by'' the leftist rebels and that `` unfortunately she was found in the house at the time.'' Col. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Amando </PERSON> <PERSON> Aviles </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Salvadoran military, told the same news conference at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> that he knows <PERSON> Casolo </PERSON> and `` she is a very nice, honest person that I consider a good American.'' Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON>, D-Conn., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hemisphere </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he was heartened by the statements about <PERSON> Casolo </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> native `` I am encouraged by these statements, and I hope they reflect a change in attitude by the Salvadoran authorities that will result in the swift and favorable resolution of the case against <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Casolo </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Dodd </PERSON> said. Still, Salvadoran President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> indicated in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> that `` a judicial process'' was called for. `` We feel that anybody that breaks the laws in this country, no matter what nationality they are, should be submitted to the judicial process,'' <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said at a news conference. `` If there is enough proof, and apparently in this case there is, in order to start a judicial process, one will be started,'' he said. Of former Attorney General <PERSON> Ramsey </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, who was in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> to advise <PERSON> Casolo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said: `` If he is involved in any way in the politics of <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> then his permit -LRB- visa -RRB- will be revoked immediately.'' Casolo, 28, has maintained she is innocent of any military connection with the rebels. She works in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> as a representative of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>, Texas-based <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seminars </ORGANIZATION>, providing tours for Americans who come to see and study the country. She was arrested a week ago after Salvadoran officials, acting on a tip from a captured rebel, dug up the back yard of the house she had been renting for the past three months and found dynamite and thousands of rounds of rifle ammunition. Friends suggested she was framed by the Salvadoran government, but the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration took a different view. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Monday, `` This is hardly a case of a someone having a few things flipped in their shopping bag on the way home.'' And the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> began reviewing the case to determine if she broke the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Neutrality Act. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> took a softer approach Wednesday, saying <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials were `` monitoring her case closely to assure she is well treated.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DefenseSecretaries     12-02 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Secretaries,0473</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Defense Secretaries Still Skeptical of Change</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Summit Rdp, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PHIL WEST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite the rapid political change in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the role Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is playing there, six former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense secretaries are still skeptical of the permanence of the shift. `` I think that we should recognize that although Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is immensely popular in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and even in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that his popularity, his position in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> itself has weakened dramatically,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON>, who served from 1973 to 1975 in the <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> administrations. <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> said Friday at the Third Annual Report of the Secretaries of Defense that <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is walking a fine line that could tumble him from power if his reforms become too politically and financially costly. `` The Soviet economy is in serious decline. There is a possibility of a recession within the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s position is precarious. He may or may not survive, and it probably is in our interest that he survive.'' The others participating in the forum, <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Laird </PERSON>, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> McNamara </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlucci </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumsfeld </PERSON>, agreed that the Soviet reform spirit might not last. The panel discussion was sponsored by the nonprofit <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> were in <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> to hold a weekend summit aboard <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet warships. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> Friday as `` a dynamic new Soviet leader'' whose policies of openness and other reforms are advancing the cause of world peace. But <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>, who served as <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s defense secretary from 1981 to 1987, warned, `` The Cold War is not over.'' <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> can transform soldiers into farmers _ and back again _ in a matter of days. They can just as easily change their party leaders, <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said. He cited the reversal of what appeared to be democratic reforms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> when the army cleared Tiananmen Square of demonstrators. `` The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is quite capable of reversing these things, like firing into crowds,'' <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON> said. Still, the former defense secretaries agreed that the opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall and relaxed travel in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact nations could lead to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troop reductions in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. And each said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> should keep hands off any attempts at reunifying <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` We'll be bringing Americans home. And you'll be seeing that by the end of the year,'' predicted <PERSON> Laird </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s defense secretary from 1969 to 1973. <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> said the changes sweeping <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> are staggering. `` The <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact threat is quite different. For that reason, we can spend somewhat less than we have on our readiness posture in <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. And I stress somewhat less,'' <PERSON> Schlesinger </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0614EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Virus-Monkey     12-02 0456</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Virus-Monkey,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deadly Virus Found in Three Monkeys</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREDERICK, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Scientists who began examining the carcasses of 100 laboratory monkeys imported from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> by a <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> firm say they have so far discovered three with the ebola virus, considered the deadliest virus to humans before AIDS was discovered. Health officials also say they are monitoring the 25 employees at the <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> research firm that had received the monkeys in October even though they believe the disease would have turned up in the employees by now if any had been infected. Officials said none of the employees have shown any symptoms. The monkeys had been shipped to <ORGANIZATION> Hazleton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Products </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Reston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Corning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Glass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> that uses primates for cosmetics and drug testing. This is the first time the virus has been found in a non-human and the first time it had been found in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The discovery of the first infected monkey was announced earlier this week. `` We do n't know where they got the virus,'' <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Dasey </PERSON>, a spokesman at the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Infectious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diseases </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Detrick </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Frederick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, said Friday. `` We're continuing to help <PERSON> Hazleton </PERSON> and public health officials determine how far it has spread through the monkey colony,'' he said. In mid-November, medical investigators helped <LOCATION> Hazleton </LOCATION> determine that some of the monkeys suffered from simian hemorrhagic fever and that one monkey had the ebola virus. All of the animals in the shipment were then destroyed, authorities said. Since then, 17 monkey carcasses have been sent to <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Detrick </LOCATION> for necropsies, similar to autopsies in humans. The first seven arrived Wednesday, and three, including the initial animal, had the virus. Ten more delivered Friday have not been examined, <PERSON> Dasey </PERSON> said. It was not immediately known when the remaining necropsies would be performed. The ebola virus causes a contagious disease that is transmitted through body fluids and secretions, though not through casual contact, according to Dr. <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fishel-Hoch </PERSON> of the institute. It was first identified in <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION> in 1976, where over 500 people died. The virus kills 50 percent to 90 percent of those it infects. There is no vaccine. Health officials said Friday that <PERSON> Hazleton </PERSON> employees who had worked with the monkeys had worn surgical masks, gowns and gloves on the job. `` At this point, I do n't see where we have a health problem,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION>. `` We probably would have seen something by now if someone was infected, but we're still taking every precaution we can.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> said the 25 workers will be examined daily for the next three weeks in cooperation with the <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0615EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HealthCareSpending     12-02 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Health Care Spending,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Seeking to Tighten Medicare Spending</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The White House budget office wants to trim about $ 9.5 billion from projected spending on health and social programs in fiscal 1991, according to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration budget documents. Most of that would come from shaving $ 8 billion from what otherwise would have been spent on the <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> program next fiscal year under current law, according to the documents obtained Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> _ which includes <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, Medicaid, Social Security, the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institutes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> _ proposed a fiscal 1991 spending plan with $ 8.2 billion in savings. Of that total, <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> proposed to trim $ 5.1 billion from projected 1991 spending on <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, which finances health care for the nation's 33 million elderly and disabled. The White House Office of Management and Budget, however, wants to trim $ 8.1 billion from projected growth in the program, through reductions in payments to doctors, hospital reimbursement rates and other payments to hospitals for capital improvements and medical education. An <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> source, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said the budgets of a number of programs, including <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, are the subject of `` serious discussions'' between White House budget and department officials. Medicare spending is expected to reach $ 114 billion this year. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bromberg </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION>, which represents private hospitals, called the proposed cut `` ridiculous'' and said he doubted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would go along. `` The economic impact of not having your income keep up with your uncontrollable cost increases means either reduced quality or reduced quantity _ either you cut services or the quality is going to suffer,'' he said. Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>, ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, is circulating a letter among his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> colleagues saying the nation's rural, inner-city and teaching hospitals `` simply can not continue to absorb another year of significant budget cuts.'' This year, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> restored about half of the $ 5 billion that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had proposed to cut out of Medicare for the fiscal year that began Oct. 1. In the federal-state Medicaid program, which provides health care for the poor, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> sought to expand eligibility to include pregnant women and infants up to 150 percent of the poverty level, up from the current 133 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> source said the department is reassessing whether states should be required or just encouraged to expand eligibility. Governors have complained that expansions of the Medicaid program are straining their state budgets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0616EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SeditionTrial Bjt   12-02 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sedition Trial, Bjt,0576</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Spends Millions to Try Radicals; Loses Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHELLE LOCKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government dropped its sedition and racketeering case against three leading militants of the 1970s after three years and more than $ 2 million in trial costs. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Budd </PERSON> said Friday he will not retry the case. Prosecutors claimed the radicals conspired to overthrow the government by force through a series of bombings and bank robberies. `` Given the amount of effort already expended in the investigation and prosecution, and the effort that would be needed for a new trial, I have decided that the best course is not to seek a retrial,'' he said. The federal jury cleared the three of sedition charges with a partial verdict Monday, then deadlocked on whether alleged bombing exploits constituted racketeering. A mistrial on the racketeering charges was declared Wednesday. Defendants <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Levasseur </PERSON> and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> will not go free because they are serving 45-year sentences on convictions in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> federal court on some of the bombings. But the third defendant, <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Levasseur </PERSON>, has been released from prison after serving 3 -LCB- years of a five-year federal term for harboring a fugitive, her husband <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>. `` I am grateful for my new life,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Levasseur </PERSON> said. `` I think it was a very reasonable thing that the government is doing by not retrying this case and I want to thank the jury and the community that they come from here for having belief in my innocence.'' Defense attorneys were delighted. `` I'm speechless. After 2 -LCB- years or whatever it's been on this case, it's the right result and I'm a little bit overwhelmed that the government did the right thing in this case at this juncture,'' said attorney <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>. Estimates of the trial costs ranged from $ 2 million to $ 10 million, much of it for the crew of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> marshals brought in to maintain security. The case began in May 1986 with an indictment against eight people on charges of seditious conspiracy, racketeering and racketeering conspiracy. Each count carries a maximum term of 20 years and $ 20,000 in fines. During the course of the case, charges were dropped against two of the defendants who were already serving long prison terms. Two others pleaded guilty and charges were dropped against a fifth person after a judge suppressed evidence seized at her house. By the start of trial in January, only three defendants remained. Prosecutors claimed the three were members of an underground group which bombed courthouses and other facilities from 1976 to 1984 in a plot to overthrow the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. They claimed the group robbed banks to finance their actions. But the defense hailed the jury's rejection of the seditious conspiracy charges as vindication of their argument that the indictment in effect was for `` thought crimes'' and should never have been lodged. The government has used the sedition statute only a few times since it was first invoked to punish Confederates during the Civil War, according to <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, a professor at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> England </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>. It was used to keep protesters from hindering the draft during World War I and to prosecute Puerto Rican nationalists accused in an assassination attempt against then President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Truman </PERSON>. Last April, nine white supremacists were acquitted of seditious conspiracy charges in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0617EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Osprey     12-02 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Osprey,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pentagon Shuts Off Money For Osprey Aircraft</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has ordered an immediate halt to all production spending on the V-22 Osprey, the vertical takeoff plane the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> and members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> want but the administration wants to cancel. Deputy Defense Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON> sent instructions Friday to <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> to `` terminate forthwith'' all contracts financed out of the previous fiscal year's $ 334 million for procurement, said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartung </PERSON>, a department spokesman. Those contracts were for items that take a long time to supply, the so-called `` long lead'' items. Though all $ 334 million had been obligated, `` much of it remains unspent,'' said <PERSON> Hartung </PERSON>, reading from <PERSON> Atwood </PERSON>'s memo. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this fiscal year refused the administration's request to kill the plane, but did limit its appropriation of $ 255 million to research and development. Though the <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> had placed a high priority on the Osprey to ferry troops ashore from ships off landing beaches, <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> decided that the $ 27 billion needed for the desired fleet of aircraft could be better spent elsewhere and helicopters used for the ferry job. Backers of the plane, to built near <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, by a joint endeavor of <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Bell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Textron </ORGANIZATION>, argued that it could be enormously useful in easing airspace congestion around heavily used airports, but critics retorted that if it were commercially valuable, airlines and manufacturers would finance it themselves.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0620EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RockyFlats     12-02 0589</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rocky Flats,0608</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rocky Flats Halts Plutonium Production Indefinitely</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN K. PAULSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GOLDEN, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government halted operations at the Rocky Flats nuclear weapons plant to resolve safety questions including whether enough plutonium dust has accumulated in the pipes to cause an uncontrolled nuclear reaction. Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> announced a major management shakeup at the plant and said it would not reopen until the government and the plant's new contractor _ <ORGANIZATION> EG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> G </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> _ are satisfied safety concerns have been met. At a news conference at the plant, 16 miles north of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said plutonium operations had been scaled back 20 percent and would be shut down altogether in the coming days. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> acknowledged that any long-term shutdown could seriously affect the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' nuclear weapons capability. The plant is the only one of its kind in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that makes plutonium triggers for nuclear weapons. Other plants in the nuclear weapons industry that have been at least partly shut down in the last two years include the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Site </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, the plutonium processing plant at the Hanford Reservation in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, and the Feed Materials Production Center, a uranium plant in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. Rocky Flats has been plagued by safety accusations in recent years and is the target of a federal criminal probe that so far has not resulted in indictments. Earlier this fall, <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION> terminated its management agreement with <ORGANIZATION> Rockwell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and signed a new accord with <ORGANIZATION> EG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; G, which is scheduled to take over fully Jan. 1. After touring the plant, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said, `` Although no major hardware problems were identified by the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> team, conduct of operations, standards of performance, engineering support and management structure remain deficient.'' Among the safety concerns he cited was an October report issued by a team of independent investigators which found weapon-grade plutonium in a pipe that serves as an exhaust ventilation duct at one of the plant's main buildings. Initial reports indicated there was enough plutonium present _ about 12 pounds _ to cause `` criticality,'' or a nuclear reaction, but another study found there was less plutonium in the ducts than originally thought. Both reports said there was no evidence a reaction had occurred. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said the criticality issue does not pose a public safety threat. `` Nevertheless, because it is an important safety issue, I am asking EG & amp; G to independently review the report's findings and produce their own action plan,'' he said. Gov. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Romer </PERSON>, who was present at <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' news conference, said the decision to shut down plutonium processing at <ORGANIZATION> Rocky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flats </ORGANIZATION> shows a new commitment by <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> to safety. He added: `` It's obvious that the proof is in the pudding, and it's my job as governor of <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> to make sure the citizens are safe.'' Rep. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, D-Colo., who earlier called for a complete shutdown at Rocky Flats, said <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> `` seems to be taking a positive, if somewhat uncertain step, but in the right direction. <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON> said it was unclear how the shutdown period at Rocky Flats would be evaluated and verified. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> admitted that <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> made major mistakes at Rocky Flats. `` We did not bring our management into the modern world and we're going to do that now,'' he said. Part of the shutdown period will be dedicated to safety training, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said. He said it would be necessary to regain public trust. `` Of course we have a credibility problem. What we are trying to do now is regain it,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0630EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NBC-GE     12-02 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-NBC-GE,230</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper Reports Network Removes Reference to Parent Company</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A producer at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show says his deletion of an unfavorable reference to <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in a report on defective aircraft engine bolts had nothing to do with <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION>'s ownership of the network. `` I definitely was n't more careful because <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> was involved,'' executive producer <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> in a story published today. The original report said that <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION>, a manufacturer of aircraft engines among other things, accepted defective bolts from a supplier and for eight years did not require that the supplier certify the product's quality. The report, broadcast Thursday on the network's morning show, mentioned other manufacturers, but only the part pertaining to <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> was cut, the newspaper said. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said `` an expanded spot'' about the GE allegations will air on the show next week. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> said he did not think the reporter, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ-TV </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, had `` journalistically -LRB- covered -RRB- all his bases.'' The <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> station had prepared and originally aired the report. <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> called the omission `` one of those things.'' <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> said he had been asked by `` Today'' show producers whether he had contacted GE for comment on the report. The reporter said he had done so on several occasions. `` My view is that you make a mistake when you treat your employer differently than anybody else,'' <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Magers </PERSON>, an anchorman at <ORGANIZATION> WMAQ </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted as saying.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0646EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Soviet-Bullfights     12-02 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Soviet-Bullfights,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spanish Bullfights to Be Staged in Moscow</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The best of <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>'s bullfighters will go to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> next year to battle 30 bulls in a Soviet demonstration of their death-defying art, <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported. The official news agency said Friday that five bullfights will be staged in June at <LOCATION> Luzhniki </LOCATION> stadium, which seats 100,000 people. <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said the agreement for the bullfights was signed by representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperation </ORGANIZATION> with Foreign Countries and the Spanish firm <PERSON> Tresin </PERSON>. `` It is so far unclear which of the -LRB- Spanish -RRB- matadors will arrive,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported. `` But in the opinion of master bullfighter <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Galindo </PERSON>, a 25-year-old toreador with 10 years of experience behind him, the best will be here,'' the news agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-India 1stLd-Writethru   12-02 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0701,0722</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leader of Opposition Coalition Named Prime Minister</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs with Singh sworn in, Gandhi offering congratulations;
picks up 4th pvs, `Singh's selection...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VIJAY JOSHI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vishwanath </PERSON> <PERSON> Pratap </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was sworn in as prime minister Saturday to replace <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, and the new leader said his first goal would be to bring dignity to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, whose previous government was dogged by allegations of corruption. President <PERSON> Ramaswamy </PERSON> <PERSON> Venkataraman </PERSON>, who administered the oath of office at the presidential palace, has given <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> 30 days to prove his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> coalition </ORGANIZATION> can muster a vote of confidence in the new <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>, now consigned to the role of opposition leader, smiled as he approached <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> after the 10-minute ceremony. He was one of the first to offer congratulations. On Friday, <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> also was elected parliamentary leader of the centrist <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> and of the coalition's largest party, the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s selection came after last-minute conferences, a fistfight, and allegations of skullduggery within the front, which is united by little more than antipathy to <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. It formed a cohesive opposition force to defeat <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> in national elections Nov. 22-26. `` My first task is to restore the dignity of the country,'' <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> said Friday. `` We should make an <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> of which every Indian will be proud.'' The 58-year-old former defense minister said foreign policy would remain largely unaltered and that the government would take the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> into confidence on `` national issues.'' The Janata Dal has 141 of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s 144 seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>'s new policy-making lower house. The other three seats went to smaller parties in the coalition. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s party has 192 seats, and its allies have another 17. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> has also been promised support by the <ORGANIZATION> Bharatiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which has 88 seats, and by a combination of left-wing groups, which won 51 constituencies. That would give the coalition and its tacit allies 283 seats _ enough to carry a vote of confidence in the government. Although the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has more seats than the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, it would have had more trouble forming a coalition. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> became prime minister in 1984 after the assassination of his mother, Prime Minister <PERSON> Indira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>. His aides predicted the new government will fall apart before its five-year term expires, clearing the way for new elections and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s return to power. The party governed <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> for nearly all <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 42 years of independence. The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said it would not stake a claim to form the government. Instead, it appeared prepared to wait to see if <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> could preserve a government with his ideologically diverse allies. Coalition members said Thursday that <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, a former defense minister, was the only candidate for prime minister. But <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>'s professed reluctance for the job spurred two other candidates, <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Devi </PERSON> <PERSON> Lal </PERSON>, to enter the fray A whirlwind of consultations began Friday as <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and other leaders drove from house to house and office to office. A few hours before <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was named prime minister, riot police quelled fistfights between supporters of <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON> in the street outside <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON>'s home. <PERSON> Ram </PERSON> <PERSON> Jethmalani </PERSON>, a senior member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, was punched and kicked by supporters of <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON> when he got out of his car to begin a hunger strike aimed at persuading <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON> to step aside in favor of <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>. The 78-year-old <PERSON> Jethmalani </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s top criminal lawyers, fell to the ground as the two sides traded punches. <PERSON> Chandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Shekhar </PERSON> stalked out of the parliamtentary meeting after <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was chosen party leader. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> was in <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s Cabinet until 1987, when he resigned amid reports his investigations into government corruption were proving embarrassing to the prime minister. Shortly afterward, Swedish and Indian newspaper and radio reports disclosed the Swedish arms manufacturer <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> paid as much as $ 50 million in commissions and kickbacks to get a $ 1.4 billion contract to supply the Indian army with artillery guns. <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> vigorously denied wrongdoing, and the charges have never been proved, but they raised serious questions about the <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s integrity and cost him popular support
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0645EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WrinkleCream     12-02 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wrinkle Cream,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Studies to Begin on `Second Generation' Wrinkle Cream</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Researchers start clinical trials next month on a new vitamin A cream that researchers believe will smooth the small wrinkles from aging, sun-damaged skin, without the irritating side effects of Retin A. Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON>, chairman of dermatology at <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, said the cream, called <LOCATION> Pelretin </LOCATION>, has proven in animal tests to be able to restore wrinkled skin to a youthful look. Now, he said Friday, the cream will be tested for six months on 240 patients in three cities to see if it works on humans. The results should be known in about a year, but it may take up to four years before <PERSON> Pelretin </PERSON> is approved for prescription use, the researcher said. The clinical tests were organized after <PERSON> Pelretin </PERSON> was tested on rabbits and the rhino mouse, a rodent that is genetically disposed to develop wrinkles early in life. The results of the animal tests, said <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON>, were `` dramatic.'' <PERSON> Pelretin </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON>, is a `` first cousin'' to Retin A, a prescription cream that was developed to treat acne but which doctors discovered also is effective against skin wrinkling. `` Pelretin should offer an advantage over Retin A because the early studies suggest it has a similar therapeutic response but with less side effects,'' he said. `` This is really a second generation of cosmetic pharmaceutical.'' The side effects of Retin A include a reddening of the skin, scaling and flaking, along with a burning sensation, <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON> said. The doctor said <PERSON> Pelretin </PERSON> `` has been through all of the studies ... to make sure it is a safe product to be used in human testing.'' Both Retin A and <PERSON> Pelretin </PERSON> contain a Vitamin A compound that some researchers claim has been shown in tests to smooth aging, damaged skin. Other dermatologists, however, claim that the creams only give the appearance of smoothing the skin and that the effects are not real. <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON> said his research with Retin A demonstrates that the compound does remove some wrinkles, giving what he called `` excellent'' results for 28.5 percent of patients who use the cream and `` good'' for 47.6 percent. But he said about half of the patients who used the placebo also showed `` good'' results because `` we taught them how to take care of their skin.'' <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON> said laboratory tests have shown that vitamin A compounds do improve skin tone. He said biopsies of skin treated with Retin A show that it has a hormonal effect that causes skin tissue to thicken. This, in turn, causes some wrinkles to smooth out. Volunteers for the clinical tests are being accepted at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, and at hospitals in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>. The study is to start Jan. 8. <PERSON> Nigra </PERSON> said the patients in the study must be white, between 40 and 70 years of age and have skin that has been moderately to severely damaged from a lifetime of exposure. Other races will be tested later, he said, although dark skins tend not to be easily damaged by the sun.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0333EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Comaneci     12-02 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Comaneci,0537</SECOND>
<HEAD>Perfect Gymnast Lands in U.S.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BETH J. HARPAZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, who vaulted gracefully into American hearts as a tiny gymnast performing airy gyrations in the 1976 Olympics, has leaped what remains of the Iron Curtain to come live in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The 28-year-old <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, who defected from <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> on Tuesday, flew here Friday on the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> plane `` Liberty Bell'' from <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. `` I'm very happy because I'm here in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and I wanted from long time to come here,'' she said in halting English at a news conference at <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> F. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. `` I wanted to have a free life.'' <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> contacted a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> on Friday morning and was quickly granted refugee status, said <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> deputy spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>. He added, `` We certainly welcome Ms. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>.'' Asked how long she had thought about defecting, she replied, `` A long time. I had it in my mind for a few years.'' <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> has traveled abroad frequently since becoming the first gymnast ever to score a perfect 10 at the Olympics. She won 21 gold medals altogether in Olympic and other international meets during her career, which earned her a life of privilege in a country that has endured chronic shortages of consumer goods for most of this decade. Her defection Tuesday to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> was a blow to the hard-line government of Romanian President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>, who had named the gymnast a `` Hero of Socialist Labor'' for her athletic accomplishments. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was held up as a role model for Romanian youth. When asked what political impact her defection will have on <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> replied: `` It's not my business.'' The refugee status means <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials believe <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> has a well-founded fear of persecution if she returns to <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, where the government has rejected the reformist tide sweeping other East European countries. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> was accompanied at the news conference by a man who appeared to be translating reporters' questions for her. She introduced <PERSON> Konstantin </PERSON> <PERSON> Panit </PERSON> by saying: `` This is my friend who helped me to come here. I want to thank him.'' Her former gymnastics coach, <PERSON> Bela </PERSON> <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON>, left <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1981 and had encouraged <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> earlier this week to follow his example. `` I knew she was unsatisfied and unhappy about her personal situation,'' he said. `` I was very happy to know she chose freedom and decided to make this very difficult step.'' <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON> said he suspects she will be bombarded by `` business propositions.'' <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON> coached the then 14-year-old <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> during her perfect performances at the <LOCATION> Montreal </LOCATION> games. Speaking from <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> on Friday, <PERSON> Karolyi </PERSON> said he planned to return to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Sunday to meet with <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, possibly in <LOCATION> Indianopolis </LOCATION>, headquarters of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Gymnastics Federation. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON> would be eligible to apply for permanent resident status in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in one year, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials who requested anonymity said. <PERSON> Comaneci </PERSON>, accompanied by six other Romanians, crossed the border into <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> on Tuesday and went into hiding. She reportedly told a border guard she was leaving her homeland `` for the sake of freedom.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0407EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     12-02 0724</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspected Nazi Guard Stripped Of U.S. Citizenship</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge has issued a court order stripping <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship from a former <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> man accused of serving as a Nazi SS guard at World War II concentration camps. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said Friday that the judge's order stripping <PERSON> Jakob </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Denzinger </PERSON>, 65, of his <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizenship was issued last Monday after the man's attorney told the government <PERSON> Denzinger </PERSON> did not plan to respond to the charges. <PERSON> Denzinger </PERSON>, who had been a successful businessman in <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION>, fled the country before the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> filed its complaint last summer. He is believed to be in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the department said.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>AIDS Rally in Front of White House Brings 78 Arrests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dozens of AIDS activists who were arrested for blocking a public roadway in front of the White House say they were protesting what they call a lack of leadership on the issue by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Many of the 78 who were arrested Friday are directors and top officials of AIDS groups from across the country. They say more money is needed for prevention efforts and health and social services for victims. In all, about 200 protesters gathered in <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> across from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> at a rally marking World AIDS Day. Speakers at the rally mocked a statement by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> earlier this week in which the president said the government is committed to continued AIDS research. Protesters shouted, `` Lies, lies, lies.''
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Oak Ridge Tritium Sales Resume</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has concluded that amounts of a key component of nuclear warheads that had been listed as missing were n't stolen after all, so the agency is resuming commercial sale of the material. The material, tritium, has been sold for 25 years in small amounts for research and for making glow-in-the-dark markings, as for clock faces, exit signs and airport runway markings in remote areas. It is also used to boost the power of nuclear warheads and the power thermonuclear weapons. The department had suspended commercial shipments from the <ORGANIZATION> Oak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> earlier this year after customers complained they had not received all of the material they had been billed for. Friday, the agency said it had found no evidence to support the possibility that the material had been stolen. Deficiencies in measurement methods were among the causes of the shipping discrepancies, the agency said.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Court Asked to Stop Exclusive Programming Rule</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> firm is again asking a federal appeals court to stop a rule from taking effect in January that would let local TV stations stop cable TV systems from carrying some syndicated shows. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, who is representing <LOCATION> Tulsa </LOCATION>, Okla.-based <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Video </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, said Friday he had petitioned the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> for the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to stay the implementation of new syndicated exclusivity, or syndex, rules. Opponents claim the rules will cause massive headaches for cable operators and reduce the opportunities for viewers to watch some of their favorite TV shows. A three-judge panel of the court in October denied an earlier request for a stay, and then on Nov. 17 denied the overall challenge to the rules. <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> said he was seeking a review by the panel or by the full court on First Amendment grounds. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> decided to reimpose the rules in 1988 after an eight-year lapse.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>Malaria Drug Recalled; Wrong Medicine in Bottle</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Chloroquine is CQ</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A malaria drug is being recalled by a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> company because some of the bottles instead contain an animal diuretic. The recall by <ORGANIZATION> Biocraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Elmwood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, applies to Goldline brand 250 milligram chloroquine phosphate tablets packaged in 100-tablet bottles labeled as lot number 14311, the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. The recall began after a pharmacist found a bottle containing the animal diuretic, a drug that steps up production of urine, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said. No injuries have been reported. Bottles containing the wrong drug have been found in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>. Using tablets from the erroneously labeled bottles would not protect against or treat malaria, which can be life-threatening, and large amounts of diuretics can lead to irregular heartbeat, low blood pressure and general weakness, the agency said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0415EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PhoneStrike     12-02 0249</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Phone Strike,0255</SECOND>
<HEAD>Striking NYNEX Workers Approve Contract</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Striking telephone workers ratified a contract negotiated last week after a four-month walkout, and planned to return to work on Monday. `` It's over, it's over, it's over,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Master </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>. `` We're happy. Eighty-five percent of union workers approved the contract with <ORGANIZATION> Nynex </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. The ratification Friday marked the final settlement of strikes against regional telephone companies that began in August. The strikes at one point involved 200,000 workers in 20 states. The <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION>'s 40,000 regional members struck <ORGANIZATION> Nynex </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION>. New England Telephone, another <ORGANIZATION> Nynex </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary, was struck by 20,000 members of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> settled first, and its workers returned to work last month. `` We are very pleased,'' <ORGANIZATION> Nynex </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonomo </PERSON> said, after the <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> ratification vote. `` The settlement is fair for everyone _ customers, employees and shareholders. We're looking forward to welcoming all our employees back to work on Monday, and dedicating ourselves to providing the quality service our customers rely on us for.'' The rancorous <ORGANIZATION> Nynex </ORGANIZATION> walkout left one striker dead after a picket line confrontation; the company reported hundreds of instances of sabotage against its equipment. The strike created long delays for people and companies seeking new telephone installations. The major point of contention concerned the company's insistence that workers share part of their health costs. But the final settlement did not include any health-cost sharing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0432EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CaliforniaFoxes     12-02 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-California Foxes,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Growing Populations Of The Red Fox Has Officials Worried</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Roving bands of cunning red foxes are outwitting <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> officials, who worry that the animals threaten endangered native birds and other animals. `` The population seems to be exploding now for some reason and we are not sure why,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Sitton </PERSON>, wildlife management supervisor of the state <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fish </ORGANIZATION> and Game in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` This has resulted in a terrible, terrible problem for native species, pushing some to the brink of extinction.'' Red foxes have been spotted in <LOCATION> Torrance </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Segundo </LOCATION>, and near the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. They attack endangered birds such as the least tern and the clapper rail. Attempts to control the animal, which is not native to the area, have proved futile. `` They are rather shy and wary of people,'' said <PERSON> Rudi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mattoni </PERSON>, a biologist. `` The story about being foxy is no joke: They are very difficult to catch.'' <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, a biologist with the Natural History Museum of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> said no one really knows how the red fox, a native of the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, got to this part of the state. <PERSON> Mattoni </PERSON> said despite her efforts, up to 20 species of small animals have disappeared from the dunes just west of the airport because of the predator's appetite. `` Remember how common it used to be to see rabbits on the runways?'' <PERSON> Mattoni </PERSON> asked. `` Well, ai n't no more rabbits.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891202-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-12-02-89 0433EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Obit-Ailey Bjt   12-02 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Ailey, Bjt,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Giant of Modern Dance Dies at 58</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARBARA ROSEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
