<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-GermanRefugees     08-08 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-German Refugees,0493</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bonn Closes Its East Berlin Mission Due To Refugee Overflow</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 West German officials said the <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> government closed its <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> mission to the public Tuesday because its capacities were `` completely exhausted.'' The West German government accused <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> of being responsible for a wave of refugees seeking to leave their communist homeland. Scores of East Germans have fled to West German diplomatic missions in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>; the Hungarian capital of <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> officials said 130 East German citizens are in the West German mission in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and are refusing to leave, demanding that <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> allow them to emigrate. Claus <LOCATION> Duisberg </LOCATION>, an aide to Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>, called on <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to `` create conditions ... that would give people reason for staying.'' A leading West German parliamentarian, <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON>, said East German leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> should either initiate political reforms or resign, a newspaper reported. `` <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> and his old men should finally leave,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Cologne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted <PERSON> Lintner </PERSON> as saying. East German officials have refused to adopt political reforms like those under way in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Hundreds of East Germans have been trying to leave through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, which has been dismantling border barriers along its frontier with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. Seventy-two East Germans who fled through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> arrived at a temporary housing center in <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, on Tuesday after traveling by train from <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. News reports say about 200 East Germans are inside the West German Embassy in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, demanding that their government let them move to the West. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> news reports say about 20 East Germans are inside the West German mission in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> on Monday accused the <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> of `` gross interference'' in East German's internal affairs. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> summoned <PERSON> Lothar </PERSON> <PERSON> Glienke </PERSON>, head of the East German diplomatic mission in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>, to the chancellery to protest the statement, said <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> government spokesman <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON> said West German officials also discussed the situation at the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> mission with <PERSON> Glienke </PERSON> and appealed to the East German government to `` contribute to the solution of these matters.'' `` The federal government wants to continue its constructive cooperation with the German Democratic Republic -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB- despite this situation,'' <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON> said. West German officials said <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> agreed not to arrest refuge-seekers inside the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> mission if they leave the complex, but refused to guarantee they would be permitted to leave the country. The West German newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Bild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeitung </ORGANIZATION> reported the number of East Germans who moved to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> _ both legally and illegally _ increased dramatically since last year. It said the figure for the first seven months of this year was 55,970 compared with 39,832 for all of last year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 2333EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Obit-Mladek     08-08 0228</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Mladek,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Czech, IMF Official Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON>, a member of <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>'s last non-communist government and a retired <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> official, died of cancer at <ORGANIZATION> George </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON>, who was 77, died Monday. <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON> was also a founder of the Central and <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which promoted East European artists. Trained as an economist, he served in the anti-Nazi Czech army in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> before becoming head of the exile Czechoslovakian government's monetary department in the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION>. He was vice chairman of the Czech delegation to the 1944 <ORGANIZATION> Bretton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Woods </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, which planned <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>'s postwar economy and where the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION>, the worldwide lending agency, was created. An official in the finance ministry in the government of Persident <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> Benes </PERSON> after the war, <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON> represented <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> on the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION> executive board. He became the <ORGANIZATION> IMF </ORGANIZATION>'s deputy director of operations at its <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> headquarters after the communists took power in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> in 1948 He was head of the fund's central banking service for 14 years before retiring in 1977. <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Meda </PERSON>, established the art foundation in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and helped mount shows of East and Central European art at the city's <PERSON> Hirschorn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Corcoran </PERSON> art galleries. Born in <LOCATION> Bochnia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, in what was then the Austro-Hungarian Empire, <PERSON> Mladek </PERSON> became a naturalized American citizen in 1960.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PublisherQuits     08-08 0321</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Publisher Quits,0328</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publisher Of Arizona Republic and Phoenix Gazette Steps Down</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY LOPEZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, publisher of The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>, resigned Tuesday, saying he felt it was time to move on. `` I just turned 60 last week, and sometimes you ask yourself how much time do you have left to do things you want to do?'' he said. `` I've had 3 -LCB- years as publisher and brought some terrific people _ managing editors and assistant managing editors _ on board.'' `` I've gotten as much satisfaction as a publisher could have,'' he said in an interview, adding that it was time `` to take a breather.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said he did n't know what he'd do next but was stepping down immediately, trying to sell a screenplay and might write a novel. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION> company that controls the newspapers, said a search would begin for a successor to <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, `` a person with a proven track record as a publisher of a major metropolitan newspaper.'' Central Newspapers is owned by the <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON> family and includes Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> as one of its owners. It owns <ORGANIZATION> Phoenix </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which was headed by <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> and which publishes the weekly <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> as well as the daily Republic and Gazette. Editors of the Republic, <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> will report directly to <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pulliam </PERSON>, publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indianapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, until <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s successor is named, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Shover </PERSON>, director of public affairs for the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> newspapers. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a former columnist, took over the <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> newspapers on March 11, 1986. He took an active role as publisher, describing maverick Republican Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> as a ideological juggernaut even as <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> attacked the newspapers and their reporting. <PERSON> Mecham </PERSON> was ousted by a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> of Impeachment last year but found innocent on criminal charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMEPublicService     08-08 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-APME Public Service,0840</SECOND>
<HEAD>Public Service Finalists Announced</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twenty newspapers have been selected as finalists in the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> Managing Editors Association's 19th annual Public Service Awards competition The finalists were announced Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> judges, who met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The finalists were chosen from 126 entries _ 73 from newspapers with more than 50,000 circulation and 53 with less than 50,000 circulation. One winner from each category will be announced in October at the APME convention in <LOCATION> Des </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Moines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. `` The high quality of the entries reflects the extraordinary commitment of talent and resources by newspapers to probing examinations of the core problems afflicting the communities we serve,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Giles </PERSON>, immediate past president of <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> and chair of the judging committee. `` The themes of the entries focused on the most troubling problems we face as a democratic society: drugs, homelessness, care of the aged, toxic chemicals, race relations, the environment, governmental corruption and incompetence,'' said <PERSON> Giles </PERSON>, who is editor and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Giles </PERSON> said the judges were particularly impressed with the strong entries from the smaller newspapers. Finalists in the less than 50,000 category, listed alphabetically, are: The <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, for a report on the effects of alcoholism among the Indian residents of Gallup, N.M. The State-Times of <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, for its investigation of improprieties by a parish clerk of court that led to a special grand jury investigation. The Beverly -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Times and The Peabody -LRB- Mass. -RRB- Times, for an in-depth report on the homeless in the suburbs of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Gwinnett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Lawrenceville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, for its disclosures that county officials and their spouses had spent $ 50,000 in public money on a junket to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The stories led to reforms and repayment of most of the money. Herald-Dispatch of <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, for a report through which West Virginians set the agenda for the state's gubernatorial campaign The Journal of Commerce -LRB- <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -RRB-, for its investigation of how the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> handles famine relief shipments to poor nations. The stories forced the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> to hold open bidding for contracts to ship the food. <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News, for its special report on destitute Haitian, Mexican and Guatemalan migrant workers who had been victimized by slumlords. <LOCATION> Poughkeepsie </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal, for a series that exposed how bigotry affected the lives of <LOCATION> Dutchess </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s small black community. <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION> -RRB- Progress, for an investigation of abuses in land deals that allowed developers to pay low taxes and benefit from special city projects tailored to their developments. The stories led to a series of reforms. The <LOCATION> Wilkes-Barre </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times Leader, for an investigation into illegal activities by local sewer department officials. The stories were followed by a public investigation and reforms. Finalists from newspapers with more than 50,000 circulation are, alphabetically: <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News, for its coverage of the Exxon Valdez oil spill. <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, for its investigation into the mismanagement, greed and corruption that created the savings and loan crisis. <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION>, for an investigation of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Olympic Committee that revealed widespread improprieties and led to corrective measures. The <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, for its investigation of a $ 2 million land deal that became a $ 42 million taxpayer purchase of used equipment, which the city later resold for a nickel on the dollar. During the investigation, the city's chief lawyer was jailed for ignoring a judge's order to provide public documents to the newspaper. The <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News, for its examination of substandard housing in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Courant, for its series `` Two Connecticuts,'' which explored inequality and separateness in the state. The <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sentinel, for its series that brought to public view a system of neglect and abuse in homes for the aged in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. The series led to reforms. <LOCATION> Roanoke </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times & amp; World-News, for an investigation of how <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>'s weak regulation of the pest control industry had resulted in shocking abuses. The newspaper's efforts spurred the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> to pass a tough law. <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION>, for its exhaustive portrait of homosexuals in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. USA Today, for its extensive examination of campus security at 50 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> colleges and universities that resulted in a comprehensive report card on campus crime. The judges of the <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> Awards competition are past presidents of <ORGANIZATION> APME </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to <PERSON> Giles </PERSON>, they are: <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Allison </PERSON>, senior vice president-editor of the <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Press-Telegram; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davies </PERSON>, editor and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hartford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Courant </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daubel </PERSON>, editor and publisher of the News-Messenger, of Fremont, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haiman </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Poynter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Petersburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Natt </PERSON>, editor and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shoquist </PERSON>, dean of the <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Iran-CIA 1stLd-Writethru a0414 08-08 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iran-CIA, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0414,0389</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: U.S. Says Iran Broke CIA Spy Ring</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 8th, `It was...,' to UPDATE with CIA spokesman
not commenting on Times report.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has broken a network of spies who provided the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> with intimate details and documents about Iranian military planning, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said in Tuesday's editions. Citing unnamed <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said the Iranians had detected the network months before it actually collapsed and had used the spies to give the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> false information. But some officials told the Times that before the network was compromised, it yielded valuable military intelligence, particularly about the Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s operations in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> at a time when American naval forces were confronting the Iranians. The network did not supply intelligence on hostage cases or political developments. The Times' sources confirmed for the first time Iranian claims that spies had been arrested. The sources said the Iranian military, many of whose members were trained in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, was considered one of the less difficult groups in the country from which to recruit agents. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> had more difficulty recruiting agents from among pro-Iranian militants or officials in the Iranian Government who deal with <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. All of those in the dismantled intelligence ring were believed to be Iranians, the Times said. It was not known how <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> uncovered the operation or how long <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> used it to feed false information to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, when informed of the <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> report, said, `` We do not comment on allegations of intelligence activity.'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> first disclosed the existence of the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> operation on April 21, when <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who was then speaker of the Iranian <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, told a Friday prayer meeting in <LOCATION> Teheran </LOCATION> about `` several dens of espionage.'' Over the next few months, Iranian television broadcast a succession of programs in which purported spies confessed to their roles. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials told the Times that the broadcasts _ which described everything from secret writing techniques to the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> recruitment of agents through greed, entrapment and blackmail _ were a mixture of fact and fiction. Several officials told the Times that most of those identified were double agents controlled by <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BalloonCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0654 08-08 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Balloon Crash, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0654,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Investigator Says Balloon Leaked Before Takeoff</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `The balloon...,' to CORRECT spelling of town
to Paonia, sted Panonia.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hot-air balloon that crashed and killed its pilot was leaking before take-off during a national competition, a federal investigator said Monday. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mock </PERSON>, who was killed Saturday when his balloon deflated at 3,000 feet as thousands of spectators watched, should have noticed rips in the balloon's fabric during inflation, said <PERSON> Armond </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, an investigator for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. `` If the pilot had looked closely at the balloon, he would have noticed the separations I showed you,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said at news conference where the balloon was displayed. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said he also was unable to locate a large thermometer required for the balloon by federal law. The device warns pilots about overheating. The balloon was 12 years old, although registration records showed that Mock of <LOCATION> Paonia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, bought it in January, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. The average life of a hot-air balloon is 10 years, he said. Mock, a former crop-dusting pilot, had logged 180 hours of balloon flight time, most of it over the past 12 months. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said it was the first balloon fatality he has investigated that involved the fabric. Accidents involving power lines are the most common, he said. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said the fabric ripped `` at the top of the balloon. That's the most critical part. Once you lose that there's nothing you can do.'' Although only one seam ripped open Saturday, several other seams had begun to separate and could have split completely at any time, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said. The fatality was the first in the 19-year history of the national balloon championship, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RecumbentBikes     08-08 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Recumbent Bikes,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iowa Company Makes Recumbent Bicycles</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GREG SMITH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GUTTENBERG, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Troy </PERSON> <PERSON> Thein </PERSON> gets some funny looks from motorists when he rides his bike to work. It could be his unusual posture _ leaning back with his feet pedaling in the air _ or the fact that he keeps up with traffic going 50 mph. `` People right here in town still look at me funny. They say, ` What's that? Where did you get that?,'' said <PERSON> Thein </PERSON>. `` The other day I was coming down the <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION> hill and was going 52 miles per hour.'' <PERSON> Thein </PERSON> is one of three workers at <ORGANIZATION> Kann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturing </ORGANIZATION>, the <PERSON> Guttenberg </PERSON> company that makes the Linear brand of recumbent bicycles. The company also makes aluminum semi-trailers, commercial work boats and grain-hauling bodies for trucks. Instead of the standard bicycle seat, the recumbent bicycle has a cushioned chair that supports a rider's back, making it easier to generate pedal power. The upright position of a rider also puts less pressure on the diaphragm for easier breathing, and the position allows for an unrestricted view without neck cramping. The Linear bike has an aluminum frame and under-the-seat steering so that a rider's arms hang down in their natural position. Its 18 gears are shifted by a flick of the thumb. The Linear, designed by company president <PERSON> Dirk </PERSON> <PERSON> Kann </PERSON>, is the only recumbent on the market that can be folded. That enables the 7-foot bike to fit in a car trunk, <PERSON> Hansel </PERSON> said. `` You have to get used to it, but once you do, it's extremely comfortable. It's much more efficient than the traditional 10-speed or 12-speed,'' said <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansel </PERSON>, director of production and marketing at <LOCATION> Kann </LOCATION>. Recumbent bicycles have been around since the 1920s, <PERSON> Hansel </PERSON> said, and <PERSON> Kann </PERSON> has been making them for five years. The company hopes within two years to be making 1,200 recumbents annually. <PERSON> Hansel </PERSON> said the Linear, which retails for about $ 850, is faster than conventional bicycles. `` A recumbent would just walk away with it in a race,'' he said. The world record speed for bicycles _ 65 mph _ was set in the mid-1960s by an aerodynamic recumbent. However, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kukoda </PERSON>, a senior editor who road-tests bicycles for Bicycling magazine, said the recumbent has its disadvantages. `` I think they're inferior going up hills because there's no way to stand up. You're not able to use the biggest muscles in the body, the rear-end and lower back. I found it takes a lot more power and energy to climb hills,'' <PERSON> Kukoda </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from the monthly's headquarters in <LOCATION> Emmaus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> disagrees <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> and a companion, <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pot </PERSON>, plan on Aug. 2 to embark on a 44,000-mile journey around the world riding Linear recumbents. `` When I'm going up a hill, I find I'm breathing easier and am not as tired when I get to the top than if I were hunched over a traditional bike. I'm able to recover a lot faster,'' <PERSON> Finney </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MaggotTreatment     08-08 0258</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Maggot Treatment,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Maggots Used To Treat Teen-Ager's Leg</HEAD>
<DATELINE>POOLESVILLE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Doctors used maggots to clean up rotted skin caused by a massive infection on a teen-ager's legs, and the treatment resulted in a remarkable recovery, her parents said. <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillingham </PERSON>, 17, was stricken with <LOCATION> meningococcemia </LOCATION>, a blood-borne bacterial infection that eventually caused her to suffer heart failure, kidney problems, diseased skin and the loss of one foot and the toes on the other foot. She was critically ill when she was taken to <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> on May 11. She was in fair condition Monday, a hospital spokeswoman said. Antibiotics used to treat the bacteria had caused blood clots, which reduced the flow of blood to her legs, resulting in the rotting of the skin on her lower legs, said the girl's father, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillingham </PERSON>. Her left foot and ankle and her toes on the right foot had to be amputated. Then doctors pondered how to clean the remaining skin. Antibiotics did not work fast enough. So on July 21, more than 1,500 fly larvae were scooped onto her legs with tongue depressors and secured with tape. Maggots eat only dead flesh, leaving healthy skin intact, said Dr. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Fields </PERSON>. After 36 hours, doctors used a high-pressure hose to wash them from her legs. The skin grafts are taking and she will soon be fitted with prostheses and learn to walk again, her family said. <PERSON> Dillingham </PERSON> called her recovery miraculous. He said the medical bills were expected to be as much as $ 750,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-S&amp;Ls Bjt   08-08 0646</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-S&amp;Ls, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Administration Ready to Begin S&amp;L Bailout</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is poised to begin pumping money into the nation's failed savings and loan institutions as soon as possible after the president signs the bill on Wednesday. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> intends to enact the historic legislation in a White House ceremony on Wednesday, said administration and congressional sources, speaking on condition of anonymity. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it will borrow the first $ 5 billion installment of the bailout on Thursday. The legislation, passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday, authorizes $ 50 billion in borrowing over the next 26 months to close or merge 500 insolvent S & amp; Ls. Of that, $ 20 billion must be borrowed in the next eight weeks, before the end of the 1989 fiscal year. <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> officials said $ 15 billion of this year's borrowing will be used to replace high-rate certificates of deposit at some of the 262 failed thrifts already under government control. The goal is to reduce operating losses until regulators can rescue the thrifts permanently. `` The effect ... may be quite significant,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Breeden </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief adviser on savings and loans. `` You're taking some of the institutions that have been rate leaders out of the marketplace. That will reduce pressure on all other institutions, both banks and thrifts, that have had to pay a premium to compete against these unhealthy firms.'' The remaining $ 5 billion raised this year will be used to either shut down or attract new owners to the thrifts in the worst financial trouble. The first of these deals could be announced as soon as this week. `` I think the process will begin very quickly,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deposit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which is getting the job of managing the bailout. However, he said the frequency of rescues will be `` more measured'' than the frantic pace struck at the end of last year, when the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> committed $ 16 billion in a two-day spending spree to rescue 75 institutions. The legislation, in addition to funding the bailout, imposes tough new financial standards on savings and loans and triggers the most sweeping overall changes in the regulatory bureaucracy in 50 years. Among many changes, the <ORGANIZATION> Resolution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trust </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a new agency headed by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, will be created to oversee the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION>'s management of the bailout. <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> said an organizational meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> RTC </ORGANIZATION> board is planned on the same day as the White House signing ceremony and that the board will appoint an executive director. Officials said the board likely will choose someone already within the government as a temporary director until a permanent appointment is made. The administration originally planned to borrow only $ 10 billion in fiscal year 1989, which ends Sept. 30. However, as part of a deal struck with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> just before final passage of the legislation, it agreed to raise $ 20 billion this year. That will balloon the 1989 deficit to near $ 170 billion, the highest in three years. The government will raise another $ 30 billion for rescues in 1990 and 1991, but as part of the compromise the administration will borrow that money through a new, quasi-private agency and the spending will not be counted in the deficit. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it will borrow the first $ 5 billion on Thursday by auctioning 247-day cash management bills, which the government must be repay on April 19. In a related development, the <ORGANIZATION> FDIC </ORGANIZATION> said it is taking over nine insolvent <ORGANIZATION> S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Ls in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, bring the total under government control to 262 in 33 states. Meanwhile, one of the first institutions taken over by regulators this year, <ORGANIZATION> Cartersville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION>, was sold to the <ORGANIZATION> Prudential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Prudential </ORGANIZATION> is investing $ 20 million for $ 56.9 million in assets. No government assistance is involved.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     08-08 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Agriculture Secretary Seeking End to Farm Export Subsidies</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> is stepping up his call for a global agreement to end export subsidies for farm goods as the end of the current round of international trade talks looms. `` The economic case for reform can hardly be more compelling,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Feed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grains </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on Monday. `` The resistance is political.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiators have been pushing the European Community in the current <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round of trade talks to set a deadline for ending all practices that distort agricultural markets. Thus far the Europeans have declined. The negotiations, aimed at updating the 97-nation General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, have 18 months to run. `` The <ORGANIZATION> EC </ORGANIZATION> view seemingly is that such distortions should continue forever _ a most discouraging outlook indeed for the developing countries and for European consumers,'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative before taking over at the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> this year, is a longstanding critic of export subsidies. His remarks in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> contained a new barrage of choice rhetoric on the issue. He described the current system of subsidies under which governments pay farmers and exporters to slash prices and thus stimulate overseas sales as a game of `` fool's monopoly'' and said the place to `` put an end to this madness is the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> Round of Multilateral Trade Negotiations.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> also acknowledged in effect that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is often an active player in the subsidy game. `` Our European colleagues have said repeatedly that there are no angels in agriculture trade,'' he said. `` The question is, how do we get closer to heaven?'' He took aim at two lingering criticisms of the American position in the talks. `` There are some who say that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> proposal is unrealistic _ that governments can not and should not get completely out of agriculture,'' he said. `` But that is not the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. proposal.'' <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> reiterated that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has no complaint about financial supports for agriculture as long as they avoid distortion of global markets. `` We have called only for the elimination of trade-distorting measures over a period of time sufficient to allow farmers to adapt to the new environment.'' He also scoffed at the complaint that the negotiators have never agreed on a definition of which practices are `` trade distorting.'' `` We have 18 months, the final stage of the <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Round </LOCATION>, to decide that,'' he said. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, however, left no doubt as to his view. `` Perhaps the most vivid example is grain,'' he said. `` Ten years ago the <ORGANIZATION> EC </ORGANIZATION> had net imports of nearly 20 million tons. Now the <ORGANIZATION> EC </ORGANIZATION> has net annual exports of about 30 million tons. Their stated goal was self sufficiency. But that goal was reached long ago.'' `` The Community now uses billions of European currency units to unload its surplus production on the world market, undercutting lower cost competitors. `` In contrast the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, most unwisely, has unilaterally disarmed itself by taking vast amounts of land out of production. That action has helped support prices everywhere, but the result has been a loss in market share.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Squalid living conditions in poverty-ridden `` colonias'' along the Mexican border was the topic of a July 25 chat between Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman E. -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Kika </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. The colonias, or shantytowns, often lack such basic facilities as safe drinking water, elementary sanitation and paved streets. Several are located in <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> la </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Garza </LOCATION>'s district in south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and the chairman has come under increasing pressure to do something about them. Consumer advocate <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> criticized de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON> at a committee meeting two years ago over the painful situation in the colonias, and community activists have turned up the heat since then. <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> on Monday announced a $ 5.5 million package of loans and grants targeted for water and sewer projects in colonias in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The funds will be available Oct. 1 and represent 10 percent of the <ORGANIZATION> Farmers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> office reserve, which is held for emergency use to ease health hazards connected with community water and waste treatment, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-08 0906</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0939</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Carl </PERSON>, the lead singer of the band .38 Special, says his <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> roots and family values have kept his perspective in check despite the topsy-turvy life as a rock' n' roll star `` When everything goes awry in the music biz, when they do n't like your demo tape and the telephone calls stop coming _ and it's hot and smoggy outside _ your kid's there and starts giggling or gets jam all over you, it does n't matter Because that's your kid, and your kid is great,'' he said <PERSON> Carl </PERSON>, 39, joined .38 Special two years ago when the 12-year-old band was looking for a new lead singer. A few months ago, `` Second Chance,'' with <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> as vocalist, hit No. 1 one on the adult listening chart and No. 2 on the rock charts. He said the most difficult part of being in the band is leaving his wife of 18 years, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON>, and children, <PERSON> Eva </PERSON>, 10, and <PERSON> Nick </PERSON>, 8, when the group goes on tour. But he said his family has been supportive. `` I've walked away from a lot of opportunities and made a lot of sacrifices because of my family. Because whatever happens, they're there,'' he said
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>TOBINSPORT, Ind. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 AIDS activist <PERSON> Belinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> is moving back to her western <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> home, and she may have fences to mend. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on AIDS and the president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> With </ORGANIZATION> AIDS, left <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, two years ago after she found she had the virus. Often in speeches around the country, <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> told the story of how hard it was for her to find AIDS information and support in rural <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> and of how the local municipal pool closed for a week after she swam in it. The media gave <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> a `` bad rap'' for focusing on the swimming pool story, she said. She believes the acts of kindness and compassion she experienced from people in the community were much more important. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> became infected with the AIDS virus two years ago from a blood transfusion after she had complications while giving birth to her second child. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, 31, her husband, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Carden </PERSON>, and their two children have been living in southern <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> for the last two years. She is looking forward to returning to <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>. `` I'll be glad to get back because there are a lot of people there who have helped me enormously,'' <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said last week.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Performer <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Belafonte </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> are among five artists to win the annual Kennedy Center Honors. The <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that it will present the awards at a dinner Dec. 2. The other winners: actress <PERSON> Claudette </PERSON> <PERSON> Colbert </PERSON>, dancer <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Danilova </PERSON> and composer <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Schuman </PERSON>. The next day the five will be received at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and will be guests of honor at nationally televised ceremonies. <PERSON> Belafonte </PERSON>, 62, <PERSON> Colbert </PERSON>, 85, and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, 75, are stars of stage, screen and television. The Russian-born <PERSON> Danilova </PERSON>, 82, has been a ballerina, choreographer, teacher and lecturer. <PERSON> Schuman </PERSON>, 79, has written 10 symphonies and numerous other works.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is n't alone in its appeal of a multimillion-dollar libel award to entertainer <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>: Some of the nation's top news organizations have joined the network's fight A jury in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> awarded <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION> $ 19.3 million in damages over allegations that <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> libeled <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> by linking him to mob figures in the purchase of a hotel. A judge later reduced the award to $ 5.3 million. In its appeal to the 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said the award to <PERSON> Newton </PERSON> was `` excessive and insupportable.'' Joining <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> in friends-of-the-court briefs filed last month were <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, Capital Cities @ <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Gannett </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jones </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Copley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION>, according to Monday's editions of the Las Vegas Review-Journal. <PERSON> Newton </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> Galane </PERSON>, said he consented to the other media supporting <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> so the appeals court could be hear `` all possible arguments.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Spence </PERSON>, the maverick trial attorney and author of `` And Justice for None,'' says the final frontier of injustice can be found behind the closed doors of corporate boardrooms. `` If I had to identify a single enemy in this country,'' <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> said in a recent interview, `` it would be ... the corporation. This king controls and owns our judicial system, controls and owns our congressmen and our presidents, pulls the strings of our media and washes the brains of our children.'' `` A justice system reflects the power structure and so the power structure is corporate <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` The purpose of the system is to maintain the status quo.'' <PERSON> Spence </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Jackson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyo. </LOCATION>, and also keeps a home in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Barbara </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, gained prominence when he tackled chemical giant <ORGANIZATION> Kerr-McGee </ORGANIZATION> in 1979 to win a $ 10.5 million jury award for the heirs of <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Silkwood </PERSON>. A federal appeals court reversed the award. <PERSON> Spence </PERSON> said the family eventually settled for `` little more than a single year's interest on the jury's original award. <PERSON> Silkwood </PERSON>, a workers' rights advocate, was killed in 1974 in a car crash on her way to meet a reporter from <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> to talk about alleged exposure of workers to plutonium.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-IowaGuns     08-08 0553</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iowa Guns,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iowa Uses 16-Inch Guns in Firing Exercise</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Military Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The USS Iowa's test firing of its 16-inch guns marks their first use since an explosion killed 47 sailors in April, but a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman says the turret involved in the blast was not used. The test took place Friday without incident while the ship was deployed for the Mideastern hostage crisis, <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said Monday. Chief of Naval Operations Adm. <PERSON> Carlyle </PERSON> <PERSON> Trost </PERSON> had ordered a moratorium on the use of the weapons in all ships shortly after the incident April 19 in which 47 sailors were killed, but that decision was modified in June. Because fleet commanders need to respond to the possibility of war, attack, or other contingencies, the so-called `` live-fire training'' was permitted. `` The test was successful and without incident,'' <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said guns from two of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s three turrets were used in the exercise. The No. 2 turret, the one involved in the April explosion, was not used, he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> has yet to release the results of its investigation into the explosion in the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s No. 2 gun turret, one of the worst naval disasters since the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war. The report has been submitted to the commander of surface forces for the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and will eventually land on <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>'s desk after being passed up the chain of command. The <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was one of several ships dispatched to the eastern <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> as part of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> show of military force ordered in response to the ongoing hostage crisis. The <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> to make a port call in <LOCATION> Marseilles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, but cut short its visit to head closer to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> last week. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said the commander for the 6th fleet in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>, Vice Adm. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, authorized the test firing. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, aboard the guided missile cruiser USS Belknap, canceled a four-day call at the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Sevastopol </LOCATION> last week in order to oversee the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> movements in the area. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> refused to discuss the number of guns used in the exercise or the amount of explosives used to pack them. There are three guns on each of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s gun turrets. Each gun can fire projectiles weighing up to 2,700 pounds at a maximum range of 23 miles. It also has 12 5-inch guns. The battleship is also equipped with a variety of other weapons, including Tomahawk and Harpoon cruise missiles. The only <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aircraft carrier in the <ORGANIZATION> 6th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>, the USS Coral Sea, also is in the eastern <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION>, said a <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official. The aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, ordered from <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> north </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> as part of the show-the-flag exercise, was scheduled to be on station today, the official added. Defense Secretary <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, in remarks to reporters on Monday, confirmed the positioning of the two carriers. Although the <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was required to cross thousands of miles of ocean to reach its station, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> called the deployment `` not that unusual for us. `` We always have at least one carrier group in the Med ... There are various and sundry other forces available in that part of the world, as is normally the case,'' he added.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TreasuryBills     08-08 0165</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Treasury Bills,150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Treasury Rates Rise</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Interest rates on short-term <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> securities are at their highest level in two weeks. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> on Monday sold $ 6.6 billion in three-month bills at an average discount rate of 7.94 percent, up from 7.65 percent last week. Another $ 6.6 billion was sold in six-month bills at an average discount rate of 7.70 percent, up from 7.35 percent last week. The rates were the highest since July 24 when three-month bills sold for 8.09 percent and six-month bills averaged 7.73 percent. The discount rates understate the actual return to investors _ 8.21 percent for three-month bills with a $ 10,000 bill selling for $ 9,799.30 and 8.12 percent for a six-month bill selling for $ 9,610.70. In a separate report, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> said Monday that the average yield for one-year <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> bills, the most popular index for making changes in adjustable rate mortgages, fell to 7.73 percent last week, down from 7.86 percent the previous week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0222EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-LandingContract     08-08 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Landing Contract,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>FAA Cancels Contract for New Landing Systems</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL PAGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says it still plans to bring a new generation of landing systems to the nation's airports by the end of the century despite falling three years behind schedule and canceling the main contract. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> on Monday ended a $ 79 million contract with the <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> to build 178 microwave landing systems and said it will ask for new contractors' proposals later this year. The company was chosen in 1984 to build systems that are to replace the instrument landing systems used for years at most airports. In a prepared statement, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said engineering and production problems at the <LOCATION> Commack </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, - based company have delayed the program by three years But the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said it remains committed to putting the new microwave landing systems at major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airports in 1998 and at all airports around 2000. <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> has delivered two of the systems sought in the contract. One has been installed at the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.H. </LOCATION>, airport. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said it will buy 26 systems from other sources, test that equipment and then decide whether to move ahead. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said it plans to award a new contract in 1991. <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION>, through its parent <ORGANIZATION> Emerson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, said it will sue over the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> decision. The microwave landing system is intended to give pilots greater flexibility in their landing approaches at airports and help airports increase their flight capacity. The system uses high-frequency microwaves to direct planes to landings, allowing them to make curved and steeper approaches outside the strict paths necessary under the current system. The system is virtually immune to weather hazards. In its letter to <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said the company has `` failed to perform and deliver in accordance with the schedule of the subject contract.'' But Hazeltine blamed the government for production delays, saying problems involving payments and timing of deliveries were the result of changes the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> made in the contract after it was awarded. The agency had planned on putting new microwave systems at the <LOCATION> Laconia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Manchester </LOCATION> airports in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, but <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said that because of the delays it may put early systems at high-profile, high-volume airports such as <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> plans to buy 750 of the new systems, if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approves.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0229EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hinckley     08-08 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hinckley,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>John Hinckley Says He Backs Gun Control</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> says his attack on President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> could have been prevented with proper gun control. <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON>, now a patient at a mental hospital, says he shot <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in a `` paradoxical rage induced by the constant use of Valium.'' In papers filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> also sought permission to be interviewed `` on rare occasions by other responsible members of the news media ... including <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>.'' `` I believe that my rehabilitation and my full recovery can only be aided by my ability to communicate to the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Canan </PERSON>, moved for a court order permitting <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> to be interviewed for the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> program Prime Time. <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> said that if a waiting period for buying weapons had been required, `` I believe I would not have gone forward with the effort to shoot the president.'' The fact that there is no waiting period `` raises serious questions about the gun laws,'' <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> said in the papers. <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> said that on two occasions he was arrested while in possession of weapons in the same city where President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> was appearing. `` The fact that ... no action was taken by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Secret </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> raises serious questions,'' said <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON>. Authorities at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Elizabeths </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> is in custody say they will never allow <PERSON> Hinckley </PERSON> to be interviewed, <PERSON> Canan </PERSON> said in the court papers filed Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GagOrder     08-08 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gag Order,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Muzzles Angry Supplier to Top-Secret Secret Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> intelligence officer is under a judge's order not to discuss his complaints of waste and fraud in a secret plan for maintaining the government after a nuclear attack. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court Judge <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> issued the gag order against <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> and his lawyer, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Mroz </PERSON>, after their names appeared in a magazine article about the `` continuity of government'' program, according to government sources. The program is aimed at enabling the government to regroup in the event of a nuclear attack. <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> owns a small firm that provided security services related to the program to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee investigator attempted to interview <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> as a result of the article in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> News & amp; World Report, but was told the judge's order extended to conversations with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, said the sources, who spoke Monday on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> issued the order a week ago today. <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> in March 1987 began alleging there were irregularities in the program, according to papers on file in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Court of Claims. <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> has since been made a target of the investigation, which he claims is an effort at retaliation. Details of <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON>'s allegations are contained in a federal court suit that was placed under seal early this year because of the highly classified nature of the project. The project includes mobile communications systems and command-post bunkers around the country, according to the magazine. After <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>'s gag order last week, a computerized docket sheet at the federal courthouse was altered, so that case now is entitled merely `` Sealed v. Sealed.'' The docket previously had said that <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> and his firm, <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evaluation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, are suing the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, three federal agencies, a private corporation and an <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> officer who oversaw his contract. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported that the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and a federal grand jury are looking into the continuity of government program. The investigations reportedly focus on allegations that contracts were awarded improperly or that payments were made for work not properly done, resulting in millions of dollars in costs that may not be justified. On Christmas Eve 1987, after <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON> continued to make allegations to superiors, the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> told him that his contract was not being renewed despite earlier assurances that it would be, according to papers he filed in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Court of Claims. He says he is still owed $ 500,000 in unreimbursed costs. <PERSON> Westerman </PERSON>, a retired major who spent 20 years as an Army counterintelligence officer, took his allegations to the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the inspector general's office at the emergency management agency. In January, two months after filing his case with the claims court, he was informed that his contract was the focus of a criminal investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for possible fraud. He recently received a `` target'' letter from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> informing him he is the focus of that probe. His claims court case is suspended pending the outcome of the criminal investigation. `` I think there are certain individuals in the government who are using this process to ruin my client financially,'' <PERSON> Mroz </PERSON> said Monday after a hearing on the claims court case. <PERSON> Mroz </PERSON> said the individuals, whom he did not identify, are engaging in `` retribution ... in connection with certain allegations by my client about waste and fraud as well as their attempted cover-up of their own wrongdoing in the operation of his contract.'' <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> spokesman Lt. Col. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapla </PERSON> said regarding the allegations of irregularities in the secret program, `` the appropriate authorities within the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the executive branch review -LRB- the program -RRB- regularly.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan 3rdLd-Writethru a0441-a0442-a0443 08-08 0625</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0441-a0442-a0443,0638</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Kaifu Chosen Party President, to Succeed Prime Minister Uno</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with two grafs to UPDATE with details. EDITS thereafter
to conform. COMBINES urgent series a0441, a0442, a0443. No pickup. ADDS
byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID THURBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s troubled governing party on Tuesday overwhelmingly elected <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> to become party president and succeed Prime Minister <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> in a vote likely to influence the nation's future political balance. The 58-year-old <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>, a two-time former education minister, is the party's second new leader in two months. Like Uno, he has little power base of his own and hopes to overcome scandals and a tax policy that loosened the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>' grip on power for the first time since 1955. Party officials said <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> received 279 votes. <PERSON> Yoshiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayashi </PERSON>, a former health and welfare minister, received 120 votes, while <PERSON> Shintaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Ishihara </PERSON>, a novelist and former transportation minister from the party's nationalist wing, received 48, with four invalid votes out of the total of 451. Party members watched silently as six officials counted the ballots and placed them in separate black lacquer trays, but broke into applause when the winner was announced. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> rose from his seat and bowed. In an attempt at greater democracy, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> decided for the first time in 17 years to select the president by a vote of their <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> members and 47 delegates from prefectural party organizations. The party president is expected to be confirmed as prime minister on Wednesday by the lower house of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, where the governing party has a large majority. In elections July 23, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> lost their majority in the upper house for the first time since the party was formed 34 years ago. Meanwhile Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> officially opened a new session of Parliament on Tuesday, and called for the lawmakers to promote world peace and the nation's prosperity, <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> stepped down as prime minister June 2 to take responsibility for the Recruit influence-buying scandal, which reached the top ranks of the governing party, bureaucracy and business. His successor, <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>, was plagued by reports that he kept paid mistresses, and announced his resignation July 24 to take responsibility for the loss in upper-house elections. All three candidates to replace <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> agreed in speeches to party members Monday that the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> should revise an unpopular 3 percent sales tax that outraged Japanese housewives and contributed to the loss of the upper house. General elections for the lower house are expected before spring. `` The situation the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> now faces is the worst since its founding'' in 1955, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> said in his speech, and declared: `` I believe the <ORGANIZATION> LDP </ORGANIZATION>'s resurrection is the only way for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to maintain freedom, democracy, peace and affluence.'' He said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> also should play a greater role in the world. `` It is not enough for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to simply maintain the security treaty with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and not to play a more responsible role now that <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> has grown so powerful and economically affluent,'' he said. `` We are responsible for fulfilling the world's expectations of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> might be able to help President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform efforts in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and contribute to the opening of Eastern European countries. <PERSON> Ishihara </PERSON>, 56, said in his speech: `` Any further decline in the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s strength threatens <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s free enterprise system, which has enabled the people, through their efforts, to create the most dynamic economy in the world.'' Stressing the image problem, <PERSON> Hayashi </PERSON>, 62, said: `` Public anger toward the party has not calmed down even after our election defeat. There seem to be persistent distrust and anger among the people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-KaifuProfile     08-08 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Kaifu Profile,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Japanese Leader Fulfills 29-Year-Old Pledge</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Japan</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRIL JONES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In 1960, a cocky 29-year-old politician predicted that in another 29 years he would be prime minister of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Toshiki </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> made that prophecy reality Tuesday as he was voted to head the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, assuring him of becoming <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 19th postwar premier. A few weeks ago it seemed most unlikely. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> did n't figure in the early race to succeed <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>, who is stepping down after less than two months in the wake of his party's thrashing in recent parliamentary elections. But with senior party leaders virtually eliminated from serving in the nation's highest office because of their own links to an influence-peddling scandal, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> was called on as an experienced politician with a clean image to lead the party out of its current crisis. The head of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> becomes prime minister because of the party's majority in the lower house of Parliament. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> is expected to be formally named on Wednesday. The party lost its majority in the upper house in an election last month, forcing Uno, already besieged by charges that he kept paid mistresses, to take responsibility for the setback and resign. `` We must overcome the obstacles, which I deeply regret,'' <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> told party members in a speech Monday. `` We must seriously consider the harsh reality of the election results.'' A veteran politician who served as education minister in the Cabinets of two prime ministers, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> is <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s second-youngest postwar leader. Only <PERSON> Kakuei </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanaka </PERSON>, premier in 1972-74, was younger, taking office at age 54. An eloquent speaker who studied debating in college, <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> learned his political ropes as a protege of the late Prime Minister <PERSON> Takeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Miki </PERSON>, and was once considered a future party heavyweight. His influence waned, however, as the small intra-party faction to which he belonged became overshadowed by larger groupings within the party. The Liberal Democrats turned to him amid calls for a younger leadership, and because of his support for political reform, which he inherited from <PERSON> Miki </PERSON>. He was also a compromise candidate between the main rival factions, whose leaders were tainted by the so-called Recruit Co. scandal. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> himself has acknowledged receiving $ 108,000 in donations from Recruit, but has claimed they were all legitimate political contributions. He moved quickly to repair damage to the Liberal Democrats since formally declaring his candidacy on Friday, appealing particularly to women, who felt estranged by allegations about <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>'s affairs and a new consumption tax forced into law by the party earlier this year. `` We must think of constructing a social balance between men and women that respects women's place in society and makes use of their abilities,'' he said in his Monday speech. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON>'s drawbacks are a lack of experience in foreign and financial affairs, not heading his own faction and never having served a top party post. Some political analysts therefore believe his administration will end in October when the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> elect a new party president for a two-year term. Others, however, believe <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> could last longer, depending on how he fares in the coming three months. `` If he succeeds in hammering out his own color and philosophy, there is a possibility his administration could last an unexpectedly long time,'' <ORGANIZATION> Gakushuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law professor <PERSON> Hidekazu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kawai </PERSON> told the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Nihon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Keizai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kaifu </PERSON> considers the number 29 particularly significant. Aside from his vow at age 29, he graduated from prestigious <ORGANIZATION> Waseda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in the 29th year of the reign of the late Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, and was first elected to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 29th general election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0257EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtonInBrief     08-08 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington In Brief,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shrimpers Must Now Limit Trawls To 105 Minutes</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Environmentalists are threatening to take the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> back to court over Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON>'s decision allowing shrimpers to abandon devices that protect endangered sea turtles in favor of regimented trawl times The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> and other conservation groups argue that the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> must uphold the law requiring shrimpers to equip their nets with turtle excluder devices, and that limited trawling is ineffective in protecting sea turtles such as the <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s ridley. Under a rule that took effect at 12:01 a.m. EDT today, shrimpers were to begin pulling their nets every 105 minutes to check for entangled sea turtles. <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> predicted compliance with the limiting trawling times would be far better than with the turtle excluder devices that shrimpers loathe. But conservationists said only TEDs can save the <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>'s ridley from extinction before the end of the century.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>Caution Urged in Sri Lankan Travel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> has warned Americans to avoid unnecessary travel in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> because of political tension and the widespread potential for violence. The travel advisory, which expands on an earlier warning, came Monday, a day after <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> published a story about a 30-year-old American tourist who disappeared traveling alone in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> on March 28. The earlier advisory listed some areas as safer than others in the country where ethnic Tamil rebels are waging civil war.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>___</HEAD>
<HEAD>AT&amp;T Accuses MCI of Illegal Discounting</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has criticized a complaint by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> that <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> offered large business customers illegally low prices to win their long-distance telephone business. AT & amp; T officials said Monday they hope the complaint will lead to a reversal of a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> policy that exempts <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T competitors from having to file tariffs with the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> detailing rates and other terms they offer customers. In its complaint to the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T alleged that <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> has used unlawful discriminatory discounts the past two years to win contracts with the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Westin </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> and Vista hotels; <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Uniguard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION>, which filed a similar complaint against <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T last year after <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> won a contract for Holiday Inns' long-distance and reservation system, called Monday's complaint a `` smokescreen.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0302EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RivkindResigns     08-08 0308</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rivkind Resigns,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>Miami INS Director Rivkind Resigns</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>, the volatile <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> immigration chief who ignored orders to deport Nicaraguans but sent home Haitian boat people, announced his resignation. <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>, district <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> director since 1983, said Monday he would resign Aug. 21 to teach criminal justice at a small college in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. Three years ago <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON> refused to send back a group of Nicaraguan refugees and announed he was flouting <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policies that treated the Nicaraguans the same as other Central Americans, who have no special immigration status. The more than 800,000 Cubans in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> _ the largest <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> community anywhere except the city of <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION> _ admired <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>'s anti-communism and enforcement of an open-door policy for Cuban refugees. Thousands of Nicaraguan refugees also live in the region. <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON> said the criticism that hurt him most were claims by Haitians in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> that his adherence to the federal order to send Haitian boat people back home _ while allowing Nicaraguans to stay _ was racist. He said it was `` simply not true'' that under his term Haitians were discriminated against. `` I think it's dangerous and irresponsible to make statements about discrimination in a community as volatile as this.'' `` It's true that my relationship with Mr. <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON> has been up and down some days. Sometimes we are friends, another time we are enemies,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Gerard </PERSON> <PERSON> Jean-Juste </PERSON>, a leader of the 100,000-member Haitian community here. `` I hope that the next district director to come will provide equal justice, equal treatment to the Haitian refugees as is given to the Cubans.'' <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON> said he tired of being held to official government positions. `` I am one who likes to speak out on social issues, and government sometimes says do n't speak out,'' said <PERSON> Rivkind </PERSON>, who will teach at <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Henry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Martinsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Ireland-U2     08-08 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Ireland-U2,0244</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guitarist Adam Clayton of U2 Rock Group Bailed on Drug Charge</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LON5 of Aug. 7</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> of the Irish rock group U2 has been charged with possession of marijuana. The 29-year-old bass guitarist, dressed all in black, appeared briefly in <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> on Monday but under Irish law was not required to enter a plea. <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> was arrested near his <LOCATION> Dublin </LOCATION> home Sunday night and charged with possessing marijuana and with having the drug with the intent to supply someone else, police told the court. Judge <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Windle </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> to post bail of $ 710 and to return to court on Sept. 1. If convicted of possession of marijuana, <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> faces a maximum fine of $ 1,420. Police said there is no fixed penalty for a conviction for possession of the drug with intent to supply, and the judge usually takes into account the circumstances of the arrest and the amount of drug involved. Det. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Garda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Siochana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>'s police force, told the court that when the first charge was read to him, <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> replied: `` There was nothing found in my possession.'' <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> made no comment when the second charge was put to him, <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION> said. The musician stood with his hands clasped behind his back facing the judge as the detective gave his evidence. The British-born musician became an Irish citizen earlier this year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0308EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-CentAm-KeyPoints     08-08 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CentAm-Key Points,0180</SECOND>
<HEAD>Key Points Central American Peace Accords</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Central America, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TELA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 These are the major points in the peace accords signed Monday by the presidents of <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>: _ The Nicaraguan Contra rebels are to begin demobilizing within 30 days. Resettlement of the Contras and their dependents is to be completed within another 90 days. _ <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> will no longer allow its territory to be used by rebel forces fighting another government. _ <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> will drop its case in the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> against <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> protesting the presence of Contra forces in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. _ The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> will be asked to provide mechanisms to verify the demobilization and end of hostilities. _ Leftist rebels in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> are asked to give up their fight and `` initiate a dialogue'' with the Salvadoran government. _ The five nations will cooperate in the fight against drug trafficking and use. _ The five presidents agreed to meet again in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> before the end of the year.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CorporateNegligence Bjt   08-08 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Corporate Negligence, Bjt,0693</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Demands CEO Appear In Person To Enter Guilty Plea</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATIA BLACKBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chemical company's chief executive will answer questions about a toxic spill this week in a court case that environmentalists and legal experts say could set a precedent for punishing corporate negligence. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> twice has refused to accept pleas from officials representing <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a Philadelphia-based chemical company charged with polluting a <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> waterway in a 1985 toxic bleach spill, and requested the appearance of chief executive and board Chairman <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON>. `` Who is this corporation?'' <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> asked in a hearing earlier this year. `` I think the public is entitled to know who is responsible.'' <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> was to appear in court Wednesday, a company spokesman said. <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> has declined to comment on his appearance. The case is the first in which the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government based its criminal investigation solely on corporate negligence, said prosecutor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>. `` To my knowledge, this is the first case of a federal judge's ordering a particular individual from a corporate body to appear to plead the guilt of the corporate entity,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Skover </PERSON>, professor of civil procedure and constitutional law at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Puget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sound </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Law </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Skover </PERSON> predicted <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>'s tactic will be used again, possibly in lawsuits against <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> over the 11 million gallons of oil spilled in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> has said that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> is the subject of a criminal investigation because of the March spill, the nation's largest. `` The device used by <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> may prove very effective in alerting all corporations that the top executive will not be allowed to pass the buck,'' <PERSON> Skover </PERSON> said. Environmentalists agreed that corporate executives will take notice of the <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> case. `` How can you be a corporate executive and not take responsibility for your corporation?'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortman </PERSON> of the Northwest office of Friends of the Earth. `` We no longer accept the notion that corporations are faceless letterheads that ca n't be threatened or held accountable.'' The negligence charges in the case were aimed at corporate officers and employees as well as the company, <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said. `` Corporations are run by people who are responsible for what happens,'' he said. The only <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> employee to admit wrongdoing was <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> plant manager <PERSON> Orval </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. High. He received two years' probation and a $ 5,000 fine for negligently discharging pollutants and failing to notify the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. The case involved a spill of at least 75,000 gallons of a chemical containing sodium dichromate into <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>'s Hylebos Waterway, which flows into Puget Sound. The spill occurred when a 180,000-gallon storage tank ruptured. Sodium dichromate is a toxic compound used as a bleach in the paper industry. It contains hexavalent chromium, a cancer-causing agent. Last year, a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> indicted the company and four company officers. On May 2, prosecutors and <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> lawyers reached a plea agreement, which called for the company to plead guilty to five misdemeanor counts and pay a $ 1.1 million fine. The agreement covered two counts of negligently failing to maintain adequate storage tanks at its <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> plant, two counts of discharging pollutants, and one count of failing to promptly report the spill to the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. Charges against the company officials, including three executives, were dropped. <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON> was not charged. In May, <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION>'s attorneys appeared at <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>'s federal courthouse to plead guilty to the reduced charges. But <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> refused to accept their pleas and asked that corporate officers appear instead. In June, <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> sent three corporate officers but <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON> changed his mind. He asked to see <PERSON> Tuttle </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> declined to comment on the company's reaction to <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>'s order except to say there was `` surprise.'' In the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Pennwalt </ORGANIZATION> employs 135 people in <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> and 170 at a <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, plant. The <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION> operation produces chemicals used in paper, adhesives and bleach. The company reported first-quarter earnings of $ 28.5 million this year, on sales of $ 279.9 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890808-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-08-89 0311EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Rocket     08-08 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Rocket,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Launch of Japanese Weather Satellite Rocket Fails</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
