<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Homosexual-Scouts     03-20 0344</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Homosexual-Scouts,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Denver Minister Threatens To Drop Boy Scouts Over Homosexual Stance</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE WHEELAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> minister said Monday that he would drop his church's sponsorship of a Boy Scout troop unless the organization reverses itself and allows a homosexual man to serve on the troop's parents committee. `` I believe the Boy Scout law is a correct one _ to serve God and country,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON>, rector of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Barnabas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` But I do n't think God or my country trashes people. If the Boy Scouts have departed from that, they should let the sponsoring agencies know they have departed from that old law.'' <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON> said the homosexual man, who has a son in Troop 13, was one of 16 people appointed to the parents committee, which supervises the activities of the 35 scouts in the troop. He said the Boy Scout organization revoked the man's registration after learning that he was an admitted homosexual. <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON> would not name the father. The Boy Scouts of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> has upheld the decision at the district and regional levels. The case now is before the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> of the Boy Scouts, <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Barclay </PERSON> <PERSON> Bollas </PERSON>, a spokesman at the organization's national headquarters in <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said Monday that the <ORGANIZATION> Boy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Scouts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> has a policy barring membership to homosexuals and has invoked that policy before. `` We do not believe homosexuals make appropriate leaders for a youth organization like the Boy Scouts,'' <PERSON> Bollas </PERSON> said. Both the troop committee and the parents of the scouts have voted to support <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON>'s campaign on behalf of the man. <PERSON> Ostertag </PERSON> said it is not easy finding volunteers who will take scouts on camping trips and oversee their work on merit badges, especially in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> neighborhood, where many residents are single. `` This is Holy Week, and I feel uncomfortable celebrating Good Friday and then having to turn around to this man and say, ` You're trash, and we do n't want you around,''' the minister said `` I do n't go for that.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Guns 1stld-writethru a0667 03-20 0772</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Guns, 1st ld-writethru, a0667,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: To update with Times report, 3 new grafs after 5th graf previous
``This is''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday defended his lifelong membership in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> while voicing support for a `` constitutionally sound'' further crackdown on semiautomatic weapons. `` We are in different times now and I am convinced that reasonable men and women can work together to find an answer to the problem,'' he told a group of women state legislators at the White House. Meanwhile, White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> called for a cooling down of emotions in the gun-control dispute, saying `` the president feels we do n't need to be threatening each other.'' He was referring to news reports that <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> officials had indirectly threatened drug czar <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> with political retaliation if he pursues a course toward more firearms restrictions _ allegations that the gun owner's lobby denied anew Monday. `` This is not a time to be threatening people, but rather a time to try to work together to solve a problem that clearly needs to be solved,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. While considering gun measures, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is also looking at moves to fight the drug problem in the nation's capital, including the possible use of federal troops, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is willing to consider bringing in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> under federal command, or using regular military forces, if the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> police force is unable to curb <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s mounting murder rate, the newspaper reported in its Tuesday editions. The administration has not detailed how the Guard might be used, the newspaper said. The administration last week announced it was banning the import of semiautomatic weapons. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had said the move reflected a `` pulse change'' on his part on the subject of gun control, which in the past he has steadfastly opposed. `` Clearly there's been some evolution of his -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s -RRB- thinking'' on gun control, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Monday. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has directed <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> to review the entire subject of semiautomatic weapons. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said that neither an expansion of the ban nor other new restrictions on guns would be proposed during the overall review that <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> is overseeing. The president told his audience: `` On the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, of which I'm a member _ a proud member, I might add _ I believe that we can find accommodation between the legitimate interests of the sportsman and the interest of the police chiefs in protecting their people who put their lives on the line every single day.'' `` The country needs to know that there is some answer to this. I do n't yet know what it is,'' he said. While much of the answer rests with the states, `` we have a responsibility'' at the federal level as well, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` We have got to give the police proper support when they lay their lives on the line for us. And so we'll find some answer that is constitutionally sound and that also protects the lives, as best one can from <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, of police officers.'' Sources who spoke on condition of anonymity told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last week that <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> had been receiving warnings from the rifle association through third parties hinting that <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>'s campaign fund-raising abilities might be used against him if he ever sought political office. <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> said through a spokesman, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, that `` there have been a lot of phone calls, a lot of pressure. Let's cool off.'' <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> LaPierre </PERSON>, legislative director for the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>, insisted Monday that `` we never made a threat in the first place. It's not the way we operate, it's not the way the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> functions. I do n't know how to be any clearer than that.'' He said that the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> shares the nation's `` heightened outrage about violent crime'' on the nation's streets. `` We want to be a part of the solution, we're going to be in there in a constructive way.'' But, he said in an interview, `` we do n't believe we should be pushed into a cosmetic solution that wo n't address the real issues and wo n't solve the real problems.'' `` There's nothing new about semiautomatic firearms. They've been around for a century,'' he said. He claimed the problem was failure to use existing laws to prosecute drug dealers who use guns illegally. `` It's not that we do n't know who these people are: they glow in the dark.'' Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, meanwhile, said he had not heard about alleged <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> threats against <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> but `` if they're saying that they should n't.'' `` <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s doing a good job. The president is very serious about what he has had to say,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador-Election 5thLdWritethru a0814 03-20 1098</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Election, 5th Ld Writethru, a0814,1132</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Arena Claims First-Round Victory; Violence Leaves At Least 32 Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 14 grafs to UPDATE with victory statements and no
report from Christian Democrats. Pick up 12th pvs bgng: Ana Guadalupe...
with changes to conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS GRANT MINE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The right-wing <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> claimed victory in Sunday's presidential election scarred by clashes between rebels and troops that left at least 29 dead. Three journalists also were killed. The alliance, known as Arena, said its candidate gained more than 50 percent of the vote. That would be enough to avoid a runoff election next month against the incumbent <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are sure and we proclaim oursevles the victors,'' <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Aubuisson </PERSON>, founder of <PERSON> Arena </PERSON>, told a news conference. Arena presidential candidate <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> said the party had results from 75 percent of the polling places and he was assured of victory. Election authorities said preliminary officials results were expected Monday. A boycott by leftist rebels and scattered gun battles between guerrillas and troops trimmed the voter turnout. Six soldiers and 23 guerrillas were killed in battles as the rebels tried to disrupt the voting, according to Col. <PERSON> Emilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Ponce </PERSON>, chief of the joint chiefs of staff. Two Salvadoran journalists and a Dutch television cameraman also were killed _ one during clash at a rebel-held town and the others at military checkpoints. <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON> had said he expected to do better in the countryside than in the capital, but <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s Channel 12 television station said <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> was running strongly enough to win a clear majority. The Christian Democrat headquarters was virtually deserted Sunday night and the party provided no results. `` We have the 50 percent that is needed to win and I can assure you there will be no second round,'' said <PERSON> D'Aubuisson </PERSON>. `` I am proud to have been able to carry such a good and capable man as <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> to the presidency.'' Critics claim <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> is still controlled by <PERSON> D'Aubuisson </PERSON>, a retired army major who has been accused of having links with rightist death squads. <PERSON> D'Aubuisson </PERSON> has repeatedly denied the allegations. Polls closed at 5 p.m. -LRB- 6 p.m. EST -RRB-. There was no official word on turnout, but a spot check by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> at several polling places in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> showed between 55 and 65 percent of those registered had cast ballots. <PERSON> Ana </PERSON> <PERSON> Guadalupe </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, a rebel spokeswoman in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said enough people had stayed away from the polls to prove that no election could be held without participation by the guerrillas' <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> She said no polling places or voters had been attacked, as the guerrillas had pledged, but rebel assaults on government installations prevented the army from taking voters to the polls. The guerrillas had imposed a transport ban and sabotaged telephone lines and electricity, which cut or restricted power to 80 percent of the country. Roman Catholic churches were crowded with Palm Sunday worshipers and by midday there were long lines of voters at polling stations in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. Turnout was light in many smaller towns. `` With these problems it's better to stay home,'' said <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, 23. He spoke in front of his home in the capital as guerrillas retreated from an assault on a military post three blocks away. Sporadic rifle fire echoed from the slope of the Guazapa volcano, a guerrilla stronghold north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, as troops fought insurgents in the 9-year-old war that has claimed an estimated 70,000 lives. There were seven presidential candidates and the three major ones were <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON> and <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ungo </PERSON> of the leftist Democratic Convergence. <PERSON> Christiani </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON> were the only contenders with a chance to win. Christian Democrat President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s five-year term ends June 1. <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>, barred by law from running for re-election, is <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s staunchest ally in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. He is dying of liver cancer. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> has vowed to follow free-market policies and reduce state intervention in the eonomy. His party promised to step up the war if the guerrillas of the <ORGANIZATION> Farabundo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marti </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> do not agree to lay down their arms. <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> voted Sunday morning in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and told a group of his supporters, `` I hope the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> realizes that -LRB- Salvadorans -RRB- want democracy, with this effort they're making to vote. We do n't want any more bombs.'' <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mena </PERSON> is a lawyer and heads the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>' conservative wing He struggled against opposition charges of corruption in the government and inability of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> to deal with the economy and the civil war. Leaders of the Democratic Convergence maintain formal links with the guerrillas. This is the first election since 1977 in which socialist candidates have competed. About 1.83 million people out of a population of 5 million were eligible to vote. Polls opened at 7 a.m. in 243 of the country's 262 municipalities and closed at 5 p.m. Nineteen towns in the north did not set up voting stations because election officials deemed those rebel-held zones too dangerous. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sebastian </LOCATION>, 30 miles east of the capital, turnout was light. `` The people are frightened,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON> of the American <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>. `` There is no question that the intimidation by the -LRB- guerrillas -RRB- is working.'' <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON> is one of 21 congressmen, state politicians and private citizens named by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to be official election observers. He said turnout Sunday was `` far less'' than during three previous elections he attended this decade. <PERSON> Cornel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lagrouw </PERSON>, a cameraman for Dutch national television, was killed as army troops moved to oust guerrillas occupying the eastern town of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <PERSON> Javier </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> photographer for <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lagrouw </PERSON> was part of a group of six journalists and two drivers who were in the town. The others dragged him away and fled in two cars, but they came under repeated helicopter fire despite press markings and white flags on the vehicles, <PERSON> Gentile </PERSON> said. The military said it had no immediate information on the report. Two Salvadoran journalists were killed and another seriously wounded when security forces fired on their vehicles. The armed forces said the vehicles failed to heed orders to stop at roadblocks. In the March 1988 elections for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Arena </PERSON> won 32 seats, the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> 23 and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conciliation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> six. But a group called the <ORGANIZATION> Authentic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> split from the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION>, taking 16 seats from <PERSON> Duarte </PERSON>'s faction. The next legislative elections are set for March 1991.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 2354EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-BRF--ChildPlummets     03-20 0152</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Child Plummets,0154</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Survives 15-Floor Drop</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KUALA LUMPUR, Malaysia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 2-year-old boy plunged 15 floors down a rubbish chute inside a Penang city apartment building but suffered only bruises when he landed on a pile of garbage, a newspaper reported today. The daily <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said that <PERSON> Firdaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Zainal </PERSON> <PERSON> Abidin </PERSON> was playing other children Monday when the youngster's sister told their father the boy was missing. The boy's father, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cpl </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Zainal </PERSON> <PERSON> Abidin </PERSON> <PERSON> Saad </PERSON>, said he looked everywhere for the boy before noticing the rubbish chute was open, the newspaper reported. <PERSON> Zainal </PERSON> rushed down to the ground floor and found his son face down and crying on top of the rubbish, the newspaper said. He rushed his son to the hospital, where doctors examined him and sent him home, saying he had no injury other than bruises on his forehead and elbow, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Same-SexMarriage     03-20 0780</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Same-Sex Marriage,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorneys Propose Change In Law To Allow Homosexuals To Wed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER McNULTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON> wants to substitute five words in the state civil code with two words that supporters say would undo years of anti-gay discrimination and opponents say would undermine society's structure. The change <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON> wrote in a proposed code revision, unanimously endorsed by the <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> directors, would define marriage as a `` personal relation arising out of a civil contract between two people.'' Under the law now, it's between `` a man and a woman.'' The change would have let <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brinkin </PERSON> take a three-day leave after the death of his lover of 11 years. His employer would n't let him off, though a co-worker got time off for the death of a stepmother he had never met. It would have made it easier for <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitchens </PERSON> and her partner to adopt. <PERSON> Hitchens </PERSON>, an attorney, had to become the child's guardian, leaving her partner with no legal parental authority until they successfully challenged the law; ultimately, they legally adopted two children. It also would force hospitals to allow a gay AIDS patient's lover into intensive care. Many only let in relatives. Gay couples live in a `` limbo-like state outside of the law,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Keane </PERSON>, president of the local association. `` It's a pariah-type class that's set up within the law. To me, it's an unfairness issue.'' Redefining marriage to include homosexuals would grant all the rights, privileges _ and burdens _ of marriage to gay couples. Among the areas affected if the proposal is made into law are tax exemptions, inheritance laws, pensions and health plans, as well as parenting privileges and adoption rights. `` We're not for it,'' said <PERSON> Deacon </PERSON> <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, spokesman for Catholic Archbishop <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>. `` To us, marriage is a sacrament with deeply religious overtones. Our church believes marriage can only be entered into by a male and a female.'' <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON> believes some inequities may warrant compensation, but calls for use of contracts `` that do n't establish a quasi-marriage.'' The resolution must survive two local reviews to be considered by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bar </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delegates </ORGANIZATION> in September, when about 500 representatives of the state's 117,000 lawyers will consider and propose new laws and and plan repeal efforts. If it passes, Bar lobbyists will seek a legislative sponsor. The specification of `` a man and a woman'' became law in 1977 after a spate of gay marriages, which were n't prohibited then. Under the amendment signed by Gov. <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, homosexuals have little say regarding partners' medical care and can not share insurance coverage or health benefits. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION>, the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city governed by a majority of gay city officials, unmarried city employees may add their partners to health benefit and pension plans. <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Santa </PERSON> <PERSON> Cruz </PERSON> offer similar benefits. In <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, where an estimated 10 percent of residents are gay, <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supervisors </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Britt </PERSON>, the panel's only gay member, has spent years trying to provide sweeping rights to `` alternative families.'' <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON>, who is not gay, is a member of the bar association. She said her proposal also would include child custody, community property and spousal support obligations. Supporters do n't anticipate throngs of gay couples flocking to the altar, but they insist that everyone should have the opportunity _ and equal rights. Auto insurance companies that offer family reductions exclude homosexuals and unmarried heterosexual couples, and income tax laws favor married couples in some ways, according to <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Strauss </PERSON> of the Lesbian Rights Project. `` So long as benefits are given or taken away based on relationship status, then we want access to them as well,'' said <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldstein </PERSON>, an attorney with National Gay Rights Advocates. Like many lesbians, <PERSON> Hitchens </PERSON> says she would marry if she could. After 12 years with her partner and two adopted children, she said economics _ not emotion _ would prompt her to tie the legal knot. <PERSON> Brinkin </PERSON>, who lost a court battle against his employer over bereavement leave for the death of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, is n't sure whether he would marry. `` My commitment comes from my heart and I do n't need a piece of paper to do that.'' Advocates of the change say the issue is purely a question of law, that the equal protection clause of the 14th Amendment of the Constitution prohibits discrimination against classes of people and should cover homosexuals. `` My guess is that the debate is going to be much more sociological than legal,'' said <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wied </PERSON>, president of the State Bar. `` Society would recoil at this idea. My guess is that lawyers will follow suit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GayRoommates     03-20 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gay Roommates,0620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Court To Decide If Surviving Gay Lover Should Be Evicted</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BELLAFIORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> were regarded by friends as a loving couple, their <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> apartment the home of `` any happily married couple.'' But <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> faces eviction because their landlord disagrees. When <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> died in <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON>'s arms in 186, <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>'s name was on the lease to the rent-controlled apartment the two men had shared for a decade. Leases pass from parent to child or spouse to spouse under the rent control laws in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s tight and pricy real estate market. <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> says that as a `` family member'' he should have succession rights even though his name was n't on the lease. The landlord, <ORGANIZATION> Stahl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, maintains <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> had no right to the desirable apartment because he was not a member of <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>'s `` traditional family unit ... those related by blood, marriage or adoption.'' According to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Lambda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, a gay rights group, `` The case is about individuals who live in families that vary from the <PERSON> Ozzie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harriet </PERSON> mold.'' State court Judge <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Baer </PERSON> ruled that the men were a family under the rent-control law because of `` the time, love and commitment given by <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> to <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Baer </PERSON> halted the eviction, but was overturned on appeal. The Court of Appeals, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s highest court, will hear arguments April 26. <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> is allowed to stay in the apartment while the case is in court. `` It's not just a question for gay people,'' <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON> said. `` It's an issue about the right of each individual to enter into a non-traditional, non-orthodox relationship and be protected by the law.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> must decide whether people in non-traditional living arrangements _ homosexuals, unmarried heterosexuals, even elderly couples _ have the same protection as married couples and blood relatives. The court ruled in 1984 that one member of a homosexual couple could n't adopt the other to keep from being evicted from an apartment that only allowed family members to live together. `` This is the most important case in the country dealing with non-traditional family arrangements,'' said <PERSON> Stoddard </PERSON>. The court's decision could affect insurance, hospital visiting rights, inheritance and other areas in which the definition of `` family'' is crucial <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> had hired <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> to manage his exclusive <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> beauty salon and made him sole beneficiary, leaving him $ 5 million. <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> and <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> exchanged bracelets in 1977 as a symbol of their commitment. <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON>, 33, now wears both. He cared for <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> during the final months of his life and was holding <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> in his arms when he died in September 1986. <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON>, 33, says he and <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> `` regarded one another ... as spouses.'' `` Their friends regarded them as a ` married couple' and their apartment as ` the home of any happily married couple,''' according to court papers. <ORGANIZATION> Stahl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> has argued that the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> never extended succession rights to `` members of a non-traditional family unit,'' and has accused <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON> of trying to turn the case into a `` referendum on homosexual rights.'' <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON>'s lawyers say <PERSON> Stahl </PERSON> is trying to create that impression `` to prejudice the atmosphere,'' and that the case is simply about family rights. `` What this case is about is people's relationships, whether they will be protected, based on the strength of the relationship,'' said <PERSON> Nan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, a lawyer for the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, which represents <PERSON> Braschi </PERSON>. `` It -LRB- speaks -RRB- in terms of family relationships. Family would be not just spouses. You're protected under this law if it's your uncle.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0120EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-JFK-Evacuation     03-20 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-JFK-Evacuation,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Suspected Bomb Forces JFK Building Evacuation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A wing of the International Arrivals Building at <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> F. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airport </ORGANIZATION> was evacuated Sunday night after an airline received a bomb threat and a suspicious bag was found, authorities said. The threat turned out to be false and police from the bomb squad determined that the bag did not contain a bomb, said <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Officer <PERSON> Phillip </PERSON> <PERSON> Montuori </PERSON>. Shortly after the bag was found sitting in the departure level of <ORGANIZATION> Aer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lingus </ORGANIZATION> airline with no apparent owner, a telephone bomb threat was received by Egyptair airline, said <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Officer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON>. The anonymous caller told Egyptair that a bomb was set to explode at 10:05 p.m. in the arrivals building, <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON> said. Some 300 to 400 people were evacuated from the east wing of the building at about 8:20 p.m., <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON> said. They were permitted to return at about 10 p.m., he said. <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON> said the scare `` delayed whatever flights were there for several hours, whatever flights would have been going out of the east wing. The Egyptair flight that was going to take off did n't until the whole thing was over. No information was available on the bag's contents and police could not immediately determine its owner, <PERSON> Ebert </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     03-20 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0492</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VANCOUVER, British Columbia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Those who doubted opera is for high-brows got a sharp reminder at a casting call for a production of <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` Aida.'' About 2,000 people hoping to play soldiers, slaves and other extra roles in the extravaganza planned for next month began lining up in the rain at 6 a.m. Saturday for auditions at B.C. Place Stadium. Ads seeking extras had said the minimum height requirement for women was 5-feet-2 and 5-feet-8 for men. But when the stadium doors opened four hours later, the women were told anyone under 5-foot-6 was out of luck. `` We started a mass rebellion,'' said student <PERSON> June </PERSON> <PERSON> Derlachter </PERSON>, who is 5-feet-4 -LCB-. After haggling, folks 5-foot-4 and above were told they could stay. `` A lot of short people cheated by wearing high heels,'' complained Ms. <PERSON> Derlachter </PERSON>, who made it inside but was not among the 503 people selected. Production manager <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Bilodeau </PERSON> said he could not explain how the mixup on heights occurred. The two-day production of the opera about <PERSON> Aida </PERSON>'s romance during a war between <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> is scheduled for April 27 and 29.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>HESSMER, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This town's one-man police force says officials have idled his squad car because he wo n't turn the town into a speed trap. `` Out of gas: mayor and city council refuse to buy gas'' reads a plywood sign on top of the car parked at <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Villemarette </PERSON>'s house. `` They're wishing that I'd quit. But I'm too old in this game to quit that easy,'' said <PERSON> Villemarette </PERSON>, police chief and only officer in this central <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> village of about 800. <PERSON> Villemarette </PERSON> claims Mayor <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeansonne </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aldermen </ORGANIZATION> want him out of office and have heated up a long-running feud over speeding tickets since he won re-election in October to a third term. He says he encouraged two part-time patrolmen to quit by giving them bad working hours after the board urged the officers to set traps. `` They'd park on the edge of town near the speed zone signs. A person from <LOCATION> Marksville </LOCATION> comes cruising in ... and they would stop that person, no questions asked. To me, that's a big ripoff. `` Or they would be hiding in the brush waiting for a nice little family to come down. I do n't go for all that malarkey,'' the police chief said. But <PERSON> Jeansonne </PERSON> said the board decided to allocate $ 50 a month for gasoline instead of reimbursing the chief an average of $ 275 a month because the squad car is driven much less. `` Most times, his car is parked at City Hall or the Baptist church,'' <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauthier </PERSON> complained. While the dispute simmers, <PERSON> Villemarette </PERSON> said, he will use his own car to answer police calls. And <PERSON> Gauthier </PERSON> said Avoyelles Parish Sheriff <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Belt </PERSON> has agreed to patrol the town.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AfterBotha     03-20 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-After Botha,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Botha's Heir Apparent Stirs Hope In Some Quarters, Doubt In Others</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The selection of a shrewd, affable pragmatist as President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>'s successor is contributing to a surge of hope for a peaceful breakthrough in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s political stalemate. So far, however, the optimistic musings are coming almost exclusively from whites. Black leaders make clear they will be relieved when <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> steps down. But they suspect his heir apparent, F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, will preside over changes more cosmetic than substantive. <PERSON> Mangosuthu </PERSON> <PERSON> Buthelezi </PERSON>, the Zulu political leader denounced by many black activists as too conservative, says he will oppose de Klerk until the government gives blacks full voting rights. There is no sign de Klerk contemplates such action. At the other end of the black political spectrum, the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla movement says changes under de Klerk will be in personal style, not National Party policy. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> `` are pieces of the same carcass,'' spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sebina </PERSON> said from the outlawed movement's exile headquarters in <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>. `` If the meat is bad, the meat is bad.'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, 73, resumed his presidential duties last week after an eight-week convalescence from a stroke. In the interim, he resigned as <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader and was replaced by <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, the minister of national education. In a dramatic chain of events, Nationalist newspapers and politicians began suggesting that <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> should retire, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> responded by declaring he would stay in office until next year, and the party's parliamentary caucus resolved that it wanted <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> to be president. However, the party has neither the constitutional power nor the appetite to force <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> from office. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> said Friday he will seek cordial coexistence with the president while urging his party to `` break new ground'' in pursuing political reform. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, who turned 53 Saturday, has never been viewed as liberal. But supporters and skeptics alike depict him as more open-minded and less imperious than <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, who has headed the government since 1978. After becoming party leader, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> called for a <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> `` free of domination and oppression.'' Other party officials say at least some remaining apartheid laws _ those segregating residential areas and public facilities _ may be modified. <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON>, long-serving legislator for the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Progressive </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, said of de Klerk: `` People are being too optimistic if they think he is going to throw fundamental policy overboard.'' `` But I think he's pragmatic and intelligent,'' she said. `` He realizes that change is absolutely inevitable, that the sooner we get on with it, the more chance there is that change and reform will be accomplished peacefully.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> does not have the same close ties to the military and police that <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> nurtured. But he is committed firmly to segregating neighborhoods and schools for whites who want them, and his proposal for `` genuine power sharing'' with blacks as yet has no substance. His ascendency coincides with other developments that have induced the broadest optimism about <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since black unrest broke out in 1984. British Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said last week `` encouraging changes'' were unfolding in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. These include major foreign policy initiatives, such as independence for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> and rapprochement with <LOCATION> Mozambique </LOCATION> after prolonged hostility. But anti-apartheid leaders view seemingly notable domestic developments with skepticism. For example, a government-appointed law commission attracted international publicity this month by calling for a bill of rights, abolition of apartheid laws and full voting rights for blacks. Human rights activists doubted the proposals would be implemented, and the government reacted with silence. Similarly, black clergymen were unimpressed when delegates from the white <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reformed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, to which most National Party officials belong, issued a statement describing apartheid as a sin. Last week the full policy-making body of the Afrikaner church balked at endorsing the delegates' stance. The government spurned recent suggestions by <ORGANIZATION> Dutch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reformed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Heyns </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Beeld </ORGANIZATION>, a major Afrikaans-language newspaper, that it drop its demand the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> renounce violence before negotiations are held. There is no indication jailed <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> will be freed soon. One of the most informed assessments of <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> came in a recent magazine article by his brother, <PERSON> Willem </PERSON>, a former newspaper editor who quit the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> out of disenchantment with apartheid. <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> described his brother as `` fair, friendly and humble,'' but committed to the ideology of separating racial groups. `` If F.W can give the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> a new credibility among all population groups, and in international politics, he will herald a breakthrough toward a new future. But if he continues along the old path, he will merely be a transitional figure who will let us keep treading water,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Barry-Security     03-20 0281</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Barry-Security,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor's Security Staff Babysit, Run Errands</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s security force often erforms duties such as babysitting, running personal errands and soliciting home telephone numbers from new female acquaintances, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reports. The Post, in its Monday editions, said two city-paid security officials babysat the mayor's son and a playmate while the mayor was in a hotel 20 minutes away during a trip to the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> last year. The paper quoted a model identified as <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shell </PERSON> as saying that one of the mayor's security officers approached her for her telephone number in 1987. About two dozen security officers make up the $ 1 million-a-year detail. The paper said police officials have voiced concern that the mayor often requires the officers to station themselves a few blocks away or at the police garage where the security detail is based. `` The security detail should not be leaving the mayor anywhere,'' the paper quoted one high-ranking police official as saying. Mayoral spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> said he had received no official notification of any practice of using security officers for babysitting or personal errands while <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> is left unprotected. White said it is important for the mayor to be adequately protected, adding, `` From time to time, the mayor has had threats against his life and his family. <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> has been dogged by recent allegations that he has used drugs and by charges of drug-selling lodged in the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> against a former associate, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> had visited several times at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel in December. The mayor has repeatedly denied using drugs or having any knowledge of any possible drug connection involving <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Scandal     03-20 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Scandal,0631</SECOND>
<HEAD>Britain's Tabloids Spin Another Sex-and-Politics Yarn</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Gadaff in 10th graf is cq.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LESLIE SHEPHERD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 By day, she was a lowly House of Commons researcher. By night, she dated a government minister and newspaper editors, and mingled with the upper crust. With the allegation that she's also a call girl, it all adds up to the kind of yarn on which <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s tabloid newspapers thrive. And if the headlines are to be believed, this one even has a <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> connection. According to the stories dominating front pages in recent days, the striking former <ORGANIZATION> Miss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> India </ORGANIZATION> worked as a part-time researcher for <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> lawmaker <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> from late December to late February. The job, apparently involving research for legislation <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> sponsored to end price-fixing in the book trade, entitled the 27-year-old aide to a security pass that gave her access to much of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION>. On Sunday, the News of the World alleged the woman _ identified variously as <PERSON> Pamella </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pamella </PERSON> <PERSON> Bardes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> _ also works as a call girl, charging at least $ 860 a night. The newspaper attributed its information to an `` investigator'' who spoke with her in a hotel bedroom. Other newspapers rushed into print with an array of pictures of dark-maned Miss <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> hobnobbing with the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> glitterati. They reprinted pictures of her as Sports Minister <PERSON> Colin </PERSON> <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>'s date at the Conservative Party Winter Ball. There were photos of her out and about with <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Neil </PERSON>, editor of The Sunday Times and at a party with <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trelford </PERSON>, editor of the rival Observer. No one has suggested there is anything wrong with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> seeing the high and mighty after hours. But on Friday, the tabloid <ORGANIZATION> Evening </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standard </ORGANIZATION> introduced a new element: <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>. Quoting a close, unidentified friend of Miss <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON>, the Standard said she `` is believed to have close social links with one of revolutionary <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> leader Colonel -LRB- <PERSON> Moammar </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON>'s closest aides.'' It said she made regular trips to <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> to meet <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadaff </PERSON> <PERSON> al </PERSON> <PERSON> Daim </PERSON>, whom the paper identified as a cousin of <PERSON> Gadhafi </PERSON> and a major in the <LOCATION> Libyan </LOCATION> security service. The paper quoted a security source as confirming that <PERSON> al </PERSON> <PERSON> Daim </PERSON>'s movements are monitored in the West and claimed Miss <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> made several visits to <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION> by private jet `` The news will have grave security implications for the British government,'' opined the Standard, and some lawmakers were quick to agree. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Leadbitter </PERSON> of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, an expert on espionage, said: `` The persistent reports linking <PERSON> Pamella </PERSON> <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> with people in prominent positions _ and more recently actually touching upon areas of possible security risk _ suggest, if true, the urgency of the government undertaking the fullest possible pressing and penetrating inquiry.'' The Today newspaper has already dubbed Miss <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> `` the new <PERSON> Keeler </PERSON>,'' referring to the former call girl whose simultaneous affairs with War Minister <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Profumo </PERSON> and a Soviet diplomat rocked a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> government 26 years ago. On Thursday, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s largest circulation newspaper, quoted an acquaintance, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, as saying Miss <PERSON> Bardes </PERSON> told him: `` My secrets could bring down the government, just like <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Keeler </PERSON> did.'' What these `` secrets'' might be, nobody knows. Miss <PERSON> Bordes </PERSON> has not publicly commented on her newfound notoriety and has not surfaced in public. But if she was correctly quoted, said <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell-Savors </PERSON>, `` then I'm sure many members of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> will wonder, to put it bluntly, what the hell is going on.'' Her security pass was yanked as soon as her name hit the headlines, and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commons </ORGANIZATION> security rules are to be tightened next month.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-France-Fashion     03-20 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-France-Fashion,0851</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Lacroix's Byzantine Luxury</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUZY PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Fashion Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Christian-in-Wonderland did it again. After the patchwork blaze of color in his winter ready-to-wear collection last week, <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> topped his own act Sunday with a second show, the more expensive and sublime `` luxe'' collection. Often capping the outfits with his favorite `` Mad Hatter'' hat, he showed rich clothes in the line he nicknamed `` jogging to Byzantium.'' <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> led off with a bronze taffeta belted trench coat with a grand fox collar, followed up by a tangerine long wraparound skirt topped with a beaver-collared raspberry jacket. Soft imitation leopard added more deluxe touches to jacket linings, big stoles and an occasional turban cap. Little short fitted suits with flared bell skirts came out in stained-glass shades of <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Killim </LOCATION> rug patterns. His favorite trapeze-shaped topper looked great with deep mink cuffs on hot orange-red bouclette wool over a mildly flared skirt. A fabulous, egg-shaped, carnation pink, iridescent taffeta coat over a salmon satin suit was breathtaking. For evening wear, rich women might choose the strapless dresses in `` Fortuny'' panne velvets with strapless bosoms draped in lame. The gold of <PERSON> Byzantium </PERSON> was shot through the collection, even for evening blazers with paisley patterns in the brocade. And Goldfinger himself could n't have faulted the shimmering lame trouser outfit with flared pants. Never one to shy away from color and opulence, <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> laid on both in plenty, especially for evening. But he did it with such a light touch that the audience was dazzled. The grand finale was a group of Oriental `` odalisque'' outfits with harem pants in turquoise, red and gold iridescent panne velvets. Meanwhile, this versatile designer is already well into his next project: designing 350 costumes for a spectacular production of `` Carmen'' to take place in early July in the ancient arena at <LOCATION> Nimes </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Lacroix </LOCATION>'s native <LOCATION> Arles </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Provence </LOCATION>. This time, he's putting all his inventiveness into costumes for the American stars of the opera, <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumbry </PERSON> and <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON>, singing `` Carmen'' and `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Jose </PERSON>.'' `` I grew up with <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON>, a very sexy lady and the first woman in my life,'' <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> said in an interview. `` Her outfits will be in gold and white, coral shades and earth colors, depending on the act.'' One sure thing: with <PERSON> Lacroix </PERSON> dressing her, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumbry </PERSON> wo n't look like the down-and-out cigarette girl she will play. Japanese designer <PERSON> Hanae </PERSON> <PERSON> Mori </PERSON> showed a gently demure collection under the rotunda of the old commodities market. The most `` French'' of Oriental designers and the only one to show haute couture as well went in strongly for feminine shapes and soft fabrics. Her navy pinstriped coat-dresses, suits with skirts and pants could n't have been more classic. Diagonally-striped black and turquoise knit outfits were lively but never out of line, lengths just around knee level. Like designers all over town, <LOCATION> Miss </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mori </LOCATION> is seeing spots for next winter, and imitation leopard surged up here in flyaway trapeze shortie coats over narrow black skirts and animal-spotted stockings. For a touch of hot jazz, she showed puffy Tibetan lamb coats dyed in amethyst, royal blue and shocking pink. Iridescent taffeta dresses with cloche-shaped skirts over mounds of crinolines harked back to tea-dances for debutantes in the 1950s. More interesting were the evening outfits in <PERSON> Hanae </PERSON> <PERSON> Mori </PERSON>'s forte, flower-printed silks. This time they were beautiful and bold, in turquoise, peacock, flame with gold, borrowed from the best of Japanese kimono fabrics. On Easter Sunday, Miss Mori will celebrate the opening of her new shop in <LOCATION> Monte </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carlo </LOCATION>, by presenting the collection at a charity gala for `` Les Oeuvres de Soeur Marie,'' which benefits underprivileged and elderly people. Princess <PERSON> Caroline </PERSON> will host the event for about 700 guests. <PERSON> Maryll </PERSON> <PERSON> Lanvin </PERSON>'s collection was eclectic, bright and attractive, aimed at women who frequent the best shops, clubs and restaurants. As usual, the clothes were young and well-cut, mainstream rather than trend-setting. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> and big bands of violet piping were combined happily in a daytime group that had short flannel skirts, pants, shetland blazers and boleros. Worth noting were her big, bold diagonal plaids, in shades of yellow, red, emerald, purple. Fuzzy plaid mohair coats and flyaway short trapeze coats looked outstanding over suits with long shetland jackets and lean dark skirts. Another new plaid was multicolored windowpane style on a dark boucle fabric. It was striking in suits with both pants and short or longer skirts - the easy alternatives here. The shimmering dresses with hip-bloused tops and leg o'mutton sleeves or shifts were looked pleasingly different in their outsized paisley patterns. Sleekly fitted moire dresses in gem colors with short skirts flaring at the hem are made to order for little dinners or big cocktail parties. And <PERSON> Lanvin </PERSON>'s late-day wear was best in fitted quilted silk jackets with splatter motifs on very bright colors over dark silk jersey skirts or flowing pajamas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-OxfordDictionary Bjt   03-20 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Oxford Dictionary, Bjt,0882</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BARR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OXFORD, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 5,000 `` new'' words in the second edition of the Oxford English Dictionary say more about the glacial pace of lexicography than about the age of the words. There are freshly minted terms such as AIDS-related, antiquark, fax, <ORGANIZATION> Filofax </ORGANIZATION> and ghetto-blaster; words or word senses redolent of the 1960s such as acid, downer, grok and chopper, and jazz-age coinages such as Big Apple. There's even one new word from Anglo-Saxon: `` ash,'' the symbol that combines the letters A and E. The second edition, to be published March 29, reflects more than a century of scholarly labor. It pulls together the 400,000 entries in the first edition, completed between 1879 and 1928; the first supplement of 1933; the four-volume second supplement of 1972-1986; and the 5,000 new entries. That chronology explains why the OED took so long to catch up with `` Big Apple,'' <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s nickname. The first use of the term recorded by the dictionary is in 1927, though `` we've since heard there was record of it in 1906,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, the co-editor responsible for new words in the second edition. `` Now, in the first edition of OED the letter B came out in 1885, 1886, so -LRB- Big Apple -RRB- was n't available for inclusion then. `` I think it was a pity it was n't included in the supplement. Perhaps it was n't really widely well known. I do n't know.'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> also does n't know why his entry for `` Pythonesque,'' inspired by the satirical lunacies of comedy troupe called <PERSON> Monty </PERSON> <PERSON> Python </PERSON>'s Flying Circus, was ultimately rejected by <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Burchfield </PERSON>, editor of the second supplement. `` So I thought, I've had enough of that, so I put it back in again for the second edition,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` Nobody objected so it's gone in.'' Also inducted: acid rain, acupressure, barf, bleeper, creation science, detox, <ORGANIZATION> Diner </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, dingbat, duty-free, endangered, est, fast track, foxy, Great Leap Forward, greenmail, lap-top, nose job, passive smoking, plastic money and Visa. From now on, the 20-volume dictionary will be subject to rapid updating because this edition was prepared on a computer. <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> hopes to offer it on computer discs by 1991. The computer version will solve the age-old problem of looking up a word you ca n't remember. The computer can look for definitions, and much more. The basic work of lexicography, however, is still done on index cards, now numbering in excess of 3 million, each containing a quotation found by a paid or volunteer reader to illustrate the use of a word. The method is the same used by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A.H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, the first editor of the OED, who took on what was supposed to be a 10-year task in 1879 and had completed the letter T at his death in 1915. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON>, who appears in photos looking like an Old Testament figure in mortarboard and long white beard, instructed his researchers to `` make a quotation for every word that strikes you as rare, obsolete, old-fashioned, new, peculiar, or used in a peculiar way.'' They were also asked to produce as many quotations as possible for ordinary words. The OED surveys English from the middle of the 12th century, and the research net covered the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australasia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and the English-speaking parts of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. `` We regard the OED as an international dictionary now,'' said co-editor <PERSON> Edmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>. That's reflected in its production. The dictionary was edited in <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, the computer program was developed by the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Waterloo </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ontario </LOCATION>, the text was keyboarded in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, and the 10,000 sets, each weighing 137.7 pounds, were printed in <LOCATION> Taunton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. It's hard to explain exactly when a word becomes so widely used that it qualifies for the OED, <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said, but in practice words are almost always added by consensus, based on citations from printed sources. `` It is not our job to lay down what standard English is,'' said <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, but to produce a photograph of English as it is used. `` The dictionary records the language, warts and all,'' <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. `` I would say we do n't prescribe ourselves, but we try to make it obvious in the entries if you are dealing with a particular use that a group of people dislike.'' If a word is misused enough, it may rate an entry. Thus, contractural, a common misspelling of contractual, earned a citation in the OED, <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> said. Some day, it may be the standard spelling. ` Over history, over and over again, you see what was originally a non-standard variation becoming standard, and the standard one becoming old-fashioned and falling out of use,'' <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said. `` These days, ` disinterested' is condemned when being used in the sense of not interested, but actually it's older in that sense. ... `` We can only report that people, grammarians or whatever, said that a usage was wrong,'' <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> said. `` But very often you will find in the quotations that <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> or <PERSON> Dryden </PERSON> or whoever actually did use this supposedly wrong usage, and that rather confounds the extreme prescriptivist point of view.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 1253EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Iran-RocketFuel     03-20 0394</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Rocket Fuel,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Agencies Apparently In Conflict Over Rocket Fuel Bound For Iran</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Customs officials are trying to block a shipment of a rocket fuel component allegedly headed for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, but a lack of cooperation between federal agencies could help free the chemical soon, it was reported. A shipment large enough to fuel 300 military missiles was seized in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in February 1988 when <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> agents said it was being loaded onto an Iranian freighter, according to Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. But the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> issued a special export license to the chemical's owner, blocking Customs' court fight to forbid the shipment, the newspaper said. A federal judge in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> issued a temporary injunction requiring the government to release the 1,144 drums of ammonium perchlorate last week. Another hearing is scheduled for today. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Sim </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> ruled the rocket fuel ingredient was not among munitions restricted for shipment to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and that Customs failed to prove the shipment was bound for <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The 286,000 pounds of the rocket fuel component shipped from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> in January 1988 by <ORGANIZATION> Grindius </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, was seized the following month as it was being loaded onto an Iranian freighter in the <LOCATION> Dutch </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Rotterdam </LOCATION>. The shipment was being sent during the Iran-Iraq war, when those countries were using surface-to-surface missiles. <PERSON> Grindius </PERSON> contends it never intended to sell the chemical to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>. The shipping bill of lading shows it was bound for a buyer in <LOCATION> Basel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION>. Following the seizure, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> issued a special export license covering the shipment. The <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> has urged the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to revoke the license. The department has declined to do so and would n't comment on the case pending its court outcome. Customs officials also said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is not sure whether it will pursue the agency's case because of <PERSON> Lake </PERSON>'s initial ruling. Lake blamed a lack of cooperation and communication between the various governmental agencies for the apparent conflict. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> exports between 1 million and 2 million pounds of ammonium perchlorate every year, mostly to friendly nations. The compound has been in short supply since May when an explosion in <LOCATION> Henderson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, destroyed a plant operated by <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Production </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the primary manufacturer of ammonium perchlorate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-OldandPoor     03-20 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Old and Poor,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Documentary Shows Troubles of Elderly Poor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY ESTILL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` That's my problem, I'm a survivor,'' said the old woman. As she said it, she raised her blue eyes so they made contact with the social worker sitting across the table and, coincidentally, with the camera. There was a smile on her face as she talked about how strong she was, how strong she had been all her life, how she had always taken care of herself _ and of her husband before he died. But now, she was alone and sick and poor and beyond finding much to look forward to on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. The more she talked the sadder she became until she concluded that `` 68 is long enough to live.'' And then she wept. It is but one of several such scenes from a television documentary _ `` On the Other Side of Easy Street'' _ airing this week on Public Broadcasting System stations across the nation. Without exception, the old people put on faces of strength, even humor for the camera. But they are not actors and, also without exception, their eyes reflect despair and, in some cases, a bewildered sense that they thought it was n't supposed to turn out this way. Indeed, that is the central point to the film: that despite the Social Security program that has helped keep an increasing proportion of elderly Americans from the poverty that afflicted their own elders, those who remain poor _ well over 3 million _ do so with little hope. `` The film shatters the stereotype that elderly persons are well off and none are poor,'' said <PERSON> Horace </PERSON> <PERSON> Deets </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION>. `` ... So many people struggle every day to retain some dignity in the face of extreme poverty.'' <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Villers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which financed the film along with <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION>, said after a preview screening that the problems portrayed in the film `` are not insoluble.'' `` Frankly, it's a question of political will,'' said <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON>, who made the point that _ unlike younger and healthier people _ the elderly have little prospect of working their way out of poverty. While not a pleasant viewing experience, the film drives home the point that even the best laid plans do n't always turn out. And it shows that cutting through government red tape to get available benefits is not the easiest thing to do, especially for a new widow reeling from the death of her husband from a long illness that wiped out what they thought would be a financial cushion. <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> issued a study in conjunction with release of the film that showed fewer than half the elderly people eligible for the Supplemental Security Income program, which is supposed to provide a safety net for the poorest of the poor, actually get their benefits. The reasons vary widely from state to state and individual to individual but, in most cases, result from failure of the bureaucracy make the program easily available for those too unsophisticated or too proud to seek it out. For those who do, the maximum benefit is $ 368 per month for an individual and $ 553 per month for a couple.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower'sShadow Bjt   03-20 0916</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower's Shadow, Bjt,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nominee Faced Grilling on Warm Milk, Cigarettes and Derrieres</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the aftermath of the brutal <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> battle over former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>'s attempt to run the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, the tenor of a confirmation hearing seems to be getting, as one senator says, a little bizarre. As evidence, here are a few questions put by Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, to <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> during his confirmation hearing last week to be deputy secretary of state: <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>: Well, let's get to the important questions, Mr. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>. ... First of all, have you ever drunk anything stronger than warm milk? <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>: Yes, sir. -LRB- Laughter -RRB- <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>: Strike one. I notice you smoke, too. Strike two. ... Have you ever in public or private pinched a woman's behind? <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>: Can I divide that into two questions? -LRB- Laughter -RRB- ... No, sir. The nominee, a man to whom laughter came as easily as diplomatic analysis during the drawn-out hearings, apparently took no offense at <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>'s questions and went on to discuss with him the tragedy of hunger that is gripping the African nation, <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. The 30-year veteran of government service, who'd accumulated a massive store of goodwill among senators, was swiftly confirmed a day later by the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. But all kidding aside, <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>'s two days of confirmation hearings served to point out that much confusion remains about what is required of a nominee for high public office, whether in personal standards of conduct, or in attempting to deal with questions of real or apparent conflict of interest. It was clear that the shadow of Tower's ruined quest for confirmation, which foundered on allegations of alcohol abuse, `` womanizing'' and the nominee's $ 1 million in fees as a consultant for defense contractors, haunted <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>'s nomination, and may well haunt others in the future. Some of the most tense questioning during the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Foreign Relations Committee hearings came from Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, R.-N. He prodded <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> about the more than $ 900,000 in income, bonuses and severance the nominee received during his last of four years with the international consulting firm headed by former Secretary of State <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>. `` You know the big deal that was made about <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> told <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>. `` He was a piker compared to your income.'' <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, an arch-conservative who had been a vocal critic of <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s policy of pursuing detente, said he was worried about possible influence by the firm's foreign clients. `` There are a lot of people who wonder whether the advice you might give to the president or the secretary of state might be colored by the ongoing interest of firms, foreign firms ... who have been paying you substantial fees,'' <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> told <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said he had provided analyses of political, economic and societal developments for his clients, many of them multinational corporations, but that he never lobbied the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government on their behalf or engaged in any political activity for them. To return to government and avoid `` even the appearance of a conflict of interest,'' <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said he cut all ties with <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> <PERSON> Associates </PERSON>, sold all his investment stocks, and volunteered to disqualify himself for a year from any dealings with the 15 clients he'd worked for while at <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON>'s firm and been paid more than $ 5,000. This, his attorney <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> argued, went `` far beyond'' what has customarily been required from government appointees, such as cutting all ties with their former business associates and then being recused on a case-by-case basis on the advice of government ethics attorneys. But <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON>'s actions did not satisfy <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, who said he wanted the names of all of the <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> clients made public, whether <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> had worked for them or not. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON> argued that since <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> had been paid out of a company pot of funds, and not just by the clients he served, it was necessary for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel to have such information. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> said that was difficult for him, since the list was considered confidential by the company. <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>' request proved too much for Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., who argued that `` it's bizarre'' to require a nominee to disqualify himself from all dealings with any client that paid part of his income, even though he'd had no business dealings with them He said such a requirement would have disqualified former Secretary of State <PERSON> Cyrus </PERSON> <PERSON> Vance </PERSON>, former deputy secretary of state <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitehead </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> OMB </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON>, Secretary of State <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Shultz </PERSON> and Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>, many of whom had extensive business contacts with huge investment or law firms. `` I think we're getting a little daffy. ... We'll be assured that the only person who'll we'll ever have as a secretary of state will be someone who has a career that is distinguished by doing nothing,'' <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> argued. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> sought to defuse the problem by offering to disqualify himself from any possible future dealings with any client of the <PERSON> Kissinger </PERSON> firm from the past two years, even those he did n't work with As well, an `` informal'' arrangement was worked out, <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> said, that did not require the nominee to meet a higher standard than what is required under the law. <PERSON> Eagleburger </PERSON> agreed to disclose the names of the clients to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> legal adviser, who is obligated to keep them private under an attorney-client relationship, and provide the list to the committee chairman, Sen. <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, who agreed to treat it as a classified document.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressionalHistory     03-20 0798</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congressional History,800</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Film, Book Focus Attention on History of Congress</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> goes into its third century, the history of the first two is coming in for some increased attention. It has been a neglected subject, with much more scrutiny focused on the White House at the other end of the central stretch of <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. Now, however, there is a 724-page book on the history of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, made up of speeches by former Majority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. Va.. And tonight, most public television stations are carrying a 90-minute special called `` The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' using paintings, photographs, newsreels, sound recordings and narration to depict the 200 years since the first <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> met in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on March 4 Historian <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leuchtenburg </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION>, speaking at a recent gathering at the Capitol to launch <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>'s book, lamented that members of his profession have paid relatively scant attention to congressional history. Others whose business it is to get a balanced view of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> agree with him. `` Few good books have been written about <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> despite the richness of the subject matter,'' <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, who covers the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, wrote recently. In tonight's television program, writer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> McCullough </PERSON>, the narrator and co-author, stands before a backdrop of the Capitol and says, `` We are so accustomed to seeing our history measured by the presidency that we forget the extent to which the real story of our country takes place right there.'' And it is in fact the building that is in many ways the star of the film, whose producer, <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, won Academy Award nominations and other honors with previous documentaries about the <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> and Statue of Liberty. Roaming around the Capitol, the camera fixes lovingly on the glowing rotunda, presents speeded-up images of tourists passing the building's monumental statues, focuses on the hands of <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> in a 19th-century portrait. It picks out the bust of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>, tucked away in an alcove off the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor along with those of others who presided over the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> as vice president. There is also the voice of <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON>, interrupted by applause as he tells a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, `` Old soldiers never die; they just fade away.'' There is even a shot of <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, awed by his first sight of the Capitol dome as he arrives in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to take up his <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> duties in the movie classic, `` Mr. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> Goes to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' The film deals with the silliness and the back-room deals on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> as well as such high drama as the civil rights debates of the late 1950s and early 1960s. On the whole it is, as <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> told a preview audience at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, `` a very uncynical, though not entirely uncritical, view of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' If all of this sounds to you like a Valentine to an institution that is so often a whipping boy, surely we can count on the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> reporters, those hard-bitten men and women who cover the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, to provide a more realistic and perhaps cynical view. Well, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> and his colleagues interviewed some of them, so listen: <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> McDowell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Richmond </LOCATION> Times-Dispatch and <ORGANIZATION> Media </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, speaking of the Capitol dome. `` It's a hat. It's a very majestic nice hat, but a little bit ludicrous, on something that we all care very much about. ... The people are being represented under that thing; and I can live with that corny thought.'' <PERSON> Cokie </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>: `` It would be a true disaster if the modern demands of security keep <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children from the ability to just sort of roam the Capitol Building.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Broder </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Post: `` It's also a kind of a wonderful place, if you just let yourself have the freedom to do it, to stand still for a moment and look at the people who are coming there to see their <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> at work. It's marvelous to see their expressions as the dignity and the beauty of that building reach them for the first time.'' Ms. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> again, on how the lawmakers go about their work: `` I think quite frankly, by the time the whole messy business is over with, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, that they've done a pretty good job of it.'' So much for cynicism. The film was underwritten by the information industry giant <ORGANIZATION> Ameritech </ORGANIZATION> and co-produced by <ORGANIZATION> WETA </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and Florentine Films. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>'s book, `` The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, 1789-1989,'' is available from the <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Printing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and its depositories around the country for $ 55.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, covered <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for eight years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SuperfundConflicts Bjt   03-20 0571</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Superfund Conflicts, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>EPA Can't Detect Superfund Conflicts</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Citing a report that found the Superfund program ripe for a contracting scandal, a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel chairman says the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> must avoid the `` morass of abuses'' that have plagued <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> purchasing. The <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> concluded in a new report that the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is letting the growing number of contractors in the Superfund program police themselves on potential conflicts of interest. Procedures are so lax that the agency might not discover a company it hired to investigate a hazardous waste dump also was working for the polluter of the site, the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> said in a report obtained over the weekend by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Mich </LOCATION>., who requested the study, wrote <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Reilly </PERSON> on Friday, `` The Superfund contract program must avoid at all costs the morass of abuses and conflict of interest problems that plague the defense procurement system `` While it is important ... for contractors to have effective internal procedures in place, it is also important that <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> personnel have the independent capability to police the Superfund contract system.'' <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> is chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and the panel's investigations subcommittee, which has been investigating the Superfund program. The report concluded, `` This system is currently dependent on contractors' identifying and informing appropriate <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials about conflicts.'' It warned that a company working for both sides could feed the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> biased data, thereby weakening legal efforts to recover cleanup costs from a polluter. The report said the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> `` relies heavily on contractors to avoid conflicts, but does not review contractors' performance to ensure compliance with <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s conflict of interest requirements.'' The investigators said few conflicts have been found so far, but cautioned, `` This risk is a growing possibility in light of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s continuing efforts to expand the number of contractors used to perform remedial and technical enforcement activities. In the 1988 fiscal year, more than $ 600 million in contracts were approved by the agency for Superfund projects, compared to $ 97.3 million in fiscal 1982. Superfund, an $ 8.5 billion program to clean up hazardous waste sites, relies increasingly on private companies for the preliminary investigations of polluted sites, because the government has neither the manpower nor the expertise to do the work. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Connor </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s procurement and contracts management division, said, `` We're not in a position to police every situation with every firm out there. The amount of effort required to do that would just be overwhelming.'' He said a company caught working for both the agency and polluters at the same site could face a ban on <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> work or termination of the contract. `` We could take the position of being purists,'' he said, by prohibiting even `` the appearance'' of a conflict. But he asked, `` How strict can we get in appearance situations and still have companies that will work for us? There is a limited industry. We do n't want to set up private sector contractors vs. public sector contractors.'' The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> investigators looked at seven contracts valued at $ 745 million and involving work at sites all across the country. Five of the contracts were for studies that led to recommendations on how to clean up the sites. Two contracts were for investigating the parties responsible for pollution, so legal cases could be developed for recovery of cleanup costs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     03-20 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0842</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON>, who is returning to <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> this week for the first time in 22 years, says he initially turned down the lead role in `` Our Town,'' but changed his mind because `` it would be fun to be back on stage.'' The 80-year-old Academy Award-winning actor on Tuesday takes over the role of Stage Manager in the play based on <PERSON> Thornton </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilder </PERSON>'s drama of a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> town `` We do n't have many American classics like this,'' <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON> told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON> said he at first turned down the role but changed his mind. `` I thought it would be fun to be back on stage,'' said <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON>, who is replacing <PERSON> Spalding </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON> said he does n't expect to feel any jitters about returning to <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION>, where he first appeared nearly 60 years ago in `` <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> for Short.'' `` After more than two or three minutes, all that is gone,'' said <PERSON> Ameche </PERSON>, whose recent films include `` Trading Places,'' and `` Cocoon,'' for which he received an Oscar.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This week's broadcast of `` Peter Pan,'' which has n't been televised in more than 15 years, should bring back painful memories to <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, who broke her elbow teaching co-stars how to fly in the production. `` I started really fast and suddenly I'm out of sight, and I do n't feel anything pulling me back,'' <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, who portrayed <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> in the 1960 movie, said in this week's People magazine. `` I'm heading for the wall, and like a shot, I hit it. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, now 75, broke her elbow in two places. She said the crewman who was supposed to pull her back was new and `` so excited he forgot.'' The story of the little boy who never wanted to grow up will be broadcast on <ORGANIZATION> NBC-TV </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. It was last televised in 1973. After that, the rights to the movie were held up for years by the 1979 Broadway revival with <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LEXINGTON, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You would n't know <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> these days, and that's exactly what she was hoping for when she bought the false buck teeth and sunglasses she now wears in public. `` It's just been real hard,'' the model said Saturday in a speech at the 15th annual Institute on the <ORGANIZATION> Ethics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do live in a state of having to watch my every move. ... Imagine the kind of person you most dislike and think of people thinking of you as that kind of person.'' Ms. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON>'s liaison with former Sen. <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> destroyed the Colordao Democrat's bid for the 1988 presidential nomination. <PERSON> Hart </PERSON> withdrew from the race in May 1987. `` I basically lost everything I had worked for all of my life,'' she said _ her reputation and credibility as well as her livelihood. Ms. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> said she frequently is recognized in public and has tried to hide her appearance by pulling her hair back. In addition, she added. `` I have a disguise. I have buck teeth that I put on. They cost me 80 bucks. You guys want to see?'' When the audience said yes, Ms. <PERSON> Rice </PERSON> donned a pair of glasses, bent over and inserted the false teeth. She stood upright, looking like quite a different person. `` I hope,'' she said, `` time will eventually take care of all of this.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> says actor <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON> ought to be in pictures _ particularly those of the campaign poster variety. `` He's a phenomenon, much like a young <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> in the way he works the women in the audience. ... He'd make a good politician,'' <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> said in April's Cosmopolitan magazine. <PERSON> Lowe </PERSON>, 25, rose to fame as part of the so-called brat pack of young, new actors in films like `` St. Elmo's Fire,'' `` The Outsiders,'' and `` About Last Night.'' He also made a name for himself with a string of romances with high-profile women like Princess <PERSON> Stephanie </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Monaco </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Fawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, ex-secretary to <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>, on trial for his role in the Iran-Contra affair.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>INDIANAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Cartoon cat <PERSON> Garfield </PERSON>, his creator <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Smokey </PERSON> the Bear with join Gov. <PERSON> Evan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bayh </PERSON> and 170 schoolchildren in planting a tree on the Statehouse lawn on Arbor Day. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> native, is the 1989 Arbor Day spokesman for the Hoosier state. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, who also created the `` <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Acres'' comic strip, is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audubon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> and The Nature Conservancy. `` Now is the perfect time for all Hoosiers to contribute something to their communities,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said in a statement. `` Plant a tree, plan a celebration, do something fun for Arbor Day.'' Arbor Day, the second Friday of each April, is set aside to recognize and honor the benefits trees provide.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890320-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-20-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PresidentialPups     03-20 0334</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Presidential Pups,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Presidential Puppies `Doing Fine'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
