<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 5thLd-Writethru a0800 06-07 1101</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0800,1133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troop Trucks Reinforce Occupation, Turmoil Spreads</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with estimate of 200,000 troops
in capital area. Pick up 6th pvs, `In Washington...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos BEJ13,17; others upcoming</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<UNK>Associated Press Writer</UNK>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Embassies scrambled to evacuate their citizens from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> on Thursday, and hundreds of troop trucks roared into the capital to reinforce the military occupation after <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s turmoil spread to more than a dozen cities. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ordered embassy dependents to leave the country, one day after Chinese soldiers, saying they were looking for a sniper, sprayed a diplomatic compound with gunfire. Trucks, many piled high with supplies, rolled into central Tiananmen Square for more than an hour Thursday. Some carried troops with rifles aimed at people bicycling along the road. It was not immediately known whether these were the same troops, the <ORGANIZATION> 27th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, that left the city in two large convoys Wednesday. The 27th was responsible for killing and wounding thousands of people when it stormed the city Saturday to wrest control of <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> from students demonstrating for democratic reforms. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence estimates put the death toll at 3,000. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> is also surrounded by armies said to oppose the harsh martial law crackdown, setting the stage for a possible battle between rival military factions. Reports surfaced of skirmishes between soldiers, but no serious clashes. Diplomats estimate 200,000 soldiers from 13 army groups have moved into the capital area. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> urged all Americans to leave <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> at once, calling the situation `` volatile, uncertain and increasingly dangerous.'' It ordered the evacuation of 258 diplomatic dependents. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> chartered commercial planes to supplement regular <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airline departures from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and officials organized transportation to help <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens get to airports, department spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said. At <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> Thursday morning, about 10,000 troops stood in formation, did drills or jogged around the 100-acre square. About 40 tanks were lined up on the north end with guns pointing in all directions. An additional 20 tanks and armored personnel carriers were at the south end of the square. There were no signs of anti-aircraft weapons. The situation in the provinces was deteriorating. Increasingly violent demonstrations protested the weekend military invasion of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. State television broadcast a statement from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> that any members found to have `` plotted, organized and led the rebellion'' would be expelled and punished severely. The warning mentioned no names, but conservative party leaders who ordered the crackdown were said to have singled out party chief <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON> as the instigator and ordered his ouster. Another government announcement said soldiers were authorized to `` forcibly dispose of, on the spot'' anyone who resisted arrest. Several citizens were reported killed Wednesday. In the provinces, crowds protesting the army's invasion of the capital barricaded major roads and railways in anticipation of military assaults. <PERSON> Roland </PERSON> <PERSON> Dumas </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> foreign minister, declared in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> was `` on the verge of civil war'' and the French Embassy staff would be reduced `` to the indispensable minimum.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision to stop arms sales and military contacts in protest of the bloody crackdown was a `` detriment to bilateral relations.'' Many other nations also imposed sanctions or froze relations. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> condemned the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for giving refuge to dissident <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, who fled to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. It accused <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> of attacking the communist system and said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was interfering in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s internal affairs. Chinese informants reported seeing the bodies of three people killed by soldiers and said seven people were killed or wounded near the railway station when a convoy of thousands of troops sped toward the eastern suburbs Wednesday morning. While no major fighting has materialized between the <ORGANIZATION> 27th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and supposedly rival military units on the edges of the city, a witness said the 27th and 38th armies, based in <LOCATION> Hebei </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> respectively, fought each other with automatic weapons early Wednesday about 12 miles east of downtown. The witness believed two bystanders were killed but was not sure about military casualties. Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said there were some clashes between small army units. State television showed Chinese reporters Wednesday on a tour of garbage-strewn Tiananmen Square. Soldiers appeared to be sparsely deployed and tanks could be seen on the side near the imperial palace. `` Not one person died on the square,'' a martial law official said. Witnesses and students driven from the square after a three-week protest said hundreds were shot down or crushed by tanks during the invasion early Sunday. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s top leaders have not appeared since the crackdown began and official media report little about the violence. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials believe 84-year-old <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xioaping </PERSON>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s senior leader who has been reported in ill health `` is still alive ... and still running the show.'' In other cities: _ Six people were run over by a train while manning a barricade near the <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> railway station Tuesday night <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> radio said angry crowds set the train ablaze and beat 21 railway security officials who tried to put the fire out. _ Tens of thousands of people in <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> blocked roads and held anti-government demonstrations <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> radio said the unrest `` wrecked the city's life.'' _ In <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION>'s capital, <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION>, provincial radio said 100 people were arrested after a `` gang of scoundrels'' stormed city offices and beat up 300 security officials on Sunday The radio did not comment on unconfirmed reports that 20 people died killed in clashes with security forces. _ The <LOCATION> Heilongjiang </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Daily </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Harbin </LOCATION>, northeastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, said roadblocks severely affected public transport and the situation was `` extremely serious. _ Also in the northeast, the mayor of <LOCATION> Changchun </LOCATION> said people blocked factory gates and `` if this situation continues, the city's economy will be paralyzed Embassies arranging flights for nationals included those of <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> press spokesman <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Koss </PERSON> said 125 embassy dependents would leave on a special commercial flight Thursday and 73 dependents from four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> consulates leave as soon as possible. In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said fewer than 1,000 Americans remained in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Evacuation efforts gained urgency after soldiers fired on a diplomatic compound, then surrounded it in what they said was a search for a sniper who killed one soldier and wounded three. Security officials took a Chinese man away. Public transportation remained suspended in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and shoppers formed long lines to buy scarce, expensive vegetables and meat. National television said postal service and milk delivery would resume Thursday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-US-Pakistan 3rdLd-Writethru a0818 06-07 0907</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Pakistan, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0818,900</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush and Bhutto Seek Political Solution To Afghanistan Stalemate</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS grafs 18-20: ``In an,'' with Mrs. Bhuotto's nuclear
remarks in interview report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Laserphoto WX15</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Tuesday told visiting Pakistani Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is willing `` to explore any serious avenue'' to achieve a political solution in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> in turn said after private talks with the president that `` we are in complete accord'' on the situation in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, stalemated since the pullout of the last Soviet troops in February. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said the withdrawal of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> proved the effectiveness of <LOCATION> U.S-Pakistani </LOCATION> support for the Afghan resistance fighting the Marxist regime in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> shares a common border with <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. `` We agreed, however, that the job is not done,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> continues and their struggle for self-determination goes on.'' `` Prime Minister <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> and I discussed ways to encourage a political solution in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> that will lead to a non-aligned, representative government willing to live in peace with its neighbors, to replace the illegitimate regime in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> will continue to explore any serious avenue towards this end.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials had anticipated a rapid demise for the government of <PERSON> Najibullah </PERSON> after the Soviet pullout, but it has not happened. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> said she and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> `` have reviewed the situation in the light of the prevailing circumstances and we are in complete accord'' on what needs to be done. `` <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> remains committed to a political solution of the Afghan problem, whereby the brave people of <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> will have the right to freely choose their own government without interference from outside,'' she said. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, the daughter of former Prime Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, said that while the Soviet pullout `` has brought a welcome change in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>, the continued fighting and prolonged presence of over 3.5 million Afghan refugees pose serious threats to the peace and stability of the region.'' After a full-dress military ceremony on the White House lawn, including a 19-gun salute, and an Oval Office meeting with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> went to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for a meeting with Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> and a lunch in her honor. At a state dinner Tuesday evening, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> joked during the exchange of toasts that Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> had `` refused my latest offer. She's not going double or nothing on this year's Harvard-Yale game.'' Keeping up the Ivy League banter, Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> responded: `` Ladies and gentlemen, I studied at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> and believe me, I did n't know until tonight that <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION> ever produced charming men. I'm glad I met the only one.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> is a 1973 <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> graduate; <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is a 1948 graduate of arch-rival <ORGANIZATION> Yale </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> has a standing request to buy 60 more F-16 fighter jets from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brushed aside reporters' attempts to ask about reports that approval of the jet sale is imminent. An administration official, briefing reporters at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> discussed the F-16 sale, but `` I would n't anticipate any specific announcement from outside'' during her visit. The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, indicated there were no stumbling blocks to the sale, but normal steps such as congressional notification would take more time. On another topic, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> `` assured me that <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s nuclear program is committed to peaceful purposes.'' He said he underlined his commitment `` to discourage proliferation of nuclear and chemical weapons, ballistic missiles, in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> region and around the world.'' In an interview with editors of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> said she had `` very frank talk'' with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>, and assured them <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> does not intend to build nuclear weapons. She said she wanted <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to help <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> reach a nuclear test-ban treay with `` other countries in the region,'' an apparent reference to long-ti8me rival <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, according to a report on the interview in Wednesday editions. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> exploded what it called a nuclear `` device'' in 1974. <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> last month said <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> `` clearly'' was developing nuclear capability and Indian appeared interested in developing thermonculear weapons. The two leaders also discussed efforts to combat drug production and trafficking. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he `` applauded her tough stance on eradicating the opium cultivation'' and thanked her for extraditing an alleged drug trafficker. The two countries were expected to sign agreements on housing, narcotics and education this week during <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s stay. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, the third largest recipient of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid, is slated for $ 380 million in economic assistance and $ 240 million in military aid next year. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s father was deposed by Gen. <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> <PERSON> ul-Haq </PERSON> in 1977 and hanged two years later for a political murder. <PERSON> Zia </PERSON> remained in power until perishing in a mysterious plane crash last year that also claimed the life of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Raphel </PERSON> and an American general. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>, who had picked up her father's fallen standard and been jailed for a time under <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, led her <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to victory as head of a coalition government last November. Mrs. <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> was scheduled to address a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Wednesday. She also had stops here at the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monetary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>. She will receive an honorary degree at her alma mater, <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, on Thursday and visit the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. She departs for home Saturday evening.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0425EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     06-07 0343</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Shannon' Awaits NBC's Deal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Network audiences are doing their summer tune-out as the prime-time schedule fills up with reruns. For the week ending June 4, the three networks had a combined audience share of 59, the lowest since last September when it dipped to 58. The only shows that are n't in reruns are news programs and the occasional pilot that did n't make it to series. But <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> got a surprising reaction to `` <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>'s Deal,'' which landed in the top 10 in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> ratings last week. The two-hour pilot, about a former corporate lawyer who lost it all because of a gambling problem, was written by independent filmmaker <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON> -LRB- `` Eight Men Out'' -RRB- and aired as <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s Sunday movie. `` <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>'s Deal'' had a 14.5 rating and 25 share and ranked 10th, in a tie with <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 60 Minutes.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had been saying there were no plans to take the pilot to series, although <PERSON> Sayles </PERSON> has written two more episodes. After the ratings came in, the network said it was considering keeping the show around. `` <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>'s Deal'' dealt a poor hand to its competition on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Tony Awards,'' honoring the year's finest on Broadway. It had its lowest rating ever, a 9.3 and 16 share. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the week, its 50th in a row, with an average prime-time rating of 12.7. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> came in second with a 9.6. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had a 9.4. Each rating point equals 904,000 households with television. The share is a percentage of sets in use. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was the top-rated show of the week, followed by <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Cheers,'' `` The Cosby Show,'' `` A Different World'' and `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years,'' CBS' `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Have Faith'' and `` Who's the Boss?'' then `` <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>'s Deal and `` 60 Minutes.'' `` ABC World News Tonight'' was first in last week's news race with an 8.9 rating and 20 share. The `` CBS Evening News'' had an 8.4 and 19 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' had a 7.7 and 18.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0426EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Knight-BagehotFellows     06-07 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Knight-Bagehot Fellows,0234</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seven People Named for Knight-Bagehot Fellowships</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: A longer version on financial wires.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION> announced the seven people selected as 1989-90 Knight-Bagehot Fellows in Economics and Business Journalism. The fellowships are designed to provide formal business and economics training for journalists at mid-career. Fellows spend an academic year attending classes at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s schools of business, law and international affairs. The 1989-90 fellows are: <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Copetas </PERSON>, national correspondent for <PERSON> Regardie </PERSON>'s magazine in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Corman </PERSON>, international trade reporter for the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Dietrich </PERSON>, a producer for <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Also named Tuesday were <PERSON> Micheline </PERSON> <PERSON> Maynard </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> Reuters </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, a correspondent for the <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>; and <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Talib </PERSON>, news editor of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Straits </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>. The fellowships are funded by an endowment from the <ORGANIZATION> Knight </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> and by grants from a number of foundations and corporations including the <ORGANIZATION> Olin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, the <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Fund </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Kraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jones </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. The fellowships are named after <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON>, a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist and businessman, and <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bagehot </PERSON>, a 19th-century economist and editor of the Economist magazine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0427EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     06-07 0597</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of May 29-June 4. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.8 rating, 18.8 million homes. 2. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 3. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 4. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.4 million homes. 5. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.6, 15.0 million homes. 6. `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.5 million homes. 7. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 8. `` Have Faith,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 9. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8, 13.4 million homes. 10. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 10. `` <PERSON> Shannon </PERSON>'s Deal'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.5, 13.1 million homes. 12. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2, 12.8 million homes. 13. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 13. `` Golden Girls Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1, 12.7 million homes. 15. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.5 million homes. 15. `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8, 12.5 million homes. 17. `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5, 12.2 million homes. 18. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1, 11.8 million homes. 19. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.7 million homes. 19. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.7 million homes. 19. `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9, 11.7 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 22. `` Little Girl Lost'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 12.8. 24. `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 25. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 25. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 27. `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 28. `` TV Bloopers Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 28. `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 30. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 30. `` Assault and Matrimony'' _ `` NBC Movie of the Week,'' 11.6. 30. `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 11.6. 33. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 33. `` <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>'s by the Bay,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 35. `` NBA Playoffs: <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> vs. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 11.4. 35. `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 11.4. 37. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 38. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 39. `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 10.8. 40. `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 10.7. 41. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 42. `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 43. `` Fair Game Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 44. `` 48 Hours: The Deprogramming,'' CBS, 9.9. 45. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 45. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 47. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 48. `` Club Med'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 9.5. 48. `` Rocky III'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 9.5. 50. `` Warm Hearts, Cold Feet'' _ `` CBS Special Movie-Thursday,'' 9.3. 50. `` Tony Awards,'' CBS, 9.3. 52. `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 9.1. 53. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 53. `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 55. `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 56. `` ABC News: Lying, Cheating, and Stealing in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.5. 57. `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 58. `` Beauty and the Beast,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 59. `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 60. `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.4. 61. `` International Rock Awards,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 62. `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 62. `` Earth-Star Voyager,'' Part 2, _ `` ABC Family Classic,'' 6.7. 64. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 65. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.5. 65. `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 6.5. 67. `` Charlie Brown Special,'' CBS, 6.4. 68. `` Real Genius'' _ `` CBS Saturday Movie,'' 6.0. 68. `` North & amp; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, Book II,'' Part 4, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 70. `` ABC News: World in Turmoil,'' 5.7. 71. `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.5. 72. `` Live-In,'' CBS, 5.3. 73. `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 74. `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 75. `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 76. `` Gang of Four,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 77. `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 78. `` Summer Blockbusters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9. 78. `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0018EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-WorldReaction 2ndLd-Writethru a0784 06-07 0970</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-World Reaction, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0784,0993</SECOND>
<HEAD>Governments Prepare to Evacuate Citizens; Protests Continue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>EDs: LEADS with 22 grafs to insert Thatcher comments, Japan to
stop aid and evacuate citizens. Picks up 23d pvs: `New Zealand and Switzerland
...' EDITS to tighten. ^By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Governments around the world tried to evacuate their citizens from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Tuesday as an outpouring of protest and condemnation of the bloodshed in the Chinese capital continued. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> joined the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in banning military sales to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> _ the toughest measures announced by the many countries protesting <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s military crackdown on demonstrators that left hundreds of people dead. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> froze political relations, barring contacts involving Chinese government officials. The Dutch government summoned Chinese Charge d'Affaires <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Qin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ping </PERSON> and told him <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION> `` is exceptionally shocked by the violent and brutal actions of the <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>.'' <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> also delivered a firm message to the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> ambassador in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> and the orchestra of <ORGANIZATION> Vienna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> scheduled a commemorative concert for the Chinese victims. Dutch government officials canceled a state visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> by Queen <PERSON> Beatrix </PERSON>, and <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> Foreign Secretary Sir <PERSON> Geoffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> said a November visit by <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> and Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> `` can not take place as long as those responsible for the atrocities ... remain in control of the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government.'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> also said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> will not allow mass immigration from the colony of <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, due to be handed over to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1997. He said an open door policy `` could more than double the ethnic minority population of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> said earlier that about 3.5 million <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> eligible for British passports will not be given the right of residence in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> but <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> will show `` greater flexibility'' about immigration from <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. She expressed `` utter revulsion'' at the Chinese crackdown and said, `` We will be thinking how best to demonstrate that in practical ways.'' <PERSON> Howe </PERSON> announced <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> immediately is banning arms sales to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> due to the `` slaughter of innocent people'' and banned military contacts and visits by senior <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> officials. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> refused to say what arms <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> sells to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> but the <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> said sales amounted to $ 4.68 million a year. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> sells <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> more than $ 600 million of military equipment a year, and private <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dealers do about $ 85 million worth of military sales with <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Francois </PERSON> <PERSON> Godet </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Swiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official, said the ban marks the first time <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> has withdrawn approval from contracts already agreed. he declined to say how much the contracts are worth, but sources said they amounted to a few million dollars. Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> said his government is not considering economic sanctions against <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> but <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Taizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Watanabe </PERSON> said that because of the situation aid projects `` can not go on.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the largest contributor of aid to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the assistance, most in the form of loans, totaled $ 6.1 billion as of 1987, the latest figures available. The 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> strongly condemned the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> action and appealed to authorities to stop using force. But it did not propose any joint protest measures. People in <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> copied a protest started in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> on Monday by withdrawing deposits from <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> branches. A crowd formed outside the bank, where a senior official said three to four times more people than usual withdrew money. He said he did not know how much was withdrawn. Meanwhile, many governments warned their citizens in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to leave the country or take strict security precautions as reports spread of Chinese soldiers battling each other in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> urged the 1,440 Americans in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to leave and planned arrangements for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airlines to fly them to safety. <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> said the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> chartered a <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 to evacuate Britons to <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. About 50 Canadians, heeding advice from <LOCATION> Ottowa </LOCATION> to leave immediately, flew out Tuesday, and 200 more were to leave on a special flight Wednesday, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> said. The Australian government chartered a jumbo jet to evacuate its citizens and Foreign Minister <PERSON> Gareth </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> said the increasing violence indicates `` the larger potential for really full-scale civil war erupting.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> arranged for two special commercial flights to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Tuesday to help its citizens leave and <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> officials said further flights were planned, pending permission from <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> authorities. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> also hired jets for evacuations. <PERSON> Achille </PERSON> <PERSON> Occetto </PERSON>, head of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, urged the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> to take a strong stance against the massacre and distanced his party from the leaders responsible for the crackdown. <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> has the largest communist party in the West. In <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> members of the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION> called on <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leaders to use `` wisdom, reason and a weighted approach'' but did not denounce the violence. The Soviet Foreign Ministry has made no comment. The two communist giants are trying to mend fences after decades of estrangement. Protesters, mainly Chinese students, demonstrated outside <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> embassies in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Madrid </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Abu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhabi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arab </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Emirates </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>; the Hague in the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Greeceother </LOCATION> and other cities. In <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the pro-government newspaper The Citizen questioned why <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is the target of international boycotts `` when whatever faults we have are tiny by comparison ... to the horror of the massacre of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>.'' East German state newspapers indirectly took sides with the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government's use of force. The <ORGANIZATION> Junge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> newspaper appealed to East Germans not to believe media reports that bore the `` viewpoint of Western politics'' and gave `` good grades to those holding out in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to protest the government, and bad grades to those calling for calm and reconciliation.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0229EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Khomeini'sSon Bjt   06-07 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Khomeini's Son, Bjt,0919</SECOND>
<HEAD>Khomeini's Son Emerges From Shadows, But Power May Elude Him</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> has emerged from the long shadow of his father and appears to be making a bid for power himself, a move some analysts believe is doomed to fail. He was making his moves even before <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> died Saturday. But the death of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s revolutionary and spiritual patriarch, before the leadership issue could be settled, has added urgency to the son's campaign. `` A lot of emotions are rampant in <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> now,'' <PERSON> Shahram </PERSON> <PERSON> Chubin </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> Graduate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, said in a telephone interview. `` Some people will be trying to take advantage of that and <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> is one of them.'' The Assembly of Experts, the body formed in 1979 to ensure a smooth transition after <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s death, on Sunday named President <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> as a caretaker leader until the succession is resolved. In the meantime, rivals in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> are jockeying for power. Although <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> is only a middle-ranking cleric, or hojatoleslam, and holds no official title, he was one of his father's closest advisers. As <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s private secretary, he controlled access to the reclusive patriarch and wielded considerable influence behind the scenes. The younger <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, 43, took an increasingly high public profile as his father's health declined. He has allied himself with radical figures in the hierarchy in the power struggle that has intensified since the Aug. 20 cease-fire in the war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>. Speculation rose that he sought to establish himself as his father's political heir by engineering the March 28 dismissal of his father's designated successor, <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Hussein-Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> was his father's eyes and ears since their days in exile and through the Islamic revolution that toppled the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Reza </PERSON> <PERSON> Pahlavi </PERSON>. Last month, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> newspapers published lengthy excerpts of a 110-page memorandum <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON>, lashing him for seeking to undermine <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s regime and consorting with opposition groups. The document appeared to be aimed at publicly projecting <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> as a candidate to inherit his father's mantle. <PERSON> Masoud </PERSON> <PERSON> Rajavi </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khalq </ORGANIZATION>, or People's Holy Warriors, the main Iranian opposition movement, says <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> was grooming <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> as his successor. <PERSON> Rajavi </PERSON> said in a statement that <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s dismissal of <PERSON> Montazeri </PERSON> for criticizing the regime `` prepared the ground for this appointment.'' He argued that <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s appointment of a special committee to amend the constitution, including downgrading the religious qualifications of his successor from `` divinely inspired authority'' was aimed at making room for <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON>. But analysts believe the black-bearded <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> could eventually become a political casualty now that his father is dead. They believe that bereft of the ayatollah's authority, and with no secure power base of his own, <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON>'s influence could evaporate. `` As <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s health deteriorated, he was able to control his father's statements and this gave him some authority,'' <PERSON> Chubin </PERSON> said. `` But it would be rather difficult for him to be the keeper of the flame now that <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> has gone. <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> has neither the religious credentials nor the administrative experience to rule and it's not clear whether claiming dynastic credentials will be enough. `` He could become a pawn in the power struggle, a front man for more powerful people following his father's death.'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> specialist <PERSON> Shireen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview: `` I do n't think he'll emerge as <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s strongman. `` His power is really quite vicarious, stemming primarily from his position as his father's gatekeeper. I do n't believe he can fill his father's shoes.'' With 40 days of mourning declared for <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has been engulfed by a wave of emotion for its dead leader, a development <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> could exploit to advance his political ambitions. But Ms. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> cautioned: `` Using <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s name could be a double-edged sword. There was already a backlash against <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> and that in the end could work against <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON>. The revolution is against dynasties. `` He could well become a major player ... but he's not a person of great convictions and he'll have to associate himself with one group or another to stay in play.'' From the outside, the political maneuverings in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> are often opaque. But last August, <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> was seen as a member of an unofficial troika with <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> and <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON>, both so-called `` pragmatists,'' who had effectively taken over day-to-day control as <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON>'s health failed. Now he's aligned with the radicals led by Interior Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Akbar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohtashemi </PERSON>, Prosecutor-General <PERSON> Musavi </PERSON> <PERSON> Khoeiniha </PERSON>, Intelligence Minister <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Rey-Shahri </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Tavasoli </PERSON>, a powerful behind-the-scenes figure in <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION>. Some analysts believe <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> could swing back to <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> again if he sees him gaining ground. But for now he's lined up against <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who was earlier outflanked by the radicals in the fundamentalist resurgence decreed by his father in February. <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s shrewdest politicians, appears to be maneuvering his way back and could well come out on top again, as he has done many times before. There is speculation <PERSON> Ahmad </PERSON> will run in presidential elections scheduled for Aug. 18. So far the only announced candidate is the formidable <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, who won the highest ballot in last year's parliamentary elections with more than 1.3 million votes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AIDS Bjt   06-07 0647</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS, Bjt,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Authorities Predict More Widespread AIDS Testing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MONTREAL (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> health official says the time is coming when doctors will report the names of people testing positive for the AIDS virus and try to trace victims' sexual contacts. But activists criticized the proposal. Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Assistant Secretary for Health, said he did n't know when such a system would be in place, but when it happens `` we will have normalized HIV and will handle it like syphilis.'' HIV, or human immunodeficiency virus, causes AIDS. <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>'s remarks Tuesday at the Fifth International Conference on AIDS drew immediate criticism. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON>, executive director of the Gay Men's Health Crisis in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, opposed the proposal because he feared names would not be kept confidential and that people known to be infected would suffer from the stigma associated with acquired immune deficiency syndrome. `` People lose their jobs, their housing and their schooling opportunities,'' he said. `` That's not like other diseases.'' Furthermore, he said, tracing patients' sexual contacts will not work for AIDS as it does with syphilis because HIV patients may have been infected for years when they are diagnosed. Tracing partners so far back is unlikely, he said. The consequences of reporting would discourage many people from submitting to testing, <PERSON> Dunne </PERSON> said. `` The only way people are going to come forward is if there's something effective'' to help them, he said. The Gay Men's Health Crisis received numerous calls Tuesday from people who were already concerned that their names might be recorded if they seek testing. Dr. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> health commissioner, floated a similar proposal at the AIDS meeting Monday. <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has directed the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> to prepare a report on discrimination against people with AIDS and HIV infection, <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said, in anticipation of moves toward reporting the names of those tested. He said early identification of infected people through contact tracing could allow them to be treated promptly with new drugs now being tested. The cost of such treatment would run into the billions of dollars, <PERSON> Mason </PERSON> said. He did not know where that money might come from. In other conference reports: _ Researchers said initial studies on a new AIDS drug called CD4 showed that the medicine is safe and may reduce levels of HIV in the body. The drug is a decoy intended to confuse the virus and draw it away from the blood cells it ordinarily infects. In expeimental use on 18 people, Dr. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Yarchoan </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> found that the drug appeared to lower virus levels in the body by about 50 percent. However, he cautioned that this could have been a natural fluctuation instead of a result of the drug. Another team found no clear evidence of virus reduction, but researchers said they were still encouraged by the drug's potential and said higher doses could have a greater effect. _ In a report scheduled for presentation today, <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cancer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> reserachers said a recently discovered herpes virus may accelerate the development of AIDS in people infected with HIV Dr. <PERSON> Paulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lusso </PERSON> said the virus, called HHV-6, enhanced the growth of HIV in test tube, causing more cells to die more quickly. More than half of Americans, Canadians and Europeans have been exposed to HHV-6 without any ill effects and may be capable of passing it on, studies have shown. _ Researchers at <ORGANIZATION> Johns </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hopkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> said it was now possible to predict two years in advance which patients infected with HIV will develop AIDS Studies suggest that a majority of people infected with the virus get AIDS or related illnesses. A similar study by researchers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, found that a combination of five laboratory tests can predict which patients will develop AIDS during a four-year period.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0115EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 10thLd-Writethru   06-07 1134</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 10th Ld-Writethru,a0417,1177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers Who Suppressed Protests Fire As They Leave City Center</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 18 grafs with troops appearing to be taking up positions
for an attack. Picks up 12th pvs, `The troops chanted ...' EDITS therefter
to trim, conform.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of the troops responsible for the bloody crackdown on the pro-democracy movement fanned out from the city center Wednesday, spraying gunfire as they passed Chinese and diplomatic residential areas. They appeared to be taking up positions for an attack, possibly from rival military factions which had moved into the city's outskirts Most of the troops from the <ORGANIZATION> 27th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, in a convoy of hundreds of trucks and support vehicles, appeared to be shooting into the air, although some aimed at an apartment complex where hundreds of diplomats and other foreigners live. Several dozen bullets hit the windows of apartments facing the main street. There were no reports of injuries. At a nearby intersection, troops took up defensive positions behind barricades and trees as if expecting an attack. Troops were also seen reinforcing positions at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Railway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> to the east of <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> and at the <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> northeast of the square. The 27th drove unarmed pro-democracy demonstrators from the center of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on early Sunday, killing hundreds in the most violent suppression of a popular movement in Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 40-year history Troops from the 28th and 38th armies and soldiers from northeastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have moved into the city, raising fears of a battle. The 27th Army is closely linked to President <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangkun </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> hardliners. The 28th Army is believed to back <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>, a moderate who challenged the conservatives and was stripped of his post as <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader. The 38th Army, which is based around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, reportedly refused orders to open fire on civilians and opposed the martial law crackdown. There have been several skirmishes between rival military groups, but no major clashes. An unidentified general appeared on national television Tuesday night and denied factional divisions in the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement condemning the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for what it called its `` short-sighted'' policies toward <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, joining other Western countries imposing sanctions on <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, has suspended arms sales and other military contacts to protest the violent suppression of the pro-democracy movement. The ministry, in a statement read on television, insisted the situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is stable and there has been no change in the nation's foreign policy. About 3,000 foot soldiers carrying rifles left <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in two waves Wednesday. The first group of about 1,000 had packs on their backs and marched 20 abreast. They were accompanied by a tank and two armored personnel carriers. Some 400 split soon from the main group and turned toward the south. Some in the second group were in plain clothes. The troops chanted, `` Down with corruption, we love the people, we love the capital, we love youth, long live the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'' as they left their positions in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>. People along the sidewalks initially cheered when they heard the chanting. But one office worker said, `` They can sing any slogan they want but then they start shooting.'' An undetermined number of troops and tanks remained in the square. Another group of 600 foot soldiers wearing red armbands was seen advancing toward the square from the west. They appeared to be preparing to take over traffic control. Thousands of foreigners are trying frantically to leave <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has told all Americans to leave as soon as possible and the <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> has told the 3,000 Japanese in the city to prepare for immediate evacuation. Many nations were arranging for special planes to transport their nationals out of the country. The state-run <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> <PERSON> Shi </PERSON>, one of five members of the party's policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Politburo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Standing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, received a telegram from the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> supporting the crackdown. The report, read on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> radio, was significant because the telegram was sent to <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> and not <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>. Although <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> has not been seen publicly since May 19, officials have not confirmed he has lost his post. Diplomats have often considered <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON>, 64, a top candidate to replace <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>. But a Chinese source said Wednesday that a family member said <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> had not been appointed party chief. <PERSON> Qiao </PERSON> generally is viewed as the party's law-and-order chief. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> radio also reported that conservative Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> attended a meeting Tuesday to hear reports on industrial production. A <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> newspaper reported that <PERSON> Li </PERSON> was shot in the thigh by a young guard officer but his wounds were not serious. The reports were the first official indications of leadership positions since Saturday's assault. The leadership, including senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, has not made any public appearances since the crackdown. A report that <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> had died added to the chaos. The report, from <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, was denied by the government. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration said it appeared likely that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s senior leaders had left <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Soldiers continued firing into crowds around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Tuesday and early Wednesday. Witnesses said a small boy was killed and a girl wounded in the head Tuesday. Anti-government demonstrations spread to <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nanjing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chengdu </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Shenyang </LOCATION> and other cities. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most famous dissident, astrophysicist <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, took refuge in the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. He had told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> last week he was concerned conservatives might arrest him. Government spokesman <PERSON> Yuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mu </PERSON> said on television 300 people were killed in Saturday's crackdown, including 23 students; and 7,000 were injured and 400 soldiers were missing. The evening TV news said 32 people were arrested, most of them for trying to set fire to public buses. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> intelligence reports reaching <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> indicate 3,000 people probably were killed, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official said Tuesday. On Tuesday afternoon, witnesses said the <ORGANIZATION> 27th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> fought with soldiers from <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> province's 28th Army, believed loyal to <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>. There were no reports of casualties. The brief exchange, including several rounds from a tank cannon, occurred just south of the <LOCATION> Military </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Museum </LOCATION> in western <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. It followed unconfirmed reports of soldiers fighting soldiers in the western and southeastern parts of the city. The <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is organized into about 22 Group Armies. Each has about three divisions and totals about 40,000 soldiers. Hundreds of citizens flocked to the bridge at <LOCATION> Muxudi </LOCATION>, also in the west, to welcome soldiers Tuesday evening who said they were from the 38th Army. `` Exterminate the 27th Army! Avenge blood with blood!'' people in the crowd chanted as they handed buns, eggs and cigarettes to the troopers. `` People, do not be afraid!'' said a voice from a loudspeaker carried by the soldiers. `` The 38th Army will not kill the people.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0413EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-07 0813</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0849</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Alessandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>, granddaughter of the late fascist dictator of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, visited <ORGANIZATION> Judaism </ORGANIZATION>'s holiest site and appealed for an end to religious prejudice. Miss <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>, 23, who is here for a film in which she portrays an <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldier, visited the sacred Western Wall and the Yad Vashem Holocaust museum and said she `` felt just sick'' after seeing displays of Nazi atrocities. `` There are no words to describe those things,'' she said Tuesday. Miss <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON> said she saw no irony in her visit even though her grandfather, <PERSON> Benito </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>, was an ally of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, who perpetrated the Holocaust in which 6 million Jews died. `` I'm a new generation, and I want to give a message ... to overcome all the prejudice, to say ` Let's shake hands and be friends,''' she said. `` I do n't feel anything bad against me here,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Mussolini </PERSON>, who is also a niece of actress <PERSON> Sophia </PERSON> <PERSON> Loren </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's been a long time coming, but Oscar-winning actor <PERSON> Dustin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> is finally going to be a graduate. The <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Monica </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> board voted unanimously Monday to give an honorary associate in arts degree to <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON>, who enrolled in 1955 to study music but changed to theater arts and never graduated. Superintendent <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> sent word through his agent that he would be honored to accept the degree. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> is currently appearing in `` The Merchant of <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION>'' in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hoffman </PERSON> has been nominated six times for Academy Awards, including `` The Graduate,'' `` Midnight Cowboy,'' `` Lenny'' and `` Tootsie.'' He won Oscars for his performances in `` Rain Man'' and `` <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> vs. <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BRASILIA, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British pop star Sting, a campaigner to protect the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> rain forest and native Indians, was stung by criticism and bureaucratic hassles during a visit to the capital. Sting came here after a two-month international tour to raise funds for creation of a huge Indian reservation in the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle. At a meeting Monday to discuss the campaign, <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Juruna </PERSON>, a Xavante Indian and ex-congressman, accused the singer of taking advantage of the `` purity and innocence of the Indians'' for self-promotion: `` Why does n't he dedicate himself to resolving the problem of AIDS or defend the Indians of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>?'' Sting also was told that to visit <ORGANIZATION> Xingu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION>, a major Indian reservation in central <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, he would have to meet the usual bureaucratic requirements to enter the restricted area. The red tape was waived for the singer on previous visits. According to news reports, Sting said nothing but later canceled a scheduled news conference.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Neighbors are complaining that <PERSON> Aretha </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> is giving them a case of the blues by neglecting her house on the city's west side. The two-story brick home, deeded to the singer in 1972 by her then-husband <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, was condemned last year by the city. Now, the yard is overgrown and littered. `` We live in a nice neighborhood, but <PERSON> Aretha </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> does n't care about us,'' said <PERSON> Theodora </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, who lives behind the house <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> could n't be reached for comment. There was no answer Tuesday morning at the office of her attorney, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Tennen </PERSON>. City records show the house was bought by White and <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> for $ 18,500 in 1967, when they were married. The market value of the house and land is about $ 42,500.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> BIRMINGHAM </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ala. </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> will be the grand marshal for a Do-Dah-Day parade. Automobiles and marchers with their pets will be featured in Saturday's parade. Entry fees will benefit the <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Humane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` Let's do it,'' Miss <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> told her publicist when she heard about the parade. `` I love animals and people, especially old people and children.'' Miss <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>, the former church secretary whose tryst with <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> crumbled his PTL ministry, said she no longer attends church services but still believes in God.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three-time Iditarod champion musher <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Butcher </PERSON> says she has much in common with her four-legged teammates. `` These are athletes, like any other athletes,'' <PERSON> Butcher </PERSON> said. The 150 sled dogs she and her husband own have speed, endurance `` and the same thing I happen to have: drive and the competitive spirit.'' Ms. <PERSON> Butcher </PERSON> came from rural <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> to claim the 22nd annual Tanqueray Amateur Athlete Achievement Award on Tuesday. She received a silver platter in honor of her achievements in the 1,168-mile Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race. `` I love my dogs. I love living in the wilderness. I'm a lucky person to have something I enjoy doing,'' she said. Her 1987 mark of 11 days, 2 hours, 5 minutes and 13 seconds stands as the record for the dogsled race from <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>. She also won in 1986 and 1988, but came in second this year after several dogs became ill.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0456EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CBSAffiliates     06-07 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CBS Affiliates,0443</SECOND>
<HEAD>CBS Exec: CBS Is Network of 1990s With More Sports, Innovative Programming</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Third-place <ORGANIZATION> CBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> plans to become the network of the 1990s with more sports coverage and innovative programming, the president of the <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> broadcast group told affiliates. <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stringer </PERSON>'s comments Tuesday were enthusiastically received by broadcasters attending the network's annual affiliates meeting. The mood was in contrast to the skepticism at last year's meeting, which followed the network's first-ever third-place finish in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> prime-time ratings behind <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Referring to praise for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>'s news coverage of the weekend massacre in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Stringer </PERSON> said: `` It gives me great pleasure to see my old friend <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rather </PERSON> become the talk of the town again. When people ask what <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tisch </PERSON> is going to get for $ 3 billion, this is an example.'' <PERSON> Tisch </PERSON> is president of CBS. The broadcasters also heard from Rather and <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>, who talked by audio hookup to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and by television satellite to White House Chief of Staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> defended President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s cautious reaction to events in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` We're pushing as hard as we can, but we ca n't push beyond the point of constructive interaction,'' he said. `` We do not want to give anyone cause to feel we are intervening or instigating bloodshed.'' Former First lady <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> talked briefly following a discussion on drugs by Rather, <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stutman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Stutman </PERSON> said the only effective way to fight drugs was a three-pronged assault of law enforcement, treatment and education. `` I hear people blame other countries for our drug problem,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said, `` but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> alone is responsible for its drug problem. It's an illusion to think we can stop drugs by sending troops to foreign countries when we ca n't even stop drug sales in our own neighborhoods.'' <PERSON> Stringer </PERSON> compared the battles between the three commercial networks and cable television as <PERSON> Gulliver </PERSON> being chained down by the tiny Lilliputians in <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>'s satire `` Gulliver's Travels.'' `` I look on cable as the media's one-armed bandit. Viewers only win when it comes up three bars, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. We spent $ 4 billion in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> and they take our programs and charge people money to watch.'' The networks have long fought the cable industry's ability to use network programming without paying a fee. <PERSON> Stringer </PERSON> also referred to network efforts to overturn regulations by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> prohibiting networks from participating in the syndication market.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Foley-Analysis Bjt   06-07 0629</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Foley-Analysis, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Political Blood Lust Still in Evidence on Republican Right</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM DRINKARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the House Republican leader warned his <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> colleagues against a French Revolution mentality in which `` evil Democrats'' are hauled to the guillotine, some began humming the French national anthem. The incident at a party meeting Tuesday illustrates the political blood lust that persists in a chamber fractured by months of ethics charges and countercharges, and the uphill fight new House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> will have in trying to restore order. `` The task I see for myself is to create the environment where ... debate can take place without recriminations, without the kind of angry, hostile feelings between members'' that have dominated the House of late, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> told reporters. `` This tension which has built up over a period of many months is going to require a little time to turn around,'' he said. `` It's not going to be done in a day. ... But I believe it will happen.'' Some Democrats, stung by the sacrifice of former speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> in the ethics storm, have turned their sights on Rep. <PERSON> Newt </PERSON> <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, R-Ga., who filed the original ethics charges against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> An ethics investigation of <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>'s book-promotion deal could begin as early as Thursday. Of the ethics committee and <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, Rep. <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Slaughter </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, said: `` I want them to treat him fairly, but I certainly want them to treat him.'' The political knives remained out in the Republican camp, as well. <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> political operatives were searching financial disclosure reports for possible ethical shortcomings of Democrats, and <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON> spoke of new ethics cases yet to be filed against members of the majority party. Minority Leader <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, who warned his colleagues against a frenzy of political executions, blamed the atmosphere on `` 35 years of uninterrupted power'' for Democrats and said ethics abuses wo n't be forgotten. `` I am all for putting an end to bitterness,'' <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> said. `` I am all in favor of putting our House in order, but we wo n't do so by sweeping things under the rug.'' In an acceptance speech to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> directed many of his comments at the Republican side, promising increased consultation and appealing to shared values of trust and public service. The calming style was in sharp contrast to that of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Where <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> confronted, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> counsels; where <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> followed his own compass, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> seeks advice. Republicans will now be looking for that style to be translated into changes that will benefit them. <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> may be able to buy some peace by permitting more Republican amendments to be offered to bills on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor, or by bringing legislation before the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> under less restrictive rules. `` If he does, I'll be totally and cheerfully bipartisan,'' said <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION>'s chief gadfly. But he doubted that <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> would be able to give the Republicans much latitude on issues they want most, such as a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution and the death penalty for drug and other offenses. `` Those are anathema to the left wing of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. While he appealed for cooperation, <PERSON> Foley </PERSON> did not seek to hide his own ideology. He openly acknowledged at a news conference that he is a liberal, the label that Democratic presidential nominee <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> sought vainly to avoid last year. And he clearly reserved the sole right to set the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s agenda, the prerogative of the majority. `` Procedurally, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> will try to work with the Republicans to be fair,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Budget </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` I think the difference will be he will be a fighter on issues the Democrats stand for.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Drinkard </PERSON> covers <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0508EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugDecriminalization Bjt   06-07 0837</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Decriminalization, Bjt,0857</SECOND>
<HEAD>Advocates Say It Would Cut Crime, Cost</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vowing that the `` scourge'' of drugs will stop and drug czar <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> organizing the troops for a full-scale war, calls for decriminalization of drug use are like cries in the dark. But the cries are getting louder and have drawn together people from disparate sides of the political spectrum _ from conservative <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON>, a former prosecutor. Advocates of such a stance point to a drop in crime rates following the 1933 end of Prohibition that had outlawed liquor sales since 1920. Today, huge drug profits and artificially high drug prices are fueling the violent crime plaguing cities throughout the country, they say. Removing the profits would remove the criminals, the argument goes, and the billions of dollars now spent on unsuccessful enforcement efforts could be funneled into treatment and education programs. But the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration maintains the need for `` zero tolerance'' of illicit drug use, and fighting the war on drugs _ even if it requires scarce federal financial resources _ is a priority on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. In March, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told one group of high school students that legalizing drugs would be `` 180 degrees wrong.'' A recent forum featuring advocates of decriminalization _ organized by the libertarian-leaning <ORGANIZATION> Cato </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and featuring presentations by <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> Professor <PERSON> Ethan </PERSON> <PERSON> Nadelmann </PERSON> and attorney <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Ostrowksi </PERSON> _ drew attendees from <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>'s Office of National Drug Control Policy, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. The three who spoke to the forum emphasized that they were n't advocating use of now-illicit drugs `` The available evidence indicates that legalization would not lead to an explosion in drug use. The repeal of alcohol prohibition did not,'' said <PERSON> Ostrowski </PERSON>. `` The decriminalization of marijuana in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> did not. The cheap and ready access to cocaine and narcotics in the 19th century did not. `` The fact is, most people in our society are capable of acting responsibly when it comes to drugs,'' he said. `` Users of nicotine are declining. Alcohol abusers are only a small percentage of the population.'' The panel members differed, however, on how much decriminalization they want. <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON> stressed that although he believes marijuana use and sales should not have criminal penalties, he was not advocating that sales of cocaine, heroin and other dangerous drugs be allowed in the same manner that alcoholic beverages are now sold. `` The model that I think makes the most sense is the model in <LOCATION> Holland </LOCATION>, in which the government treats addicts as patients and says that you can obtain these substances from certified health professionals,'' <PERSON> Schmoke </PERSON> said. `` But if you obtain these substances outside the public health system, you're subject to criminal sanctions.'' Such a plan lowers the crime rate, because `` you do n't have to rob and steal and break into people's houses to obtain enough goods to buy drugs,'' and it restricts the spread of AIDS that otherwise would be transmitted through the sharing of needles, he said. <PERSON> Nadelmann </PERSON> said that from a strict cost-benefit analysis _ including money spent for enforcement of drug laws as well as the cost of violence, corruption and the need for ever-expanding prisons _ the prohibition on drugs makes no sense. He acknowledged that while the illegality of some drugs may make some people, particularly those in higher socioeconomic groups, stay away from the substances, the nation ca n't ignore the violence plaguing inner cities, much of it caused by the illegality of the drug-dealers' trade. Ever-increasing spending on unsuccessful enforcement makes no sense, <PERSON> Nadelmann </PERSON> argued. `` Everything we've been doing in the past or that we're talking about doing now and that people are talking about doing in the future in terms of criminal justice approaches is doomed to failure,'' he said. `` Twenty years of experience has shown that. `` And it has nothing to do with corruption in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> or turf squabbles between law enforcement agencies or with whether or not we have a drug czar or whether or not his name is <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Nadelmann </PERSON> said. `` What it has to do with is the nature of the market, the nature of the commodity and how lucrative the whole thing is.'' It's impossible to wipe out all the opium fields in the world, he said, and it's impossible to intercept all the cocaine imported to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> without virtually closing down foreign trade and sealing the borders. Former Sen. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> said after the forum that he remained undecided on the issue. `` I think the strongest argument is getting the criminal element out of the drug business,'' said <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON>, who ran unsuccessfully for president in 1972 and is now on the lecture circuit. But <PERSON> McGovern </PERSON> said he doubted <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is ready to hear the decriminalization arguments. `` Maybe five to 10 years down the road, you'll be getting more serious evaluation of this side of the argument,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0409EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-RichcoSubsidies Bjt   06-07 0627</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Richco Subsidies, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>Questions Raised About Company's Subsidies, Ties to Fugitive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY MASSEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is reviewing a grain company's possible links to a fugitive commodities trader in <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and its receipt of at least $ 65 million in government export subsidies. At issue are the company's ties to <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>, who fled to <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> in 1983 before his indictment for criminal tax evasion, racketeering, mail and wire fraud. A department official confirmed Tuesday that <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> was examining <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, a Swiss-based company with an office in <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, and payments it received through the Export Enhancement Program, known as EEP. The review was started at the request of the chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee, Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, D-Kan., who raised questions about the company at a hearing earlier this year and on Tuesday asked the agency for a full investigation <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, in a letter to the agency, said `` an unmistakable line of ownership, control and profit runs from'' <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> through a series of subsidiary arrangements. `` While I am disturbed that a company whose main operations lie outside of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can establish but a nominal onshore presence and qualify to receive <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION> bonuses, as appears to be the case with <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grain </ORGANIZATION>, I am truly shocked that a fugitive from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> justice can benefit from a program funded by taxpayer dollars,'' <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> said in his letter to Agriculture Secretary <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON>. Under the Export Enhancement Program, private exporters can sell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities at lower prices to meet foreign competition and then collect free government surpluses of grain or other commodities as bonuses, or subsidies. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowder </PERSON>, under secretary for international affairs and commodity programs, said <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> had started `` checking through what the connections are'' between <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Rich </PERSON>. He declined to provide any details on the findings so far. An official of <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Church </PERSON>, declined to comment about the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> review and would not provide any information about the company. <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> asked that <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>'s Office of Inspector General determine whether <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> qualified for the export subsidy program and whether department eligibility guidelines need to be changed to close any possible loopholes used by <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> has the same telephone number as <ORGANIZATION> Clarendon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AG </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION> Marc </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rich </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Co.. A.G. of <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> <PERSON> Clarendon </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> company settled a federal tax evasion case in 1984 by pleading guilty and agreeing to pay more than $ 200 million in back taxes, fines and other penalties. Criminal charges against <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> were unaffected by the settlement. The government alleged that <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> and his commodity-trading empire cheated the government out of millions of dollars in taxes through a series of illegal oil transactions among Rich-controlled companies. <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> has received at least $ 65 million worth of subsidies through <ORGANIZATION> EEP </ORGANIZATION>, ranking it ninth among grain exporters in the program, according to information supplied to a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> committee by <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. Most recently, <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> picked up estimated subsidies of $ 250,000 for a wheat sale to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Last month, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> approved use of the subsidy program for the sale of 1.5 million tons of wheat to the Soviets. <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> handled at least 30,000 tons of the initial part of the wheat deal. Subsidies averaged $ 8.46 per ton for <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> and four other companies, according to <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, who met Tuesday with <PERSON> Yeutter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Crowder </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> might need to pass legislation disqualifying <ORGANIZATION> Richco </ORGANIZATION> from the export program unless <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> administratively barred it from receiving more subsidies. `` The export enhancement program has undergone some criticism anyway. It would be a shame to jeopardize its future because we're providing bonus commodities to a tax fugitive,'' said <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON> `` This is a guy of renowned international bad dealings.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0501EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AssaultWeapons     06-07 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Assault Weapons,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>NRA Tries to Counter Police Endorsements of Gun Bans</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While several police organizations are urging <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve strict controls on semiautomatic assault-style weapons, some 225 officers gathered on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to say those groups do n't speak for them. `` The average policeman in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> right now is extremely upset with the misrepresentations,'' said Patrolman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Aveni </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, who asked that his department be identified only as being in <LOCATION> Camden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J </LOCATION>. The notion that policemen favor `` gun bans as a solution to violent crime'' is wrong, said <PERSON> Aveni </PERSON>, who recently organized a group called Law Enforcement for the Preservation of the Second Amendment, which guarantees the right to keep and bear arms. `` The majority of us have taken an oath to uphold the Constitution,'' he said in an interview. `` The Second Amendment's the cornerstone of the Constitution If the Second Amendment goes, there's no guarantee that the rest of the Constitution will remain intact. ... Without arms, people are powerless to dissent against any kind of tyranny or repression of government.'' <PERSON> Aveni </PERSON> was one of the 225 officers flown to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> to participate in a news conference Tuesday and lobby their respective congressmen and senators. The only state not represented by an officer was <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. They were here to combat the impact of gun-control endorsements by law enforcement officials such as <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Behan </PERSON>, who are pushing for controls on assault-style weapons including semiautomatic versions of the AK-47 and Uzi. Law enforcement groups that have taken similar stands include the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organizations </ORGANIZATION> and the Police Executive Research Forum. `` For thousands of us out there that the chiefs, the appointed officials, do not speak for the law enforcement officers that are in the field, in the trenches, doing the job,'' said <PERSON> Patrolman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Maples </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Memphis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. But <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fraternal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Order </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, countered that his organization speaks for 200,000 of those officers, not for their bosses. `` The Fraternal Order of Police does speak for the cop on the street,'' <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said. `` There are no chiefs, there are no sheriffs. They do n't speak for anyone except for the cops on the beat.'' The contention by some law enforcement leaders that their officers are being `` outgunned'' by criminals wielding assault-style weapons `` offends me,'' Officer <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Pyle </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said at the news conference. <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, Officer <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Steiner </PERSON> said criminals have better firearms because they're making more money these days. `` Unfortunately, police departments have for many years been forced to look at the bottom line in terms of low bid, and that applies to our safety equipment in particular,'' <PERSON> Steiner </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION> Police Lt. <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said many of the officers attending were `` under direct orders from their police chiefs to disassociate themselves from their respective police departments'' in their comments. `` The remarks that are made here should not be construed as the official policy of our respective police departments,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890607-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-07-89 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirlineHubs     06-07 0561</FIRST>
