<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0103EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     08-05 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0480</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A researcher who spends his time studying roadside trash has found that most litterbugs are men. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Syrek </PERSON>, whose research provided the basis for a cleanup campaign that cut roadside littering by 60 percent in the state since 1985, discovered that men did most of the littering, and they `` do n't respond positively when you use the word ` please' in telling them to stop.'' Some Texans found the `` Do n't Mess With <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>'' campaign a tad macho, but it worked, said <PERSON> Syrek </PERSON>, who evaluates roadside litter for 16 state governments. With his on-site inspections, <PERSON> Syrek </PERSON> found that men did 70 percent of all deliberate littering, `` and 90 percent of all accidental littering _ where things fly off the bed of a pickup truck, for example _ involve male drivers,'' he said. Seventy-five percent of the men involved were younger than 35. The $ 2 million advertising campaign has included appearances by country singer <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, football players and other celebrities. Studying roadside trash is a good way to see the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Syrek </PERSON> said. `` There is some incredibly beautiful countryside that we get to see in detail,'' said <PERSON> Syrek </PERSON>. `` At least, we do when the litter is gone.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NORTHAMPTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Only three Republicans are left in this town, jokes the man who started the annual <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> footrace, `` and one of them is in bad health.'' Luckily, Democrats are willing to participate. The annual 10-kilometer `` I do not choose to run'' honors a president who was `` more of a man for brisk walks,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Greater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northampton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` But <LOCATION> Cal </LOCATION> has n't been here for a long time,'' he said. `` And the T-shirts have become a real collectors item.'' So prized are the race T-shirts that only the first few hundred runners to sign up for Sunday's race will get them. The aquamarine shirt is emblazoned with a drawing of a buttoned-down <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON>, who declined to seek a second term in 1928. <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON>, mayor of <LOCATION> Northampton </LOCATION> in 1909, would n't have much of a constituency now, said <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kotfila </PERSON>, who started the run as part of a Coolidgefest in 1983 on the 50th anniversary of the 30th <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president's death. `` He was really an amazing, witty man, who held every elected office from city councilor to mayor to state legislator, governor, vice president and president. And here, in his adopted home, we did n't even have a monument.'' There was opposition to the festival, <PERSON> Kotfila </PERSON> said. `` I think there may be three Republicans left in town and one of them is in bad health,'' he said. `` A lot of people found it hard to believe that we were trying to resurrect <PERSON> Coolidge </PERSON> and thought we should leave well enough alone.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0104EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Women'sCaucus     08-05 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Women's Caucus,0555</SECOND>
<HEAD>Abortion Rights Battle Poses Risks, Opportunities, Female Politicians
Told</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY R. SANDOK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. PAUL, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Renewed threats to abortion rights should be viewed as a significant opportunity to unify the women's movement, speakers told the National Women's Political Caucus `` We must bring the same spirit to the fight for abortion rights that we brought to the fight for the ERA -LRB- Equal Rights Amendment -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Holmes </PERSON> <PERSON> Norton </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Georgetown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> law professor, told the caucus' biennial convention on Friday. `` That means leaving no state unturned. It means the same grunt work this caucus did in state after state for the ERA. There is no shortcut, no magic pill, no easy way,'' she said. `` Ironically, despite internal and perhaps inevitable disagreement over tactics, this issue can and will bring greater unity.'' <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> congresswoman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and a founder of the 18-year-old caucus, said they expect abortion will be the issue that prompts young women to join the fight for women's rights in numbers not seen since the movement's peak during the 1970s It presents `` an opportunity to revitalize the movement so it may complete the mammoth job that remains to secure women their rights and their freedoms,'' said <PERSON> Norton </PERSON>, former chairwoman of the <ORGANIZATION> Equal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opportunities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Norton </PERSON> said the caucus `` must not underestimate the need for a resilient, confident mass movement of broad appeal if we are to prevail on the troublesome issue of reproductive choices.'' But, she added, `` we must avoid the single-issue ... approach of the anti-choice crowd'' when seeking to stop efforts to impose abortion restrictions authorized by a recent <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision. <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> said the threat of abortion restrictions will mobilize the nation's young people like no issue since the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War: `` Abortion is the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> of this generation for young people everywhere.'' A woman's right to decide whether to have children `` free from intrusion or coercion by government or church or the outright violence of any individual is as precious and individual a liberty as the right to speak and the right to believe and the right to pray,'' <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> said. Without the free exercise of that right, she said, `` no woman can be deemed to be fully free or equal.'' `` The idea that the unborn fetus is -LRB- entitled to -RRB- protection from the moment of conception is biologically ignorant and philosophically outrageous,'' <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> said. `` No civilized nation can be allowed to declare an unborn fetus to be a person under the Constitution before women are declared to be persons under the Constitution.'' Although the number of women holding elective and appointive offices has increased during the past two decades, the gains have been incremental, <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> said. `` At the rate we're going it will take 410 years to get equal numbers of men and women in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said. `` We have ... allowed ourselves to lower our sights and lower our demands. I believe we have to begin thinking in new ways.'' <PERSON> Abzug </PERSON> suggested asking both political parties to commit all open seats to women until equity is reached in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> House and pursuing the idea of having one of each state's two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senators be a woman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-WallaceSmith     08-05 0225</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Wallace Smith,0230</SECOND>
<HEAD>W. Wallace Smith, Former President of RLDS Leader Is Dead at 88</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INDEPENDENCE, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, former president and prophet of the Reorganized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints, died Friday. He was 88. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was the grandson of <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, founder of the RLDS, and the father of <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, the current president of the church, which has about 1,000 congregations and 150,000 members. <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was ordained the fifth president of the <ORGANIZATION> RLDS </ORGANIZATION> in October 1958 and became president-emeritus in 1978. He was replaced by his son as president. The church was formed when the Mormons split into several factions, the largest of which followed <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Young </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, following religious persecution in 1844. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> expanded the RLDS into other cultures and countries during his 20 years as president. The church was established in 15 countries when he took over, and congregations opened in 20 more countries during his tenure. In addition to his son, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> is survived by a daughter, <PERSON> Rosalee </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> <PERSON> Elser </PERSON>. His wife, <PERSON> Rosamond </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunnell </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, died in August 1986. The church said his body will lie in state in the conference chamber of the RLDS Auditorium in Independence for public viewing on Tuesday. Funeral services will be conducted at the auditorium at 10 a.m. Wednesday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0633EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d e BC-Jazz     08-05 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Jazz,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Billie Holiday Remembrance Opens `Classical Jazz'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer Billie Holiday and tenor saxophonist <PERSON> Lester </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> were remembered by three singers and three tenor players at the opening of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s third annual `` Classical Jazz'' series. The first of six concerts, each centered around outstanding figures from the history of jazz, was sold out Friday night at <ORGANIZATION> Alice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tully </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION>. The performers were <PERSON> Abby </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> with <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Heath </PERSON>, <PERSON> Etta </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> with <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Person </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> with <LOCATION> Buck </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>, who had the longest set, has an individual timbre, sounding not at all like Billie Holiday. Her delivery is warm, open and generous. She seems a balance of tough and vulnerable and she seems to be giving of herself. She's mesmerizing, pulling the audience with her into the world of Billie Holiday's songs. <PERSON> Heath </PERSON> and each member of Miss <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON>'s trio stretched out in interesting solos. <PERSON> Etta </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> <PERSON> Person </PERSON>, who have been performing together since 1976, have their pattern set with his sax providing melodic fills between her lines of singing. Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> wraps her words and syllables around the instrumental music, the way Miss Holiday did. She also had a trio on stage. Pianist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Braham </PERSON> captured the imagination. <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Horn </PERSON> played her own piano accompaniment, with bassist and drummer. <PERSON> Buck </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> played saxophone with them on every other song. Miss <PERSON> Horn </PERSON>'s approach is lightness. If the other two singers were airplanes, she was a glider, touching down occasionally. Then right away, and in no hurry, she'd lift off again.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0015EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HurricaneDean 1stLd-Writethru a0683 08-05 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hurricane Dean, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0683,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hurricane Dean Drifts North Away from Islands</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf with 10:30 p.m. EDT position.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hurricane Dean drifted northward Friday in the open <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> after veering away from northern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> islands and the southeastern <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>, forecasters said. `` It may strengthen a little bit. There are changes that are taking place around it,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheets </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>. At 10:30 p.m. EDT, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>'s winds of 85 mph were centered near 23.0 north latitude and 64.91 <LOCATION> west </LOCATION> <LOCATION> longitude </LOCATION>, about 600 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. The hurricane was moving north at about 12 mph, forecasters said. `` Our latest reconnaissance positions indicate that indeed it may start a little bit more fast speed toward the north, and you can see that on the satellite,'' Sheets said. A weakening of upper atmosphere currents that steer the storm kept <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> away from the islands Thursday, after it initially headed toward the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. The hurricane was moving very slowly. `` We're still expecting it to turn to the north and then eventually go to the northeast,'' said forecaster <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Gross </PERSON>. Asked about the storm's potential for hitting <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION> in about three days, he said: `` They're very easy to miss.'' The second hurricane of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> season became a tropical storm Monday night and was reclassified a hurricane Tuesday when its maximum sustained wind speed passed 74 mph.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0113EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names CORRECTIVE   08-05 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, CORRECTIVE,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: Members who used the second item in PM-Names, a0421, of Aug.
4 under a Los Angeles dateline are asked to use the following story.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously reported Friday that jurors found divorce attorney <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> innocent in a civil lawsuit filed by a former client who had accused him of legal malpractice in her 1984 divorce case. The verdict was actually a two-part ruling. Jurors found that <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> had failed to exercise the care and skill ordinarily used by an attorney in such cases. But the jury refused to assess any damages against <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON>, ruling that his failure had not injured his former client. In a separate finding, jurors denied a counter-suit filed by <PERSON> Mitchelson </PERSON> seeking unpaid legal fees for handling the divorce case.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SouthAfrica     08-05 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-South Africa,0724</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Apartheid Groups Regain Offensive With Defiance Campaign</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sidestepping an array of state-of-emergency bans, the militant core of the anti-apartheid movement is back on the offensive with a defiance campaign that has government leaders groping for a response. Crushing the campaign by force could wreck the government's ongoing initiatives to improve its international standing Allowing unchecked civil disobedience could fuel widespread black activism and a white backlash against the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in advance of parliamentary elections next month. The campaign, launched Wednesday when about 270 blacks and <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION> sought and received treatment at segregated white hospitals, is led by many of the activists who have been detained or restricted during the 3-year-old state of emergency. `` People have decided to take the matter into their own hands,'' said <PERSON> Essa </PERSON> <PERSON> Moosa </PERSON>, a lawyer involved in the campaign. The campaign's leaders have designated themselves and their various organizations as the <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, a loose alliance which in effect takes the place of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> UDF </ORGANIZATION> was banned in February 1988, and by late last year, activists were conceding that the emergency crackdown had seriously weakened their organizational prowess. The first sign of a resurgence came in January, when <ORGANIZATION> UDF </ORGANIZATION> affiliates helped organize hunger strikes by hundreds of detained black activists. Faced with the prospect of detainees starving to death without ever being charged, the government chose to free virtually all those held under emergency regulations. Now comes the defiance campaign, which envisions the first sustained use of mass civil disobedience in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since the 1950s. Its masterminds are activists who have proved their resilience and persistence. Two of the <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>'s key leaders are <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morobe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mohammed </PERSON> <PERSON> Valli </PERSON> <PERSON> Moosa </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> UDF </ORGANIZATION> officials who escaped from detention to sanctuary at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Consulate last year. The government allowed them to emerge without the restrictions imposed on many other <ORGANIZATION> UDF </ORGANIZATION> leaders. Another key component of the new movement is the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African Trade Unions, the main black labor federation, which has defied a government decree barring it from political activity. The government may have trouble responding decisively to the defiance campaign because of a partial power vaccuum at the top. President P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> will retire after the Sept. 6 election, and neither he nor his designated successor, F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, has been eager to make bold moves in recent weeks. The government's point man in coping with the defiance campaign is Law and Order Minister <PERSON> Adriaan </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON>. He asserted last month the organizers sought to provoke violence and had endorsed hand-grenade attacks on election candidates. The Mass Democratic Movement denied the allegations and mocked <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> after the hospital protest proceeded peacefully, with minimal disruption to health services. <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> belittled the protest as `` political pestering'' but said further acts of defiance `` are a time-bomb that could explode at any moment.'' Health Minister <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Niekerk </PERSON> complained that sick blacks had been used as pawns and said no hospitals elsewhere in `` the civilized world'' would be targeted by protesters. Anti-apartheid leaders agreed, saying no civilized country's hospitals would be racially segregated. The Mass Democratic Movement says the defiance campaign will be extended soon to other targets, possibly segregated schools and recreation facilities. <LOCATION> Mineworkers </LOCATION> have begun protesting workplace segregation and 17 former detainees in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> said they would defy the restrictions imposed when they were freed. The Citizen, a pro-government newspaper, conceded in an editorial Friday the activists `` scored a propaganda victory, highlighting segregation at white hospitals, issuing defiant statements and challenging the authorities without suffering any serious consequences.'' The Citizen said the government might regret its decision to avoid a pre-emptive crackdown on the protest's organizers. The government's dilemma has been aggravated by the fact that its current policy documents repudiate racial discrimination. <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> himself declared during the week that `` apartheid is no longer the policy of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>.'' If <PERSON> Vlok </PERSON> was speaking the truth, said <LOCATION> Morobe </LOCATION>, then the defiance campaign would only be of help.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Crary </PERSON>, news editor at the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> bureau </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, has been reporting from <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0141EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StateFair-Disturbance     08-05 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-State Fair-Disturbance,0280</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dozens Injured When Crowd Presses into Concert Grandstand</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 50 people were injured when a crowd trying to get into a standing-room-only area for a Friday evening grandstand concert at the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> State </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION> pressed into the area before it was opened. State Highway Patrol troopers at the scene said most of the injuries were minor. <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, director of public relations, said 58 people were treated at the fair; about a dozen later were taken to hospitals. Doctors' Hospital North nursing supervisor <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Crader </PERSON> said eight teen-agers were treated for minor injuries. `` I think there was one broken foot, but it was pretty minor stuff. There were varying complaints,'' she said. After the disturbance, Gov. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> met with fair officials and managers of the acts scheduled to appear Friday night. Following the meeting, the manager for one of the acts, New Kids on the Block, announced that the entertainment would be presented one act at a time, and if authorities felt the crowd was getting unruly, the rest of the show would be canceled. After the announcement, <PERSON> Celeste </PERSON> walked along the perimeter of the grandstand, telling concertgoers to `` Be cool and pass it back.'' Trooper <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Esslinger </PERSON> said he could not estimate the size of the crowd for the 8 p.m. concert. The crowd had been building all day, and the grandstand was largely filled by late afternoon, witnesses said. The standing-room-only area had not been opened when the crowd broke for the seats, witnesses said. A thunderstorm broke shortly after the crowd rushed into the area, adding to the confusion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0026EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>b w AM-S&amp;Ls 8thLd-Writethru 2Takes 08-05 0801</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-S&amp;Ls, 8th Ld-Writethru, 2 Takes,a0409-a0411-a0782,690-1,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Passes S&amp;L Bailout</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Combines pvs; raising grafs 9-10 of 7th Ld bgng: ``The bill,''
to grafs 4-5 to bring explanation of bill higher; INSERTS graf 7: ``Republicans
in,'' with party breakdown. Should stand for AMs. A roll call will move.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed and sent to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> early Saturday a landmark savings and loan bailout providing tens of billions of dollars to cover the losses of savers whose deposits disappeared in a wave of fraudulent lending. By 201-175, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed the $ 159 billion financial rescue _ the biggest in the nation's history _ following a frantic 48 hours of negotiations between <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved the measure only two hours earlier, giving President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a victory on his first and biggest legislative initiative since taking office last January as <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> recesses for a month. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had agreed in advance to the compromise, the second in as many days. The bill provides $ 50 billion over the next three years to close and merge 500 insolvent S & amp; Ls and pay off savers whose billions of dollars in government insured deposits were lost to failed and often fraudulent loans, most of them in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. It also totally overhauls the regulation of the industry to try to fulfill <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s promise that `` never again'' will taxpayers be asked to pay for losses. S & amp; L owners will be required to put billions of dollars more of their own money at risk as a buffer between risky loans and the federal deposit insurance funds. The administration lobbied <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans throughout the day to provide the winning margin as Democrats defected from the bill in large numbers in response to a compromise hiding most of the cleanup costs off the budget and out of the official federal deficit. Republicans in the House supported the bill 119-40 while Democrats opposed it 135-82. Fifty-one members did not vote and five voted `` present.'' Rep. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., accused <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members of losing their conscience and their backbone in bowing to a veto threat from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and agreeing to financing the bulk of the bailout's costs through 30-year bonds `` It should have been paid for by taxes, but the president could not bring himself to say the word,'' said <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>. `` So we have fostered this unconscionable debt on our children and grandchildren.'' But with the losses of federally insured deposits mounting at a rate of $ 20 million to $ 30 million a day, supporters said it would be equally unconscionable for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to go on vacation without fixing the problem. `` I for one do n't want to take the chance of another bank-holiday crisis,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Chalmers </PERSON> <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, referring to the wave of bank closings at the end of the <PERSON> Hoover </PERSON> administration in early 1933 that deepened the Great Depression. `` The alternative are unthinkable,'' added Rep. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Texas </LOCATION>. `` The savings of million of Americans are at stake unless we do something,'' Sen. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON>, D-Mo., said just before the unusual `` divison'' vote in which supporters and opponents indicate their position by standing The procedure leaves no record of who votes yes or no. But four senators stood in opposition and three others asked to be recorded as opponents. They were Sens. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Kent </PERSON> <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON>, D-N.D.; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grassley </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Neb </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Ky.; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, R-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION> `` I think it is the best bill possible to craft under the circumstances,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the `` It will make major reforms in every area.'' President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was on the phone with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> members from both parties throughout the day, according to sources, pleading for support. And Treasury Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> was dispatched to the <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> to negotiate a resolve to the impasse. <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, a former appointed Republican senator from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, spent nearly an hour on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor lobbying former colleagues. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> took the bill the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor only after <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, reached an accord on off-budget bonds <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> had demanded that the off-budget bonds to be used for much of the financing be registered with the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> as carrying a risk higher than normal government securities. He and <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> agreed that the <ORGANIZATION> SEC </ORGANIZATION> may demand full disclosure to investors of risks but the bill does not require registration. <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> earlier Friday joined with three other committee chairmen to oppose the Thursday accord _ Reps. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, D-Calif. and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, D-Mich.. <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON> leads the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Rostenskowski </PERSON> chairs <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON> is in charge of Budget and <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON> heads
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HUDProbe 1stLd-Writethru a0659 08-05 0490</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Probe, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0659,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pierce Friends and Foes Sought His Favor, Reports Show</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: INSERTS two grafs after 6th graf pvs, In its, with NY Times
report; picks up 7th graf pvs, The newspapers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The crowd of people seeking favors from former Housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> included his successor and one of his most vocal critics in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, according to reports published Friday. Four-dozen boxes of documents from <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s eight-year tenure at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> contained mounds of requests for his time or help, the reports said. The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and The <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Street </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>, citing documents obtained under the Freedom of Information Act, report that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> became involved in selected cases at the behest of political associates. In testimony before a congressional subcommittee in May, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he did n't do special favors for consultants or developers and had merely instructed subordinates to give personal requests `` careful consideration.'' Among the documents released to the newspapers were numerous letters asking <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> for help or thanking him for the department's approval of one project or another The reports did not specify in every case whether <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> himself interceded on behalf of those who sought his help. According to the Journal, among those who wrote <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> were <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, the current <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> secretary who at the time was a congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>; former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Caspar </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberger </PERSON>; Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>; and Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Democrat who has been one of the most outspoken critics in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> of the influence peddling that existed at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s tenure In its Saturday editions, the Times said the documents also showed <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials withheld from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> records that showed the extent of political favoritism in the award of federal subsidies for low-income housing. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON>, R-Pa., asked <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in early 1988 for two years of records on the awarding of the subsidies The documents show <PERSON> Heinz </PERSON> was given data only for a four-month period after the program had been revised to curb political abuses, the Times said. The newspapers quoted a letter from <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Watt </PERSON>, in which the former <ORGANIZATION> interior </ORGANIZATION> secretary thanked <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> for his support of a suburban <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> housing project that was awarded $ 28 million in Section 8 moderate rehabilitation funds in May 1986. <PERSON> Watt </PERSON> was paid $ 300,000 by the developer of the project to help obtain money from Housing and Urban Development and, according to previous testimony, had met with <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> to discuss the project. `` Thanks!'' <PERSON> Watt </PERSON> wrote to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> on June 6, 1986. `` You are a man of your word.'' Asked for comment by the Times, <PERSON> Watt </PERSON> referred to his congressional testimony last spring in which he said his contacts with <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> were proper. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> faces no charges of wrongdoing, but congressional investigators have questioned the truthfulness of some of his testimony. The <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> could not be reached for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CliffSatire     08-05 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cliff Satire,0705</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cliff'shanger: Publisher Fights Injunction Against Cliff's Notes
Satire</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY SCHWARTZ</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge has issued a succinct order to the creators of a parody of Cliff's Notes, the yellow-and-black booklets that have aided generations of struggling students by condensing <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON>, <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> and <PERSON> Milton </PERSON>: Change it. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Wohl </PERSON> <PERSON> Kram </PERSON> ruled this week that the upcoming satire looks too much like the real thing, and that the parodists can not use any cover that might be confused with <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON>'s Notes The decision was described as unprecedented by <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Trager </PERSON>, lawyer for the parody's publisher, <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON>. She moved to seek an expedited appeal of the ruling, as well as an immediate stay. `` If this ruling is upheld, it will deal a significant blow to free speech and First Amendment liberties and will endanger the viability of parody as a literary form,'' said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, president and publisher of Doubleday. Ms. <PERSON> Trager </PERSON> said that although the judge did not enjoin the production of any parody, her restrictions on the cover meant exactly that. Recreating the appearance of the subject is `` the essence of parody,'' she said, and a parody of Cliff's Notes without a yellow-and-black cover would be like a parody of Time magazine without a red border up front. The satire, `` Spy Notes,'' was produced by the editors of Spy magazine, a brash <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> humor monthly, and was to reach bookstore shelves next month. It ridicules and boils down trendy best sellers like `` Bright Lights, <LOCATION> Big </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>,'' `` Slaves of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'' and `` Less Than Zero.'' Like this on `` Less Than Zero'' _ `` Clay meets <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> and Rip at a nightclub called The Roxy. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> takes them all to see a dead body in an alleyway. Then they all go to Rip's house, where there is a delirious, naked 12-year-old girl tied to a bed.'' It also offers `` Questions for Review,'' `` Biographical Notes'' and `` Suggestions for Further Reading,'' mostly a listing of gossip-column appearances of authors <PERSON> Bret </PERSON> <PERSON> Easton </PERSON> <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> McInerney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tama </PERSON> <PERSON> Janowitz </PERSON>. The cover is yellow with black stripes, and the titles of the `` summarized'' works are in the same block letters used on Cliff's Notes covers But instead of the mountain depicted in the lower right corner of real Cliff's Notes, Spy Notes features a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> skyline. In addition, the words `` A SATIRE'' are printed nine times in pink letters on the Spy Notes cover. After Cliff's <ORGANIZATION> Notes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> learned of Spy's plans, the company went to court to seek an injunction against the parody's cover. Cliff's claimed the parody was a trademark violation which would confuse the public. The company's product has been used by generations of college and high school students who either failed to read assigned works or failed to understand them. In its complaint, Cliff's Notes noted `` the excellence of its literary works'' gave it `` an outstanding reputation and acceptance among members of the public throughout the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' The judge said she disagreed with <PERSON> Doubleday </PERSON>'s theory that `` the First Amendment gives the parodist unbridled freedom to use a registered trademark as part of a parody or satire.'' She found that the Spy Notes cover design and Cliff's Notes trademark cover `` are similar to a degree that would cause consumer confusion.'' `` Consumers could believe that <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON>'s was satirizing Spy, that Spy was a division of Cliff's, or that <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON>'s licensed Spy,'' she said. The judge agreed with <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON>'s that Spy Notes `` goes far beyond ` conjuring up' the Cliff's Notes image, and instead merely copies it with minor differences added in an attempt to avoid trademark violations.'' <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, lawyer for Cliff's, said his client `` is as much entitled to the First Amendment protection as Doubleday is. It would be a perverse injustice if someone in the name of the First Amendment was able to take a trademarked cover design and be immune from liability.'' <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON>, co-editor of Spy, said the judge's ruling defied understanding. `` It's a shocking and puzzling decision ...,'' he said. `` I do n't see how anyone could possibly confuse the two.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AIDSTest     08-05 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Test,0437</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Early-Diagnosis Test Finds AIDS Virus Instead of Body's Reaction</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRENDA C. COLEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Abbott </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratories </ORGANIZATION> is marketing a new test that detects the AIDS virus rather than the body's response to the virus and can reveal infection weeks earlier than currently used tests, the company said Friday. AIDS-virus tests now in use detect the presence of antibodies _ proteins manufactured by white blood cells to fight invading organisms. Antibodies usually appear in a person's system six to 10 weeks after infection. The new test detects AIDS antigens _ proteins on the surface of the invading virus. The new test can signal the presence of the antigens about two weeks after infection, a spokesman for the North Chicago-based company said. ` This test complements the antibody test. It does not replace the antibody test,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>, associate professor of medicine and director of the HIV treatment program at Rush-Presbyterian-St. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Medical Center Test was approved Thursday for commercial sale by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, making it the only approved test for the AIDS virus in the country. Though antigens are the first detectable sign of infection, they effectively `` disappear'' with the appearance of antibodies, which remain in the body. The antigen test is thus not always able to reveal the presence of infection. Antigens only reappear when the virus becomes more active, a possible signal that the infected person will get sick, either with immune problems, with a mild form of AIDS known as AIDS-related complex or with full-blown AIDS, said <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON>. To identify which infected people are likely to develop symptoms _ some may be infected for years without any symptoms _ doctors can check patients with the new test every three or four months, said <PERSON> Abbott </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>. `` If you come up where the antigen test is positive, that might be the opportune moment to intervene with AZT or some form of antiviral therapy,'' <PERSON> Weber </PERSON> said. AZT, or zidovudine, is the only drug approved by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> for fighting AIDS. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said antigen-positive patients have a 75 percent chance of developing symptoms, compared with 29 percent for antigen-negative patients. The new test, available under the trade name HIV AG-1, is already under manufacture because is has previously been used to monitor the effectiveness of AZT. It will continue to be valuable for that purpose, <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Kessler </PERSON> said the test will probably cost $ 100 to $ 120 at the lab, which is `` not out of line'' with other laboratory tests for viruses.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CongressRdp 3rdLd-Writethru a0785 08-05 0923</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0785,870</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Passes $159 Billion Bailout For Thrifts</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: LEADS with 4 grafs to raisee S&amp;L legislation, approved in both
the House and Senate; Picks up 5th graf pvs, bgng, While Congress, xxx</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> approved an historic savings and loan rescue plan early Saturday after the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> overwhelmingly approved a $ 286.5 billion military spending bill, ignoring President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s veto threat. In the rush to complete its work before a monthlong recess, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed the compromise $ 159 billion savings and loan bailout plan and sent it to the House. The S & amp; L vote in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> on President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s first and biggest legislative initiative was anti-climactic, without even a roll call. A sharply divided <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> passed the bill 201-175 just moments after midnight. At the outset of its more than 15-hour lawmaking marathon, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted 312-105 to adopt military appropriations legislation. The measure would cut $ 1.8 billion from <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, strictly curtail production of the B-2 bomber and eliminate all funds for the Midgetman nuclear missile, the advanced tactical fighter and cruise missile. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has threatened to veto the bill. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> also passed legislation on financial liability for oil spills, aid to farmers hit by the drought and a temporary $ 70 billion extension to the $ 2.8 trillion federal debt limit, which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> had approved earlier. While <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> pushed for speedy action on a series of bills, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> complained to <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, about <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> delays on 120 of his appointments. `` The president wanted to register his deep concern that these were being held up for artificial reasons not related to the candidates themselves,'' presidential press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters at the White House. The `` artificial reasons,'' according to administration officials and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., are party politics Among the nominations the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has not yet acted on are <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s selection of <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON>, who has been linked to the Iran-Contra affair, as ambassador to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and several nominees to the scandal-plagued <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> Away from the legislative action and White House complaints, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee said it had decided to investigate three lawmakers accused of sexual improprieties. The committee voted in secret session Thursday to conduct preliminary inquiries into the conduct of Reps. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill.; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buz'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, D-Calif. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> was convicted in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> on a misdemeanor charge of contributing to the unruliness of a He was sentenced June 30 to 180 days in jail and fined $ 1,000 for having sex with a teen-age girl. Two former aides to <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> have filed a complaint alleging he sexually harassed female members of his staff. Three Democrats filed a complaint against <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> after news reports said a Peace Corps volunteer complained the congressman fondled her while he was traveling in <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, D-Minn., disclosed that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee has completed a preliminary inquiry of his previously disclosed book contract that an opponent claimed was a device to circumvent limits on fee income The senator said the committee had decided to proceed with its investigation. The last major legislative battle before the recess concerned the thrift bailout. A tenuous compromise with the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration, agreed to late Thursday night, was threatened as key House Democrats announced opposition. In particular, they objected to financing provisions that would keep much of the cost of the bailout outs they said, add substantially to the overall expense to be borne by taxpayers. With savings and loan losses mounting at a rate of $ 20 million or more a day, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wrote to the lawmakers, `` Final passage remains critical to the stability and solvency of the financial system.'' The landmark bill would close or merge hundreds of insolvent savings institutions. Setting the stage for the difficult task of deciding the S & amp; L bailout, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> moved quickly on the defense appropriations bill that largely conformed to the military authorization plan passed by the chamber last week. Despite word from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> budget office that the president's senior advisers would recommend a veto, and a similar assessment from the ranking Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the chamber gave overwhelming approval to the plan. In fact, the vote for the appropriations plan _ 312-105 _ amounted to a stronger statement than the 261-162 approval of the authorization bill. `` They have conformed,'' Rep. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, ranking <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> member on <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said of the two pieces of legislation. `` But that still makes it veto-bait in my opinion.'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said he hoped that when members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> meet early in September to craft a final version of the bill, the `` most egregious add-ons and deletions can be modified and limited to make it acceptable to the administration.'' Among the other final-day action taken by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 99-0 to increase industry's financial liability for oil spills, create a nationwide system to clean up such accidents and establish a $ 1 billion trust fund to help compensate for damages The vote came less than five months after the tanker <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> struck a reef in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>, spilling 11 million gallons of oil. _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved a compromise plan providing $ 895 million to farmers who suffered crop losses caused by the drought and other weather-related problems <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials have indicated that the president will sign the legislation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0205EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Potty-TrainingDeath     08-05 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Potty-Training Death,0384</SECOND>
<HEAD>HRS Workers Punished in 2-Year-Old's Death</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three state child-welfare workers were suspended and a fourth has quit following the death of a 2-year-old boy whose parents allegedly dunked him repeatedly in a toilet for soiling his diapers. The workers ignored guidelines in returning <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> to his mother and stepfather, ignoring warnings that they were abusing the boy, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rehabilitative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> said Friday. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> died of a brain hemorrhage July 28, shortly after the HRS workers returned the boy to his parents from foster care. <PERSON> Sheryl </PERSON> <PERSON> McGee </PERSON> <PERSON> Coe </PERSON>, 20, and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Coe </PERSON>, 22, both of <LOCATION> Lakeland </LOCATION>, were held without bond Friday facing first-degree murder charges in the case. HRS Secretary <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Coler </PERSON> said he was upset that the staffers recommended the child be returned to the Coes despite the abuse reports and their failure to fulfill an agreement to attend drug-abuse counseling. `` We're not talking about facts that were n't known or somebody who did n't show up somewhere or that the information was n't there,'' <PERSON> Coler </PERSON> said Thursday, the day of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s funeral `` We're talking about people not following procedure. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was taken from the Coes' custody in March 1988 after HRS officials said the Coes had been negligent. He was returned to them in late May despite the warnings of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s foster parents, the <LOCATION> Kirklands </LOCATION>. The foster parents said they repeatedly told HRS workers that they feared <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> would be in danger if returned to the Coes. Three child-welfare workers involved in the case, case worker <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Barber </PERSON>, her supervisor <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, and subdistrict administrator <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> McFadyen </PERSON>, have been put on a 10-day, paid leave. Case worker <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> DuBoise </PERSON> quit, <ORGANIZATION> HRS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Konicki </PERSON> said Thursday. After a closed meeting Friday with angry parents in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, HRS district administrator <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON> said HRS has `` got to intensify the review effort of supervisors in high-level supervision, so we fully understand the complexities in the case.'' The parents who requested the meeting have been protesting for the past several days in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> with placards in the downtown area, criticizing HRS' handling of such cases. They also held a candlelight ceremony along the <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> riverfront Thursday night on behalf of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and other child-abuse victims.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-F-16Suit 1stLd-Writethru a0796 08-05 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-F-16 Suit, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0796,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Appeals Court Overturns Multi-Million Dollar Verdict</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 3 grafs to CORRECT time element to Monday, sted Friday;
picks up 3rd graf: `The judgment ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A $ 3.1 million judgment won by the widow of an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> pilot killed in an F-16 jet crash in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> more than six years ago has been overturned by a three-judge federal appeals court panel. The widow, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Harduvel </PERSON> of <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON>, can petition the full 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> to reconsider the case. If the request is refused, she has said she plans to appeal to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. Retired <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> served on the appellate panel and wrote its opinion released Monday. The judgment was rendered by a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jury in April 1987 against <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION>, the F-16 fighter jet contractor, on the grounds that the plane was defectively designed and manufactured. Mrs. <PERSON> Harduvel </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Acosta </PERSON>, told the appeals panel the plane had a severe electrical malfunction causing the crash into a mountain that killed Capt. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Harduvel </PERSON> in November 1982. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Dumbroff </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-based attorney representing <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION>, asked for a reversal, contending the crash was a result of pilot error. The panel rejected the argument that there were defects in the designing and building of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>'s newest jet fighter and overturned the lower court verdict.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FreudLibel     08-05 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Freud Libel,0579</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Appeals Court Upholds Fabrication of Quotes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB EGELKO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A psychologist intends to appeal a federal court ruling that allows a journalist quoting a public figure to make up a quote if the quote does not `` alter the substantive content'' of what was said. The 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled on Friday that <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Masson </PERSON>, a former director of the <ORGANIZATION> Freud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>, could not sue writer <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> for $ 10.2 million over a <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yorker </ORGANIZATION> magazine article and book that allegedly quoted him as saying many things he never said. The purported quotes included <PERSON> Masson </PERSON>'s self-description as an `` intellectual gigolo,'' his comment that after <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON> <PERSON> Freud </PERSON> he would be regarded as `` the greatest analyst who ever lived,'' and a statement that he would have turned the <PERSON> Freud </PERSON> house into `` a place of sex, women, fun.'' In a libel suit by a public figure, who must prove that harmful statements were deliberately or recklessly false, quotations can be fabricated if they are `` rational interpretations of ambiguous remarks'' or `` do not alter the substantive content of unambiguous remarks,'' said the opinion by Judge <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Alarcon </PERSON>. He was joined in his opinion by Judge <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Holcomb </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. But the dissenter in the 2-1 decision, Judge <PERSON> Alex </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozinski </PERSON>, said fabricated quotes were the equivalent of lies. `` If authors are given license to invent quotations on the basis of what they perceive to be a speaker's character, there are no words whatsoever that they can not put into a subject's mouth,'' <PERSON> Kozinski </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON>, lawyer for <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> and her publishers, said the ruling vindicates his clients. He said they never conceded that any quotes had been made up or changed, other than `` a word here and a word there.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleven </PERSON>, a lawyer for <PERSON> Masson </PERSON>, said the ruling would be appealed. `` We do n't think there's any need to allow that sort of alteration to protect the values that the First Amendment is designed to protect,'' he said. <PERSON> Masson </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> resident, was fired in 1981 as director of the New York-based <ORGANIZATION> Freud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>. He said he was fired and fell out of favor among psychoanalysts because he had written that <PERSON> Freud </PERSON>, the father of modern pscyhoanalysis, knew the evidence was to the contrary when he declared that women usually fantasized claims of childhood sexual abuse. His suit attacked <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON>'s 1983 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yorker </ORGANIZATION> article, `` Trouble in the Archives,'' and her 1984 book, `` In the <ORGANIZATION> Freud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Archives </ORGANIZATION>,'' on the struggle between <PERSON> Masson </PERSON> and directors of the archives over his views on <PERSON> Freud </PERSON>. <PERSON> Masson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> had maliciously painted a false picture of him by fabricating quotes, citing numerous statements that were not in her tape-recorded interviews. He also said he notified the New Yorker and the book publisher of the fabrications before publication. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON> dismissed the suit in 1987. An appeals court upheld his ruling. <PERSON> Kozinski </PERSON>, in his dissent, said the quotes distorted <PERSON> Masson </PERSON>'s taped statements: for example, he never called himself the greatest analyst, just the only one who held his views In addition, <PERSON> Kozinski </PERSON> said, journalists are supposed to vouch for the accuracy of the quotes they use. He also quoted <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Shawn </PERSON>, editor of the New Yorker at the time of <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON>'s articles, as calling the magazine `` the most accurate publication not only in this country, but in the entire world.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0211EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hostages-Excerpts     08-05 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hostages-Excerpts,0769</SECOND>
<HEAD>Excerpts from Rafsanjani's Speech</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Hostages, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Excerpts from the prayer sermon by new Iranian President <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>. Friday's speech in <LOCATION> Farsi </LOCATION> was broadcast by <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio and translated by The Associated Press in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 One of the most vociferous, revealing and at the same time very ugly events this week took place in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. This can reveal the face of the hegemonistic powers of the world. See how ugly the issue is. A country by the name of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, which is from the root up an usurper, officially enters a town with military forces, with a helicopter, and takes the Friday prayer leader of the town along with two of his security men. This is not at all acceptable by any international standard, and no country can say this is right. No international law can condone this action. A country can not enter another country, kidnap and leave ... and then confess to it. OK, it used to do this and not confess, it would deny it. This was n't boastfulness. It was a crime, but not boasting. But it confessed. It announced. This is to make a laughingstock of all those individuals who adhere by international laws. What happened in return? Some innocent people, whose identity is n't even known. A number of unknown people combating covertly, announced that a person they had -LRB- been keeping -RRB- as a spy had been killed. They hanged him in revenge. Their reason was that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s agent, and we will take our revenge on this American person whom we have captive, and who is implicated in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s crime, in return for Mr. <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON> <PERSON> Karim </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>. This was what they said. Then they threatened that they would kill the rest -LRB- of the hostages -RRB- too, if you do n't free <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON>. ...
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 So what should we do in this situation? Here there is one clear point and a somber point: The clear point is that a government has officially confessed, confessed to all about its crime. The somber point is that a group has killed someone, who may be innocent, but we do n't know, therefore we will not make any judgment on this. We do n't even know who he is, and so we do n't make any judgment And we do n't know this group either, whether they are righteous people or not, who they are. We only know only that the people of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> are innocent people. And innocent people can not be condemned without reason. ...
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Global arrogance -LRB- The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> -RRB-, if it wanted to do something, it would have been clear: It should take <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> by the collar and say free <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> so that the issue is finished. If you take a criminal and ask him to stop his crimes, this is popular in the world. They might say, `` No, this does n't concern us and we are no match for <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>.'' This is not acceptable to us. No one accepts this. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> itself does not accept this, the people of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> do n't accept this. If <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> really wants to stop <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> it must announce, it must say, `` Until <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Obeid </PERSON> is freed <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> aid will be stopped.'' This Congress that convenes in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, these bigwigs that sit and vote there, this is the way you should vote. Why do you think so crookedly, and speak so arrogantly? Instead of going after a self-confessed, known, boastful criminal, you order that your warships gather from around the world toward innocent <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. ...
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 What kind of idiots are you? See how ugly the world is? See how the idiotic are the politicians who rule the world? If they want to solve the problems of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> there are ways, the ways are clear; they do n't want to solve the problems, they are not prepared to stop backing Maronite rule in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. They are still hoping, waiting for the day to have a Maronite <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. One Jewish <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>, one Maronite <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. ...
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 I state, I tell the White House, the problem of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> has solutions, the freeing of the hostages has solutions, reasonable, prudent solutions. These bullyings, arrogant approaches and tyranny will not solve the problems. Come let us enter reasonably, we too will help solve the problems there, so the people of the region can live in peace and harmony.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0056EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-HouseS&amp;LRollCall 3Takes   08-05 0497</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House S&amp;L Roll Call, 3 Takes,</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is the 201-175 roll call Saturday by which the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> approved and sent to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a $ 159 billion bailout of the savings and loan industry. A `` yes'' vote is a vote in favor of the bill providing money to cover the losses of depositors in failed S & amp; Ls and overhaul the government's regulation of the industry. Voting yes were 82 Democrats and 119 Republicans. Voting no were 135 Democrats and 40 Republicans. X denotes those not voting. Present denotes those who voted they were `` present'' at the time of the vote but did not vote `` yes'' or `` no'' on the issue. There are 3 vacancies in the 435-member House.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALABAMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bevill </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Browder </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Erdreich </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Flippo </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ALASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARIZONA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Udall </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Kolbe </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kyl </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON>, Y; Stump, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ARKANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Hammerschmidt </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CALIFORNIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Anderson, X; <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Beilenson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Berman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Boxer </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dellums </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dymally </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Matsui </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Mineta </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Panetta </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pelosi </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Roybal </PERSON>, N; Stark, N; <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Waxman </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Dannemeyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Dornan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dreier </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gallegly </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Herger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lagomarsino </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Lowery </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCandless </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moorhead </PERSON>, N; Packard, Y; <PERSON> Pashayan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rohrabacher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shumway </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>COLORADO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Skaggs </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hefley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>CONNECTICUT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Gejdenson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kennelly </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DELAWARE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Carper, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>FLORIDA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Fascell </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gibbons </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hutto </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lehman </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bilirakis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Goss </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Grant </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> James </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McCollum </PERSON>, N; Shaw, Y; <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON>, Y; Young, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>GEORGIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Darden </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hatcher </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Jenkins </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Rowland </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y. Republican _ <PERSON> Gingrich </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>HAWAII</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Akaka </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Saiki </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IDAHO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>ILLINOIS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Annunzio </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, X; Costello, N; <PERSON> Durbin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lipinski </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Poshard </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Russo </PERSON>, N; Sangmeister, N; <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Yates </LOCATION>, N. Republicans _ Crane, N; <PERSON> Fawell </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hastert </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hyde </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Madigan </PERSON>, present; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Michel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Porter </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>INDIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Jontz </PERSON>, N; Long, N; <PERSON> McCloskey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Visclosky </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hiler </PERSON>, Y; Myers, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>IOWA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Nagle </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Grandy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lightfoot </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>KANSAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Glickman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Slattery </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Meyers </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Whittaker </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0058EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-HouseS&amp;LRollCall 1stadd   08-05 0401</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House S&amp;L Roll Call, 1st add,</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Whittaker, Y.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>KENTUCKY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Mazzoli </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Natcher </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Perkins </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bunning </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Rogers </ORGANIZATION>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>LOUISIANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hayes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Huckaby </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tauzin </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Holloway </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Livingston </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McCrery </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MAINE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Snowe </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MARYLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Byron </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Cardin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hoyer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McMillen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mfume </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bentley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Morella </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MASSACHUSETTS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Atkins </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Donnelly </PERSON>, X; Early, N; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Mavroules </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Moakley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Studds </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Conte </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MICHIGAN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Bonior </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Carr </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Conyers </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Hertel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kildee </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Traxler </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wolpe </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Broomfield </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Schuette </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Upton </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Vander </PERSON> <PERSON> Jagt </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MINNESOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Oberstar </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Penny </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Sabo </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sikorski </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Vento </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Frenzel </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Stangeland </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Weber </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSISSIPPI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Espy </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Whitten </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republican </PERSON> <PERSON> _ </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MISSOURI</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Clay, Y; <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Volkmer </PERSON>, Y; Wheat, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Buechner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Emerson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hancock </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>MONTANA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ Williams, <ORGANIZATION> X. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Marlenee </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEBRASKA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Hoagland </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Bereuter </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEVADA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Bilbray </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Y. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Vucanovich </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW HAMPSHIRE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW JERSEY</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dwyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Guarini </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Pallone </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Roe </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Torricelli </PERSON>, X. Republicans _ <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rinaldo </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Roukema </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Saxton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW MEXICO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Richardson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Y. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Schiff </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Skeen </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NEW YORK</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Ackerman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Downey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Engel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Flake </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hochbrueckner </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> LaFalce </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lowey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Manton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McHugh </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> McNulty </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Mrazek </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Nowak </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Rangel </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Scheuer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, N; Slaughter, N; <PERSON> Solarz </PERSON>, Y; Towns, N; <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Boehlert </PERSON>, Y; Fish, Y; <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Green </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Horton </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION>, Y; Lent, Y; <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> McGrath </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Molinari </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Paxon </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clarke </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Hefner </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, X; <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, X; <PERSON> Neal </PERSON>, N; Price, Y; Rose, X; Valentine, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ballenger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coble </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> McMillan </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>NORTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Dorgan </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>MORE</HEAD>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w BC-HouseS&amp;LRollCall 2ndadd   08-05 0374</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-House S&amp;L Roll Call, 2nd add,</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHN: Dorgan, N.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>OHIO</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Eckart </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Feighan </PERSON>, N; Hall, N; <LOCATION> Kaptur </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Luken </PERSON>, X; Oakar, Y; <PERSON> Pease </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Traficant </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> DeWine </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gillmor </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gradison </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Kasich </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, Y; <PERSON> McEwen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Oxley </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Regula </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wylie </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OKLAHOMA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ English, N; <PERSON> McCurdy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Synar </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Inhofe </PERSON>, X.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>OREGON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ AuCoin, X; <PERSON> DeFazio </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Wyden </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>PENNSYLVANIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Borski, Y; <PERSON> Coyne </PERSON>, N; Foglietta, N; <PERSON> Gaydos </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Kanjorski </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Kolter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kostmayer </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Murtha </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Walgren </PERSON>, N; <LOCATION> Yatron </LOCATION>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Clinger </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gekas </PERSON>, X; Goodling, Y; <PERSON> McDade </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Ritter </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schulze </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Shuster </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Weldon </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>RHODE ISLAND</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republicans _ <PERSON> Machtley </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Schneider </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH CAROLINA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Derrick </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Patterson </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Spratt </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Tallon </PERSON>, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Ravenel </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Spence </LOCATION>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>SOUTH DAKOTA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TENNESSEE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Clement </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, Y; <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, N; <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, present. Republicans _ <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Quillen </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Sundquist </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TEXAS</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ Andrews, N; <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>, present; <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bustamante </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON>, Y; de la <PERSON> Garza </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Gonzalez </PERSON>, Y; Hall, N; <LOCATION> Laughlin </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Leath </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON>, Y; Pickle, Y; <PERSON> Sarpalius </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Stenholm </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, Y. Republicans _ <PERSON> Archer </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Armey </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Barton </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Combest </PERSON>, Y; DeLay, N; Fields, Y; <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>UTAH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrat _ <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Republicans </PERSON> _ <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Nielson </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VERMONT</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Olin </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Pickett </PERSON>, present; <PERSON> Sisisky </PERSON>, present. Republicans _ <PERSON> Bateman </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Bliley </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Parris </PERSON>, Y; Slaughter, Y; <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WASHINGTON</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Dicks </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Foley </LOCATION>, X -LRB- by tradition, the speaker seldom votes -RRB-; <PERSON> McDermott </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Swift </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Unsoeld </LOCATION>, Y. Republicans _ <LOCATION> Chandler </LOCATION>, Y; <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WEST VIRGINIA</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Mollohan </PERSON>, Y; <PERSON> Rahall </PERSON>, N; Staggers, N; Wise, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WISCONSIN</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats _ <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, X; <PERSON> Kastenmeier </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Kleczka </PERSON>, N; <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION>, N; Obey, N. Republicans _ <PERSON> Gunderson </PERSON>, Y; <LOCATION> Petri </LOCATION>, N; <PERSON> Roth </PERSON>, N; <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, N.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>WYOMING</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Republican _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, Y.
</TEXT>
<HEAD>End House-S&amp;L Roll Call _ 3 Takes</HEAD>
<TEXT>

</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Hostages Bjt   08-05 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Hostages, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Waiting in Hostage Drama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is in a `` holding pattern'' as it pins its hopes on continued diplomatic efforts to resolve the crisis involving hostages held by Moslem extremists, an official said. The administration on Friday voiced optimism, tinged with caution, at the promise of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s new president, <PERSON> Hashemi </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>, to help find a solution to the hostage situation. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said he would explore the overture `` to the fullest.'' `` I do n't want to raise hopes beyond fulfillment, but there's reason to be somewhat encouraged,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said about <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>'s Still, presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is `` always skeptical of what we hear from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>,'' while <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> sounded a slightly more positive reaction. `` Based on the excerpts we have seen, President <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON>'s remarks appear to be moderate and are therefore encouraging,'' she said `` We have reason to believe that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is genuinely engaged and no reason to believe that its engagement is not focused in a positive direction.'' The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which does not have direct relations with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, was using <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> as an intermediary to seek help from <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, generally believed to wield influence with the <ORGANIZATION> Shiite </ORGANIZATION> kidnappers, officials said. The president also called the head of the Geneva-based <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Cornelio </PERSON> <PERSON> Sommaruga </PERSON>, on Friday to voice support for the agency's involvement in trying to free the hostages, said <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. Efforts by the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> were alluded to by <PERSON> Rafsanjani </PERSON> when he said he would help the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> find solutions. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke of a `` very extraordinarily broad exercise of diplomacy here in the last couple of days'' during which aides said he has appealed to dozens of world leaders for help. The diplomatic efforts are continuing, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. Another administration official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said `` It's in a holding pattern,'' while the administration watches for its diplomatic overtures to produce results. No new messages went to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> on Friday, the official said. During a photo session, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was asked about the massing of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> naval strength in the <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> as a possible indicator he had decided to retaliate militarily if another <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostage was killed. `` If I had made such a decision, I expect this would be the last place I'd be talking about it,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> denied <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had selected specific Lebanese targets to hit if kidnappers had carried out a threat to kill American hostage <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>. `` I will say he did not make final decisions,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` It does not help the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government or the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to be discussing military tactics ... to be flexing our muscles in public.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was he was `` certainly pleased'' that the kidnappers on Thursday indefinitely suspended their death threat against <PERSON> Cicippio </PERSON>. `` I'm encouraged. But I do n't want to get the hopes of the hostages' loved ones up once again, to have those hopes dashed. This is a brutal process, where you see people paraded before cameras and their families get their hopes up,'' the president said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CongressRdp Bjt   08-05 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress Rdp, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress Passes Financial Bills</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> capped a pre-vacation flurry of fiscal action by giving final approval of a bailout for the savings and loan industry early today and by granting President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s request for an increase in the national debt limit After weeks of intense wrangling and a last-minute legislative showdown, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved the S & amp; L bill without a roll call. Shortly after midnight, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> then sent the package to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on a narrow 201-175 vote, with most of the chamber's ruling Democrats voting against. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is expected to sign the 1,000-page legislation, which would overhaul the thrift industry. One of the biggest hangups on the S & amp; L bill was its impact on the federal deficit and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plan to keep the $ 159 billion cost `` off-budget.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won a compromise from the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> by threatening a veto. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> also gave voice vote approval and sent to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a bill temporarily adding $ 70 billion in new borrowing authority to the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s current credit limit of $ 2.8 trillion. The interim debt bill, which would expire Oct. 31, was approved earlier in the week by the House. The bill is needed because a permanent debt ceiling increase to more than $ 3 trillion has bogged down in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, and without more borrowing authority the government would default on its obligations this month. The permanent debt bill is expected to become a legislative vehicle for a variety of amendments in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> returns next month for its fall meeting. Earlier Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ignored threats of a possible veto and passed a $ 286.5 billion military spending bill that would slash billions of dollars from <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s strategic weapons programs. The bill, approved 312-105, would cut $ 1.8 billion from <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wars </ORGANIZATION>, strictly curtail production of the B-2 bomber and eliminate all funds for the Midgetman nuclear missile, the advanced tactical fighter and cruise missile. Also Friday: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved an $ 18.4 billion spending bill for fiscal 1989 operations of the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Postal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, and other government agencies The bill was approved only after a controversial amendment to restore <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s military pension was put off until the fall, when it will be taken up as a separate bill. Among the items in the spending bill is $ 200,000 to remodel the Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s official residence, to better accommodate his young family. The measure contains $ 5.5 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, $ 300 million more than this year, and $ 1.3 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, $ 100 million above 1989 spending. It also aims to prevent credit card companies from joining with charities to seek business, and thus taking advantage of subsidized mail rates. Another part of the bill would suspend for one year enforcement of a tax law designed to encourage companies to give health insurance to low-level workers. Business groups have complained that the requirement is expensive and time-consuming. _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee announced it will conduct preliminary inquiries into the conduct of Reps. <PERSON> Gus </PERSON> <PERSON> Savage </PERSON>, D-Ill.; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buz'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> R-Ohio </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bates </PERSON>, D-Calif. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> was convicted in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> on a misdemeanor charge of contributing to the unruliness of a child for having sex with a Two former aides to <PERSON> Bates </PERSON> have filed a complaint alleging he sexually harassed female members of his staff. Three Democrats filed a complaint against <PERSON> Savage </PERSON> after news reports said a Peace Corps volunteer complained the congressman fondled her while he was traveling in <LOCATION> Zaire </LOCATION>. _ Sen <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, D-Minn., said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee has decided to proceed with its investigation of his book contract that an opponent claimed was used to circumvent limits on outside income _ The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, in a bill reacting to the Exxon Valdez disaster, voted 99-0 to increase industry's financial liability for oil spills, create a nationwide system to clean up such accidents and establish a $ 1 billion trust fund to help compensate for damages _ The <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> approved and sent to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a bill providing $ 895 million to farmers who suffered crop losses caused by the drought and other weather-related problems
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890805-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-05-89 0237EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-05 0921</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0954</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
