<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 2350EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan 1stLd-Writethru   04-26 0781</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0662,0803</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Shaken Takeshita Searches For Successor</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with budget passing committee.
Pick up 4th pvs, `The normally...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TETSUO JIMBO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The governing party on Thursday forced the 1989 budget through a parliamentary committee, paving the way for Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> to resign in a far-reaching political scandal. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> pledged Tuesday to resign after <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> passes the budget to take responsibility for the scandal, which involves influence-peddling and questionable stock dealings among senior government officials. The <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was expected to ram the budget through Parliament later Thursday. The opposition is boycotting the session, demanding new elections and that former Premier <PERSON> Yasuhiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakasone </PERSON> be summoned to the assembly to testify about his role in the scandal. The Budget Committee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s powerful <ORGANIZATION> Lower </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, took about two minutes to approve the budget There still was no clear successor to <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, since many senior party leaders are linked to the scandal. Former Foreign Minister <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>, 75, widely viewed as the top candidate for interim premier because he is untouched by the scandal, expressed reluctance again Thursday due to poor health. On Wednesday <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> met with <PERSON> Shintaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, secretary general of the governing party, and the two agreed to decide on a successor after <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s April 29-May 6 `` Golden Week'' holidays. The normally unflappable prime minister appeared shaken following the suicide Wednesday of <PERSON> Ihei </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>, 58, an aide since 1958 and the man who handled <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s scandal-tainted political donations. `` I strongly regret -LRB- his action -RRB-,'' <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> told reporters. `` We walked side by side for over 30 years.'' <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>, who had served <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> since 1958, was found dead Wednesday in his <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> apartment. Police said he had slashed a wrist and an ankle with a razor and hanged himself after leaving notes to his wife and several other people, including <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>. Police declined to reveal the notes' contents. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> said he had not seen <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s note, but thought it was possible the suicide was linked to the stock-profiteering and bribery scandal. <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s name, not <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s, appeared on loans and share dealings with the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> that are under suspicion both for political ethics and bribery. The company, an information services conglomerate, is accused of trying to buy influence with politicians, bureaucrats, business leaders and media executives. Author <PERSON> Yotaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Konaka </PERSON>, a government critic, said, `` Mr. <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON> had used all his might to protect Prime Minister <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> by putting all blame on himself, and he probably made his choice -LRB- to die -RRB- after losing the object to protect when the prime minister resigned.'' <PERSON> Tetsuro </PERSON> <PERSON> Muroboshi </PERSON>, who has written books on a number of corruption scandals, said he could not the motive was responsibility for <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s fall. `` I suspect Mr. <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON> was cornered by something _ something he could escape from only by ending his own life,'' <PERSON> Muroboshi </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> announced his resignation plan after disclosures over the weekend that <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON> had accepted a $ 384,000 loan from Recruit. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> on April 11 that he had received more than $ 1 million in political donations from Recruit, but he did not mention the loan. He told reporters later he had not known about it. <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON>'s name also was on opposition parties' list of 154 influential people who earned handsome profits after buying bargain-price stock in a Recruit subsidiary before it was offered for public sale. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> denied personal involvement in the stock deal. Prosecutors had questioned <PERSON> Aoki </PERSON> several times. Fourteen bureaucrats and businessmen _ but no politicians _ have been arrested on bribery and securities law violation charges in the case. The wide swath of Recruit's donations, loans and share transactions cut through the political leadership have made it difficult for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> to find a replacement for <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>'s age and health _ he is a diabetic _ make most observers consider him an interim choice who would serve for a few months while the party chooses a longer-term leader. The head of the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> becomes prime minster because of the party's big majority in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. `` When the time is right, he will announce his acceptance,'' <PERSON> Keichiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Nakamura </PERSON>, a aide to former Prime Minister <PERSON> Miki </PERSON>, told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Nakamura </PERSON> called <PERSON> Ito </PERSON>'s acsencion `` certain'' and said his clean reputation will boost the Liberal Democrats' ailing image. <PERSON> Hideo </PERSON> <PERSON> Sato </PERSON>, dean of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tsukuba </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION>, agreed. `` I think we need exactly that kind of person,'' <PERSON> Sato </PERSON> said. `` He is apparently not involved in big money-making connections with business, and lives in a modest home.'' <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> served as acting prime minister briefly after Prime Minister <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ohira </PERSON> died in June 1980.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DrugEnforcement     04-26 0403</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug Enforcement,0416</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thornburgh Calls For More International Cooperation In Drug War</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL WARREN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorney General <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> on Wednesday night praised a growing emphasis on international cooperation in the war on drugs, and promised multinational operations against drug traffickers. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> spoke at the 20-member <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, which President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is to adress Thursday morning as part of two-day visit to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> spoke to reporters before his address to a closed session of the conference. `` Drug trafficking operations cross many national boundries and are beyond the reach of any one nation,'' he said. The attorney general added that during his trip to <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> last month, he made plans for more combined efforts against drugs. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> praised the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION> adopted last December in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, and called for its early ratification by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The multilateral agreement by more than 100 drug-producing and consuming nations is an effort to establish a set of internationally recognized drug trafficking offenses as guidelines for domestic law in each country. In his speech, released before the closed session, <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> praised the arrest earlier this month of <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON>, who was thought to control much of the Mexican drug trade. `` None of us are naive enough to think that the arrest of one kingpin will dismantle any cartel,'' <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> said. `` But the fact that we now have ` untouchables' such as <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallardo </PERSON> and -LRB- former Colombian kingpin -RRB- <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehder </PERSON> behind bars sends powerful signals worldwide.'' All member nations of the conference have laws on the books or pending to control drug-processing chemicals, <PERSON> Lawn </PERSON> said. Legislation signed into law last November by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> requires manufacturers to keep sales records and encourages them to report suspicious purchases of precursor chemicals to the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION>. The law drew particular praise from the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> delegation, which maintains its country has been blamed unfairly for the international drug scourge. The seventh annual conference, meeting in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the first time, has drawn upper-level drug enforcement officials from <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in an effort to develop a hemispheric anti-drug strategy. On Thursday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is scheduled to participate in a simulated drug interdiction exercise and to address an opening ceremony at a high-tech center where the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> will gather intelligence and coordinate the fight against drug smugglers throughout the eastern <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Space 1stLd-Writethru   04-26 0385</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Space, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0762,0393</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cosmonauts Leave Space Station</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with cosmonauts landing. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three Soviet cosmonauts returned to <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> on Thursday, leaving the space station Mir with no one at the helm for only the second time since it was launched more than three years ago. The descent module touched down in <LOCATION> Kazakhstan </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> at 6:59 a.m. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> time, the official news agency <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> reported. The Soyuz TM-7 landed about 90 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Dzheskazgan </LOCATION> in cloudy skies with observation helicopters on hand. Launch director cosmonaut <PERSON> Vladimir </PERSON> <PERSON> Gzhenebekov </PERSON> told Soviet television `` a little correction'' was made, but there were no problems with the landing. Mir, considered the showpiece of the Soviet space program, is expected to remain unmanned until August in what officials called a money-saving move prompted by delays in preparing new scientific equipment for the spacecraft. The Soviet media and and candidates in recent elections complained the billions of dollars spent on space would be better applied to social services on <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION>. Officials also said the break also would give scientists a chance to review the masses of information gathered since Mir was launched in February 1986. Cosmonauts <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Volkov </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sergei </PERSON> <PERSON> Krikalev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Valery </PERSON> <PERSON> Polyakov </PERSON> spent Wednesday packing a landing module and mothballing some on-board systems, the <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> news agency reported. A new crew is scheduled for launch this summer for a six-month mission aboard the orbiting station. The new cosmonauts are to install new modules that will approximately double the station's size and equipment and `` usher in the second phase of Mir's service life,'' <ORGANIZATION> Tass </ORGANIZATION> said In September, an Afghan and a Soviet cosmonaut were forced to postpone the landing of their Soyuz TM-5 capsule in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> for a day because of equipment and crew errors. They touched down safely a day late but were running dangerously low on food and air. In December, two Soviet cosmonauts returned from the Mir after breaking the record for the longest time in space with a year-long stay. They and a French crew member stayed on board an unplanned extra three hours because the memory of a computer aboard their capsule overloaded, Soviet media reported. <PERSON> Gzhenebekov </PERSON>, however, denied that there were serious problems on those occasions on the television news broadcast.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 2359EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 4thLd-Writethru a0791 04-26 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0791,0708</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Push by Police Blockades in Pro-democracy March</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout with march passing more police blockades, details;
pickup graf 17 pvs `But the....' TRIMS thereafter</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tens of thousands of Chinese students, cheered by bystanders, surged through police roadblocks Thursday to press for more democracy in a march that Communist authorities had vowed to stop. Riot police fitted with helmets, shields and sticks closed 100-acre Tianamen Square, the students' destination at the center of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Truckloads of police were parked along the square, about nine miles southeast of the campus area where the march began. `` Police get out of the way, people's police belong to the people,'' the students shouted as they pressed through a barricade of about 300 police at a major intersection in northwest <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. Student leaders urged youths from dozens of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> universities to march to <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION>, the symbolic center of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, to protest harsh government statements condemning their 11-day-old campaign for democracy. Government officials, in mass meetings Wednesday, declared the demonstrations illegal. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Communist Party Secretary <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Ximing </PERSON> told a special meeting of 10,000 city party officials, `` We must firmly stop such riots.'' However, by noon, the marchers had pushed through three police blockades set up along the route. Authorities gave way, and there were no injuries. `` It was like watching an iron bar bend'' one bystander said, describing the police retreats. When three truckloads of armed police pulled up at an intersection, it was surrounded by a crowd shouting, `` People love the people's police, the people's police love people.'' Students with arms linked sang the national anthem and shouted `` long live democracy'' as they headed down the main road from their campuses to the square. Others shouted `` down with bureaucracy, down with corruption.'' Students reported that thousands of troops had massed near the <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> along the student route toward the center of the city. `` I already know that I might die today. I am prepared,'' said one student. Thousands of bystanders along the street shouted `` Get out of the way!'' and `` Do n't beat them!'' when police temporarily blocked the students at one intersection. Along the route, thousands of people leaned out windows and applauded the students. Doctors and patients in bathrobes from a local hospital grabbed for pamphlets the students were handing out. A Chinese journalist speaking on condition of anonymity said the government moves against the protest were made by order of senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> to stop the students' campaign against official corruption and for sweeping democratic reforms such as a free press. `` The peasants support us, the workers support us, the army supports us, so why should we be bothered by students?'' the journalist quoted <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> as saying Tuesday. The journalist, from the official <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>, spoke on condition of anonmyity. Spurred by the April 15 death of ousted <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, a reformer, tens of thousands of students marched repeatedly to Tiananmen Square last week. They held unprecedented sit-ins outside government and party headquarters in the largest student protest in four decades of Communist rule. More than 70,000 students from 41 <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> schools began a class boycott Monday. They have demanded that 84-year-old <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> step down, and they want Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> to open a dialogue with them. Loudspeakers at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> appealed to the students Thursday, `` We urge you to think what kind of problems will arise if you leave the university. Think what kind of effect this will have on your family and parents.'' But the students have won widespread support from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> residents, who have donated more than $ 8,000 to their campaign. Huge crowds have flocked to read the students' posters, and many people have expressed agreement in unprecedented street-side political debates. In front of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, one middle-aged man told several dozen listeners Wednesday he had canceled his newspaper subscriptions. `` There's no point reading them, all the papers are the same,'' he said. <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> officials announced they had dismissed the editor of <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>'s weekly <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most outspoken newspaper, and would reorganize it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SovietDefectors     04-26 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet Defectors,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weather Keeps Defectors On Little Diomede</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NOME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A second day of bad weather prevented the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> from bringing two Soviet defectors to the mainland from <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diomede </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>, a Guard spokesman said Tuesday. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Haller </PERSON> said that when weather permits, a Guard helicopter will fly the men from the island in the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>. From there they will be flown to <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> to file formal requests for political asylum. The two sought asylum just hours before officials signed a protocol aimed at easing travel restrictions between <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>. Their applications will be forwarded to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for review and a recommendation, said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, district director of the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The final decision rests with the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>, he said. The process usually takes several weeks, <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said. Soviet officials are aware of the defections, but `` at this point we have no comment,'' said <PERSON> Andre </PERSON> <PERSON> Dronov </PERSON>, a Soviet vice consul based in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> declined to identify the men or provide additional information about them. But sources on the island, who asked not to be identified, said the men were apprentice journalists from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in their mid-30s. They are staying at the local Guard armory. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said they were the first Soviet defectors in his 10 years with the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The men were reported missing when the Soviet delegation prepared to leave the island by helicopter after a party following the signing ceremony. Other National Guardsmen helped the Soviets search for the two, said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Stimpfle </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Nome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> official who had reached the island before the weather turned bad. <PERSON> Stimpfle </PERSON> said the guardsmen apparently either did n't know about the defections or felt it was n't proper protocol to inform their Soviet guests. Adj. Gen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaeffer </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, said the timing of the defections was embarrassing. `` The governor is trying to get along better with the Soviets and here comes a couple of people who are basically messing up the operation,'' said <PERSON> Schaffer </PERSON>, `` All of us would have liked to say, ` Sorry guys, let's try next week.''' <PERSON> Stimpfle </PERSON>, still weathered in on the island, said the defectors are being kept under tight security. `` Everything is hush, hush,'' he said. `` They've even got the armory windows blacked out with ponchos or something.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AmnestyComics     04-26 0784</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Amnesty Comics,0802</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Adventures of `Felipe' Teach Immigration Law to Aliens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHLEEN GRUBB</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SACRAMENTO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 No superheroes grace the pages of <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON>'s comic books, no archvillains with maniacal plots to control the world, and not a single `` Pow!'' `` Zap!'' or `` Bam!'' Even so, the black-and-white adventures of `` Felipe'' and his friends as they try to conquer a mountain of bureaucratic obstacles to become legal <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents may be the most dog-eared literature in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Distributed free at employment offices, churches and social service agencies, the booklets are lessons in applying for residency under the complex 1986 Immigration Reform and Control Act, better known as the amnesty program. `` Amnistia'' or `` Amnesty,'' about applying for temporary residency, was out of print soon after the release of 50,000 copies a year ago. `` The Second Phase,'' about permanent residency and avoiding disqualification, is in its second printing four months after distribution of the first 30,000 copies. `` We've never had this kind of response with any material before,'' said <PERSON> Emily </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldfarb </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Immigrant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which produced the books. The potential audience in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> exceeds 1.58 million, the number of applicants for residency status under the amnesty program. `` All this subject matter is deadly boring if you are n't affected by it If you are affected by it, it's not deadly boring _ it's terrifyingly boring,'' said <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON>, 39, a former Mexican government economist who got the idea after he married a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen and moved from <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. So Juarez lightened it up, capitalizing on the gallows humor and love of storytelling he said is the heritage of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, where political cartooning has enjoyed a long tradition and soap opera-style novellas are popular. `` Lots of people say, ` Why a comic book? That's for a kid or the mentally retarded.' There's nothing comic about the situations portrayed in the comic books. Actually, it's a matter of life and death. It's going to determine where they live and work. But there's no reason to lose your sense of humor.'' When the characters discuss the difficulties of obtaining documents and witnesses' sworn statements to prove they've been in the country since Jan. 1, 1982 _ the cutoff date for amnesty applications _ <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> laments: `` Even my mother-in-law wanted to use the opportunity to get rid of me.'' The idea was so good that the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>, which had said it could n't afford to produce <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON>'s book, followed suit The government version also proved popular, said <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyborn </PERSON>, outreach coordinator with the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. `` I do n't think we have any left, actually.'' <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON> writes the scripts in Spanish, then translates them for English editions. A former student of dramatic arts, he gets help with illustrations from his media-wise family _ his father works in advertising, his brother in film-making, and his sister is a television director in <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. He strives to write the scripts in the idioms of everyday Spanish, while accurately imparting information about the amnesty program _ a task that can be a `` nightmare'' because experts frequently disagree on the complex law. <PERSON> Goldfarb </PERSON> believes that unlike with government brochures, people hang onto the comics and read them aloud to their families, reaching illiterate people who otherwise might be misinformed or exploited by swindlers. `` They're fun to read,'' she said. `` The graphics and the conversations and the cultural aspects of it are things that people can identify with.'' `` Amnistia'' dealt with the first phase of the amnesty program, but applying for residency is just the first step. The application dealines were May 5, 1988, for aliens here since 1982 and Nov. 30 for seasonal agriculture workers who had picked perishable crops at least 90 days between May 1985 and May 1986. The second phase deals with permanent residency and problems like arrests, unemployment and welfare dependancy that can make applicants ineligible. Two more issues are in the works to address mandated AIDS tests; qualifying for government assistance including free and reduced-price school lunches and prenatal and infant medical care, and meeting requirements for a basic understanding of English, and American civics and history. If the next issue wins a state grant, <PERSON> Goldfarb </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Immigrant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> plans to print 70,000 copies for distribution by its 80 nonprofit member organizations in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, then make it available to other organizations throughout the state to reprint. <PERSON> Juarez </PERSON> said the widespread readership is its own reward and has inspired him to try producing as his next project an analytical Spanish-English language magazine for <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s rapidly growing Hispanic population.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0102EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     04-26 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0422</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Wins Again</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD DE ATLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> domination of prime-time reached 44 weeks _ two shy of the record, but <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s comedy heavyweight `` Roseanne'' beat out `` The Cosby Show'' for the top spot. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had six of the top 10 shows and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had three, while <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> managed only one. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s cumulative rating was 13.3, with a 23 share for last week; <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> was second with an 11.8 rating and a 21 share; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.6 and 20, according to the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Each rating point represents 904,000 households with televisions The share is a percentage of sets in use. Two sitcoms about families _ the blue-collar `` Roseanne'' and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s upper middle-class Huxtables on `` The Bill Cosby Show'' _ placed first and second in the ratings, respectively. `` Roseanne'' served as a lead-in for the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> premiere of the new series `` Have Faith,'' with a spring debut at No. 3. The show is about three Roman Catholic priests and a monsignor in a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> parish. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` A Different World'' was fourth, followed by its `` Cheers''; `` The Wonder Years,'' on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; `` The Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` 60 Minutes,'' CBS; and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Empty Nest'' and `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>'' made its debut at 18th place. The show is a half-hour retool of the failed hourlong `` Tattinger's.'' The made-for-television movie, `` Baywatch: Panic At <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> Pier,'' about muscular <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lifeguards, was in 11th place for <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. The show from former <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> chief Grant Tinker's production company is a contender for a fall series The <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION> movie `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON>,'' returning one of television's most popular detectives to the small screen, was in 21st place, while <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s two-part miniseries `` Around The World In 80 Days,'' starring <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Brosnan </PERSON>, landed in 30th and 31st places In news, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' took first place for the week with a 10.0 rating, followed by `` CBS Evening News'' with 9.3 and `` NBC Nightly News'' with 8.9. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is closing on the 46-week first-place Nielsens run that <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> achieved in the 1962-1963 season, when the CBS schedule included `` The <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> Show,'' `` The <PERSON> Beverly </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillbillies </PERSON>,'' `` The <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> Show'' and `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>.'' <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Married ... With Children,'' recently under fire by groups critical of the show's portrayal of family life, stood in 49th place and was the network's highest-rated show for the week, followed by `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' at 58th and `` 21 Jump Street,'' in the 76th spot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ANPAOfficers     04-26 0245</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ANPA Officers,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Publishers' Association Picks Board Members</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowles </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, president and publisher of two <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, newspapers, has been elected to a one-year term as chairman of the board of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cowles </PERSON>, 57, runs The Spokesman-Review and the <ORGANIZATION> Spokane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chronicle </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cowles </PERSON>, three other officers, four returning board members and one new board member were elected by voice vote at the <ORGANIZATION> ANPA </ORGANIZATION>'s annual meeting Tuesday <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochs </PERSON> <PERSON> Sulzberger </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, will become a member of the <ORGANIZATION> ANPA </ORGANIZATION> board for one year as its immediate past chairman. Other officers elected to one-year terms were <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Schermer </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Lee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprises </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Davenport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, as vice chairman; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Erburu </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mirror </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> as secretary; and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennack </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> as treasurer. The new member elected Tuesday to the 22-member board was <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>. He will serve for two years. Four board members re-elected to two-year terms, beginning Wednesday, were <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferre </PERSON>, president and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuevo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dia </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newhouse </PERSON>, president and general manager of The Star-Ledger of <LOCATION> Newark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON>, editor and co-publisher of The Free Lance-Star of <LOCATION> Fredericksburg </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Bangor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     04-26 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0801</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of April 17-23. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 26.3 rating, 23.8 million homes. 2. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.6, 18.6 million homes. 3. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Have Faith,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.2, 18.3 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.0 million homes. 5. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.7, 17.8 million homes. 6. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 7. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.6, 16.8 million homes. 8. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.7 million homes. 9. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.8, 16.1 million homes. 10. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 11. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.5 million homes. 11. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Baywatch: Panic at <LOCATION> Malibu </LOCATION> Pier'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.1, 15.5 million homes. 13. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.4 million homes. 14. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2, 14.6 million homes. 15. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.6, 14.1 million homes. 16. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5, 14.0 million homes. 16. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5, 14.0 million homes. 18. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Nick & amp; <PERSON> Hillary </PERSON> <PERSON> Special </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4, 13.9 million homes. 19. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` B.L. Stryker'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 15.2, 13.7 million homes. 20. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8, 13.4 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 21. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON>'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 14.7. 23. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 24. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 25. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 26. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.8. 26. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 13.8. 28. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 29. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 30. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 30. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Nearly Departed,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 30. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Around the World in 80 Days,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 13.2. 33. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Around the World in 80 Days,'' Part 3, _ `` Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 34. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 35. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` The Red Spider'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 12.8. 36. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 37. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 38. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 38. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.5. 40. -LRB- X -RRB- `` People Magazine on TV,'' CBS, 12.1. 41. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 42. -LRB- 44 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 43. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 44. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Poker Alice'' _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 11.4. 45. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.9. 45. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` The Littlest Victims'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 10.9. 47. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 47. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 10.8. 49. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` One of the Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 49. -LRB- 73 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Working High,'' CBS, 10.6. 49. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 49. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 53. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 54. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Rescue: 911,'' CBS, 10.4. 55. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Heartland Special,'' CBS, 10.2. 56. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 57. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Heartland,'' CBS, 9.8. 58. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 59. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 60. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkes </PERSON>,'' CBS, 8.9. 60. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Live-In,'' CBS, 8.9. 60. -LRB- X -RRB- `` This is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, Part 7,'' CBS, 8.9. 63. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Bugs Bunny: <PERSON> Bustin </PERSON>' Out,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.4. 64. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.8. 65. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Burning Questions _ Working in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>: Hazardous Duty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.5. 66. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 66. -LRB- X -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.2. 68. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 69. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Little Bit Strange,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 70. -LRB- 102 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> Hour,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.2. 70. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` The Return of the Shaggy Dog,'' Part 2, _ `` ABC Family Classic,'' 6.2. 72. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 73. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 73. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 75. -LRB- 105 -RRB- `` Dream Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.2. 78. -LRB- 108 -RRB- `` Men,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.5. 80. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 81. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 82. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.3. 83. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0627EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d e BC-Dance     04-26 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Dance,0388</SECOND>
<HEAD>NY City Ballet Opens Season</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The dancers looked like winners as the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ballet </LOCATION> opened its spring season playing its strongest suit, choreography by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>. `` Mozartiana,'' from 1981, `` Episodes,'' from 1959, and `` Tchaikovsky Piano Concerto No. 2,'' from 1941, all choreographed by <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON>, comprised Tuesday's opening night program at the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> State Theater. On this occasion, the modern movements in `` Episodes,'' to <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Webern </PERSON> music, had the most bite and gave the most pleasure. <PERSON> Helene </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexopoulos </PERSON> and <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Kozlov </PERSON> had a duet lighted by two or sometimes one spotlight, just on them. This gave their very athletic movements, as when he faced the audience with her clinging upside down on his back, a look of mystery and futurism. We also saw modern-looking postures and moves in the duet by <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Whelan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jock </PERSON> <PERSON> Soto </PERSON>. These young dancers gave this great performance art a new look. Miss <PERSON> Whelan </PERSON>, not yet a principal or soloist, was filling in for ballerina <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> <PERSON> Watts </PERSON>. The other two couples in `` Episodes'' were <PERSON> Judith </PERSON> <PERSON> Fugate </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jukka </PERSON> <PERSON> Aromaa </PERSON> and <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Calegari </PERSON> and <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Neubert </PERSON>. Peter Frame seemed to be struggling with his angular solo. The very musical <PERSON> Kyra </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON> was joined by <PERSON> Jean-Pierre </PERSON> <PERSON> Frohlich </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ib </PERSON> <PERSON> Andersen </PERSON> in `` Mozartiana'' to open the evening. Four tiny girls from the <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ballet </ORGANIZATION>, as always, added charm to `` Mozartiana.'' The final ballet, `` Tchaikovsky Piano Concerto No. 2,'' has for its leading ballerina role the same poignancy and elegance given the star of `` <LOCATION> Swan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>.'' When the ballet was new, its name was `` Ballet Imperial,'' because the choreography is in the tradition of the Russian masters. <PERSON> Balanchine </PERSON> dropped the title and scenery in 1973. But <PERSON> Darci </PERSON> <PERSON> Kistler </PERSON> and <PERSON> Melinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> wore tiaras, which made them look regal. And <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Luders </PERSON>, a superb partner who can look like a pale prince, is perfect for a mood of quietly heroic sadness, which the music and dance sometimes dips into. Miss <PERSON> Kistler </PERSON> was substituting for <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON>. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> conducted. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Moredock </PERSON> was the assertive piano soloist in the <PERSON> Tchaikovsky </PERSON>. The season will run through June 25.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ANPA     04-26 0607</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ANPA,0626</SECOND>
<HEAD>Newspaper Publishers Urged To Use Technology, Updated Ads, To Thrive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Newspapers must use the latest technologies and updated advertising techniques in order to remain a competitive, thriving force in their communities, publishers have been told. Some newspapers are already following that advice with impressive results, news executives were told at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s 103rd annual convention on Tuesday. These papers, for example, are using telephone recordings of up-to-the-minute sports scores and boldly colored ads in the middle of their stock listings. `` If newspapers are going to be as successful in the future as they've been in the past, we have to be much more zealous about getting close to our customers and staying there. Technology can help us do that,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Batten </PERSON>, president of Miami-based <PERSON> Knight-Ridder </PERSON> <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> spoke to more than 500 people gathered for a morning session at the three-day meeting, which ends today. In 1967, he said, 73 percent of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> adults said they read a newspaper every day, while last year, `` everyday readership hit a new low of 51 percent,'' and sank to 29 percent `` among the group that is key to our long-term future _ adults between 18 and 29.'' That decline, as well as the aging of the baby-boom generation, an increase in two-income households and growing cultural diversity, must be dealt with through technology, <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said. `` Used intelligently, the telephone and the computer can let us recreate the kind of personal relationships that newspapers had with their customers 20 or 25 years ago,'' <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said. He cited the Providence -LRB- <LOCATION> R.I. </LOCATION> -RRB- Journal-Bulletin, which offers telephone recordings of soap-opera updates, publishing an access code for readers. The code is changed daily, so that those who want to use the service must read the paper to find it. More than 20,000 calls a month are recorded on the system, <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, he said, the <ORGANIZATION> Boulder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camera </ORGANIZATION> gets more than 77,000 calls a month for recordings of sports scores and stories that come in after the paper has gone to press. The systems are relatively inexpensive, requiring little more than a personal computer, phone lines and tape recordings, <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said. He said newspapers have little choice but to change with their readers. `` These -LRB- changes in readers -RRB- are threats, not to our existence but to our pricing flexibility, to our ability to finance the news coverage that our communities deserve and that we want to provide,'' <PERSON> Batten </PERSON> said. Other threats include a trend among advertisers toward using direct mail and other techniques to communicate directly with consumers, said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennack </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Direct mail represents 14 percent of all <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> advertising and its growth is expected to outpace traditional media advertising, <PERSON> Bennack </PERSON> said. Newspapers must develop new strategies for capturing advertisers' dollars, such as updating their television guide sections and standardizing ad sizes used in the guides, said <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tillis </PERSON>, marketing vice president at <ORGANIZATION> Knight-Ridder </ORGANIZATION> and president of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Tillis </PERSON> noted that with the spread of cable television, `` more promotion dollars are being spent by networks, stations,'' and others. Another recommendation is `` adoption of the ` island position' on the first page of agate stock listings in your financial sections,'' he said. <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> Standen </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, noted the recent introduction by <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>'s Oregonian newspaper of a boldly colored ad in the middle of its sports scoreboard. `` I think the long-term outlook for our business is bright,'' he said. `` But that future depends on our ability to change and make new opportunities happen.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TrainDerailment     04-26 0231</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Train Derailment,0237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Michigan Train Derailment Forces Evacuations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILFORD, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ten cars on a train hauling potentially toxic chemicals derailed Tuesday night, forcing evacuation of residents up to half a mile away, officials said. No injuries were reported and no chemicals were believed to have leaked as result of the accident, which was reported around 7:45 p.m., said <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>. It was not known exactly how many people were evacuated, <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> said. Evacuees were taken to <ORGANIZATION> Milford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>. The train was hauling chemicals from <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> plant 80 miles north of here to <LOCATION> Freeport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Milford </LOCATION> is about 20 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. The derailed cars were described as empty, but <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Goggin </PERSON> said they may have contained up to 100 gallons of chemicals. At least nine of the other cars on the train that remained on the tracks carried potentially toxic chemicals, <PERSON> Goggin </PERSON> said from the company's <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> headquarters. The chemicals were styrene monomer, a liquid used in refrigerator liners and auto interiors; vinyl chloride, a compressed gas used as an adhesive; and propylene oxide, a liquid used to make foam for seats and other products, he said. The cars were owned or leased by Dow, though the crew was employed by a rail company, <PERSON> Goggin </PERSON> said. He said he did n't know the name of the rail company.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ANPA-Minorities     04-26 0426</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-ANPA-Minorities,0437</SECOND>
<HEAD>Study: Minorities Vital To Future Of Newspapers</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-ANPA</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attracting more minority readers would enable newspapers to tap into fastest-growing segments of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population and could offset flat circulation trends, a publishers' task force says The group presented a 40-page report, titled `` Cornerstone for Growth: How Minorities Are Vital to the Future of Newspapers,'' to news executives at the annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday. The study recommends that newspapers pursue not only minority readers, but minority employees and advertisers as well. `` What we have done, in a very quantifiable way, is to make the case that what is right and fair is also smart business,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, publisher of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the task force. Daily newspaper circulation is about 63 million, barely more than the 62 million of 1970. But the task force report noted that 87 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population growth between now and the year 2000 will be among minorities, principally blacks, Hispanics, Asian-Americans and native Americans. Further, the report concluded, more than 56 percent of workers joining the labor force between now and the year 2000 will be members of minorities. In order to attract both this advertising target audience and future employees, newspapers will have to adjust their sights to better serving minorities, the report said. `` This ... is a particularly useful tool for publishers as they continue to change their newspapers to better meet the needs of their communities,'' said <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Ochs </PERSON> <PERSON> Sulzberger </PERSON>, publisher of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> ANPA </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to providing profiles on what some newspapers are doing to adapt to the changing demographics in their markets, the report debunks myths about minorities that researchers said have slowed growth in newspaper readership, circulation and advertising: _ Although some have suggested pursuing minority markets is futile because minorities do n't read newspapers, the report found minorities at higher income and education levels have the same readership rates as non-minorities _ about 70 percent. _ Although some argue that Spanish-speaking and Asian groups resist English-language newspapers, the report concluded their children will be among the newspaper's future readers. _ Although some argue that minorities ca n't afford to buy newspapers or advertise in them, the report found minority income levels increasing and growing faster than non-minority income. While non-minorities' disposable household income rose just 18 percent from 1980 to 1986, comparable figures show blacks' income increasing by 21 percent, <PERSON> Hispanics </PERSON>' by 45 percent and Asian-Americans' by 58 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TankerSpill-Excerpts     04-26 0590</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tanker Spill-Excerpts,0623</SECOND>
<HEAD>Excerpts From Radio Conversations In Alaskan Tanker Spill</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Tanker Spill, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are excerpts from radio conversations taped March 24 after the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> ran aground in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> in the nation's worst oil spill. The exchanges timed off automatically and began 23 minutes after the ship's log indicated the tanker ran aground. The tapes were obtained under a Freedom of Information Act request filed by the <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. 12:27 a.m. AST: Exxon Valdez Captain <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>: `` We've fetched up hard aground north of <LOCATION> Goose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION>. Evidently we're leaking some oil and we're going to be here for a while. 1:07 a.m. Coast Guard Cmdr. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` This is the captain of the port, Commander <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>. Good evening. Do you have any more of an estimate as to your situation at this time?'' <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>: `` Ah, not at the present, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON>. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> here. A little problem here with the third mate, but we're working our way off the reef. We've, ah, the vessel has been holed and we're ascertaining right now, we're trying just to get her off the reef and we'll get back to you as soon as we can. <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Take it slow and easy. You know, I'm telling you the obvious, but take it slow and easy, and we're getting help out as fast as we can.'' <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>: `` We're in pretty good shape right now, stability-wise, and, ah trying to extract her off the shoal here. You can probably see me on you radar, and, ah, once we get under way, I'll let you know, do another damage control assessment.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Before you make any drastic attempt to get away, make sure you do n't you know, start doing any ripping. You got a rising tide, you, another, about an hour and a half worth of tide in your favor, ah, ah, once you hit that max, I would n't recommend doing much wiggling.'' <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>: `` Major damage has kind of been done and we kind of rock and rolled over it. We're just kind of hung up on the stern here. We're just, ah, we'll drift over it. Ah, I'll get back to you.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Captain of the port out.'' 1:59 a.m. <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Any update, captain?'' A new, unidentified voice on the Exxon Valdez: `` We're still surveying tanks, trying to assess the damage.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>, do you have capacity on board to internally transfer if you need to?'' The Valdez voice: `` Yes, we could do that.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` OK, that's, obviously you know better than I do, but that's highly recommended if, once you've determined which tanks are holed, to drop the head if you can.'' The Valdez voice: `` Yes, roger that.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Are you still working, trying to get off?'' The Valdez: `` No, our engines are stopped right now. We're going to wait'til there's a little more water underneath us.'' 3:19 <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Have you had a chance to detect whether or not any noticeable amount of oil has dropped out of any tanks and, if so, which tanks are they?'' A voice from the Exxon Valdez: `` Ah, the initial figure is 138,000 and the chief mate's taking another check on it right now.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` Which tank is that, or tanks?'' The same Valdez voice: `` Right now, our starboard slop tank, two starboard wing tanks, and possibly five center.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>: `` You said starboard?'' The voice: `` <PERSON> Roger </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> McCall </PERSON> -LRB- gloomily -RRB- _ `` <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> on that, and that was barrels, correct.'' The voice: `` That's correct.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bush'sVillage     04-26 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush's Village,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush's Ancestral Village Hopes for Presidential Visit</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MESSING, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On the day <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> took over the presidency from <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, a phone conversation between two innkeepers added an Old World footnote to the transition. `` Well then,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Farrell </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Ballyporeen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, to <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> in Messing, <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. `` I suppose it's over to you.'' And so it was. On Jan. 20, one minute before opening time, the mantle of presidential ancestral village passed from <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Ballyporeen </LOCATION> to Messing, the English hamlet that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s forebears left for the New World in 1631 When it comes to the business of presidential roots, it's the pubs that seem to be first to have greatness thrust upon them. A highlight of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s 1984 trip to the town of his 19th-century peasant ancestors was <PERSON> O'Farrell </PERSON>'s pub, where he stopped for a drink. Now <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, owners of the Old Crown Inn, are hoping <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will visit Messing when he comes to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> at the end of May and stop by for a pint of local brew. Tucked away in the <ORGANIZATION> Essex </ORGANIZATION> countryside, one hour's train ride east of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, Messing is largely a bedroom community, so empty on weekdays that `` you could shoot a cannon through it and nobody would notice,'' according to <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, the innkeeper's wife. The prospect of presidential glory is n't universally welcomed. `` There are one or two people who are apprehensive of hordes of tourists arriving and of commercialization and trivialization,'' says <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, chairman of the parish council. But he doubts it will happen. Messing's `` nice old buildings would look pretty daft if they were all modernized and turned into gift stores,'' said <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, an engaging, tousle-haired man of 46 who takes Messing's presidential connection with a healthy sense of humor. With one pub, one restaurant, four streets and 250 inhabitants, the village is so small that its main street is called simply The Street. But as tourism becomes one of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s biggest industries, <ORGANIZATION> Essex </ORGANIZATION> county authorities have developed a heritage trail for <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> visitors, and Messing wants a piece of the action. `` Business-wise, it will certainly be better for us. We die a death during the week,'' says Mrs. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>. Although there is no <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> ancestral home or family burial place in Messing, the medieval church and quaint houses offer good photo opportunities. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, says <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, is the biggest thing to happen to Messing since an earthquake in 1884 knocked down the pub. `` Presumably if he comes the whole thing will be so fantastically organized that we locals will get totally squeezed out,'' he says. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Peskett </PERSON>, the respected British genealogist who traced <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s origins to Messing, says the president is directly descended from an aristocratic farmer who left for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in 1631. Mrs. <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> likes to daydream about the president's ancestor strolling in for a drink at the very spot where she's now serving breakfast. Messing's native population has dwindled over the centuries, but it is now being replenished by affluent refugees from <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, 46, moved here six years ago and commutes to a senior post office job in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The Harrises, who are in their 40s, arrived in 1986 after six years in <LOCATION> Bahrain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kuwait </LOCATION> and bought the pub. Understandably, Messing rooted for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the election, and the pub served cake and champagne when he won. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> invited him to visit. Though noncommittal, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in his reply that `` Messing will always have a special place in our hearts.'' In <LOCATION> Ballyporeen </LOCATION>, <PERSON> O'Farrell </PERSON> says he had no regrets about ceding the crown. `` I felt quite good about it because President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> had a very successful tenure and it was good to see someone going out on a high note, especially when there's so much pessimism about these days,'' he said in a telephone interview. As for <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, he's just happy that fate has linked his village with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` It's nice,'' he said, `` to see a local lad make good.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Students     04-26 0899</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Students,0930</SECOND>
<HEAD>From Upper Class Families, Dissent Is Born In China</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 They gather by the tens of thousands in the capital and elsewhere to call for more democracy, the end of high-level corruption, and freedom of expression. Who are these students protesting communist methods; what do they want? Here is a report by an <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> correspondent who went among the students for this story.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They come mostly from the families of intellectuals. Their parents are government officials, many of them are <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members and now they want to change <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The tens of thousands of students who took to the streets in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> last week and began an unprecedented class boycott Monday are by no means the downtrodden of this country of 1.1 billion. They are its future scientists, writers, teachers and diplomats. And they are calling for a new <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, one that is democratic, with a free press and respect for human rights. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Qiang </PERSON>, a senior at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, remembers when he first began believing something was wrong with his country. The son of a county official in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s northwest, <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, recalled that `` people were always giving us presents.'' `` There were big meals, TV sets. We never paid for anything. Last month we got a new video, now we have three,'' he said. `` I did n't think this was strange until I left home and found out that governments are n't supposed to work like that.'' It was his first summer vacation from university. `` My father wanted to welcome me home with a banquet. We went out and had a party. But we did n't pay. The hotel manager owed him a favor because my father gave him state funds to repair his building.'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON> asked his father why he did not pay. `` This is <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' was the answer. `` This is not the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> that I want to be a part of,'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON> said, expressing a belief shared by many protesters. <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s classmate, a 24-year-old woman from Inner <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION>, said she was brought up to respect individual rights. `` My parents are doctors and we've always had a good relationship. They let me live my life, never reading my private letters like other parents. I only wish the government would treat me the same.'' Although not a member of the 48 million-member <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the woman belongs to its <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>, a training ground for young communists. She said she believes participating in the protest does not conflict with the Marxism pushed by the league. `` <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Marx </PERSON> was a democrat. I do n't pretend to understand the real socialism that he wrote about, but I know this is n't it,'' she said. Like many students, the woman was unclear about what kind of government she wants in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` But I do n't see that as a problem. I know I do n't understand democracy. But my worry now is not with the future, it's with the present. We have a system that is rotten.'' Indeed, compared to the pro-democracy protests of 1986-87, student demands _ a free press, more funds for education and publication of the financial records of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leadership _ are relatively clear Still, most students expect the protests to fail. They choose to view their movement in a romantic light, as a glorious but inevitably futile cause. `` When the time comes they will crush us,'' said one young man as he gazed at thousands of Chinese soldiers during a demonstration last week. `` I'm not afraid, but they will crush us just the same.'' Students said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s increasing openness to the West and the large number of books translated into Chinese also helped spark their discontent. Several students cited the 1957 book, `` The New Class,'' in which former <LOCATION> Yugoslav </LOCATION> official <PERSON> Milovan </PERSON> <PERSON> Djilas </PERSON> charged communism has produced a new class of privileged leaders instead of a classless society. `` It was an enlightenment for me because it comes from a socialist country and from a top leader there, too,'' said a 20-year-old sophomore studying psychology. Many students said they looked up to leaders of Western democracies. `` I read in the paper that <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s prime minister, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON>, admitted he had been a drinker and a bit of a playboy,'' said one student. `` That to me is a wonderful thing. None of our leaders would ever do that. They lack honesty and guts.'' Wu Xi, one of the few demonstrators from a peasant background, said it was not until he took a trip back home after two years at university that he made up his mind to try and change <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` I remember when I was in high school. We were taught to love <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, and really we did love him,'' he said of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 84-year-old leader who instituted 1978 agricultural reforms returning land to peasants `` But this time when I went home my family could barely feed me. If this is not <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s fault, then I do n't know who to blame.'' Many students openly look down on their countrymen, expressing impatience with their unwillingness to provide more than some material and spiritual help to the demonstrators. But they also doubt themselves. `` The Chinese people are numb. They are asleep,'' said one student. `` But I do n't know if we can wake them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Deaths 1stLd-Writethru a0781 04-26 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deaths, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0781,0200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds: ADDS Strichman. An AMs separate moved as a0736 on Makoti.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Edwin Makoti</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARARE, Zimbabwe (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Letsholo </PERSON> <PERSON> Makoti </PERSON>, a founding member of the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africanist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, died Friday after a long illness. He was 68. <PERSON> Makoti </PERSON> spent most of the movement's 30 years in exile. He served in various posts for the group, including administrative secretary, <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> secretary and its representative in <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ghana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Makoti </PERSON> was head of publicity and information. The congress is a guerrilla-backed movement, outlawed in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, formed in 1959 to fight to end <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s system of racial segregation.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>George Strichman</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Strichman </PERSON> 72, former Chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Colt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, died Monday of cancer. Before joining Colt in 1963, he was president of <ORGANIZATION> ITT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kellogg </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Strichman </PERSON> led a reorganization of Colt through acquisition and divestiture, dropping some of its firearms manufacturing and adding aerospace equipment. He was also chairman of overseers of the Jewish Theological Seminary of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and a member of its board of directors. <PERSON> Strichman </PERSON> was also chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Rensselaer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Polytechnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-China-Deng Bjt   04-26 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Deng, Bjt,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>Demonstrations Show Decline In Deng's Popularity</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Student demonstrators in the past week have shouted what few <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> have dared to whisper _ that senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> is losing the support of the people. In posters, speeches and chanted slogans, students are proclaiming that the savior of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> is too old and too autocratic and should cede power. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, who turns 85 in August, is still believed to be widely admired among the populace for his decade-long program of market-oriented reforms. But many people are angered by his government's failure to halt inflation and end rampant corruption. Rising public discontent was manifested when bands of youths, many unemployed, burned and looted buildings in riots that followed student rallies in two <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> cities. During widespread pro-democracy demonstrations two years ago, students praised <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s reforms, which brought relative prosperity to millions of Chinese. One banner affectionately read, `` Comrade <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, how are you?'' This time, posters appeared reading `` <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, your time has come,'' urging the old revolutionary to retire. One poster compared him to <PERSON> Tzu </PERSON> <PERSON> Hsi </PERSON>, the autocratic empress dowager who ruled <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> from behind the scenes as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s last imperial dynasty crumbled. Some participants in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> demonstrations last week smashed soda bottles on the ground in a symbolic act of disdain for <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>. The Chinese word for small bottle sounds the same as <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s name, `` Xiaoping.'' `` <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> is a great reformer, but he's a dictator and dictatorship's time is done,'' said <PERSON> Wu'er </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaixi </PERSON>, a student leader at <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Normal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> `` We are disappointed in <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>,'' said a <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student. `` Now we think he has made many mistakes. He is trying to control power to the point of autocracy, even though he is retired in name.'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> has sought to avoid the turmoil of <PERSON> Mao </PERSON> <PERSON> Tse-tung </PERSON>'s final years, when factions fought for power while the mentally and physically enfeebled Chairman lay dying. In 1987, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> stepped down from all his posts except the chairmanship of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. But he is still <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s undisputed leader, the man the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and the government turn to when tough decisions must be made. Although Western diplomats who attended meetings with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> recently insist he remains mentally sharp, rumors persist he is losing his grasp. `` A lot of people hope <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> will die,'' said one student. `` He is old, maybe he is crazy.'' General outrage over corruption and nepotism among <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leadership has also not spared <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> One poster referred to <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s son, who has been linked to shady business deals as head of the <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> Welfare Fund for the Disabled, as `` Prince'' <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Pufang </PERSON> Intellectual disenchantment with <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> heightened after the student demonstrations two years ago, when he allowed, or perhaps instigated a numbing political campaign against Western liberal thought. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> also oversaw the ouster of his chosen successor, the reformist party chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>. It was <PERSON> Hu </PERSON>'s death on April 15 that touched off the current demonstrations. Intellectuals also chafe at <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s policy of pushing economic liberalization without tackling democratic reforms. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> has said political reform _ meaning mainly a reduction in the party's role in government and business _ will take a decade, and it will be at least 20 to 30 years before national elections are possible. For most of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 1.1 billion people, <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> is the man who emerged from the ultraleftist chaos of the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution to restore family farms, encourage private initiative and open <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to the outside world. But in the past year the economy has been staggered by 30 percent inflation, severe shortages of materials and energy, panic buying and pandemic corruption. Even the peasants, among the first to benefit when <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> moved quickly to break up the communes, are unhappy about soaring prices for fertilizer and feed and low prices for grain the state forces them to grow. `` I remember when I was in high school, we were taught to love <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>. And we really did love him,'' said one student from the countryside. `` But this time when I went home my family could barely feed me. If this is not <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>'s fault, then I do n't know who to blame.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0518EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--UnusualSentence     04-26 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Unusual Sentence,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Abortion Protesters Sentenced To Think About Civil Disobedience</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCHESTER, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group convicted for trespassing during an anti-abortion demonstration said they would defy their sentence of community service. So the judge decided to get tough. City Court Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Manning </PERSON> <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> on Tuesday sentenced the 11 to prepare two-page reports on civil disobedience after reading essays by <PERSON> Plato </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Thoreau </PERSON>. They had been convicted in December of trespassing at a hospital during a demonstration last May. `` I think it's a bold and honorable step on his part to fulfill his duty under oath to pronounce sentence, yet to honor our conscientious objections,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, leader of <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION>, a group that has conducted protests at abortion clinics. `` He's basically sentencing us to a dialogue with him about why we do what we do.'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said he and his co-defendants will obey the sentence because it does not require them to `` repay society for an evil done.'' <PERSON> Regan </PERSON> told them he has the `` deepest respect'' for their objection and ordered the essays sent to the court by June 16.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RamboKillings     04-26 0339</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rambo Killings,0351</SECOND>
<HEAD>Steiger Guilty on All Counts in Double Slaying; Faces Death Sentence</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK SEAVY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARTFORD, Conn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A college student described as obsessed with war games and sadomasochistic sex was convicted of murder Tuesday in the 1987 Rambo-style slayings of two men who broke up an outdoor party he was attending. <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, who could receive the death penalty, stared impassively as the verdict by a panel of three <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judges was announced after two days of deliberations. Judges <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keefe </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON> convicted <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, 25, of capital felony, two counts of murder and one count of conspiracy to commit capital murder in the July 11, 1987 slayings of <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON>, 25, and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, 25. The judges tentatively set sentencing for June 6. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mac </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, said he would apppeal. He also said he would file a motion to dispense with the penalty phase of the trial on grounds that the state's death penalty statute is unconstitutionally vague. The bearded, heavyset <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> is the great-grandson of the late <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, founder of the <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, Mass.-based <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>'s chain of department stores <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> and Price broke up a party on a cul-de-sac near the home <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON>'s family had just moved into, authorities said. One of them allegedly poked <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> in the nose with an iron bar. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON>, who was among the revelers, left the party, and went to his home, where he picked up two guns, and put on camouflage clothing and a black knit ski mask. He returned to <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON>'s home with two friends and shot <PERSON> Seymour </PERSON> and Price to death with a 9mm automatic pistol, firing at least 19 armor-piercing bullets at the victims. During the four-month trial, <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> was described as being obsessed with guns, war games and sadomasochism. <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> conceded that <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> shot the two men, but argued his client suffered from mental disease. <PERSON> Steiger </PERSON> chose to have his case decided by the judges rather than a jury.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-26 0722</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The wife of the late <PERSON> Shah </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> says she was reluctant to leave her homeland when her husband was deposed in 1979, and offered to stay behind as a symbol of hope for his supporters. `` I said to my husband, ` If you think you should go because it would calm things, then let me stay.' Not that I would have interfered politically, but if I had stayed, people would have seen his representative, and it might have given hope to our supporters,'' said deposed Empress <PERSON> Farah </PERSON> <PERSON> Diba </PERSON> in an interview in the June-July issue of Memories magazine. <PERSON> Farah </PERSON> said she's not sure the Islamic revolution that forced her husband from his Peacock Throne could have been avoided. `` Progress caused so any changes and brought with it so many problems,'' she said. `` We were trying, in one generation, to jump from feudal and semi-feudal conditions to the 20th century and beyond.'' She said if Iranians had known what his successor, <PERSON> Ayatollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruhollah </PERSON> <PERSON> Khomeini </PERSON> and his followers would be like, she's certain there would not have been a revolution. <PERSON> Farah </PERSON> has homes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Randy </PERSON> <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, voted favorite entertainer at the Viewers' Choice Awards by The <ORGANIZATION> Nashville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> cable channel, says he has n't tired of winning awards during his short four-year professional career. `` You can always find room for another one,'' said <PERSON> Travis </PERSON>, who has dominated country music awards for the past three years. <PERSON> Travis </PERSON> also won Best Album for `` Old 8 X 10'' at the second annual Viewers' Choice Awards presented Tuesday at the Grand Ole Opry House. <PERSON> Ricky </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelton </PERSON> won favorite male vocalist, No. 1 video and favorite song, both for `` I'll Leave This World Loving You,'' in voting by country music fans. <PERSON> Reba </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON> beat out rising star K.T. <PERSON> Oslin </PERSON> for favorite female vocalist. The <ORGANIZATION> Oak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boys </ORGANIZATION> won favorite group for the second straight year, and the quintet <ORGANIZATION> Shenandoah </ORGANIZATION> won favorite newcomer on the basis of its No. 1 song, `` The Church on <LOCATION> Cumberland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON>, 85, was presented a special award named after Grand Ole Opry comrade <PERSON> Minnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearl </PERSON> to honor his lifelong humanitarian endeavors. `` I hardly know what to say except it makes my heart feel good,'' <PERSON> Acuff </PERSON> said after receiving a standing ovation.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> is doggedly denying reports that she had attempted to smuggle <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>, her beloved Cairn terrier, into <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. `` We were given the wrong information, were n't we <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON>?'' said Ms. <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> during an interview in her dressing room at the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION> where she performed a benefit concert Tuesday night with <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. At the time of the incident April 9, Swedish authorities said they suspected the American singing star had attempted to slip the dog into the rabies-free country to circumvent a law requiring a four-month quarantine But Ms. <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> said they were barking up the wrong tree. She said she traveled by private bus to <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> because of an ear infection, and when they got to the border they were waved through. The next thing Ms. <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> knew, two Swedish customs officials were knocking at the hotel door, demanding that <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> be quarantined or face deportation. <PERSON> Lilly </PERSON> remained under house arrest at the Grand Hotel in <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> before being put on a plane for <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> paid a fine for breaking the law before leaving <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>. `` The law is the law,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ENGLEWOOD, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilford </PERSON>, no youngster himself, took part in a reading of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON> at a home for elderly actors on the 425th anniversary of the Bard's birth. The event was the 2nd Annual Edwin Forrest Day Celebration at the Actors' Fund Complex, which cares for about 50 entertainment industry members. Joining the 81-year-old <PERSON> Gilford </PERSON> for the readings Tuesday were entertainers <PERSON> Zoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Caldwell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barnard </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Moss </PERSON>, <PERSON> Patrice </PERSON> <PERSON> Munsel </PERSON> and <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> was the first idol in American theater and bequeathed a large share of his fortune to found the <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Forrest </PERSON> Home for Retired Actors in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> when he died in 1872. The Actors' Fund in <LOCATION> Englewood </LOCATION> is a result of the <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> home, said Actors' Fund spokeswoman <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Krull </PERSON> The Shakespearean readings were required in Forrest's will.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-WashingtonAuction     04-26 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Washington Auction,0314</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lincoln Letter Brings Top Price At Auction</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first newspaper account of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>'s inauguration failed to sell at a <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s auction Tuesday timed to coincide with the bicentennial celebration surrounding <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s swearing-in. The May 2, 1789 issue of the Gazette was the `` solitary disappointment'' of the sale, which otherwise brought in $ 1.4 million _ more than twice the pre-sale expectations, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said in a statement. The top item was an 1855 letter from <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> about his <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> defeat, which sold for $ 77,000 to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> dealer <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>. It was expected to bring at least $ 25,000. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> also bought an autograph letter of <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON> concerning a `` true history'' of his life for $ 20,900. Its pre-sale estimate was between $ 10,000 and $ 15,000. All prices include <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s 10 percent commission. The Gazette account of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s April 25, 1789 inauguration in lower <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> was expected to bring at least $ 10,000, but bidding stopped at $ 4,500 and the item was pulled. `` The market for early American newspapers at auction is not a large one,'' said <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s printed book expert, <PERSON> Selby </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiffer </PERSON>. Among the other Washington-related items, a 12-page excerpt from the diary of the man who served as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s secretary from 1786 to 1793 sold for $ 9,350, less than its pre-sale estimate of at least $ 15,000. It provides, among other entries, a version of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s memories of <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>'s treason in 1780 Two <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> letters also were sold: a 1780 letter to Gen. <PERSON> Nathanael </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON> commending his Revolutionary War service and a 1796 letter to <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>. Both letters had pre-sale estimates of at least $ 9,000. The Greene letter sold for $ 23,100 to <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Neville </PERSON>, a California-based dealer. The Marshall letter sold for $ 19,800. The name of the buyer was not available, <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890426-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-26-89 0234EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AbandonedPig     04-26 0240</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abandoned Pig,0246</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plight of Grunt the Homeless Half-Ton Pig Tugs at Citizen's Heartstrings</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARSON, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
