<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 2331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-RoseInvestigation 1stLd-Writethru a0719 06-26 0658</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rose Investigation, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0719,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rose Bet on Games Beginning in '85, Investigator Says</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with more details from report. No pickup.
A version moved on sports wires.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY78</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RONALD BLUM</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 and
</TEXT>
<NOTE>BEN WALKER</NOTE>
<NOTE>AP Sports Writers</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> bet on <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> games over a three-year span beginning in 1985, and once accumulated a $ 400,000 gambling debt over a three-month period, the sport's investigator concludes in a 225-page report released Monday. The report by baseball investigator <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON> was publicly released Monday by a state judge who had kept it private until after he ruled on <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>'s request for a temporary restraining order. `` Between May and July 1987, Rose bet ... $ 2,000 per game on baseball, including <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> games,'' the report said. <LOCATION> Hamilton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Common Pleas Judge <PERSON> Norbert </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nadel </PERSON> released the report Monday under pressure from the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, which said he had no reason to keep it sealed. <PERSON> Nadel </PERSON> on Sunday granted <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>'s request to block a hearing that was scheduled for Monday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> with baseball Commissioner <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON> <PERSON> Giamatti </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>'s manager, could be banned from the game for life if it is determined that he bet on the <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON>'s report said there was much evidence that he did, although it noted that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> has denied under oath he ever bet on major league baseball. `` The accumulated testimony of witnesses, together with documentary evidence and telephone records, reveal extensive betting activity by <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> with professional baseball and, in particular, <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> games, during the 1985, 1986 and 1987 seasons,'' <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON> said in the report. The report quotes <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> associate <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Janszen </PERSON> as saying `` within a three-month period of time, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> was in debt over $ 400,000 to the bookie in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>.'' It does not indicate if the debt was due to baseball debts or wagers on other sports. Rose bet 52 times on the <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> _ and won 29 _ from April 8-July 5, 1987, according to gambling records cited in <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON>'s report. <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON> cited telephone records and betting slips supplied by <PERSON> Janszen </PERSON>, who claims to have run bets for <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, as supporting evidence. He also said that evidence supports the testimony of bookmaker <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, who claims he took perhaps more than $ 1 million in bets on behalf of Rose over a two-year period. `` The evidence revealed that in order to protect his stature as one of the most famous baseball players in major league history, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> employed middlemen to place bets for him with bookmakers and at the raetrack and to pay gambling losses and collect gambling winnings, thereby concealing his gambling activity,'' <PERSON> Dowd </PERSON> wrote. Despite the $ 400,000 debt, the report said, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> had been successful early in the 1987 season in bets with <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>'s chief accuser <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, an associate of <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, recalled being told by <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> during the 1987 season that he was `` getting murdered'' by <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> on baseball. `` <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON> stated that <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> advised him that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> had him ` hooked' for ` about seventy-five thousand,' `` the report said. In addition, the report says that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> owned half of a $ 47,646 Pik-Six ticket at <LOCATION> Turfway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> on April 6, 1989. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gioiosa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>'s former housemate, `` falsely represented to the <ORGANIZATION> IRS </ORGANIZATION> that he was the sole winner,'' the report said. <PERSON> Gioiosa </PERSON> has been indicted for that and <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> is under investigation by a federal grand jury in <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. After the <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> beat <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> 5-3 Monday night, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> was asked if he believed the report was balanced. `` I can give you an outline,'' he said. `` There's 225 pages and there's two paragraphs positive about me. It's such a biased report it's unbelievable. But we will face that because there's not a thing we can do about it.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stachler </PERSON>, a Rose attorney, said he was not bothered that the report was made public. He declined further comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 2337EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Flag 1stLd-Writethru   06-26 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Flag, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0652,330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Undecided on Flag Amendment</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 5-7 bgng ``In an,'' with flag comments from interview.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> supports legislation to restore criminal penalties for flag-desecration, but has n't decided whether to back a constitutional amendment, his spokesman said Monday. `` We have n't undertaken a kind of legal analysis that would yield some definitive action,'' said press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. However, he said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s views were clear. `` He was very upset'' about last week's 5-4 <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling overturning flag-desecration laws in 48 states, `` and I'm sure -LRB- <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> -RRB- shares the views of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and others who have all expressed their feeling that the flag should not be desecrated in any way,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. In an interview published in Tuesday editions of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I think I've sublimated some of the passion I feel, and I'm very open-minded as to what to do about it. And I've asked our attorney general -LRB- <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> -RRB- and chief of staff -LRB- <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> -RRB- to recommend what to do about it. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told his interviewers the depth of his feeling possibly `` goes back to one's own personal experience in life, too, being in the service and all, in combat.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s plane was shot down and two crew members killed in 1945. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was rescued from the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> bu a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> submarine. `` Flag burning is wrong, dead wrong,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said after the ruling, but said he would enforce the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> edict as president. There have been moves in both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to meet the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>'s objections and make flag-desecration a federal offense, but lawmakers are divided on how best to accomplish that. Some favor an amendment to the Constitution. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is looking at possible legislation. But at this point we do n't have an official view in terms of legislation,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. `` But I think the president's attitude is certainly clear. And if legislation was developed and passed, I'm sure it would be one that he would support.'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said a `` preponderance of scholars seem to be suggesting that -LRB- a constitutional amendment -RRB- is not a very good way to go.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 2339EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Helmsley     06-26 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helmsley,0405</SECOND>
<HEAD>Helmsley Tax Evasion Trial Begins</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By VERA HALLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hotel queen <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> went on trial Monday on federal charges that she evaded income taxes by disguising about $ 4 million in renovations to her mansion as business expenses. Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>, 68, watched as potential jurors were questioned about their impartiality and how much they knew about the highly publicized case. By late afternoon, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> had interviewed 18 potential jurors and dismissed four. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> said he would screen the pool of 160 prospective jurors this week and allow attorneys to make their final peremptory challenges July 5 before opening arguments. One man was excused because he said he was upset about being asked his salary and because he was mad at judges in general for allowing the flag to be burned, referring to last week's <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision. The other potential jurors who were dismissed were a man who had read an article about Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> in Monday's <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>; an accountant who once did work for a company that will be named at trial; and a man who said he was angry with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> for the way it handled a tax problem. Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> was named in a 47-count indictment in April 1988 with her husband, <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>, and two former <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> executives. The Helmsleys, who head a $ 5 billion hotel and real estate empire, were accused of evading personal income taxes by concealing about $ 4 million in renovations to their <LOCATION> Greenwich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, mansion as business expenses. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>, 80, has been found incompetent to stand trial because of his memory lapses. The other defendants, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Turco </PERSON> and <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Licari </PERSON>, are charged with helping create bogus invoices to make it appear the renovations on the 28-room mansion were tax-deductible improvements on business properties. Many potential jurors said they knew the <ORGANIZATION> Helmsleys </ORGANIZATION> from media reports and Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON> from advertisements for her hotels that portray her as the `` queen'' of Helmsley-owned hotels. <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> allowed jurors to remain in the pool if they said they could be impartial. One answer given by a 28-year-old architect's intern prompted a cold stare from Mrs. <PERSON> Helmsley </PERSON>. The juror was asked what he knew of the Helmsleys from the media. `` He's old and feeble, and <PERSON> Leona </PERSON> runs things,'' the man said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 2349EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-German-Chemicals     06-26 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-German-Chemicals,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>Germany Moving Against Firm in Iran Chemical Weapons Deal</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The West German government is taking action against a German firm that has arranged the sale to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of chemicals that make poison gas, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials confirmed Monday night. The officials said Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> discussed the sale with Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> during <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>'s visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last week. `` We've been very happy'' with the German response, said one official, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Both officials said they did not have precise details of just what the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> government was doing in the case. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said in Tuesday editions that a <LOCATION> Dusseldorf </LOCATION> firm, which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials did not identify, had acted as a broker in arranging the sale to <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> of hundreds of tons of thionyl chloride, a chemical that can be used to make mustard gas, by an Indian manufacturer. The bulk of the chemicals was said not to have been delivered. Iranian troops were the targets of several gas attacks by <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> in the eight-year war between those two countries. Last winter, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials accused German firms of helping <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> built a plant that could be used to produce chemical weapons, though <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> insisted the plant would be used for pharmaceuticals. In response, the <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> government has proposed legislation to stiffen export controls and penalties for violating them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-UnisysDocuments     06-26 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Unisys Documents,0206</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Again Extends Sealing Order On Unisys Documents</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge Monday extended a sealing order on several documents seized by government agents who were looking for evidence that <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> bought information to help it win defense contracts. Judge <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> extended until July 27 the sealing order affecting documents taken from the offices of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> employees <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Elfering </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Geiger </PERSON>. The three were among those searched on June 14, 1988, in a nationwide sweep by federal agents investigating possible bribery of public officials, conspiracy and fraud in the defense department's procurement system A number of documents relating to searches of the <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> facilities of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> have been sealed at the government's request since June 16, 1988. Other documents have been made public since the initial sealing order was filed. On May 17, the court had extended the sealing order for several of the documents until June 26, when the government had believed that its need for continued sealing of the documents would end. However, because of scheduling conflicts, the government moved to extend the order until July 27 because it had been unable to proceed as quickly as expected.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0015EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-AgentOrange     06-26 1154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Agent Orange,1186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Vets Hope Agent Orange Decision Will Open Door for Benefits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report; dated matter in 22nd graf, `A scientific
...' ^By MITCHELL LANDSBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Maier </PERSON> believes he lost his arm in the service of his country. His country, until now, has disagreed. The arm _ a casualty of cancer, not combat _ was amputated at the shoulder seven years after <PERSON> Maier </PERSON>'s discharge from the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. But the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veteran, now 46 and living in <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, puts the blame for his cancer on Agent Orange, the toxic herbicide <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops sprayed over the jungles of southeast <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. He is convinced it was awash in the coffee-colored <LOCATION> Mekong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> water pumped aboard his ship for showers. Like more than 34,000 other <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans who believe they have become ill because of Agent Orange, <PERSON> Maier </PERSON> applied for government disability benefits. And like all but five of those applicants, he was denied. Now <PERSON> Maier </PERSON> hopes his claim will be reconsidered, thanks to a federal judge's ruling in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> last month that found the government failed to give Agent Orange claimants the benefit of the doubt. To the surprise of many veterans, the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration decided not to appeal. Instead, Veterans Secretary <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> announced that the Department of Veterans Affairs, the new name for the <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, would rewrite its rules for granting disability. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON>'s decision could open the door to claims from hundreds of thousands of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans. Although 34,000 have applied for disability on the basis of Agent Orange exposure, about 250,000 veterans are listed in a registry of those who believe they were exposed to the herbicide. Many never applied because they believed they did n't stand a chance of getting disability. Officials for some veterans' organizations say they're cautiously optimistic that the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has changed its attitude along with its name. `` It is our feeling at this point that Secretary <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> really does want to see some change,'' said <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kasinitz </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, the group that brought the lawsuit in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Others remain skeptical, their attitude reflecting the deep bitterness that many <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans feel toward a government that they believe used and abandoned them. `` We'll believe it when we see it,'' said <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Sparrow </PERSON>, the executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Vietnam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Victims </ORGANIZATION>, an advocacy group based in <LOCATION> Stamford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> `` It's my feeling that they'll probably do as little as they can,'' said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Hosty </PERSON>, an attorney for Swords to Plowshares, a <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> group that provides counseling and representation for veterans seeking benefits. Still, Ms. <PERSON> Hosty </PERSON> added, `` I would love to be surprised. I would love to be wrong.'' Agent Orange, named for the orange-striped drums in which it was stored, was developed for the military in the early 1940s. It was a 50-50 mixture of two powerful herbicides _ 2,4-D and 2,4,5-T. In <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops sprayed Agent Orange from the air to strip away the enemy's jungle cover and deplete its crops. It worked devastatingly well. The herbicide was banned after the chemical dioxin, which is present in 2,4,5-T, was found to be the most carcinogenic substance ever tested on laboratory animals. Veterans organizations have pointed to evidence that the herbicide may cause serious disorders, including non-Hodgkins lymphoma, soft-tissue sarcoma and a liver ailment known as PCT. The VA, on the other hand, has maintained that Agent Orange has been scientifically linked to only one illness in humans, a severe skin rash called chloracne. And the government has insisted that veterans seeking benefits because of chloracne provide proof that they got the rash from Agent Orange, a burden that has been impossible for most to meet. However, in what some veterans see as a partial admission of responsibility, the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has provided free medical care to anyone who believes he or she became ill because of Agent Orange. Under <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON>'s new orders, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> has begun redrafting its guidelines for disability benefits, starting by changing the way in which it determines whether a `` significant statistical association'' exists between Agent Orange and a disease. A scientific advisory committee planned to review the proposed changes at a meeting today with changes to be published in the Federal Register. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> will make a final decision on the changes, probably in October. Once new guidelines are in place, the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s advisory committee will reconsider whether links exist between Agent Orange and diseases that veterans believe it has caused. Again, a final decision will be up to <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON>. The stakes are high, as the makers of Agent Orange can attest. After veterans filed a lawsuit against them, seven chemical companies settled out of court for $ 180 million in 1984. <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> has said cost is irrelevant to the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>'s stance. Disability benefits, which are independent of medical benefits or Social Security, currently range from $ 73 a month for a veteran who is 10 percent disabled to $ 1,468 a month for a veteran who is 100 percent disabled. If just 30,000 veterans were found to be 10 percent disabled, the cost to the government would be more than $ 26 million a year. For that reason alone, some veterans' advocates say they doubt the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> will adopt sweeping changes. `` The VA would literally be opening the doors to tens of thousands of claims,'' said <PERSON> Sparrow </PERSON>. `` I just do n't see how they could do it.'' <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Juarbe </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> program for the Veterans of Foreign Wars, commended <PERSON> Derwinski </PERSON> for taking `` a step in the right direction.'' Still, <PERSON> Juarbe </PERSON> said, `` I think the bottom line is, we're still going to require legislation. ... Given the way the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION> has ruled in the past, we're not confident that we can rely on the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Veterans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> to carry out this policy.'' One such piece of legislation was introduced in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> earlier this month. A bill by <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., and <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Daschle </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.D. </LOCATION>, would provide disability benefits for veterans who have non-Hodgkins lymphoma or soft-tissue sarcoma, two of the diseases associated with Agent `` It is time to end the bickering over which study shows the most connection between Agent Orange and certain illnesses and time to begin helping <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> veterans,'' said <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> lieutenant who skippered a patrol boat in the <ORGANIZATION> Mekong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Claxton </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> sergeant who was, along with <PERSON> Maier </PERSON>, one of the original plaintiffs in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> lawsuit against the <ORGANIZATION> VA </ORGANIZATION>, said he is optimistic about prospects for change. `` I just want the satisfaction of seeing that people are treated with justice and compassion,'' said <PERSON> Claxton </PERSON>, 46, of <LOCATION> Lansing </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, who believes his exposure to Agent Orange caused bleeding colitis and a nervous disorder. However, he added: `` Personally, I do n't ever expect to be paid back for what Agent Orange did to me. You pay a heavy price for war.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Eccentrics     06-26 0436</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eccentrics,0453</SECOND>
<HEAD>Author Praises U.S. Eccentrics; Half in California</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One man's life work is hypnotizing frogs into pumping iron, and one woman used to get her paycheck from Bozo the Clown. `` Are we a little kooky?'' asks frog mesmerist <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Steed </PERSON>. `` Look at it this way. We work when we want to work, we make a fairly decent living, we make people happy and we're happy ourselves.'' Psychologist <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeks </PERSON> agrees. In an upcoming book, he says such people are among eccentric Americans who share many positive qualities. `` Many of their personality traits add up to a very good recipe for human happiness,'' said Weeks, of the <LOCATION> Royal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Edinburgh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>. True eccentrics, he said, have a sense of humor, intense curiosity, a high sense of integrity and a desire to make the world better or at least happier. Weeks has been studying offbeat people for the past five years, and in an earlier book, `` Eccentrics: The Scientific Investigation,'' focused on Europeans. His new book is about Americans, and about half his estimated 1,000 subjects are from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Weeks does n't believe Californians are by nature flaky. But <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> seems to take pride in its oddballs, he said in an interview published in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jose </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's very tolerant and proud and nurturing of eccentricity,'' he said. `` In some parts of the world, by contrast, eccentricity is denigrated. In <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, for example, they call them ratbags. Not in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.'' Among Weeks' subjects was <PERSON> Steed </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Emeryville </LOCATION> across the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> and has toured the fair circuit with 40 frogs and many laughs. His hypnotized frogs lie on their backs and lift tiny barbells with their front legs. <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoneberg </PERSON> is another Californian who became one of Weeks' subjects A former writer for <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s `` Bozo the Clown'' television show, <PERSON> Stoneberg </PERSON> said being eccentric is `` quite complimentary.'' `` I'd rather go down as an eccentric than as a routine, normal person,'' she says. <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Miner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> is an artist who sells religious television programming from her home. She says her eccentricity `` is meant to make everyone laugh and get a giggle.'' One time, she said, she tried to get a giggle out of the postmaster general of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by poking her finger in his stomach and saying, `` Ding, ding, ding.'' Weeks, 45, whose Scottish accent belies his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> birth, says eccentrics are curious because they're committed to whatever they're doing. But theirs is not a neurotic preoccupation because `` they're not really concerned about what other people think about them,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GrenadaTrial     06-26 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Grenada Trial,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Those Accused of Killing Caribbean Leader Wait and Wait</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT GLASS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ST. GEORGE'S, Grenada (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly six years after an army firing squad killed Prime Minister <PERSON> Maurice </PERSON> <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> after a military coup, 17 people accused in the slaying still await a final verdict. <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s death in a factional struggle within his ruling party helped lead to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> invasion of the island in 1983. The prisoners claim they were convicted in a U.S.-backed show trial to justify the invasion and eliminate the remaining inner circle of Bishop's Marxist regime. Of the 16 men and one woman, 14 are condemned to hang for murder. Three soldiers charged with the actual shooting face decades in prison for manslaughter. However, the prisoners are asking the Court of Appeal, <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>'s highest court, to throw out their December 1986 convictions for the killing of <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON> and several supporters Their appeal has been dragging on since May 1988, straining the tiny island's treasury and the patience of many of the nation's 90,000 residents, who have little sympathy for the prisoners `` The people are fed up with it,'' said <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierre </PERSON>, editor of the <ORGANIZATION> Grenadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION>, an independent weekly newspaper. `` It's been going on and on and on. ... They want it finished with.'' The original High Court trial lasted nearly eight months, and it took a year to produce a 9,000-page court record. The 13 defense lawyers won a six-month delay to prepare the appeal. Seven months into the appeal, the president of the three-judge court died, and the appeal had to start again with a new president. At the current pace, it will go on through fall because the six-lawyer prosecution team has n't even started its case. Meanwhile, the Grenadian government is paying court costs as well as the fees and expenses of the 10 Jamaican lawyers representing those prisoners who claimed indigency. So far, the case has cost the government $ 2.7 million, or 5 percent of the nation's annual $ 55 million budget. `` It's bleeding us, but we're prepared to spend that sort of money ... so that we can say, ` Look at the sacrifice we're prepared to make,''' to give the defendants a fair trial, said Justice Minister <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. The killing of <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>, a popular prime minister, resulted from a dispute over leadership of his radical People's Revolutionary Government. A hard-line <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, led by <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Coard </PERSON>, took control and placed the prime minister under house arrest. On Oct. 19, 1983, hundreds of Bishop supporters converged on his residence and set him free. However, troop reinforcements rushed in, allegedly on orders of the military council. <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>, three members of his Cabinet _ including his pregnant mistress, Education Minister <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleft </PERSON> _ and four other people were lined up against a wall and shot by three soldiers. A witness said one assailant slit <PERSON> Bishop </PERSON>'s throat long after he was clearly dead and also cut off a finger to steal a ring. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> ordered the invasion involving 1,900 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops and small forces from other <LOCATION> Carribean </LOCATION> island nations. He said he wanted to protect the lives of about 1,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizens in <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION> and help restore democracy. Those on death row include <PERSON> Coard </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Grenada </LOCATION>'s former deputy prime minister; his wife, <PERSON> Phyllis </PERSON>; the former armed forces commander, Gen. <PERSON> Hudson </PERSON> <PERSON> Austin </PERSON>; and the former ambassador to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornwall </PERSON>. The prisoners have accused authorities of human rights abuses ranging from withholding of sheets, blankets and underwear to beatings, bread-and-water diets and long periods of solitary confinement. Mrs. <PERSON> Coard </PERSON>, a former member of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who wrote a book in prison called `` <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> War on One Woman,'' claims she has been held in solitary confinement for the past 4 -LCB- years and allowed to see her husband only in court. Prime Minister <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Blaize </PERSON> scoffed at the prisoners' allegations, and <PERSON> Terrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Marryshow </PERSON>, leader of the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Maurice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bishop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION>, called them `` only the victims of a situation that they themselves created.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0040EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Spill'sReach 2Takes   06-26 1205</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spill's Reach, 2 Takes,1235</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Three Months, Blot of Oil Still Spreads Across Alaska Coastline</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Sunday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Oil Spill Rdp</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three months have passed, and the sea still coughs up dead birds with every change of the tide. Three months have passed, and an army of workers 9,000 strong has yet to completely clean even one heavily oiled beach. Three months have passed, and the biggest oil spill in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history gets bigger every day, spreading its slime farther across <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s wild southern coast, pushing its poison deeper and higher along the food chain. `` We keep hoping for some kind of closure, some sign that this is all the damage we have and we can deal with it,'' says <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Castellina </PERSON>, superintendent of Kenai Fjords National Park. `` But we ca n't. The oil disappears one day when the waves clean a beach, only to wash up on another beach the next day.'' Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>'s bountiful waters and mountainous islands were the first to be fouled after the tanker Exxon Valdez rammed a reef March 24 and spilled almost 11 million gallons of North Slope crude oil. But the damage did n't stop there. Streamers of oil and tar balls leaked out between the sound's barrier islands and were pushed by Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> currents to beaches 450 miles away. Oil now has tainted more than 700 miles of shoreline, from the glacier-carved cliffs of Kenai Fjords to the clamoring bird rookeries of Katmai National Park, from lonely <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION> beaches to the mouths of <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> salmon streams. Cleanup workers have found the oil-soaked bodies of about 26,000 sea birds, 784 sea otters and 57 bald eagles. The spreading oil has other victims. Fishermen and other coastal residents who make their living from the ocean cringe each week at news of more beaches polluted and more fishing grounds closed. The wreck of the Exxon Valdez created an environmental catastrophe that unfolds in one little tragedy after another: _ A wildlife official filming damage on a beach sets a video cassette down on a black rock, and the rock crawls away It turns out to be an oil-smeared duck. _ A burly fisherman breaks into tears as he describes steering his boat through the slick: no water lapping, no birds crying, just the sickening silence of oil slipping past the hull _ At a bird rescue center in <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION>, some of the patients are failing They have been washed clean, but not before swallowing fatal doses of oil. They do n't cry out; instinct tells them not to advertise their distress to predators. `` They just get real quiet, sit in a corner and die,'' says rescue coordinator <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Holcomb </PERSON>. Like a candy bar in the hands of a 2-year-old, crude oil from the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> has gotten onto everything. Rainbow sheens on the water stream from suffocating mats of black goop on beaches. Wind and waves whip oil into a sticky froth that workers call `` chocolate mousse.'' Tar balls bob in the surf, washing ashore to melt in the sun and sink into the sand. Oil splatters driftwood logs high above the tide line and sinks as much as 3 feet into gravel beaches. Undulating blobs of oil hang below the water's surface, ready to foul fishermen's nets. At first, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> boldly promised to clean it all up. `` We're going to pick up _ one way or the other _ all the oil that's out there,'' <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornett </PERSON> told reporters one week after the Exxon Valdez ran aground. The promise did n't keep for long. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> was too slow and the spill was too big for booms to contain the oil immediately after the accident. And the company missed its chance during the first few days to burn off large quantities of oil or disperse it with chemicals. Some oil was skimmed up, but for the most part <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> had to wait for oil to wash up on shore, where the goo could be scraped, wiped or flushed painstakingly from rocks and gravel. By May 1, the clean-it-all promise had been modified. Exxon proposed to clean 364 miles of coastline by mid-September, noting that it might have to leave 191 additional miles of lightly oiled shore to be washed by nature. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> approved <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s plan, but even the limited cleanup may prove beyond the company's capability, despite an investment of more than $ 200 million to date. The cleanup effort now includes more than 9,000 workers, 800 boats, 45 oil skimmers, and 60 airplanes and helicopters. Hundreds of workers clad in rain slickers and hard hats crowd into coves that in most years might see a few fishermen or recreational boaters, if anyone at all. Barges nose up to shore, carrying generators and boilers to heat the water sprayed from hoses on the beach. Skimmers just offshore pick up oil as it flushes off the beach, while yet more vessels tend containment booms to keep the washed-off oil from spreading. Where there is n't enough machinery, workers hit the beaches with shovels, absorbent pads and plastic bags, scooping and scraping and wiping by hand. `` It has become pretty labor-intensive,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Amos </PERSON> <PERSON> Plante </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, which is overseeing <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s cleanup effort, has `` signed off'' on about 50 miles of shoreline along Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. But that does n't mean a beach is clean _ it just means <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> can move on. Even the most intensive scrubbing can not touch oil imbedded deep within a beach. The word `` clean'' is now taboo on official forms used to track <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s efforts. Workers do n't clean beaches anymore. They `` treat'' them. The difference is more than semantics, as a visit to a Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> beach with a state environmental official shows. `` This,'' says <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Provant </PERSON> as he kicks an oily rock, `` is a treated beach.'' Provant, the on-scene cleanup coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> Alaska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION>, is standing on a <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> beach known to officials as GR-1A. The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> signed off on this beach May 29, declaring that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> crews had `` completed removal of gross contamination.'' Provant saw it back then, and it looked pretty good, he says. But now the oil is back. Globs of mousse litter the cobbled beach. Rainwater beads up on the rocks as it would on the waxed hood of a car. Provant digs into the sand, and his hand comes up greasy brown. `` If you dig, you find oil down quite a ways,'' Provant says. `` You can see how much oil has been washed back in or has percolated up from below. We're really not through with this beach.'' Provant's agency hounds <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, suggesting ways the cleanup could run more efficiently. Exxon, state and federal officials spend hours each day arguing over how deeply to clean particular beaches, or whether cleaning them will do more harm than good. `` Everybody wants a clean beach, us included,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Plante </PERSON> `` The definition of clean is subject to interpretation. What we're obviously going to do is work as hard to do the best job we can. We may have some disagreements over whether it's sufficiently clean.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Spill'sReach-1stAdd     06-26 0561</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Spill's Reach - 1st Add,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>VALDEZ: sufficiently clean.''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 While the arguments rage onshore, the death toll mounts at sea. Stymied by vast distances and stormy weather, bird rescuers have been able to capture, clean and release only about 500 sea birds. For every surviving bird, more than 50 dead ones lie in freezer vans _ more than 26,000 in all. And that's just a fraction of total mortality. Some biologists say that for every dead bird collected, perhaps 100 have died unnoticed. Sea otters appear to be the hardest-hit marine mammal. The 784 dead sea otters collected so far represent about one-tenth of Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>'s total population. Harbor seals may be suffering, too, but few carcasses have been found. `` Dead seals sink like lead balloons,'' explains state marine biologist <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Frost </PERSON>. The oil's lethal reach extends down the food chain. On some beaches, mats of oil have wiped out all life, suffocating intertidal creatures such as limpets, mussels, crabs and starfish. And the oil reaches upward, to the tops of tall shoreside spruce trees where bald eagles roost. Oiled sea birds have become a fatal attraction for scavenging eagles, killing 57 of the birds of prey. Biologists have collected lifeless eggs from 30 abandoned eagle nests in the spill area. Hungry brown bears on the shores of Katmai National Park have feasted on oily bird carcasses until they could eat no more, digging holes in the sand to cache the leftovers. Bears are hardy creatures, but biologists have radio-collared 30 of them to study their reaction to swallowing so much oil. `` We have n't determined what effect it has on them. But I can imagine what it would do to me,'' says Katmai National Park Superintendent <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Bane </PERSON>. At the very top of the food chain are the humans who live close to nature in coastal villages. When Aleut natives complained that the oil spill kept them from gathering food through fishing and seal-hunting, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> flew in cases of beef, chicken and diced ham. It gave the villagers stomachaches. Many commercial fishermen have been idled by the spill, though some have landed jobs with <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>, leasing their boats at rates of $ 3,400 a day and more. Most of the salmon and halibut swimming beneath the oil appear to be surviving. But fisheries worth more than $ 110 million have been canceled or postponed by <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> officials worried that surface oil might taint fish as they are hauled from the water in fishermen's nets As spring turns to summer, even <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> officials are starting to waver on the question of finishing the cleanup by mid-September, a deadline long dismissed as unrealistic by some state and federal officials. `` It's always a hope,'' says <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Plante </PERSON>. `` But it's tougher to predict whether we'll do it by then. That's our plan. We've always said we will not leave it uncleaned, and if that means coming back, so be it. The sooner the better for all concerned _ particularly for 120 frisky sea otters now swimming restlessly in floating pens. They've beaten the odds, thanks to rescuers at an otter hospital in <LOCATION> Seward </LOCATION> The animals are clean, healthy and ready to return to the wild. But they must stay put, biologists say, because the wild is not ready for them.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-LogElection     06-26 0697</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Log Election,0715</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oregonians Vote On Keeping Logs Home To Save Jobs</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Monday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GRANTS PASS, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> voters face a measure Tuesday that urges <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to let the state halt shipments of raw logs overseas when domestic lumber mills are starving for timber and workers' jobs are jeopardized. The ballot proposal, called Measure 2, seeks to ban export of logs cut on state land and calls on <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to make permanent a ban of export of logs cut on federal land. Both supporters and opponents view Measure 2 as a symbolic test of the public will with jobs at mills jeopardized by both the high prices for raw logs and by environmentalist lawsuits aimed at protecting the rare Northern spotted owl and the ancient forests where they live. `` This is the first opportunity anybody in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has had to say ` We want timber jobs, we need timber jobs.' That's really the issue on Tuesday,'' said <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Stout </PERSON>, vice president for lands and timber for <ORGANIZATION> Bohemia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a lumber company in <LOCATION> Eugene </LOCATION> that has contributed $ 100,000 in support of Measure 2. But because of a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruling on the same issue five years ago, the options of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> voters are strictly limited. The high court ruled that only <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has the right to restrict trade, declaring an <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> law banning log exports unconstitutional. Because of the ruling, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would have to pass enabling legislation for the state export ban to become effective, even if it is passed Tuesday as most expect it will. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is seeking just the opposite, having proposed to lift a ban of exports of logs cut on federal land, currently in effect on a year-to-year basis, to take advantage of premium prices paid by log buyers in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. Within the timber industry itself, opinions are mixed. Many companies make money exporting unprocessed logs, while others are struggling obtain logs for their mills. The <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rim </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which opposes export restrictions, has decided to concentrate its efforts on defeating the enabling legislation in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, rather than seeking victory in Tuesday's referendum, said association executive director <PERSON> Rolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Glerum </PERSON>. `` We did n't feel we could raise the money to fight'' Measure 2, said <PERSON> Glerum </PERSON>. `` Even if we were to win it, it still would n't have any effect. The whole thing is triggered by the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' The group's members include <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the leading exporter of raw logs in the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, as well as stevedoring companies, shippers and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Longshoremen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Warehousemen </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>. `` One reason we oppose this is we feel it is the camel's nose under the tent,'' said <PERSON> Glerum </PERSON>, because supporters `` would just as soon see all log exports banned.'' Indeed, a recent White Paper from the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> pointed to stopping all log exports as a quick fix to the timber supply crunch that has plagued <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> mills the past year. <PERSON> Glerum </PERSON> and other opponents expect Measure 2 to pass. A recent poll by The Oregonian newspaper showed support running more than 8-to-1. A campaign spending report from May 26 showed Citizens to Save Oregon Jobs raised nearly $ 800,000 to push for passage, primarily from non-exporting timber companies. `` We're talking primarily about <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> logs for <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> jobs,'' said <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Amedeo </PERSON>, a lobbyist who serves on the steering committee for the campaign. `` The big battle, because it is a non-traditional election date, is to get enough voters to the polls. `` I think in terms of sending a message back to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, which is part of what the ballot measure does, the more people who vote, the more significant the message.'' State Rep. <PERSON> Bernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Agrons </PERSON> was one of the few voices in the Legislature opposing the measure. A former vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Weyerhaeuser </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Agrons </PERSON> said the measure would deprive the common school fund and counties of revenues from state timber. Last year, $ 12.5 million in state timber revenues went to the common school fund and $ 18.3 million went to local governments, predominantly schools. Export logs are generally considered to bring a premium price about 25 percent higher than domestic logs.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0105EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TroubledMayor Bjt   06-26 0650</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Troubled Mayor, Bjt,0670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Troubled Tom Bradley Readies for Fifth Inauguration</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE V. BIGELOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> prepared to be sworn in Friday for an unprecedented fifth term, but investigations into his finances and ethics are putting a damper on party plans. The inaugural party, to be held on the south lawn of <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hall </LOCATION>, is expected to be `` a day of celebration and at the same time reflection,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Chandler </PERSON>, a mayoral spokesman. The 71-year-old <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> rose through the ranks of the police department and <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to become the first black mayor of a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city when he defeated <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Yorty </PERSON> in 1973 following a bitter campaign. These days, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> points with pride to the city's emergence as the gateway to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rim </LOCATION>, as the successful host of the 1984 Summer Olympic games and to a downtown redevelopment effort. In April's non-partisan primary, he defeated City Councilman <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> with 52 percent of the vote, just enough to avoid a general election. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was expected to soar past <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>, but found himself wounded by disclosures about his financial ties with savings banks that do business with the city. Newspaper reports prompted the city attorney to begin a conflict-of-interest investigation on March 31. The state <ORGANIZATION> Fair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Political </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Practices </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> later joined the investigation. Deeper digging into <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s investments yielded questions about whether he had traded political favors for preferential treatment at <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Burnham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lambert </ORGANIZATION>, the investment banking firm. This in turn prompted inquiries by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. In a surprise address to the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> on May 10, the taciturn <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said he made `` an error in judgment by engaging in outside employment.'' But <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> maintained he did nothing illegal, and said he expects to be vindicated in the still-pending inquiries. Since the speech, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> has maintained silence about details of his investments, denying interview requests. The spurt of disclosures about <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> appears to have tapered off in recent weeks, although investigations apparently have gone in new directions. One trail, which ran to <ORGANIZATION> Drexel </ORGANIZATION> investments by <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Majority Whip <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, led the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Democrat to resign. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s amalgam of labor, minority and business support has remained largely intact throughout the controversy, although his influence over the City Council has diminished. Some say one barometer of the mayor's strength is with his proposal to the council last year to raise the cap on <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Redevelopment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> spending downtown to $ 5 billion from $ 750 million. The money would be spent on revitalizating blighted parts of downtown; expanding child care, services for the homeless; and building affordable housing for low-income residents. The council is considering creating an oversight committee for the agency, cutting into the mayor's control. A hearing is scheduled for Tuesday to discuss how much power such a committee would have. Even <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s friends say the mayor does n't hold as much clout as he once did. `` There's no question that -LRB- <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> -RRB- has been tarnished by the many stories, some of which I regard as frivolous and some bordering on yellow journalism,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, executive secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> and a longtime <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> political ally. `` It's been my experience that politicians, and especially a powerful politician, when he's in trouble, the sharks smell the blood and they go for the jugular,'' <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> has continued to support <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, calling him a `` person of high integrity.'' `` Judgments should n't be made until all the issues have all been thoroughly explored,'' he said. `` There is not a feeling that it's all over,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> confidante <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON> said of the mayor's career. `` He's held his head up high through all of this.'' Still, <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON> conceded, `` You have a feeling underneath that he knows that he's walking more carefully and not twisting arms as forcefully as he might've in the past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0111EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Pinch-HitterPilots Bjt   06-26 0756</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pinch-Hitter Pilots, Bjt,780</SECOND>
<HEAD>Course Prepares Passengers to Fly the Plane</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FREDERICK, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a pinch, you can fly a plane. At least that's what instructors in a unique eight-hour flying course try to convince pilots' spouses and others who might be forced to fly and land a plane in an emergency. It is rare for a heart attack, food poisoning or other sudden illness to disable a pilot in mid-flight. But it happens once or twice a year, and sometimes with dramatic results as air traffic controllers help a novice find an airport and safely land. The ground school instructor in a recent course sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Owners </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> asked <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, 52, of <LOCATION> Graysonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, how she felt about the prospect of taking the controls of her husband's <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> 201. `` I'm scared to death,'' she said. But after four hours of flying with an instructor in the `` pinch-hitter'' course that has taught 35,000 non-pilots the fundamentals of flying, Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said, `` I feel a lot different about our little plane. I think I understand it better.'' While the course covers only small planes, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, who is in charge of flight instruction for the foundation, said that in the unlikely event an airliner's flying crew was disabled, he'd `` go with the odds'' and ask a trained pinch-hitter to take the controls. One student described herself as a former stewardess and said she took the course because `` if you can work the back end of a plane, you should be able to work the front end.'' Another trainee, <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bradford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, told the class that after her husband's parents were killed in the crash of their small plane, her husband, <PERSON> David </PERSON>, stopped flying for more than 10 years. She bounced the family's <PERSON> Piper </PERSON> <PERSON> Archer </PERSON> twice on the runway before bringing it down undamaged with a little help from her pinch-hitter instructor. `` I thought it was nerve-wracking,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Zuckerman </PERSON> said. `` But I loved taking off. I never thought it was so easy and so much fun. I think I could land it if I had to.'' <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Scranton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, who survived a crash with her husband four years ago, said she thinks the course is a necessity for a pilot's wife. But after the crash it took him a while to convince her to take the class, she said. Once in the air, people who have never flown a plane find it deceptively simple. A push forward on the steering yoke and the aircraft descends. A pull back and it climbs. Steering left or right is almost like steering a car, but on the ground, steering is done by foot pedals, not the yoke. Engine speed is controlled with a hand throttle, but trainees often forget that putting the plane into a descent will also speed it up and climbing will slow it down. The four-hour ground school aims to build confidence, but it also includes a basic explanation of what makes a plane fly and a description of its parts and instruments. Started in 1961, the weekend course is taught about 20 times a year, each time at a different airport around the country. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Busch </PERSON>, flight training director for the foundation, said about a third of the trainees go on to get pilot licenses. Only a handful ever actually have to fly with a disabled pilot, <PERSON> Busch </PERSON> said. In 1983, pinch-hitter graduate <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> was in the right rear seat of her husband's plane when he suffered a heart attack and died. A 78-year-old woman, <PERSON> Edith </PERSON> <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON>, was sitting by the right-side controls, but the owners and pilots group gave Mrs. <PERSON> Turner </PERSON> an award for taking over the radio and coaching and assisting Mrs. <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> through a safe landing. It takes 40 to 60 hours of flying to qualify for a regular pilot license and costs $ 3,500 to $ 4,000. The pinch-hitter training costs $ 240, not including use of an aircraft. Trainees are encouraged to use the plane they regularly ride in as a passenger, but they also may rent one. Ideally, the course culminates in the pinch-hitter landing the plane unassisted by the instructor. `` I'm not really sure how much control I had over the plane in that final landing,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said after completing the course. `` If, God help me, the time ever comes when I have to fly on my own, then ... well, <PERSON> God </PERSON> help me,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0114EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-26 0886</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0924</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British punk rock star <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Idol </PERSON> must pay nearly $ 23,000 in medical expenses and damages to a woman who was trampled during one of his concerts, an arbitrator has ruled. <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>, 31, was sitting in the second row at Memorial Coliseum for the May 13, 1987, concert when she was trampled by a crowd that rushed the stage at Idol's invitation, according to court documents. Idol called to the crowd, `` I'm lonely. Come on down here.'' <PERSON> Hammond </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Casey </PERSON>, said his client was knocked to the floor and pinned under folding chairs while the crowd stepped on her. She suffered multiple sprains and contusions. <PERSON> Clifford </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Olsen </PERSON>, a retired <LOCATION> Multnomah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> circuit judge who was the arbitrator, said in the June 15 ruling that <PERSON> Idol </PERSON> acted `` in deliberate disregard of the safety.'' Idol, whose real name is <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Broad </PERSON>, said in his deposition that he did n't remember the concert.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OKLAHOMA CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be inducted into the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cowboy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hall </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fame </ORGANIZATION> during ceremonies July 21. `` We are honored to include him among the greatest Westerners of our time,'' said <PERSON> Byron </PERSON> <PERSON> Price </PERSON>, director of the hall. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> will be inducted into the hall's Hall of Great Westerners, which salutes people who made significant contributions to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> heritage, and the Western Performers Hall of Fame, which honors actors whose movie and television portrayals have kept the lore and legacy of the Old West alive. As the one-time host of the television program `` Death Valley Days'' and star of `` <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trail </ORGANIZATION>'' and several other Western movies, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> exemplified the cowboy hero admired by generations of fans, museum officials said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Col. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, the promoter who helped transform <PERSON> Elvis </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON> from a <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> truck driver into an entertainment legend, was honored at a gala dinner marking his 80th birthday. Saturday night's party was at the <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hilton </LOCATION>, where Presley set attendance records. <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotels </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Barron </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilton </PERSON> called <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> a `` living legend'' who could have achieved any goal he desired _ from the business world to politics. Telegrams of congratulations were read from a variety of political and entertainment figures, including President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hope </PERSON>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cosby </PERSON> and <PERSON> Presely </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Priscilla </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolff </PERSON>, the sole surviving member of the Untouchables, said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> once asked him to join his gang. In an interview in Sunday's <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sun-Times </ORGANIZATION>, the 86-year-old former lawman said he was on vacation in <LOCATION> Hot </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ark. </LOCATION>, when <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> spotted him. `` I can remember this so clearly: <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> walking up to ask me if I was ` Wallpaper,''' recalled <PERSON> Wolff </PERSON>, who earned the nickname by searching rooms so thoroughly he'd go through everything but the wallpaper. `` He said he would love to have me join him,'' <PERSON> Wolff </PERSON> said. `` You know, work for him. I told him that I would live longer if I did n't.'' <PERSON> Wolff </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> policeman before joining the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prohibition </ORGANIZATION>, was an adviser for the 1987 movie, `` The Untouchables,'' with <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON> as <PERSON> Eliot </PERSON> <PERSON> Ness </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Get this: Comedian <PERSON> Louie </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> sold his house to a magician. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, who was featured with sitcom actress <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON> in `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Fun Couple Summer Tour,'' sold his two-story house in <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> to an unidentified <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> magician, said <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawyer </PERSON>, his real estate representative. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> also appeared in the <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> movie `` Coming to <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' and is in `` The <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> Hour,'' scheduled for broadcast in April. <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>'s home was built on property once owned by <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>. Lawyer said <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> bought the house two years ago, at a price which was not disclosed. He sold it during the past two weeks for nearly $ 600,000, Lawyer said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ST. MORITZ, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Voters in this luxury resort gave Dutch brewery tycoon <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Heineken </PERSON> approval to tear down a 72-year-old villa that some wanted to preserve as a historic monument. Eighty-five percent of the 1,431 voting residents rejected a proposal to bar destruction of the <ORGANIZATION> Villa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boehler </ORGANIZATION>, according to official results Sunday. <ORGANIZATION> Heineken </ORGANIZATION>, 65, touched off protests in 1984 when he asked authorities to allow removal of the villa, which he bought for a reported $ 2.7 million the year before. He said the `` revolting yellow monstrosity'' partially obstructs the view from a house on adjacent land that he bought decades ago, and sought approval for replacing the villa with an annex to his multimillion-dollar pied-a-terre. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutishauser </PERSON>, chief curator of monuments in <LOCATION> Grisons </LOCATION> canton, argued the villa, built for an Austrian industrialist by renowned German architect <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Tessenow </PERSON> in 1917, is unique and should be officially protected.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON> recently married a dancer 31 years younger than him, vowing to make this marriage _ his fourth _ work. <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON>, 53, who has appeared in such films as `` Easy Rider'' and `` Blue Velvet,'' said he met <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> LaNasa </PERSON>, a ballerina and choreographer, two years ago. `` It was love at first sight,'' he said. The couple tied the knot at the <ORGANIZATION> Wayfarers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chapel </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rancho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verdes </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, about 30 miles from their <LOCATION> Venice </LOCATION> home. `` I am going to work on this one,'' <PERSON> Hopper </PERSON> said in this week's People magazine
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Senators'Trips Bjt   06-26 0667</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senators' Trips, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Many Senators Cut Privately Funded Travel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senators facing re-election in 1990 have cut down on privately financed travel that sometimes takes them to pricey resorts, according to a study of financial disclosures. The group, comprising almost a third of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, took 179 privately financed trips in 1988 compared with 223 in 1987. Such travel _ usually paid for by corporate and trade associations _ has been severely criticized this year by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and private organizations. The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> study of 33 senators was based on travel statistics compiled on the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION>, an organization founded by consumer advocate <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> that culled the data from 1988 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> financial disclosure reports filed last month. Senators are required to list all reimbursed travel expenses totaling at least $ 250. The lawmakers were not surveyed on why the number of trips dropped. While legal, the trips leave members in potential conflicts of interest involving special interest groups that are pushing for passage or defeat of legislation. The invitations often include airfare, several days at a resort or top-of-the-line hotel, and expenses for a spouse. Task forces in both houses are considering whether to eliminate speaking honoraria in return for a congressional pay raise, but an end of those fees _ up to $ 2,000 per speech _ would not necessarily prevent privately funded travel. `` Many of these junkets are designed to give lobbyists the chance to fraternize with lawmakers, frequently at pricey resorts, and provide special interest groups with yet another opportunity to gain access and influence with members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' said <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Claybrook </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Watch </ORGANIZATION>'s parent group, Public Citizen. Those who traveled frequently, however, probably have little to fear from the voters, according to two political scientists, <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> associated with the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do n't think it will be a devastatingly effective campaign weapon in 1990,'' said <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON>, unless the travel has caused a senator to miss votes. `` You're going to have much more luck slamming a guy for doing it on public expense than at the expense of private interests,'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said. `` The public reaction is, ` We do n't give a damn if it's taken out of special interests, but do n't take it out of our pockets.''' <PERSON> Thurber </PERSON> said there were few studies on voters' reaction to congressional trips, but added it was his `` gut reaction'' that the trips `` play almost no role in the way they evaluate the performance of a member of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>.'' The AP found that among those whose current six-year terms are winding down: _ Eighteen traveled on fewer privately paid trips in 1988 than in 1987, while 10 increased their travel and five had the same number of trips in both years The ratio becomes 18-9 in favor of reduced travel when <PERSON> Sens </PERSON>. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, D-Colo., and <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, are subtracted from the list Both have announced their retirement. _ The gap in the number of trips is greater, 164 in 1988 compared with 223 in 1987, without Sen. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> McClure </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, who listed no trips in 1987 and 15 in 1988 _ Six senators facing re-election were among the top 15 privately financed travelers in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> They are Democrats <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, 24 trips; <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Exon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, 23 trips, <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnston </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, 21 trips; <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>, 21 trips; and Republicans <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, 24 trips, and <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, 21 trips. Public Citizen found that all senators took more than 1,100 privately financed trips during the 100th <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, led by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>. with 37; <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, 34; <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif., 33; <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Bumpers </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ark </LOCATION>., 30 and Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, Senators who did not accept privately paid travel during the period were Sens. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>,; <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0123EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-Massacre 1stLd-Writethru a0428 06-26 0277</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Massacre, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0428,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>About 30 People Massacred On Mindanao Island</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: To CORRECT to guerrillas, sted villagers, SUB 6th graf, `Villagers
exchanges ...' Picks up 7th, `Maralit ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist rebels raided a mountain village in a remote area of <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION> island and massacred about 30 people as they worshipped in a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> church, the military said Monday. The raiders beheaded three people, including a <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> minister, before fleeing, the report said. Lt. Col. <PERSON> Cresencio </PERSON> <PERSON> Maralit </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION>, said the incident occurred early Sunday in the village of <LOCATION> Rano </LOCATION>, about 640 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Maralit </PERSON> said many of the villagers had joined an anti-Communist vigilante group and had refused to pay `` revolutionary taxes'' to the communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. According to <PERSON> Maralit </PERSON>, about 40 members of the <PERSON> Ubo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bagobo </PERSON> tribes had gathered inside a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> chapel for morning worship when about 100 guerrillas arrived. Guerrillas exchanged gunfire for about 15 minutes with members of the congregation, who were armed, <PERSON> Maralit </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Maralit </PERSON> identified the dead pastor as <PERSON> Abadi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayap </PERSON>. But a denomination official in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> said records indicated no such pastor by that name. Bishop <PERSON> Erme </PERSON> <PERSON> Camba </PERSON>, secretary-general of the denomination, said the victim could have been a lay pastor. The bishop said he was still trying to verify the report. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> has been widely criticized by the military for alleged links with <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rebels because of the denomination's outspoken stand on human rights. In the past, most beheadings in <LOCATION> Mindanao </LOCATION> have been carried out by religious fanatics who are frequently used by the military to fight the Communists.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SenateSilhouettes     06-26 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Senate Silhouettes,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: Senators of the Past Cut a Fine Figure</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At 400 pounds, Sen. <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> was the weightiest person ever to serve in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, a Democrat who served first in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, then in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, was so heavy he had difficulty finding a carriage driver willing to take the risk of hauling all those pounds. Once, wrote <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s assistant doorkeeper for much of the 19th century, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> `` got into a hack and went right through the bottom, onto the ground _ and if the horses had not been very tame he would have been killed.'' Sen. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> _ and the extreme rotundity of his profile _ is presiding this summer over the marble-clad rotunda of the <ORGANIZATION> Russell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Office Building, looming from a balcony in the form of a giant, shadow-casting silhouette. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and the silhouettes of six of his senatorial colleagues of his era form the somewhat whimsical background of an exhibit illustrating the triumph and travail experienced by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in its first 100 years, 1789-1889. Born in 1802, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> served in the House for 15 years. He was appointed to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1844, dying four years later. <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON>, who made good use of his powers of observation during his 60 years of service to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, noted that <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> rarely rose from his specially constructed and commodious chair to address the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON> wrote that <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> told him the reason `` was that he was so big and fat that I would have to fan him, and it would not look very dignified in such a body as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.'' But if <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> was an infrequent speaker, he did listen intently to the major addresses of others. On Jan. 26, 1830, he walked across the Capitol and joined the throng crowding into the chamber of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, determined to hear Sen. <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> defend the federal union. The `` enormous'' congressman was given a seat in the tiny lobby behind the presiding officer's chair where he became wedged in by other spectators. Because he was separated from the chamber by a painted glass screen, he could hear <PERSON> Webster </PERSON> but could not see him. Describing the scene, <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON> said the frustrated congressman `` deliberately pulled out his knife and removed the obstructing paint on the glass.'' But the operation `` caused quite a noise,'' <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON> said. `` Everybody was looking to see where that scratching came from.'' Finally, <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON> said, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> cleared an area `` as large as a man's hand,'' obtaining a `` good view'' of the famous <PERSON> Webster </PERSON>. The senatorial silhouettes, originally made on paper during the 1840s and 1850s and now reproduced larger than life, bring together an unuusal cast of characters. Joining <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> in larger-than-life profile is, for example, Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, a thin, stick-like figure described as `` one of the most brilliant, deranged and pathetic men ever to serve in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> was known to stride into the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> followed by a pack of hunting hounds while flicking a riding crop and drinking a cup of beer. Abusive in speech, he once provoked a duel with Sen. <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> from which both men emerged unscathed. <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> lived to be 99, dying in 1833 just days before his 100th birthday. Also on the railing above the rotunda floor is a far less colorful lawmaker, Sen. <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Grundy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, who was described by doorkeeper <PERSON> Bassett </PERSON> as a consummate insider and master of parliamentary tactics. Near <PERSON> Grundy </PERSON> is Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Forsyth </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> who cut a more visible public swath with blistering oratory and cutting wit. Informed that President <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s opponents were forming the new Whig party, <PERSON> Forsyth </PERSON> remarked: `` It is a glorious name, and I have no doubt they will disgrace it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HolyGrail     06-26 0662</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Holy Grail,0685</SECOND>
<HEAD>Indiana Jones And the Truth About the Holy Grail</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SONNI EFRON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Holy Grail may not exist but it's a proven moneymaker. Scholars say the makers of the blockbuster movie `` Indiana <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and the Last Crusade'' are just the latest to cash in on the search for the impossible icon. A 12th century abbot was the first to claim he had found the cup that <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> used at the Last Supper, and his monastery became the wealthiest in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Eckehard </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, professor of Germanic medieval literature at <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. The Grail has since inspired romantic poems in several languages, a <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> opera and even a Monty Python movie. But it had n't been a subject for archaeologists until filmmakers <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> decided to dispatch their swashbuckling searcher for antiquities played by <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>. In the movie, Dr. <PERSON> Indiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> sets out in search of his father -LRB- <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Connery </PERSON> -RRB-, who has disappeared while hunting for the Holy Grail. Together, they outsmart <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> plunderers who are after the Grail because they believe anyone who drinks from it will gain immortality. The truth about the Holy Grail is tangled in centuries of legend, stretching from the Druids to <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>. `` Indiana Jones'' screenwriter <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Boam </PERSON> said the different strands of Grail lore were so contradictory he chose among them and made up the rest. The three knights guarding the cup are <PERSON> Boam </PERSON>'s creation, for example, as is the notion that the Grail could not be taken from its resting place in an ancient temple in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. There is, however, some evidence that the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> were interested in the Grail. <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> used it in speeches as a metaphor for Aryan racial purity. <PERSON> Boam </PERSON> said <PERSON> Lucas </PERSON> discovered <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s interest in occult artifacts while making `` Raiders of the Lost Ark.'' <PERSON> Boam </PERSON>'s research turned up reports that the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> had looted a monastery in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> in hopes of finding the Grail. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and other scholars said the Grail myth flourished in 12th century <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, though it has roots in earlier Celtic mythology. According to the legend, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> of Arimathea used the chalice from which <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> served the wine at the Last Supper to catch his blood during the crucifixion. The apocryphal story has it that <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> eventually brought the Grail to the monastery of <LOCATION> Glastonbury </LOCATION> _ a tale the abbot of <LOCATION> Glastonbury </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Blois </PERSON>, promoted. `` If you had a precious relic, people would come on pilgrimages,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. `` They also managed to fabricate the story that King <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> was buried there, and also that they had Excalibur,'' <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON>'s sword. `` It was a tremendous publicity stunt, and it made <LOCATION> Glastonbury </LOCATION> the single wealthiest monastery in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> until the Reformation,'' he added. Grail tales also were written in medieval French and German. One legend had the Grail coming to rest in the south of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, and by the 15th century, a <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> king had a collection of grail cups, according to popular book on the subject, `` Holy Blood, Holy Grail.'' A German version inspired <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> to write the opera `` Parsifal'' in 1882. Hollywood took up the trail in 1954, when <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> played a sculptor who made the cup for <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> in `` The Silver Chalice.'' There is, however, no evidence the Grail existed, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. The Metropolitan Museum of Art in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> does have a figured silver cup that was once said to be the Grail. The <ORGANIZATION> Antioch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chalice </ORGANIZATION>, discovered in <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> in about 1910, was exhibited at the 1938 World's Fair, said curator <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON> of the Cloisters, which once owned it But the chalice was made 500 years after <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>' birth, and scholars never believed the claims, she said. Still, the Grail persists as a symbol of purity, faith and resurrection. `` The Holy Grail has come to take on a far greater meaning than the object itself,'' said <PERSON> Boam </PERSON>. `` It stands in for perfection, or any goal people might have.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-KochIndustries     06-26 0346</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Koch Industries,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Justice Investigates Kansas Company Accused of Stealing Oil From
Indians</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Kansas-based company faces a criminal investigation based on allegations that it stole oil from Indian-owned wells, according to a spokesman for a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> probe stems from information about <ORGANIZATION> Koch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Industries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> gathered by a special investigating committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Indian Affairs, spokesman <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> said. `` This has been referred to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney,'' <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON>, a spokesman for <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON> said <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> officials and representatives of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> will meet before a formal investigation begins, although no date has been set for the meeting Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said her office can `` neither confirm nor deny the existence of an ongoing investigation.'' The special <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> committee focused on <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>, the country's largest independent oil purchaser, at a May 10 hearing in which witnesses said <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> employees purposely mismeasured oil from wells on Indian lands In a 57-page statement issued June 8, <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> said the committee `` unjustly defamed <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and caused severe damage to its reputation and business.'' The 49-year-old company said the figures the committee used in its allegations were inaccurate, and that comparisons with other companies were based on noncomparable statistics. The committee used `` anecdotal evidence which was misleading at best and false at worst'' at the hearing, the Koch statement said. But <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> said the committee stands by its findings. `` The committee's investigators caught <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> employees in the act of stealing oil on six separate occasions,'' he said. `` Koch gaugers and supervisors also admitted to committee investigators that it was company policy to mismeasure oil.'' <PERSON> Hirsch </PERSON> said documents the committee subpoenaed from <LOCATION> Koch </LOCATION> and almost 30 other companies corroborated the committee's findings. He said the committee will review <PERSON> Koch </PERSON>'s June 8 statement before making its final report, sometime this fall. The special committee has been investigating all areas of Indian affairs and came upon the <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> case while probing federal agencies assigned to protecting Indian lands.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890626-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-26-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Zaire-Lobbyists     06-26 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Zaire-Lobbyists,470</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lobbyists Vying to Represent Zaire President in US</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
