<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 2340EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-UMassTakeover     04-25 0516</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UMass Takeover,0535</SECOND>
<HEAD>52 Students Arrested After Takeover Of University of Massachusetts
Building</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AMHERST, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fifty-two students were arrested Tuesday evening after occupying a University of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> building overnight to protest Defense Department-funded research. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, thousands of <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> students got an unscheduled holiday after demonstrators occupied the campus administration building to protest possible tuition increases, prompting officials to suspend classes. About 60 police in riot gear arrived at the University of <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> around 5 p.m.. About two hours later, a bus drove away with 29 students who had camped inside Memorial Hall Those students were charged with trespassing, and another 23 students were arrested for lying in front of the bus to prevent it from leaving, police said. About 300 students stood outside the building chanting and looking on as the students inside the hall were arrested. About 35 students had occupied Memorial Hall since 1 p.m. Monday. They declined an offer to meet with administrators in the provost's office Tuesday morning, and instead presented a list of demands that included a halt to all <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> research at the 25,000-student campus. About 40 students left the building Tuesday morning after several university administrators told them they would be arrested after 5 p.m., said university spokeswoman <PERSON> Jeanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>. The takeover was the second at the western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> campus in a week. Seven protesters were arrested April 19 on charges of disorderly conduct and trespassing after also demonstrating against military-funded research on campus, particularly research into anthrax. All research at the university is non-classified and researchers must make their work public under university rules. About $ 11.6 million, or 22 percent of grant money received at the university, came from the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in 1988, according to the school. Chancellor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> issued a statement telling the students the research would continue on campus until school administrators decide differently. `` The policy will not be negotiated with students,'' <PERSON> Duffey </PERSON> said. The latest occupation began when students rallying Monday at the Student Union against military research marched toward the administration building. Several then ducked into Memorial Hall en route, and more followed. Members of the local chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> have contended that the research is dangerous to the town, promotes militarism and should be banned. The university has argued the purpose of the anthrax research is peaceful and the strain of bacteria used is non-virulent and has been under study at the school for 23 years without incident. The <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> health board has scheduled a hearing for Wednesday on the question of the safety of the anthrax research. Tuesday was the first time since 1969 that classes at <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> have been canceled because of student protests, said school spokesman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> DeCiccio </PERSON>. Protesters demanding a face-to-face meeting with Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> said they feared tuition at the college _ now $ 1,250 a year _ would be increased and the college staff would be reduced because of state budget cuts. The governor had no immediate comment. Tuition for next year has not been set, <PERSON> DeCiccio </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Senators-CentralAmerica     04-25 0440</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Senators-Central America,0452</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators: U.S. Cannot `Wimp Out' on Panama</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICHARD COLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> can not `` wimp out'' on fraud in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s upcoming presidential vote and still maintain credibility in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> senators said Monday after touring the region. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sens. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>., <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON>, D-Va., and <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., hopscotched through <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> over the weekend, visiting with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> The scheduled May 7 election in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, which the senators said is widely expected to be stacked in favor of Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s candidate, is a test of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attitudes toward next year's Nicaraguan elections `` We can not allow to go unchallenged what is obviously a massively fraudulent election in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>. The senators called <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> a test in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sincerity, saying the nation's actions will be used to judge attitudes toward next February's elections in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, which pit a leftist Sandinista government against the U.S.-backed Contra rebels. `` If we wimp out in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, and passively let a fraudulent election go forward ... I think our moral standing within <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> and our credibility to the world community will be seriously compromised,'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must immediately focus world attention on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, persuading as many foreign observers as possible to oversee the vote even though <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has sought to ban such activities. `` One of the things we have failed to do is to bring international pressure with respect to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Mack </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said reports that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had approved aid to the Panamanian opposition were understandable, because the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has legitimate economic and military interests in the nation, especially the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>. But he said he was puzzled by the $ 10 million amount reported. `` I was surpised, because the people with whom we met indicated they were expecting to spend approximately $ 1 million on the oppsoition campaign, and they had already raised a substantial amount of that,'' the senator said. `` I was unclear where the figure $ 10 million came from.'' In <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, the senators said, Sandinista foreign ministry official <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> met with the senators to discuss next year's scheduled election in that country But <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> refused to answer the senators when they asked point-blank if the Sandinistas would peacefully transfer power to the winners of the February 1990 election, <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said. In a visit to the Yamales Contra camp in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> said, he found the rebels in high spirits. He said they would prefer to be fighting, but understood their role in pressuring the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> to comply with their commitment to democratize <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Italy-Seatbelts     04-25 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Italy-Seatbelts,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Mandates Use of Seatbelts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Drivers and passengers in this car-mad country will have to buckle up beginning Thursday and keep the bambini in the back seat, the government announced. A communique from Premier <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>'s office Monday said that people caught without their seat belts on will be subject to fines ranging from 12,000 lire -LRB- $ 9 -RRB- to 50,000 lire -LRB- $ 37 -RRB-. The regulations do not apply to pregnant women. The new rules also require babies and toddlers to be in car seats and relegate children up to the age of 12 to the back seat. The regulations were drawn up by the ministries of the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Works </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Transport </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--TreviFountain     04-25 0116</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Trevi Fountain,0117</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Steals Coins From Rome's Famous Wishing Fountain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Startled tourists watched as a man scaled a barrier and scooped up coins from the city's famed <LOCATION> Trevi </LOCATION> fountain until police arrested him, authorities say. According to legend, tourists who throw coins over their shoulders into the 18th century fountain will return to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>. On Sunday afternoon, 41-year-old <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Fascelli </PERSON> entered the fountain, which is without water due to restoration work, police said Monday. `` It really makes no difference who throws the coins into the fountain. People who really want to return will come back anyway,'' <PERSON> Fascelli </PERSON> said as he was taken into custody, according to the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> newspaper <PERSON> Il </PERSON> <PERSON> Messaggero </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-People-LucilleBall     04-25 0475</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People-Lucille Ball,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lucille Ball Improving, Daughter Says Hairdo Utmost Post-Surgery
Worry</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB THOMAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedian <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>'s first words to her daughter after last week's emergency heart surgery was about her hairdresser's appointment, actress <PERSON> Lucie </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnaz </PERSON> says. `` I went to mom's bedside where she was all tied to tubes and things and I told her, ` Hello mom, I love you,''' Miss <PERSON> Arnaz </PERSON> told 150 people Monday at the <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Eastman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kodak </ORGANIZATION> Second Century Award ceremony. `` She mumbled something under the oxygen mask, but I said I could n't hear her. Finally I asked the nurse if I could lift the mask a little to hear what she was saying. So I did, and mom said, ` Would n't you know _ this is the day I was going to get my hair done.''' Miss <PERSON> Ball </PERSON> was honored for her work in helping young people in the entertainment field. Miss <PERSON> Arnaz </PERSON> accepted the award on her mother's behalf. The 77-year-old actress was in serious condition and improving daily, said <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` The outlook is very encouraging,'' he said. `` Her doctors have her in the chair for longer periods each day. Her spirits are good and she's cracking jokes.'' She was moved Monday from the cardiac surgical intensive care unit to a step-down unit, `` technically another intensive care unit,'' said Wise. `` She should be in her own room toward the end of the week. At the luncheon, Miss <PERSON> Arnaz </PERSON> said she was glad the award was n't postponed after her mother's heart attack `` because it means very, very much to her at this time. Presenting the award, comedian <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> told of being visited by Miss Ball on the second night of her <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> show, `` Once Upon a Mattress.'' `` She came backstage to visit us all and she spent 30 to 35 minutes in my dressing room answering my questions,'' Miss <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said. Miss Ball's husband, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>, also attended the luncheon, where guests signed a huge card with the `` I Love Lucy'' heart logo and the words, `` We Love <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> _ Get Well Soon.'' Wise said the mounds of get-well wishes arriving at the hospital represents the biggest outpouring of affection for any celebrity confined to <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION>, known as the `` hospital to the stars.'' `` We've received a tidal wave of mail with a couple thousand letters coming in today,'' said Wise. `` It's taken four volunteers several hours to sort it. She wants everything sorted so she can see every one of them when she gets home.'' Inside a package addressed to Miss Ball, <PERSON> Wise </PERSON> said, `` You can hear ` Twinkle, Twinkle Little Star' playing on a music box inside.'' The surgery was performed April 18 when doctors replaced her aorta and aortic valve with the donated organ tissue of a 27-year-old man.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0057EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-25 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0741</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Director <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> and actress <PERSON> Amy </PERSON> <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> have agreed amicably to end their 3 -LCB- - year marriage `` Our mutual decision, however difficult, has been made in the spirit of caring. And our friendship remains both personal and professional,'' the couple said in a statement issued by publicist <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>. `` We have decided to make this statement public in order to protect the privacy of our family, which is of great importance to us,'' it said. The divorce announcement followed months of speculation by supermarket tabloids that the couple would split. <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> and Miss <PERSON> Irving </PERSON> were married in November 1985. They have a 3-year-old son, <PERSON> Max </PERSON>. Details on child custody arrangements and division of property were n't disclosed. <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON>, 40, directed the box-office smashes `` Jaws'' and `` E.T. _ The Extra-Terrestrial,'' among other hits. Ms. <PERSON> Irving </PERSON>, 35, was nominated for a supporting actress Oscar for `` Yentl'' and recently starred in `` Crossing Delancey.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version moved on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WILBERFORCE, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It's now Dr. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>. The heavyweight boxing champion and high-school dropout was being given an an honorary doctorate in humane letters by <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> today. <PERSON> Tyson </PERSON>, dubbed `` Iron Mike'' for his devastating knockout punch, was being honored at commencement ceremonies for his positive influence on young people, the university said. `` <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> demonstrates that hard work, determination and perseverance can enable one to overcome any obstacles,'' said <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, president of the predominantly black university. `` When <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> tells -LRB- students -RRB- to study and go to college, it means so much to them.'' Boxing promoter <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON>, secretary of <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, also were to receive honorary degrees.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DELAVAN, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six celebrated entertainers became the first to enter the Clown Hall of Fame, capping a weekend of clowning around. More than 300 people attended Sunday's ceremony in which <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Skelton </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON>, <PERSON> Emmett </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> <PERSON> Sr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Griebling </PERSON> and <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> Adler </PERSON> were inducted. Master of ceremonies <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who is also a clown, said the gathering provided clown fans a chance to give a `` collective hug back to those who have given so much.'' The art of clowning is special because clowns share their experience directly with their audience and no two performances are alike, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON> accepted their awards in person while <PERSON> Skelton </PERSON> addressed the audience via a videotaped message. Relatives of <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, <PERSON> Griebling </PERSON> and <PERSON> Adler </PERSON>, who are deceased, also were on hand. The inductees were elected in January by members of the Clown Hall of Fame and Research Center. The center was created to promote the circus heritage of this city, which was the headquarters of about two dozen circuses in the 19th century, including P.T. <PERSON> Barnum </PERSON>'s. Other festivities held during the weekend `` Clown Town Colossal'' included clown performances, carnival games, rides, circus concessions and a parade.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s boyfriend was fined $ 1,175 and ordered to do 300 hours of community service for smashing a photographer's camera outside the actress' home <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON>, 24, an aspiring actor and former bagel baker, also was put on two years' probation. Neither he nor <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, 42, were present at Monday's hearing before Municipal Judge <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenberg </PERSON>. Camilletti pleaded no contest in February to two counts of vandalism for the July 27 incident. A reckless driving charge was dismissed at sentencing. Talks continued on how much restitution Camilletti should pay two freelance photographers whose equipment he damaged. Deputy City Attorney <PERSON> Renee </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurents </PERSON> said the amount was expected to be settled by Friday. During a news conference after the incident, <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> angrily denied he was trying to run down the photographer when he smashed the actress' Ferrari into a photographer's car. The actress blamed pesky paparazzi and the frustration of living in a media spotlight for the flare-up. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, who won a best actress Oscar in 1988 for her role in `` Moonstruck,'' has since moved out of the home. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> says he now lives in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and asked if he could perform the community service there. <PERSON> Camilletti </PERSON> met <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> nightclub on her 40th birthday. He could have been sentenced to one year in jail and fined $ 2,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerSpill 1stLd-Writethru a0680 04-25 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0680,0745</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon and State Squabble Over Cleanup, Rough Weather Slows Work</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with more on cleanup, salmon being released
in Prince William Sound, comments by Quayle; CORRECTS that halibut decision
will be Wednesday, sted Tuesday; no pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSAN GALLAGHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s top environmentalist squabbled over the pace of the oil spill cleanup Monday as skimmers in the Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> sought refuge from rough seas for the second day in a row. Hatchery owners on Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>, meanwhile, announced that 24 million salmon fry have been released into the sound, where they must swim through seas hit by the spill. The salmon had to be released Sunday and Monday in conjunction with the bloom of plankton in the sound to enhance their rate of survival. `` We really have no choice but to release them now,'' said <PERSON> Heather </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the non-profit <ORGANIZATION> Prince </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> William </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sound </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aquaculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, which owns three hatcheries in the sound. It is unclear what will happen to the fry as they migrate to the open sea if they encounter oil, <PERSON> McCarty </PERSON> said. As cleanup work continued in the sound, gale warnings and seas swelling to 18 feet kept aircraft on the ground and skimmers close to shore Monday, said coordinators of the military's role in the cleanup. Exxon, however, called a news conference to announce that the cleanup was ahead of the pace calculated in the oil company's federally approved plan, which figures the cleanup will be done by Sept. 15 K.T. <PERSON> Koonce </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for exploration and production, said 70 percent of the 10.1 million-gallon spill had evaporated, dissipated or been recovered. The company said 1.8 gallons had been recovered. An estimated 1.2 million gallons remains afloat. The oil spilled March 24 from the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION>, a fully loaded tanker that ran aground on <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> as it steered from the Valdez terminal through Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelso </PERSON>, commissioner of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s Despartment of <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION>, questioned <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s claim and said the oil company's efforts remain inadequate. `` I would look carefully at the figure and not take it at face value,'' said <PERSON> Kelso </PERSON>, adding that the estimate was based on <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s computer models and could be off by as much as 50 percent `` What I want to see is some results,'' he said after <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s news conference While the rough seas kicked oil onto beaches that had previously been spared, Monday's weather also broke up oil and increased the likelihood that more crude will be carried to the open seas of the Gulf of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. `` We see this -LRB- storm -RRB- as a good thing,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gleason </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oceanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atmospheric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. Fishermen from Homer and other maritime communities south of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> have sewn absorbent material into nets and are picking up oil in much the same way they might be gathering herring this time of year. A cleanup priority has been set for beaches where seals come out with their pups each summer. Thousands of sea birds and hundreds of otters already have been found dead. State officials have canceled or postponed herring, black cod and shrimp harvests in the sound, and closed a portion of the <LOCATION> Kodiak </LOCATION> herring fishing grounds. Fisheries officials in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> were expected to decide Wednesday whether to cancel the May 15-16 halibut season. Heavy oil has been reported around the <LOCATION> Barren </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> at the mouth of <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Inlet </LOCATION> where many large boats congregate for the 24-hour open season. In <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, meanwhile, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> warned oil companies not to use the nation's worst oil spill as an excuse to raise gasoline prices. `` If they are, it is going to be a very difficult situation for them,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who plans a firsthand look at the cleanup next month, said in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. Allegations have been made that a temporary shortage of oil caused by the spill was used a pretext for gas price hikes. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> made his comments after meeting with former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> as he left on a trip to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. He is scheduled to visit Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> on his way back May 4. <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said he would tour the area, and collect information for President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APMeeting     04-25 0790</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Meeting,0815</SECOND>
<HEAD>Expanding AP Service Offers New Products, Faster Delivery Within
A Year</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Associated Press will introduce three new services for readers this year to help meet the changing needs of the news industry, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> President and General Manager <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> said. `` I want to reaffirm something that I think you know is true, at least I hope you know is true,'' <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> told news executives at the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> annual meeting Monday. `` That is that I want quality service and responsiveness to be the twin themes of everything the AP does.'' Earlier Monday, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> both addressed the annual meeting and luncheon, highlighting the start of the 103rd annual convention of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, reporting on his first 100 days in office, listed among his accomplishments savings and loan legislation, ethics proposals, the beginning of a war on drugs and agreements with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on the federal budget and Contra aid. `` In three short months we've made a good start coming to grips with issues demanding urgent attention and decisive action,'' he said. At the same time, defense and foreign policy reviews, environmental legislation and a program to deal with homelessness `` are all on the near horizon,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> added. He also suggested his relationship with the media had matured after a sometimes-rocky presidential campaign. `` Both of us, government and the news media, need one another and we owe each other a measure of respect, honesty and integrity equal to the work we're engaged in,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. The president also pledged continued administration efforts to win the release of <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> corrrespondent, who last month began his fifth year as a hostage in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. Hours before departing on a trip along the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> rim </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> addressed his remarks to the `` declinists'' both at home and abroad who have predicted a diminished standing for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as a global power. `` The point that I will stress to my Asian hosts is that when Americans express doubts about the health of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> society, it's usually a sign of renewal, not of decline,'' he said <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON>, who followed <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the luncheon, told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> annual meeting that improving technology was quickly changing the business of reporting and delivering news, and that the pace would only accelerate. As an example, he noted that this year the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> was able for the first time to deliver a presidential inauguration picture in time for East Coast afternoon newspapers, by using direct transmission from a digital camera onto the AP photo network. He said the news products to be introduced later this year are aimed at different sections of the newspaper _ new state weather maps, a sports statistic page and a regular story package aimed at readers over age 50. The state weather maps would compliment national and regional maps already provided. The AP also will supply a national weather map in color via its GraphicsNet system of computer-to-computer transmission. The full-page layout of sports agate, complete with graphic labels and headlines, would be transmitted over the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s GraphicsNet system and updated throughout the day The biweekly package of stories and columns aimed at Americans age 50 and over, dealing with such subjects as retirement planning, health and legislation affecting the elderly. An added staff member will be assigned to this package, called `` Prime Time.'' In his `` report card'' to the members, <PERSON> Boccardi </PERSON> also said the AP this year will complete the conversion to a 9,000-word-a-minute high-speed transmission system for <ORGANIZATION> DataStream </ORGANIZATION> and DataFeature news copy, after a delay caused by a worldwide shortage of advanced computer memory chips. He also said a new highspeed photo service, PhotoStream, will be running on a test-basis by mid-year. The <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s annual report noted that 72 more daily newspapers joined the news cooperative in 1988, bringing total membership at the end of 1988 to 1,483 dailies, representing 95 percent of daily <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> newspaper circulation. The meeting agenda also included election of seven members of the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s 21-member board of directors, including three new members. All members were elected to three-year terms. The new board members are: <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brunswick </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burleigh </PERSON>, senior vice president-newspapers and publishing, <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION>; and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Junction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>. Four incumbent directors were re-elected: <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the News-Press @ Gazette of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the Raleigh -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News & amp; Observer and Times, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, chief executive officer, <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lifvendahl </PERSON> of The <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sentinel <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> is chairman of the board.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0129EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APBoardElection     04-25 0399</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Board Election,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boyd, Burleigh And Montgomery Elected To AP Board Of Directors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Burleigh </PERSON> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> have been elected to the board of directors of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Four incumbent directors were re-elected. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the News-Press @ Gazette of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joseph </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of the Raleigh -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News & amp; Observer and Times, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, chief executive officer, <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lifvendahl </PERSON> of The <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sentinel were elected to new three-year terms on the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> board. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> is chairman of the board. Directors were elected from among 12 nominees at the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> annual meeting on Monday. <PERSON> Burleigh </PERSON> and <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> were chosen to succeed retiring directors <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> H -LRB- <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of The Press-Enterprise of <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> of The Greeneville -LRB- <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun. <PERSON> Hays </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> were not eligible for re-election because they have served the maximum three consecutive three-year terms on the board. <PERSON> Burleigh </PERSON> is senior vice president for newspapers and publishing, <ORGANIZATION> Scripps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> is chairman of the board, president and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publishing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Montgomery </LOCATION> is president and publisher of <ORGANIZATION> Montgomery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Publications </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON> was elected to fill the vacancy created by the resignation from the board of <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fanning </PERSON>, who resigned as editor of The Christian Science Monitor last year Her term on the board expires in 1991. The AP membership earlier Monday approved a resolution that was passed in February by the executive committee of the board of directors authorizing the sixth-place vote-getter - excluding the separate voting for a director representing a city of less than 50,000 population - to fill her unexpired term The voting for directors was based on membership bonds held by the newspapers that make up the cooperative news agency. The results: <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, 14,145 bond votes. <PERSON> Daniels </PERSON>, 13,644. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, 12,379. Lifvendahl, 12,117. <PERSON> Burleigh </PERSON>, 10,570. <PERSON> Boyd </PERSON>, 7,959. <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Totter </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gabriel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tribune </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Covina </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, 6,133. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bartlett </PERSON>, The <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News, 5,152. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Star-Telegram, 3,428. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Salt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>, 2,065. <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> was elected to the board to represent a city of under 50,000 population. In that separate contest, he received 12,377 votes. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Natt </PERSON> of The Daily News of <LOCATION> Longview </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, had 8,054 votes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Energy-ShortChina     04-25 0767</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Energy-Short China,0788</SECOND>
<HEAD>China Faces Worst Energy Crisis In Decades</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Xinghua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clothing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Factory </ORGANIZATION> has abandoned plans to buy new machines from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> because it does n't have the electricity to run them. `` Without the right connections it would take years to get approval for the extra power,'' said <PERSON> Man </PERSON> <PERSON> Ying </PERSON>, energy manager at the 250-employee factory in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The factory also ca n't buy air conditioners for the sweltering summers and this past winter went days without heat because of a lack of coal. `` We send out special teams to look for coal,'' she said, adding that they sometimes must pay free market sellers and profiteers up to 130 yuan -LRB- $ 35 -RRB- a ton for it, three times the state-set rate. <PERSON> Xinghua </PERSON> is forced to shut down once a six-day week, every Friday, in the midst of the worst energy crisis in Communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 40-year history. But it is more fortunate than factories in the key industrial cities of <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Shenyang </LOCATION>, which operate only three or four days of their usual six-day week. In parts of <LOCATION> Jiangsu </LOCATION> province, another industrial center near <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, up to a third of the factories were closed and 40 percent of the power plants had stopped working at the end of the year because of coal shortages. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, 500 factories employing 100,000 now operate only on night shifts because they have no power during the day. Not only factories are affected. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, a city of 10 million people, elevators in high-rise buildings do n't work, new color televisions sit idle and people stock up on candles. The official Guangming Daily noted that even the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has been ordered to shut off all electrical appliances every Thursday. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has been losing an average 200 billion yuan -LRB- $ 54 billion -RRB- a year during the 1980s due to power cuts. Last year the losses were believed to be double that as up to one-third of production capacity was unused. The crisis reflects the inability of energy production to match the nation's explosive industrial growth. Industrial output increased by more than 20 percent in 1988, but production of coal, used for 70 percent of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s energy, was up only 4 percent. Energy supplies have also failed to cope with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s new-found prosperity which has resulted in a surge of demand for televisions, refrigerators, microwaves and other electrical appliances. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> last year, energy consumption by households jumped 29 percent, while power supply was up by only 3 percent. The Guangming Daily noted that one large luxury hotel in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> today consumes as much energy as all of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> did in the early 1950s. Another problem is that <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, although the world's largest producer of coal with 970 million tons last year, ca n't get the power to the places it is needed. Most of the nation's coal is mined in the north, but industry is centered mainly along the southern coast. Half the country's badly overtaxed railway system and a third of river transport is devoted to carrying coal, but that still was n't enough. Last year about 8 million tons, or 3.5 percent of the state coal supply quota, was not delivered. According to a report in the weekly publication Outlook -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Liaowang </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, one large coal mine in <LOCATION> Shanxi </LOCATION> province, in the heart of coal country, had to stop operations temporarily because it lacked fuel to run its bulldozers. Low investment in energy industries, inefficient small mines and artificially low state-set prices for energy have widened the gap between supply and demand. Profiteering by officials with access to coal supplies _ even in the army _ is pandemic. Coal should sell for the state-price equivalent of $ 8 to $ 11 a ton but it goes for $ 54 to $ 80 after passing through the hands of various middlemen on its way to <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>. The government is considering various possible solutions, including more investment in energy production, higher taxes for energy use and higher energy prices, to achieve what appears to be an impossible goal of producing 1.5 billion tons of coal by the year 2000. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> now has no nuclear power but is building two plants along the southern coast and has plans for others. As a stopgap measure, the government is hoping that its harsh austerity campaign begun last fall will slow the economy down enough to relieve the energy crisis. `` If we consider energy to be the lifeblood of modern society,'' the Guangming Daily said, `` today's <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> can be compared to a patient suffering from anemia.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cambodia-Vietnam     04-25 0707</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-Vietnam,0728</SECOND>
<HEAD>Withdrawal Could Improve International Climate For Vietnam ^Eds:
Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ENG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHNOM PENH, Cambodia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When it withdraws from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> will be at peace for the first time since its war for independence began half a century ago against the French, Japanese and eventually the Americans. Reformers now in control hope ending nearly 11 years of occupation will bring better relations with the outside world, including the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. They believe <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> risks economic disaster without expanded trade and assistance from abroad. Orders for <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s invasion of neighboring <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in December 1978 came from founders of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> made inflexible by the long struggle. Several have resigned or died since, and the reformers pledge to withdraw the remaining occupation forces by Sept. 30. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> says 50,000 of its soldiers remain in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, but foreign intelligence estimates put the number as high as 70,000. A new and bloodier round of civil war between the Hanoi-sponsored Cambodian government and the three-party guerrilla groups opposing it may begin after the withdrawal, but the departure will be a boon to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Its occupation, aided by the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, angered nations on which Vietnamese trade and economic development depend, such as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations: <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brunei </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s invasion overthrew the brutal <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> regime, which was allied with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> army made a punitive strike into <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> early in 1979. Because of sanctions and its isolation, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> soon found itself in worse shape economically than the devastated country it had occupied. <PERSON> Ngo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dien </PERSON>, Vietnamese ambassador to <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, says relations with <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> have improved and trade along the <LOCATION> China-Vietnam </LOCATION> frontier has resumed. `` After the withdrawal, we will see even more changes,'' he added. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> says it will not consider aid or diplomatic relations until Vietnamese military forces leave <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, but <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>'s pledge and its efforts to account for Americans still missing from the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war have caused more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> congressmen to recommend quicker reconciliation. <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> talks of turning <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION>'s `` battlefields into markets.'' As a condition for a return to normal relations with the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has demanded that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> force <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> to leave <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> and <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON>, leaders of the two countries, are to meet next month in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for the Chinese-Soviet summit in 30 years. Asked whether <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> made its decision under Soviet pressure, <PERSON> Ngo </PERSON> <PERSON> Dien </PERSON> said: `` Mr. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> of course welcomed the withdrawal because he has something in his hands for the summit.'' `` Some people may call it pressure. Some people may call it good coordination between close friends who have the same aim.'' Improving relations with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> might enable the non-communist world to wean it from dependence on the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and encourage the limited steps <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> has taken toward a more open, freer society. For three centuries, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> has found itself shrinking with <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s steady territorial expansion. Communist-led Vietnamese guerrillas used Cambodian and Laotian territory as sanctuaries and supply routes for the war against the French and the Americans, and helped communist movements to victory in the two countries. Since economic reformer <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> became party chief in late 1986, however, <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> has taken steps to get out of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> and has withdrawn troops from <LOCATION> Laos </LOCATION>. A Soviet diplomat based in <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> said privately that some Vietnamese `` saw themselves as the rulers of this country, but luckily the others got the upper hand.'' <PERSON> Uch </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s political department in the government installed by <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, suggested greater independence for <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> will accompany the end of occupation. `` For the moment, I think we have to stick together because of the political configuration in the region, but I think in the future we do n't want to wall ourselves in,'' he said. `` We certainly want to expand our relations to all neighboring countries, especially the <ORGANIZATION> ASEAN </ORGANIZATION> countries.'' According to the Soviet diplomat, `` <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s influence will remain'' after withdrawal, `` but it will not be monopolistic.'' <ORGANIZATION> Ngo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dien </ORGANIZATION> suggested <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> would stop using military means to resolve problems and would fix its attention on economic development.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Genes-Jobs     04-25 0603</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Genes-Jobs,0622</SECOND>
<HEAD>Genes May Influence Happiness on Job, Study Suggests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Genes may influence how satisfied one is at work, according to a study. But the study does not imply that people who dislike their jobs are genetically doomed to unhappiness at work. The apparent impact of genes is quite modest, suggesting `` we're not totally hard-wired'' for job satisfaction, said industrial psychologist <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON> Besides, he said, just as nutrition can modify the genetic influence on a person's height, the job setting may affect the hypothesized genetic contribution to job satisfaction. The study suggests that genes may be one reason that some people seem happy no matter what they do, while others have trouble finding a satisfying job, <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON> said. The research is presented in this month's issue of the Journal of Applied Psychology by <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON>, a professor at the Industrial Relations Center of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Carlson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION>, and colleagues <PERSON> Lauren </PERSON> <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Bouchard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Segal </PERSON>. <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON> said the study does not prove genetic influence over job satisfaction, but only supports the idea. He also noted that the study was small, and cautioned against applying the results to the general population. Two scientists who have studied genetic influence on personality said the study fits in with previous research. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Loehlin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION> said other research suggests genetic influence on personality and temperament, and an effect on job satisfaction appears plausible. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION> said Finnish studies of twins have found evidence that genes may influence a person's job choice, satisfaction with life, and frequency of changing jobs for such negative reasons as dissatisfaction or being fired. But psychologist <PERSON> Leon </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamin </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Northeastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, who has analyzed nature-versus-nurture research, said Monday he was skeptical. The reason for studying identical twins reared apart is that since twins in a pair share identical genes but grow up in different environments, some similarities between them may reflect genetic influence. But <PERSON> Kamin </PERSON> said previous studies showed twins reared apart tend to grow up in similar family environments, which he said could explain such similarities as degree of job satisfaction. The <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> study focused on 34 pairs of identical twins who had been separated at an average age of less than 6 months. They were not reunited until about age 32, on average. Twenty-five pairs were women. Each twin completed a 20-item questionnaire about satisfaction with the `` major job'' in his or her life. <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON> said the job list was diverse, including research chemist, coal miner, assembly line worker, computer analyst, machinist, nurse and financial planner. Seventeen women said being a housewife was their major job. When researchers analyzed the various levels of general job satisfaction reported by the 68 people, about 30 percent of the differences appeared to be explained by genetic influence. The rest was attributed other factors such as environment. Comparing jobs held by each member of twin pairs, researchers found evidence that twins tended to hold jobs with similar degrees of mental complexity, physical demands and physical coordination requirements. That finding supports the idea that genes also affect what jobs people seek, researchers said. But analysis showed it does not explain the apparent genetic influence on job satisfaction. <PERSON> Arvey </PERSON> said there are several possible ways genes could influence happiness in the workplace. Affecting personality is a `` very likely mechanism,'' he said. Alternatively, he said, genes may influence what people pay attention to in their job environment, such as supervision, or may affect what people want from a job.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BattleshipExplosion 3rdLd-Writethru a0746 04-25 1018</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Battleship Explosion, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0746,1046</SECOND>
<HEAD>President, Ship Captain Honor Iowa's Dead</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 24th, ```Nobody in...,' to UPDATE with
skipper refusing to say definitely whether turret can be repaired.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos NKX5,6,8,9,10,11,13,15, LaserColor NKX5C,NKX9C</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By D.W. PAGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of grieving friends and relatives of the fallen 47 crewmen from the battleship USS <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> gathered quietly Monday and heard President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praise their loved ones as `` brothers in eternity.'' `` We join today in mourning for the 47 who perished, and in fact, for the 11 who survived,'' the president told a packed memorial service at <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION>. `` They all were, in the words of a poet, ` the men behind the guns.' `` They came from <LOCATION> Hidalgo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>; <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. They came to the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> as strangers, served the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> as shipmates and friends, and left the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> as brothers in eternity. In the finest <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> tradition, they served proudly on a great battleship, the USS Iowa.'' The president, a World War II <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> pilot, said he was proud to recommission the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> in 1984 and said it had earned 11 battle stars in two wars. But with the still-unexplained fire and explosion last Wednesday in the battleship's No. 2 gun turret, he said, `` Fate has written a sorrowful chapter in the history of this great ship.'' The <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s commander, Capt. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON>, said the turret's crew was the best gun crew on the ship, and called its chief _ Chief Gunner's <PERSON> Mate </PERSON> <PERSON> Reginald </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gibson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ `` my No 1 chief.'' Victims' relatives and hundreds of sailors and officers in dress blues were among the 6,000 people crowded into a hangar for the service. A bouquet of red roses was placed in front of the podium; behind were an American flag and the battleship's banners. Outside, another 2,000 people listened to the service on loudspeakers. As many as 500 <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> crewmen were unable to attend the service because they were delayed by traffic and were not permitted to enter the hangar because of security measures to protect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Many were angry they could not attend, said Machinist's Mate <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Finn </PERSON>, 38. `` It was very important to them,'' <PERSON> Finn </PERSON> said. The service came a day after the World War II-era battleship eased into its home port, its gun barrels scorched and its 1,500 crewmen at the rails in white uniforms and black armbands in memory of their dead shipmates. <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> told the crowd of mourners that he remembered the men of turret No. 2. `` I remember their faces as they toiled at their guns, sweating an honest sweat that comes from young men dedicated to a great cause,'' he said. `` I remember as they talked among themselves, looking so much like sailors of the past, sharing the exuberance of the times and the dreams of the future,'' he said. `` They were the life, the spirit and the soul of our ship. ... They made the ultimate sacrifice for us. ... The men of Turret Two will be part of the spirit of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> forever.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recounted seeing the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> off the coast of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> as a naval aviator in World War II, and the great sense of confidence the big ship lent to the fleet. Addressing the children of the victims, he said: `` You must never forget that your father was <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s pride.'' At the end of the service, while the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hymn </ORGANIZATION> was played, President and Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> greeted and consoled the families of the lost men. After the 45-minute service, the families attended a private reception with <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said 45 victims' families attended the service. At a press briefing following the reception, <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> praised the hundreds of men who fought the fire for their courage. `` God gave birth to 500 heroes,'' the captain said. `` Fire on a ship is the most terrifying fear ... you have nowhere to run. `` Our extensive training paid off,'' he said. `` Besides the firefighting crews, we had cooks, engineers, deck seamen, <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION> all fighting to save the ship.'' <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> said the blast occurred just as he was turning to Vice Adm. <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, commander of the 2nd Fleet, to tell him to watch the No. 2 turret because it contained his best crew. `` This was my best turret,'' <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> said. He said turret chief <PERSON> Ziegler </PERSON> `` was the most meticulous of men. He was my No. 1 chief of the 84 chiefs aboard. `` Nobody in that turret did anything unless they were qualified,'' <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> refused to give a definite answer to reporters' questions about whether the damaged turret could be repaired, saying the battleship could operate without it if necessary All but 11 men in the huge gun turret died almost instantly last Wednesday when the explosion ripped through it. At the time, the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> was conducting open seas gun exercises off <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said the investigation into the blast is continuing. <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials have refused to speculate on the cause of the explosion. Cmdr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morse </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>'s weapons officer, said the guns were thoroughly inspected the morning of the accident, and <PERSON> Moosally </PERSON> said he had no hesitation about the guns' safety. `` I'll be in the turret for the first shot to go off,'' the captain said. One of the survivors, Gunner's Mate 3rd Class <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, said that at first the men down in the powder magazine in the lowest level of the turret did n't know anything was wrong. `` We were waiting for the gun to fire, and we were n't sure,'' he said. When the men discovered that no one was answering the interior turret communications link, <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> ordered the powder returned to the magazine and the compartment evacuated. The sailors found smoke everywhere as they climbed through hatches and up ladders outside the turret toward the sea deck, <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> recalled. `` My first thought was that I'd better get to a lifeboat station, because if the fire got to the magazine things would be bad,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RareRhinos     04-25 0462</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rare Rhinos,0479</SECOND>
<HEAD>World's Rarest Rhinos Found In War-Ravaged Region Of Vietnam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RAEBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Editor</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Years of war and defoliation in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> failed to eradicate a small population of the world's rarest rhinoceroses near <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, wildlife officials say. An American researcher said Monday that he and a team of Vietnamese biologists had found tracks of a population of perhaps 10 to 15 <LOCATION> Javan </LOCATION> rhinoceroses in the eastern part of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s Song Be province. Since the 1960s the rhinos had been thought extinct except for about 50 living on the western tip of Java, said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON>, director of <ORGANIZATION> Wildlife </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>, a division of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zoological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. `` It was suspected that some still survived in <LOCATION> Indochina </LOCATION>, but there was no definite evidence of them,'' <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON> said. Live animals were not sighted, but a dead one was found and the animal's tracks left no doubt about their identification, he said. The find is important not only because it improves the survival odds for the <LOCATION> Javan </LOCATION> rhinoceros, but also because the rhinos can be used to encourage preservation of wilderness in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON> said. `` You may well say that the rhino is a national treasure of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` But the real treasure is the habitat there, the forest. `` Many of these ... charismatic species are in effect symbols, flagship species, in that they arouse emotions. They motivate a government to protect an area, because they get popular support.'' In <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, as elsewhere in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, rhino horn is used as a constituent of many different medicines, <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON> said. The dark gray Javan rhinoceros is similar to the African black rhinoceros, but is chunkier and has heavy skin folds that give it an armored look. An adult weighs 3,500 pounds, stands 5 -LCB- feet tall and is up to 11 -LCB- feet long. <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON>, who has tracked endangered animals around the globe, most recently in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>, found the rhinos' tracks during an expedition to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> in February and March. He was there with <PERSON> Vo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thanh </PERSON> <PERSON> Son </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hanoi </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Yuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dang </PERSON> and <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinh </PERSON> <PERSON> Thuy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s national research council to make the first wildlife survey of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s southern forests. The tracks were found along the <LOCATION> Dong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, 75 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, formerly <LOCATION> Saigon </LOCATION>. The region where the rhinos were found is a hot, humid patchwork of forest, native tribesmen's fields and huge expanses of bamboo up to 40 feet tall. `` The Vietnamese are real conscious of conservation, and I think they'll make an effort'' to protect the rhinos, <PERSON> Schaller </PERSON> said. He recommends stiff penalties for killing and selling rhinos, and the enlargement of a wilderness reserve near where the rhinoceroses were found.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-EngineFails     04-25 0170</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Engine Fails,0175</SECOND>
<HEAD>Midway Plane Returns To Airport As Flames Shoot From Engine</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A DC-9 jet carrying 55 passengers was forced to turn around minutes after takeoff when the pilot discovered flames shooting from an engine. The <ORGANIZATION> Midway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> twin-engine jet landed safely at <LOCATION> Midway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on the city's southwest side with no injuries, said <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the airline. The plane had departed for <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> at 8 p.m. and returned to Midway eight minutes later. Ms. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said a compressor, which mixes air and fuel, failed and the fuel ignited as it was discharged out of the rear of the engine. She compared it to a car backfiring _ `` a big backfire from a big engine.'' `` I'm sure the passengers heard a loud bang and the pilot noticed a loss of power in the engine,'' Ms. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said Emergency vehicles were summoned as the plane returned using only one engine. Ms. <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> said the passengers were assigned to other flights to <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CharterRevision     04-25 0435</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Charter Revision,0447</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chairman Wants to Eliminate New York's Board of Estimate, Expand
Council</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER ALAN HARPER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of a commission appointed to rework the city's unconstitutional government proposed eliminating the powerful <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> on Monday and expanding the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> to 50 members. The mayor would take control of contracts _ a lightning rod in view of the city corruption scandals surrounding Board of Estimate-awarded contracts that have resulted in criminal convictions. However, various bodies would have oversight responsibilities. Mayor <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> and City Comptroller <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON> were generally pleased by the proposals made by <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON> <PERSON> A.O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Charter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. The five borough presidents who sit on the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION> opposed them, however, with <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Golden </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> saying <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> `` is telling the boroughs to drop dead.'' At a public hearing, <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> also put forth the idea of a bicameral legislature, but not as a formal proposal. He said a new, 19-member house would be the equal of the <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, but that it would only work if it gave greater representation to blacks and Hispanics. The commission was created by the mayor to look into ways city government could restructure itself as court challenges to the Board of Estimate made their way through the legal system. In March, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> ruled that the board was unconstitutional because it violated the one-person, one-vote doctrine by giving each borough equal weight even though they varied widely in population. The commission, which had been on hold pending the court's ruling, then went into high gear with a self-imposed mandate to get its proposals on the November ballot The chairman's proposals are the first formal agenda around which the 15-member commission can debate. <PERSON> Schwarz </PERSON> presented part of the proposals Monday for discussion with the rest to be reviewed by the commission Tuesday. His proposals are not final. Under his proposals, the powers of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Estimate </ORGANIZATION>, made up of the borough presidents, the mayor, the city council president and the comptroller, would be dispersed. The comptroller no longer would be involved in policy and would be limited to fiscal matters and oversight and audit functions on contracts. `` I think it is a useful focus for reconstituting the city government,'' Comptroller <PERSON> Goldin </PERSON> said. `` The comptroller's role has always been overwhelmingly fiscal. This recognizes that reality.'' The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> would expand from 35 to 50 members, with the districts to correspond as closely as possible to community board districts. The city council president would continue as an ombudsman.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BetteDavisTribute     04-25 0531</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Bette Davis Tribute,0553</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bette Davis Honored by Film Society of Lincoln Center</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY49</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> slapped <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Cagney </PERSON> and <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON>, shook <PERSON> Miriam </PERSON> <PERSON> Hopkins </PERSON>, yelled at several leading men and shot one. And between these film clips shown at a <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> tribute on Monday night, several people who worked with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> praised her for her artistry and versatility. `` Working with <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was as happy and rewarding as any experience I've ever had. Barring grand opera I ca n't think of anything beyond her range,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON>, who wrote and directed the 1950 movie `` All About Eve.'' <PERSON> Ann-Margret </PERSON>, <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> also spoke in honor of Miss <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> during the program at <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>. The actress herself, who spoke last, proved that she still has verve and the ability to respond to the moment. `` I had hoped one day someone would, on one of my award evenings,'' she began, and was interrupted by laughter. `` Are you laughing, thinking I'm bragging?'' she asked, then continued, `` would show not only clips from my most well-known films but would include scenes from my earliest films.'' That was done, as a scene from the first of Miss <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' more than 80 movies was shown. In the brief clip from 1931's `` Bad Sister,'' <PERSON> Conrad </PERSON> <PERSON> Nagel </PERSON> came in while Miss <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was powdering a modestly diapered baby, kissed her and exited. Two of the speakers mentioned being warned by others that <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> could be selfish. <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> said other writers and directors predicted he and the star would have a disastrous head-on collision. `` Directors said, ` She will rewrite and she, not you, will direct.''' They were wrong, <PERSON> Mankiewicz </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzgerald </PERSON>, who appeared with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> in `` Dark Victory'' in 1939, said she'd been given advice by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> theater friends. `` They said, ` She'll turn you around so the camera can only see your ear. If the set has a lot of furniture, try holding onto something.' `` For the first two or three days I tried to do that. I found she was always sure I was properly lighted; she was wonderfully kind and thoughtful, so I stopped. Afrerwards she said she thought they'd got somebody who was raving mad. We became good friends and stayed that way.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> acted with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> once, in `` Right of Way,'' made for TV in 1983. `` I jumped at the chance,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said. `` From the first day, it felt just great to be there with <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> on the set and watch the way this wonderful actress works. I consider myself very fortunate to have worked with this woman I love and admire. It means a lot to me to be here tonight.'' <PERSON> Ann-Margret </PERSON>'s first film role, at age 18, was as <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>' daughter in the 1961 `` Pocketful of Miracles. <PERSON> Ann-Margret </PERSON> said, `` Miss <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> was so kind and so caring. `` Nobody has matched her intelligence and incredible energy. There's nothing like watching her entering a scene with her eyes blazing, ready to stand up for herself or cut somebody else down to size.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     04-25 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0362</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Pet Sematary' Buries Box Office Competition With $12 Million Take</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> was a big winner at the box office last weekend with its `` Pet Sematary'' and `` Major League'' earning a combined $ 17.2 million in ticket sales. Based on a premise that sometimes dead is better, `` Pet Sematary'' sold $ 12 million to win the top spot in its first weekend. `` Major League'' was second at $ 5.2 million, according to <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co </ORGANIZATION>. In third and fourth place were `` Say Anything'' and `` The Dream Team.'' The Oscar-winning film `` Rain Man'' clung to the No. 5 position after 19 weeks in release, followed by `` She's Out of Control'' in sixth and newcomer `` Red Scorpion'' with <PERSON> Dolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundgren </PERSON> in seventh. `` See You in the Morning'' with <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Bridges </PERSON> and <PERSON> Farrah </PERSON> <PERSON> Fawcett </PERSON> debuted in the No. 8 position with $ 1.8 million. In ninth was `` Disorganized Crime.'' `` Speed Zone'' was tenth. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by Exhibitor Relations, with distributor, weekend gross, number of theater screens, average per screen, total gross and number of weeks in release. 1. `` Pet Sematary,'' Paramount, $ 12 million, 1,585 screens, $ 7,600 per screen, $ 12 million, one week. 2. `` Major League,'' Paramount, $ 5.2 million, 1,615 screens, $ 3,240 per screen, $ 25.7 million, three weeks. 3. `` Say Anything,'' 20th <ORGANIZATION> Century </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fox </ORGANIZATION>, $ 3.8 million, 1,113 screens, $ 3,418 per screen, $ 9.04 million, two weeks. 4. `` The Dream Team,'' Universal, $ 3.2 million, 1,459 screens, $ 2,220 per screen, $ 15.7 million, three weeks. 5. `` Rain Man,'' <ORGANIZATION> MGM-UA </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.4 million, 1,391 screens, $ 1,709 per screen, $ 155.7 million, 19 weeks. 6. `` She's Out Of Control,'' <ORGANIZATION> Weintraub </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2.2 million, 987 screens, $ 2,246 per screen, $ 6.8 million, two weeks. 7. `` Red Scorpion,'' SGE Entertainment, $ 2.1 million, 1,268 screens, $ 1,640 per screen, $ 2.1 million, one week. 8. `` See You in the Morning,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.8 million, 743 screens, $ 2,466 per screen, $ 1.8 million, one week. 9. `` Disorganized Crime,'' <ORGANIZATION> Walt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.6 million 1,462 screens, $ 1,106 per screen, $ 5.4 million, two weeks. 10. `` Speed Zone,'' <ORGANIZATION> Orion </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.5 million, 1,195 screens, $ 1,235 per screen, $ 1.5 million, one week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0641EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--NoDivorce     04-25 0102</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--No Divorce,0105</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawyer Fined More Than $100,000 In Divorce Case</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MACON, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A judge ordered a lawyer to pay more than $ 100,000 to a man who remarried erroneously believing his divorce was final. <PERSON> Alvin </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDougald </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, apparently never filed the divorce petition of <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>. Judge <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> <PERSON> Culpepper </PERSON> said <PERSON> McDougald </PERSON>'s actions had been `` fraudulent'' and were `` intentional, willful, wanton and were taken without regard to the consequences'' to Wood. <PERSON> Culpepper </PERSON> on Monday ordered <PERSON> McDougald </PERSON> to pay Wood $ 50,000 in punitive damages, $ 50,000 to compensate Wood for mental suffering and $ 2,875 in actual damages.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-PressCards     04-25 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Press Cards,0558</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police To Investigate Palestinian Press Cards</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police Minister <PERSON> Chaim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON> says he has ordered an investigation into press cards Palestinians are issuing foreign journalists for the occupied lands, where <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> police have posed as reporters. Many foreign reporters have acquired such cards since a scandal last month involving two police officers who were filmed using a `` Press'' sign on their vehicle during a raid against Arab rioters in east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. Police later imposed limitations on the practice, but did not rule it out altogether, saying it was a legitimate decoy method in dealing with the 16-month Palestinian uprising. In addition, Jewish settlers living in the occupied lands have sometimes used `` Press'' signs to pass unharmed through Palestinian roadblocks where stone-throwers hurl rocks at cars with the yellow Israeli license plates. Palestinians have alleged that <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> secret service agents were also presenting themselves as journalists. Masked Palestinian activists have often stopped reporters to check their credentials. <PERSON> Bar-Lev </PERSON> said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio Monday that police would look into the Palestinian-issued press cards. `` Those issuing these cards are an organization in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` We will check if it's against the law, and what law, and what steps can we take against people issuing these cards.'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Slater </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said foreign journalists had to use the Palestinian cards because <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> security officials had posed as journalists. `` After police were posing as journalists, the Palestinians saw the Israeli press cards as identifying either a real journalist or a police agent,'' he said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. `` I can understand that the Palestinians want to make our work easier and give us their cards.'' `` It gives them some possibility to check if the man is really a reporter and we accept it, it makes it easier for us,'' said <PERSON> Slater </PERSON>, whose organization represents 200 to 300 foreign journalists posted in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` If a reporter has to get a card from some element, it's not a violation of some norm but a natural thing in every conflict in the world ... in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' he added. But <PERSON> Yoram </PERSON> <PERSON> Ettinger </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, said that `` the very acceptance of a Palestinian card in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, I think, is a challenge to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s sovereignty.'' `` As far as I know the card has a map of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> from the <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> river to the sea which means the elimination of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>,'' he said on <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> radio. Neither <PERSON> Slater </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Ettinger </PERSON> identified the organization that produces the press cards. The Israeli news agency <ORGANIZATION> Itim </ORGANIZATION> said it was a Jerusalem-based organization called `` Palestinian Press Office.'' <PERSON> Radwan </PERSON> <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyash </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> based in east <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, said his office has been issuing cards for foreign journalists for the last two years. There is no map on these cards. `` The cards are not a challenge to anybody and have no political significance whatsoever,'' <PERSON> Abu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayyash </PERSON> said. `` It has nothing to do with the uprising or an independent Palestinian state. Moreover, our association has a license from the Israeli <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>.'' He said the cards were issued upon request by foreign reporters who `` told us, we are harmed by your people, would you do something to help us and we did.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0641EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Car-House     04-25 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Car-House,0186</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Smashes Through House, Misses Sleeping Couple</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KINGSTON, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sports car crashed into a house and tore through a bedroom but missed the couple sleeping there. The car left the street at about 1:30 a.m. Sunday, ran up a small embankment and hurtled through the air. It glanced off a pickup truck parked outside the house, crashed through the house and landed about 35 feet away in a yard next door. `` All I heard was a big explosion and glass smashing and the wall came in and fell on me,'' said <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Viator </PERSON>, the owner of the house. `` If they had n't hit my pickup, they would have come through the wall and landed on top of my wife and me.'' The driver of the car was taken to <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> with cuts and bruises and released. A passenger suffered a broken breastbone. <PERSON> Viator </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Ann </PERSON>, escaped serious injury. Their children, 9-year-old <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> and 5-year-old <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON>, were asleep in their bedroom in a far corner of the house and were not injured.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SmallestEmbassy Bjt   04-25 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Smallest Embassy, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embassy of Dominica is Family Affair</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALEXANDRIA, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ambassador <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>'s pinstripe pants are wearing a little thin these days He will miss his prime minister's arrival from <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> this weekend because he'll be flying to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, where he doubles as ambassador to <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. Not to worry, says <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>, puffing contentedly on his pipe. He will leave the welcoming ceremonies to the capable hands of his local embassy staff _ his wife, <PERSON> Angela </PERSON>, and their 25-year-old son, <PERSON> McDonald </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> is the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> diplomatic representative of the 86,000 people of <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> -LRB- pronounced <LOCATION> Dom-i-NEE-ca </LOCATION> -RRB-, a mountainous, lushly forested island nestled between the French islands of <LOCATION> Guadeloupe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Martinique </LOCATION> in the eastern <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> His embassy, the smallest in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, occupies the <ORGANIZATION> Benjamins </ORGANIZATION>' eighth-floor apartment in a high-rise condominium overlooking suburban <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION> His wife says they have `` the best view of any embassy in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.'' The embassy's only official decoration is the <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> national flag, mounted on a six-foot pole in the foyer. <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> is too poor to furnish <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> with a chauffeur-driven limousine, so he drives to his diplomatic appointments in the family's 1987 <LOCATION> Plymouth </LOCATION> sedan. When the ambassador invites guests to an embassy dinner party, his German-born wife dons an apron and prepares the food. `` I am what you call a gourmet cook,'' says Mrs. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>. `` I love to do my own cooking.'' <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON>, 65, a retired economist and official of the International Fund for Agricultural and <ORGANIZATION> Rural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> agency, has served without pay as <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>'s ambassador to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and the Food and <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> since 1986. He gets an annual $ 25,000 expense account to cover the costs of telephone calls, correspondence and his shuttle flights between <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, where he spends eight months a year. While he's away, Mrs. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> handles routine embassy affairs, and their son steps in when they're both traveling. `` We get up early and get our work done like any other embassy,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> says. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> and his wife are staunchly proud of their country, which gained its independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> in 1978, and their beloved leader, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Eugenia </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, first female prime minister of the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. She arrives Sunday for three days of meetings with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, legislators and a private group seeking to raise $ 600,000 to rebuild <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> building, which was destroyed by fire in 1979. `` <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION> is one of the most unspoiled and physically one of the most beautiful countries in the world,'' <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> said in a recent interview. The island, 29 miles long and 15 miles wide, contains vast rain forests, volcanic peaks, waterfalls, hot springs, a cratered `` boiling lake'' and 365 rivers _ one for each day of the year. It is the home of the world's only Sisserou parrots and the only full-blooded Carib Indians, and the waters off its southwestern coast are considered a scuba diver's paradise. <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> also praises his country's 95 percent literacy rate, a new highway network, the doubling of <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>'s production of bananas _ its main export _ an excellent debt-payment record and plans to build an international airport to spur tourist traffic. The ambassador reminds people that he represents the Commonwealth of <LOCATION> Dominica </LOCATION>, not the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, even though his embassy receives phone calls and mail _ some of it top secret _ for the other, much larger <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> nation. Says Benjamin: `` Whenever I see the ambassador from the <LOCATION> Dominican </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, I say, ` Would n't it be a good idea for us to merge our two embassies? Then we could share our secrets fully'.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Looters     04-25 0237</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Looters,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Arrest 98 In Changsha Rioting</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-China</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police in the southern city of <LOCATION> Changsha </LOCATION> arrested 98 people, just six of them students, for looting that occurred during a student demonstration last weekend, an official newspaper reported today. The People's Daily said those arrested were caught looting 28 shops and a shopping arcade Saturday in what the official press described as the worst rioting in 40 years of Communist rule. Rioting also broke out Saturday in the ancient capital of <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION>, with crowds throwing rocks and setting fire to buildings and vehicles. The daily said that of the 98 detained in <LOCATION> Changsha </LOCATION>, 32 were workers, 28 were unemployed, 26 were peasants, six were self-employed and six were students. It said 52 were waiting trial. The outbreaks of violence occurred as university students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and other cities took to the streets to mourn former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, a reformist who died April 15, and call for democratic reforms. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Saturday, 150,000 students congregated on Tiananmen Square in the center of the city for a peaceful demonstration. Student leaders in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have made efforts to keep unemployed youth and other potential troublemakers out of their ranks. Most of the other demonstrations have also been peaceful, although foreign sources said students at the <ORGANIZATION> Agricultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hefei </LOCATION>, eastern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, last week smashed windows and furniture in a campus cafeteria.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890425-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-25-89 0248EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Wright     04-25 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Wright,690</SECOND>
<HEAD>Wright a Major Non-Subject During Lawmakers' Back-Home Meetings</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By STEVEN KOMAROW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
