<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DefenseProbe-Profiles     01-07 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Defense Probe-Profiles,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Profiles Of Those Indicted In Defense Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Defense Probe Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are brief profiles of the individuals indicted Friday in connection with the federal government's investigation into <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> fraud and the three figures who pleaded guilty to charges stemming from the probe _ <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Berlin </PERSON>, the only government employee indicted in the case, headed the ship systems engineering branch of the <ORGANIZATION> Naval </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> from October 1986 until he was reassigned by the Pentagon in June 1988 <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> procurement specialist, faces charges of accepting bribes in exchange for providing classified information. Court documents say <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> provided information to <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Newbury </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Greenlawn </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> Alexandria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, defense consultant, worked in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s Joint Cruise Missile Project from 1977 to 1983 According to affadavits released last week, <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON> was hired by <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> to get inside information from the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> that would allow the company to compete for a $ 15.9 million contract for battlefield equipment. The indictments said <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> agreed to pay <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON>'s firm $ 160,000 to obtain inside information in obtaining a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> contract. _ <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Woodland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, consultant, has worked for a number of aerospace companies, including <ORGANIZATION> Northrop </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Hawthorne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Stromberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carlson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Winter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, then a unit of <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dynamics </ORGANIZATION> and later a division of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> unit of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> The indictment said <PERSON> Lackner </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> struck an agreement that <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> would help <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> win a contract in exchange for money. _ <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Colarusso </PERSON>, 58, is a former senior vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a division of <ORGANIZATION> Emerson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electronics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Colarusso </PERSON>, who worked at the <LOCATION> Greenlawn </LOCATION> office, joined <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> in 1959 and was appointed senior vice president in He resigned on Dec. 1, 1988. <PERSON> Colarusso </PERSON> pleaded guilty to one count of conspiracy to defraud the government and commit wire fraud. _ <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Furciniti </PERSON>, 54, is a former marketing representative of the <ORGANIZATION> Hazeltine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, who held the title of vice president He worked for the company for 20 years, resigning in May 1988 to take a job with another firm. Like <PERSON> Colarusso </PERSON>, he pleaded guilty to conspiracy to defraud the government and commit wire fraud. _ <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Savaides </PERSON>, 41, is a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C.-based lobbyist for <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> According to the government, <PERSON> Savaides </PERSON> had a financial relationship with <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON>. Affadavits showed that <PERSON> Parkin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Savaides </PERSON> had planned at one time to divide $ 150,000 from <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION>. _ Other <ORGANIZATION> Teledyne </ORGANIZATION> employees named in the indictment are <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaub </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Schnittjer </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PayRaise     01-07 0669</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pay Raise,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Speaker Takes No Position On Pay Raise Question</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, who normally has strong influence over the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> agenda, says he will `` neither encourage nor prevent a vote'' on a 50 percent pay raise proposed for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, judges and top executive branch officials. While <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> declined to take a stand Friday on the politically risky pay plan, he said lawmakers would ban speaking fees and certain other outside income for themselves if the proposal were enacted. The large pay raise was recommended by a presidential commission and endorsed Thursday by President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, who will formally send the proposal to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> with his budget plan on Monday. `` We must ensure that the door to service remains open to Americans who must work to support their families, educate their children and save for their retirement,'' the president wrote <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in a letter explaining his position. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> also proposed an end to the often-criticized outside income system for members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. The raise will become law automatically unless each house of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> rejects it by Feb. 8 _ 30 days after <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s budget submission. `` I think that the speaker -LRB- House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> -RRB- is committed to making sure there is no vote,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Tauke </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Iowa </LOCATION>, who has proposed legislation requiring <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to vote on any pay raise, while delaying enactment until the next <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said Friday, `` I will neither encourage nor prevent a vote. Regular procedure will be followed.'' Regular procedure normally means legislation would go to a committee, be the subject of hearings, and return to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor after committee approval. Such a process normally takes far longer than 30 days. Referring to outside income for lawmakers, called honoraria, <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> said, `` If the pay raise takes effect, there will be a ban on speaking fees and certain other forms of outside income-earning limitations are being drafted in bipartisan consultations.'' In the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, has promised a vote. Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, called the pay raise preposterous and said he had asked <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders to schedule an early vote on a resolution of disapproval. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> chose not to modify the presidential commission's recommendation that members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and federal district judges, who now make $ 89,500 a year, be paid $ 135,000 The speaker's annual salary would go from $ 115,000 to $ 175,000, and that of majority and minority leaders from $ 99,500 to $ 155,000. Top executive-branch officials such as Cabinet members would get raises from their current $ 99,500 a year to $ 155,000. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s proposal would raise a president's annual pay to about $ 350,000 from the current $ 200,000, where it has stood since 1969. However, such a hike would not take effect until 1993 because of a constitutional prohibition on raising a president's pay during his term. President-elect <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said Friday he supported <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s decision, but may take another look at the issue when he becomes president. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> takes office Jan. 20. Asked by reporters if the nation could afford the big pay increase at a time when it is grappling with huge budget deficits, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said: `` Well, I do n't know whether we can afford anything than to get this deficit under control.'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxpayers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has a personal stake in his recommendation because his pension would rise by 56 percent if the pay raise is approved. The pension is tied to Cabinet salaries. The pension increase from $ 99,500 to $ 155,000 annually also would apply to former <ORGANIZATION> Presidents </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and the three former presidents should refuse the increase. A White House press spokesman, <PERSON> B.J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, said the taxpayer union figures were accurate, but had no comment on the call for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to refuse the increase. `` The president was not aware of that when he approved the pay raise,'' <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know whether it would have changed his decision, the other factors being so overwhelming.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HealthBudget     01-07 0263</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Health Budget,0268</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report: Budget Will Include Boost For AIDS</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Federal funding for AIDS programs would expand by 30 percent while <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> and Medicaid would be restrained under a health and human services budget the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration will submit to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Monday, a published report said. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in its Saturday editions reported that the $ 424.4 billion budget for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> amounts to $ 22.8 billion more than the department got in 1988. More than half of the budget, $ 260 billion, would be spent on Social Security, which would receive $ 13 billion more than is now spent to cover an increase in recipients and a 3.6 percent cost-of-living boost, the Times said. The proposed expenditures are subject to revision by President-elect <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> after Jan. 20 and by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has said he would not make cuts in Social Security, which goes to more than 40 million Americans. For AIDS, the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration recommended spending $ 2.5 billion, including $ 1.6 billion for research, education and prevention and $ 925 million for treatment and other assistance for AIDS victims. The administration proposed $ 106.1 billion for <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION>, an increase of $ 10 billion, but still $ 3.5 billion less than would have occurred under current law. It proposed $ 36 billion for Medicaid, a boost of nearly $ 2 billion but $ 2 billion less than under current law, the Times said. <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> is the health insurance program for 31 million older Americans and 3 million other disabled persons and Medicaid is a federal-state health program for the poor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0054EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-INS-CentralAmericans     01-07 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-INS-Central Americans,0476</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawsuit Filed against New Political Asylum Process</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOEL WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HARLINGEN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Central American immigrants filed suit against the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Naturalization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, demanding that the agency once again let them travel to their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> destinations to apply for asylum. The lawsuit, filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, seeks to reverse INS rules of Dec. 16 that made it impossible for most asylum-seekers to leave south <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> or work while waiting 30 days for approval or denial of their claims. `` It would allow the asylum applicant to have the interview and the adjudication of the asylum claim heard and decided by the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> office nearest their intended residence in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON>, who heads the national <ORGANIZATION> Immigrant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Refugee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Project </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lawyers </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION>. A hearing has been set for 9 a.m. Monday on their motion for a temporary restraining order. <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> declined comment on the lawsuit because they had not seen it. Most Central Americans enter the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> illegally in the <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION> area of the lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, the nearest land point to <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. Officials with the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> said nine personnel were added Friday, bringing the total of <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> asylum adjudicators to 16, and will speed up processing and eliminate a backlog. The lawsuit accuses the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> of imposing a policy change without allowing public comment; of denying aliens access to the asylum process and access to counsel; and improperly restricting the right to work. It cites the case of a 69-year-old Nicaraguan woman who said she slept outside the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> for three nights to keep her place in line, then was told she needed a fingerprint card. She said she then walked four miles to the <ORGANIZATION> Harlingen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to obtain the prints, then returned to the <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> office where she again slept outside to keep her place. Before Dec. 16, asylum-seekers in <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> were allowed to travel to their <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> destinations to apply for asylum, often <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> INS </ORGANIZATION> officials said they adopted the new procedure in <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION> to reduce huge case backlogs in those cities and to curb abuses of the system that delayed processing for legitimate asylum cases. They also said the new procedure apparently has begun to deter frivolous claims, with the more than 2,000 claims a week in early December reduced to about 1,000 a week since Dec. 16. Those who previously would have traveled out of the area are staying in places such as the condemned Amber Motel in <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, on the border 25 miles south of <LOCATION> Harlingen </LOCATION>, and a squalid, makeshift campsite where several hundred people have carved out spaces in the brush.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     01-07 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0088</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 0-2-4-3.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 08; 20; 23; 33; 36.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 01; 05; 13; 30; 34; 42. Bonus: 05451.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 06; 14; 15; 41; 45; 51. Supplementary 2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 9-2-1-9.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 6-2-0; 0-0-6-0; 2-4-4-9-7; 0-1-3-0-2-2.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 14; 16; 20; 28; 32; 37.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GraniteScrapped     01-07 0187</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Granite Scrapped,0192</SECOND>
<HEAD>South African Granite Scrapped For Bus Tunnel</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city's transit and sewage authority is giving up $ 480,000 of granite it bought for a downtown bus tunnel because the stone came from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, the agency announced. `` It would violate the spirit of our policy and would be an affront to the community'' to use the granite, executive <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibbs </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> Thursday. The granite _ enough to cover 24,000 square feet _ is sitting in supply yards in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, where it was cut. `` We're going to have to eat the cost,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalberer </PERSON>, superintendent of the $ 430 million tunnel project. <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> hopes to sell the granite for scrap to recoup some of the cost, he added. <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Royer </PERSON> agreed with the decision. `` This could be a serious affront and embarrassment for lots of people,'' he said. The <ORGANIZATION> Metro </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> banned the purchase of South African goods because of that country's policy of racial segregation, or apartheid, after a county councilman and city councilman protested the use of South African steel in tunnel work in 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NotDrafted     01-07 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Not Drafted,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Man To Register Under New Law Now Too Old To Be Drafted</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAFAYETTE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The first man since the Vietnam War to get through eight years of draft eligibility without being called to arms said something was missing from his 26th birthday celebration. `` I'm proud within myself about it. I wish I had an award or something though. That would have been nice. Maybe a plaque to hang on the wall,'' said <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, the first 18-year-old to sign up and be processed by the Selective Service System after draft registration was revived in 1981, turned 26 on Friday. That made him too old to be called up even if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president reactivate the draft, according to <ORGANIZATION> Selective </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> officials in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` I did n't have to go active and I'm glad about that,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. `` But if it was God's will I would have gone. It's a blessing to be a soldier for this country.'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said he had no idea he was the first man in the country to register when he did so. He said he just followed the law and signed up. `` I was n't worried about being drafted when I was 18. I do n't think I even thought about it, but if it had happened it would have just happened When I turned 21 I got more worried about it,'' <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> said. The draft was stopped in 1973 after the end of the Vietnam War, but registration was revived on Jan. 5, 1981. Federal law requires every man to register with <ORGANIZATION> Selective </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> within 30 days of his 18th birthday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0119EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FAA-Cracking     01-07 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FAA-Cracking,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Airlines Asked To Replace Rivets On Older 727s</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The federal government is recommending that airlines replace tens of thousands of rivets on more than 600 older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 passenger jets. In a proposed directive issued Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> also urged the carriers to adopt special inspection procedures until the rivet work is done. The repairs are not expected to disrupt air service because most of the work will be done on a timetable that could stretch over as long as four years, <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The proposed directive is the result of increasing concern about cracking on older commercial jetliners. It is similar to an order issued last October for older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s. A final order will not be issued until after a brief period to allow public and industry comment. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> estimated the repairs and extra inspections of 623 older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727s will cost the airlines $ 35.7 million. In a separate action Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> broadened a previous directive for special inspections of older <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> DC-9s to include any aircraft with at least 45,000 landings. Last November, the agency told airlines to conduct repetitive inspections using the electronic `` eddy current'' method of all DC-9s that have had more than 55,000 landings because of concern about possible cracks in the fuselage skin. But the agency said since then it has discovered cracks on more than 20 aircraft that had between 45,000 and 52,000 landings, prompting the special precautions for the additional aircraft. The agency said 476 DC-9s belonging to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air carriers would be affected by the new directive. Under the order, airlines must conduct repetitive eddy current inspections of the fuselage skin as well as an area just over the wings on the DC-9s. The inspections must be conducted at least every 5,800 landings. The proposed directive on the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727s requires that airlines over the next four years replace from 3,300 to 4,150 rivets on each plane, depending on the model of 727 involved. It said the `` countersunk'' rivets now on the planes is believed to cause cracking under some circumstances, while the substitute `` button-head'' is less likely to do so. The <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> said cracks on both the 727 and 737 aircraft have been traced to a `` cold bonding'' process that was used in the earlier models of the plane to bind sheets of fuselage skin together. That method was discontinued in later models. The agency said it plans to order eddy current testing and increased visual testing of the <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 on a regular basis until the rivets can be changed. Last October, the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> ordered thousands of rivets replaced on older <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 737s to help guard against cracking. There have been a number of incidents during the past year in which large cracks developed on older aircraft.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0030EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonRiot 2ndLd-Writethru a0757 01-07 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Riot, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0757,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>Inmate Riot Quelled At Milledgeville Lockup</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 5 grafs to UPDATE injuries, number of officers involved;
picks up 4th graf: `The riot ...</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILLEDGEVILLE, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Inmates at the Youthful Correctional Offender Institution rioted for about two hours Friday, but corrections officers and police tactical units stayed on overnight, authorities said. Three inmates and one corrections officer were injured in the uprising and there was `` minimal damage'' to the lockup said <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said she did not know what set off the disturbance or how many inmates were involved. Despite the name of the facility, the average age of the 970 inmates at the prison is 24, according to Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said the injured officer, who was not identified, broke his hand, apparently by slipping and falling. The injury, she said, `` was not in contact with an inmate.'' She did not have details of the inmates' injuries. Five tactical units of 18 officers each were called in to help stop the uprising, which began about 4:45 p.m., apparently in sympathy with a disturbance at a nearby state prison earlier this week. The riot, which broke out around 4:45 p.m. with inmates damaging and breaking property, Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said. The crowd control officers used tear gas to halt the uprising in the Kemper Building, one of three units comprising the lockup, Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said. `` When they did -LRB- use tear gas -RRB-, they immediately began to quiet down. It then spilled over into the <ORGANIZATION> Holly </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Building </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- a second unit -RRB-,'' she said. Tear gas was not used in the second unit, because the situation there was not as severe, Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said. `` There was no damage done. It was mostly a lot of yelling, a lot of cussing,'' she said. Because the tear gas spread beyond the Kemper Building, about 100 inmates could not be returned immediately to their cells, and were held in a yard until the gas clears, Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said. Two tactical units from <LOCATION> Milledgeville </LOCATION>, in central <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> about 25 miles east of <LOCATION> Macon </LOCATION>, and one from <LOCATION> Reidsville </LOCATION> remained on the scene, Ms. <PERSON> Drake </PERSON> said, adding that the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> would begin an internal investigation into the disturbance. If the inmates who were responsible are identified, they would be segregated from the rest of the prison population and would face administrative charges, she said. Friday's uprising marked the second disturbance at a <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> prison this week. On Tuesday, inmates rioted at <ORGANIZATION> Rivers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Milledgeville </LOCATION>, an incident officials called the most serious in the state in 10 years. More than 900 inmates participated in the earlier incident, with three officers and three inmates injured and $ 300,000 in damage reported.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     01-07 0977</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1017</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rock star Prince has made a clean breast of it in the new year by getting a new manager, lawyer and accountant. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> has hired film director <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Magnoli </PERSON> as his manager, replacing the management team of <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavallo </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Ruffalo </PERSON> and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Fargnoli </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Leeds </PERSON>, operations manager for <ORGANIZATION> PRN </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Productions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Magnoli </PERSON> directed <PERSON> Prince </PERSON>'s 1984 hit movie `` Purple Rain. `` It's a new year,'' <ORGANIZATION> Leeds </ORGANIZATION> said Friday, explaining the change which took effect Tuesday. He declined to elaborate. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> also severed his 11-year relationship with attorney <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> and retained the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> law firm of <PERSON> Ziffren </PERSON>, <PERSON> Brittenham </PERSON> and <PERSON> Branca </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Leeds </ORGANIZATION> said. He also replaced Moultrie Accountancy with the accounting firm of <PERSON> Breslauer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jacobson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rutman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Broadway debut of the hit British comedy `` <ORGANIZATION> Lettice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Lovage'' has been postponed until next season because its star, <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, is still recovering from a fractured shoulder, a spokeswoman for the play said. The play, which won the <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> Evening Standard award for best comedy of 1988, had been scheduled to open on Broadway April 2 but now will be pushed back to the 1989-90 season, spokeswoman <PERSON> Merle </PERSON> <PERSON> Frimark </PERSON> said Friday. She gave no specific dates. Miss <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> broke her shoulder while riding a bicycle on vacation in November. The play, written by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaffer </PERSON>, author of `` Amadeus'' and `` Equus,'' concerns an eccentric woman who gives tours through the stately homes of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Ole Opry star <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, who suffered a mild heart attack earlier this week, is to undergo heart bypass surgery, according to his publicist. `` He will be transferred to <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Monday and then the surgery is tentatively scheduled for Tuesday morning,'' publicist <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, 48, who wrote the song `` Act Naturally,'' was in stable condition after being admitted to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Tuesday after complaining of chest pains. `` He's eating well and in good spirits. He even joked about it, saying when he gets out of the hospital, he could join <PERSON> Waylon </PERSON> -LRB- Jennings -RRB- and -LRB- <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> -RRB- Cash as a trio to perform a song called `` Bypass 101.'' Both country music singers had bypasses in the last month.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farms, estates and mansions belonging to notables such as country music singers <PERSON> Ronnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Milsap </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> Sr. will be auctioned Jan. 21 for up to $ 30 million, an auctioneer said. Among the properties being sold are the <ORGANIZATION> Giles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Milky </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Way </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Farms </ORGANIZATION> retreat built by candy bar magnate <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mars </PERSON>, the farm of <PERSON> Milsap </PERSON> and the former <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> estate of <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>. Auctioneer <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Arvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hensley </PERSON> says the sale of 200 properties will be `` the largest diversified auction ever in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> history.'' `` It is not a distress sale,'' said <PERSON> Hensley </PERSON>, who has spent the last several months organizing the properties and a catalog distributed to thousands of potential bidders across the country. `` We are auctioning off history and we are auctioning the future,'' she said.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version is moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> is suing his boss, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON>, for more than $ 1 million that the star outfielder claims the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> owner owes to his foundation for fighting drug abuse. In a lawsuit filed Friday in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> has not complied with a stipulation of his contract to pay $ 300,000 a year to the <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> Foundation. <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON>, in a statement, said an investigation of the foundation discovered `` numerous questionable practices'' that would be outlined in a counter-suit to be filed Monday. `` I just wish he had chosen another course, but there can be no turning back now,'' said <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON>, who has been publicly feuding with <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON> for several years. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON>'s attorney, said the <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION>' suit will allege excessive limousine expenses of more than $ 40,000 over a two-year period, excessive and disproportionate management and administrative costs and other items <PERSON> Winfield </PERSON>'s suit seeks $ 450,000 that he says <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> owes going back to Sept. 1, 1987, plus the balance owed for the duration of the player's 10-year contract, for a total of $ 1,050,000. A <ORGANIZATION> Winfield </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> statement said it was the third time the foundation has had to sue <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> for non-compliance. In 1982 and 1983, <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> paid the full amount owed, it said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Wozniak </PERSON>, co-founder of <ORGANIZATION> Apple </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Computer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, has briefly set aside his floppy disks to spin record discs. The 33-year-old entrepreneur this week made his third appearance on <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose-based </LOCATION> <LOCATION> KSJO-FM </LOCATION>, acting as substitute co-host of a morning drive-time program, said station manager <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Baronfeld </PERSON>. `` Our audience is between 22 and 38,'' said <PERSON> Baronfeld </PERSON>. `` He reaches that upper end. They can react to a guy like <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> who grew up listening to <PERSON> Santana </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Doobie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Wozniak </PERSON> is an avid collector of vintage rock' n' roll albums and also organized two `` <LOCATION> US </LOCATION> Festivals,'' high-tech concert festivals that married modern music with computer technology.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, who played the saucy maid <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> on the British television series `` Upstairs, Downstairs,'' will make her Broadway debut in a one-woman comedy about a middle-aged English housewife. `` <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentine </PERSON>,'' written by <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, author of the play and film `` Educating <PERSON> Rita </PERSON>,'' concerns a housewife who dreams of a life beyond the kitchen sink. The show, which was a success in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> last winter, will open Feb. 16 at the Booth Theater after a week of previews, said <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Rinaldi </PERSON>, a spokesman for the show. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> will appear under a special exchange agreement between <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> and British Actors' Equity associations that will allow American <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> <PERSON> McAllen </PERSON> to appear in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> this spring in `` Aspects of Love,'' a new <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON> musical.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StarlessWalk     01-07 0206</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Starless Walk,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Commission Says No To Hard Rock Cafe Star Walk</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Hard Rock Cafe is going to try again to persuade a city commission to allow a `` walk of fame'' on the sidewalks surrounding the French Quarter rock' n' roll eatery, a spokeswoman said. `` They plan to resubmit their proposal, and for the moment have pledged that the <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> side be dedicated to native <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> musicians such as Fats Domino,'' said spokeswoman <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutson </PERSON> in a news release Friday. The restaurant sought permission from a committee of the <ORGANIZATION> Vieux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday to install 10 to 12 brass plaques, emblazoned with stars, as tributes to musicians who have visited the Hard Rock. Similar sidewalk plaques have been installed at Hard Rock Cafes in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and other cities. All five members of the <ORGANIZATION> Vieux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s architecture committee, expressed displeasure with the idea. The commission is charged by the city with guarding the historic beauty and architectural integrity of the French Quarter _ the oldest section of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> port city. Among the complaints: the quarter should not be home to memorials for the living and sidewalks should not be used for advertising.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Iran-Contra Bjt   01-07 0472</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran-Contra, Bjt,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Leaders Question Attorney General On Secrets Policy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leading senators are demanding Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> explain why the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration refused to release classified information deemed important to the Iran-Contra case against <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. The <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's position on the secrecy question contributed to a move by independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> earlier this week to have two key charges against North dropped. <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> on Friday strongly defended the administration's refusal to allow the release of more classified material in the North case, saying that dropping the conspiracy and theft counts is `` hardly'' going to provide `` a precedent in every case. The attorney general said the question is whether it is more important `` to go ahead with a particular criminal prosecution'' as opposed to `` what harm might come to the country's long-term interests'' by exposing sensitive information. An interagency intelligence group in the administration refused to permit the release of additional classified material which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said must be disclosed in order for North to get a fair trial. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> then decided to abandon the charges that the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide illegally diverted more than $ 14 million in U.S.-Iran arms-sale profits to the Nicaraguan rebels. Three others are also charged with the same counts, but their trials have been severed. North still faces 12 other charges. His trial is scheduled to begin Jan. 31. The Classified Information Procedures Act `` requires a full explanation to the congressional committees ... as to why'' conspiracy and theft charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON> `` could not be tried without disclosing classified information,'' said the chairmen of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> committees. In a letter to the attorney general, the senators asked <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON> to include the explanation in his next semiannual report on the operation of the law, which was passed by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to prevent defendants from using `` graymail'' to scuttle their prosecution. The letter came from Sens. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., and <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Maine </LOCATION>, respectively chairman and vice-chairman of the intelligence panel and Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON>, D-Del., who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> on Monday is expected to grant <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>'s motion to drop the two counts against North. The Classified Information Procedures Act requires the attorney general to report to the congressional intelligence and judiciary committees any time criminal charges are dismissed on grounds that continued prosecution in open court would jeopardize national security. The lawmakers acknowledged that <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, not the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, had decided to seek dismissal of the two central charges. But they said the <ORGANIZATION> CIPA </ORGANIZATION> reporting provision was enacted `` to provide an opportunity for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to review, as appropriate, circumstances of this sort.'' Such reviews are needed to `` ensure that decisions not to prosecute alleged criminal conduct were, in fact, prompted by legitimate national security concerns.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Derailment-Drugs     01-07 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Derailment-Drugs,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amtrak, Tower Operator Given Blame For Derailment</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> and a control tower operator who tested positive for drugs share the blame for a Boston-bound train derailment that injured 25 people, says the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The operator, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, fled the control tower after the January 1988 accident in <LOCATION> Chester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, and later tested positive for marijuana and small traces of cocaine and methamphetamine. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said in a report Friday that <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>, who resigned after the accident, let the `` Night Owl'' train travel on a section of track undergoing maintenance. The train struck a work vehicle. The <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Connor </PERSON>'s failure to hit the proper switch so the train could cross to the right track was the result of `` of impairment by drugs or distraction or both.'' The agency said <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> shared responsibility with <PERSON> Connor </PERSON> for the accident. It said the passenger line should develop a procedure `` to prevent locomotives or trains from entering out-of-service track sections, unless permission has been received from the person in charge of the out-of-service track ... `` <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> also failed `` to adequately monitor the activities and job performance of the tower operator,'' the agency said. <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobsen </PERSON> said Friday that he had not yet seen the <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> report.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PrematureBirths     01-07 0373</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Premature Births,0383</SECOND>
<HEAD>``Take-It-Easy'' Program Reduces Premature Births, Study Suggests</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MALCOLM RITTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A program that included paid work leaves and avoiding physical exertion cut the premature birth rate at a French hospital by a third, but its cost-effectiveness is debatable, researchers say. Participants could take longer leaves than the six-week paid leave available to <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> women before their due date, said researcher <PERSON> Emile </PERSON> <PERSON> Papiernik </PERSON>. For example, a woman whose job involved a lot of standing might begin the leave 10 weeks before the due date, said <PERSON> Papiernik </PERSON>, chairman of the obstetrics and gynecology department at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paris </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. The program also included teaching women to avoid physically taxing situations at home like moving a household, and to follow such steps as sitting rather than standing when washing clothes, <PERSON> Papiernik </PERSON> said Friday in an interview. It also stressed close relationships with caregivers, he said. The overall goal was to reduce physical exertion that triggers the uterus to contract during pregnancy. A study of more than 16,000 deliveries at the hospital found that while premature deliveries stood at 5.4 percent of live births for 1971-74, they decreased to 3.6 percent for 1979-82. The study could not demonstrate statistically that work leaves themselves made a difference, but they probably helped, <PERSON> Papiernik </PERSON> wrote in a book about the research. But an American expert said the French approach would incur `` inappropriate and unnecessary costs'' in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> because most participants would have had full-term pregnancies anyway. Most women at risk for premature births carry their fetuses to term, and physicians can not predict with great accuracy who will deliver prematurely, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southwestern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> MacDonald </PERSON> also said many women may not want to pass up economic and psychological benefits of working. He and <PERSON> Papiernik </PERSON> spoke at a seminar sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> March </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dimes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Birth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defects </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>. Some 350,000 American babies every year are born more than three weeks before the end of the normal 40-week term, the foundation says. They account for 70 percent of infant deaths, and are at risk for such problems as cerebral palsy, seizure disorders, mental retardation, and impairments of vision and hearing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0140EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Reagan-Hirohito     01-07 0430</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Reagan-Hirohito,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Lauds Japanese Emperor For Role In Ending WWII</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> WASHINGTON </LOCATION> _ President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> mourned the death of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, saying he played `` a truly heroic role'' in ending World War II hostilities between his country and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` On behalf of the people and government of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, we extend our deepest condolences to His Imperial Majesty, the Emperor, to the Imperial family, and to the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION>,'' the president said in a statement released by the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> shortly after the annoucement of the emperor's death Friday. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said the emperor's 62-year reign `` spanned one of the most tumultuous, and yet at the same time constructive eras in the history of mankind _ an age of unprecedented economic collapse, a most vicious war, astonishing scientific acheivement, and dramatic political and social changes throughout the world.'' `` It was also an era of unprecedented reconciliation. His majesty played a truly heroic role in bringing hostilities between our two peoples to an end and leading the Japanese people through a period of reconstruction and reconciliation that has resulted in both the prosperity the Japanese know today and in the close relations our two nations and peoples now enjoy,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. The president recalled the late emperor had visited the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in 1975, and that he and his wife <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> had `` enjoyed several meetings with him, most recently in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>'' in 1986. The statement also noted the first couple had entertained the former Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and Crown Princess <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> at the White House in 1987. `` While we mourn the passing of His majesty, we shall long remember him for his contributions which strengthened the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States-Japan </ORGANIZATION> relationship and set a future course of continued close and friendly relations,'' the president said. Presidential spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said that because there will be a waiting period before <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral, the decision on whom to send would be up to the incoming administration of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> sent letters of condolence to both <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s son, <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>, and the prime minister of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Sean </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON>, a press aide in the vice president's office. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> met the late emperor once on a 1982 visit to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Akahito </PERSON> visited <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at his home during a trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year. The two played tennis together on that occasion. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s office did not release the text of the letters. <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> conveyed `` his sincerest condolences'' to <PERSON> Akahito </PERSON> on the death of his father, and expressed similar sentiments in the letter to the prime minister.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-Profile 2Takes   01-07 1066</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-Profile, 2 Takes,1096</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Biggest Decision of a 62-Year Reign _ Surrender in World War
II</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Hirohito, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> TOKYO </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> _ Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> will be remembered for one overwhelming decision during his 62-year reign: <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> must bow to defeat for the first time in its history and end the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> conflict in World War II. Shortly after that decision, and for most of his reign, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> became a figurehead, isolated from his subjects by tradition and steeped in his great love, the study of marine biology. He was the last survivor among the national leaders of the World War II era. But in his first 20 years, the `` Son of Heaven'' was worshiped as a divinity descended from the <ORGANIZATION> Sun </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Goddess </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amaterasu </ORGANIZATION>. The solitude of animal and plant life under the seas which so intrigued <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was in keeping with the character of the man who became the 124th occupant of the Chrysanthemum Throne at the age of 25 on Christmas Day 1926, designating his reign `` Showa'' _ `` enlightened peace.'' The emperor was generally portrayed as having played no significant role in planning or carrying out <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s military adventures in the 1930s and 1940s. But it was his first effective decision as emperor, and his most courageous, that ended the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> conflict. On Aug. 10, 1945, four days after history's first atomic bomb devastated <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> and one day after a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bomber dropped the second atomic bomb on <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION>, the generals and admirals of Imperial <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s wartime government argued for hours in the sweltering bombproof shelter beneath the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> palace. Should <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> agree to the Allies' surrender demand, or fight on until annihilation? Speaking in what some of those present described as a slow and obviously nervous monotone, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, the spiritual and titular leader, offered his opinion for the first time. He spoke of his sorrow over the soldiers and sailors killed in the long war, and of families who lost everything in air raids. `` I can not bear to see my innocent people suffer any longer,'' he said. `` Ending the war is the only way to restore world peace and to relieve the nation from the terrible distress with which it is burdened.'' Then, evoking a memory of his grandfather, the Emperor <PERSON> Meiji </PERSON>, whose reign -LRB- 1867-1912 -RRB- saw the end of 250 years of feudal Japanese isolation from the outside world, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> told the officers: `` The time has come when we must bear the unbearable.'' In the days that followed, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> continued his break with tradition. In a national radio broadcast Aug. 15 _ the first time ordinary Japanese ever actually heard his voice _ he personally announced the decision to surrender. He told the ravaged nation that `` the war situation has developed not necessarily to our advantage.'' Three weeks later, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> donned a silk cutaway coat, striped trousers and a top hat to meet the Allied commander, Gen. <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> MacArthur </PERSON>, at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. It was the first time <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> had ever gone to see anyone, and the first of several calls on the general who had led the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> war against <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and became its postwar governor. On New Year's Day 1946, at <ORGANIZATION> MacArthur </ORGANIZATION>'s insistence, the emperor publicly renounced his divinity. It was a choice that enabled <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> to remain as the symbolic head of his nation and assured that he would not face charges as a war criminal, as some abroad had demanded. It also was an act that seemed to relieve no one as much as this gentle, shy and retiring man who never seemed very comfortable as a `` living god.'' The emperor's status in the eyes of many Japanese changed to that of a kind uncle. He became a widely respected authority on marine biology. He possessed rare collections of marine life, discovered several species himself and wrote or co-authored at least 12 books on hydrozoa, or sea animals, his specialty. In recent years, his life had become the subject of a popular comic book series. Still, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> and the imperial system remained important to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. A nationwide survey by the daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Mainichi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shimbun </ORGANIZATION> in March 1987 indicated more than 80 percent of 2,184 people polled supported the imperial system, while only 11 percent said it should be abolished. Five percent said the emperor should have more power. From 1946 to 1954, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> toured <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to encourage the people to rebuild. The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, which ran his affairs, said <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> considered the postwar period one of the most fulfilling times of his life, in which the nation made a phenomenal recovery from a war that cost 3.1 million Japanese lives. Despite the humanization of the Imperial family, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> remained under strict control of the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Protocol was maintained at nearly all times and he was prohibited from speaking on any controversial subject. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> was born on April 29, 1901. In accordance with age-old imperial custom, he was taken from his parents as an infant to be reared in isolation by household functionaries and trained for one role, that of emperor. His education came as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> surged into the modern world. The feudal samurai ethic was still strong; when his grandfather died, Gen. <PERSON> Maresuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Nogi </PERSON>, the mentor for the 11-year-old prince, calmly committed ritual suicide to follow the emperor, his master, to the grave. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> studied government and law with private tutors. When he was 20, his father, <ORGANIZATION> Emperor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taisho </ORGANIZATION>, sent him abroad _ the first time any member of the immediate imperial family was allowed outside <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> visited <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Scotland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, receiving various decorations. He was also received by <PERSON> Pope </PERSON> <PERSON> Benedict </PERSON> <PERSON> XV </PERSON>. The young man handled money for the first time, paying his own fare on the <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> subway. He developed a passion for bacon and eggs and it became a lifelong breakfast habit. A palace chamberlain said in a 1980 interview that <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> shunned Japanese food `` unless it is forced on him by an unwitting host.'' <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> also acquired a preference for Western clothes. He was never seen in public wearing traditional Japanese garb, and a palace official confided that the Emperor of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> did not even own a kimono. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> became prince regent on Nov. 25, 1921, after his father became a mental and physical invalid, became emperor five years later and was formally enthroned in 1928.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DeConcini-Trip     01-07 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DeConcini-Trip,310</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senator Puts Off Mideast Trip After Questions Raised About Aide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ariz </LOCATION>., has postponed a trip to the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> after approval was withdrawn for his chief political fundraiser to accompany him as a temporary staffer on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> payroll, a spokesman said The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reported in today's editions that Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the new <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> chairman, withdrew approval for <PERSON> Earl </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> to make the trip after receiving an inquiry about the <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> had been scheduled to leave today for a 12-day trip to nine <LOCATION> Mideast </LOCATION> countries. Spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Maynes </PERSON> said <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> had arranged the trip and it now would be postponed. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, a retired Phoenix-area real estate investor who has been <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON>'s chief fundraiser and <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> adviser for years, was being placed on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> payroll for 21 days so he could arrange, and go on, the trip, <PERSON> Maynes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> planned to repay his $ 115 salary to the government and pay as much of his expenses as he could, the spokesman said. The Post reported that a spokeswoman for <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said that committee tradition did not permit members of a senator's personal staff to make trips on committee business without approval from the majority leader. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> was placed on the payroll temporarily so he could travel on military aircraft and get an official passport and visas, <PERSON> Maynes </PERSON> said. `` I'm not exactly sure why Sen. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> as the majority leader approved it in December and then as chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Appropriations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> unapproved it today,'' <PERSON> Maynes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> had planned during his trip to discuss his opposition to arms sales to the Arab countries. The State Department hoped officials in those countries might persuade the senator to be less vociferous in his opposition, <PERSON> Maynes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Katz </PERSON> has traveled with <PERSON> DeConcini </PERSON> to the area twice before, although those trips did not involve military transportation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-POWCallBack     01-07 0703</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-POW Call Back,0719</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Mary Anne' Calls Back, Makes Connection with POW Her Family Rescued</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER MUNNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the 44 years since he survived a massacre of Americans at a Japanese prisoner of war camp in World War II, <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> had often wondered what happened to his Filipino rescuers. A balky telephone answering machine almost cost him a chance to find out. But thanks to the persistence of a <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION> nurse named <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Ancheta </PERSON>, <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> finally has been able to track down the guerrilla band that saved him. Forty-four years ago, Mrs. <PERSON> Ancheta </PERSON> was <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> <PERSON> Major </PERSON>, a 7-year-old whose father ran a guerrilla camp in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>; <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> was a young Marine who was brought into the camp with malaria. `` He was shaking like a leaf, he had the chills,'' she said Friday. `` I remember him, although I did n't remember his name.'' Last month, she noticed an article about a reunion of American prisoners of war in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, saw <PERSON> McDole </PERSON>'s name and called his home on New Year's Eve. But the tape on his answering machine ran out and he did n't get her last name or phone number. Publicity about his request to have `` <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>'' call again resulted in a story in a <LOCATION> Green </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> newspaper Wednesday. Mrs. <PERSON> Ancheta </PERSON> saw it and called <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> on Thursday. `` I saw it at 11 at night and it was too late to call. I could n't sleep and I called the next morning,'' she said `` I felt like I have known him all that while. It's overwhelming. I'm so glad to know he's alive and well after all that ordeal.'' For <PERSON> McDole </PERSON>, the conversation recalled December 1944, when he and about 150 other Americans were held by the Japanese in <LOCATION> Palawan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prison </LOCATION>. He had been there 33 months when <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> forces staged an invasion nearby. `` They made a feint to come toward us but turned away,'' <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> recalled. `` That's when the Japanese decided to annihilate the group of prisoners. They had us down in trenches, and they threw in gasoline and torches. The ones who climbed over the edge were machine gunned.'' <PERSON> McDole </PERSON>'s trench was the one nearest to a 60-foot cliff overlooking a bay. `` We had started digging through anyway, and we knocked the side of ours out and went over the cliff. I think 20, 25 of us made it to the beach, but some of them panicked and they were gunned down. `` I got pinned down and hid under a pile of garbage. I stayed there all night and part of the next day. I thought I was the only man of the 150 to be alive. You do a lot of praying and crying, and I knew that if I did n't make it, nobody would know what happened. They -LRB- the Japanese -RRB- would probably blame it on our own planes.'' Of the 150 prisoners, 11 escaped and six were brought to the guerrilla camp run by Maziro Major, now 88 and retired in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> after a career in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. `` It turns out he was educated in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, which is where he met his wife,'' <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> said. `` They were wonderful to us. They saved our lives.'' The rebels protected and healed the Americans for a month, when they were picked up by a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sea plane. The two groups never made contact again. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> eventually became a nurse in the office of her husband, Dr. <PERSON> Valentino </PERSON> <PERSON> Ancheta </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Algoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, while <PERSON> McDole </PERSON>, 67, is now chief of the patrol division of the <LOCATION> Polk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's office. <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> said he, too, was overwhelmed by the call. `` It's brought back some of the concerns of what happened to the family. I've thought about them all a lot Then all of a sudden, boom, you get a call and I find out the captain is still alive and this is his daughter. I'm going to get a letter off to the captain today. I feel real good.'' `` All these years, I had been hoping to meet one of those men,'' she said. She and <PERSON> McDole </PERSON> said they both hope to attend a reunion next December.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-1975Interview     01-07 0706</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-1975 Interview,0723</SECOND>
<HEAD>In Only Exclusive Interview, Emperor Spoke of Concern for the Japanese
People</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Throughout his lifetime, Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> reigned behind the wide moats and imposing stone walls of the vast Imperial Palace grounds in central <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. During his 62-year reign, only once did an exclusive interview with him appear in print. The <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> zealously protects the imperial family from intrusions, but granted the unique interview to a persistent <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> journalist shortly before <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s 1975 visit to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> bureau chief for <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Magazine </ORGANIZATION> from 1968 to 1980, kept his campaign secret from competitors. `` Ever since I came here I waited for an occasion to persuade the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> to grant me an interview,'' <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON>, now chief editor of Focus, a Japanese-language magazine, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. For six months after the announcement of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s trip, <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON> spent about half his time meeting with lower - and middle-level officials `` I knew they could n't help me, but I asked them not to oppose or discuss my campaign,'' <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON> said. Finally persuaded that an interview before the emperor's <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visit would be worthwhile, <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Household </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> officials relented. <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON> was permitted to meet the monarch at the Imperial Palace for 32 minutes. Although he was asked to submit questions in advance, <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON> was allowed to ask other questions. The emperor described his overseas tours _ to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in 1921 and with Empress <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON> again in 1971 _ as the happiest times of his life. `` My happest expectation is looking forward to our trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> told <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON>. `` As to my view of Americans, they seem to have very clear-cut views; they are always straightforward, pragmatic and realistic; I believe they are a people who are very easy to be friends with,'' the emperor said. During his two-week visit with the empress, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> met government officials and farmers and dined with <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> stars. He had said the visit was the fulfillment of a 50-year-old dream. Although <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> admitted to a desire `` deep in my heart'' to become a common man and to be closer to his people, he also expressed his belief that `` most Japanese still have a respect for the imperial family.'' The imperial tradition has survived for centuries in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, he said, `` because, throughout history, the imperial family has always given first thought to the welfare of the people.'' The next emperor, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s son Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>, `` may have his own ideas, but it has always been the tradition of the imperial family to act for the benefit of the people so I am also looking forward to such an attitude on his part as well,'' he said. The emperor hesitated to name influential people in his life, but did speak of his grandfather the Emperor <PERSON> Meiji </PERSON>. During the <LOCATION> Meiji </LOCATION> era -LRB- 1868 to 1912 -RRB-, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s grandfather played an important role in introducing public education and in modernizing his mostly agricultural nation. `` I always have kept his deeds in my mind,'' <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> said. The emperor said the saddest time of his life was during World War II. Unable to watch his people suffer further after the atomic bomb attacks on <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nagasaki </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> accepted Allied surrender terms in August 1945, urging his nation to `` bear the unbearable.'' `` At the time of the termination of the war, I made the decision on my own. That is because the Prime Minister failed to obtain agreement in the Cabinet and asked my opinion. So, I stated my opinion and then made the decision according to my opinion,'' <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> told <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON>. The emperor has never made a direct public admission that he opposed the war, maintaining that the constitution would not permit him to do so. `` Now at the time of the outbreak of the war and also before the war, when the Cabinet made decisions, I could not override their decisions,'' he said. <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON>'s interview went to press soon after he met <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. About a week later, the emperor met with a small group of foreign reporters, who had been outraged when the exclusive Newsweek article appeared. `` Nothing could top that interview,'' <PERSON> Krisher </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0159EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Japan-Succession     01-07 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japan-Succession,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>Order Of Heirs To The Throne</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Hirohito</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With the death of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> today and the ascension of Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> to the Chrysanthemum Throne, here is the new order of heirs to the throne. 1. Crown Prince <PERSON> Naruhito </PERSON>, 28, formerly known as Prince <PERSON> Hiro </PERSON>, eldest son of <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>. 2. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, 23, second son of <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>. 3. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitachi </PERSON>, 53, second son of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. 4. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Mikasa </PERSON>, 73, youngest brother of <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>. 5. Prince <PERSON> Tomohito </PERSON>, 42, eldest son of <LOCATION> Mikasa </LOCATION>. 6. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Katsura </PERSON>, 40, second son of <LOCATION> Mikasa </LOCATION>. 7. Prince <PERSON> Takamado </PERSON>, 34, third son of <LOCATION> Mikasa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-Empress     01-07 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-Empress,0580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Once Familiar, Empress Now Rarely Seen in Public</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Hirohito, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Once a familiar figure who often accompanied Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> in his travels, Empress <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON> in recent years has been confined to a wheelchair and seldom makes public appearances. The 85-year-old empress married <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, who died Saturday, nearly 65 years ago and would have celebrated her anniversary later this month. Born March 6, 1903, <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON> was the daughter of Imperial Prince <PERSON> Kuniyoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuni </PERSON>. She was brought up in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, attending the elite Peer's School for Girls. She later received instruction from two <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Quakers </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Vining </PERSON> and <PERSON> Esther </PERSON> <PERSON> Rhoads </PERSON>, who were credited with inspiring many of the democratic changes which permeated the private life of the imperial family. Mrs. <PERSON> Vining </PERSON> also tutored Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> to his fluent English. At age 15, Princess <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON> was one of several prospective brides selected for <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, then crown prince. He chose her over the objections of some powerful court officials, including the <PERSON> Fujiwara </PERSON> family that traditionally supplied imperial brides. They tried to stop the engagement by producing medical records of color blindness in her mother's family, but doctors disputed the claims and <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> made it clear he already had decided. Once betrothed, the couple met only nine times during their six-year engagement. The wedding, set for 1923, was postponed after the Great Kanto Earthquake in September left much of the capital burned and in ruins. They were wed in an elaborate ceremony on Jan. 26, 1924. On Christmas Day in 1926, <PERSON> Nagako </PERSON> became empress of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> when <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> succeeded to the legendary Chryanthemum Throne on the death of his father, the <ORGANIZATION> Taisho </ORGANIZATION> emperor. Married longer than any imperial couple in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s history, she called him `` okami,'' or honorable master, and he affectionately referred to her as `` Naga-miya,'' Naga from her name and miya meaning princess. She gave birth to seven children. The first four were all girls, and court officials urged <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> to take a concubine to ensure there would be a male heir to the throne. But the emperor refused, and the next child was a boy, Crown Prince <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>, who was born on Dec. 23, 1933. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitachi </PERSON> was born in 1935 and a fifth daughter in 1939. Two of their children died, a daughter during infancy and the eldest child, the former Princess <PERSON> Teru </PERSON>, at age 35 in 1961. The empress enjoys writing 31-syllable poems called `` waka,'' and plays the piano, violin and koto, a 13-stringed Japanese instrument. She studied painting under two of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s most respected artists, signing her work `` Toen,'' or Peach Garden. Collections of her works have been published in two volumes, and an exhibition of her drawings was held when she and <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> traveled to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in 1975. According to custom, she spent most of her time with her husband and family at the moated imperial palace in central <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> or their mountain and seaside villas. She kept busy with various indoor duties, including newspaper clipping for the emperor and keeping track of greetings to foreign dignitaries, imperial household officials say. Confined by a back ailment and hip problems to a wheelchair, the empress in recent years has rarely appeared in public. But her smile, graceful wave and devotion to her husband have made her a familiar, grandmotherly figure to the Japanese.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MultipleTransplant Bjt   01-07 0676</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Multiple Transplant, Bjt,0694</SECOND>
<HEAD>Transplant Experts Hopeful Despite Another Death</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCIA DUNN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Multiple abdominal organ transplants are still in the early stages of development where failure is common, but hope remains high despite the death of another toddler following the risky surgery, experts say. `` We're in areas that are essentially unchartered,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON>, chief of pediatric surgery at Children's Hospital of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` What we're doing is making tentative steps and then very carefully analyzing where we've been and what we've learned before we make any decision about the next one, when we'll do one or whether we'll do one.'' The fifth of six children in the country to undergo a multiple abdominal organ transplant died Friday. Three-year-old Rolandrea Dodge of <LOCATION> Fruitland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, survived six weeks with a transplanted liver, pancreas, stomach, small intestine and portion of a large intestine, and was awaiting another set of organs. Four other recipients died shortly after the transplants, and the sole survivor, <PERSON> Calvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliveira </PERSON>, 14 months, of <LOCATION> Deerfield </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, was doing well Friday, despite a seizure earlier in the week and a bout of pneumonia, said Dr. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Alessandro </PERSON>, a transplant fellow at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION>. The boy received a small intestine and liver Dec. 31 at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> and Clinics in <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>. `` Every organ that's been transplanted has had its early problems,'' <PERSON> D'Alessandro </PERSON> said. `` There are hurdles that you have to go over and along the way you have to learn from everything that's been done in order for things to progress. The death of five patients is `` very disappointing,'' said Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, director of transplantation at Rush-Presbyterian-St. <PERSON> Luke </PERSON>'s Medical Center in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> `` But this is what happened in the early days of liver transplantation,'' he said. <PERSON> Rolandrea </PERSON>, better known as <PERSON> Rolly </PERSON>, was with her parents, <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cyndi </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodge </PERSON>, when she died in the hospital's intensive care unit. The child's chances of withstanding another five-organ transplant, providing a suitable donor could have been found, began to dwindle Friday as her condition swiftly deteriorated. Her name was placed back on the transplant waiting list Wednesday, four days after tests showed her small intestine was being rejected by her body's natural immune system. Doctors do not know whether any of the other four organs transplanted Nov. 29 were rejected or to what degree, <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> said. The child was born with a disorder that prevented her intestines from absorbing food and liquids. The nation's first multiple abdominal organ transplant was performed in 1983 by Dr. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Starzl </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION>, who pioneered liver transplants. That first patient, a 6-year-old girl, lived only a few hours. <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>, director of the Center for Biomedical Ethics at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION>, questioned the ethics of the operation. `` Even if it worked well and people were living with a good quality of life, I'm still not sure there are enough potential donors,'' <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON> said. `` It's very rare to have someone with five good organs. `` I'm also not sure society is going to view giving them all to a single person is the best thing to do. I do n't,'' he said. `` I think if you can spread the organs to more people, that is what should be done. The ethical principle should be to save the most lives.'' Intestines are especially difficult to transplant because of the extremely technical nature of the surgery, the lack of biological markers indicating organ rejection, and the bowel's ability, unique among organs, to counterattack the patient's immune system, <PERSON> D'Alessandro </PERSON> said. The longest survivor of a multiple organ abdominal transplant, <PERSON> Tabatha </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>, 3 -LCB-, of <LOCATION> Madisonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, died last May, six months after receiving five organs at Children's Hospital. `` Unfortunately, many, many children are in desperate need of having this sort of operation,'' <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> said. `` We ca n't possibly think about the success and failure. What we're thinking about is trying to have a child who has a fatal disease ... and trying to have them live and have a good life.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Hirohito-AkihitoProfile     01-07 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hirohito-Akihito Profile,0830</SECOND>
<HEAD>Akihito: A Long Preparation For Updated Imperial Role</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Obit-Hirohito, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARI TAKETA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>, who becomes <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s first emperor to ascend the Chrysanthemum Throne as a human and not a living god, has quietly transformed the cloistered monarchy into a popular symbol of the people. The gray-haired <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> has waited 55 years to take up the imperial mantle. A gracious, self-effacing man schooled among commoners, he has spent those years maturing with his country. As <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> lay dying, the prince assumed the full roster of the emperor's official duties on Sept. 22. The prince's daily shuttles from his residence near the forested imperial compound to <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s deathbed drew swarms of photographers. Whether in predawn darkness or afternoon drizzle, <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON>'s face showed the same stoic deference to the ailing monarch, and court physicians listening outside the imperial chamber reported quiet conversations between father and son. <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> took on the imperial duties once before as <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> recuperated from intestinal bypass surgery in September 1987. He retained a few responsibilities but returned most after the emperor's recovery. Those duties include affixing the imperial seal to government laws and appointments, opening sessions of parliament and receiving foreign ambassadors. To these the prince has added frequent visits to factory openings, festivals and various observances across <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. And with numerous trips abroad as his father's proxy, he has almost single-handedly brought <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s monarchy into the global age and the eye of a curious public. `` I want to be a man with a strong moral backbone with keen, reliable insight and knowledge,'' he once reportedly told a friend. `` I want to shake up the imperial protocol system.'' <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> set his most spectacular imperial precedent with his marriage in 1959 to a commoner. <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> <PERSON> Shoda </PERSON> was the beautiful, cultured daughter of a wealthy miller, and the young prince courted her by phone in a widely reported romance that was conservative, but refreshingly typical. The match shocked the imperial retinue and thrilled the public. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> gave his consent and the couple married after a cavalcade that drew 500,000 gawking subjects onto the streets of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> and his princess produced three children: <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Hiro </PERSON>, who at 28 is next in the imperial succession; <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> <PERSON> Aya </PERSON>, 22, and 19-year-old Princess Nori. They broke another imperial tradition with their decision to raise the children by themselves. Born Dec. 23, 1933, as a militaristic <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> geared for growing confrontation in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> was shuttled among the imperial family's countryside villas when American planes began firebombing <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> in the closing months of the war. He was still short of his 12th birthday when his father's armies were crushed and the nation suffered the ultimate defeat in 1945. At the urging of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> occupation officials, <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> also surrendered the divinity that had been the birthright of every Japanese monarch, and agreed to a new constitutional role as `` the symbol of the state and of the unity of the people, deriving his position from the will of the people.'' <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> took his role seriously. `` The imperial family should always be passive,'' he has said. `` The most important thing is the will of the people.'' Having inherited a centuries-old legacy of passive monarchs, his job may have been made easier. The prince, who was invested as heir to the throne in an unprecedented public ceremony in 1952, soon set off to represent his father on state visits around the globe, including the coronation of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> in 1953. With <PERSON> Michiko </PERSON> he has visited at least 41 countries in 22 official trips to `` deepen understanding mutually and promote friendship between the peoples,'' he has said. <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> shares his father's proclivity for science and is a respected scholar of gobiid fish, a mudsucker. He holds membership in the <ORGANIZATION> Ichthyological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Linnean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION>. `` He wants the imperial family to remain a cultural symbol of the nation,'' his longtime chamberlain, <PERSON> Yasuo </PERSON> <PERSON> Shigeta </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, and has encouraged his children to take up specialties. He sent his first-born to study at <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, explaining, `` If -LRB- <PERSON> Hiro </PERSON> -RRB- remains in the country, he can not know even what the common people routinely experience.'' `` As a matter of fact, I rode a bus for the first time when I went to <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> speaks fluent English and has acted as his father's interpreter in meetings with foreign dignitaries He inherited his mother's tutor, <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Vining </PERSON>, a Quaker from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Vining </PERSON> recalled once asking her youthful pupil what he wanted to be when he grew up. Replied the prince, `` I will become emperor.'' Recent polls show his subjects welcome the career choice. A nationwide newspaper poll in 1987 showed more than 80 percent of the public wants to keep the imperial system.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890107-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-07-89 0220EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TobaccoTaxes     01-07 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tobacco Taxes,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>California Tobacco Tax Hike Means Coughing Up More Cash for Smokes</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: First available for Saturday AMs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHLEEN MACLAY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
