<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 2336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Britain-Explosion Advisory   09-03 0033</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Explosion, Advisory,0033</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Eds: Upcoming in about 15 minutes, a 2nd Ld-Writethru to AM-Britain-Explosion, a0769, updating with police saying the explosion was connected with the controversy over `` The Satanic Verses.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>The AP</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 2353EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-Lebanon     09-03 0210</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Lebanon,0216</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israel Bombs Guerrilla Base in South Lebanon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> warplanes destroyed a guerrilla base in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> 21 miles north of the <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> border Monday, the army said. All planes returned safely from the early morning raid, a military statement said. An army spokesman said the planes struck a guerrilla base in the village of <LOCATION> Majdal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Balhis </LOCATION>, about three miles east of <LOCATION> Mashghara </LOCATION>. The spokesman, who is not identified under military regulations, would not say which militia operated the base nor give the reason for the raid. The air raid follows attacks Wednesday and Thursday in which Katyusha rockets were fired at <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Galilee </LOCATION> district from south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The attacks caused no injuries, but one rocket damaged a house in <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Shmona </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Galilee </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Panhandle </LOCATION>. Israeli authorities blamed that rocket attack on the militant Shiite Moslem militia <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION>, or Party of God. Also on Thursday, <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> troops fought a battle with four guerrillas just north of the border, and one member of the Shiite militia Amal was killed. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> suffered no casualties in the firefight. The air attack was the the 10th time Israeli war planes have struck in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> this year. The last raid, on Aug. 27, was aimed at a <ORGANIZATION> Hezbollah </ORGANIZATION> base.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Nicaragua-Godoy     09-03 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Godoy,0346</SECOND>
<HEAD>Experienced Politician Chosen As Opposition Running Mate</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Nicaragua</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DORALISA PILARTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reyes </PERSON> brings solid political experience and a controversial personality to the campaign for which he is running as opposition vice presidential candidate in next February's election. While crowds at the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opposition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday night cheered <PERSON> Violeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrios </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>, the presidential candidate, hecklers three times shouted the name of <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>'s rival for the No. 2 spot. While perhaps not an auspicious start for a political candidate, <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>'s strong personality _ which some have described as arrogant and abrasive _ can take the heckling. The hostility stems from his four-year, eight-month tenure as Labor Minister under the leftist Sandinista government, against which he is running now. As Labor Minister, <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> instituted a system of salary levels that became widely unpopular. Detractors say his government post also makes his allegiance to the opposition somewhat suspect. <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> was Labor Minister from July 19, 1979 to March 31, 1984, when he resigned. He said later that he quit because he disagreed with the leftist Sandinista ideology. His resignation however reflects his political talent _ the government gave him a going-away reception, showing he must have left in good stead. The 55-year-old lawyer has been better at defending himself from power plays within his own party, the Independent Liberals, than in attacking the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION>. Political attacks against <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> stem not only from his personality as from his tenure as president of the <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for 10 years. One critic, who prefered to remain unidentified, called <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> `` dictatorial and Machiavellian.'' <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> follows a long tradition of Liberalism in his family. His grandfather, Gen. <PERSON> Paulino </PERSON> <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON>, was the spearhead of the <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Liberal revolution of 1983. He has said that the slogan of the French revolution, `` Liberty, Equality, Brotherhood,'' encapsules the most important concepts for the individual and society. <PERSON> Godoy </PERSON> is married to <PERSON> Sonia </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercado </PERSON>, a Mexican; they have three children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--VintagePlaneCrash     09-03 0149</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Vintage Plane Crash,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>World War II-Era Plane Crashes Into House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A World War II vintage fighter crashed into a house shortly after takeoff from <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> on Saturday, injuring the pilot and a passenger, authorities said. The house was heavily damaged but no one was at home and no one on the ground was injured when the single-engine P-51 crashed about 5:45 p.m., said <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wells </PERSON>. There was no fire, he said. The pilot reported engine trouble and was trying to return to the airport when he crashed, said a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> duty officer who declined to identify himself. The 56-year-old pilot and a 19-year-old woman passenger were taken to a hospital where they were being examined, said a nursing supervisor. The P-51 was one of the main fighter planes used by the Allies during World War II.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0119EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u n BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0004</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 1 a.m. EDT: 110.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 3 a.m. EDT: 120.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0615EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 5 a.m. EDT: 120.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0703EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u n BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0004</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 7 a.m. EDT: 121.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0817EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 8 a.m. EDT: 121.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0851EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-PandaCubDeath     09-03 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Panda Cub Death,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Panda Cub Dies At National Zoo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The latest cub born to the giant panda Ling-Ling died from complications caused by infections it developed either during or after birth, a National Zoo spokesman said Sunday. The female cub, born to <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON> on Friday, was found dead early Sunday, said chief zoo spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoage </PERSON>. The cub was believed to have contracted the infection either while it was still in its mother's womb, or shortly after it was delivered. All of <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON>'s previous cubs have died. Had this one survived, it would be the first giant panda successfully bred in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The 4-ounce female cub was confined to an oxygen-filled incubator since late Friday, and was fed a milk-like formula through a tube that was inserted down the throat and into the stomach. She was also innoculated with immunoglobins that had been prepared from the blood of her father, <LOCATION> Hsing-Hsing </LOCATION>, and given special formula antibiotics. <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON> was known to have urinary and reproductive tract infections, <PERSON> Hoage </PERSON> said. The cub was the fifth that <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON> had given birth to while in captivity. None of them had survived as long as the latest one. One of the cubs was born stillborn and the other three died shortly after birth. Previously <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON>'s longest-lived cub was born in 1987 and lived about 40 hours before dying, possibly because of the same infection that took the life of her most recent offspring, <PERSON> Hoage </PERSON> said. Ling-Ling and <LOCATION> Hsing-Hsing </LOCATION> were given to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government during President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> in 1972. Since that time they have mated on numerous occasions, but <PERSON> Ling-Ling </PERSON> has only given birth four times.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 0919EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 9 a.m. EDT: 126.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1011EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 10 a.m. EDT: 134.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-VaBeachRiot 1stLd-Writethru a0638 09-03 0391</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Va Beach Riot, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0638,0398</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two People Shot, Over 100 Stores Looted in Va Beach Rioting</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Rewrites throughout to UPDATE with resort strip closed, add
quotes, other detail. No pickup.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>VIRGINIA BEACH, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rioting broke out early Sunday in this resort city, and more than 100 downtown stores were looted and at least two people shot before a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> military police attachment was deployed, authorities said. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Roche </PERSON>, assistant director of public information for <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, said guardsmen were called out by Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> shortly after 4 a.m. to assist local authorities. She did not have exact figures on the number of guardsmen involved. She said the rioting began around 2 a.m. when police confronted a mob on <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, the main beachfront thoroughfare. She had no estimate on the crowd size or what may have set off the rioting. City Manager <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> ordered much of the resort strip closed, and residents were told to avoid the area. An estimated more than 25,000 college students from predominantly black schools up and down the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> are in town for the annual Greekfest. <PERSON> Roche </PERSON> said she did n't know if the riot was related to the gathering. Police reported at least four injuries, including the two men shot. <PERSON> Roche </PERSON> was unable to identify any of the injured or say what their condition was. She said police officers were not involved in the shootings. Police reported scattered gunfire and several fires in the area overnight. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said police, backed by state troopers and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, were in `` crowd control positions'' in the oceanfront area. At 7 a.m., the area was reported quiet. <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Kanz </PERSON>, front desk manager at the <LOCATION> Kona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Motel </LOCATION>, said authorities were not allowing anyone to leave the hotel `` even for breakfast'' unless they were checking out to go home. Many college students were staying at the motel, and they remained in their rooms while guardsmen and police patrolled the streets, she said. `` It's a heck of a way to end the season,'' she said. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bremer </PERSON>, desk clerk at the <LOCATION> Kona </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kai </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> two blocks away, said some families were checking out of the motel early. He said cash registers from nearby stores had been hurled into the street by looters. `` It's pretty messy,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 11 a.m. EDT: 137.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BRF--Bloomski's     09-03 0176</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Bloomski's,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports: Bloomingdale's to Open Moscow Stores</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Bloomingdale </ORGANIZATION>'s, the lavish department store that <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s conspicuous consumers know as <ORGANIZATION> Bloomies </ORGANIZATION>, will open two shops in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> next year, Soviet newspapers reported Sunday. <PERSON> Bloomingdale </PERSON>'s began capitalizing on `` Gorbymania'' in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> by selling Soviet goods in its <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> store in May. But the opening of two shops in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> would be more significant, given the market-oriented reforms aimed at filling the nation's store shelves The newspaper <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Pravda said <PERSON> Bloomingdale </PERSON>'s and the <ORGANIZATION> Moscow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> signed a letter of intent for the joint venture bringing the stores to the capital. They are to open in January, the paper said. In its report on the venture, the newspaper Pravda noted that the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> store sells Soviet products in a special `` perestroika'' department, a reference to President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s reform program. The brief articles did not say whether the two <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> shops would accept Soviet rubles or limit their sales to hard currency, which ordinary Soviets are prohibited from possessing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1157EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Carter-Ethiopia Bjt   09-03 0785</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Carter-Ethiopia, Bjt,0808</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former President Carter is Host to Ethiopian Talks This Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARC RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, in the mode of his Camp David triumph, is staging talks this week between the Ethiopian government and Eritrean rebels on the 28-year-old war that has killed hundreds of thousands. Ten years ago, <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> brokered the Camp David peace agreement between <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. The sessions beginning Thursday have a more modest goal: getting the two sides to sit down together. `` In the history of political affairs, the most significant single step is the first meeting,'' <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> said last month in announcing the talks. Previous attempts have failed to arrange talks between the Ethiopian government and the well-organized, heavily armed rebels fighting for independence for their province. But <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, during a July visit to the East African nation, said the opportunity for peace has never been better. The war has turned more than 1 million people into refugees. It has drained the Ethiopian economy, contributed to the suffering from famine and drought and led the government to bring in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> military aid. The two sides now have agreed that <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> should act as a neutral observer for the preliminary talks, which the participants say they hope will lead to more substantive meetings. Neither Ethiopian leader <PERSON> Mengistu </PERSON> <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Mariam </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Isaias </PERSON> <PERSON> Afwerki </PERSON>, general secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Eritrean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, will attend the meetings at the Carter Center. The center, opened in 1986, houses the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> presidential library and museum as well as a think tank, a conference center and offices of foundations devoted to peace and public health. Carter Center officials will not disclose the size of the negotiating teams, where the groups will stay or security plans. The meetings will be closed, and no one knows how long they will last. <PERSON> Dayle </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Carter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s director of conflict resolution programs, said extensive efforts have been made to ensure the negotiators feel comfortable during their stay. `` Not just their physical comfort, but the feeling of neutrality,'' she said. `` We are making every effort to provide for them a congenial environment in every aspect.'' For example, <ORGANIZATION> Carter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> personnel are careful not to term the <LOCATION> Ethiopian-Eritrean </LOCATION> conflict a `` civil war,'' which Ms. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said implies support for the government's view of the struggle as a conflict within a single state. Eritrean guerrillas, which share some Marxist principles with the <LOCATION> Ethiopian </LOCATION> government, believe their province at the northern tip of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, with 3.5 million people, should be an independent nation. An ancient Ethiopian kingdom, <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> has been ruled by the Ottoman Turks, the Italians and, finally, the British during World War II before becoming part of a federation with <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> after the war. Fighting broke out between <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> in 1961 and <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> annexed <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> in 1962. <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> has long been coveted territory because its location on the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sea </ORGANIZATION> gives <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> its only ports. <ORGANIZATION> Mengistu </ORGANIZATION> came to power after the 1974 ouster of Emperor <PERSON> Haile </PERSON> <PERSON> Selassie </PERSON>, who had ruled since 1930. With the change in power came an increase in the Soviet presence in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> and the withdrawal, during the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> administration, of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid and advisers. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has continued to provide humanitarian aid. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> recently has directed less attention to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. A second rebel group, the <ORGANIZATION> Tigre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, took up arms 14 years ago in a fight for increased autonomy in its province, which borders <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION>. It also has made overtures for peace and accepted <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> as an observer, but that conflict will not be a part of this week's talks. The <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> talks mark the second time this year <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> has been at the center of an major international event. Last spring he served as an observer in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s elections and then briefed President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on the voting, which he said was rife with fraud. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> plans to play a background role in the Ethiopian talks. He and his center will serve mainly as a vehicle for bringing the opposing sides together, according to Ms. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON>. Some of the principles of the 1979 Camp David talks can be applied here, Ms. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` What worked at Camp <PERSON> David </PERSON> was that the parties met on neutral ground,'' she said. `` Neither side had the upper hand, and a third party was present with a sincere interest in resolution.'' Though the Camp David talks lasted 13 days, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Menachem </PERSON> <PERSON> Begin </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> actually met face-to-face for only two days, Ms. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> literally shuttled back and forth,'' Ms. <PERSON> Powell </PERSON> said. `` We hope that part wo n't be replicated. We hope they'll meet in the same room.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1238EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--LadyGodiva     09-03 0196</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Lady Godiva,0200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stark Protest Against Development Plans</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COCKINGTON, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A latter-day <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Godiva </PERSON> rode naked on a horse through this village to protest a company's plan to replace old stables and farm buildings with luxury housing. `` I'm not an exhibitionist. In fact I am terrified,'' said <PERSON> Lyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Brierly </PERSON>, 42, who made the ride Saturday. `` But if this is what it takes to save the village then I'd do it again and again until someone sits up and takes notice.'' <ORGANIZATION> Prudential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> company </ORGANIZATION>, which has owned the village since World War II, has met strong resistance to the development plans and is involved in negotiations with the district council and the <ORGANIZATION> Cockington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Cockington </LOCATION> in southwestern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> is a cluster of thatched-roof houses. It has a pub designed in the 1930s by the architect Sir <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lutyens </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Brierly </PERSON>, a nurse, said she feared the stables were targeted for development because visitors had complained about horse manure in the village. `` The horses are part and parcel of the village life itself. Ask anyone about <LOCATION> Cockington </LOCATION> and they'll immediately think of the horses,'' she said. Her ride was mentioned in several national newspapers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1225EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0007</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0005</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 Noon EDT: 142.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Refugees     09-03 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Refugees,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>Red Cross Says Exodus of East Germans to Begin Next Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Authorities this week will begin the long-awaited exodus of East Germans seeking asylum in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officials disclosed on Sunday. West German <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> also said authorities believed East German police have infiltrated the emergency camps in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> that are holding thousands of people awaiting safe passage to the West. `` We reckon that's so, but we're not equipped to do anything about it,'' he said in response to a question. He sought to dampen speculation that the transfer would begin Sunday, telling reporters the East Germans would leave `` sometime'' this week. Asked what was holding up the exodus, <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said: `` We're awaiting word from the West German Embassy.'' Since vacationing East Germans began crowding the embassy in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> to demand passage to the West in July, the embassy has declined to comment on the developments. While legal travel to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> is difficult for most East Germans, they have relatively little difficulty getting permission from their Communist government to visit <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, a liberal Soviet bloc country. More than 1 million have vacationed here annually in the last few years. More than 200,000 East Germans were thought to be in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> before the weekend, and Premier <PERSON> Miklos </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON> has estimated that up to 20,000 of them want to go to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. A bilateral agreement obliges <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to send East Germans trying to flee to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> back to their homeland. But Hungarian officials have refused to do so, and their decision to permit the East Germans to go West has led to tensions with <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. It also has resulted in a strengthening of ties with <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where government officials have praised <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s handling of the problem. <PERSON> Karsten </PERSON> <PERSON> Voigt </PERSON>, a senior West German opposition official, last week called on government officials to provide financial and moral support for <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s reform-minded <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> leaders. On Saturday, West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> appealed to countrymen to welcome the East Germans, while other officials and politicians called on the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> leadership to stop the exodus by introducing reforms. Holidaying East Germans, frustrated by political rigidity and economic stagnation at home, began using <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> as a springboard to the West after it started removing barbed wire and other barriers from its border with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> in May. Since then, more than 6,000 are estimated to have fled to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> en route to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which grants them automatic citizenship and helps them start new lives by giving them financial and social aid. Others seeking to emigrate first crowded the West German Embassy in <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>. With government approval, Hungarian charitable organizations opened the first camps for East Germans in mid-August, after the crush of would-be refugees staying in the embassy forced <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> to close it. <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said that 4,000 East Germans had been placed in four camps and a small boarding house by early Sunday afternoon, following more than 1,000 new arrivals during the weekend. Hundreds more were staying in tents and trailers near the <LOCATION> Zanka </LOCATION> camp, about 90 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION>, said other <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> officials. While no official details of plans to move the East Germans had been made public by Sunday, developments in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> over the past week indicated they would be moved by rail through <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> to temporary quarters in <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION>, the main West German state bordering <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION> Sunday, volunteer workers put the finishing touches on five tent communities with room for more than 5,000 people. Austrian rail officials continued to hold up to 50 railway cars ready for quick movement to border points with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>. Many of those in the <LOCATION> Budapest </LOCATION> camps huddled in tents or trailers to escape occasional showers, while others attended religious services on camp grounds or in city churches.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-SocialLegislation Bjt   09-03 0712</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Social Legislation, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Child Care, Minimum Wage Remain at Front of Congress' Domestic Agenda</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DIANE DUSTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Areas of social concern _ child care, minimum wage, parental leave and greater opportunities for the disabled _ will be among the issues facing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> when it returns this week, but no one is predicting quick action. Child care legislation, the issue that became a focus of the 1988 presidential campaign, has passed the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The bill calls for direct grants to child care providers and would establish non-binding federal guidelines. But in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a companion bill is embroiled in a dispute between two committees with jurisdiction over it. Besides that, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Republicans are pushing the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> plan _ tax credits for lower - and middle-income parents of children under age 4 regardless of whether both parents actually work and pay for outside child care Whether child care legislation passes the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> before it recesses for the year sometime in November is anyone's guess, but legislative staffers believe if the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> does agree on a bill, it will be one that will be acceptable to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and the White House. The child care issue has been kicking around since 1971 when President <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> vetoed legislation similar to that under consideration now, calling it anti-family. Another bill was considered by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1975, but never made it to the president. It remains at hot issue, with six of 10 Americans surveyed this summer in a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Post-ABC News Poll saying they think the federal government should provide child-care assistance to low - and middle-income families The main disagreement now is between the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. Basically, the Ways and Means approach is to put money for child care programs into block grants that go to the states with no strings attached. The committee already has acted by putting language on child care into the budget reconciliation bill. That legislation is the omnibus bill into which all committees are expected to contribute deficit reduction plans. A committee said the markup of the committee's proposal for the child care bill is scheduled for Thursday and will include an effort to make it conform to the budget reconciliation proposals. The provisions of the bill passed by Education and Labor include: _ putting more money into Head Start so those programs can run all day instead of half a day; _ using public school systems to help care for children over 3 years old; _ grants to providers for the children of parents who ca n't afford the full cost of day care; _ improving day care quality While containing the provisions of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> bill, the Education and Labor version goes further. As for minimum wage, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> must reach a compromise with the White House if there is to be final action. After the first attempt at raising the minimum wage fell to a presidential veto, Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., reintroduced the very same measure It has been voted out of committee and awaits a full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote, but staff members say talks are going on with the administration to determine how it might be changed on the floor in a compromise with the White House. Meanwhile, Rep. <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, D-Pa., introduced a bill in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> that would raise the minimum wage from $ 3.35 to $ 4.25 by 1991, the maximum amount acceptable to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> But it does not contain a provision demanded by the White House that would allow employers to pay new workers a less-than-minimum wage for up to six months. The issue of family leave has gained the attention of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and awaits debate on the floor of both the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The measures would require employers to provide up to 10 weeks of unpaid leave for family emergencies. Another measure that may see its way through <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> this session is called the Americans with Disabilities Act. This bill is considered the most comprehensive civil rights measure since the 1964 Civil Rights Act. It would prohibit discrimination against people with disabilities in private sector employment, public accommodations, transportation, public services and telecommunications. It expected to be on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor soon with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> action later in the fall.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1310EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 1 p.m. EDT: 147.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1315EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Medellin     09-03 0917</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Medellin,0946</SECOND>
<HEAD>Medellin Paralyzed by Fear</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Colombia, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEDELLIN, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the cocaine capital of the world, the new war between the government and traffickers is one of nerves as well as firepower. An industrial city of 2 million, cradled in lush green mountains, <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> suffers almost daily bombings and burnings by the henchmen of drug bosses in a war that began with the Aug. 18 assassination of a presidential candidate. But bloodshed since that killing has been limited to unlucky bystanders in the past two weeks. Property, not people, has been the principal target, fear the main weapon. The city continues to function, its shops opening each day and its workers and businessmen filling the streets, factories and offices. But fear and tension is pervasive. `` There's no direct confrontation, but instead subversive actions ... sporadic and surprising,'' Mayor <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said. `` It's harder to combat them than in a regular war.'' The government has arrested thousands of people and seized hundreds of millions of dollars in assets since it declared a crackdown on drug kingpins on the same day presidential hopeful <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON> was assassinated. Drug traffickers have responded with more shootings and bombings. In response to the traffickers' campaign of terror, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> last week imposed a strict 10 p.m.-to-6 a.m. citywide curfew. He concedes that the measure was as much psychological as tactical. `` The curfew is not just to prevent the attacks, the bombs,'' he told foreign reporters at a news conference. `` It's also so that the entire community knows that we have a problem.'' For a city like <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, it's a drastic measure. The townspeople are known for a kind of restless joy of life and the night has always been vibrant, with the bars and dance halls full of loud music and people, drinking shots of the licorice-flavored local `` aguardiente.'' For the moment, the party's over. At 10 p.m. the city's 4,000 police aided by thousands of army soldiers take over the streets, armed with automatic and semi-automatic rifles. They round up curfew violators at gunpoint, hustling them down the streets to gathering points and packing them into city dumptrucks headed for a volleyball arena. Most of the violators are ill-dressed, sometimes barefoot drunks and tramps, as well as male and female prostitutes. Many stumble and sway, their eyes glazed by cheap alcohol. They yell and whistle derisively at their military guards, creating a din in the tin-roofed arena. The violators are held until the curfew ends at 6 a.m. Those found to have criminal charges pending are shipped to the police jailhouse. The rest are set free. `` This is just what the city needed. Now there are no more wounded, there are no more dead at night,'' said an army officer. `` Now the people can sleep in peace.'' But real peace has remained elusive. The morning after the curfew first took effect Wednesday, a bomb strapped to a juice vendor's bicycle blew up in broad daylight Several people were injured. `` It has n't stopped people from going outdoors, but when you do go out you always carry a fear that something will happen while you're passing by,'' said <PERSON> Rubiela </PERSON> <PERSON> Toro </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> housewife. So far, the traffickers' targets in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> have been political or economic: political party offices, statesmen's homes and country clubs, banks and factories have been bombed or burned. In recent days they've been seeking a truly big bang, evidently to further fray the stretched nerves of the community. They set up rockets to fire at a liquor plants' huge tanks of alcohol, but police interrupted the attempt. They fired rockets at gasoline storage tanks but missed. On Thursday, the bomb attached to the bicycle was placed outside the country's largest paint factory, and according to a company source, inside were 3,000 gallons of highly explosive nitroglycerin. `` If that bomb went off 30 yards down the street, half of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> would have blown up,'' said the source, who spoke on condition he not be identified. On Saturday, the traffickers took the battle to <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, setting off a powerful bomb outside the offices of the daily newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION>. Since <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> was founded in 1616 by <LOCATION> Spanish </LOCATION> immigrants, its people have developed a repution for being keen traders and industrious entrepreneurs. But since the drug underworld emerged in the 1960s, dealing first in marijuana and now primarily in cocaine, that reputation has been sullied by gangland violence. Bloodshed reached new horrific heights in the last 18 months, with an underground war between the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel and that of the southeastern city of <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION> for control of the $ 1 billion <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> market. A <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> journalist said that up until the curfew, which put the feud on ice, his newspaper was reporting an average of six killings a day. The traffickers also have killed the provincial governor and police commander as well as scores of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> judges in a successful effort to avoid arrest. Judges and law enforcement officials are known to receive threats in the most terrible forms, such as a mutilated photograph of their children. The traffickers' new aim is to get the government to end its nationwide crackdown and agree to negotiations. The government, so far, has categorically rejected the suggestion. Mayor <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, however, favors talks with the cocaine barons and sees them as inevitable. `` No one knows when the war is going to end,'' he said. `` But I think it's going to end at the negotiating table.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1324EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-MotherJones Bjt   09-03 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mother Jones, Bjt,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>Small Town Holds Legacy of Mother Jones, Labor's `Hell-Raiser'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN DOWLING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOUNT OLIVE, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 She was once `` the most dangerous woman in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' For close to half a century, coal miners from <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> knew her as a fiery champion of organized labor in an era when picket lines were often met with bayonets. Today, memories of <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> `` Mother'' <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> have faded even in the coal-mining country where she is buried in the only union-owned cemetery in the nation. But a handful of labor activists and scholars want to ensure she is more than a footnote to the history of the labor movement. `` She serves as kind of an inspiration to workers who wo n't be satisfied until they are on an equal plane, in control of their destiny,'' said labor historian <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Sangamon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, which holds an annual <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> commemoration. From the 1870s almost until her death in 1930, her white-haired, grandmotherly figure was in the thick of some of the nation's most bitter labor disputes. At a time when miners bought food from the company store and slept in company houses on company land, she was a fierce socialist who once bristled when called a `` great humanitarian.'' `` Get it right,'' she retorted. `` I'm not a humanitarian. I'm a hell-raiser.'' Her history is a litany of clashes with police, prosecutors and government authorities, most of whom she saw as tools of the `` high-class burglars'' who owned mines and factories. The authorities saw her as a subversive of the worst kind. `` There sits the most dangerous woman in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> prosecutor said of her in the early 1900s. `` She crooks her finger _ 20,000 contented men lay down their tools and walk out.'' Historians say <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> was given to rewriting her own history, and indisputable facts about her early life are few. An Irish immigrant trained as a teacher, she lived briefly in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> but settled in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, in the 1860s. She married an ironworker who was an active union member, and had three children. Her husband and children died in an 1867 epidemic of yellow fever, and the young widow moved back to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, where she worked as a dressmaker and was drawn into union work. Despite nearly 60 years as a labor organizer _ she was, by her reckoning, 100 years old at her death in 1930 _ her tangible legacy is limited, in part because of her distaste for institutions. Though closely associated with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, she feuded with some of its best-known leaders, such as <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. The miners union gave her permission to organize, but she never held office, <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. It is also unclear how she made the leap from dressmaking to the coal fields. `` She was n't an administrator, she was n't a functionary,'' <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. `` She suffered the bureaucrats very poorly. ... She would be just as upset today as she was in 1910 or 1920, and she'd be upset in some ways with the labor unions.'' Years before her death she requested burial in <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Olive </LOCATION>, about 40 miles northeast of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, in a cemetery bought by miners as a resting place for four comrades killed in the <ORGANIZATION> Virden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massacre </ORGANIZATION>, an 1898 clash between striking workers and mine guards in a nearby town. For years, <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' tomb was the site of an annual pilgrimage. `` They would have speakers, prominent labor people, thousands of visitors,'' says <PERSON> Viola </PERSON> <PERSON> Krivi </PERSON>, a coal miner's daughter who as a 10-year-old filed past the tomb. `` You could n't walk down the sidewalk, the streets were so crowded.'' The annual tributes stopped as many of the area's mines shut down. Some of the tradition has been revived in recent years with the <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> <PERSON> Dinner </PERSON> at Sangamon State that includes a pilgrimage to the gravesite. It is held the second Saturday in October. `` In the last 10 years she has started to get some attention, but until the'70s she was pretty much neglected,'' <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said. `` It's true not only in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> but in most of the country. One reason she is better known now is the existence of the 13-year-old San Francisco-based magazine <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, a liberal journal best known for its expose on the problems of the Ford <PERSON> Pinto </PERSON>. Today, a hand-lettered sign along Interstate 55 guides visitors to <PERSON> Mother </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>' grave, a 22-foot edifice of pink granite that towers over a one-acre cemetery bordered by cornfields. `` The resting place of real union people,'' reads a sign hanging from a wrought-iron arch over the cemetery gate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1322EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SouthAfrica 1stLd-Writethru   09-03 0661</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0650,0678</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thousands of Blacks March on Whites-Only Beaches</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 10 grafs to UPDATE arrest figures, most protesters
released, quote from white hecklers; picks up 7th pvs, ``At a...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN PARKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DURBAN, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of blacks marched, picnicked and waded at a `` whites-only'' beach Sunday. Police made 58 arrests, but waited more than two hours before breaking up the protest. The crowd, estimated at 5,000 to 10,000, stretched for more than a mile along the shore, the biggest beach protest ever in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. Organizers claimed a victory over segregation and vowed further acts of protest during a nationwide defiance campaign. Several dozen whites, some carrying whips and wearing `` whites only'' T-shirts, yelled abuse as the throng paraded along the segregated sections of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s most heavily used beachfront. Other sections of the hotel-lined shore have been opened to all races in recent years. One angry white man barged into the crowd, yelling and pushing, but police said they could control the situation on their own. Some whites yelled to the officers, `` Shoot them dead.'' At one point, police arrested about 10 black youths who unfurled a flag of the outlawed <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla movement. They remained in custody late Sunday, but police said the other 48 people arrested during the course of the protest were released after a few hours. The police contingent of several hundred officers was equipped with shot guns and a water cannon, but they made no efforts to stop the protesters from moving onto segregated <LOCATION> Addington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>. In contrast, police used clubs and whips and arrested 500 people Saturday in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> while breaking up a planned protest march to <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. White lifeguards remained at their posts during the beach protest and white surfers continued to paddle off the shore while black children splashed nearby. After about 2 -LCB- hours, police officers announced that the protest was illegal and began moving the crowd away. At a news conference later, protest leaders said they considered the event a success. `` It's the dawn of a new age,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Mogoba </PERSON>, a prominent Methodist leader. More than 1,300 people, including prominent activists such as Anglican Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, have been arrested since Wednesday in connection with the defiance campaign. Most have been released pending possible court action. The defiance campaign began Aug. 2 and has intensified steadily in the days leading to Wednesday's segregated parliamentary elections, which exclude the black majority. A two-day national protest _ probably including a general strike _ is planned for Tuesday and Wednesday by major anti-apartheid groups. The majority of the beach protesters were youths, many wearing yellow caps with the slogan `` Free the Beaches.'' The crowd included many Indians and some whites as well as blacks. Local police officials had warned activists last week that the protest could trigger violence, and some roadblocks were set up in an attempt to keep protesters away from the beach. Police reported that several small bombs exploded Friday night in trash bins along the beachfront. Near the bins, pamphlets purportedly written by white right-wing extremists warned activists not to proceed with the protest. Previous targets of the defiance campaign have included segregated hospitals, schools and buses. Many activists have defied restrictions imposed on them following their release from detention, and several banned organizations have declared that they were resuming operations. Protesters were whipped by police at a defiance protest at a whites-only beach near <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> on Aug. 19. At least two Cabinet ministers of the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> have expressed regret for that incident, but the government has given no public indication that it is ready to make major changes in remaining segregation laws. By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the 28 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1329EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Labor'sDay 1stLd-Writethru a0649 09-03 1298</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Labor's Day, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0649,1200</SECOND>
<HEAD>Labor Celebrates Success Abroad, But Questions Abound At Home</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs 34th graf prv with 6 grafs, beginning ``Kirkland refers
xxx to update with Dole remarks on TV Moved in advance Aug. 31 as b0356.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Labor Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Striking <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> employees, coal miners and phone workers are the symbol of both the uncertainty and solidarity the American labor movement reflects on this Labor Day. In an extraordinary year, labor has suffered some major losses yet won some impressive victories, although the spotlight on the negatives has tended to obscure the bright spots. A number of unions have proven that labor-management cooperation can work but, as in the case of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auto </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, learned as well that too much of a `` good'' thing can prove troublesome. Others have found hope in their solidarity _ particularly in the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and miners' strikes _ but will spend labor's traditional holiday wondering if their jobs are the price they will pay for their pride and determination. The movement has lost one nemesis, <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, but gained another, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>. Union workers here can take pride in remarkable developments in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> _ their dues helped support the Solidarity trade union from its underground days to its historic rise as leader of the first non-communist government in the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc. Through the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> unions funneled thousands of dollars worth of printing equipment and other supplies to Solidarity while it was outlawed. `` I think the role of the American trade union movement in this should not be overlooked,'' <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said last week. <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>, head of the 14-million member <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>, the major umbrella group for the nearly 18 million Americans who belong to unions, says those who are eulogizing the labor movement do n't understand it `` The key to any evaluation of the labor movement ought to examine what we regard as the most important measure and that is internal cohesiveness and solidarity,'' he said. `` And I think it's fair to say that we do have a higher degree of solidarity and cohesion today than we've had in many, many years. A number of developments bolster <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON>'s point. Among them: _ The virtually unprecedented support of the pilots' union when the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union struck Eastern on March 4 _ Joint negotiations between former enemies, the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brotherhood </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electrical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, with <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> and the `` baby Bell'' regional telephone companies That solidarity continued in a number of strikes against the regional companies. _ Nationwide wildcat strikes to support 1,700 miners who struck <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> after lengthy and bitter negotiations failed to bring a settlement <ORGANIZATION> Pittston </ORGANIZATION> is seeking to halt its contributions to union pension funds, a move that likely would cause other companies to follow suit. Still, there have been setbacks for labor as well. A trickle of defections among union pilots turned into a steady flow that has allowed Eastern _ and <LOCATION> Lorenzo </LOCATION> _ to move ahead with plans to reorganize the carrier as a smaller, non-union airline. Labor still hopes to use Congress and bankruptcy court to oust <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> but its chances appear slim as the strike reaches the six-month mark on Labor Day. The most highly publicized failure of `` Big Labor'' was the Auto Workers' defeat in an election at a <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> plant in <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION>, its first attempt to organize a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> plant fully owned by the Japanese. At <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION>, and at other industries that traditionally have been the backbone of trade unions, the labor movement is running into two main obstacles: management programs to undermine union support by giving workers more say and perks, and intricate anti-union campaigns to defeat organizing drives including screening applicants to determine their attitudes toward unions. At <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> screened more than 100,000 workers for about 3,000 jobs. But <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said the Japanese are n't to blame for doing that. `` They are led into this course in some cases not by anything inherent in their culture or their own countries, because in many instances they have a history of dealing with trade unions in their own countries with good faith, but are following the advice of hustlers, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> hustlers, who have made a new profession out of trying to guide employers for a fee,'' <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said. To counter such tactics, labor is changing the way it looks at organizing and now accepts as `` associate members'' workers at plants where organizing efforts failed and immigrant workers looking for residency status in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. By getting its foot in the door, and offering those workers benefits such as cut-rate credit cards, insurance and legal services, unions hope to foster goodwill that will bring success in later elections. Such a concept, once reviled by traditionalists in the movement, has brought in 300,000 associate members in the past three years and, according to <LOCATION> Kirkland </LOCATION> and other federation officials, is beginning to pick up steam. The federation also is now stepping in to avoid most fighting among unions by deciding which affiliate should get the chance at non-union companies targeted for organizing. And the affiliates are making fresh efforts at attracting women, minorities and workers in the growing service sector. The noisy year for labor has to some degree obscured some remarkable contract agreements. The Steelworkers union won back many of the concessions workers were forced to give earlier in the decade when the industry was nearly crippled. The <ORGANIZATION> CWA </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> IBEW </ORGANIZATION> came out of the <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T talks and the regional negotiations settled so far with contracts that include innovative packages of parental leave, elder care and child care benefits. And <ORGANIZATION> UAW </ORGANIZATION> workers at a joint Chrysler-Mitsubishi plant in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> last week agreed on a new contract believed to have the best job-protection provisions ever included in a major industrial contract. In the final months of 1989 the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> strike and legislative initiatives are likely to dominate labor's agenda. Pending on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> are efforts to raise the minimum wage and a number of other labor-backed measures, including expanded child care benefits and a number of bills designed to curb mergers and acquisitions. Also pending, but unlikely to pass, is a measure designed to force President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to intervene in the Eastern strike. <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> refers to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> as `` <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> <PERSON> Lite </PERSON>,'' sharing his former boss' pro-management bent but not his virulent anti-union philosophy. Labor Secretary <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said Sunday the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration was striving to maintain close contact with the organized labor leadership. `` We talk at least once a week with the <ORGANIZATION> AFL-CIO </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said. Appearing on <ORGANIZATION> CNN </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Newsmaker Sunday'' program, Mrs. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> noted that `` what I have been very pleased to see _ and we're urging a continuation of this approach _ is cooperation between management and labor.'' `` That trend has been occurring over the last 10 years. It's very important that it continue, if we're going to become ever more competitive on a global basis _ that there not be so much confrontation and more cooperation between management and labor,'' she said. Even though <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is regarded as no friend of the labor movement, he is not seen as its No. 1 enemy, as was <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. That designation has been passed to <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>, who was successful in making <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> a non-union carrier and appears on the verge of winning again at Eastern. His recent talk of selling <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> has sparked hope in the labor movement that the airline unions might yet pull a victory out of defeat. <PERSON> Kirkland </PERSON> said there will be no winners even if the carrier returns to the union fold. But his contempt for <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> was clearly evident as he added a caveat. `` Scorched earth on both sides is not a victory,'' he said. `` Of course it's better than scorched earth on just one side.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1336EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Afghanistan     09-03 0542</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Afghanistan,0562</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebels Hold Strategic Post But Offensive Checked</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NEIL MACFARQUHAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Heavy air force and artillery bombardments by the Afghan army have failed to break rebel control of a strategic post near the border city of <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION>, government officials and diplomats said Sunday. But the major assault by U.S.-backed rebels against the city appears to have stalled, they said. Also Sunday, the Afghan <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> issued a statement criticizing the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for continuing to arm the Pakistani-based rebels, saying it underscored an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> desire for war in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Government sources and diplomats said the assault on <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION>, which began 10 days ago, was aimed at gaining recognition from the non-aligned summit that begins in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> on Monday. President <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> said in a statement released Sunday that he would seek special backing for his peace proposals at the conference. In the <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION> fighting, government sources said the Afghan troops had recaptured three posts but still were trying to take four more fortified positions lost in earlier fighting. The most strategic of those was at <LOCATION> Daragai </LOCATION>, 10 miles south of the city, because it controls the main supply routes between <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and the capital. The provincial capital, just 18 miles from the <LOCATION> Pakistani </LOCATION> border, is considered the most vulnerable to rebel assault because supply lines are so short. `` We have felt a lot of pressure in the last week,'' said one government official, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` The threat has diminished, but their effort has not collapsed.'' The guerrillas issued a statement Saturday in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> saying the Afghan army had failed to take the position at <LOCATION> Daragai </LOCATION>. The official described the fighting around the city as `` serious.'' He said <LOCATION> Khost </LOCATION> remained secure because the strategic routes into the city were heavily mined. The government supplies its troops by air because the road to the capital has long been controlled by the rebels. Government troops also have been fighting rebel assaults around the city of <LOCATION> Jalalabad </LOCATION>, 120 miles east of the capital, and in the southeastern province of <LOCATION> Kandahar </LOCATION>, the officials said. <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION> was quiet a day after rocket attacks killed 16 and injured 52. The Afghan Foreign Ministry issued its criticism of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in response to remarks made Thursday in <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomsen </PERSON>, special <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> envoy to the guerrillas. <PERSON> Tomsen </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would continue to arm the guerrillas in their effort to topple the Soviet-backed government in <LOCATION> Kabul </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> also support the rebels. <PERSON> Tomsen </PERSON>'s statements `` indicate the war-mongering policy of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' the statement said. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> withdrew its 115,000 troops in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in February under a U.N.-sponsored agreement to end the fighting that started in 1979. The rebels formed an interim government but have failed in repeated efforts to capture a provincial capital to use as its seat. The president, speaking to the official agency <ORGANIZATION> Bakhtar </ORGANIZATION> before his departure late Saturday, said he would propose that the non-aligned movement set up a committee to pursue his peace proposals. <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> are expected to lead the fight against the committee. <PERSON> Najib </PERSON> has proposed negotiating with the rebels in conjunction with a six month cease-fire to be followed by nationwide elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Vietnam     09-03 0386</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Vietnam,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnamese Leader Stands Firm Against Democratic Reform</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vietnamese leader <PERSON> Nguyen </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> sharply rejected a multi-party system for his Communist nation and declared that freedom of speech amounts to anarchy. Expressing unease with the kind of changes sweeping the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, and other Communist countries, <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> would keep liberalizing its economy but not its political system. `` It is not our policy to hasten renovation of the political system while preparations are still inadequate,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader said. `` Neither is it our intention to effect limitless democratization.'' `` The Communist Party of <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> is the leader, initiator and pacesetter in renovation,'' <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> said. `` We shall not allow any force to set up any opposition party to work against the people and against socialism. Once again, we declare that we resolutely reject pluralism, a multi-party system or opposition parties.'' His comments came in a 10,000-word speech laden with Marxist terminology and dogma. <PERSON> Linh </PERSON>, an economic reformer who has also taken some steps toward political liberalization, gave the address at a meeting in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> on Friday to mark <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s National Day. A text was seen in <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION> on Sunday. Its basic thrust reflected a recent conservative trend in <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION>, with official media lashing out at liberal reform in <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. Some observers believe the trend stems from leaders' fears that <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s `` open-door'' economic policy will lead to a popular pro-democracy movement such as occurred in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. Others, however, believe the recent conservative declarations are a tactical ploy by party liberals to appease conservative elements. `` Democracy does not mean that one is free to say what one wants to say, write what one wants to write and do what one wants to do, no matter what the consequences may be,'' the Communist leader said. `` These are essentially anarchist acts.'' <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> said that while <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> believes in the reform occurring in some Communist countries, there were `` opposition forces of all colors which are misusing liberalization and openness to fish in troubled waters.'' He accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other `` imperialists'' of trying to undermine the Communist camp and launching `` frenzied attacks against socialism.'' However, <PERSON> Linh </PERSON> said capitalist-style reforms would continue in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. He said the pace of such changes has quickened considerably since they were first launched two years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-NuclearLessons     09-03 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nuclear Lessons,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>Regulators Ponder Reasons for Plants' Sudden Fall From Grace</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two years ago the Calvert Cliffs nuclear power plant in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> was on a roll. Today, it's on its back and federal regulators are wondering whether the traumatic tumble is symptomatic of broader problems in the nuclear industry. One concern is that owners of some plants, dissatisfied with the profit outlook in nuclear energy, are turning too much of their corporate attention to other businesses _ sometimes taking on projects far removed from the nuclear field. <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, which owns the Calvert Cliffs station, denies that its move into new enterprises in the early 1980s, including ownership of nursing homes, led to the nuclear plant's decline It says complacency was its downfall, and that an infusion of new senior managers will put the plant back on track. Whatever the reason, regulators are stunned that a nuclear plant long considered one of the best in the business could suddenly drop to near the bottom of the heap. Both of <LOCATION> Calvert </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cliff </LOCATION>'s nuclear reactors have been closed since May because of mechanical problems. One may be restarted in October, the other next spring, although the utility must first get a go-ahead from the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which has had the plant under special surveillance since last winter. <PERSON> Calvert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cliffs </PERSON> is not the only source of worry for regulators. Although the nuclear industry's overall record in safety and efficiency has been improving lately, the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> is concerned that signs of trouble are cropping up unexpectedly at some plants. They cite as examples the <LOCATION> Surry </LOCATION> plant owned by <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which last May was hit with a $ 500,000 fine for violating <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> rules _ one of the largest fines ever imposed by the agency _ and the <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION> plant of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION>, which in late August drew especially low marks in a regular <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> review of its operating performance. One of the dilemmas facing regulators is determining when a dropoff in performance at an individual plant may be serious enough to force a shutdown. There are no clear guidelines for making this judgment, officials said. The <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> now is mulling the case of the <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> nuclear station in <LOCATION> south </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, which has been ranked among the worst performers for three straight years in the commission's biannual review of operations at all 112 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> nuclear plants. The commission has repeatedly criticized <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION>'s performance, citing, among other things, unstable management by <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the plant owner Last June some <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> officials suggested the commission might force <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> to close if it did n't show improvement by the end of the year. Also, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>, administrator of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s Northeast regional office, said recently he had `` a real concern'' that the reason for problems at the Nine Mile Point 1 nuclear plant, near <LOCATION> Oswego </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, was a `` diversion of attention'' by its owner, <ORGANIZATION> Niagara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mohawk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, to its financial troubles. The most puzzling case, however, is Calvert Cliffs, which in August 1987 was inspected by a team from the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and given a clean bill of health. `` Calvert Cliffs is a good example of what is expected from a well managed and operated plant,'' the inspectors' report said, adding that `` no shortcomings in equipment, personnel and operating practices were found that would compromise safe operation.'' The report included some mild criticism of the plant's maintenance and industrial safety training programs, but the overall judgment was that Calvert Cliffs was above the average of nuclear plants inspected in other countries Then the trouble began. Last spring and summer, Calvert Cliffs suffered a series of mishaps and was fined by the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> for violations of safety regulations. The toughest blow, however, was an extraordinary incident last September in which a diver at the plant drowned in a water storage tank after disregarding safety rules. `` That shook them up; it shook us up,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Murley </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s office of nuclear reactor regulation. Three months later the plant was put on the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>'s list of worst-run plants in the country, and this summer it was reaffirmed on the list. `` Their fall from grace came so quickly and they fell so far, given the good performance that they'd had over the years,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION>, said in a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> officials in mid-August. <PERSON> Murley </PERSON> says Calvert Cliffs had such a consistently good operating record in the past that its own managers _ and federal regulators _ may have become complacent. `` They had a halo effect for years,'' he said. <PERSON> Murley </PERSON> said he is confident that <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> methods of monitoring nuclear plant performance _ including special on-site audits about once a year _ are adequate to ensure public safety. But some other officials have expressed doubt about whether <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> warnings to plant owners are enough to force improvements. `` My problem with -LRB- yearly inspections -RRB- is they are so late,'' <ORGANIZATION> NRC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Carr </PERSON> told a recent commission meeting. `` They come out so long afterward, the guy can lull himself into saying, ` Well, we fixed that ... We are in better shape now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1419EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--AutobahnCrash     09-03 0089</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Autobahn Crash,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>26 Injured in Chain-Reaction Pileup on Autobahn</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MUNICH, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chain-reaction pileup involving 115 vehicles on a major autobahn injured 26 people on Sunday, authorities said. Police blamed the series of collisions on drivers traveling too fast during a heavy rainstorm. Four of the victims were seriously injured. The pileup occurred near <LOCATION> Allershausen </LOCATION>, 30 miles north of <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, creating a traffic jam 12 miles long on the autobahn linking <LOCATION> Nuremberg </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. Police said $ 445,000 in damage was done to vehicles involved.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0030 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1433EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-FireApology     09-03 0368</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Fire Apology,0380</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Court's Behest, Four Whites Appear in Black Church to Apologize
for Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ADAIRVILLE, Ky. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Four white people who set fire to a church founded by freed slaves returned to the newly renovated building to give their court-ordered apologies to the congregation. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sircy </PERSON>, 22, bowed his head and cleared his throat during Saturday's dedication of the new <ORGANIZATION> Smith </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Grove </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AME </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, then said, `` We're sorry, but I know that's not enough.'' The congregation of about 60 people responded, `` Amen!'' `` What we did was wrong,'' said <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Estep </PERSON>, whose husband stood nearby. `` It was an accident, but it was still wrong. And I'm sorry. As <PERSON> Sherri </PERSON> <PERSON> Davenport </PERSON>, 19, spoke, her grandfather, <LOCATION> Herman </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> of <LOCATION> Adairville </LOCATION>, listened from the church doorway. Afterward he said he was proud of her courage in taking responsibility for her action. `` What's done is done; they ca n't bring it back,'' <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> said. `` But they did what they could.'' <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 22, echoed that sentiment after the service. `` There just was n't a whole lot we could say _ just that we're sorry.'' The congregation gave the four young people a round of applause as they left the church. `` I think what they did was a fantastic gesture,'' said <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, who grew up near the church. `` We are just amazed that this type of thing could happen,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Garrick </PERSON>, 57. `` When I lived here, this would have never have happened because of the racial prejudices in the area. I think it's wonderful that the court made them come out here and apologize. Last October the four young people, all residents of this rural western <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> town, pleaded guilty in <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Court </LOCATION> to breaking into the 116-year-old church and setting it on fire in May 1986. Before their sentencing, the four had paid $ 6,000 to rebuild the church, and prosecutors agreed to amend the charges from felonies to misdemeanors. But when Logan District Judge <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> sentenced them, he ordered them to apologize to the congregation of face contempt of court, with possibly a year in jail and a $ 500 fine. <PERSON> Prince </PERSON> also put each of the four on probation for two years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0031 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1451EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Bangladesh     09-03 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bangladesh,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nationwide Strike By Rival Groups</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FARID HOSSAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Shops, banks and schools closed and armed police patrolled the streets Sunday during a nationwide strike called by opposition groups. Except for a few rickshaws, the streets of <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> and other major cities were deserted and many government and private offices closed during the six-hour strike, witnesses said. Strike supporters in small groups paraded through downtown <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, chanting slogans, deflating rickshaw tires and harrassing rickshaw pullers, witnesses said. At least 16 people were arrested, police said. Baton-wielding police clashed with members of a procession near a mosque in central <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, police and witnesses said. About 20 people, including two opposition leaders, were slightly injured, they said. In downtown <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION>, a gasoline bomb was thrown at a jeep taking two policewomen to work. The jeep exploded and the two women jumped to the street, police said. One officer, an inspector at the department's special intelligence branch, suffered severe head injuries and was in a coma, police said, speaking on condition of anonymity. An eight-party opposition alliance headed by the <ORGANIZATION> Awami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> called the strike to protest an Aug. 10 attack by unidentified gunmen on the home of the <ORGANIZATION> Awami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> chief Sheikh <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON>. No one was injured in the attack, blamed on the <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> whose leaders plotted the violent 1975 coup that toppled the government of Mrs. <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON>'s father, <PERSON> Sheik </PERSON> <PERSON> Mujibur </PERSON> <PERSON> Rahman </PERSON>. Party leaders denied any involvement the attack and called a strike demanding a ban on the <ORGANIZATION> Awami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> and its allies. <PERSON> Hasina </PERSON> and another opposition leader, <PERSON> Khaleda </PERSON> <PERSON> Zia </PERSON>, have been leading a 6-year-old campaign against the government of President <PERSON> Hussain </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>, who seized power in a military coup in March 1982. They are demanding <PERSON> Ershad </PERSON>'s resignation and new elections.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0032 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1452EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     09-03 0663</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, recovering from breast surgery and getting ready to make a new movie, has bought a house here in sight of her childhood home so she can occasionally get away from it all. `` Maybe now more than ever <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> is home,'' Miss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. `` The people that I love the most are there, and to me that's what home is `` The surgery was a complete success,'' she said Thursday of the operation two weeks ago to have a malignancy removed. `` My recovery has been amazing. I really ca n't believe I feel so well. `` I think it's such an incredible thing that they can do the reconstructive surgery right at the time, so you do n't have to go through this incredible trauma that I think women had to go through up until recently,'' she told The <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Miss <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who starred in `` The Rookies,'' `` Charlie's Angles,'' and `` Scarecrow and Mrs. <PERSON> King </PERSON>,'' said when she finishes the television movie she described as a psychological thriller, she'll `` come home to <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>. `` It's just a sweet little house, nothing grandiose,'' she said. `` One of the best things I like about it is I can look right across the way to that tiny little house in which my sister and I grew up. `` I never imagined I'd be 40 and not have three or four babies running around the house and a husband and all of that. But I still hope that that'll happen,'' she said. Her two marriages ended in
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MACKINAC ISLAND, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> married his former executive assistant, <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, among the flowers and Victorian bric-a-brac of the governor's summer mansion. More than 150 tourists who waited in the road for four hours for a glimpse of the bride and groom applauded as the Blanchards emerged Saturday to take a horse-drawn carriage built for <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> to their dinner reception at the nearby Grand Hotel. The wedding was the second for both, but a first for the summer governor's mansion. The crowd applauded as the governor waved and shouted `` Hello, everybody!'' In her debut as the state's first lady, Mrs. <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> stumbled only once when, unaccustomed to her new name, she introduced herself as `` <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>.'' `` Oh no! It's <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> now,'' she said. __ <LOCATION> KANSAS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> CITY </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo </LOCATION>. -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Country singer <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said he's in the battle to help farmers `` for the duration'' as he announced his fourth Farm Aid concert will be held somewhere in the <LOCATION> Midwest </LOCATION> next spring. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> is founder and chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Farm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which has raised $ 12 million with three concerts to support family farmers in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said he intends to continue holding Farm Aid concerts until the farm crisis is over. `` We're here for the duration,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said before a non-benefit concert Saturday. `` That means when farmers get 75 percent of parity.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Anjelica </PERSON> <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> reportedly paid nearly $ 2 million for <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamberlain </PERSON>'s house, which the actor is giving up to move to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> for his new TV series `` Island Son.'' But actor <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON> is n't moving in with her, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported Sunday. `` Miss <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> will live in her new home without <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicholson </PERSON>, her boyfriend of several years,'' her real estate agent, <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Coons </PERSON>, was quoted as saying. `` When I asked her why they lived apart, she said, ` It just works out better that way.' `` But they live a stone's throw away from each other.'' Miss <PERSON> Huston </PERSON> recently finished a movie with <PERSON> Woody </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> and will attend this month's Emmy Awards ceremonies as a nominee for her role in the miniseries `` Lonesome Dove.'' The 3,500-square-foot house near <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> has two bedrooms, a maid's quarters and a pool. The home was completely remodeled by <PERSON> Chamberlain </PERSON> in an Oriental motif while he was starring in the TV miniseries `` Shogun.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0033 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1501EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ColliderQuarrel     09-03 0511</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Collider Quarrel,0528</SECOND>
<HEAD>Texas Towns Feud Over Super Collider Fame</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WAXAHACHIE, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The superconducting super collider project has got three towns on a super collision course over bragging rights to the giant atom smasher, bringing out their big artillery on billboards and bumper stickers. All three _ <LOCATION> Waxahachie </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ennis </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Midlothian </LOCATION> _ want people to think of their town first when they think of the collider which is slated for <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and, in fact, wo n't touch any of the three. The fight is n't quite so heated as the battle that preceded it, when politicians all over the country sought to get the multibillion-dollar federal project in their state. Instead, it's a battle fought with bumper stickers and billboards. <PERSON> Ennis </PERSON> proclaims itself `` Super Collider Country'' and <LOCATION> Midlothian </LOCATION> boasts it's the `` Gateway to the Super Collider.'' So far, <LOCATION> Waxahachie </LOCATION> has smashed the competition. At 18,150 people, it is the biggest town in <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and will be encircled by the 53-mile collider ring. It calls itself `` The Center of Attention, Home of the super collider.'' The other two towns are on the outskirts of the ring, which is to be built in the country south of <LOCATION> Dallas-Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>. Shortly after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced in November that <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> would be the collider site, the <ORGANIZATION> Waxahachie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> printed hundreds of bumper stickers proclaiming itself the center. The town also rented billboard space off Interstate 35 to carry the same message. That was enough to make officials in <LOCATION> Ennis </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Midlothian </LOCATION> stomp in protest. <PERSON> Ennis </PERSON>, a town of about 14,150 people east of <LOCATION> Waxahachie </LOCATION>, countered with its own boast on a billboard on Interstate 45. `` The only thing <LOCATION> Waxahachie </LOCATION> has is its name,'' said <PERSON> Kipp </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, executive vice president of the <ORGANIZATION> Ennis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>. `` It sticks. Even though it's hard to say, you do n't forget it.'' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokoll </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Waxahachie </LOCATION> city manager, scoffs at such talk. `` We are not going to let one peon city to the east like <LOCATION> Ennis </LOCATION> think they are the home of the super collider,'' <PERSON> Sokoll </PERSON> said. `` The only thing <PERSON> Ennis </PERSON> does better than us is play football.'' <LOCATION> Midlothian </LOCATION>, population 5,000, wo n't be left out, said <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Mundo </PERSON>, executive director of the town's chamber of commerce. She's the one who came up with the slogan: `` We are the Gateway to the Super Collider.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the state agency in charge of acquiring the land for the collider, is shying away from the feud. `` We have tried not to get caught up in the local competition,'' commission spokeswoman <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said last week. `` We have always referred to the super collider as being in <LOCATION> Ellis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>.'' Ground has not been broken for the colossal project, but officials say it should be operational by 1996. The collider is expected to reveal new information about the nature of matter and the origins of the universe. It will hurl minute beams of protons toward one another inside a 53-mile tunnel. It is expected to create 4,000 temporary construction jobs and 3,000 permanent positions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0034 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1506EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Finland-Hungary     09-03 0432</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Finland-Hungary,0446</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grosz Rules Out Force By Hungarian Communists</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HELSINKI, Finland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Hungarian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Karoly </PERSON> <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> promised that the party will not use force to hold onto power if it loses the nation's first multi-party elections next year, a newspaper reported Sunday. In an interview by the daily <ORGANIZATION> Helsingin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sanomat </ORGANIZATION> newspaper, <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> acknowledged that Hungarian communists want to wield power. However, he added that the party would `` draw its own conclusions'' if it were to lose the elections, due to be held at the latest in 1990, according to the paper. `` We would not be satisfied with such a situation,'' <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> was quoted as saying. However, he ruled out using force as a political weapon, saying, `` We would not use tanks but political arguments to get back into power.'' He said he will step down as party general secretary during a party congress on Oct. 6, but that he would continue to be active in politics. `` I want to remain in the party leadership,'' he said. In <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON> was scheduled to meet with President <PERSON> Mauno </PERSON> <PERSON> Koivisto </PERSON> on Monday. <PERSON> Grosz </PERSON>'s power was diluted in June when party reformers established a ruling presidium with the general secretary as one of four members. Party chairman <PERSON> Rezsoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Nyers </PERSON> has described himself as `` first among equals'' on the new body. In <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> on Sunday, the reformers preparing for the party congress clashed over how far to go in revamping the party. Presidium members <PERSON> Imre </PERSON> <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON>, <PERSON> Miklos </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Nyers </PERSON> spoke at a two-day conference of reformist communists held to plan strategy for the October congress. <PERSON> Nyers </PERSON> told the nearly 400 delegates that the party's political and economic policies must be revamped. However, <PERSON> Pozsgay </PERSON> went further, calling for a `` Copernican revolution,'' invoking the Polish astronomer whose discovery that the earth was round shook conservative-minded colleagues in the 16th century. <PERSON> Nemeth </PERSON>, in comments Saturday, appeared still more radical. He said `` dyed-in-the-wool Bolsheviks'' who can not accept far-reaching reforms should be free to split and form rival parties. Party Central Committee Secretary <PERSON> Gyoergy </PERSON> <PERSON> Fejti </PERSON> told a rally Saturday that 10,000 members a month have been leaving the party in the recent past. He said only 200 new members had been enrolling each month. Since endorsing the idea of a multi-party democracy in February, the Hungarian communists suffered upset defeats in three parliamentary by-elections. The voting represented <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s freest voting in over 40 years. Party reformers, who advocate a free-market economy in addition to a pluralistic political system, hold views that often put them closer to some non-communist opposition groups than to conservatives in their own party.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0035 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1511EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-HolidayTraffic     09-03 0008</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Holiday Traffic,0006</SECOND>
<TEXT>
 3 p.m. EDT: 195.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890903-0036 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-03-89 1518EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-DrugWar 1stLd-Writethru a0653 09-03 1050</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug War, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0653,990</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Battles in an Old War</HEAD>
