<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines-Military     03-05 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-Military,0294</SECOND>
<HEAD>Restructuring of Army Planned In Wake Of Corruption Allegations</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The military chief plans a major restructuring of senior echelons of the army in the wake of allegations of widespread corruption and inefficiency, newspapers reported Sunday. Several major newspapers quoted unnamed sources as saying Chief of Staff Gen. <PERSON> Renato </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> announced the impending changes last Friday during a closed-door session of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s defense committee. The <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> Bulletin, The <ORGANIZATION> Manila </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION>, quoted de Villa as saying the shakeup would effect regional and division commanders. No date was given for the shakeup, but the papers said it was expected to be announced in a few weeks. The Inquirer quoted the defense committee chairman, Sen. <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Maceda </PERSON>, as telling his colleagues that if <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Villa </PERSON> did not move soon, he himself would open formal investigations into the allegations of corruption. The calls for a shakeup in the senior ranks have increased following a series of embarassing incidents. They include the November escape of Communist rebel commander <PERSON> Romulo </PERSON> <PERSON> Kintanar </PERSON> from a <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> stockade; the takeover of a military headquarters by renegade policemen last January and the recent arrest of several police and military officers on car theft charges in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. Last week, <PERSON> Maceda </PERSON> charged that unidentified generals and colonels were receiving thousands of dollars annually from criminal syndicates in return for shielding them from arrest. <PERSON> Maceda </PERSON> also challenged military claims that government forces have gained the upper hand in the 20-year war against the communist <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. Ten senior officers, including army commander Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Mariano </PERSON> <PERSON> Adalem </PERSON>, are scheduled to retire this year. But the newspapers said the shakeup will affect many senior officers not scheduled for retirement.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NoTV 1stLd-Writethru a0544 03-05 0307</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-No TV, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0544,0313</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Takes Up Mom's Challenge, Does Not Watch TV For Year</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 7 grafs to UPDATE with boy receiving award; pickup
6th graf pvs, ``It was ...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GREEN BAY, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemens </PERSON> awarded her 13-year-old son a $ 500 check Saturday night for fulfilling a dare to go a year without television. `` I'm just so proud of him,'' she said. `` That a teen-ager could do that is fantastic.'' <PERSON> Don </PERSON>, an eighth-grade student, described himself as a TV fanatic when his parents offered him the challenge of purging the tube from his life for 12 months. `` Bet you ca n't do that,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Lemens </PERSON> said she told him. Her husband, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON>, upped the ante with a $ 500 reward if he gave up 365 days worth of his favorite cartoons, movies and situation comedies. The time trial ended at 8:39 p.m. Saturday. Mrs. <PERSON> Lemens </PERSON> said the absence of TV allowed her son more time for homework. While it did n't produce an improvement in his grades, she said, he has shown more interest in reading and non-television activities. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> said he plans to spend some of the money on stereo equipment and put the rest in the bank. He said the money was not the chief incentive. `` It was the challenge, not the money,'' he said. `` It helped me to motivate myself and realize that you can do anything you want if you try.'' The Journal of the American Medical Association estimates teen-agers watch an average of 21 hours of television a week. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> said he was above that average before the challenge. While the rest of his family watched television, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> said he would retreat to his room or to other diversions. `` I did my homework and read books, and in the summer I went outside and played,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-VirginIslands-Cocaine 1stLd-Writethru a0640 03-05 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Virgin Islands-Cocaine, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0640,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bail Increased In Drug Case Of Marion Berry Acquaintance</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout to RESTORE AP logo, first name of Lewis; MINOR
EDITING; no pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHRISTIANSTED, U.S. Virgin Islands (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal judge on Saturday doubled the bail of an accused cocaine trafficker who is a key figure in the federal investigation of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Marion </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>. Chief U.S. District Court Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said new information provided Saturday by the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney's Office in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> prompted the increase in bail from $ 100,000 set late Friday to $ 200,000. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said authorities had more than tripled their estimates of the amount of cocaine involved in two sales allegedly made last week by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>. Earlier, <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gow </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> allegedly sold six to seven grams of the drug to agents on <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> and would be charged with two counts of distributing cocaine. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> remained jailed in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Thomas </LOCATION> on Saturday and was to appear in court there Monday for a bail hearing. The judge said federal prosecutors have 30 days to file charges. An <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> statement said <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> was arrested Friday after allegedly attempting to sell agents the cocaine derivative `` crack'' twice last week on St. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>. The 48-year-old St. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> resident allegedly sold five `` rocks'' to agents Thursday and another 20 on Friday just prior to his arrest, according to court reports and the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> release. <PERSON> O'Brien </PERSON> said he had set bail at $ 100,000 over the telephone Friday on the `` bare-bones'' statement that both transactions involved a total 25 pieces of crack. But he said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney's Office informed him Saturday the transaction actually involved 20 envelopes containing 85 pieces of crack. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report said that during the alleged buys, which it said were recorded on video and audio tape, <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> told agents he could sell them `` pure cocaine'' that could be converted into crack. <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> was the target of a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> police investigation in December when a maid at a local hotel claimed that he offered her drugs in exchange for sex. Two district police officers went to the hotel to try to buy drugs from <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, but the drug buy was called off when the officers realized that <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> was visiting <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> at the time. A federal grand jury is now looking into the circumstances surrounding <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>'s visit to the hotel. A second investigation involving both <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> focuses on possible fraud in the city's $ 260,000 joint personnel project with the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Baker 1stLd-Writethru a0543 03-05 0535</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baker, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0543,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Heads For Meeting With Soviet Foreign Minister</HEAD>
<HEAD>Precede WASHINGTON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Top 4 grafs new to UPDATE with Baker en route, additional meetings
scheduled; Picks up 3rd graf pvs, bgng: ``His session ...''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SHANNON, Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Globe-trotting Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> headed for <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> on Saturday to plan his first trip to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and to launch new East-West arms control talks. Over three busy days, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will meet with <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and separately with several <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> ministers and will make a speech Monday to mark the opening of negotiations between the Western alliance and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> scheduled back-to-back meetings in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> on Sunday afternoon with Hungarian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Varkonyi </PERSON> and Polish Foreign Minister <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechowski </PERSON> to get what a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official called `` a first-hand account of how reforms are going'' in the East European countries and to determine `` where there may be opportunity for <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. cooperation.'' On the flight to <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, with a refueling stop in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> remained secluded in his sleeping quarters on the plane and did not talk to the 17 reporters traveling with him. His session with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> is expected to produce an agenda for what would be <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s first trip to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, probably in late April or early May. It would mark a move by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to accelerate its review of policy toward Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also assured two visiting delegations of American Jews on Friday that human rights were on his agenda. Jewish emigration from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is on the rise. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is expected to push for a sustained exodus and expansion of religious freedoms. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has been waging diplomatic initiatives in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and on the arms control front while <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy remains under review and President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> take their time filling several vacant posts at the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is due to fly home Tuesday, while the negotiations between the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact open Thursday. His speech will be searched for hints of evolving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy on several fronts. The <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies, under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leadership, are pushing for sharp reductions in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact's edge of nearly 2-to-1 in tanks and artillery. Their goal is to force the Soviet-led alliance down to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> levels and then cut about 5 percent to 10 percent on both sides. East and West are starting over after 15 years of futile negotiations to reduce non-nuclear forces in Central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. They have broadened their horizons to cover the entire expanse of the continent _ from the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Ural </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. All 35 nations that signed the 1975 <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION> agreement to reduce East-West tensions are involved, but the actual negotiations will be conducted by the 16-nation <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and the seven-nation <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact. While <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> is in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, he will compare notes with the other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> foreign ministers, who are expecting a report on prospects for a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomatic initiative to resolve the <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> conflict. They are also interested in evolving <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in Central America.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0550EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Baker-Shevardnadze     03-05 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Baker-Shevardnadze,0374</SECOND>
<HEAD>Baker Arrives in Vienna to Usher in Arms Talks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VIENNA, Austria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> arrived Sunday for meetings with Soviet Foreign Minister <PERSON> Eduard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> officials in a prelude to new European talks on cutting conventional arms. Austrian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Alois </PERSON> <PERSON> Mock </PERSON> and <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grunwald </PERSON> welcomed at Baker at <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Schwechat </LOCATION> airport. He made no statement upon arrival. Over three busy days, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> will meet with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> and separately with several ministers of the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. He will make a speech Monday to herald the opening of negotiations later in the week between the Western alliance and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> scheduled back-to-back meetings in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> on Sunday afternoon with Hungarian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Varkonyi </PERSON> and Polish Foreign Minister <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechowski </PERSON> to get what a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> official called `` a first-hand account of how reforms are going'' in the East European countries and to determine `` where there may be opportunity for <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. cooperation.'' On the flight to <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, with a refueling stop in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> remained secluded in his sleeping quarters on the plane and did not talk to the 17 reporters traveling with him. His session with <PERSON> Shevardnadze </PERSON> is expected to produce an agenda for what would be <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s first trip to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, probably in late April or early May. It would mark a move by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to accelerate its review of policy toward Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also assured two visiting delegations of American Jews on Friday that human rights were on his agenda. The secretary of state is due to fly home Tuesday, and the negotiations between <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact open Thursday. The <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> allies, under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> leadership, are pushing for sharp reductions in the <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION> Pact's edge of nearly 2-to-1 in tanks and artillery. Their goal is to force the Soviet-led alliance down to <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> levels and then cut about 5 percent to 10 percent on both sides. East and West are starting over after 15 years of futile negotiations to reduce non-nuclear forces in Central <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 0712EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-CanyonQuake     03-05 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Canyon Quake,0338</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quake Aftershock At Grand Canyon; Quake Reported In Washington State</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GRAND CANYON, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A moderate earthquake that shook Grand Canyon National Park on Saturday was followed by a moderate aftershock about nine hours later, but neither caused any damage or injury, officials said. Also late Saturday, an earthquake centered 40 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> was felt over a large area of western <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state. The <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> aftershock was recorded at a preliminary magnitude of 3.9 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale of ground motion at 2:18 a.m., said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey spokeswoman <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Jorgenson </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The epicenter of the quake was near <LOCATION> Grand </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canyon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, about 60 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Flagstaff </LOCATION>, she said. Saturday's temblor at 5:41 p.m. had a preliminary magnitude of 4.0, said <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Finley </PERSON>, a Geological Survey spokesman in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> `` It was very quick,'' <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Lundy </PERSON> said of the Saturday quake. `` It probably lasted only five or six seconds. We could hear the glasses rattling in the cupboard, and you could feel the ground rumble and shudder.'' In <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state, a moderate earthquake that shook the region at 10:42 p.m. was felt as far north as <LOCATION> Vancouver </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Jorgenson </PERSON> said. That temblor, with an epicenter in the Olympic Peninsula 40 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, was recorded with a preliminary magnitude of 4.4 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale, she said. No damage or injuries were reported as a result of the quake, she added. The Richter scale measures ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Each increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. Thus a reading of 7.5 reflects an earthquake 10 times stronger than one of 6.5. An earthquake of 3.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause slight damage in the local area, 4 moderate damage, 5 considerable damage, 6 severe damage. A 7 reading is a `` major'' earthquake, capable of widespread heavy damage; 8 is a `` great'' quake, capable of tremendous damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nigeria     03-05 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nigeria,0166</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Killed In Riot Caused By Hit-and-Run Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LAGOS, Nigeria (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hit-and-run bus accident touched off a clash between police and people armed with broken bottles and stones, and four people were shot to death and five injured, authorities said Sunday. Police said the riot occurred Friday night when a bus driver trying to escape a traffic policeman ran down and killed a commuter. Youths in the area of central <LOCATION> Lagos </LOCATION> began attacking police and government vehicles, injuring five policemen, one of them critically, police said. Riot police sent to the scene were greeted by rocks and bottles thrown from behind a barracade erected by the rioters, police said. Authorities fired tear gas and pistols to break up the riot. Police said four people died from bullet wounds. Last month a policeman was sentenced to death for killing two men involved in a traffic dispute. That traffic accident caused riots that left eight people dead.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-NorthernIreland     03-05 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Northern Ireland,0139</SECOND>
<HEAD>Car Bomb Injures Seven Near Military Barracks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELFAST, Northern Ireland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb hidden in a car exploded outside a north <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION> military barracks, injuring four police officers and three soldiers as they walked nearby, police said Sunday. The Irish <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, the mainly Roman Catholic organization fighting to drive the British out of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, claimed responsibility for Saturday night's blast. It said the bomb contained 500 pounds of explosives. Police said the blast damaged <LOCATION> Girdwood </LOCATION> military barracks and nearby houses off north <LOCATION> Belfast </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Antrim </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>. A joint army and police unit had just left the barracks to patrol on foot when the bomb exploded, said a police press officer who declined to be identified further. Most seriously injured was a police officer whose leg was broken, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Obit-Ding     03-05 0096</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Ding,0100</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vice President of Xinhua Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ding </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiangqi </PERSON>, vice president of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, has died of lung cancer at age 58, the agency reported Sunday. A brief obituary said <PERSON> Ding </PERSON> died Saturday night after a life `` dedicated to the development of the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>.'' <PERSON> Ding </PERSON> began his <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> career in the 1950s in the international news department and later reported from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> and was chief correspondent in <LOCATION> Belgrade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION>. The journalist joined the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in 1951. Membership remains a key to advancement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s state-controlled media.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Attack     03-05 0107</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Attack,0109</SECOND>
<HEAD>Police Thwart Attack on Takeshita's Residence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attackers believed to be right-wing extremists tried to ram a truck loaded with gasoline into Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s residence Sunday, but they were stopped by a police barricade, authorities said. The two men swerved their pickup truck into a fence to avoid the barricade blocking the front entrance to <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s official residence in downtown <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Kojimachi </LOCATION> precinct police official said. They did only slight damage to the fence and no one was injured before the two were arrested, he said, speaking on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> was out of town at the time.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Suicide     03-05 0193</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Suicide,0202</SECOND>
<HEAD>Veteran Commits Suicide Delayed for Emperor's Funeral</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A veteran of the <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> who had planned to commit suicide the day of Emperor <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral instead killed himself last week to avoid interfering with the funeral, police said Sunday. <PERSON> Toshio </PERSON> <PERSON> Muratani </PERSON>, 66, shot himself in the head with a pistol in a <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> park Friday, a police spokesman said. The victim left a note saying he delayed his suicide until after <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>'s funeral so he would not `` inconvenience any parties concerned,'' said the policeman, who spoke on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Muratani </PERSON> served as a lieutenant in the <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> during World War II. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> fought the war in the name of the emperor. <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON>, who died of cancer, was buried Feb. 24 in an elaborate funeral attended by world leaders, including President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Two former Japanese soldiers committed suicide to follow <PERSON> Hirohito </PERSON> in death, earlier police reports said. Another veteran tried to kill himself on the southern island of <LOCATION> Kyushu </LOCATION> by ritual disembowelment but survived. A police spokesman said Sunday the veteran was `` doing well'' but was still hospitalized with a cut through his small intestine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Philippines-Cult     03-05 0148</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Philippines-Cult,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rumors of Satanic Cult Stir Fears</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ZAMBOANGA CITY, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rumors that a devil-worshiping cult is kidnapping women and children has spread fear in this city, prompting parents to keep children home at night and setting off a police inquiry. Police Capt. <PERSON> Nonito </PERSON> <PERSON> Gader </PERSON> dismissed the reported cult as a hoax perpetrated by `` drug addicts or pranksters.'' He said surveillance of several neighborhoods in <LOCATION> Zamboanga </LOCATION> failed to turn up evidence of devil worship. The rumors surfaced after leaflets describing a cult turned up in schools, markets and even government offices in this southern city of 500,000 people. The leaflets, allegedly from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Satanic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Evil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION>, include a list of the cult's holy days as well as secret signs to identify members. Unconfirmed word spread, however, that the cult is kidnapping women and children for rituals. Mystical religious cults are widespread in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Philippines-Collision     03-05 0088</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Philippines-Collision,0090</SECOND>
<HEAD>14 Killed in Jeep-Bus Collision</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CEBU, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bus with a burst tire collided with a jeep near this central city, killing 14 people and injuring 11, military and hospital authorities said Sunday. The bus driver lost control of his vehicle after one of its tires exploded late Saturday along a road in <LOCATION> Danao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, about 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Cebu </LOCATION>, officials said. The jeep involved was an elongated version of World War II jeeps widely used in this country for public transport.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-SexBias     03-05 0445</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Sex Bias,0459</SECOND>
<HEAD>Head of Chinese Women's Group Criticizes Sex Discrimination</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s official women's organization denounced sex discrimination in the work place and politics and urged new efforts to fight it, an official report said Sunday. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Muhua </PERSON>, former head of the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> and head of the All-China Women's Federation, used unusually strong language in her remarks. She said the federation should `` justly and forcefully call out to fight for women's legal rights and interests,'' the People's Daily said `` To meet the new demands of the historical era, the Women's Federation should reform its work and raise the women's liberation movement to a new level,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> newspaper quoted Ms. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> as saying in an interview with the magazine `` Party Building. Officials generally argue there is no need for a women's liberation movement in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> They say the entire population, women included, was liberated in 1949 when the Communists took power. However, the Women's Federation has become increasingly outspoken in recent months. During that time, growing economic competition encouraged by senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> has been used as a reason for firing or not hiring women or denying them scarce university seats. `` Many women workers have been fired as industries form ` high-quality labor groups' or sign contracts with their workers,'' the paper quoted Ms. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> as saying. `` There are economic reasons for this, but it also has to do with attitude.'' The labor groups are one of the recent reform moves, involving reorganizing work forces into more efficient units and firing the unqualified. Official statistics indicate a majority of those fired are women. Ms. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> said one reason for that problem is that factories do n't want to pay maternity leave She was also quoted as saying women's representation in government is `` extremely low,'' with women making up only one-fifth of the 2,976 delegates to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the legislature. According to Ms. <PERSON> Chen </PERSON>, discrimination often begins at birth and is reflected in a growing gap between boys and girls in officially registered births. Recent figures indicate more than 110 boy babies are registered for every 100 girls. She did not say whether she believed girl babies were not being registered or if they were being aborted or killed after birth. Chinese families traditionally have preferred boys to girls, believing boys are more valuable as farm laborers and as supporters of their parents in old age. The government limits most families to only one child in an effort to limit the country's population. But some local authorities, bowing to popular pressure, allow families to have a second child if the first one is a girl.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-HighLife Bjt   03-05 0434</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-High Life, Bjt,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lofty Light Bulb Changer Gets ``Weebles'' At Lincoln Memorial</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Leaving desk-bound bureaucrats behind, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> has risen high in his government career, a man you can really look up to. He's the guy who changes light bulbs at the top of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument. Every week or so, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> climbs a ladder about 515 feet above ground to install a fresh bulb in the set of eight red airplane warning lights that blink unceasingly at the apex of the popular tourist attraction. Nothing to it, says <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, a 23-year veteran electrician for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. After all, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> works inside the monument, behind 18-inch-thick walls of granite and marble. He perches 15 feet above the observation deck atop an aluminum extension ladder held steady by an assistant. When he demonstrated his lofty job late last week, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> had <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, master <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> electrician for the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> region, as his supervisor. Although the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument sways slightly in a stiff wind, <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> says the only time he feels queasy is when he climbs outdoor scaffolding with the `` weebles and wobbles'' to change light bulbs above the columns of the Lincoln Memorial. The bulbs that <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON> replaces at the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument are 500-watt spotlights that cost $ 70 apiece and last about a week or two. They flash on and off continually from four pairs of holes on each side of the pyramid-shaped monument peak. No airplane has ever struck the 555-foot <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monument, which occupies airspace that is off-limits to planes landing or taking off at nearby <LOCATION> National </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. However, seven people have died in suicides or accidental falls down the monument's observation windows or elevator shaft since it was opened to the public on Oct. 9, 1888. Bars were installed in the narrow windows on the 500-foot level after they were used for the last two suicide leaps in 1926. Thick safety glass was installed later. A high metal grill was erected above the guard rail alongside the monument's 897 steps after the last suicide down the shaft occurred in 1949. The inner stairway was closed to the public in 1976, except for escorted tours downs the steps, because of vandalism and growing congestion. An eighth death occurred at the monument in December 1982 when police shot and killed <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayer </PERSON>, an anti-nuclear demonstrator who held the monument hostage for 10 hours claiming he would blow it up with dynamite. Ironically, no one was killed during the entire 36 years it took to build the monument.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Agriculture Bjt   03-05 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Agriculture, Bjt,0658</SECOND>
<HEAD>Politburo Report on Agriculture Plays Down Importance of Leasing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN-THOR DAHLBURG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Soviet leadership, preparing for an important meeting on agriculture, has given short shrift to President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s campaign to lease more state-owned farmland to private groups. In last week's two-day Poliburo meeting, the 12-member ruling body referred to leasing as only one of many forms of management it said were necessary to ease chronic Soviet food shortages, Pravda reported Saturday. And in a speech in the Siberian city of <LOCATION> Omsk </LOCATION>, the head of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s commission for agriculture, <PERSON> Yegor </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, also made only one mention of leasing. His speech was carried Friday by Pravda, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> daily. <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON>, reputedly a conservative force on the Politburo, opted instead for more traditional formulas calling for increased investment to better life in villages and to modernize farm machinery and technology. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> in October said the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> leadership had decided to extend `` to the whole of agriculture'' an experiment that leased collective farmland to small groups and families, who would choose their crops and keep most of the profits. Farmers, he said in a speech, must again become `` complete masters'' of the land. With the exception of small garden plots tilled by individual citizens, all farmland is state-owned in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. Since the bloody drive launched by dictator <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> in 1929 to eliminate the independent peasantry, the mainstays of the Soviet agricultural system have been the `` kolkhozes,'' or collective farms, and the `` sovkhozes,'' or state-owned farms. A leasing system runs counter to Marxist-Leninist theory, which holds that a socialist form of ownership, such as the collective farms, is a higher and more efficient form of organization than private farming. Any changes would threaten the entrenched bureaucracy that runs the collective and state-owned farms and the sprawling superministry of agriculture. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, the son of a Russian peasant, has not called for the dismantlement of collective or state farms, which have been run for decades like factories, with orders from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> on what and when to plant handed down to the wage earners who work the fields. But he said in October the practice of paying them `` unearned money'' had to stop. In the past 20 years, he said, capital investment in the agriculture sector rose 140 percent, but production increased only 41 percent. In contrast, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said, dairy farms run on the leasing system produce more milk per cow than ordinary farms. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> acknowledged in January that the leasing campaign ran into opposition from bureaucrats and collective farmers, who view those who enroll in it as latter-day descendants of the `` kulaks,'' or rich peasants. `` Leasing is proceeding with difficulty, and thus many people, the innovators, are being called kulaks and <ORGANIZATION> Rockefellers </ORGANIZATION>,'' he said. `` Many people, especially the lazy, do n't like the fact that leasing is destroying the ... habits of the years of stagnation, when you could get a good salary no matter how you worked.'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said a law was being drafted to prepare the interests of farmers who entered into long-term leases. The Politburo, preparing for a meeting of the party's policy-making <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on agriculture later this month, said it supported the creation of `` multiple forms of ownership and types of management _ of kolkhozes, sovkhozes, agro-industrial amalgamations, processing enterprises, leasees, members of cooperatives, leasing collectives, farmsteads, personal farmplots of citizens,'' Pravda said In <LOCATION> Omsk </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Ligachev </PERSON> used similar language, calling for the `` spread of different organizational forms of production, based on self-accounting, the brigade and lease relations, cooperatives and also the democratization of management on all levels,'' Pravda said. The Politburo report did not say when the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> would meet again, but at its last plenum in January, the 300-plus member body announced it would hold a plenary session March 15-16.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-TheOilCurse Bjt   03-05 0857</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-The Oil Curse, Bjt,820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Venezuelan Riots Point Up Questionable Blessings of Oil Wealth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bloody riots in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> this week highlight a question that has puzzled political analysts since the oil price spirals of the 1970s: What did the billions in oil income buy for the poorer exporting countries? The full answer is not yet clear, but a new study by a <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> economist concludes that for some countries, including <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, the wealth was wasted. <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> and its fellow <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> members were the chief beneficiaries _ at least temporarily _ of the oil supply disruptions of 1973 and 1979 that pushed prices from less than $ 2 a barrel to nearly $ 40. The immediate losers were the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and other oil-importing nations, which suffered a prolonged economic slump. A decade after the last oil price shock that was triggered by the 1979 Iranian revolution, economists and political scientists are still trying to determine what happened to the mountains of oil income earned by the exporters. So, too, in a less academic way, are people in the slums of <LOCATION> Caracas </LOCATION>, the Venezuelan capital. Riots that began there on Monday claimed at least 200 lives in a crisis triggered by new government austerity measures, including increases in gasoline prices and transit fares. Martial law was imposed on Tuesday. A few analysts have been saying for years that the oil exporters' wealth was squandered and that most members of the <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petroleum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exporting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Countries </ORGANIZATION> may be worse off today than before they began reaping the richest trade returns in history But their judgments lacked a longer perspective on how the <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> economies have performed. Now, the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON>, in his new book `` Oil Windfalls: Blessing or Curse?'' has provided a comprehensive and detailed analysis of the oil boom fallout. His conclusion: Most of the oil exporting nations are worse off now than before the boom, making the decade of oil windfalls a massive net loss for the whole world. The troubles for the oil exporters have been made much worse, of course, by the steep fall in oil prices since 1986, from $ 30 a barrel to roughly $ 15 a barrel now. During the 1970s, it was widely believed worldwide that prices would keep rising. <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON>, a senior financial economist at the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>, focuses on five <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> members: <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Algeria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Ecuador </LOCATION>, plus non-OPEC member <LOCATION> Trinidad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Tobago </LOCATION>. He says that of these six, only <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION> succeeded in using its 1970s oil wealth to strengthen its overall economy, mainly by improving its agricultural sector. <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> probably fared the worst, <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> says. By the mid-1980s, Nigerians' overall standard of living was lower than before the boom, he concludes. As a measure of <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION>'s failures, <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> writes that in 1972-84, the economy grew at an average annual rate of 2.5 percent despite the largest investment boom in the nation's history. By contrast, in the six years prior to the 1973 oil price spiral, Nigerian economic growth averaged 9.2 percent a year. <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> adds, however, that despite the massive waste of oil income on such failed projects as steel factories, <LOCATION> Nigeria </LOCATION> did spend wisely to improve primary education. One of the chief reasons for the economic problems resulting from the oil boom in these six countries, <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> says, was the speed at which oil wealth grew. In <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>, for example, oil export income soared more than fourfold at the start of the boom, from $ 641 million in 1973 to $ 2.64 billion the following year. The governments, which own the national oil monopolies, felt compelled to spend the money rapidly in order to demonstrate to their publics that it was not being hoarded or extorted, <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> says. This often led to overly risky investments and too little attention to the need for basic economic changes such as tax reform. `` Oil exporters ended the period worse off than they would have been with a far lower, more predictable rate of increase in oil prices or, indeed, with constant real oil prices,'' <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> writes. <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, unlike many of the other oil exporters, was more cautious in spending its oil windfall, perhaps out of respect for the views of <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON>, who helped create <ORGANIZATION> OPEC </ORGANIZATION> in 1960. He once called oil `` the devil's excrement'' and said, `` It brings trouble.'' In the early years after the 1973 price boom, which was triggered by the Arab oil embargo, the Venezuelan government created the Venezuelan Investment Fund to manage the money it saved abroad. By 1978 the nation's accounts with the rest of the world were in balance. Today its foreign debt of $ 33 billion is fourth largest in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. In 1979, at the start of the second oil boom, <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>'s private investment began to fall, in part because of what <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> calls inconsistent government policies. Money began flowing out of the country. Subsidies fell. Unemployment grew. `` The overall picture that emerges is one of a dramatic failure of economic policy under complex yet seemingly exceptionally favorable conditions,'' <PERSON> Gelb </PERSON> writes. `` Nothing appears to have been gained from the windfalls ...''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-MarcosMania     03-05 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos Mania,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Marcos Countrymen in North Press for His Return</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FERDINAND, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many of <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' fellow northerners are clamoring for his return from exile and insisting his death abroad could deepen their estrangement from the government of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. `` There's going to be war,'' said <PERSON> Chit </PERSON> <PERSON> Guarin </PERSON>, a 27-year-old medical technician who works near this village named in honor of the favorite son of <PERSON> Ilocos </PERSON> <PERSON> Norte </PERSON> province. `` This is his home. Besides, he is very bright, and he gave us a lot.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, who was born in the <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> town of <LOCATION> Sarrat </LOCATION>, to return from exile in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, despite claims from his family that the former president may soon die. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, 71, has been hospitalized since January with heart and respiratory ailments. Here in <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> and other Ilocano-speaking areas of the north, the former president is still widely viewed as a hero. `` He is a blood brother and a province mate,'' said <PERSON> Pacita </PERSON> <PERSON> Juan </PERSON>, 46, a farmer. `` Many will become rebels -LRB- if <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> dies in exile -RRB-,'' said <PERSON> Felicito </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamayo </PERSON>, mayor of the town of <LOCATION> Marcos </LOCATION>, which includes <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> village. Their views highlight the political estrangement many of the 6 million Ilocanos, the third-largest of more than 80 language groups in the country, feel toward Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. Government officials in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, 240 miles to the south, say most Filipinos agree with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s stand toward <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, which she says is based on national security. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has lived in <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> since he was overthrown in a popular uprising that swept Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to power three years ago. In <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and other parts of this island nation, people generally express contempt for <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. Many in this region, however, believe <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> won the fraud-tainted 1986 election against Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, which was held about two weeks before the uprising. In <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON>, which has about 400 residents, Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> received 10 votes in 1986. Residents said they were stunned by the news in 1986 their leader was gone. `` Old people wept,'' recalled <PERSON> Junel </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosqueta </PERSON>, 20. `` They said, ` <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is gone; when will be come back?' All of them went to hear Mass and to pray.'' <PERSON> Melecio </PERSON> <PERSON> Duldulao </PERSON>, a village leader, said <PERSON> Ilocanos </PERSON> had come to believe <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> `` was president-for-life.'' `` I had gotten used to him,'' he said. `` We have lost hope that he will still be president now.'' However, most people in this region say they accept the new government while believing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> should be allowed to die here. `` It's not a question of being an Ilocano. It's a question of being a Christian,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Rock </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonoan </PERSON>, spokesman of the Roman Catholic archdiocese. `` I would prefer that he -LRB- <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> -RRB- be given the chance to come back and die in his country. He is already powerless. I do n't see why many people are so afraid.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> Marcos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agro-Industrial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, a state-funded elementary and high school, fourth-grade students were asked if they wanted <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return. `` Yes!'' they shouted in unison. `` <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is not the cheater. <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> is the cheater,'' said 11-year-old <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Mamayan </PERSON>, referring to Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> by her nickname. `` We do n't want what <PERSON> Cory </PERSON> is doing to <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>. She is trying to picture <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> as a thief,'' said <PERSON> Arnel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramirez </PERSON>, 7. Adults here fondly recall a visit <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> paid to their remote, mountain village during the 1950s when he was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. Others recall the public works projects he provided for his home province. `` Before 1963, no vehicles entered our place,'' said <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Abrigado </PERSON>. `` But after that, we had roads and electricity.'' Most people interviewed brushed aside government allegations <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> embezzled billions of dollars during his administration. Others said they did not care because <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> boosted the province's economic development
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Spain-Chess     03-05 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Spain-Chess,0132</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ivanchuk Wins International Tournament</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LINARES, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vasily </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivanchuk </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> won the international City of <PERSON> Linares </PERSON> chess tournament after drawing with <PERSON> Lajos </PERSON> <PERSON> Portisch </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in the 11th and last round. The 20-year-old Soviet ended the tournament unbeaten Saturday with a total of 7.5 points. He earned $ 6,521. Former world champion <PERSON> Anatoli </PERSON> <PERSON> Karpov </PERSON>, also of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, drew with <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> Timman </PERSON>, of the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION>, and was second in the final standings with seven points. He won $ 4,348. Other results in the last round were: <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Short </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, defeated <PERSON> Johan </PERSON> <PERSON> Hjartarson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>. Short finished at 5.5 and <PERSON> Hjartarson </PERSON> with three points. <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sokolov </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> at 3.5, drew with <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Beliavsky </PERSON>, also of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, who had 4.5.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a BC-Eastern     03-05 0459</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Eastern,0474</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eastern: Pilots Crippling Themselves, Airline, By Honoring IAM Strike</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCY GORDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> pilots, who have virtually shut down the carrier by honoring the picket lines of striking Machinists, are risking not only their careers but the existence of the airline, a company spokesman said Sunday. `` By continuing to stay out, the pilots are committing economic suicide,'' spokesman <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said at a late-morning news briefing discussing the effects of the <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union strike, in its second day Sunday. `` This is a pilot's strike. There should be no mistake about that, and it's a pontentially tragic mistake,'' <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said. `` It places 3,600 pilot careers in jeopardy and it risks the very existance of a great airline,'' he said. `` But maybe, just maybe, it's not too late.'' <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said that about 150 pilots had crossed the picket lines Saturday, and said there were indications more would work Sunday. Eastern was able to get only 85 of its normal 1,000 Saturday flights into the air because the pilots could n't be matched with available aircraft quickly enough, <PERSON> Matell </PERSON> said. Eastern expected to fly 125 flights Sunday, and had managed to get 12 up by 10 a.m., he said. Eastern managers thought they had prepared for the stike by hiring non-unionists and slashing the weekend schedule by up to 75 percent, but those plans ripped apart when most pilots and flight attendants honored picket lines. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, a spokesman for the pilots union, had said Saturday that `` It's very clear the airline is n't going to fly without us.'' Meanwhile, sympathizers across the country were mobilizing for massive pickets Monday that threatened rush-hour nightmares, especially in the congested <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> metropolitan area. Strikers planned picketing at commuter railroads and received assurances that no rail workers would cross their lines. The walkout that began at 12:01 a.m. Saturday by 8,500 mechanics, bag handlers and ground crews escalated a 17-month union-management battle at the nation's seventh-largest airline, which ordinarily schedules more than 1,000 flights with 100,000 passengers daily. Both sides were deadlocked on $ 150 million in wage concessions that company boss <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> demanded. Talks collapsed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> at midnight Friday and no new discussions were planned. The main target of the striker hostility was <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>, head of <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which bought Eastern in 1986. He is widely mistrusted by <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> workers because of what they call his triumphant union-crushing campaign at sister carrier <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. Many accuse him of provoking the strike to do the same at Eastern. Battered by years of labor tension and growing competition in the deregulated airline business, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> has racked up nearly $ 2.5 billion in debt and claims to be losing more than $ 1 million a day.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1153EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Eastern-CommuterRailroads     03-05 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Commuter Railroads,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Railroads Governed by the Railway Labor Act</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Eastern Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a list of the 12 commuter railroads governed by the federal Railway Labor Act, and therefore vulnerable to secondary boycotts from the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union strike, which entered its second day Sunday. The list was provided by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. _ <ORGANIZATION> Massachuetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> _ Northern Indiana Commuter Transportation District _ <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> and suburban <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Metro-North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commuter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rail </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION>, serving <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburbs _ <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rail </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>, serving <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> suburbs _ <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jersey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> _ PATH, <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trans-Hudson </ORGANIZATION> rail system, in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> SEPTA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Southeast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, of <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> METRA </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> CalTrans </ORGANIZATION>, which operates between <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fransisco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> PAT </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alleghany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> _ <ORGANIZATION> Tri-Rail </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s new 67-mile rail system
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1202EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-TowerSuccessor Bjt   03-05 0779</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tower Successor, Bjt,760</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Said Ready to Move to Second Choice, Just in Case</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejects <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> as defense secretary, the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> is expected to move quickly to name a replacement, even though it is n't acknowledging the possibility of defeat. `` The president has told his staff and has told the nation that he's not talking about successors, he's talking about getting his nomination confirmed,'' said White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. Still, administration aides and congressional sources say privately that the president is mindful of the odds against winning Tower's confirmation; and that the White House is determined not to be caught off balance. The speculation is that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s would select a candidate who could be confirmed quickly _ either someone now in government or someone who in the recent past had been a Cabinet or sub-Cabinet official. Some Republicans in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have been pressing <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to give the job to his <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Adviser </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>, who is widely respected on both sides of the aisle. In fact, if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was determined to keep Tower as part of his administration, he could do a job swap, giving him Scowcroft's present job _ which does not require <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation and which is not in the military line of command Although Scowcroft's name has been heard most frequently in recent White House speculation, there is no shortage of candidates. Among them: _ Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, senior Republican on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. A former secretary of the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> would sail through the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> if nominated. However, a big political minus to Republicans would be the loss of a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seat, since <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> Gov. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Baliles </PERSON> would surely fill the vacancy with a member of his own party. _ Former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Rumsfeld </PERSON> Now a corporate executive, <PERSON> Rumsfeld </PERSON> was former President <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>'s defense secretary in 1975-77. He is mentioned frequently as a likely contender for the post, but his support of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> against <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in last year's <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> primaries could work against him. _ Former Rep. <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> He was the senior Republican on the Appropriations defense subcommittee for many years and was highly regarded for his knowledge of the defense budget and for his skill in arguing defense issues. _ <PERSON> Drew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON>, former <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary The president of <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> has become a <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> workhorse with a string of high-level assignments and would bring a management perspective to the job. He was in President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s first Cabinet and most recently was co-chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which tried to tackle the problem of the budget deficit. _ <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Augustine </PERSON>, chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Martin-Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION> He reportedly was offered, and turned down, the chance to be deputy defense secretary, but might view the No. 1 spot differently. He has been involved in developing various proposals for defense modernization. However, his lack of previous government service could be a liability. When asked whether <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has considered alternatives, whether anyone on his staff has considered alternatives, or whether the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> personnel office has done any preliminary work in such a direction, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> is emphatic. `` To my knowledge and under every instruction that I've been given by everybody of any authority, the answer to that no, no, no and no,'' says the presidential spokesman. But analysts and leading Republicans in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> suggest otherwise. `` If there has n't been at least one session in the Oval Office to bat around alternatives to Tower, then they're nuts. They've got to have a contingency plan,'' said <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> of the conservative <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has to come forward with someone very quickly who can be confirmed quickly,'' if Tower loses, <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said, suggesting that additional delays in getting his defense team in place are `` the last thing he wants to do.'' Sen. <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Gramm </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, an outspoken Tower defender, said he believed `` several people'' might be considered as backup candidates for Tower, but that the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> has given no signal it is wavering in its support for Tower. Rep. <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, R-Ill., a former member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who was a top <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign adviser, said she assumes the president's senior staff has given consideration to a successor to Tower even if <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has not `` Of course, they'll have alternatives ready. That's what staff is for,'' she said in an interview. `` You always plan to the possibility of losing.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was entirely proper in forbidding his staff to talk about possible backup candidates. `` It is not the appropriate time,'' she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-CongressRdp     03-05 0725</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress Rdp,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congress To Focus On Tower Nomination, Wright Ethics Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM LUTHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The fledgling 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, with no major legislation to consider, will be dominated this week by highly partisan squabbles _ one behind tightly sealed doors and the other in the glare of television. The only significant legislative activity will come in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, which will begin writing a bill to raise the $ 3.35 minimum wage to at least $ 4.25 and perhaps as much as $ 4.65 an hour. The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration supports an increase to no more than $ 4.25 _ and only then if workers are exempted until they have been on the job for at least six months. With the nation looking on, the Democratic-controlled <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will resume debate Monday on the nomination of former Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>, a Republican, to be secretary of defense. A final vote is likely this week, and despite President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s pleas, no Democrat has announced support for Tower. No Republican has come out against him. On the other side of the Capitol, a 12-member committee evenly divided between the two parties will attempt to wrap up its investigation of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, the most powerful Democrat in government. The ethics committee has been looking into <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s behavior for nine months, and has diligently guarded against news leaks of its private discussions. The panel is considering six allegations against <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. Most of the attention has centered on assertions that he improperly used his office to produce and sell a book on which he made $ 55,000, in part by selling the book to special interests. He also is accused of having lobbied improperly on behalf of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> savings institutions. The speaker says he is confident that he will be vindicated. A finding that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> violated <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics standards would send the matter to the full House. Regardless of the outcome, Republicans already have vowed that <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> will be their chief target in the 1990 elections. A <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> vote against Tower would make history. Never before has the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> rejected the <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> nominee of a president entering his first term. Tower, an acknowledged expert on military matters, is under fire for what some senators view as a drinking problem and because be sold his advice to the defense industry after leaving government as a senior arms negotiator. Tower, a former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, served 23 -LCB- years in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The depth of his problem became clear when all 11 Democrats on the panel opposed him and only the 9 Republicans voted for him. Another <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> nominee, former Education Secretary <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, is likely to have a much easier time. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is expected to vote Thursday to recommend confirmation of <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> to head the federal government's battle against illegal drugs <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, who has the warm endorsement of Sen. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Biden </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Del., chairman of the committee, told the panel he plans to target casual drug users as well as drug distributors The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> will vote Tuesday on confirming career diplomat <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON> to be <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON> has faced some criticism because while serving as ambassador to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, he received a document from a Central American leader offering $ 1 million worth of military equipment to the rebels fighting the leftist government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. The letter, received at a time when the law barred <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the rebels, was delivered directly by <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON> to <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>. Until committees begin churning out legislation, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has little to do except nominations and housekeeping measures. Leaders of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration may begin negotiations late in the week aimed at producing a budget for the 12 months that begin next Oct. 1. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed a $ 1.16 trillion spending plan that he says would reduce the budget deficit below the $ 100 billion maximum allowed by law. Democrats complain that the president's plan leaves to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> the tough decisions on which programs to cut to meet that deficit target. Hanging over the budget discussions is <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s pledge not to raise taxes. Democratic leaders say any workable plan must include some tax increases but they are not about to take the first step unless they are joined by the president.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1320EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-People     03-05 0885</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-People,0919</SECOND>
<HEAD>People in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY44</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryant </PERSON> <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> say anything about the anti-Willard memo? Viewers of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' show will find out Monday when <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> returns to the air after a week of vacation in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. He's been silent so far; asked to comment Friday, <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> replied, `` not a chance, not a chance.'' The private memo was leaked last week to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Newsday </LOCATION> and included some pretty blunt criticisms of <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON>'s on-air colleagues. <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> especially was blunt about `` Today'' weather forecaster <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> for using time on the No. 1-rated morning show to offer homey birthday greetings and plug charity events. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON> said, `` holds the show hostage to his assortment of whims, wishes and bad taste.'' The memo, to `` Today'' executive producer <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, was written last August. Sources apparently retrieved it from <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON>'s computer file. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> suggested last week that if he ca n't work a reconciliation with <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON>, `` I do n't think I belong here.'' <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON>'s co-host, <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, who was not mentioned in the memo, suggested everyone `` lighten up.'' `` Sure it was a problem, but every family has its ups and downs,'' she said. Other `` Today'' show personalities who were subject to <PERSON> Gumbel </PERSON>'s grumbles included movie reviewer <PERSON> Gene </PERSON> <PERSON> Shalit </PERSON> -LRB- his reviews `` are often late and his interviews are n't very good'' -RRB- and consumer reporter <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Horowitz </PERSON> -LRB- `` a walking cliche'' -RRB-
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 British rock star Sting, who has said he will lead a campaign to preserve the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> rain forest, says the destruction of the jungle is tied to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s $ 121 billion foreign debt. The Brazilian government claims it must develop the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> to pay off its huge debt. But development equals environmental destruction, critics say. `` The truth is that the world is in debt to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, not the contrary,'' Sting said in an interview published Sunday in <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>'s Jornal do Brasil newspaper `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> produce more dollars and <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> produces more air. It's a question of how you value things. I personally value air more.'' He said that `` the foreign debt and rain forest destruction are linked'' because the country's debt-induced poverty `` forces people, who live at the margins of existence, to go to the forests out of necessity.'' Sting said he believed the foundation he established to help save the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> `` will be useful in influencing public opinion in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> to reduce the paying back of the debt.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AUSTIN, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Willie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Rosalynn </PERSON>, are the drawing cards for two fund-raising events on April 2 that will benefit some of <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>'s homeless The funds will be channeled through Habitat for Humanity, an organization that has spread to more than 300 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities and more than 25 foreign countries since it started more than 10 years ago. Habitat for Humanity renovates or builds homes for needy families around the world. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> is a board member of the organization, which is based in <LOCATION> Americus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga </LOCATION>. The Rev. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Mann </PERSON>, pastor of the 3,000-member <ORGANIZATION> Riverbend </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Baptist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, said 90 percent of the events' proceeds will be used locally and 10 percent will be used to build homes in foreign countries. The fund-raising will start with a $ 100-per-ticket reception, limited to 250 people. Among the sponsors will be Lady <PERSON> Bird </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, wife of the late President <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. Later, 100 members of the Riverbend chorus will perform with a 27-piece orchestra. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> will speak and <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> will sing.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MEMPHIS, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> is planning to expand the horizons of his career when he directs his first movie later this year. Beginning May 1, <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> will direct `` Staggerwing'' on location in northwest <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>. `` It's a whole career change,'' <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> said in an interview while in <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> with his one-man show about <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Twain </PERSON>. He said the film is spun from a true story of a mastermind criminal and will star <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Strathairn </PERSON>, with a screenplay by <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Minetree </PERSON>. Filming will take place in <LOCATION> Fayetteville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bentonville </LOCATION>, Ark. `` What attracted me initially was the fact that <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>'s script has a beginning, a middle and an end, and that's rare enough these days,'' <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> said. `` And it's full of so many wonderfully rich characters.'' <PERSON> Holbrook </PERSON> credited his second wife, actress <PERSON> Dixie </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, with the move toward directing. `` She's pushing me onwards into new efforts. She thinks any movie I direct will be an instant, fabulous success,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The only house built in the <LOCATION> Motor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> by pioneering architect <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> has been put up for sale by <PERSON> Domino </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pizza </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON>, who decided not to restore the home. <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON>, a collector of <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s work who bought the house a year ago, has listed the cement-block building on <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s north side for $ 295,000. The original purchase price was not disclosed. The house was designed in the 1950s for a prominent local attorney. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> died in 1959. Domino's bought it with the intention of restoring it and loaning it to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION>, a company spokesman said Friday. But <PERSON> Monaghan </PERSON> scrapped the project because of a commitment to building a new <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> museum at Domino's Farms, the company's headquarters near <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON>, the spokesman said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1321EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-BRF--Italy-Mafia 1stLd-Writethru a0671 03-05 0189</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Italy-Mafia, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0671,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Jailed for Life in Mafia Slaying of Prosecutor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 4 grafs to CORRECT that one ordered the killing and
two carried it out, sted all three ordering slaying; picks up 5th graf
pvs, ``Montaldo was ...''</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CALTANISETTA, Italy (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A court has sentenced three men to life imprisonment for the 1983 killing of an assistant state prosecutor who was investigating the Mafia. One of them, <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvatore </PERSON> <PERSON> Minore </PERSON>, is a reputed Mafia figure who is a fugitive. He was convicted and sentenced Saturday for ordering the killing of <PERSON> Giangiacomo </PERSON> <PERSON> Ciaccio </PERSON> <PERSON> Montaldo </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Caltanisetta </LOCATION> court sentenced <PERSON> Ambrogio </PERSON> <PERSON> Farina </PERSON> and <PERSON> Natale </PERSON> <PERSON> Evola </PERSON> for carrying out the killing. The court sentenced two other men to 10 - and 14-year prison terms for Mafia association Three people were acquitted. <PERSON> Montaldo </PERSON> was shot in his car on an isolated mountain road in western <LOCATION> Sicily </LOCATION> in January 1983. He had collated a dossier on Mafia drug and money-laundering operations that vanished after his death, state television said. <PERSON> Montaldo </PERSON> accused many politicians of working with criminals and was known for his outspoken attacks on them.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-ChicagoMayoral     03-05 0758</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chicago Mayoral,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Mayoral Candidates Have Democratic Roots</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES LITKE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The front-runner for next month's mayoral election is a Democrat, his closest pursuer was a Democrat as recently as December, and the No. 3 man in the race was Democratic county chairman just 18 months ago. An out-of-towner might ask what these guys _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, <PERSON> Alderman </PERSON> <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and former county chairman-turned Republican <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> _ are fighting about? But Chicagoans are n't surprised. `` When you have only one functioning party choosing one candidate, the other guys get blocked, then frustrated, then go off on their own and call themselves something else,'' explains <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Royko </PERSON>, a veteran political observer and columnist for the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, a black, ran as a Democrat when he was elected alderman and is now running for mayor as an independent. <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> entered the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> primary at the last minute as a write-in candidate, and even though he got 80 percent of the white vote in his unsuccessful independent mayoral challenge in 1987, he is regarded as third in the race now. The city's last Republican mayor was <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hale </PERSON> `` Big Bill'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, a three-term mayor so brazen about his alliance with gangsters that his portrait hung in the headquarters of the <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> gang. <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> was eased out in 1931 by <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> `` Pushcart Tony'' <PERSON> Cermak </PERSON>, credited with bringing to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> the modern political machine: a coalition of ethnic voters bound by the principle of self-interest _ everybody gets something. What followed was a succession of politicians as diverse as <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>'s father, the late <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> _ the last of the big-city `` bosses'' who died in 1976 _ and <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, a reformer whose 1983 election as the city's first black mayor and whose death just months into his second term in 1987 altered the course of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. `` If the old man -LRB- <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> -RRB- were alive, there's a lot about the party he would n't recognize, even if his son winds up at the top of it,'' said <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Loyola </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor and author of `` Himself,'' a biography of the elder <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>. `` In his day, a Democrat was a Democrat first and whatever else he was came second.'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> changed that by winning with little more than a single racial bloc, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> said. The town is about 40 percent white, 40 percent black and 20 percent Hispanic and other minorities. `` And what you see now, essentially, are three men _ two white and one black _ relying on the same strategy, trying to do essentially the same thing,'' he added. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s 1983 election came after a racially charged campaign. But his ability to govern fairly eased the fears of many whites who opposed him, and he was re-elected in 1987 with significantly less strife. The younger <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> last week became the first white to oust an incumbent black mayor in a major <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> city by defeating <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, who filled in after <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s death. But their primary campaign was surprisely free of rancor and appeals to race, considering the racially split voting. <PERSON> Daley </PERSON>, 46, three-term <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> state's attorney, received significant support from liberals and an emerging Hispanic bloc, though the lion's share of his support came from many of the same white ethnics who made his father mayor for 21 years. Black voter turnout was depressed, according to some estimates, by as much as 20 percent in wards that had proved crucial to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s victories. Most political observers laid the blame for that at the feet of <LOCATION> Evans </LOCATION>, 45, who waged a long and often-bitter battle with <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> to be recognized among blacks as <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s righful heir. <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> was elected acting mayor after <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s death largely because of the support of white aldermen. `` That split still exists, and that's the reason <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> likely will win April 4,'' said <PERSON> Lu </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON>, an influential black political activist and radio commentator. `` Many, many <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON> supporters are saying that <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> and his allies are the reason for <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>'s loss, and many are saying they will not vote for <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>. `` People are saying <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> will split the white vote with <PERSON> Daley </PERSON> ... but I say <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON> wo n't have much of an impact. Why should white Democrats cross over and vote for <PERSON> Vrdolyak </PERSON>? They've already got their candidate.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleppner </PERSON>, a political science professor and author, put it this way: `` Almost everybody in the city may still think of themselves as Democrats, but now, most of them are black Democrats or white Democrats.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1403EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Germany-USSoldier     03-05 0389</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Germany-US Soldier,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>Officials Questioning U.S. Soldier Thought To Have Defected</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE BOEHMER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military officials questioned an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldier Sunday whose 11-day disappearance led to speculation he had defected to communist <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The officials refused to say what may have prompted the absence of Spec. 4 <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peri </PERSON>, who they say had access to classified information. They said he returned a portable computer that was missing from the 11th Armored Cavalry Regiment intelligence office where he worked. <PERSON> Peri </PERSON>, 21, of <LOCATION> Laguna </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Niguel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, `` returned voluntarily to his unit'' about 5 p.m. Saturday, according to Lt. Col. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gauci </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gauci </PERSON> said <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> was in military police custody in <LOCATION> Fulda </LOCATION>, 65 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> made no statement about where he had been, said Lt. Col. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Dye </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s 5th Corps in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. `` He -LRB- Peri -RRB- is being questioned. He has been given legal counsel,'' <PERSON> Dye </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dye </PERSON> said <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> returned to his unit in civilian clothes and appeared to be in good health. <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> disappeared Feb. 21 from the 11th Armored Cavalry Regiment in <LOCATION> Fulda </LOCATION>. The disappearance baffled military officials, and speculation on his absence ranged from possible foul play to defection to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. Some officials speculated he had defected after a military vehicle he signed out was found Feb. 23 near the town of <LOCATION> Obersuhl </LOCATION>, at the East German border. Obersuhl is in a remote rural area 35 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Fulda </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials said <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> had an excellent record as a soldier, and they did not rule out foul play or illness as the reason for his absence. <PERSON> Peri </PERSON> worked as an electronics warfare signal specialist. He was responsible for operating equipment that detects enemy radar and other signals. He has been stationed in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since March 1988. <PERSON> Gauci </PERSON> said <PERSON> Peri </PERSON>'s relatives in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> had been notified of his return. In March 1987, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Pvt. <PERSON> Wade </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON>, 22, of <LOCATION> Riverside </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, defected with his West German girlfriend to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> returned to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> in November 1987 and was court-martialed as a deserter. He was given a bad conduct discharge after being found guilty of a lesser charge of being absent without leave.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1411EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-SuicidePact     03-05 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-Suicide Pact,0561</SECOND>
<HEAD>Girls' Suicide Attempt Becomes Political, Social Issue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KELLY TUNNEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A suicide pact by four girls who took rat poison so their parents could lavish everything on their brother has shocked Koreans and raised questions about male chauvinism and the plight of the poor. The girls, aged 6 to 13, were found unconscious Feb. 27 after they took the poison. The youngest died immediately, but doctors said the other three would recover. <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Soon-mi </PERSON>, the eldest daughter, told police the girls made the suicide pact because they wanted to save their parents money and ensure their 3-year-old brother would have the best education possible. The incident has shocked <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Koreans </LOCATION>, who have sent toys, dolls and more than $ 15,000 worth of donations to the hospital where the three surviving girls were taken. A social organization vowed to pay the girls' school expenses through college, and <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Ok-sook </PERSON>, the wife of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>, sent a letter asking the girls `` not to lose hope.'' Newspaper editorials blamed public policies they said do too little for the poor in a nation of growing prosperity. Education in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> is free up until the end of the sixth grade, and the oldest daughter was due to enter seventh grade. Educating four daughters would have been a major expense, especially since most Korean women have little hope of finding good jobs in the male-dominated society. `` It's regrettable and shocking that the male-first idea was planted deep inside the minds of such young girls,'' said <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Kye-kyung </PERSON>, publisher of the weekly Women's News, a leading advocate of women's rights. `` We still live in a society dominated by men, despite our economic success,'' she said, `` This is a typical case that gives us a lesson. It may lead to a movement against prejudice and restrictions on women's rights.'' Opposition politician <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Dae-jung </PERSON> visited the girls' parents at the hospital and said, `` I am grief-stricken. I feel a great burden as a politician, and I will focus on ways to promote the livelihood of alienated people.'' The girls' father, <PERSON> Yang </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-bun </PERSON>, 44, is a factory worker who supports the family on the equivalent of $ 362 a month. Police said the family lived in a small two-room apartment. `` The deprivation of these children forced to resort to suicide contrasts sharply with their affluent peers whose birthdays and graduation from schoool are often celebrated at posh hotels by expensive feasts, `` said an editorial in the <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Herald </LOCATION>. It said the incident `` has turned into a socially and politically explosive issue.'' Financial donations to the family included $ 700 from a grieving father whose daughter was killed recently in a traffic accident and $ 3.60 from a first-grader. The hospital said the family had dozens of hospital visitors, including Cabinet ministers. The <ORGANIZATION> Korea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said a composition written by the eldest daughter, Soon-mi, ought to move citizens to reflect on the tragedy. Soon-mi wrote that when a neighbor visited to collect money for the poor, `` I searched my pocket and found a 500 won coin -LRB- worth 74 cents -RRB-. I was supposed to buy school things. But I put it into the charity pot, hoping that the money would be used for helping the needy.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890305-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-05-89 1422EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BabyKilled     03-05 0439</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Baby Killed,0454</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-Ager Acquitted In Killing Of Baby</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Note contents.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANITOWOC, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
