<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 2328EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Congress-Drugs 2ndLd-Writethru a0796 09-26 0587</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress-Drugs, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0796,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Negotiators Agree To $9.4 Billion War On Drugs</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 3-5 pvs bgng: ``Republicans said,'' with new grafs
3-5 bgng: ``As part,'' to update with drug package nailed down, passage
of two appropriations bills. Should stand for AMs.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senator negotiators agreed Tuesday to boost the war on drugs to $ 9.4 billion, capping a week of talks with the White House and lifting a Republican blockade that stalled action on four money bills. `` It seems that everything is worked out so we have an agreed-upon package,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, the chief <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> As part of their deal, <ORGANIZATION> Republicans </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> agreed that later this year, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> would consider elements of a crime-fighting package unveiled by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in June but dormant since then. With the agreement in hand, the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed two of four appropriations bills that had been stalled by Republicans for more than a week in a move to gain leverage in bargaining over the drug package. Within an hour the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed a $ 14.4 billion foreign aid measure and a $ 157.4 billion bill for labor, health and education programs. The White House indicated its approval of the agreement earlier in the day before it was cemented. Presidential press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the outlines of the plan appeared `` consistent with our objectives.'' `` We do expect to accept this arrangement and hopefully we can get on with implementing the drug plan,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. The negotiations began early last week after Democrats proposed to add $ 2.2 billion to the $ 7.9 billion proposed by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in his Sept. 5 address to the nation on the scourge of drugs. They said that education, treatment and prevention programs were underfunded in the administration's battle plan for fighting the drug war. The freshly minted package funds the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's initial $ 7.9 billion war on drugs plus $ 400 million in other crime-fighting money requested by the president in June as well as $ 200 million for juvenile justice programs and the $ 900 million boost that had been the center of week-long negotiations The $ 900 million would provide $ 100 million for law enforcement and the rest for prevention, education and treatment, the `` demand side'' of the drug war that Democrats say was underfunded in the president's original plan. `` Without building up the demand side, then we're really caught fighting the drug war with one hand behind us,'' <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> said. Actually, the $ 200 million for juvenile justice already was contained in a bill to provide money for the State, <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Departments </ORGANIZATION>. Moving them into the drug package, raised the total added by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> to $ 1.1 billion, exactly half the amount that <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> initially had sought. The increase would be funded through reductions in other spending programs that would be 0.43 percent if applied across-the-board. Under the plan, however, appropriations subcommittees would be able to pick and choose among programs, allowing some to escape the full brunt of the cuts. Many elements of the president's crime-fighting package are contained in the drug strategy, but some highly controversial elements are missing and the administration has been pushing for action on them. They include applying the death penalty to a wider range of crimes than under current law. Another key provision would place limits on the number of appeals that could be filed by certain prisoners, and a third would ease restrictions on how police and prosecutors obtain certain kinds of evidence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 2330EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HandicappedProtest 1stLd-Writethru a0751 09-26 0679</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Handicapped Protest, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0751,0693</SECOND>
<HEAD>Protesters Seeking Bus Wheelchair Lifts Occupy Federal Building</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 8-9, `He said...', to UPDATE with protesters apparently
leaving building by late Tuesday. Picks up 10th graf, `The protest...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AX4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICIA WALSH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Handicapped protesters who occupied a federal building for two days won a pledge of government support Tuesday, but failed to win an order requiring wheelchair lifts on all new public buses bought with federal funds. The <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> `` can not issue a summary order commanding immediate access including wheelchair access for all transit,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON>, chief counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mass </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, who met with the protest leaders. `` We would if we could.'' But <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> said DOT officials and the protesters had agreed on three points: _ <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> will be urged to meet promptly with disabled activists to ensure a `` principle of accessibility'' until <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passes the Americans with Disabilities Act _ The protesters will be allowed to continue a `` symbolic presence'' at the <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> building in downtown <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> _ Officials will relay to <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> the protesters' concern that new rules for handicapped accessibility to air travel are not being drafted quickly enough `` This agreement by no means resolves the problem of access; it just brings us a step closer,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, 38, of <LOCATION> Alpharetta </LOCATION>, one of the protest leaders who met with <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> and other DOT officials. He said he did n't know if the protesters would leave the building, where they blocked elevators and entrance doors earlier Tuesday. But by late Tuesday, it appeared the protesters had left; none were visible inside the building. `` We may stay here through Thursday, or we may just leave a sticker on the wall. There could be a constant vigil at the building, or we could all leave,'' he said earlier. The protest by members of ADAPT, or American Disabled for <ORGANIZATION> Accessible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, began Monday when <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to address the convention of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. At least two dozen protesters chained themselves to doors or blocked exits with their wheelchairs Monday. Authorities attempted to eject several protesters from the building Monday evening, but President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> intervened and let them spend the night inside rather than send them out into the rain. On Tuesday, the protesters made good on a threat to block entrances to the building's main level at noon if their demands were not met by then. About two hours later, while federal officials met with protest leaders outside the building, about 160 chanting, singing activists kept federal employees and visitors from using 12 of the 14 main-floor elevators by blocking them with wheelchairs. Security officers were able to keep two elevators open by using plant stands to keep wheelchairs away from them. About 100 protesters spent Monday night in the building, eating take-out food and sleeping under blankets provided by attendants. Early Tuesday, a group of <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> bartenders brought them coffee and doughnuts. `` It was an uncomfortable night,'' said <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, 39, of <LOCATION> Salt </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. But he added: `` The misery that we're going through is worth it if we get what we want. All we are asking for is a lift on every bus so that we can be more independent. We're not asking for a million dollars.'' But government officials have estimated that putting wheelchair lifts on all new public buses would cost $ 90 million a year. ADAPT also has been trying to force the installation of lifts on all new buses through the courts. In <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, a federal appeals court panel backed their lawsuit, saying federal law requires lifts on new buses. But in July, the full 3rd <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> overturned that ruling, saying government officials did not have to put lifts on all buses if they thought some other method of serving the handicapped would be better. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Churchill </PERSON>, an attorney for ADAPT, said the group was waiting to see what <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> did on the bus issue before deciding whether to appeal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 2345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-FilmInstitute     09-26 0311</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Film Institute,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Attends Gala For American Film Institute</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER CONNELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> joined a galaxy of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> celebrities Tuesday night in paying tribute to the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> on the 24th anniversary of the federal arts legislation that gave it birth. Eyeing the black-tie crowd that included actors <PERSON> Charlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heston </PERSON>, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Fairbanks </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Travolta </PERSON> and <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Reeve </PERSON> and actresses <PERSON> Marlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> and <PERSON> Brooke </PERSON> <PERSON> Shields </PERSON>, master of ceremonies <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Valenti </PERSON> crowed: `` Welcome to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, the entertainment capital of the world.'' <PERSON> Valenti </PERSON>, the longtime head of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> and onetime <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide to <PERSON> Lyndon </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, added, `` There are things that happen here that a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> scriptwriter would give his life to be able to put down.'' It was <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> who signed the legislation on Sept. 29, 1965, creating the National Endowments for the Arts and the Humanities, which two years later spawned the independent, non-profit <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. The institute has been a leader in efforts to preserve motion pictures and television, and trains young directors through a program in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> joined in the entertainment at the gala at the National Building Museum, following a string of celebrities who repeated famous movie lines. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, looking across the ballroom to his wife <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> at a table 30 yards away, repeated <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogart </PERSON>'s toast from `` Casablanca'': `` Here's looking at ya, kid!'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called film `` the mirror of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> ... and also in a sense the conscience of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>.'' He cited such films as `` Coal Miner's Daughter,'' `` Hoosiers,'' and several recent movies that portrayed drugs in a bad lights, including `` Lean On Me,'' `` Clean and Sober'' and `` Dancing As Fast As I Can. `` I want to thank the film industry for helping stop this terrible threat to our kids. ... I welcome your leadership,'' said the president.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Drugs 2ndLd-Writethru a0406 09-26 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Drugs, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0406,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alleged Source of TV Drugs Arrested</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: INSERTS graf 5: ``U.S. Magistrate,'' with hearing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> teen-ager was arrested Tuesday on charges of selling the crack cocaine that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> displayed on television to illustrate the seriousness of the nation's drug problems. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, 18, was indicted earlier in the day by a federal grand jury on four counts of unlawfully distributing crack and one count of using a telephone to help arrange an alleged sale. The alleged distribution started in April, on one occasion near <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> in July, according to the indictment. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> was picked up at his home in southeast <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> by city police and <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> agents, said <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Cornelius </PERSON> <PERSON> Dougherty </PERSON>. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Magistrate <PERSON> Pattrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Attridge </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> held without bond pending another hearing Wednesday. In a Sept. 5 televised speech, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> held up a clear plastic bag containing a handful of crack nuggets and said they had been seized across the street from the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> a few days previously. The alleged dealer was lured to <LOCATION> Lafayette </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> _ not one of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s drug markets _ four days before by undercover drug agents after <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> staffers asked for a sample from the vicinity of the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to show that dealing could happen anywhere. Officials of the <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> said they had planned to make the purchase a few blocks away before the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> request. The transaction with an undercover <ORGANIZATION> DEA </ORGANIZATION> agent was photographed, but the dealer was not taken into custody then because agents hoped he would sell a larger amount later and identify his supply organization, officials said. A planned arrest last week fell through when the suspect did not show up.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Philippines-US 5thLd-Writethru a0829 09-26 0831</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines-US, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0829,0853</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gunmen Kill Two Americans Near Base Hours Before Quayle Arrives</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES thruout with Quayle proposing December talks on bases.
EDITS to conform. No pickup. ^LaserPhotos MLA7, MLA9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EILEEN GUERRERO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen believed to be communist rebels ambushed and killed two American civilians working at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military base Tuesday, shortly before Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> arrived to discuss the future of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military installations in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. On Wednesday, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> condemmed the killings as `` cowardly murders'' and said the slayings will `` only serve to strengthen'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> support for President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. Meeting with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> later, he proposed that talks begin in December on extending <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military bases in the country. Police arrested at least 15 people on Wednesday for joining rallies protesting <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s visit. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials banned non-essential travel between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases by the 40,000 American troops, civilian employees and military dependents in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. There is growing opposition among Filipinos to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases. Following his hour-long meeting with Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> told reporters he delivered a letter from President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> suggesting the talks on the future of the six bases, whose lease expires in September 1991. The ambush victims were employees of <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, which contracts to maintain an electronic warfare training range at Camp O'Donnell. The camp is a U.S.-run facility about 50 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> and 12 miles from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Clark Air Base. <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aerospace </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> identified the victims as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, 45, and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Buchner </PERSON>, 44. He said both were retired from the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. Their hometowns were not available. The Americans slowed their car as they approached a dump truck and a jeep blocking a highway near <LOCATION> Capas </LOCATION>, 60 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, police said. Six men jumped out of the jeep and riddled their car with gunfire, according to police Lt. <PERSON> Pepito </PERSON> <PERSON> Pimentel </PERSON>. The assailants then opened the car door and pumped bullets into the victims, <PERSON> Pimentel </PERSON> said. The attack occurred about 5 p.m. `` We deplore this senseless and cowardly act of terrorism,'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` Acts like this will not deter us in our resolve to support the democratic government in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>.'' Col. <PERSON> Florentino </PERSON> <PERSON> Amorabon </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constabulary </ORGANIZATION> in central <LOCATION> Luzon </LOCATION> island, said the assassins were believed to be members of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, which operates in the area. In April, rebels killed <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Col. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Rowe </PERSON> as he was driving to the headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assistance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Quezon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, near <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. In October 1987, rebels killed three Americans in simultaneous attacks outside Clark Air Base. Also Tuesday, gunmen killed a member of Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s presidential guard, about a mile from where the president met with <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> on Wednesday The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> operates <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Subic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> naval base and four smaller installations in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, but there are increased calls for an end to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military presence. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has offered new talks on the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases but refuses to say whether she will support an extension. Any new agreement must be ratified by two-thirds of the 23-member Philippine <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, where opposition to the bases is strong. In a statement released Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> called <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s visit `` part of the intensifying pressure by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on the Aquino regime'' to extend the bases. `` This pressure covers all aspects, economic, political and military,'' the rebels said. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is overextending legal means and is using dirty and underhanded tactics to achieve its ends.'' As <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> arrived from <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> Tuesday evening, hundreds of leftists burned his effigy and an American flag while chanting `` Bases out!, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> go home!'' In a speech Wednesday to a business group, <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> deplored the killings of the two Americans. `` It should go without saying that these cowardly murders deserve the strong condemnation of all civilized men and women,'' <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said. `` The people of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, like the the people of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, are sickened by the acts of vicious terrorists who wish to drown freedom in the blood of innocent men and women.'' Two hours before <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s arrival, about 150 members of the League of Filipino Students and the Youth for Nationalism and Democracy reached the airport terminal and began a noisy demonstration against the visit. After negotiations with police, the group agreed to pull back about a half mile away. Police estimated the crowd grew to nearly 1,000 by the time <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> arrived. Earlier, nine policemen were injured and nine students arrested when security forces broke up a rally at <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Adamson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, officials said. Also Tuesday, suspected rebels killed Capt. <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Daileg </PERSON>, a staff officer of the <ORGANIZATION> Presidential </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, in an ambush in the city's <LOCATION> Pandacan </LOCATION> district. Police and troops have been on alert in the capital following bombings in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION> that have killed two people and injured 16 since Sept. 16.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0036EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PeopleDrain     09-26 0634</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-People Drain,0653</SECOND>
<HEAD>East Germans Coping With Holes in Work Force</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Tuesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 With thousands of East Germans going <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in the past few months, those staying behind have found themselves without the services of some important people _ from the village baker, to the town plumber, to medical specialists. There are visible signs of the `` people drain'' in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. An official sign on a shuttered bar called `` Restoration 1900'' says the establishment has received `` permission to close'' because the manager is ill. Local residents say that in truth, the manager fled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> two months ago `` An operator of three other bars in this area also went West a while back. He's since been replaced,'' said a middle-age East German walking past the bar on the city's Husemannstrasse. A vegetable shop a few blocks away is shuttered as well, and residents say its owner also has gone to the West. East German reform activist <PERSON> Jens </PERSON> <PERSON> Reich </PERSON> says his eye doctor has fled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` I fear my dentist's gone as well,'' said <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>, an <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> founder of the fledgling New Forum pro-democracy group. About 100,000 East Germans have either fled or emigrated legally to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> this year, the greatest flood of East German refugees since the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall went up in 1961. More than 17,500 of them have gone through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> since that country opened its Western border to East Germans Sept. 10. The refugees say they left their homeland because they could no longer bear the lack of democratic freedoms and because they want better lives in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. The exodus has produced a new rash of demands for political and economic reform among many East Germans who remain behind. Within two weeks of the exodus, <PERSON> Reich </PERSON>'s group collected signatures of more than 2,000 citizens supporting its pro-democracy demands. Church officials in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> have intensified their calls for democratic change as well. They say leaving the country is no way to change it. `` Someone who is in <LOCATION> Bavaria </LOCATION> can not be of service to a patient at the Catholic hospital in <LOCATION> Erfurt </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' East German Roman Catholic Bishop <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanke </PERSON> has said. Sources within the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the drain of medical personnel is so severe in the district of <LOCATION> Suhl </LOCATION> that doctors there have been forbidden to travel out of the country. Officials have not released any figures on how the exodus has affected medical care or any other professions or businesses. The West German Frankfurter Rundschau newspaper said Sept. 18 it was told by church officials a number of hospitals have had to replace employees ranging from student nurses to chief physicians. The refugees who have fled West in the past few months are mostly young people who left behind good jobs, and in many cases promising careers. According to a study released Sept. 12 by <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s Ministry for Inner-German Relations, the refugees worked in industry, medicine and other service-sector areas, crafts, administration and education <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> has a population of 16.6 million. No one has said the refugee exodus means economic disaster, but the Communist leadership has acknowledged it is causing problems. Residents across the country have reported that some department stores are operating with drastically reduced staffs, many gas stations are shortening their work days, and other establishments are closing down completely. The <PERSON> Frankfurter </PERSON> <PERSON> Rundschau </PERSON> said that at times, cynical humor takes over when those left behind talk about employees who have gone West. `` A hairdresser in <LOCATION> Erfurt </LOCATION> coolly tells a customer: ` So, you want to make an appointment with <PERSON> Bettina </PERSON>? Then you'd better call <LOCATION> Passau </LOCATION> or make a complaint to -LRB- West German Chancellor -RRB- <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>,''' said <PERSON> Rundschau </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FrogCrossing     09-26 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Frog Crossing,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mayor Has Solution to Frog-Crossing Sign Thefts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STEVENS POINT, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The city leaped at a chance to put its `` Frog Crossing'' signs back up, and the mayor even thinks he's figured out a way to keep souvenir hunters from slipping away with them `` I am going to have a T-shirt made of the frog-crossing sign,'' Mayor <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> said after the signs were re-posted last week. `` Maybe if we get people to buy T-shirts, they wo n't steal the sign.'' The two signs have been missing since shortly after they were erected in July 1987 on a stretch of road through the <LOCATION> Schmeeckle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reserve </LOCATION>. Suspicious minds linked the signs' disappearance with the return of students that year to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wisconsin-Stevens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION>. The signs were posted along two ramps that were cut in the curb to help frogs and other small animals cross the road. A city worker came up with the design, featuring four frogs in various stages of leaping. Recently, one of the original signs was recovered and repaired, and officials decided to give it another try. `` The general reaction is that folks are glad the sign is back up,'' <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> said. `` The real purpose was to highlight that there is a nature preserve.'' When the first signs disappeared so quickly, official decided it would be pointless to keep putting them up in a battle with souvenir-hunters. This time, T-shirts are n't the only deterrent to theft, <PERSON> Schultz </PERSON> said: `` They welded the bolts this time.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0035EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NBC-Colombia     09-26 0181</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-NBC-Colombia,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC Buys, Airs TV Footage of Mercenaries in Colombia</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` NBC Nightly News'' aired videotape pictures Monday of what it said were British and Australian mercenaries teaching private soldiers for Colombian drug lords how to kill with sophisticated weapons and equipment. The footage was taken by one of the mercenaries, Australian <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tagley </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> correspondent <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> reported. He gave no further details about <PERSON> Tagley </PERSON>'s background. <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> said 11 highly paid British and Australian mercenaries, `` experts in assassinations and explosives,'' had gone to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. He quoted <PERSON> Tagley </PERSON> as saying they had been told they were being brought to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to fight communist guerrillas, but when they arrived there they realized they actually were working for the drug cartel. NBC News paid <PERSON> Tagley </PERSON> for his videotape, said an <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> McQuay </PERSON>. She declined to say how much. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> on Aug. 21 broadcast video footage of what it said were Israelis teaching the drug soldiers. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> has denied that the Israelis, which Israeli newspapers said were former military officers, did anything wrong.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Lebanon-Refugees Bjt   09-26 0755</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lebanon-Refugees, Bjt,0778</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beirutis Flock Home, Glad But Impoverished After Refugee Ordeal</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RODEINA KENAAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A million refugees have flooded back into <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> after six months of fighting, many impoverished by their ordeal and some fearful lest the savage shelling flares up again. Long lines of cars began streaming into the shattered capital within minutes of the announcement Friday by <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> leader Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> that he was accepting an Arab League cease-fire. Hundreds more Lebanese booked passage for the three-hour ferry crossing from <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> to the Christian port of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION>, while others flew into the newly reopened <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> airport. The six months of fighting killed at least 929 people and wounded 2,741. <PERSON> Issam </PERSON> <PERSON> Baydoun </PERSON>, a Sunni Moslem bank employee who fled during the shelling battles that pitted <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s mainly Christian fighters against <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its Moslem militia allies, was among the returnees. `` I have spent most of my 30 years' savings during the 2 -LCB- months of forced migration to the south,'' said the 55-year-old father of two. <PERSON> Baydoun </PERSON> said he fled his <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> home in a seven-story apartment building in the heavily shelled district of <PERSON> Ras </PERSON> <PERSON> el-Nabeh </PERSON> in July, when `` things could not be borne anymore.'' `` My wife had started taking sedatives,'' he said. `` My daughter screamed every time a shell crashed nearby or because of the sound of a rocket passing overhead.'' Just like many other west Beirutis, <PERSON> Baydoun </PERSON> headed south. He rented a two-room house for $ 900 a month in <LOCATION> Iqlim </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kharroub </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Chouf </LOCATION> mountains. `` In all, I spent $ 3,000 in only 75 days of exile,'' he said. `` Believe me, now that we're back I ca n't afford to restore my shell-pocked house.'' Asked whether he would be able to rent another house in the south if fighting broke out again, <PERSON> Baydoun </PERSON> said: `` I am a conscientious employee and have a good reputation at the bank. The bank manager might be willing to lend me some money on temporary basis. But to tell you the truth, God knows when I will be able to pay him back.'' He was glad to be back, albeit impoverished, saying `` there's no place like home.'' The Baydouns' neighborhood is in a section of west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> where <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its allies installed their advance artillery batteries. On the opposite side are <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s troops as well as Christian militants from the Lebanese Forces. East Beirut residents also breathed relief when the Arab league commitee announced the opening of all crossings linking both sectors of the capital, the lifting of the 6-month-old blockade of the Christian heartland and the opening of the airport. `` May God guide them to the right path,'' said <PERSON> Samira </PERSON> <PERSON> Gobril </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Maronite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> housewife who expressed hope that the leaders of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s factions would work together for a durable peace. `` May God keep utmost in their minds the plight of the poor population.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Gobril </PERSON>, 38, and mother of an 11-year-old boy and an 8-year-old girl, lives in the frequently battered Christian area of <LOCATION> Ashrafieh </LOCATION> a few miles from the Green Line that divides east from west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. She had fled to the fashionable mountain resort of <LOCATION> Faraya </LOCATION>, 20 miles to the northeast. `` This time we could afford it,'' she added, but `` it'll take my husband five years of hard work to recoup the amount of money we have spent during the last four months.'' Police said at least 1 million refugees who fled <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> have returned since Friday. <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> took the brunt of the shelling, forcing all but 150,000 of its remaining 1.5 million people to flee. Some of those that did not travel to safer areas of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> took the ferry to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, either to wait out the fighting or to apply for American, Canadian, Australian and other visas as a gateway to a new life away from their country, shattered by 14 years of civil war. Estimates vary. Immigration officials in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> say about 20,000 Lebanese are on the small east <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> island whose population numbers just 691,000. But relief agency officials working to ease the refugees' plight said the actual number of Lebanese in <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> probably reached 30,000 at the height of the fighting and perhaps more. The Christian refugees' only exit to the outside world has been through a hydrofoil ferry service from the port of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Larnaca </LOCATION> on the south <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> coast. Moslems, too, have been fleeing to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, though they are still a minority of the Lebanese refugees on the island.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     09-26 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0598</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Lite Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FLOODWOOD, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Liubakka </PERSON> is a newcomer to politics, but he figures he's bound to get a hefty vote in next year's gubernatorial race That's because he's running as founder of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Apathetic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. With a 60 percent voter turnout expected in the 1990 election, <LOCATION> Liubakka </LOCATION> can claim the other 40 percent of the electorate as constituents. `` They wo n't vote, and a ` no' vote is a vote for me,'' the 36-year-old contractor said recently. The unofficial party _ it's known as <ORGANIZATION> NAP </ORGANIZATION> _ even has a mascot: a battered eagle. The bird's neck is longer than most eagles' because it's been stretched a few times. Its left wing is clipped from giving away so many handouts. Its tail feathers are lost. On the rare occasions <PERSON> Liubakka </PERSON> removes his tongue from his cheek, he'll betray serious worries about the state of the body politic. `` Our intention is to slap everybody in the face with ignorance,'' the unregistered candidate said, `` and hopefully this blunt hint will get them out to vote more.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DUBLIN, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The northern third of the country will have more snow than usual but it'll be a mild winter for most of the country, says no less an authority than the Old Farmer's Almanac. <PERSON> Abe </PERSON> <PERSON> Weatherwise </PERSON>, who claims 80 percent accuracy in `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s oldest continuously published periodical,'' predicts a white Christmas in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> The 198th edition of the 224-page almanac hits the newsstands and supermarkets this week with its familiar planting and tide tables, anecdotes and other tidbits, such as 100 ways how to avoid untimely death. -LRB- No. 49, avoid combing hair in the dark; No. 77, never whistle in a coal mine. -RRB- <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, a collective pseudonym, says the almanac's predictions are `` based on state-of-the art analysis of recurring solar cycles.'' He predicts that a cold, wet and snowy spring in the North will be balanced by warm, dry spring weather west of the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>. The summer of 1990, says <PERSON> Abe </PERSON>, will be hot and dry in many areas east of the <ORGANIZATION> Rockies </ORGANIZATION>. In addition to weather predictions, the almanac has advertisements for hernia appliances, secrets of winning lotteries and rules of thumb for rhubarb pie. It also advises that cows and pigs bred for leanness will boost the popularity of red meat and inflation will run at 6 percent. Among other predictions: the return of the 4-inch-wide necktie for men, short hair for women and lower prices for videocassette recorders.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>POMONA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most everyone has heard of killer bees and killer whales _ but what about killer snails? One man is determined to prove that the combative cousins of common garden snails are the answer to eliminating the slow-moving but voracious plant munchers. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrie </PERSON>, 34, sells a hostile snail breed that he claims will prey on the garden pests. `` It's the tough new snail on the block,'' <PERSON> Harrie </PERSON> said the other day from his demonstration booth at the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION>. The shell-less critters ambush garden snails, following their slime trails and attacking them when they lay their eggs, <PERSON> Harrie </PERSON> said. The bloodthirsty snails, known to scientists as Rumina decollata, usually leave their victims mortally wounded, rather than killing them outright, he said. <PERSON> Harrie </PERSON>, who sells the attack snails for $ 20 per 100, claims they're too slow-moving to move from the garden to the house, and pose no danger to children and pets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0003EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 3rdLd-Writethru a0402 09-26 1006</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0402,1039</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Two Killed When Bomb Explodes in Hilton Hotel; Drug War Widens</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 13 grafs to UPDATE with police chief's comments,
owner of hotel, room where blast occurred, doctors at convention. Picks
up graf 12 pvs, `A leading ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A bomb exploded Monday night in the <ORGANIZATION> Cartagena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION> on the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> and reports said two doctors were killed and another was wounded, the chief of the police in that coastal resort said. Another bomb exploded at a <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION> bank Monday night, injuring a passer-by, Col. <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview. A fireman at the hotel told a Colombian TV news crew the blast ripped through the sixth floor of the <ORGANIZATION> Cartagena </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hilton </ORGANIZATION>, whose majority owner is the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tourism </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. The bomb exploded in room 642, the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> radio chain <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> said in a report from the scene. The two doctors who were killed were attending a medical convention at the hotel, <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> said. Their identities were not immediately available. The one who was injured was also thought to be Colombian, witnesses told <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Herrera </PERSON> said no one had claimed responsibility for the bombs. However, Colombian government security forces have presumed that scores of bombs that have exploded in major <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> cities in the last month have been the work of drug traffickers who declared war on the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government. Including the two bombs in <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION> and one Monday night in the capital of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, there have been 110 bombings, killing eight persons and injuring 132 persons. The Hilton was evacuating the approximately 1,500 guests to other hotels in <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> said, quoting its correspondent, who filed a report by radio telephone with <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>. Thousands of Americans, Canadians and other foreigners flock to <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION> each year. A group of Canadian tourists at the <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION> airport last week told the wife of an AP reporter they were cutting their vacations short and going home because the <ORGANIZATION> Canadian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> warned them of the war possibly spreading to <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION>. Police told the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> the third bomb was at a billing office of the government electric company in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, but that no one was reported injured. It was the first time bombs hit <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION> since drug traffickers declared war on the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government last month. A leading presidential candidate was quoted earlier Monday as saying <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> may have to legalize drugs in order to fight the powerful cartels waging war on the government. Also Monday, two politicians said the government should negotiate with drug lords. Representatives of the nation's 4,600 judges were to meet with the acting justice minister, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemos </PERSON> <PERSON> Simmonds </PERSON>. The judges threatened Sunday to go on strike unless <PERSON> Simmonds </PERSON> promised them better protection from drug cartels, who persistently threaten their lives. Since 1981, about 50 judges and 170 judicial employees have been killed, mostly by drug traffickers. <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Runkel </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials sent 100 bulletproof vests and other security items to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> last week to help protect judges. He said it was the responsibility of <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> officials to distribute the items. Four bombs exploded Sunday night in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, but there were no injuries, national police said. Sen. <PERSON> Ernesto </PERSON> <PERSON> Samper </PERSON>, seeking the government <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s nomination for the presidential election in March, said of the drug war: `` If the repressive action fails, the road left is legalization of drugs. <PERSON> Samper </PERSON> made the comment in an interview published Monday by the <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republica </ORGANIZATION>. He is the first serious presidential candidate to suggest legalizing drugs. The government began its crackdown on the drug cartels when leading presidential candidate <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Galan </PERSON> was assassinated Aug. 18 at a <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> political rally. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>, who by law can not run for re-election, said he would extradite drug lords to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, prompting the cartels to declare war on the government. There have been reports the traffickers are willing to pay billions of dollars to get the government to end its crackdown, but <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> has refused to negotiate. The mayor of the city of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON>, said Monday that `` after this war is over and there are many dead ... we are going to end up at the negotiating table talking with the drug traffickers.'' `` The dialogue would be Christian because it would avoid many deaths,'' the mayor said in an interview with <PERSON> Caracol </PERSON>. Also coming out Monday in favor of negotiations was the president of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION>, or lower chamber of parliament, <PERSON> Norberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Morales </PERSON>. `` We have to open the way toward this initiative because we are bleeding to death -LRB- and -RRB- our economy is in ruins,'' <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION>. On Saturday, <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> said two of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s major drug trafficking suspects had called him with an offer to negotiate with the government. He said he passed the information along to <LOCATION> Barco </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Pablo </PERSON> <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gonzalo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> offered to invest millions of dollars from their cocaine profits in Colombian industry if a truce is reached, <PERSON> Morales </PERSON> said. Government officials have said in the past that drug traffickers apparently invest the bulk of their money outside <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Escobar </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> <PERSON> Gacha </PERSON> are on the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s list of most wanted drug-trafficking suspects. They are the strongest members of the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cocaine cartel, which is said to supply 80 percent of the cocaine reaching the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The traffickers have made earlier offers. Recently, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> narcotics official with the embassy in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> said in an interview that the traffickers want pardons so they can emerge from years of hiding. In return, the official said, the traffickers apparently offered to move their operations to other countries, possibly <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. Also, he said, the traffickers suggested they would finance much of the government's 30-year-old war against leftist guerrillas. The biggest offer from the traffickers came in 1984, when the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel offered to pay off <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s foreign debt, then about $ 10 billion, in exchange for amnesty. The government refused.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Bommarito     09-26 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Bommarito,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former President of United Rubber Workers Union Dead at 74</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AKRON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rubber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> for 15 years, died of cancer Monday at <ORGANIZATION> Akron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. He was 74. <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>, moved to the <LOCATION> Akron </LOCATION> area in 1966 to become president of the Akron-based international union. Known as `` The Bomber,'' a nickname he earned after his tour of duty in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> as a Marine during World War II, <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> was a high-energy president of the <ORGANIZATION> URW </ORGANIZATION> who saw the union through a stormy four-month strike in 1976 against the major rubber companies. When <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> retired in 1981, the <ORGANIZATION> URW </ORGANIZATION> had 140,000 members, diminished by a number of plant closings from a peak of 190,500 in 1974. Dues-paying members now number about 100,000. <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> enlisted in the <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> in early 1942. When he returned to his factory job in <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> after his tour of duty, he was elected to the executive board of <ORGANIZATION> URW </ORGANIZATION> Local 101. By 1957, <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> was president of the 6,000-member local, which is now defunct. In 1960, <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> was elected an international vice president. Six years later, he was elected to the union's top post. <PERSON> Bommarito </PERSON> is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Dorothy </PERSON>, and several nieces and nephews.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Hugo-NorthCarolina 1stLd-Writethru a0689 09-26 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hugo-North Carolina, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0689,0517</SECOND>
<HEAD>Charlotte Goes Back to Work After Hugo, Many Still Powerless</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to reflect that Hugo was downgraded to tropical
storm when it hit N.C., UPDATE with Bush disaster declaration, additional
water outages, price gouging, power company workers hurt; pick up 8th graf
pvs, `The loss ...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Hugo, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RALEIGH, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Commuters struggled through rush hour with no traffic lights in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> and power companies rebuilt electric systems Monday, four days after Hurricane Hugo's remnants struck. Also on Monday, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> declared four inland <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> counties disaster areas eligible for federal assistance. `` The damage has been extensive, and the progress has been slower than expected,'' said <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Maher </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. He said it would be a week or two before full service is restored. About 280,000 Duke customers in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> were still without electricity, including <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, the utility's board chairman. `` I feel like I'm in good company,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. Preliminary damage estimates for hard-hit <LOCATION> Mecklenburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> rose to $ 336 million, but officials said the damage is so extensive it is still difficult to gauge. <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Shook </PERSON>, assistant manager of <LOCATION> Mecklenburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, estimated that 120,000 county residents, mostly in rural areas, remained without water Monday. County agencies, meanwhile, had 250 reports of price gouging. In <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, rural residents who were without water because of the power outages took showers at a high school. Drinking water was distributed from four locations around the county. `` I'm out of power at home myself,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Willis </PERSON>, the county's emergency management coordinator. `` But I have a daughter close by with power, so I can get a shower and she wo n't let me go hungry.'' Two power company workers in <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> were injured Monday when a power line came loose and hit them. One worker was in critical condition and the other was in stable condition, hospital officials said. The loss of electricity made traffic signals useless as <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> workers began their work week. A National Guardsman and a <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> police officer directing traffic at a busy intersection were hospitalized after being struck by a car during the morning rush hour. The police officer was treated for a broken leg, while the guardsman, a member of a military police company from <LOCATION> Greenville </LOCATION>, was listed in stable condition with cuts to his face and thigh. About 550 National Guardsmen are on duty in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. More than 200 <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forestry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> workers, including 56 chain saw crews, were deployed in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Morganton </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, the only coastal county to sustain major damage from Hugo, heavy rain slowed cleanup efforts. `` The rain is hampering us for certain,'' said <PERSON> Cecil </PERSON> <PERSON> Logan </PERSON>, county emergency management coordinator. `` It will delay our major cleanup efforts for at least a day.'' Beach homes were left hanging over the surf all along the county's coastline, with the dune line virtually wiped out in many areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-MetOpens     09-26 0407</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Met Opens,0423</SECOND>
<HEAD>Met Opera Opens with Dream Cast in `Aida'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Metropolitan Opera chose `` Aida'' as its opening night opera and gave it a dream cast. <PERSON> Aprile </PERSON> <PERSON> Millo </PERSON>, heralded as the next great <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON> soprano, sang the title role on Monday night. Not content just to pour out her voice of grandeur, she used shading, held notes and pianissimo and acted the slave to <LOCATION> Amneris </LOCATION> that Aida is. Seldom has a Met Opera Aida been so often on her knees. <PERSON> Placido </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON>, the Radames when this production was new last December, sang Radames again. His voice was beautiful in tone, smooth in production, sometimes ringing, occasionally tense and harder-edged than it formerly was. He does n't scoop up to high notes, as most tenors do, in `` Celeste Aida.'' The final love duet, when both inserted tenderness into their generous-size voices, was thrilling. <PERSON> Dolora </PERSON> <PERSON> Zajick </PERSON>, who made her Met debut last fall, sang a notable Amneris. She's a mezzo soprano but has a delivery like a soprano and a confident stage presence. Some Amnerises are almost unnoticed. When the two were together, this Amneris commanded more attention than Aida. As <PERSON> Aida </PERSON> was subservient, the king's daughter <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON> was regal. Miss <PERSON> Zajick </PERSON>'s voice also conveyed <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON>' love, making her a sympathetic character. <PERSON> Paata </PERSON> <PERSON> Burchuladze </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Tbilisi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S.S.R. </LOCATION>, was making his Met debut as the high priest. <PERSON> Burchuladze </PERSON>, a winner in the 1985 <PERSON> Luciano </PERSON> <PERSON> Pavarotti </PERSON> voice competition in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, has the deep notes and dark sound Americans expect and adore from Russian basses. He has sung `` <PERSON> Boris </PERSON> <PERSON> Godunov </PERSON>'' in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sherrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON> sang <PERSON> Aida </PERSON>'s father with urgency _ he's concerned with the Egypt-Ethiopia war, not with love. <PERSON> Milnes </PERSON> also sang with a beautiful tone, which characterized all the principals. The triumphal entry scene included a couple of horses and, for once in a Met production, no eccentricity. Three young dancers in Act 2 were pleasing. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON> conducted with understanding. The production, by <PERSON> Sonja </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisell </PERSON>, twice uses the device of moving a set by elevator, thereby revealing the next set either above or below it. This is dramatic and effective. The first time it was done, going from <PERSON> Amneris </PERSON>' rooms to a public square full of Egyptians, the audience gasped with appreciation. Though some were well gowned, women in the opening night audience provided less a fashion show than in some years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BoxOffice     09-26 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Box Office,0427</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Black Rain' Opens at No. 1; `Sea of Love' Still Strong</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN HORN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOLLYWOOD (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Black Rain,'' the thriller starring <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> as a cop who tracks a killer through the streets of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, captured first place in box office revenues last weekend. The Paramount movie grossed $ 9.7 million in its first three days of release. Universal's `` Sea of Love,'' the romantic suspense tale featuring <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino </PERSON> in his first film since the 1985 bomb `` Revolution,'' collected $ 7.8 million to land in second place. Universal also claimed the Nos. 3 and 4 spots. `` Uncle Buck,'' the comedy starring <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Candy </PERSON> as an overbearing relative on a family baby-sitting assignment, finished in third on receipts of $ 3.2 million. Director <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>'s `` Parenthood,'' with <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> heading an ensemble comedy cast, was fourth with sales of $ 3 million. In fifth place was `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' the comic chronicle of a relationship between <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crystal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meg </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, which grossed $ 2 million. It was followed by `` sex, lies and videotape,'' with $ 1.8 million. `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' the action-adventure sequel with <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Danny </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover </PERSON>, finished in seventh with $ 1.6 million. In eighth was the underwater thriller `` The Abyss,'' which collected $ 1.5 million. Rounding out the top 10 were `` Kickboxer'' in ninth with $ 1.432 million and `` Turner and Hooch'' in 10th with $ 1.426 million. Here are the top movies for the weekend as tallied by <ORGANIZATION> Exhibitor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> 1. `` Black Rain,'' Paramount, $ 9.7 million weekend gross, 1,610 screens, $ 6,010 per screen, $ 9.7 million total gross, one week in release. 2. `` Sea of Love,'' Universal, $ 7.8 million, 1,313 screens, $ 5,925 per screen, $ 21.4 million, two weeks. 3. `` Uncle Buck,'' Universal, $ 3.2 million, 1,784 screens, $ 1,795 per screen, $ 49.8 million, six weeks. 4. `` Parenthood,'' Universal, $ 3 million, 1,399 screens, $ 2,150 per screen, $ 78.4 million, eight weeks. 5. `` When <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Met </PERSON> <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> ...,'' <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, $ 2 million, 1,170 screens, $ 1,746 per screen, $ 78.1 million, 11 weeks. 6. `` sex, lies and videotape,'' <PERSON> Miramax </PERSON>, $ 1.8 million, 521 screens, $ 3,458 per screen, $ 15.7 million, eight weeks. 7. `` Lethal Weapon 2,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bros. </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.6 million, 1,356 screens, $ 1,185 per screen, $ 140.1 million, 12 weeks. 8. `` The Abyss,'' 20th Century <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, $ 1.5 million, 1,176 screens, $ 1,286 per screen, $ 49.7 million, seven weeks. 9. `` Kickboxer,'' Cannon, $ 1.432 million, 963 screens, $ 1,486 per screen, $ 10 million, three weeks. 10. `` Turner & amp; Hooch,'' <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>, $ 1.426 million, 1,208 screens, $ 1,180 per screen, $ 63.8 million, nine weeks.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ShuttleMishap     09-26 0418</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shuttle Mishap,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle Water Mishap May Not Delay Launch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOWARD BENEDICT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Aerospace Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Investigators hope <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s next scheduled space mission wo n't be delayed by damage caused by a surge of fire protection water that sprayed the shuttle. `` I have not given up launching on the 18th,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON>, deputy director of the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> who heads the investigation into Sunday's accident. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> is scheduled for liftoff on Dec. 18. <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said Monday the problem started when a valve failed, and then two workers in their haste to shut off the system mistakenly turned on most of the sprinklers. `` I'm chalking it up to a combination of equipment error and human error,'' he said. `` The guys who did it were only trying to help. ... Good intentions sometimes go wrong.'' As many as 200 of the shuttle's 500 woven fiberglass heat shields may have to be replaced, he said. The blankets, about the size of a beach towel, protect the top of the shuttle `` The thermal blankets are our major concern,'' <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said. He said initial inspection revealed no damage to any of the more than 20,000 silica thermal tiles. These are much smaller and tougher than the blankets and are bonded to side and bottom areas of the shuttle subjected to the highest heat. While there appeared to be no damage to electrical or electronic systems, `` we wo n't know for sure until we power up the vehicle,'' <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said. He said investigators should know within a few days if the launch will be delayed. `` If we have to replace only a couple hundred blankets, there should n't be a hit,'' <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said the accident occurred Sunday after three workers performed routine maintenance on the water sprinkler system in the building where the shuttle was being processed. When the workers finished the job, they tested the system by pressurizing it, but a gate valve that they were certain was closed failed and water began flowing from sprinklers in one of six safety zones. `` Two other workers who tried to help inadvertently turned on the other sprinklers'' and water poured onto work platforms and splashed onto the shuttle, <PERSON> Utsman </PERSON> said. Other workers were able to quickly turn off the water. He did not know the amount of water released. He said a small amount of water leaked into the closed cargo bay but did n't damage electronic systems there. He said no water entered the crew cabin.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0206EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastGermany     09-26 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East Germany,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>Honecker Resumes Some Duties; Pro-Democracy Protest, Refugee Wave
Tops 20,000</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 East German leader <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> appeared in public for the first time six weeks after gallbladder surgery, putting to rest rumors he was gravely ill but facing a crisis posed by an exodus to the West. West German officials say the number of East Germans that have fled to the West since <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> opened the floodgates on Sept. 11 has surpassed 20,000. As Communist East <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> nears its 40th anniversary, its leaders say they are discussing reforms that could stop the flow of refugees to the West, a phenomenon that is draining the country's labor pool The 77-year-old <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> resumed some official duties Monday as about 8,000 people demonstrated in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> to protest his government's refusal Monday to grant legal status to a pro-democracy group called New Forum. <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> police arrested scores of demonstrators, many of whom sang `` We Shall Overcome,'' and shouted such slogans as `` Liberty, Equality, Fraternity!'' <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s state-run news agency <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, who had not been seen in public since Aug. 14, resumed some official duties on Monday, meeting with the new ambassadors of <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION>. East German <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> sources said the party chief was expected to fully resume his duties by Oct. 7, when the country marks its 40th anniversary. Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is expected in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> for the ceremonies. After his mid-August surgery, some West German media reports said <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s condition may have been more serious than indicated by East German officials and that he had lost the will to live. The East German leadership has been hampered by <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>'s protracted recovery, leading one <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> official to call the country a `` ship without a captain. West German media have said that some East German Communist leaders have accused <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> of misjudging the meaning and scope of the exodus to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which grants East Germans automatic citizenship because its constitution does not recognize the division of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON>, a hard-line Communist who has led <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since 1971, has staunchly resisted reforms sweeping much of the Soviet bloc. As of early Monday, 20,130 East Germans had fled through <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> since the channel to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> was opened, West German border police said. In addition, more than 1,200 East German refugees waited in cramped West German Embassy compounds in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, hoping a diplomatic solution could be worked out to allow them to get to the West. East and West German officials spoke several times by telephone Monday trying to reach a compromise on the embassy occupations, said <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON>, a West German government spokesman. <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> is hoping to find a quick solution and the talks are in a `` highly sensitive phase,'' <PERSON> Schmuelling </PERSON> told reporters. In <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief for the East German city of <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION> said he thinks changes are needed to stop East Germans from leaving their homeland. <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Modrow </PERSON> said he agreed with a recent remark by retired East German intelligence chief <PERSON> Markus </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON> that the East German government must think over the causes of the East German exodus. `` On this point I am of the same opinion as my friend <PERSON> Mischa </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Modrow </PERSON> said on the first day of a four-day visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Modrow </PERSON>, however, refused to say what kind of reforms are needed in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` This is something we have to discuss at home, not here,'' he said. The number of East Germans occupying West German embassies in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, has nearly reached its saturation point, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> German </LOCATION> government sources said. About 980 East Germans have sought refuge inside the <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION> compound and 300 at the embassy in <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, the sources said. Their numbers have grown by 50 to 100 per day over the past week.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0210EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MarylandCongressman     09-26 0409</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Maryland Congressman,0419</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dyson Announces Re-election, Says Ex-Aide Improperly Pocketed Funds</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROLL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMBRIDGE, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> admitted to mistakes in judgment during a speech announcing his re-election, and promised to return $ 18,000 in campaign contributions from people linked to a defense contractor. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> also said Monday he would take `` ultimate responsibility'' for the embezzlement of $ 7,275 of his former top aide, who committed suicide in May 1988 by jumping from a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> hotel. `` Mistakes were made by my staff. I have made mistakes of judgment,'' the five-term Democrat told several hundred supporters. `` I regret the controversy these matters have caused, but I want the people of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> to know that these were mistakes of the head, not of the heart.'' <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> procurement subcommittee, said he was returning the contributions from employees and consultants for <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>, which is under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> for possible contract procurement violations. `` I am returning these funds because individual pleas entered as part of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s ` Ill Winds' investigation point to a systematic attempt on the part of <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION> to circumvent the federal laws governing campaign contributions,'' said <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>. The investigation involves charges that defense firms or their employees hired private consultants who bribed <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> officials for information needed to win multimillion-dollar contracts. The congressman also said he would donate to charity a $ 2,000 speaking fee he received from the <ORGANIZATION> Oshkosh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trucking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> on the day he voted in favor of a bill that benefited the company. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said he will report the apparent violations in accepting the speaking fee to the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>. `` Because of these errors, I anticipate that the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> will levy a fine which the campaign will pay to the <ORGANIZATION> FEC </ORGANIZATION> as a civil penalty for the violations,'' <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> also told supporters that the late <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON>, his former top aide, had improperly pocketed $ 7,275 in campaign funds. `` I must accept ultimate responsibility for these errors in judgment because <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Pappas </PERSON> was my campaign manager,'' <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON> said. `` I was not aware that <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> was writing checks to staff members and asking them to cash those checks and return the cash to him.'' <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Luna </PERSON>, an attorney who describes himself as `` an all but declared'' <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate for <PERSON> Dyson </PERSON>'s seat, said the congressman's admissions were welcomed but did n't go far enough in explaining his connection to <ORGANIZATION> Unisys </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EducationConflicts Bjt   09-26 0671</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Education Conflicts, Bjt,650</SECOND>
<HEAD>Money Issue May Slow Efforts for Consensus</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TAMARA HENRY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> wants a consensus on improving schools at the education summit starting Wednesday _ not more funds for a `` basically well-fed'' system _ but some governors say more money is a key issue. `` I do n't think you're going to find a consensus'' on the issue of money, said <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON>, a Republican who chairs the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governors </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ' </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and several key Republican governors are adamant that the two days of discussions at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Charlottesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, will not focus on more money for schools. `` The educational system is basically well-fed but it's undernourished, and we must find innovative, accountable ways to improve performance,'' the president told reporters at a recent briefing However, a key concern of some governors, particularly Democrats, is that without a federal financial commitment, the states and local governments will be forced to reshuffle scarce cash or impose higher taxes. `` We have enormous problems to surmount if we are to educate our children, and we need a real federal commitment to that effort, not just rhetoric,'' said <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>, a Democrat who said that during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration the federal share of school funds fell to 6 percent from 9 percent. `` The real problem for the federal government and the president ... is how do you shift resources for greater investment instead of ending up simply lecturing people on things they ought to do without any real help,'' said <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON>, a Democrat. `` I am hopeful we will see some increased federal funding for education,'' added <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mickelson </PERSON>, a Republican. `` But the federal government needs to balance its budget. I think they are going to, rather than give us a whole lot of money, begin to set an agenda and hold us accountable in the spending of the money.'' States already are pumping huge sums into education. For example, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> spent $ 4,069 per pupil in 1987-88, up from $ 1,524 per pupil in 1978-79. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, a Democrat, said that over the past 10 years, state financial support for public schools has risen by more than 100 percent. <PERSON> Branstad </PERSON> said, `` I think there is a feeling that there is considerable amount of money being spent on education. We want to spend it as wisely as possible.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who vowed to be the `` education president,'' has indicated a willingness to free states from cumbersome federal rules that dictate how some federal funds are spent. Democratic Gov. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> said it would be a mistake for governors to `` hammer'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> at the meeting for federal funding, but he stressed he would like more federal money for preschool programs such as Head Start. According to <PERSON> Perpich </PERSON>, the money for basic kindergarten through 12th grade education should be provided by states. <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON>, a Democrat, agreed. `` In terms of federal funding, my biggest priority is for the federal government to expand Head Start so that every eligible child has an opportunity to enroll.'' Educators said only about 20 percent of the eligible students are served by the Head Start program that cost the government $ 1.2 billion last year. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has proposed a $ 250 million increase. Money could overshadow discussions on other topics such as allowing parents to choose which public school their children will attend, restructuring the learning environment, revitalizing the teaching profession, and the proper role of government in education. The parental choice issue is the centerpiece of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s education initiatives, and conservatives want the president to promote the issue by challenging the governors to advance the idea at home. Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> said, `` the issue of equity and transportation are key to the issue of choice.'' Asked who would pay for school buses to take children to the school of their parents' choice, he said, `` It's going to be a state-by-state solution and it's going to be worked out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0221EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DirectMail Bjt   09-26 0651</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Direct Mail, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>You Want to Buy the Names of 146,983 Biology Majors?</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 You know all that junk mail that falls through your mail slot every day? If the envelope is just plain brown, it breaks <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>'s heart. <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> is a sales representative for the <ORGANIZATION> Tension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Envelope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a firm which produces about one-fifth of all the envelopes used by the direct mail industry. His territory is central <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> and he single-handedly sells 100 million envelopes a year, enough to fill 70 semi-trailers. Direct mail is big business, getting bigger. Tension Envelope has plants in 11 cities, many working two or three shifts, six days a week, making envelopes, headed for your mailbox. <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> was selling envelopes here Monday at the <ORGANIZATION> Direct </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marketing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s 72nd annual conference and exhibition, which attracted 8,000 people in the direct mail and telephone selling business and the people who serve them, like <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>. `` A plain brown envelope is insane,'' said <PERSON> Garland </PERSON>. `` The biggest opportunity for blowing the product's whistle is lost.'' He stood before a display of envelopes that were anything but plain. Some had rippled edges _ `` zippers'' to the trade _ that all but compel the recipient to open the envelope, which is the point. The latest wrinkle in envelopes is one in which the address flap flips over, allowing the recipient to reply using the original envelope. It saves storage space, <PERSON> Garland </PERSON> explained: `` If you insert a return envelope into the outgoing envelope, and you're using a million envelopes a month, you've got to find space for 2 million envelopes, not 1 million.'' Direct marketing likes big numbers. Some 88.5 million Americans, it brags, bought something through the mail in 1988, and the average mail-order purchase amounted to $ 74. The compilation of mailing lists, as might be imagined, is big business because `` targeting'' _ sending the pitch to the most likely customer _ is the name of the game. The American <ORGANIZATION> Student </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> List </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Neck </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, offers lists of students from kindergarten through graduate school. For $ 50 a thousand, you can buy the names and home and school addresses of 146,983 biology majors. <ORGANIZATION> PCS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mailing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> List </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is even more specialized. It will sell you the names and addresses of 11,438 air traffic controllers, 16,600 subscribers to Tax Angles; 15,547 auto wheel and frame alignment shops; 1,381 disc jockeys; 7,260 T-shirt stores; 425,000 `` high income women''; 10,620 hair and wig dealers or 532,390 professors. And National Demographics and <ORGANIZATION> Lifestyles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, pitching its `` relevant'' lists in a comic book, refers to folks who respond to direct marketing as `` respondoids'' and describes them as `` ever hopeful yet enslaved mail responsive mortals'' who `` long to fill out questionnaires about themselves and receive relevant mail.'' National Demographics gathers its lists from respondoids who fill out those consumer questionnaires or product registration cards that come with new hair dryers and toasters. Only 7 percent, the company says, check the little box indicating they want to be on no one's mail list. <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Caugherty </PERSON>, director of the association's Shop at Home Information Center, says most people like direct marketing. The 3,500-member association has developed codes of conduct to protect those who do n't. A 15-page pamphlet spells out the ethics of the business -LRB- `` free'' should mean `` a product or service which is offered without cost or obligation'' -RRB-. Another, aimed at policing those telephone sales calls, says the callers should not make offers `` in the guise of research or a survey when the real intent is to sell products or services or to raise funds.'' As for the latest twist, telephone machines which make a recorded sales pitch, the rules say `` a live operator'' should first introduce the recorded message. Moreover, the guidelines say, calls should n't be made `` during hours which are unreasonable to the recipients.'' Whether that's supper time, the guidelines do n't say.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AdBrouhaha     09-26 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ad Brouhaha,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Auto Industry Protests Public Service Spot Attacking Cars</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Assoicated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Few viewers are seeing it yet, but the auto industry already is crying foul over a public service ad on global warming that environmentalists are sending to radio and TV stations nationwide. And <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> wants equal time. The ad was unveiled a week ago by the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, which said it was distributing the 30-second spots to hundreds of radio and television stations to spread the warning about global warming and, specifically, what part the automobile plays. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vehicle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Manufacturers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, quickly dispatched a letter to 200 TV stations and 850 radio stations calling the ad `` clearly political'' and full of misinformation. He wrote that if the environmentalists' spots are used as a public service announcement `` we intend to demand equal time to rebut the misinformation and misleading material they contain.'' On Monday, <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>, executive director of the Washington-based environmental group, distributed a copy of <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON>'s letter at a news conference and accused the industry group of trying to `` muzzle public education on the environmental impact of automobiles. She characterized the industry's call for equal time as `` ludicrous'' and denied the thrust of the 30-second advertisement, which calls pollution from automobiles `` a major cause'' of global warming, is misleading. In a telephone interview, <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> defended his Sept. 19 letter to the radio and TV stations. <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> charged the environmentalists were misusing free air time under public service provisions by making a political statement and `` advancing their legislative agenda ... That's grass roots lobbying.'' He maintained the ad overstates the threat of global warming, which he said was still disputed in the scientific community, and puts too much of the blame on pollution from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automobiles. Carbon dioxide, which is released in the burning of fossil fuels, is a major contributor to the so-called `` greenhouse effect'' _ the creation of a gaseous veil in the atmosphere. Scientists are concerned that if accumulation of these `` greenhouse'' gases goes unchecked, the <LOCATION> Earth </LOCATION> may warm significantly by the middle of the next century. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> automobiles, however, are only one source of carbon dioxide and are believed to be the source of only about 2.5 percent of all the greenhouse gases worldwide, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. Nevertheless, a reduction of carbon dioxide emissions from motor vehicles and other sources is widely seen as essential to reducing the global warming threat. The environmental group's 30-second spot opens with a shot directly into the sun and the announcer calling global warming `` a disease of the Earth.'' It quickly pans a desert landscape and then shifts to highway and city streets clogged with cars and trucks while the announcer says `` a major cause of global warming'' is pollution from automobiles. `` We need more fuel efficient cars,'' continues the announcer over a scene of a family with its car, followed by a closeup of arid, parched earth. <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> said he would not object if the spots were run as paid advertisements that give a point of view, but said the environmentalists should not be given free air time. `` Detroit spends millions of dollars each year to advertise their new model cars and light trucks,'' replied Ms. <PERSON> Caplan </PERSON>. `` For the industry to request free air time to respond to our modest public education campaign is ludicrous.'' <PERSON> Hanna </PERSON> said there are no plans to prepare a counter-ad in case equal time is granted by a TV or radio operator. But he said spokesmen would be available to `` make people aware there's another point of view.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Hispanics-Congress     09-26 0411</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hispanics-Congress,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Reagan Official Disputes Warnings on Hispanics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Republican <PERSON> Hispanic </PERSON> says conditions for Hispanic youth are n't as bad as described by a federal study and by <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration officials. <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>, who served at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration, provoked strong disagreement with her testimony at a hearing on Hispanic children Monday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION>, Youth and Families. She disputed remarks Education Secretary <PERSON> Lauro </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavazos </PERSON> made last week when he released a report on school dropouts and said the rate among Hispanic students is `` a national tragedy.'' `` The future looks quite good for individual Hispanics,'' said <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON>. `` Native-born Hispanics, despite the ominous report from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, appear to be staying in school longer,'' she said. She challenged the statistical basis for the report and said the department's finding, like other statistical studies of Hispanics, were skewed by large influxes of recent immigrants _ arriving at a rate she estimated at 400,000 a year. <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> said Hispanic immigrants will eventually move into the economic mainstream as have earlier <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> immigrants, who also faced high dropout rates in their first generations. The studies `` diminish the very real and significant progress'' of Hispanics in this country. Her remarks put her at odds, however, with a panel of Hispanic experts appearing with her before the committee, who cited severe poverty and education problems among Hispanics. `` She's not right,'' said <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosewater </PERSON>, staff director of the committee, following the hearing. `` They -LRB- other expert witnesses -RRB- made a very clear point. There's lots of research showing not just first generation, but second and third generation -LRB- Hispanics -RRB- are not doing well in school.'' <PERSON> Raul </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinojosa </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION> said Hispanics of varying national origins are falling further behind economically. He said Hispanics have been hurt by discrimination, low educational achievement and changes in the national labor market that have reduced the availability of middle-income jobs. He said the higher fertility rate among Hispanics is a more important factor than the arrival of recent immigrants. Committee Chairman <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>., said Hispanics face `` severe poverty'' and `` incredible disparity'' with other ethnic groups, regardless of the statistics used `` The numbers are overwhelming,'' he said. <PERSON> Chavez </PERSON> is a senior fellow with the <ORGANIZATION> Manhattan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> research organization, and is a former unsuccessful <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> candidate for the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890926-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-09-26-89 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DrugAbuse     09-26 0633</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Drug Abuse,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Embargoed for release 10 a.m. EDT; time set by source</HEAD>
<HEAD>Some Sixth Graders Use Cocaine Every Week, Survey Shows</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
