<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 2334EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Pentagon-Crash 1stLd-Writethru   06-16 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pentagon-Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0768,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pensylvanian, Californian, Alaskan-Marylander Killed in Panama</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf: ``All were,'' with one graf: ``The two,'' to
CORRECT McDaniel's duty station to Fort Meade.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Army on Friday released the names of the three <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers killed when the military helicopter they were flying crashed in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Two men were identified by the Pentagon: Warrant Officer <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrid </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bessemer </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION> and Chief Warrant Officer <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cornick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. At Ford Ord, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> officials identified the third man as Staff Sgt <PERSON> Timothy </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> McDaniel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. The two officers were members of the 123rd Aviation Battalion of the 7th Infantry Division based at <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ord </ORGANIZATION>, and <PERSON> McDaniel </PERSON> was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Combat </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detachment </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Meade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, officials said. An investigation into the cause of the crash was under way, said a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, Maj. <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wood </PERSON>. The cause of the crash appeared to be a mechanical failure, she said, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials earlier had ruled out the possibility that the helicopter was fired upon. The helicopter, an OH-58 small observation craft, crashed near the Trans-Isthmian Highway as it was flying a mission for a military convoy traveling from <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clayton </LOCATION>, on the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> side of the Canal, to <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Sherman </PERSON>, on the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> announced that the helicopter went down near the town of <LOCATION> Chilibre </LOCATION>, about 21 miles north of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The battalion was among troops sent to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> following the government's nullification of the May 7 elections and post-election violence in which three opposition candidates were beaten.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-FriendshipFlight     06-16 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Friendship Flight,0218</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Pilot Lands in Greenland on World Flight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COPENHAGEN, Denmark (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eleven-year-old <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> pilot <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Aliengena </PERSON>, who hopes to fly to the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and around the world, landed his <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> 210 Centurion plane in <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> on Friday. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>'s plane and two accompanying aircraft touched down at <LOCATION> Sondre </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stromfjord </LOCATION> airport in west <LOCATION> Greenland </LOCATION> Friday afternoon after a four-hour <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> flight from <LOCATION> Frobisher </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>'s pretty tired and I hope he can get a few hours sleep before we take off for <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION> in two hours time,'' said the boy's father, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Aliengena </PERSON> The main destination of <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>'s `` Friendship Flight ` 89'' is the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, where he plans to deliver letters from American schoolchildren to Soviet kids in <LOCATION> Leningrad </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. From <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> and his Dad, along with family members, <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> reporters, a filmmaker and an observer from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in two other aircraft, are scheduled to fly across the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and finally home to <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Before that they plan to visit <PERSON> Rekjavik </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Iceland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oslo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Norway </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Helsinki </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>. The 11-year old hopes to become the youngest pilot to fly around the world, a 19,000-mile trip by the route he is taking.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-UndergroundAtlanta 1stLd-Writethru a0722 06-16 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Underground Atlanta, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0722,0633</SECOND>
<HEAD>Underground Atlanta Opens Despite Bad Weather, Protesters</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 1 graf after 2nd, `Wind and ..., to UPDATE with crowd
estimate.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto AX2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARC RICE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Brushing aside a homelessness protest, storms and a last-minute legal scare, officials Thursday opened Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, a $ 142 million attempt to transform the business district into <LOCATION> Fun </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>. Wind and rain forced the opening ceremony to be moved to a covered section of the complex and prevented a fireworks display. But people crammed shoulder-to-shoulder to get a first-day look at the more than 100 shops, restaurants, nightclubs and street vendors. Police estimated that about 200,000 people visited through the day. Mayor <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s speech capping the opening ceremony was drowned out by demonstrators blowing whistles and chanting, `` <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> keeps the homeless underground.'' Six people were arrested and charged with criminal trespassing, police said. About an hour before the complex opened, <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenrette </PERSON> refused to stop the developers from using the Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> name. He ruled that a company that claims it holds rights to the name filed a lawsuit too late. Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> adds entertainment and nightlife to a downtown that had lost most of its fun spots to the suburbs. First-day visitors appeared to be enjoying themselves, and many said they'd be coming back. `` The shops are fantastic. I've done my Christmas shopping already,'' said <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Brewer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tuscon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, who was in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> to visit a friend. But even the most enthusiastic merchants acknowledged success is uncertain. An original Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, located beneath downtown street viaducts, opened in 1969. Hurt by nearby subway construction and the perception that it was crime-ridden, it closed in 1982. Young made reviving Underground a priority of his administration, and with a combination of private investment, millions of dollars of municipal funds and the issuance of $ 85 million in revenue bonds, the project thrived. Developed over three years by <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>, the new Underground is located on and around the old site. Advocates for the homeless say many of the city's street people were displaced by the Underground construction, and that public money used for the complex could have gone to providing affordable housing. When Young was drowned out by the demonstrators, he angrily defended his administration's actions on behalf of the poor. Dignitaries on the stand, including Gov. <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, rose to applaud the mayor but the protesters shouted even louder. Young, a liberal Democrat who was prominent in the civil rights movement, said later he was not angry with the hecklers but insisted he did n't deserve their ire. `` You protest when you ca n't get people to take you seriously or talk with you,'' <PERSON> Young </PERSON> said. `` I meet with the homeless, we have a homeless task force, we put all of the resources we possibly can in dealing with the problems of homelessness. `` Maybe this helps in the sense that it puts homelessness on the national media,'' he added. `` But you're not going to be able to resolve the problems of homelessness unless we keep successful projects like this going that create jobs.'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, a partner at the Open Door Community, an organization that aids the homeless, said of the demonstration, `` I think it's a hard thing for a lot of people to understand _ why disrupt a good time? But there are a lot of people in this city who never have a good time because the basics of life are denied to them.'' Ms. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said that if Underground <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> provides jobs to the poor, they are likely to be paid the minimum wage, which she said is not enough money to live on.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-GalloPullback     06-16 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gallo Pullback,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gallo Heeds `Safe-Sober' Group, Pulls Tenderloin High-Alcohol Wines</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JACK SCHREIBMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a startling first for the largest winemaker in the world, the E. & amp; <ORGANIZATION> J. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gallo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Winery </ORGANIZATION> said it will stop for six months the sale of its its two brands of cheap high-alcohol wine in the seedy Tenderloin district. The action came Wednesday after Tenderloin-area distributor Gallo-Bay Cities, a Gallo-owned business, met with `` Safe and Sober Streets'' activists, who have protested the sale of the fortified wines in their district. `` If what we have done in this neighborhood improves the alcoholism problem in this area, we'll do the same thing in other neighborhoods,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, a spokesman for the Modesto-based winery. The protesters denounced fortified wines like <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON>'s Thunderbird and Night Train Express, and <ORGANIZATION> Canandaigua </ORGANIZATION>'s Wild Irish Rose. They said they were unable to walk through the Tenderloin without tripping over or being menaced by a wino. <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON> has never removed a product from the shelves, <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> said. The privately held company has $ 1 billion in annual sales and 28 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wine market. Sober Streets group went from grocery-to-grocery, trying to persuade the proprietors to take the cheap goods off their shelves. One grocer agreed but changed his mind, he said, after losing $ 850 in wine sales in a single day. <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> characterized the action as an experiment by <PERSON> Gallo </PERSON> to see whether or not `` our beliefs and the evidence are correct'' _ that winos deprived of their cheap wine will turn to other alcohols. The wines involved are typically made from the cheapest vinous ingredients and the merest hint of grape flavor, then hyped with grape brandy to bring the alcohol to about 18 percent by volume. They sell for around 90 cents to $ 1.25 a bottle. It's estimated that the two wines account for less than 3 percent of company sales.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JurorsPunished     06-16 0287</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jurors Punished,0296</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Who Wouldn't Pay Jurors Changes Mind</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Silvestri Silvestri is cq</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An judge changed his mind about not paying a 12-member jury, which he dismissed without pay for ignoring his instructions in a personal injury case. <LOCATION> Allegheny </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Common Pleas Judge <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> on Thursday authorized payments to the panel for five days of work after meeting with judges <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Zavarella </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cappy </PERSON>, who administer the civil division. `` It was his order and he reconsidered it,'' <PERSON> Zavarella </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> refused to comment on why he changed his mind. `` With all the publicity on the case, I think Judge <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> just wants the matter to end,'' <PERSON> Zavarella </PERSON> said. Jurors normally are paid $ 9 a day for the first three days of a trial and $ 25 for each day therafter, plus mileage. The jurors will receive between $ 82 and $ 112. One of the jurors, <PERSON> Benjamin </PERSON> <PERSON> Margolin </PERSON>, wrote <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> asking him to reconsider his decision, saying the jury was `` not fully cognizant of the law.'' `` I for one am sorry it caused such a furor,'' he said. <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> had tried twice, without success, to explain to the jurors that they had to award $ 10,514 in medical expenses to <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Culver </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Carnegie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mellon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student whose ankle had been broken in an impromptu wrestling match initiated by another student in 1987 at a fraternity party. In their first verdict, the jury decided not to award money damages to <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION>, 21, of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. After <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> repeated his instructions, they deliberated again and awarded the injured student $ 1,000, but because they ruled both men were 50 percent responsible, the student was to receive $ 500. <PERSON> Silvestri </PERSON> then dismissed them without pay on June 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0122EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GayChurch     06-16 0848</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gay Church,0873</SECOND>
<HEAD>Homosexual Congregation Breaks Ground by Joining Mainline Church</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED STYCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Though churches have condemned homosexual activity for centuries, gay men and women are beginning to find a home within a mainline Christian denomination. The Spirit of the <ORGANIZATION> Lakes </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ecumenical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> became the nation's first openly homosexual congregation to join a mainline church when it was accepted into membership of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> in April, according to its leader. `` As far as we know, we're making history,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON>, pastor of Spirit of the Lakes. `` We see ourselves as a prophetic voice. `` We hope that we're breaking ground and leading the way for other churches and other denominations to open up and recognize gay and lesbian people's rightful place in the church.'' Spirit of the Lakes has grown from 18 people meeting in a living room in May 1987 to 150 members. It was voted into membership by more than 80 percent of the delegates attending the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, the largest of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>'s three associations in <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> with 71 churches and 24,000 members. Spirit of the Lakes is considered a `` developing'' church while the association reviews the group's constitution and development plan. Those are likely to be approved at the association's 1990 annual meeting, formalizing the congregation's admission, association officials say. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Loliger </PERSON>, co-coordinator of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lesbian-Gay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Concerns </ORGANIZATION>, an <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>, Ohio-based special-interest group within the church, said the acceptance of Spirit of the Lakes is a first for mainline denominations. `` This one is certainly very different than anything we have encountered before,'' he said. `` It is an openly gay and lesbian congregation, and they have sought to become a church with that right up front.'' Most Christian churches accept homosexuals as members, equally beloved by <PERSON> God </PERSON> as others, but condemn the practice of homosexuality. But the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>, a 1.8-million-member Protestant church formed in 1957 when the <ORGANIZATION> Evangelical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reformed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> merged with the <ORGANIZATION> Congregational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Churches </ORGANIZATION>, often has been at the forefront of progressive social movements. In 1969, the church's general synod approved its first resolution supporting civil rights for homosexuals, and three years later it became the first mainline denomination to ordain an openly gay minister. In 1983, the general synod passed a resolution stating that `` a person's sexual orientation is not a moral issue'' and that sexual orientation should not be the basis for discrimination within the church. The synod encouraged <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION> churches to openly accept homosexuals as members. That inclusiveness is what attracted Spirit of the Lakes to the denomination. <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON>, 39, who grew up in <LOCATION> Anoka </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> suburb, received a master of divinity degree from the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Religion </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ-affiliated </ORGANIZATION> school in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. He took over as pastor of Spirit of the Lakes in September and immediately began pursuing membership in the denomination. `` The discussion was, ` Why bother to affiliate at all?' Most -LRB- homosexuals -RRB- look at established churches as oppressive institutions,'' <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON> said. But the membership was attracted by the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ </ORGANIZATION>'s structure, which allows autonomy for each congregation `` This is the best of both worlds for us,'' he said. `` We can remain an autonomous congregation ... and still associate with a larger Christian body. That allows us to be a community of gay-lesbian Christians and at the same time not be ghetto-ized.'' He described the congregation as college-educated professionals who come from <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, Lutheran and Episcopal backgrounds and are interested in social justice, peace, liberation and feminist theology. Although Spirit of the Lakes has generally met with quiet acceptance, some have voiced reservations. `` I do not think that any congregation should come in with a sexual or a racial orientation,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> McCutcheon </PERSON>, senior minister of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christ-affiliated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wayzata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` I would be bothered if somebody proposed a church just for men, or a church just for women, or a church just for married couples, and so on.'' <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON> says 10 percent of his church's membership is heterosexual. Spirit of the Lakes also is bucking Christian tradition which holds that the practice of homosexuality is a sin. People who interpret the Bible literally point to several Old and New Testament passages that appear to condemn homosexuality. One is <LOCATION> Leviticus </LOCATION> 20:13, which according to the Revised Standard Version says, `` If a man lies with a male as with a woman, both of them have committed an abomination.'' But <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON> and <PERSON> McCutcheon </PERSON> contend that the Bible must be interpreted in the context of the time in which it was written. When <PERSON> Leviticus </PERSON> was written, <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON> said, `` the Israelites were instinctively concerned with maximizing the probabilities of procreation. Religious laws governing sexual practices reinforced that basic tribal concern.'' <PERSON> Geslin </PERSON> criticizes people who use specific Bible verses to condemn homosexuals today. `` It's not taking the Bible as a whole,'' he said. `` It's picking out little bits and pieces to justify cultural prejudices.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0124EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:BerlinRing     06-16 1100</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Berlin Ring,1121</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Berlin Ring's Time Tunnel</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A `` time tunnel'' is the visual and philosophical centerpiece of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>'s Ring cycle at the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION>. The concept creates a thrilling sensation that everything happening on stage in the present is part of the past and part of the future. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s stunning creation, `` Der Ring des <PERSON> Nibelungen </PERSON>'' -LRB- `` The Ring of the Nibelungen'' _ dwarfs who owned a magic ring and a horde of gold -RRB-, is being performed the way the German composer intended it to be _ a four-day cycle. The Metropolitan Opera performed the entire epic about love and greed and gods and goddesses in April and May. It was the first time it had been presented in so short a span in 90 years. The Kennedy Center ring opened June 2. In all four of <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s Ring operas, `` Das Rheingold,'' `` Die Walkure,'' `` Siegfried'' and `` Gotterdammerung,'' the audience looks into the end of a tunnel designed by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sykora </PERSON>. The other end is straight ahead, far away and smaller, with a light beyond. This does n't mean that singers just stride around inside an otherwise hollow tunnel. Sometimes there are sufficient backdrops, scenery and props so that only two pieces of the 90-foot-high stucture's mouth are visible, curving across the top of the stage on both sides. The Kennedy Center's Ring is intensely theatrical. Characters move a lot; laser light flashes; fire juts up from grates in some dozen dark circles on the stage; fog pours from 20 fog machines; the flamboyantly feathered forest bird glides in on a swing instead of being an unseen voice. <PERSON> Gotz </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> staged the Ring for the company he has headed since 1981. The Ring, he said, concerns power, money and love. Its characters, and its viewers try to find solutions and a better way for the next generation. `` But they do the same errors again,'' he said. After <PERSON> Alberich </PERSON> steals the gold from the <ORGANIZATION> Rhinemaidens </ORGANIZATION> and sets the Nibelungs, now his slaves, to mine more gold, his office slides onstage _ six TV sets for overseeing the work, computers behind him, an electronic console in front of him. The mythic story, in which <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> thought human truth could be found, begins with <PERSON> Alberich </PERSON>, a dwarf who yearns for love, invading the territory of the Rheinmaidens who lead him on and then spurn him, making him so angry he renounces love and steals their gold. It ends with the death of the superhero <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Brunnhilde </LOCATION>'s throwing herself on his funeral pyre, her love redeeming the world In between is plenty of theft, betrayal and murder. Ring lovers are divided over how their beloved opera should be staged. Some prefer the naturalistic setting with the <ORGANIZATION> Valkyries </ORGANIZATION>' rock looking like a mountain top, as used by the Metropolitan and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> operas, rather than Ring cycles staged according to a director's concept Since <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON>'s grandson staged an abstract Ring in 1965, directorial `` interpretations'' have been the norm in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON>, general director of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>, and set designer <PERSON> Sykora </PERSON> created this Ring in 1986. Its Kennedy Center performances commemorate the 40th anniversary of the Federal Republic of <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. `` When the Ring was first completed and performed in <LOCATION> Bayreuth </LOCATION> in 1876, <PERSON> Wagner </PERSON> said in the next year he would change everything,'' <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> said in an interview. `` He saw ... that what he wrote in his score about the scenes was bad. But in his lifetime, it never came to a new production. The tradition carried almost 80 years.'' The <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> production was moving, as the Ring visually flowed like the silk cloth it lavishly used among present, past and future. The curved rafters in the tunnel looked like staves in a huge winecask in a Bruegel painting, but the entrances into the wings from the tunnel were metal, like submarine hatches. The armored dragon slain by <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> moves forward like a tank, with a searchlight between glowing red eyes. After it is pierced by <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON>'s sword, it collapses onto one wheel. With love so important in the Ring, <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> has added a bit of love interest not in the original text involving a giant and the goddess Freia. <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> also has Vietnam War images in the Ring, starting with the second opera, `` Die Walkure.'' Weapons, ancient and modern, khaki and camouflage cloth abound. In `` Siegfried,'' the third opera, the Wanderer dresses like a <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> War correspondent in long trench coat. <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> wears bib overalls to convey innocence, even after he weds <LOCATION> Brunnhilde </LOCATION>. It's only when he meets <PERSON> Gunther </PERSON>, king of the Gibichungs, who is dressed like a Marine officer, and his sophisticated sister that <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON> changes to slacks and blazer. Trap doors are n't used in this production. When <PERSON> Erda </PERSON> comes up from inside the earth, she sits up out of a silk cloth which covers the stage. Four silk cloths are lifted and lowered by wires to make the waves in `` Das Rheingold.'' <LOCATION> Valhalla </LOCATION> is n't prominent either. When the gods first see it, it is small and distant. When it is destroyed at the end of the Ring, a few fragments fall from the ceiling. The Ring's ending usually is taken to mean that the status quo _ gods in the sky, giants and heroes on earth and Nibelungs, who are miners and blacksmiths, below the earth _ is destroyed and will be replaced by a better system. <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON>'s idea is that history will repeat itself. The last image in `` Gotterdammerung'' is the same as the beginning of `` Das Rheingold'' _ people covered with a huge white silk cloth. Some details were n't immediately understandable, as having Loge, god of fire, dressed like a Wild West gambler, the earth goddess swimming offstage and the Gibichung king in whiteface. Musically, the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Opera Orchestra is n't as flexible, balanced or strong as the Metropolitan Opera Orchestra. It is good but often does n't rise to the high points and sometimes sounds tired. <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez-Cobos </PERSON>, the company's music director, conducted the first Ring and <PERSON> Christof </PERSON> <PERSON> Perick </PERSON> conducted the second. Great Wagnerian voices are nearly as scarce as heros such as <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON>. This production is blessed with <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Kannen </PERSON>, who sang <PERSON> Alberich </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Matti </PERSON> <PERSON> Salminen </PERSON>, who sang <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON> in both cycles and, in the second cycle, also sang one of the giants in `` Das Rheingold'' and <PERSON> Sieglinde </PERSON>'s husband in `` Die Walkure.'' <PERSON> Rene </PERSON> <PERSON> Kollo </PERSON>, probably the world's current best <PERSON> Siegfried </PERSON>, sang with beauty and without strain. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Estes </PERSON> showcased his rich voice as <PERSON> Wotan </PERSON> in the second cycle.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     06-16 0039</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0044</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Thursday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6488.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 09; 11; 19; 37; 39; 41. Bonus: 95644.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 1291.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     06-16 0074</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0077</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 6488.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 02; 03; 10; 17; 21; 29.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 09; 11; 19; 37; 39; 41. Bonus: 95644.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto Game: 04; 05; 14; 26; 46; 54. Supplementary 42.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 1291.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 8-3-8; 1-9-3-4; 6-1-5-5-0; 4-9-4-8-2-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APAppointment     06-16 0099</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Appointment,0101</SECOND>
<HEAD>AP News Editor Named for Omaha</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OMAHA, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Maryann </PERSON> <PERSON> Mrowca </PERSON>, correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Wausau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, for the past two years, has been named <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> editor in <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>. The appointment was announced Thursday by <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> Chief of Bureau <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>. Ms. <PERSON> Mrowca </PERSON>, 27, joined the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> in 1984 after graduation from <ORGANIZATION> Marquette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. She transferred to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> later that year and was named <LOCATION> Wausau </LOCATION> correspondent in 1987. Ms. <PERSON> Mrowca </PERSON> is a native of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION> she succeeds <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, who transferred to the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-Settlers     06-16 0815</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Settlers,0839</SECOND>
<HEAD>Settlers on Patrol: Gunfire at The Sound of a Stone</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUIS MEIXLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HEBRON, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As soon as a stone landed near his car, patrol leader <PERSON> Meishe </PERSON> <PERSON> Mishkan </PERSON> hit the brakes, popped a clip of 25-rounds into his Uzi submachine gun and led other Jewish settlers on a chase of a dozen Arab teen-agers. Moments later, a short, chubby settler with a white, knitted skullcap was stoned from a rooftop. `` I'm under attack,'' he yelled, crouching low, pivoting on one foot and raking a nearby rooftop with bullets. No one was hurt in Wednesday's clash. But the controversial settler patrols of the occupied lands have spurred accusations the settlers are taking too much of the law into their own hands. The organizer of the Wednesday patrol, <PERSON> Bella </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonen </PERSON>, said the settlers began the patrols in April after losing faith in the Israeli army's ability to end the 18-month Palestinian uprising against Israeli rule. `` The army is becoming more like a group of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> observers,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Gonen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION>, a settlement of 4,700 Jews that overlooks <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION>, a city with 50,000 Arabs. `` They do n't protect the Jews, all they do is separate the two sides. Army officials have ordered the settlers to end their patrols in Palestinian areas. `` It's illegal and each time the army comes across such a patrol it's dispersed immediately,'' a spokesman said. Israeli civilians, most often settlers, were involved in the shooting deaths of 19 of the 516 Palestinians killed since the uprising began. Twenty-two Israelis also have died, including six settlers. <PERSON> Gonen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kiryat </PERSON> <PERSON> Arba </PERSON> settlers began car patrols this week, which they officially refer to as `` archaeological expeditions'' to circumvent official objections. Wednesday's patrol slowly cruised through the winding streets of <LOCATION> Hebron </LOCATION> for about a half-hour until the stone landed near <LOCATION> Mishkan </LOCATION>'s car outside the <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> campus During the clash, <PERSON> Yaakov </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-David </PERSON>, a tall, thin man in his 20s who is a Moslem convert to <LOCATION> Judiasm </LOCATION>, carefully took aim before letting loose with a burst of three rounds. `` They're rounding the stone wall,'' he shouted as he charged up a hill. Other settlers stood behind him, firing their Uzis at the Palestinians who were running up the hill, behind a wall. Sharp pops could be heard as the bullets ricocheted off the stones. The encounter lasted about three minutes, after which the settlers withdrew to their cars and the Arab teens stood on a stone wall beyond gunfire range, chanting Palestinian slogans and flashing `` V'' for victory signs. `` The problem here is the media. If we chase them and run into their homes, the press will go crazy and attack us. We ca n't do anything here,'' said settler <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> as he climbed into his mud-spattered blue car and rolled up the reinforced glass windows. `` We are not shooting to kill, but if we hit one, well ...'' said the driver, <PERSON> Gilon </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-Said </PERSON>, shrugging his shoulders. As he drove away, <PERSON> Ben-Said </PERSON> broke into a chorus of the song, `` Am <PERSON> Yisrael </PERSON> <PERSON> Hai </PERSON>'' _ `` The Nation of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> Lives.'' Army troops arrived as the settler convoy pulled out, firing tear gas between the <LOCATION> Palestinians </LOCATION> and the departing settlers. Ten minutes later, the group pulled up to the grave of the biblical prophet <PERSON> Nathan </PERSON> in the nearby <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> town of <LOCATION> Halhoul </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Zvi </PERSON> <PERSON> Katzover </PERSON>, deputy chairman of <PERSON> Kiryat </PERSON> <PERSON> Arba </PERSON>'s town council, chastised his men for firing so freely and warned them to hold their fire if there was another confrontation. `` If we start shooting and other people are chasing, someone could end up with a bullet in his back,'' he said. As <PERSON> Katzover </PERSON> finished speaking, two jeeploads of soldiers pulled up. The commanding officer, a major, demanded the settlers leave the area. A jeep with paramilitary border police escorted the settlers to the gates of <LOCATION> Kiryat </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arba </LOCATION>. Later, settlers held a town meeting with a local army commander, Col. <PERSON> Baruch </PERSON>. Under military regulations, his last name may not be revealed. The meeting was scheduled following several incidents of vigilante raids on Arab villages in reprisal for stone-throwing and confrontations with troops in which one officer was beaten. A tall, husky man wearing a bush hat and a pistol holster with extra clips of ammunition attached to its side stood up and said: `` I support a family of 10. What am I suppose to do if I am attacked, call the army and wait?'' Col. <PERSON> Baruch </PERSON>, who patiently jotted down each settler's question during a half-hour session, responded in a slow, controlled voice: `` No one can promise you that there will be no stones thrown in <LOCATION> Judea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Samaria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>. -RRB-'' `` But in no instance can people take the law into their own hands. The best way for us to act is for people to let the army do its job,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Students     06-16 0814</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Students,0839</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beijing Crisis Sparks Fear Among Chinese Students Around the World</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Chinese students abroad are trying to extend their stays in their host countries because of the crisis in their homeland, which has turned thousands of exchange students into potential exiles. The Chinese government's violent suppression of a student-led reform movement has sent a shiver around the world, instilling fear in some students who had hoped to return home and hope in others who want to stay abroad. Since the June 3-4 military attack on unarmed students in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, governments have said they would extend the visas of Chinese students. Among those are the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>. In <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Immigration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it had received 10,000 inquiries from <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> students _ virtually all of the 10,600 registered in the country _ about extending their visas. Only a few have actually applied, said immigration spokeswoman <PERSON> Jenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoskin </PERSON>. `` But we expect a great deal more in coming weeks.'' `` We would consider sympathetically the case of any student who could be considered in any sense in danger by returning to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>,'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> said Thursday, assuring students in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> they need not worry about their visas lapsing and being deported. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, statistics show about 80,000 Chinese now are studying abroad, with half of them in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, according to the Returned Student Association. They were permitted to leave <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> only after passing competitive examinations. Rules published in 1987 said they had to show they `` love the motherland and cherish socialism.'' Political reliability and family connections _ relatives in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> to ensure their return _ are important. Abroad, many students hope to keep alive the pro-democracy movement. But distance from the tensions in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has not allayed fears of government reprisals. In several countries, students say they believe they are being monitored and harassed by <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> authorities. At <ORGANIZATION> Brandeis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> near <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, mathematician <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON> <PERSON> Mo </PERSON>, 26, said he suspected the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government was responsible for taking down posters after a meeting of Chinese students. In <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> student who asked not to be identified said diplomats had photographed demonstrations outside the Chinese Embassy in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. `` Although they could n't possibly identify everyone, many of us are worrying,'' he said. Another student in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, also asking anonymity, said pro-democracy activists have toned down the optimism they felt two weeks ago. `` It looks like the battle will be a long one,'' he said. `` None of us wants to do anything conspicuous. But we will continue to fight. Maybe publish a magazine or something. We wo n't make any needless sacrifices.'' Some Chinese even want to move to <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, where the mainland's old rulers fled after the communist revolution <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s de facto embassy in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> said 200 Chinese students had picked up applications for Taiwanese passports and 20 had submitted them in the last four days. In <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Free </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chinese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, which represents the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> government in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, has received several dozen applications for citizenship `` and we expect more to come,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Kate </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanniker </PERSON>. The Taiwanese government announced last week it would relax its rules and issue <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> passports to Chinese students who had pariticipated in rallies in other countries supporting the demonstrators in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. `` This is to show our concern for overseas mainland students. We hope our passports will help them complete their studies in foreign countries,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Yu-chu </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Taipei </LOCATION>. But holding a <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> passport will not guarantee permanent residence in Nationalist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, he said, because the country's laws say mainland Chinese must live four years in a free country to be eligible for entrance and residence on the island. The <ORGANIZATION> Taiwanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> has proposed offering financial help to mainland Chinese studying in other countries. Some of the 3,000 Chinese students in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> have expressed worry that their financing ends this summer, said Dr. <PERSON> Abraham </PERSON> <PERSON> Lue </PERSON>, assistant principal of <ORGANIZATION> Kings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. `` And so they are worried that if the situation in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> prevails and it's hazardous for them to return, then they're going to find it difficult to find funding and to stay on here longer,'' he told the <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION>. Some Chinese students in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> fear they will be jailed if they return home, said <PERSON> Ding </PERSON> <PERSON> Xueliang </PERSON>, 36, a <ORGANIZATION> Harvard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student who was active in the democracy movement in exile. `` We'll continue to speak out,'' <PERSON> Ding </PERSON> said. `` It could cause more trouble, but our moral obligation is to help our friends in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>.'' In <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, seven Chinese students and two businessmen have applied for asylum since the crackdown in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Inge </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomsen </PERSON>, a department head in the Aliens Directorate. She said <LOCATION> Danish </LOCATION> authorities would be cautious in forcing any Chinese to return to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> under the present circumstances.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RacialHarassment     06-16 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Racial Harassment,0832</SECOND>
<HEAD>Black Elected Officials in Alabama Accuse Federal Agents of Harassment</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOYT HARWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BIRMINGHAM, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Stung by a series of corruption allegations, black leaders across <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> are accusing federal authorities of racial harassment, but one <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney says he and his colleagues are `` equal-opportunity prosecutors.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON>, a former college professor serving his third term as <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>'s first black mayor, said federal agents tried to frame him through a developer who faces tax bribery charges, and other black officials say their phones have been tapped or they have been the target of unjustified investigations. At <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON>'s request, a special state prosecutor has been named to review the actions of the federal agents, and the federal government's own office that investigates bias allegations against law enforcement authorities is looking into the matter. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> staff is also reviewing the allegations. Blacks in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> began flexing ballot box strength after passage of the 1965 Voting Rights Act, and now hold more than 1,000 elective offices in the state, including 24 of the 141 seats in the <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>. Three black legislators from the <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> area are under indictment on federal charges they tried to bribe a former legislator, who is white, in connection with a proposed dog track. Their attorneys contend race bias was a factor that led to their indictment. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON>, the state <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> president, was convicted of federal bribery charges in September and stripped of his seat in the state <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>. He was accused of accepting $ 10,000 to use his influence to get early parole for a convicted killer. <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> contends his prosecution was spurred by his high profile opposition to the flying of the Confederate flag atop the Capitol. Those cases, and reports of <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> surveillance of other blacks, amount to selective harassment, according to <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON> and others. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>, a black attorney who is a veteran of the civil rights movement, said the actions are part of a pattern that began with President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s arrival at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> eight years ago and continues under President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. `` All of this is a conspiracy on the part of the administration to destroy <PERSON> black </PERSON> leadership and black political power,'' <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said. State Sen. <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>, a Democrat, claims that more than half the black elected officials in the state are under investigation or surveillance. But <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> of <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is colorblind. `` We're equal-opportunity prosecutors,'' he said. `` We'll prosecute any crook in the district, any time. At <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Donaldson </PERSON> said the harassment accusations were too absurd to deserve comment. As for <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON>' claim that half of the black officials are targets of some kind of investigation, `` It does n't ring true to me,'' said <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Shockley </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. At <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON>'s request, state Attorney General <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegelman </PERSON> named a special prosecutor to investigate actions of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON> said he wanted a determination of whether agents `` engaged in criminal solicitation, conspiracy, attempted bribery and-or obstruction'' of <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION>'s government. Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday that the panel's staff is making a preliminary investigation and a decision will be made later on whether to refer the matter to the full committee The assistant counsel for the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Responsibility </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Bobzien </PERSON>, said he and an investigator will visit <LOCATION> Birmingham </LOCATION> next week to conduct interviews in response to a request by <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON>'s attorney. <PERSON> Bobzien </PERSON>'s office was created in 1975 to look into complaints about employees of the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and other investigative agencies. It was disclosed this week that <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON> has been a subject of <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> scrutiny at various times dating back to 1972 when he was a city councilman supporting blacks alleging police brutality. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigated <PERSON> Arrington </PERSON> for possible bribery and financial conflicts of interest involving his business partners but no charges have been filed. The mayor was interviewed by the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> in 1985. A report Thursday in the <ORGANIZATION> Birmingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Herald </ORGANIZATION> also said that a new series of court-sanctioned <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> wiretaps has been used to monitor the telephone conversations of at least two members of the <LOCATION> Jefferson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> legislative delegation, Reps. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> and <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> wiretaps were used last year in the investigation that led to the indictments in the dog track case. <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> declined to comment on the latest wiretaps. `` I have been operating on the assumption that the phone was tapped,'' <PERSON> Rogers </PERSON> said. `` I resent the investigation. I have n't done anything.'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Polson </PERSON>, a lawyer representing Ms. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, said he did not have `` the foggiest idea'' why her phone was tapped but says it is `` more than a coincidence that it is the black politicians who are catching all the heat.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UndergroundSchools     06-16 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Underground Schools,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palestinians Battle Growing Illiteracy in Underground Schools</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY SEDOR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KAFR EIN, Occupied West Bank (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A half dozen 8-year-olds sat on the floor of a makeshift classroom in this <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> village and leafed through a science book on animals. Some drew Palestinian flags in the margins, but none could read the simple text. `` If they were in school, they'd be able to read by now,'' said <PERSON> Najah </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON>, the children's 15-year-old teacher. `` I'm trying to get them to memorize some words, but it just is n't enough.'' Illiteracy is growing among the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s 230,000 elementary school children, who have been deprived of an education for 16 months as a result of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s closure of schools. Classrooms have remained empty for all but a few weeks since Feb. 3, 1988. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> authorities say they closed the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION>'s 1,194 schools, including 145 kindergartens, because they were breeding grounds for violent protests during the 18-month Palestinian uprising. Fifteen schools in the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> also have been closed, but the army has not shut down the entire system. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has come under increasing international pressure, including a call from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, to end what many consider a collective punishment and to reopen classes when the closure order comes up for renewal on Monday. `` We would like to see the schools open but without an escalation of violence and without an increase in danger that children would be injured in the process. That's our concern, and Mr. <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>'s concern, as well,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON> said in an interview. To try to keep students from falling too far behind, Palestinians have been running underground classes in more than 100 <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> towns and villages in defiance of army orders outlawing such alternative education. The lessons are taught in unused buildings, mosques, churches or even in the open air, shaded by a tree. But, according to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> educators, these so-called `` people's schools'' have produced mixed results. `` The problem we face now is illiteracy,'' said <PERSON> Khalil </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahshi </PERSON>, principal of the Quaker-run <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ramallah </LOCATION>. `` Instead of consolidating reading skills at ages 7 to 9, we are dealing with children as old as 9 years old who are illiterate.'' <PERSON> Malashi </PERSON> said some children from poorer families, who have taken on unskilled jobs to supplement meager family incomes, may become permanent dropouts. And wealthy Palestinians, concerned about the educational prospects for their children, are leaving for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. `` Long term, the community is going to pay a price at the level of development, production and skilled manpower. This is the biggest asset of any society,'' he said. The second-graders studying in a cramped one-room stone house in <PERSON> Kafr </PERSON> <PERSON> Ein </PERSON>, a village of 1,000 about 25 miles north of <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>, spent a recent science class drawing pictures of donkeys, chickens and camels. <PERSON> Samir </PERSON>, a dark-eyed 7-year-old, carefully sketched two outlawed <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> flags onto the hump of his camel. `` I'd like to be able to read. It is important,'' he said in a small, serious voice. `` Instead, I can draw a Palestinian flag.'' Grades one through six in <PERSON> Kafr </PERSON> <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> study two hours each day, doubling up two classes at a time on opposite sides of the room. There are no classes for the upper grades, and the only teaching materials in evidence were two tattered primary-level science books, some colored markers and two chalkboards. But teaching materials were n't the only thing missing. The second-graders' 15-year-old teacher, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahmoud </PERSON>, only in 9th grade herself, conceded she has no teaching qualifications. `` What I can give them is better than nothing, but it ca n't compare with what they'd be learning in school,'' she said Besides teaching basic Arabic and math to her fourth-grade class, instructor <PERSON> Manah </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>, 20 teaches a new subject called `` national education'' ordered in April by uprising leaders linked to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. `` I teach them about the intefadeh and how not to be afraid of the soldiers when they come to the village,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Abbas </PERSON>, who wore an enamel necklace showing all Palestine, including <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, painted in the colors of the outlawed Palestinian flag.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Israel-LastTemptation     06-16 0212</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel-Last Temptation,0217</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Court Reverses Ban on `Last Temptation' Film</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has overturned a ban on <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON>'s film, `` The Last Temptation of Christ,'' though the judges said the movie is likely to offend some people. The country's 27-member Theater and <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Censorship </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> banned the film last October. The panel cited a criminal law that forbids practices offensive to the beliefs of any religious group. The movie, adapted from a 1955 novel by <PERSON> Nikos </PERSON> <PERSON> Kazanthakis </PERSON>, touched off protests by <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> groups in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Some Christians have been offended by <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON>'s portrayal of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> as a human being with passions and weaknesses. In reversing the ban Thursday, the five-judge panel said it was `` not enough that the movie is likely to stir up opposition or even offense against a portion of those who choose to see it.'' <PERSON> Amnon </PERSON> <PERSON> Globus </PERSON> of Golan-Globus Cannon, the film's <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> distributors who appealed the case to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, said its decision signaled `` the end of censorship'' in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` The ones who have to judge whether a movie should be shown or not is the public,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Globus </ORGANIZATION>. He said the movie would be shown in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> by next week, after Hebrew subtitles are completed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-16 1016</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1052</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainer <PERSON> Kris </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON> and his wife, honoring a promise to their slain housekeeper, have become guardians of the woman's three daughters. The Malibu couple's request was granted Tuesday by <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothman </PERSON> after several days of closed hearings to decide custody of <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Juana </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>'s children. <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON>, said they wanted keep a promise they made to her a week before her death: to see that her children were taken care of should anything happen to her. <PERSON> Rothman </PERSON> granted co-guardianship to the woman's sister, <PERSON> Vicenta </PERSON> <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>, with whom the children will live in <LOCATION> Culver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He refused a guardianship request from the family of <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arauz </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty in March to second-degree murder in the shooting death of his common-law wife, Ms. <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON>. The father's relatives had sought guardianship of the two children fathered by <PERSON> Arauz </PERSON>: <PERSON> Maria </PERSON>, 4, and <PERSON> Marta </PERSON>, 9. The father of their 12-year-old half-sister, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON>, lives in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The youngsters' 32-year-old mother had faithfully served the <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON> family as a housekeeper for 10 years, according to court documents. Shortly before she died, Ms. <PERSON> Aguilar </PERSON> confided in Mrs. <PERSON> Kristofferson </PERSON> that she feared for her life because of her husband's beatings A week later, she was shot three times and killed.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Burstyn </PERSON> will be Broadway's new `` <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentine </PERSON>.'' The actress who won a Tony Award for her performance in `` Same Time, Next Year'' and an Oscar for `` Alice Does n't Live Here Anymore'' takes over the title role in <PERSON> Willy </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON>'s one-woman comedy July 17, a spokesman for the show said Thursday. <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> who won the 1989 best actress Tony Award for her portrayal of <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON>, a bored English housewife who runs off to <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, leaves the play July 1. From July 3 through July 15, the role will be played by <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Kilgarriff </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Valentine </PERSON>'' won the 1989 Olivier Award in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> as best comedy of the year and also was nominated for a Tony Award as best play.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The cops may be good at nabbing criminals, but they have n't been doing very well selling 30,000 <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronstadt </PERSON> concert tickets to raise money for a sports center for young people. But prospects for selling the $ 10 tickets looked better after the police officers' plight was publicized Thursday by the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've been getting a lot of calls from a lot of different people, including some publicity agents, coming on board to help us,'' said Officer <PERSON> Dale </PERSON> <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s Hollenbeck Division `` People read the article and want to get involved and help us out.'' The newspaper story explained how Sgt. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> was dejected because he had volunteered to sell tickets to the July 1-2 <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ronstadt </PERSON> concerts, but had sold only 3,000 of the 30,000 by Wednesday. `` Where do I go from here,'' <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> had asked rhetorically. `` It's so much easier for me to go out on patrol and put my suspect in jail and go home. <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> came up with the concert idea to raise money to help meet higher operating costs of the police department's soon-to-expand <ORGANIZATION> Hollenbeck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where 10,000 youths each year participate in boxing, karate, baseball and basketball programs. <PERSON> Ronstadt </PERSON> agreed to do the benefit concerts if the police promoted them. A Hollywood production firm helped <PERSON> Gomez </PERSON> with public relations, and he hoped to get by with a tiny budget for posters and public service announcements. `` They do n't tell you they run them at 3 in the morning when nobody is up,'' he said with disgust.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON> is suing a drug store chain over a photograph of her baby that disappeared from a set of newly developed snapshots and turned up in a supermarket tabloid. Miss <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON>, star of `` The Cosby Show'' and the movie `` Angel Heart,'' filed suit Wednesday in federal court saying that when she picked up developed film from a neighborhood <LOCATION> Osco </LOCATION> Drug Store in suburban <LOCATION> Reseda </LOCATION>, a negative and photograph of her then 3-week-old daughter, <PERSON> Zoe </PERSON>, was missing. The National Enquirer ran the photo Jan. 10 with an article on Miss <PERSON> Bonet </PERSON> and musician-husband <PERSON> Lenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Kravitz </PERSON> that congratulated baby <PERSON> Zoe </PERSON> for transforming the actress `` from a high-kicking hell-raiser'' to a `` doting mother.'' The lawsuit asks for unspecified general damages and $ 5 million in punitive damages. The complaint does n't name the tabloid, but it accuses <LOCATION> Osco </LOCATION>'s parent company, <ORGANIZATION> Anaheim-based </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, of `` willful, wanton, malicious and oppressive'' conduct in its handling of <PERSON> Zoe </PERSON>'s photo. A corporate spokeswoman said no one was available to comment, and the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> bureau of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enquirer </ORGANIZATION> refused to comment.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>McLEAN, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Comedians Chevy Chase and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, talk show hosts <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Letterman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>, and weatherman <PERSON> Willard </PERSON> <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> admit to tying one on _ an ugly tie, that is. And they've donated the offensive cravats to a fund-raiser called `` Ugly Ties of the Rich and Famous.'' Anyone looking for the traditional Father's Day present can bid on them Sunday at a silent auction to benefit <ORGANIZATION> Big </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Capital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Leukemia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION>. The auction at a local hotel is open to members of the public, who may buy the ties or simply view the collection before the bidding begins.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>, who recently played <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> in a TV movie, has pleaded innocent to drunken driving charges. The 33-year-old actor, who also has played in the movies `` An Officer and a Gentleman'' and `` Lords of Discipline,'' was absent from the <ORGANIZATION> Municipal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing Thursday, but his attorney, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapiro </PERSON>, entered his plea, and <PERSON> Keith </PERSON> was allowed to remain free on his own recognizance. The charges stem from a crash about midnight May 20, when <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>'s 1988 Ford Mustang collided with another car in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> No one was seriously injured. <PERSON> Keith </PERSON>'s blood alcohol level tested at .18 percent, almost double the state standard for drunken driving.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0053EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Salvador-Unionist     06-16 0203</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Salvador-Unionist,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Leader Reported Free After Torture</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN SALVADOR, El Salvador (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A union leader who claims he was arrested by <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION>, accused of leftist ties and tortured was released Thursday, a spokesman for his group said. The union official, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Tomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazariego </PERSON>, disappeared Monday after leaving the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. He reportedly sought a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visa because he was to leave the next day for a visit at the invitation of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> labor groups. Witnesses said he was picked up by men in civilian clothes who did not identify themselves. A spokesman for <PERSON> Mazariego </PERSON>'s group, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION>, said in a telephone interview that <PERSON> Mazariego </PERSON> was released at 5 p.m. Thursday. The spokesman, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Mazariego </PERSON> reported that police accused him of links to leftist guerrilla organizations and burned his body with acid. A spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Trenton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.J. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Mazariego </PERSON> had been scheduled to give a talk in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> on Thursday and in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> on June 19. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> is the largest labor union in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Marzariego </PERSON> also serves as an official of the <ORGANIZATION> Salvadoran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telecommunications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Noriega-Laundering     06-16 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Noriega-Laundering,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reports Documents Show Noriega Deposited $50 Million</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s leader <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> has deposited at least $ 50 million in secret bank accounts since 1982, according to documents seized in a money laundering investigation, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reports. The network reported Thursday that the documents were seized in October in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> by British authorities after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s bank, the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, was indicted in the drug money case in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. British authorities this week gave <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> investigators more than 1,000 documents and show that the Panamanian general controlled up to seven secret accounts, according to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. According to the documents, <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> deposited at least $ 50 million since he opened the accounts seven years ago while his <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> salary was about $ 50,000 a year, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said. In one transaction, $ 27 million of <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s money was transferred out of a secret account in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> to one in <LOCATION> Luxembourg </LOCATION> just one day after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted on drug charges in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, according to the report. Authorities whom <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> did not identify said one key document is a letter from <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to his banker, <PERSON> Amjad </PERSON> <PERSON> Awan </PERSON>, instructing him that the accounts must be kept secret and that no bank statements ever be sent to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said authorities believe that most of the money came from <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s dealings with Colombian drug bosses, international arms dealers and the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, which reportedly had <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> on its payroll. The <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Credit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> was charged in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, in October 1988 with laundering millions of dollars in cocaine profits collected in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> cities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FirebombDeath Bjt   06-16 0695</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Firebomb Death, Bjt,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Firebomb Killing of Baby Leads to Legal Questions About Young Suspect</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOYT HARWELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GADSDEN, Ala. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-ager charged in the firebombing death of a baby has become a focus of disputes about racial justice, the death penalty for juveniles and whether <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> is imposing its legal standards on <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> is expected to decide soon whether <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> can extradite the black 17-year-old, known in court documents only as O.M. because of his juvenile status. Prosecutors deny race has anything to do with the matter, and the baby's relatives and an <ORGANIZATION> NAACP </ORGANIZATION> official agree. `` It does n't make any difference to me what color somebody is, black, white or polka dot,'' said District Attorney <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hedgespeth </PERSON>. `` What a lot of folks are not saying is that the victim of this crime was black. There is no place on my docket for white or black. It does n't matter to me.'' O.M. was charged with murder and arson in the death of 14-month-old <PERSON> Tamel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. The baby died in a kitchen blaze on the night of May 12, 1988, after a plastic jug of gasoline was tossed into his apartment at a housing project where a relative had been involved in a fight. The teen-ager's grandmother testified at a court hearing in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that the white authorities in <LOCATION> Etowah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, a mostly rural area that includes the steel city of <LOCATION> Gadsden </LOCATION>, have a longstanding vendetta against her family. The youth's father and uncle died in police custody, she said. <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> police captured the boy in December only after his grandmother, <PERSON> Alyce </PERSON> <PERSON> Guice </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, was jailed for 82 days last summer by an <LOCATION> Etowah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> judge for failing to produce the teen-ager in court. She said he disappeared the night of the fire, after police released him to her custody. The jailing set off small civil rights demonstrations in <LOCATION> Gadsden </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> passed legislation May 30 intended to block the teen-ager's return to <LOCATION> Gadsden </LOCATION> for 90 days. Council members said extradition would violate the district's ban on the death penalty, because if O.M. is convicted in <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>, he could face execution in the electric chair. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has heard arguments but not yet ruled on a challenge to the death penalty for those who were minors when they committed crimes. The <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION> boy was 16 at the time of <PERSON> Tamel </PERSON>'s death A <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> ruled March 30 that O.M. should be returned to <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>. But the extradition was delayed until after his appeal, which could make the council's action moot. <PERSON> Hedgespeth </PERSON> would not say what he has decided about whether to seek the death penalty. `` They're fanning enough flames up there in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` I'm just sitting here keeping my mouth shut.'' He said county blacks who gave him 90 percent of their vote when he was elected `` asked two things of me _ that I prosecute black-on-black crime just like anybody else, and that I not systematically strike blacks from juries.'' He said that in his 2 -LCB- years in the office, he has followed both requests. Sol Reynolds, <PERSON> Tamel </PERSON>'s uncle, said race has nothing to do with the charges against the 17-year-old. `` If they want to talk about being mistreated, the baby was the one mistreated because he is dead and gone,'' <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Tamel </PERSON>'s grandmother, <PERSON> Emma </PERSON> <PERSON> Nell </PERSON> <PERSON> Rutledge </PERSON>, said she wants whoever killed the baby to get what they deserve. Three people, all black, have been charged with arson and murder. <PERSON> Yul </PERSON> <PERSON> Devoe </PERSON> <PERSON> Guice </PERSON>, 31, who is suspected of throwing the plastic jug of gasoline into the project apartment, is in the county jail. The other alleged accomplice has not been found. <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Gadsden </LOCATION> physician who heads the local chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advancement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Colored </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION>, said he believes O.M. would get as fair a trial at home as anywhere. `` It seems to me we all want to see justice dealt out,'' <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> said. `` I have n't gotten the opinion that we are any better or worse off than some of the other areas in the country.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0247EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Thailand-Crash     06-16 0102</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Thailand-Crash,0103</SECOND>
<HEAD>16 Killed, 30 Injured in Bus Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sixteen people were killed and 30 injured when a local tourist bus and a truck collided in southeastern <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, police said today. Police Lt. <PERSON> Rathsith </PERSON> <PERSON> Doungngung </PERSON> said the accident occurred Thursday near <LOCATION> Chanthaburi </LOCATION>, about 130 miles southeast of the capital <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rathsith </PERSON> said both the bus and truck drivers fled the scene of the accident. The crash was the second accident involving a tourist bus in <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION> this month. On June 7, 22 people were killed when a tour bus was struck by a truck in central <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ChildrenandGuns Bjt   06-16 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Children and Guns, Bjt,740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen Tells Congress of Gun-Toting Child Drug Dealers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROLYN SKORNECK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The teen-ager sat gingerly at the witness table and spoke so softly that the congressmen had trouble hearing her. But there was nothing gentle or innocent in the tale she told of children carrying guns to carry out the drug trade. `` You can get guns on the street just about as easily as you can get candy,'' <PERSON> Detra </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, whose last name was not revealed, told the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Select </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Children </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> and Families on Thursday. `` Everyone knows how to get a gun if they want one. The guns range from .22 s to 9 millimeters to Uzis. Generally, she said, the youngsters get their guns from the drug traffickers for whom they work. `` If they hustle for a person _ he's a runner or a hit man _ he's getting a gun to carry out the orders the man has given him,'' said <PERSON> Detra </PERSON>, 18 The hearing on children and guns occurred one day after <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> asked state lawmakers for a law that would punish people who leave firearms within reach of children. Pediatrician <PERSON> Katherine </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Christoffel </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, representing the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pediatrics </ORGANIZATION>, painted a grim picture for the panel: `` Ten <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> children ages 18 and under are killed every day in handgun suicides, homicides and accidents,'' she said. `` Three or four times as many are wounded. One of every 25 admissions to American pediatric trauma centers is due to gunshot wounds. In 1987, gun injuries were the fourth-leading cause of unintentional-injury death for children ages 14 and under. For inner-city black adolescent boys and young men, firearm injuries are the leading cause of death.'' But <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleck </PERSON>, an associate professor of criminology at <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said accidental shootings of innocent bystanders `` are extremely rare,'' that the involvement of guns in youth suicide has fallen since 1979, and that fatal gun accidents involving youths, as well as for all people, have been declining for 20 years. Nevertheless, <PERSON> Detra </PERSON> said she knows eight people who have been shot to death, and more who have been wounded. Of those killed, she said, `` Half had guns and were in a gunfight, and half of them were innocent bystanders.'' Drug-related killings have given <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> the nation's highest per capita murder rate. So far this year, 202 murders have been committed in the District, compared to 133 at this time last year. Most have been drug-related, police say. The lure of dramatic monetary rewards in the drug trade inspires youngsters to get involved even when they see friends killed, said <PERSON> Detra </PERSON>, who graduated from high school last year and now works for a local recreation program to keep young people off the streets. `` They get involved because they want fast money, to buy cars, jewelry and radios. They do n't get jobs because the pay is too low,'' she said. Youngsters `` look at the hustlers as role models,'' in part because they have money and in part because they `` are nice to the young children,'' she said. <PERSON> Detra </PERSON> said one way to curtail youthful involvement in the drug trade is to offer better jobs at better wages. She also said youngsters need alternative role models, `` other adults who are willing to talk and spend time'' with younger children. Meanwhile, she dismissed many ideas offered by lawmakers as ways to deter young people from getting access to guns. Holding parents liable for their children's use of weapons will fail because `` there's not too many youth today who talk to their parents,'' she said. `` It's not a family bond anymore'' and parents do n't have control over their drug-dealing children. Fear of arrest and a substantial prison term for carrying a firearm also wo n't deter those in the drug trade because they feel `` it's not going to happen to me,'' she said. The only thing that might change their minds is if authorities `` lock them up so they understand it's not so easy to carry a gun and get away with it. ... They're not going to believe it until they see it.'' Passing laws making it more difficult to buy guns legally also wo n't work, <PERSON> Detra </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> has one of the toughest gun control laws in the country, yet young people have no trouble obtaining them illegally, she said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Germany-GorbachevPostcript Bjt   06-16 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Gorbachev Postcript, Bjt,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Glow of Soviet-West German Summit May Not Linger</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto DSSD1</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK J. PORUBCANSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s four-day visit to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> was enveloped by good feelings and kind words that will be difficult to translate into personal political gain. Both the Soviet president and West German Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> face an array of domestic difficulties that can not be washed away by several days of friendly, high-profile meetings. Although <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s great popularity abroad adds to his prestige and the status of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, it has not touched fundamental problems that trouble millions of Soviets _ a continued lack of food and consumer goods, housing shortages and stifling bureaucracy. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> and his <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> party have suffered in state elections the past two years, losing control of major West German cities. The chancellor is accused of mishandling recent controversies, such as the disclosure of a West German role in an alleged Libyan chemical weapons plant and the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> furor over short-range nuclear weapons. The summit produced a historic joint declaration of goals for easing tensions in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and boosted trust and confidence between Soviets and West Germans. But it was devoted mostly to creating a positive atmosphere and skirted sensitive issues like the future of divided <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and differing approaches to disarmament. After years when their tottering leaders were an embarrassment, Soviets have become accustomed to seeing foreign crowds cheering their leader. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> remains popular at home, but many Soviets are beginning to question when and if his reform policies will improve living standards. While he was away, other Soviet officials were struggling with what has become a chronic problem _ an outbreak of violence between ethnic groups, this time in the Central Asian republic of <LOCATION> Uzbekistan </LOCATION>. Reasons for the unrest are not clear, but some blame an economic collapse caused by overcrowding and unemployment. In <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> continually stressed the theme of cooperation. If the two countries do cooperate more closely, it could help the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in two ways. A lessening of military tension would allow <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to turn more of its industrial potential to producing consumer goods. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has said he needs a lessening of international tension to devote more resources to the ailing economy. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> invited finance and industry leaders in <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION> to help convert Soviet defense industries. That offers another avenue to improving the Soviet economy _ increased investment by West German business. <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> is the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s largest Western trading partner, and businessmen showed the Soviet leader a dazzling array of high technology. But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> stressed that he did not come as a beggar. He emphasized cooperation, proposing to merge the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s abilities in basic scientific research with West German technology for the benefit of both sides <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s problems are of an entirely different nature, but no less threatening. His party currently polls less support than the leftist Social Democrats and risks losing national elections in December 1990. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s slide was arrested somewhat after the even higher-profile visit two weeks ago of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, with whom he was photographed frequently during a summit that lasted less than two days. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> came to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> immediately after the <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> summit in <LOCATION> Brussels </LOCATION> on May 29-30, at which <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> were able to mend fences after a months-long dispute over negotiating with the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc to reduce short-range rockets. Having salvaged a compromise from a confrontation that threatened alliance unity, <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> was riding high during the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visit. His three sessions with <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also likely boosted his prestige. <PERSON> Ralf </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuecks </PERSON>, a leader of the far-left <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, remarked after the summit that `` Chancellor <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON> had tried to sun himself in <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s glow.'' The effects should be apparent this weekend. <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s party is running candidates for top posts in Rhineland-Palatine and <LOCATION> Saarland </LOCATION> states Sunday as well as <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> elections.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Porubcansky </PERSON>, based in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, has covered <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs for The Associated Press since 1987.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890616-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-16-89 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CoalStrike 2ndLd-Writethru a0806 06-16 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coal Strike, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0806,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>Strike Spreads to Northern W.Va. Coal Field</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf to CORRECT name to Trumka sted Trumpka and number
of workers to 6,500 sted 10,000.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK PAXTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
