<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 2328EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Greece     03-12 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Greece,0530</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S Denies Purported CIA Agent Worked for Agency</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PATRICK QUINN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government has denied it was behind a multi-million-dollar banking scandal that has rocked <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s governing Socialist party. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, in a statement released to the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Sunday, also said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government never hired a self-proclaimed <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent who made the allegation. A spokesperson for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, who requested anonymity, said the statement was given to the state-run television and radio networks Saturday, but by mid-day Sunday it had received no airplay. Premier <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s party, the <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> PASOK </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, faced a censure vote Monday brought by the conservative opposition on grounds the government's alleged involvement in a $ 200-million fraud, forgery and embezzlement scandal threatens the country's security. <LOCATION> PASOK </LOCATION>, with 157 seats in the 300-single chamber <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, was expected to weather the motion during a voice vote. The purported agent, <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mailis </PERSON>, told a parliamentary fact-finding committee last week that fugitive banker <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> was a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> employee trying to destabilize <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s government <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> is jailed in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> pending an extradition hearing. He faces charges in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> in connection with the scandal. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> government categorically states that the reported allegations of Mr. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Mailis </PERSON> concerning his connections with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government are completely without foundation,'' said the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> statement released through the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Athens </LOCATION>. The statement, issued `` as an exception to our general policy of not commenting on such matters,'' added that `` neither he nor the others he reportedly has alleged to work for the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> now work or ever have worked for the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>.'' On Saturday, <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> threatened the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that there would be `` consequences'' if banker-publisher <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON> was not quickly extradited to <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. Speaking before <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> during a debate on the censure motion, <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> did not describe the `` consequences'' but made a reference to his government's decision to shut down one of four <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military installations in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. He said talks on a new <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bases agreement were continuing, `` but their -LRB- bases -RRB- time of stay in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> is running out daily.'' The main conservative opposition <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> submitted the censure motion Thursday on the grounds that alleged government involvement in the scandal posed a `` danger for democracy and <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Koskotas </PERSON>, 34, former chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crete </ORGANIZATION>, fled <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> in November after being indicted in the scandal. He is jailed in <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass </LOCATION>. Time magazine, in an interview with the banker, quoted him as saying <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> and senior government officials allegedly authorized plans to embezzle millions from his bank. He also claimed they received millions of dollars in payoffs. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, who said he will sue Time for running the interview in its March 13 issue, has charged that there is a `` foreign and domestic plot'' to overthrow his government. To back up the premier's claims of an international conspiracy against him, the state-run television networks and pro-government press have played up the allegations made by <PERSON> Mailis </PERSON> to a parliamentary fact-finding committee investigating the scandal.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Ferriola     03-12 0197</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Ferriola,0204</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reputed Chicago Crime Boss Dies After Heart Surgery</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON>, the reputed chieftain of organized crime in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, died Saturday following his second heart transplant in recent weeks. He was 61. <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON> died at 2:50 a.m. in <LOCATION> Methodist </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he was a patient of well-known heart specialist Dr. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> DeBakey </PERSON>, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Cindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lea </PERSON> said. She said she had no further information. <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON> had undergone two heart transplants in the last few weeks, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> television stations <ORGANIZATION> WLS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> WBBM </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. His body rejected the first heart and was rejecting the second when he died, <ORGANIZATION> WLS </ORGANIZATION> said. Federal officials said <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON> emerged as the head of organized crime in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> in 1986, after prison sentences were handed to long-time reputed boss <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> `` Doves'' Aiuppa and No. 2 man <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> `` </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackey </PERSON> the Lackey'' <PERSON> Cerone </PERSON>. Aiuppa, 81, and <PERSON> Cerone </PERSON>, 74, received 28 -LCB- - year prison terms for skimming profits from <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> gambling casinos In the early 1970s, <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON> served a federal prison term for taking part in a multimillion-dollar nationwide gambling syndicate, <PERSON> Healy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ferriola </PERSON> lived in a 14-room mansion in the wealthy western <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Brook </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0036EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BigBendFire     03-12 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Big Bend Fire,0301</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fire Races Through Park, Forces Evacuation of Campers</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BIG BEND NATIONAL PARK, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fire roared through 500 acres of the Big Bend National Park on Saturday, forcing the evacuation of about 100 campers, authorities said. No injuries were reported. `` We speculate it's man-caused,'' said Big Bend National Park spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Rothe </PERSON>. `` We have n't had any lightning strikes in the area.'' Seventeen firefighters battled the High Chisos mountains blaze which campers reported early Saturday afternoon. A fire crew of Mescalero Apache Indians from <LOCATION> Alamogordo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION> was expected Sunday to help fight the fire. ` I can look out the window and see the glow of the fire up in the mountains,'' said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, an assistant manager at <LOCATION> Chisos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lodge </LOCATION> located about 2,000 feet below and at least five miles from the fire. `` The glow of the fire appears over <ORGANIZATION> Emory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peak </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said. Emory Peak, at 7,830 feet, is the highest point in the <LOCATION> Chisos </LOCATION> range. The fire burned woodlands, mostly oak, pine and juniper and trails in the <LOCATION> Chisos </LOCATION> were closed, officials said. About 100 campers, mostly college students on spring break, were evacuated from the <LOCATION> High </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chisos </LOCATION> area, said park ranger <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rothe </PERSON> said park officials believe the fire would n't spread much Saturday night because of a combination of weather conditions, including falling temperature and wind speed, and rising humidity. The blaze is the first in the 708,221-acre southwest <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> park this year, Ms. <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> said. Last year there were 27 brush fires, she said, but only two scorched more than 300 acres. The <LOCATION> Chisos </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lodge </LOCATION> was filled to capacity with more than 140 visitors Saturday night, <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> said. He said officials told him the fire presented no immediate danger to the lodge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Nicaragua-Rebels     03-12 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nicaragua-Rebels,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Report Eight Killed in Rebel Attack on Village</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rebels attacked an eastern village Saturday and in the battle six of the raiders and two local officials were killed, the Sandinista government said. <PERSON> Terencio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Marenco </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinista </ORGANIZATION> party leader in the village of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Iguanas </LOCATION>, 180 miles east of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>, said two young girls were wounded in the fighting early Saturday. He identified the slain government officials as 2nd Lt. <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, the village's civil defense chief, and <PERSON> Panfilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lira </PERSON>, head of the agricultural cooperative. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Marenco </PERSON> said the rebels belonged to a group that recently entered <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION>. Last week the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> accused rebel forces of making more than 140 attacks against Nicaraguan military and civilian targets this year in `` open violation of the cease-fire.'' The rebels' radio station <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberacion </ORGANIZATION> said Saturday that Sandinista troops had violated the cease-fire 69 times in 1989. The Sandinistas and rebels agreed to a temporary cease-fire in March 1988 but peace talks subsequently broke down. The government then declared a monthly series of unilateral cease-fires beginning in June 1988 and the insurgents tacitly accepted the truce. Both sides claim they have respected the cease-fires.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-Bush-WhyCheney 1stLd-Writethru a0507 03-12 0765</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Why Cheney, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0507,710</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Defense Nominee Quickly Available and Quickly Confirmable</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf pvs, bgng: ``In picking...'' to make it six-term;
picks up 3rd graf pvs, bgng: ``And while...''</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Cheney-Senate Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At first glance, Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> might seem an unlikely candidate to run the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, but his selection by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> won early rave reviews in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. In picking the six-term Republican from <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> moved quickly on Friday to fill the void left by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s rejection of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> less than 24 hours earlier. And while the announcement caught most political leaders by surprise, the <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> choice at once fulfilled two objectives <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> advisers had cited as critical: someone quickly available and someone quickly confirmable. To allow the politically divisive Tower defeat to fester over the weekend _ and to be churned over on Sunday television talk shows and in newspaper columns _ would have not been helpful to the president. So far, the move-quick strategy seems to be working. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders announced immediately that they would hold confirmation hearings in the coming week. `` Congressman <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> is well known and highly respected by the members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>,'' the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>, D-Ga., and the panel's ranking Republican, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, said in a joint statement Although <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, 48, lacks direct defense experience, he is a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and was senior Republican on the 15-member special panel that investigated the Iran-Contra affair. Equally important, he served as President <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>'s chief of staff. In selecting <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON>, whom <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> praised as a `` widely respected man of principle,'' the president repeated what he had done in filling many other Cabinet slots _ he reached back and picked someone whom had served in a previous Republican administration and with whom he had enjoyed a close working relationship. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> did not get wind of what was in store until Thursday _ as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was at work rejecting Tower _ when he got telephone calls from chief of staff <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sununu </PERSON> and national security adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself did n't contact the candidate until just hours before the official announcement. The president's choice makes sense, said <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON>, a political analyst for the <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enterprise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. `` You would n't have thought of him initially because he's not a defense specialist. But in terms of respect in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, he's near the top of everyone's list. `` If <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> ca n't make it through the confirmation process, no one can,'' <PERSON> Ornstein </PERSON> said. `` <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had to find someone who could sail through, and it was a wise choice.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself called <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> `` a thoughtful man, a quiet man, a strong man'' who `` approaches public policy with vigor, determination and diligence.'' And, judging from early reaction, most members of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> appear to agree. <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> has few detractors. `` I have the greatest respect for his broad range of experience and knowledge,'' said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCain </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ariz </LOCATION>., a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who had been one of Tower's strongest `` I look favorably on this nomination and hope that he will be confirmed expeditiously.'' `` An excellent choice,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Robb </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, one of the last Democrats to announce opposition to Tower. `` Unless there is a complete void in that area -LRB- defense -RRB-, the confirmation should move rapidly.'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> praised <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> as a man who `` served with distinction'' in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and promised `` prompt consideration by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> and the full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>.'' For his part, <PERSON> Cheney </PERSON> said he had `` extensive views on defense policy'' and said he was `` eager to get to work.'' White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said there was a consensus in the White House that the clock was ticking after the Tower defeat. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was being `` encouraged by everyone to do it in a hurry,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> himself said if he had made a mistake in handling the Tower nomination, it was the long delay in sending it to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. `` So when it became clear -LRB- Thursday -RRB- that the votes were n't there ... I began to think and talk to my top advisers here, get opinions from them,'' said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. And when he finally talked to <LOCATION> Cheney </LOCATION> at 1 p.m. on Friday, the president recalled: `` I said I want to make a decision fast on this, because I know him well and have known him over the years well. And so ... that's about the way it evolved.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0109EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Honduras-Paraguay     03-12 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Honduras-Paraguay,0251</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Paraguayan Interior Minister Seeks Refuge in Honduras</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By FREDDY CUEVAS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Sabino </PERSON> <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Paraguayan </LOCATION> interior minister who sought political asylum after the ouster of President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, arrived in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> Saturday. `` I will be permanently grateful to the government and the people of <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON> told reporters at the <LOCATION> Tegucigalpa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON>, 66, sought asylum in the <ORGANIZATION> Honduran </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in the Paraguayan capital of <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> on Feb. 3 after <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was forced from office in a bloody coup. He left the embassy early Saturday, two days after the new Paraguayan government granted him a safe-conduct pass to leave the country. Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who led the coup against <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, dissolved <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> after being sworn in as president and has said national elections will be held May 1. Gen. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, who ruled <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> for 34 years, fled to <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> where he is living in exile. There were reports that as many as 300 people were killed during the coup but <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> has said the casualties, including dead and wounded, did not exceed 50. <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON>'s flight on the Brazilian airline <ORGANIZATION> Varig </ORGANIZATION> left <LOCATION> Asuncion </LOCATION> Saturday after a two-hour delay blamed on a false bomb threat. He was accompanied by his wife, <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>, his children <PERSON> Augusto </PERSON> and <PERSON> Silvia </PERSON>, and the <LOCATION> Honduran </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Suazo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tome </PERSON>. The Honduran government of President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Azcona </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyo </PERSON> made no comment on <PERSON> Montanaro </PERSON>'s arrival.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0110EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-EscapeeStandoff     03-12 0451</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Escapee Standoff,0466</SECOND>
<HEAD>Escapee Dies as Gunfight, Fire End 12-hour Standoff with Police</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An escaped prisoner took six people hostage and held police at bay for 12 hours with an assault rifle, but died early Saturday when a fire and gun battle ended the standoff, officials said. <PERSON> Gomard </PERSON> <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON>, 30, released five of the hostages, including a police officer, and the sixth escaped 10 minutes after a tear gas cannister started a fire in a second-floor apartment in the <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Waipahu </LOCATION>. Police said it was not immediately clear whether <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> died in the fire, during the gunfight or by his own hand. He was armed with a Soviet-made AK-47 assault rifle, authorities said. <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> fired at least seven bursts of three shots each during the standoff, said Sgt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaainoa </PERSON>. No one was injured by the bullets, police said. The standoff came to a head at 9:25 a.m. with a rapid exchange of gunfire between <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> and police. Police then fired tear gas into the apartment. Police decided to open fire because <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> had been shooting sporadically out of the apartment throughout the morning, said Maj. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Au </PERSON>, head of the detective division. `` We were afraid that some of these shots might injure someone in the community,'' Au said. <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> and 26-year-old <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> Frisbee </PERSON> escaped from the <ORGANIZATION> Oahu </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cetner </ORGANIZATION> on Thursday night by taking two guards hostage with a handgun. Frisbee remained at large Saturday, police said. Both escapees were awaiting trial on numerous charges, including the illegal possession of firearms and terroristic threatening, police said. Police said <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> took three children and an adult hostage around 10 p.m. Friday night. Police said the adult hostage was <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Busano </PERSON>, <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON>'s friend and father of the children. At 12:15 a.m. Saturday, <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> released the four hostages in exchange for a police officer and a man identified by witnesses as <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, 26. <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON> eventually allowed the officer to leave, according to <PERSON> Roselyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Ginger </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilheln </PERSON>, <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>'s girlfriend. <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> had a leg amputated last month after a gunshot wound became infected, according to his girlfriend, Ms. <PERSON> Wilheln </PERSON> said. He was taken from the apartment by police within 10 minutes of the start of the fire. Police and firefighters found <PERSON> Olayan </PERSON>'s body in the bathroom of the apartment. They entered the apartment at 10:33 a.m., about an hour after the fire broke out. A nursing supervisor at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> was in good condition. She did not specify <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>'s injuries. Police said <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> was arrested, but did not say what charges he faced. Residents of the <LOCATION> Nani </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gardens </LOCATION> apartment complex were evacuated and spent the night huddled in blankets at a nearby shopping center.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DirectorsAwards 1stLd-Writethru a0542 03-12 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Directors Awards, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0542,0646</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Rain Man' Director Receives Directors Guild Awards</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with eight grafs to UPDATE with winners. ADDS byline.
Picks up below dash material.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAUL REYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Levinson </PERSON>, director of the hit autism drama `` Rain Man,'' was selected best director of a feature film by the <ORGANIZATION> Directors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, as it honored its own at bi-coastal banquets Saturday. Other nominees for the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION>'s achievement award for film direction were <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> of the controversial civil-rights film `` Mississippi Burning''; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON>, who engineered the animated-live action blockbuster `` Who Framed Roger Rabbit''; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Chrichton </PERSON>, director of the crime-caper comedy `` A Fish Called Wanda''; and <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, who brought the corporate Cinderella saga `` Working Girl'' to the screen. The winner of the prestigious DGA trophy, as selected by the guild's 9,000 members, almost always repeats as best director in the Academy Awards. And because the Academy's best-directed film usually receives the best picture Oscar, the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> awards hold a special significance for the film community. In the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> television directing competition, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Miner </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was voted best director of a comedy series for the pilot episode of `` The Wonder Years.'' In other television awards, <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Herskovitz </PERSON> was voted best director of a nighttime dramatic series for the `` Therapy'' episode of the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> series `` thirtysomething;'' <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> was voted best director of a dramatic special for his program `` Lincoln'' on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Trevino </PERSON> was voted best director of a dramatic daytime show for the CBS schoolbreak special `` Gangs;'' <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> won for best director of a musical or variety program for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 100th Birthday Celebration -LRB- <LOCATION> Irving </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> -RRB-.'' Other television awards went to <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Coyle </PERSON> in sports for directing <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s presentation of the 1988 World Series; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Gartner </PERSON> in commercials for a series of ads, including one for major league baseball, and <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Brockway </PERSON> in documentaries for the <ORGANIZATION> PBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performances </ORGANIZATION> program `` On the Move.'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had each entered the evening with six nominations apiece, with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` thirtysomething'' holding two nominations. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> trailed with three nominations in the five television directing categories. The awards were presented Saturday night at <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Plaza Hotel, with a separate announcement scheduled to take place at the <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hotel </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 All but one of the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> nominees _ <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON> _ was also nominated for the best director <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON>. In <PERSON> Zemeckis </PERSON>' place, the <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sciences </ORGANIZATION> nominated <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Scorsese </PERSON>, director of the much-debated `` The Last Temptation of Christ.'' With only three exceptions, the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> award winner has repeated as the Academy Award winner. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Spielberg </PERSON> won the 1986 DGA award for `` The Color Purple'' while <PERSON> Syndey </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollack </PERSON> took the best director <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> for `` Out of <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' The <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION>'s 1973 trophy was given to <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON> <PERSON> Coppola </PERSON> for `` The Godfather,'' but <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Fosse </PERSON> was awarded the Academy Award for `` Cabaret.'' And in 1969, the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> selected <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> for `` The Lion in Winter'' while the Academy chose <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Reed </PERSON> for `` <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Bernardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertolucci </PERSON> won both the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> award and the Oscar in 1988 for `` The Last Emperor'' and <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> doubled in 1987 for `` Platoon.'' Both those films also won the best picture Oscar. Earlier this year, <PERSON> Clint </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastwood </PERSON> captured the <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> best director trophy for `` Bird,'' but he was not among the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION> or Oscar nominees. In other awards competitions this season, the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critics </ORGANIZATION> named <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronenberg </PERSON> best director for `` Dead Ringers,'' the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critics </ORGANIZATION> selected <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Menges </PERSON> for `` A World Apart'' and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Critics </ORGANIZATION> picked <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaufman </PERSON> for `` The Unbearable Lightness of Being.'' As previously announced, <PERSON> Sidney </PERSON> <PERSON> Lumet </PERSON>, director of such films as `` Serpico'' and `` Running on Empty,'' was named an honorary life member in the <ORGANIZATION> DGA </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0531EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Sudan-Cabinet     03-12 0324</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sudan-Cabinet,0337</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sudan Cabinet Resigns to Form Broader Government</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DALIA BALIGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KHARTOUM, Sudan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government has resigned under pressure from labor unions and the military over its failure to end <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>'s civil war Newspapers said Sunday the outgoing <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION>'s junior partner, the fundamentalist <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islamic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>, is expected to stay out of the next government because of its objection to a proposal to freeze Islamic law. Prime Minister <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> handed his Cabinet's resignation late Saturday to the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, the country's collective presidency. Ten days earlier, <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> and 65 heads of political parties and unions signed a plan calling for a new government. The army, unions, and opposition political groups had issued an ultimatum to form a broad-based government and start peace talks with the rebel <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> in the south. There was no word Sunday on when a new government will be named. The capital of <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION>, tense since the army's ultimatum three weeks ago, was quiet. However, helmeted riot police with shields and batons stood guard on curbs and street corners. The independent daily newspaper <PERSON> Al-Khartoum </PERSON> said <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON>'s new government will include eight seats for his <ORGANIZATION> Umma </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, five for the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unionist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, and two for the powerful trade unions and professional associations. It would be the first time the unions and associations have shared power since a member of a doctors' group headed a transitional cabinet for a year after the 1985 overthrow of long-time dictator <PERSON> Gaafar </PERSON> <PERSON> Nimeiri </PERSON>. <PERSON> Al-Khartoum </PERSON> said parties from war-torn southern <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> would draw four portfolios, and independent parties and national parties from western <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> would get one each. The National Islamic Front will not be in the Cabinet, the newspaper said. The Front has rejected the pact signed 10 days ago by the other parties. The plan calls for immediate endorsement of a peace proposal reached last November by the rebels and the Democratic Unionists.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 0914EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Israel-Lebanon     03-12 0298</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Israel-Lebanon,0307</SECOND>
<HEAD>2 Guerrillas Killed in Lebanon</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli soldiers killed two Arab guerrillas early Sunday on the northern border of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s self-declared security zone in southern <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, the army said. No Israeli soldiers were hurt in the fighting, an army announcement said. It was the third confrontation between <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldiers and guerrillas in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> since February 23. The two other incidents were described by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> as <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> attempts to carry out attacks inside <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and became an issue in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. An army announcement referred to the guerrillas as `` terrorists'' but did not indicate if they were Palestinian or Lebanese. A spokeswoman, speaking on condition of anonymity, said she had no information on whether the guerrillas were trying to infiltrate into <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. The confrontation in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> took place near the town of <LOCATION> Hasbaya </LOCATION>, about five miles north of the Israeli border, the army said. <LOCATION> Hasbaya </LOCATION> is within the security zone set up by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to protect its northern border in 1985 when it withdrew the bulk of its forces from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> after a three-year occupation. Seven Palestinian guerrillas were killed in the two earlier battles, and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION>, a Marxist faction of the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, said they were members of their group. One confrontation took place on Feb. 23, and the second was on March 2. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> accused the Palestinian group of trying to infiltrate into <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in the two previous confrontation and called on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to halt its dialogue with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, saying <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> had broken his pledge to stop terrorist attacks. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials criticized the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> for the incidents, but it also called for a halt to retaliatory Israeli bombing raids against <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> positions in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1125EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-OzoneProtest     03-12 0166</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ozone Protest,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Human Trees Protest Outside Downing Street</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Six protesters dressed as trees went to Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s residence Sunday to urge her government to do more to protect the world's rain forests. The members of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Youth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> delivered 22 chestnut saplings, one for each member of the Cabinet, and a letter welcoming the government's recent support for saving the ozone layer. `` We are glad the government is concerned about the ozone layer but we want to see more action on the crucial environmental question of the destruction of the rain forests,'' said the council's chairman, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> `` Saving the rain forests is as crucial as saving the ozone layer.'' <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was the host of a 120-nation conference last week that ended with industrialized nations reaffirming plans to ban by the end of the century synthetic chemicals known as chlorofluorocarbons. The compounds destroy the ozone shield that protects the Earth from the sun's cancer-causing ultraviolet rays.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthKorea     03-12 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Korea,0478</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Demanding New Government Battle Riot Police</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY RENFREW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEOUL, South Korea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Students and workers demanding the overthrow of President <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo battled hundreds of riot police with firebombs, clubs and rocks Sunday after they were blocked from marching into the streets. Armored police vans with multiple tear gas launchers fired volleys of choking gas into the crowds around <ORGANIZATION> Yonsei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in eastern <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. `` Oust <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> Tae-woo!'' and `` Thrust a knife into the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> regime!'' protesters shouted as they charged police and pelted them with rocks and firebombs that spewed blazing gasoline. About 2,000 troopers hurled rocks back as dense clouds of white tear gas cloaked the campus. Police said some officers were injured, but they had no figures. They did not report any arrests. The violence erupted when protesters tried to march out of <LOCATION> Yonsei </LOCATION> after about 10,000 workers, dissidents and students held a campus rally to denounce the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> government and demand free labor unions. South Korean law restricts some trade union activity. In speeches, dissident leaders bitterly attacked the <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> government and big corporations that dominate the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> economy. Speakers said the government and corporations were subjecting people to lives of endless work and poverty. `` Rise up and march forth to let out our anger at the suppressors,'' dissident leader <PERSON> Paik </PERSON> <PERSON> Ki-wan </PERSON> said as thousands cheered and clapped. Thousands of protesters then marched to the school's main gate, beating drums and jabbing their fists into the air. Protesters burned an effigy of <PERSON> Chung </PERSON> <PERSON> Ju-yong </PERSON>, founder of <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's biggest company. Police broke up a protest at the company's <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> headquarters last week. Some students armed with clubs and firebombs then surged out of several gates and climbed over the school's walls to attack riot police blocking the way. Most protesters stayed on the campus and did not attack police. The clash, one of the biggest anti-government protests in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in recent months, was confined to the main road in front of the school and lasted about one hour. Riot police guarded government buildings and the <ORGANIZATION> Hyundai </ORGANIZATION> headquarters in central <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> to prevent attacks. There were no reports of any incidents. Dissidents and radical students claim <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> is a front for military rule and seek the overthrow of his government. Dissident leaders say they want to end the domination of the government bureaucracy, the military and big industrial corporations. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, a former general who took office in February 1988, has introduced broad democratic reforms. But many South Koreans oppose his government because of its ties to past authoritarian regimes. The dissidents have little public support, but they have been showing new strength following the formation in January of a new anti-government alliance. The anti-government students back the alliance.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Namibia     03-12 0173</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Namibia,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Peacekeepers Arrive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WINDHOEK, Namibia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 70 British troops arrived Sunday to join the advance contingent of <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> peacekeepers preparing to monitor <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>'s transition to independence. The British unit brought its own four-wheel drive vehicles and drove in convoy to its temporary quarters, a South African army base south of <LOCATION> Windhoek </LOCATION>. Tents reserved for the Britons had no mattresses on the beds, and South African officers began a search to find some. Soldiers and <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> administrative personnel from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Finland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> already are in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>. Some 4,650 troops from more than 20 countries are to arrive by the end of the month. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, which has ruled <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> since World War I, is to begin implementing independence next month, leading to elections in early November. The <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which has waged a guerrllia war against South African rule here for 23 years, is favored to win most votes. It needs two-thirds of ballots to have full control of a government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Refusenik     03-12 0190</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Refusenik,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Refusenik Arrives in Israel after 18-Year Wait</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 One of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s longest-waiting refuseniks, <PERSON> Yuli </PERSON> <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON>, arrived in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to a festive welcome Sunday after an 18-year struggle to gain his freedom. `` We welcome you with open arms and with a heart full of hope that many, many of our brothers in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> will come in your footsteps,'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> said as he greeted <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON> at the airport. Choking back tears, the refusenik said in Hebrew: `` All my life, my greatest ambition has been to be an Israeli.'' He said more than half a million of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s 2.5 million Jews would prefer to leave. In February, 2,425 Jews left the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, but only 13 percent went to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Most chose the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON>, 48, arrived in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> with his wife <PERSON> Ina </PERSON>, 42, and their three children. <PERSON> Kosharovsky </PERSON> was a leading Hebrew teacher in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and was arrested six times for his Zionist activities. He first was refused an emigration visa in March 1971 and applied 22 times before he got permision to leave.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1128EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Philippines     03-12 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Philippines,0209</SECOND>
<HEAD>17 Killed As Soldiers Battle Communist Rebels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers backed by helicopter gunships battled communist guerrillas in a southern Philippine town, leaving 17 people dead, the military reported Sunday. The army report did not identify those killed Thursday in clashes in <LOCATION> Lupon </LOCATION> town, 634 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. The first clash, with 50 <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> rebels, lasted two hours, the report said. Thirty minutes later, other soldiers from the same battalion encountered about 200 rebels near the same site, it said. Helicopter gunships fired rockets at rebel positions in the second battle, which lasted five hours, the report said. In <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>, a bomb exploded outside the residence of Moslem Sen. <PERSON> Mamintal </PERSON> <PERSON> Tamano </PERSON> just before midnight Saturday. It shattered windows but caused only minor injuries to a neighbor, police said. <PERSON> Kao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ayo </PERSON>, a secretary of the <PERSON> Tamano </PERSON> family, said <PERSON> Tamano </PERSON> had no idea who planted the bomb. `` The senator said he has no enemies,'' she said. Tamano is one of two Moslems in the 23-member senate. Five million of the country's 62 million people are Moslems living mostly in the southern <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, where Moslem separatist guerrillas have been fighting for self-rule for more than a decade.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Pakistan     03-12 0182</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pakistan,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Army Troops Dispatched After Gunmen Kill Five</HEAD>
<DATELINE>KARACHI, Pakistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Army troops in vehicles mounted with machine guns patrolled this seaport Sunday after roving gunmen killed five people and wounded at least seven, officials said. Rival student groups at <ORGANIZATION> Karachi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> traded gunfire from windows and rooftops for hours Saturday. The Edhi Trust ambulance service said three students were wounded, none seriously. Police and witnesses said that since Friday, there have been several incidents in which young men fired indiscriminately from cars and motorcycles, killing at least five people. Officials said the attacks appeared to be random and that no group claimed responsibility. Army troops were dispatched to enforce a curfew in violence-prone districts of east and west <LOCATION> Karachi </LOCATION>. The city of 9 million, <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>'s largest, has frequently been the site of clashes between ethnic Moslem natives and those who immigrated from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. Saturday's shooting at <ORGANIZATION> Karachi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> involved students of a fundamentalist Moslem party and of Prime Minister <PERSON> Benazir </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Pakistan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> The sniping lasted from about noon to sunset. The campus was reported quiet Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ShuttleVoice Bjt   03-12 0478</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Shuttle Voice, Bjt,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Woman's Voice Will Count Down the Final Seconds</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Since <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON> made his 15-minute suborbital flight aboard the Mercury capsule Freedom 7 in 1961, counting down the final seconds to launch has been a man's job. On Monday, <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> changes all that. The 27-year-old public affairs specialist with <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> Kennedy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> will replace <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> as the voice of Shuttle Launch Control for the liftoff of Discovery. It will be the first time a woman has served as launch commentator for a flight carrying astronauts. Her job will be to guide the news media and the public through the anxious minutes before the main engines ignite in a burst of flame and smoke, until the shuttle clears the launch tower and communications switch to the Johnson Space Center in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>. Her challenge to explain what is taking place behind the scenes and to translate the technical chatter among launch managers into `` something that anybody can understand.'' <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> is quick to contrast the significance of her new role with that of female astronauts. `` I think what they're doing is a lot more trendsetting and important than what a commentator does,'' she said, `` because they're actually doing it instead of reporting on what's been done.'' Nevertheless, <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> said, she likes to think her voice will be an inspiration to young women. `` If that would inspire somebody to go on and achieve what they want in life,'' she says, `` I think that is fantastic.'' <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> has worked for <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> for seven years, rising to her position of space shuttle specialist from a college work-study program that started while she was earning a bachelor's degree in journalism from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tuscaloosa </LOCATION>. She edited the space center newsletter, Spaceport News, for three years before she was assigned to the space shuttle beat. Now, she attends several daily meetings of launch managers to stay up-to-date on the progress of work to get three orbiters and their external fuel tanks and booster rockets ready for flight. To prepare for her debut, <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> provided launch commentary for some unmanned Atlas Centaur and <ORGANIZATION> Delta </ORGANIZATION> launches and for the early portions of some shuttle countdowns. She has watched numerous launches from her seat at the firing room console beside <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>, who is now deputy director for public affairs at Kennedy Space Center. She also hired a voice coach. Although she has learned the lingo and has carefully prepared a script, <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> knows her biggest challenge will be the `` real-time element of the job'' _ and how she'll react if there's an unexpected problem during the countdown. `` You're going to be scrambling to try and figure out what it is because you want to have the right story before you tell the world what's going on,'' <PERSON> Malone </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--SwissCowboy     03-12 0151</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Swiss Cowboy,0155</SECOND>
<HEAD>Urban Cowboy, Inspired By ``High Noon,'' Proves That Gun Is Real</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ZURICH, Switzerland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jokes by fellow train passengers about his cowboy garb and holstered revolver prompted a Swiss man to prove the gun was real, police said Sunday. The 32-year-old man fired into the train's ceiling and through a compartment door. After leaving the train, he put a final shot through the window of a train station toilet, a police statement said. No injuries were reported. Police detectives arrested the man but did not disclose his name or address except to say he was from outside <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>. He said he was inspired by the Western movie `` High Noon'' and bought his outfit for a country music festival in <LOCATION> Zurich </LOCATION>, according to police. Police reported on the Feb. 26 incident after authorities charged the man with endangering life, property damage and illegal possession of a weapon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-CaveWoman Bjt   03-12 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cave Woman, Bjt,0820</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman in Isolation Experiment in Cave Lives Like Rat in a Cage</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HOLDEN LEWIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARLSBAD, N.M. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Time passes slowly for <PERSON> Stefania </PERSON> <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>. The Italian woman has fallen into a routine of staying awake 23 hours, then sleeping for 10, after being holed up in a cave for two months as part of a research project into the effects of isolation. She has no sun, radios or clocks to guide her sense of time, and little contact with other humans. `` Sunday, Feb. 12, 10 a.m.,'' Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> writes on a computer at a desk in her plastic habitat at one end of the cave. Actually, it's noon on Wednesday, March 8. On Jan. 13, the 27-year-old Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> climbed 30 feet below the earth's surface and into the 200-foot-long Lost Cave in the hills west of <LOCATION> Carlsbad </LOCATION> to begin a four - to five-month isolation experiment An Italian research group is sponsoring the experiment, along with various <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> universities and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Space </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. As she moves about in her two-room, 200-square-foot Plexiglas house, Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> resembles a laboratory rat in a cage. Researchers monitor her with three video cameras and microphones, and they type in occasional messages to her computer, but Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> can not see or hear another human. During her waking hours, she sometimes taps away at her computer like a subject in a <PERSON> B.F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> experiment as researchers in a trailer above record the results of tests of her concentration, memory and reasoning ability. One thing researchers are discovering in isolation experiments _ intended, among other things, to give them insight into how humans might react on interplanetary space flights _ is that men tend to be more cheerful in long isolation than women. <PERSON> Maurizio </PERSON> <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON>, the experiment coordinator who once spent six months isolated in a cave, alludes to that in a brief computer conversation in Italian with his fellow native of <PERSON> Ancona </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>. `` You should change your sex,'' <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> writes to the glum-looking Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>. `` You always seem like a sad one.'' `` I feel sadder some times than others,'' she replies. After chatting via computer for a little bit, <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> asks Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> to take the series of computerized mental tests, which she performs about once a week. Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>, who had been interrupted from reading a novel to take the medical measurements and relay them by computer, becomes a little sarcastic. `` Great idea, like a dessert!'' she responds. An interior decorator by profession, <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> has livened up her 10-by-10-foot living area with colorful figures cut out of construction paper and glued to the walls. Among the paper decorations: wine bottles, a flower box and a `` window,'' covered with blue paper lace curtains, that looks out onto a white paper moon and stars. A brown paper cat sits beside the windowsill. Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> spends much of her time kneeling on a blue mat, reading. She brought 400 books with her: novels, histories, English primers. She stays in shape by practicing judo moves. She is remarkably quiet. Even though researchers can hear her, she prefers to communicate with them by computer. She does talk a little to her pets _ two mice she dubbed <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nicoleta </PERSON>, and a salamander _ all found in the cave. She keeps a vigil to prevent the rodents from gnawing at cables or eating her food, which consists mostly of rice and beans she cooks on an electric stove. Long-term space flight might be a lot like this, except for the lack of gravity in space. Medical researchers are especially interested in finding out what isolation does to one's emotional and mental well-being. `` <PERSON> Stefania </PERSON> is fine,'' says <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvagno </PERSON>, an Italian doctor who alternates 24-hour monitoring shifts with <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON>. `` As of now, she has n't expressed any desire that deals with the outside world.'' But it appears Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>'s world is n't quite a utopia. She occasionally attaches electrodes to her head before she falls asleep so researchers can study her brain waves in various stages of sleep, and the results show symptoms of mild depression. <PERSON> Galvagno </PERSON> says he and <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> sometimes joke around with <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> to buoy her spirits. <PERSON> Montalbini </PERSON> says Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>'s ability to concentrate has deteriorated. In previous experiments, people in isolation alone have improved their concentration, while members of groups isolated in caves have lost their concentration. About this time, around 4:30 p.m., Miss <PERSON> Follini </PERSON> walks over to her computer, types in `` Ciaoooooooo,'' waves to the video camera, dims the lights _ they always stay on _ lies on the mat under a blanket and stares at the camera a while. Presently she closes her eyes and falls asleep: <PERSON> Stefania </PERSON> <PERSON> Follini </PERSON>, a brown paper cat, two mice and a salamander.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Israel-MeinKampf Bjt   03-12 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Israel-Mein Kampf, Bjt,0569</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plan to Publish `Mein Kamph' in Hebrew Stirs Controversy</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LOUIS MEIXLER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Holocaust survivor's Hebrew translation of `` Mein Kampf'' has touched off a controversy over whether the book, which inspired the slaughter of 6 million Jews, should be published in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. Author <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON> argued Sunday that a Hebrew edition of the <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s manifesto will educate young Israelis about the evils of the Nazi regime. Other Holocaust survivors say it should never appear on Israeli bookshelves. So far, <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON> has not found a publisher. `` It's not easy to get someone to publish a book that is connected to <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON>, who spent the past 18 months translating the first volume of `` Mein Kampf.'' `` But 50 years after <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, we must be strong enough to look at who he was,'' said <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON>, who fled his native <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> in 1938 after watching Nazi troops parade down the main street of the Austrian capital. <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON>, a retired educator, said in an interview that young Jews should read `` Mein Kampf'' as a warning against racist ideology. He said, for example, that there were disturbing anti-Arab sentiments expressed by extreme right Israeli politicians. `` The new generation needs ... to know about the dangers that can occur,'' he said. `` There are -LRB- Israelis -RRB- who promote racism.'' <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON> said the fact his parents were killed by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> while trying to escape from <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> has strengthened his determination to see the book published in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` If people like my father ... would have had the internal strength to read the book, they would have known, and things would have ended differently,'' he said. Other Holocaust refugees vehemently disagree with <PERSON> Yaron </PERSON>, saying publication would stir deep emotion in a nation that was founded in part to shelter the survivors of the Nazi horrors. If it is published, `` there will be battles in the street,'' predicted <PERSON> Noah </PERSON> <PERSON> Klieger </PERSON>, a survivor of the <PERSON> Aushwitz </PERSON> concentration camp, who covers Holocaust affairs for the daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION> newspaper. `` We need freedom of opinion, but there is a limit, and <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> is the limit,'' he said in an interview. `` The man who wrote this book destroyed _ physically destroyed _ a third of the Jewish people.'' <PERSON> Stefan </PERSON> <PERSON> Grayek </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> of Jewish Fighters, Partisans, and Camp Inmates, also opposes publication. `` Jews do n't need to read about the worst anti-Semitism the world has ever seen,'' he said. `` We do n't need to revive <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, certainly not in <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, definitely not in Hebrew.'' He said some Holocaust survivors were considering legal action to stop publication. But he said the federation decided against doing anything, believing there was no real interest in the book. If published, he said, `` I think ... the book will end up in a warehouse and not people's bookshelves,'' <PERSON> Grayek </PERSON> said. The <ORGANIZATION> Yad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vashem </ORGANIZATION> national Holocaust memorial has refused a request to publish the translation, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Yad </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vashem </ORGANIZATION> said. `` I question why anyone would publish the book,'' said spokesman <PERSON> Menahem </PERSON> <PERSON> Fogel </PERSON>. `` It's going to upset a lot of people, and I ca n't see it selling a lot of copies. `` The book is available in its original language, and if researchers want to gain access to the book it is best that they study it in the original language,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--ParkingScandal     03-12 0111</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Parking Scandal,0112</SECOND>
<HEAD>Five Bureaucrats Investigated for Alleged Parking Fraud</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five city employees are being investigated for allegedly giving handicapped parking permits to people claiming such problems as obesity, bronchitis and panic attacks, a newspaper said Sunday. The Milan daily <ORGANIZATION> Corriere </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> della </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sera </ORGANIZATION> said authorities examined 300 of the 8,000 permits granted for handicapped parking in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s historic center and found 100 of them `` suspicious. The permit owners listed such problems as claustrophobia, anxiety, and a contagious eye infection, according to the report. Traffic and parking in the narrow streets of the historic quarter have been sharply limited in recent years due to congestion and pollution problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--BoiseProtest     03-12 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Boise Protest,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Members From Three States Protest Paper Mill Hiring</HEAD>
<DATELINE>INTERNATIONAL FALLS, Minn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 3,000 union members and supporters held a rally and marched in front of the <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cascade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> paper plant to protest the company's hiring of non-union workers for a construction project. The union members, from across <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Wisconsin </LOCATION>, were protesting two non-union contracts among the 17 the company has let for its $ 525 million paper mill expansion that will more than double production at this town on the Canadian border. `` The fact of the matter is that organized labor is going to stand together in solidarity,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Petersen </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Building </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Construction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trades </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, at Saturday's rally. A <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cascade </ORGANIZATION> spokesman defended the hiring of non-union labor. `` We're the ones investing the half billion dollars and we need to be the ones to make the decisions to make this a cost-effective project,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Boise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cascade </ORGANIZATION>'s communications director.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1212EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Robber'sComeuppance     03-12 0207</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Robber's Comeuppance,0213</SECOND>
<HEAD>81-Year-Old Bank Customer Socks It To Bank Robber</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLUMBUS, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 81-year-old man struck a bank robber with a karate-style chop after seeing him hit a female teller, causing the robber to drop a bag of money and flee, authorities said. `` I do n't believe in hitting ladies,'' said the elderly customer, who asked not to be identified. The robber scooped up some $ 10 and $ 20 bills from the floor, but left most of the money behind Friday as he ran out of a <ORGANIZATION> BancOhio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> branch on the city's south side, said police Detective <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>. <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said the robber handed a note demanding money to the teller Friday afternoon. The robber said he had a gun, but no weapon was seen, <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said. `` She -LRB- the teller -RRB- complied, but apparently it was n't fast enough for him,'' <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON> said. The robber struck the teller in the head with the money-filled bag. That was when the elderly customer at the next window punched the robber. `` I did n't give it a thought,'' the man said. `` I just hit that man because he hit that woman.'' Police refused to disclose the amount taken. No one had been arrested in the robbery by early Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-MitchellAtTheHelm Bjt   03-12 0977</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mitchell At The Helm, Bjt,850</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Majority Leader Prevailed in First Major Test</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID ESPO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Democratic Sen. <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> came under <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> attack during the debate over <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON>'s nomination as defense secretary, Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> stepped forward to deflect the blows. And when the Republicans switched gears and insisted that the key issue was President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s prerogative of picking his own Cabinet, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> deftly rebutted by cautioning against `` self-righteousness.'' `` Do n't get too locked into your present views,'' the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> senator said after reciting chapter and verse a series of past <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> votes against high-level <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> appointees. `` You may get into another one in not too long.'' If <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had much at stake in the Tower fight that culminated with rejection of the nomination, so did <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, a 55-year-old <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> native of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> whose rise to the pinnacle of power in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> has been extremely rapid by congressional standards. A former federal judge who was appointed to office in 1980, he won an underdog's race for a six-year term in 1982 and parlayed that into a landslide re-election in 1988. He presided over the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> campaign committee that helped oust the Republican majority in 1986 and two years later he won a three-way race to become majority leader. He has stressed cooperation with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in the early months of his tenure, yet also outlined a <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> agenda that includes ethics legislation, environmental concerns and social issues such as raising the minimum wage. Still, a miscue could have marred his first appearance in a leading role for a party trying to maintain its standing during lengthy Republican control of the White House. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> walked a narrow line. He stressed throughout the debate that he meant no political injury to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>. Yet he also was the careful keeper of the vote count that sealed Tower's rejection. He put his low-key debating style on display for the first time in contrast to veteran GOP leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s more aggressive approach. Moreover, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> apparently emerged without unduly antagonizing senators on the other side of the aisle. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said Sunday on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Meet the Press'' that the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> probably will be back to normal within a month or two despite bruised feelings over the Tower episode. `` I think you can say that the nomination is gone but not forgotten,'' said <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>. `` The memories will be around for a while. There will be some bruised feelings. But I think in probably 30 to 60 days we'll be back to normal. The scars are n't that deep.'' One Democratic committee chairman, speaking anonymously, said <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s approach was to avoid the appearance of partisanship, yet at the same time to support <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> who recommended rejection of Tower's nomination. `` I thought he acted calm and cool throughout. He made nobody mad on the Democratic side,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Howell </PERSON> <PERSON> Heflin </PERSON>, D-Ala., one of three Democrats to vote in favor of confirmation `` He never did any real what you call arm-twisting.'' In the same vein, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> minimized the importance of the Tower debate to his own political fortunes even as he acknowledged judgments `` inevitably'' would be made on how he performed. After initially remaining in the background, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> assumed an increasingly prominent role in the confirmation struggle. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> learned Monday night that the votes were in hand to defeat Tower's nomination, and let the Republicans know by telling reporters on Tuesday. The following day _ Wednesday _ Democrat <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> became the third Democrat to announce his support of Tower. But then a string of three wavering Democrats quickly came to the floor and declared their opposition. The effect was to blunt the impact of <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>'s long-awaited decision and seal Tower's defeat. It all bore the marks of skillful behind-the-scenes stage managing. <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> worked closely and several Republicans said it was the decision by the highly respected <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> to oppose Tower that made confirmation difficult to achieve. Yet when <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> himself came under attack from Republicans for detailing investigators from a subcommittee he heads to check out allegations against <ORGANIZATION> Tower </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> came to his defense. `` We are not going to get in a position here where one, two, three, four, five, six, seven people come over here and ask the same question and the senator -LRB- <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> -RRB- has to give the same answer over again,'' said <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>. And he showcased his debating skills when he replied to persistent <ORGANIZATION> Repulican </ORGANIZATION> claims that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was entitled to have the nomination confirmed as a matter of presidential prerogative. If they serve long enough, he said, all senators of both parties `` will inevitably contradict ourselves. We will meet ourselves coming around the corner on some issue.'' He cited Repulican opposition to several appointments made by former President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> a decade ago and said: `` There was no talk then about the president having his own way. There was no talk then about the president winning the last election. There was no talk then about the future of the confirmation process. There was no talk then about the fairness of the process.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> also worked to thwart <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>'s more aggressive approach to the debate and his efforts to shake loose a few extra votes by accusing the Democrats of treating Tower unfairly. When <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> suggested that Tower be given the right to come to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and respond to allegations against him, <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> immediately replied that he would be willing to give it serious consideration. By not rejecting the proposal outright, several Democrats said, the <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> senator denied <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> the right to level a fresh charge of unfairness. And when <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> finally made a formal proposal on the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor _ after the outcome of the struggle was clear _ <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> blocked it and the Republicans did not pursue it.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1224EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Nunn-Democrats     03-12 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Nunn-Democrats,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>To Run or Not to Run? Nunn Maintains He's Not Interested</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONALD M. ROTHBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PHILADELPHIA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The spotlight of the John Tower controversy proved hotter than <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> had anticipated and the <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> senator now yearns for a chance to lower his profile. `` I'd like to go down to <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> and check titles on real estate for about six months,'' <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> told reporters at the annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. The reporters laughed and the senator smiled. But he looked like a man who meant what he said. Like it or not, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> will have to reconcile himself to a prominence most politicians would relish. For the first time in his public career, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> was the target of partisan attacks from opponents who questioned his tactics and motives as the leader of the opposition to the Tower nomination. It was a trial by fire that seems to have strengthened his standing as a national figure. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> may not like the role <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> played in defeating his first choice to head the <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION>, but the president seemed as eager as <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> to get the bitterness behind him. Before the Tower debate, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> was seen as a figure apart from politics. `` Respected'' was the word most often used to describe the bespectacled Georgian who had carved out a reputation as the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>'s foremost authority on defense issues. The past couple of years saw a shift in <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>'s approach. No longer did he shy away from partisan jabs at the Republican administration. He mulled a run for the 1988 Democratic presidential nomination and campaigned extensively for <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> in his ill-fated effort to regain the presidency for the Democrats. But the Tower nomination was a much more dramatic step into the thick of partisan politics. That battle over, the question he often is asked is, what next? `` I have no plans or any inclination to run for president in 1992,'' he said. `` I'd like to have s much lower profile.'' As chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> had the kind of forum he seems to relish _ one that features an often dry discussions of issues. Without question, <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> was the dominant figure at the two-day meeting, despite the presence of three of the contenders for the 1988 Democratic presidential nomination _ <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> and Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>. `` When the history of the 101st <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> is written, it will be about <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>. `` He represents the best that our democratic society has to offer.'' <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>'s tribute to <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> was all the more striking for being just one of many voiced during the conference. But while <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> was bombarded with the sort of flattery that would prompt most politicians to begin thinking about their Cabinet choices, a bid for the presidency would make the fight over Tower seem gentle. <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON> represents his party's most conservative wing. While he commands unquestioned respect on defense issues his support for the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> economic program would and his conservative positions on other domestic issues would raise bitter opposition from the party activists who still control the presidential nominating process. The ideological split in the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> was dramatized by the presence at the <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION> meeting of <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, who symbolizes an approach the <ORGANIZATION> DLC </ORGANIZATION> was created to combat. `` Reverend <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> is a very credible spokesman for his point of view,'' said <PERSON> Nunn </PERSON>. `` Obviously, he and I have some very fundamental differences in philosophy.'' Those differences will not easily be bridged. -0
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITORS NOTE: Donald M. Rothberg is chief political writer</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 of The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1306EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-FirstCemetery Bjt   03-12 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-First Cemetery, Bjt,0748</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nation's First Planned City Didn't Plan Ahead For This</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LDV1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JENNIFER BRANDLON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COLUMBIA, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Its name is virtually synonymous with planning. But 25 years after its founding as <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s first planned city, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> belatedly is allowing for the one thing besides taxes that everyone must face _ death. Burying the dead was n't on the minds of <ORGANIZATION> Rouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> officials in 1963 when they purchased 15,000 acres of farmland and mapped out a city of the future. Consultants on recreation, education, sociology and other fields were hired to prescribe ideal living conditions for urbanites weary of depersonalized existence in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s metropolitan sprawl But somehow, with its focus on living well, <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> never made provisions for what comes afterward. This city of 70,500 souls had no cemetery. `` My understanding is that it was overlooked in the beginning. -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Rouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> James </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Rouse </PERSON> had very detailed plans. ... He hired all kinds of experts. The one expert he forgot was a cemetery expert,'' said <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Geller </PERSON>, who is one. Last year, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> turned over 28 acres in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> to <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> and assigned him to create a graveyard. Last Monday, <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> watched as the first burial took place. `` We had enough road to accommodate them, luckily. We've only cleared about five acres,'' <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> said. In fact, there is n't much to see of the <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION> _ just a circular driveway inside a low, curving stone wall. So far, about 20 plots have been sold and two funerals have been held. <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>'s organizers have had little time to think about final resting places. Amenities of gracious living that are in place or on the drawing board include playgrounds, bike and jogging paths, a shopping mall, cultural centers, an athletic club, golf course, community pools and a bowling alley. In the 1960s, the city _ built in rural <LOCATION> Howard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> 20 miles north of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> _ acquired a reputation for addressing urban problems through innovative, comprehensive planning. <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, which welcomed its first residents in 1967, is seeing its population graying. The people who bought houses in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> in their 30s and 40s are approaching retirement. About 60 percent of <LOCATION> Howard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s senior citizens now live in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> or in nearby <LOCATION> Ellicott </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Florence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bain </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. `` It was built as a young persons' city, but what happened was the old folks came to live near their kids,'' <PERSON> Callahan </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Scavo </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Rouse </ORGANIZATION> vice president who is overseeing the cemetery, said it has taken two decades for a graveyard to become economically feasible. `` I'm not sure it was overlooked. The market was n't here,'' he said It's still not clear how large that market is. As they approach their twilight years, even residents who love <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> apparently are not anxious to stay there eternally. The Rev. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Golueke </PERSON> of St. <PERSON> John </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> said none of the 2,400 families in his parish has mentioned a desire to be buried in <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>. But having a cemetery in the community `` does give people some type of roots,'' the priest said. `` I guess you know you've made it as a city when you have a cemetery.'' <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> residents began to talk about a cemetery in the 1970s, but no developer was interested. <PERSON> Rouse </PERSON> finally ended up doing the first phase of construction itself and giving the land to <PERSON> Geller </PERSON> to manage, <PERSON> Scavo </PERSON> said. The cemetery is expected to be able to support itself after the 25,000 graves are sold, probably in about 50 years. Cemeteries rely on trust funds financed by plot sales to pay for perpetual maintenance. The company _ a stickler for design rules _ had its own ideas about how the tract was to look. Statues, elaborate mausoleums, even simple white crosses were ruled out. Graves will be marked by bronze plates set in the ground, with nothing above ground except landscaping, a small chapel in a grove, and a communal mausoleum. <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Saunier </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forum </ORGANIZATION>, a citizen watchdog group, said she thinks the cemetery's time has come. `` It was the one thing we did n't have,'' she said. `` If you feel strongly about your community, you may want -LRB- to be buried there -RRB-. I think a lot of people do, and I think that will increase as <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> gets older.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-AFishNamedGrunt Bjt   03-12 0678</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-A Fish Named Grunt, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government's Decree: These Scads Are Mackerels</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: Lethrinus spp in 15th graf is correct.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A new government publication tries to fix the proper name on every species of fish that might end up on an American's plate so one diner's striped bass will no longer be another's rockfish. Just off the government's presses is `` The Fish List: <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Guide to Acceptable Market Names for Food Fish Sold in <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>,'' intended to end the confusion that arises because fishes swim under so many aliases. The book assigns a market name to each fish from sea, stream or lake that is sold in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and gives the scientifically-acceptable common name for each. It also tells how the fish is known locally, often by different names in different places. Fish dealers may sell their wares under either market name or common name, but none other. What some people call the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> mackerel and others call the common mackerel and still others know as the caballa, the booklet shows, are all one fish with the scientific Latin name Scomber scombrus. Scomber scombrus may be sold simply as mackerel, its market name, or as <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> mackerel, its science-accepted common name. The booklet lists 1,042 species, all fish sold for food in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. But, admits fish list compiler <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>, assistant to the director of the Division of Regulatory Guidance at the <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, `` I have missed many. I get calls every day about fish that are n't on the list.'' Rockfish illustrate the name problem. `` People in the <LOCATION> mid-Atlantic </LOCATION> area call striped bass rockfish,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>. `` To the rest of the country the rockfish is a completely different fish,'' she said. `` It is related to ocean perch, which is a rough looking fish _ squatty and with rough scales and spiny fins. What we here in the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area call a rockfish is cigar-shaped, has stripes and is very different.'' The government has long required the marketing of fish under uniform, government-accepted names. What's new is the guidebook. It was produced by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fisheries </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> because, Mrs. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON> said, fish dealers who called for guidance sometimes got inconsistent answers. What `` The Fish List'' establishes is how species with delicious commercial names are sometimes known locally by names so unappealing that anyone would be tempted to toss them back. Take the fish known to science as the Lethrinus spp. Its commercial name is emperor, but it is known in some places as the longnosed pigfaced bream, elsewhere as the rosefaced pigface bream and in yet other places as the mu. What is sold as the grunt is known in some places as the brown sweetlips. Some people call some anchovies the smig. Others call the grenadier the rattail. Uniform commercial names combat marketplace deception. About a month ago, the government seized 45,672 pounds of frozen fish fillets imported from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. They arrived labeled orange roughy, a tasty, expensive fish, when in fact they were merely the smooth oreo dory, a cheaper fish. The book lists 24 species of croaker, 38 of snapper, 18 of eel, 62 of rockfish, 31 of grouper, 15 of grunt, 21 of anchovy, 34 of shark, and 21 of mackerel _ including the jack mackerel, chub mackerel, king mackerel, snake mackerel and the Japanese scad, <LOCATION> Inca </LOCATION> scad or rough scad. These scads are mackerels, no matter what they're called. When the consumer buys flounder, he may be buying peacock flounder one time, tropical flounder another time _ or panther flounder, <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> flounder, yellowtail flounder, Arctic flounder or any of 35 other species of flounder. It does n't matter, said Mrs. <PERSON> Snyder </PERSON>. They are so much alike in taste and appearance that the customer would n't know the difference. Only another flounder could tell one from another.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 The 50-page Fish List may be purchased for $ 2.75 from the Superintendent of Documents, <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Printing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> 20402. It is document number 017-012-00341-9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0028 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1346EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Brites     03-12 0550</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brites,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bright &amp; Brief</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some people think they have space problems when the hall closet wo n't take one more winter coat or when there's no more room in the attic for grandma's collection of <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geographics </ORGANIZATION>. That's nothing. The Field Museum of Natural History is trying to cope with 2 million beetles, 9.6 million insect specimens, 1.7 million fish, 381,000 birds, 2.4 million plants, a half-million fossils, 600,000 artifacts _ 20 million specimens in all with 400,000 more coming in each year. `` We're approaching a sort of gridlock,'' said the museum's geology department chairman, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Bolt </PERSON> The botany department bulges with twice as many plant specimens as it was designed to hold. And the geology department is cramming so many fossils into storage drawers that some may get damaged. The museum, which says its holdings are widely used by researchers, is planning to close two courtyards inside the building for construction of more storage, and is considering building four underground, two-story vaults.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SIOUX FALLS, S.D. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Organizers of the first St. Patrick's Day parade here nine years ago were n't sure how popular it would be, since <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> is populated mainly by descendants of Scandinavians and Germans But `` good Lord, they came out of the woodwork,'' says <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, who helped plan event back in 1980. Organizers had figured on maybe 20 parade entries. They got more than 350. Thousands of revelers are expected to converge on <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> again Friday to celebrate what has become one of the city's most popular holidays. <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Henkin </PERSON>, chairwoman and owner of <ORGANIZATION> KSOO </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, was instrumental in planning the first <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> parade. `` They called me the Jewish leprechaun,'' she recalls. She's not sure why the idea caught on, but she says the bitter <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION> winters may have had something to do with it. `` I think people sort of have cabin fever in this part of the country after being winterized and locked up,'' she said. `` All you need is a good excuse to celebrate and, my goodness, this is a good excuse.'' `` This thing has taken off by itself and mushroomed,'' <PERSON> Henkin </PERSON> said. `` Really, the only thing we would need to do is blow a whistle and it would take off by itself.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>DUMAS, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Pauline </PERSON> <PERSON> Hobgood </PERSON> and <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> married more than 60 years ago and were divorced a quarter-century ago. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 81, remarried once and Ms. <PERSON> Hobgood </PERSON>, 80, remarried twice. But they remained friends, and on Saturday they were married again in a ceremony before dozens of relatives and friends in the Dumas Nursing Center. `` They're making my brother and I very happy by remarrying,'' said <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, the couple's daughter. `` The family has always hoped they would get back together.'' The ring used in the wedding was the same one <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> gave to Ms. <PERSON> Hobgood </PERSON> in 1928. `` After the divorce, Mother always wore the ring on her right hand,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Hobgood </PERSON> said she and <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> `` never lost touch with each other. One time, I even kept his money for him while he was in the hospital.'' Several days before the wedding, residents and staff members gave Ms. <PERSON> Hobgood </PERSON> a bridal shower. The male residents, not to be outdone, treated <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> to a bachelor party.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890312-0029 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-12-89 1347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-MinimumWage     03-12 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Minimum Wage,790</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Pushing For Increase Bigger Than Bush Proposal</HEAD>
<HEAD>By PAUL PAGE</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
