<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Cold 3rdLd-Writethru a0789 02-04 1031</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cold, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0789,1051</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cold Moves Toward East Coast Behind Freezing Rain</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to UPDATE with a fourth fatality due to exposure;
SUBS 17th graf, `Of the ...,' to conform. SUBS last graf to UPDATE with
highway partially reopened.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ASTX1, TA1, CX3, MP2, SE1, DX3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROGER PETTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Bitingly cold arctic air and freezing drizzle iced highways Friday from the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and south to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, closing scores of schools and one state government and prompting increased aid for the homeless. The urge to play in new-fallen snow resulted in four sledding deaths in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Twelve other deaths also were blamed on the weather, including four of hypothermia. A Greyhound Trailways bus with 15 people aboard spun around and overturned Friday on icy Interstate 70 in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> near the <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> line. Police said six people suffered broken limbs and ribs. Helicopters took the injured to hospitals. Temperatures early Friday were below zero all the way south to the middle <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, with readings of 20 below zero to 38 below zero over the <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>, much of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> and northwestern <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weather </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Austin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, fell from a high Thursday of 69 to a low Friday of 28, and a freeze warning was posted for the lower <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Grande </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>. Record lows were scattered from <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, including 35 below zero at <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Mason </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, had a low of 20 below zero, but wind gusting to 31 mph produced a wind chill factor of 78 below zero. <LOCATION> Minong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION>, hit 32 below zero. At noon, the temperature was only 27 degrees below zero at <PERSON> Bozeman </PERSON> and Butte, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. The weather service's official low for the Lower 48 states was 52 degrees below zero at Wisdom, <PERSON> Mont </PERSON>. But ahead of the cold air, 14 cities in the Southeast and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> reported record highs, ranging from 61 at <LOCATION> Beckley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> W. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, to 84 at <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION> The cold reached all the way to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> on Friday, less than five days before <PERSON> Mardi </PERSON> <PERSON> Gras </PERSON>. `` Snow, sleet, ice, or 80 mile an hour winds. Those are the only things that would stop a parade,'' said Assistant Police Chief <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Holman </PERSON>. In <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, the first state struck by the frigid air that had previously stunned <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> and slid over <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, moderation of temperatures is n't expected until Monday or Tuesday, and then it could warm only to about zero, said weather service spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Doherty </PERSON>. The mass of cold air remained over the eastern two-thirds of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, but temperatures continued to moderate. <LOCATION> Northway </LOCATION> was the coldest at 50 below, Fairbanks warmed up to minus 8 and <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> reached 10 above. A low pressure system moving in from the west warmed the western third of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>; above the <ORGANIZATION> Arctic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circle </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Barrow </PERSON> reached 16 above and it was 20 above at <LOCATION> Prudhoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s state government reopened Friday after shutting down the day before because of the cold and wind, but <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> closed his government because of the cold and more than a foot of snow. <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> Gov. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON> gave state workers more time to get to work because of icy roads. An estimated 200 travelers had been stranded since Wednesday at <PERSON> Dubois </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, and roads out of the area remained closed by snow Friday, among a number of highways closed in the state. In southern <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Interstate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 95 </ORGANIZATION> was closed from <LOCATION> Brunswick </LOCATION> to <ORGANIZATION> Freeport </ORGANIZATION> for 1 -LCB- hours after a 15-car pileup. No injuries were reported. Slippery roads and the cold forced school closings in <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state and <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION>. Some colleges and universities also closed. Officials at <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Corvallis </LOCATION> canceled classes for the fourth time in the school's 120-year history. The four sledding deaths in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> were unrelated. Three of the four, including a 6-year-old boy and a 12-year-old, occured in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> area; the fourth was in <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>. Of the 12 other deaths since the start of the cold wave, seven were traffic fatalities: four in <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, one in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION>, one in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and one in <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>. A utility worker was killed in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> while repairing a downed power line. And four people died of exposure, one in <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, one in <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, one in Lame Deer, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, and one in <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>. Two school buses collided on an icy parking lot in <LOCATION> Indianapolis </LOCATION>, and 17 elementary school students suffered minor injuries, officials said. Many cities stepped up aid to the homeless. Shelters in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> agreed to remain open during the day, rather than putting their clients out on the street until nightfall, said <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Hager </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>'s coordinator for the homeless. The city also contracted with hotels to house homeless people, <PERSON> Hager </PERSON> said. Some homeless shelters in <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> reported operating beyond normal capacity. In <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, as many as 400 people slept outside Thursday night, including 150 in campsites, said <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> <PERSON> Copeland </PERSON>, director of Sharing and Caring, a day shelter for the poor. Four homeless people have been treated for frostbite. <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Royer </PERSON> asked residents to donate blankets, warm clothing, toiletries and non-perishable food for the city's homeless At <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, hundreds of people were left without heat when a 4-inch natural gas pipeline ruptured. Temperatures were in the single digits at <LOCATION> Paducah </LOCATION> and residents were told to move to electrically heated buildings. <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Mont. </LOCATION>, also had to cope with Thursday's train explosion that forced the daylong evacuation of thousands of people and left some without power. On Friday, officials asked residents to cut back on use of such things as space heaters and stoves to conserve electricity. Mail delivery was curtailed at <LOCATION> Mitchell </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, after two postal workers suffered mild frostbite in wind chill factors as low as 65 below zero, said Postmaster <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Kight </PERSON>. In the <LOCATION> Sierra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> of northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, a 70-mile stretch of Interstate 80 from <PERSON> Applegate </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Truckee </LOCATION> was closed by zero visibility and high wind, but reopened late Friday afternoon to small cars only, with travelers convoyed in groups of 100 vehicles.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Marcos 2ndLd-Writethru a0403 02-04 0716</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Marcos, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0403,0735</SECOND>
<BYLINE>Precede HONOLULU</BYLINE>
<HEAD>Philippines Vice President Urges Marcos Return to Homeland</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with six grafs to UPDATE with Laurel back in Manila, quoting
doctors saying Marcos has lost will to live. Pick up 3rd pvs, `The Philippine...'
Edits thereafter to trim and conform.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vice President <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> said Saturday that doctors fear <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> has lost the will to live, has only a 10 percent chance of surviving the year, and wants to die in his own country. Laurel spoke to reporters after returning from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, where the ousted <LOCATION> Philippine </LOCATION> president, accused of plundering billions from his homeland, is in exile. He said he would seek a meeting immediately with President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> to relay <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' wish and appeal `` to her sense of Christian values'' to allow the former president to come home to die. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> has refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> or members of his family to return from <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, where they have lived since a popular uprising toppled his 20-year administration in February 1986. <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> said doctors in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> told him that <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> might not survive the trip to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> but that the former president would prefer to die on the plane rather than on foreign soil. A newspaper in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> quoted a <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> official as saying Saturday that the government has decided not to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return and would even bar his body from being sent back after he dies. The Philippine Daily Inquirer quoted Cabinet Secretary <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> as saying the government feared <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' supporters would try to destabilize the <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> administration if their leader came home. `` We ca n't risk the gains by any destabilization effort which could derail us,'' <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> was quoted as saying. The newspaper quoted unidentified government sources as saying the Cabinet considered allowing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return to <LOCATION> Laoag </LOCATION>, capital of his home province of <ORGANIZATION> Ilocos </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Norte </ORGANIZATION> about 250 miles north of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. But the idea was rejected because of fears <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> would not honor the restriction, the paper Laurel visited <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' hospital bedside Thursday without Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>'s blessing. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, 71, remained in critical condition Friday in <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>'s intensive care unit, but an attorney said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was buoyed by <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION>'s visit and doctors said his fever had subsided. <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> declined to disclose details of his conversations with <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, his doctors and his wife, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>. `` Whatever our past differences and conflicts, the reality is that the crisis in this man's life can seriously affect political stability of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. Now is the time for compassion and forgiveness in order to achieve much needed unity among all Filipinos,'' <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> said in a statement Thursday night. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife are under <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> indictment for allegedly plundering the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> of more than $ 100 million and stashing much of the money in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. When <ORGANIZATION> Laurel </ORGANIZATION> was asked whether <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> would ever return to his homeland, he replied: `` That's up to her,'' referring to Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' son, <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said he relayed a letter to Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON> asking that his father be allowed to return. Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, who has repeatedly refused to allow <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to return, said she had not received the letter. `` I can just make a decision once I know what the letter is all about,'' she told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Laurel </PERSON> conceded his was a personal, not official, visit, but said he would make a full report to Mrs. <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was breathing with the assistance of a respirator following emergency surgery Wednesday to reduce fluids building up in his lungs. Hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> Kop </PERSON> said <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was alert but unable to talk because of the respirator. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was admitted to the hospital Jan. 15 for treatment of pneumonia and bronchial asthma. In December, he was hospitalized twice with congestive heart failure. The Marcoses would need permission from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney general and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to leave the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, according to Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> LaBella </PERSON>, the prosecutor in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government's racketeering case against <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> and his wife. A federal judge in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is to decide this month whether <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> is healthy enough to stand trial on criminal racketeering charges. Mrs. <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> pleaded innocent and is free on $ 5 million bail.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BarbaraBush Bjt   02-04 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Barbara Bush, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Lady Supports Ban on Assault Weapons</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERENCE HUNT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP White House Correspondent</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says she fears guns and, despite the president's membership in the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rifle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, favors banning the rapid-fire assault weapons used in a wave of gang killings and the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> rampage that left five children dead and 29 others wounded. The first lady, in an interview Friday, also expressed `` enormous sympathy'' for the financial plight of members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, who are taking political heat for a 51 percent pay increase. `` I know it sounds outrageous to people at home, but if they saw the cost of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> housing .... It's terrible. And the sacrifices the family makes,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. She said her family had not been able to live off her husband's salary in the 1960s when he was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>, but had to rely on the money he had earned as an oilman She said they probably could have made it on his congressional salary if they had n't owned two homes and had n't wanted to send their children to private schools. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said she did not want to discuss the `` politics and policies'' surrounding handgun ownership. Her husband, President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, opposes new federal handgun controls and is a lifetime member of the <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> NRA </ORGANIZATION> is the most powerful lobby against laws regulating firearms. `` I myself do not own a gun,'' she said. `` I choose not to get into that. I'm afraid of guns. ... I'm so afraid I'd shoot the wrong person.'' <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, before moving to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> eight years ago, revealed she had owned `` a tiny little gun'' that she kept by her bed for protection while her husband was away. In her first White House interview in 1981, Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said she had gotten rid of the weapon. Marking the end of her second week in the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spent part of Friday afternoon giving her first interviews since her husband became president. `` I feel at home here,'' she said, sitting on a couch, bathed in light from an arched window behind her. Asked if her husband had changed in any way since becoming president, she replied, `` I do n't see a difference with him.'' Pointing to several people in the room, she said, `` I see a difference in you and you and you. Not me. I mean it's just different when you're president. Everybody treats you differently when you're president.'' Joking about her husband's former status as vice president, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said, `` I spend half my life saying, ` Could you please get the vice president on the phone?' and the operator says, ` Do you really want <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>' or ` Do n't you know <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>'s in <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>.''' More seriously, she said, one big difference for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is that `` everything you say becomes major, and it is major. He is the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.'' And yet, she said of her husband: `` I think he's exactly the same.'' She said many people who used to kid with her husband had stopped doing that briefly but `` after awhile they all became normal again. It just took a little while. ... `` I call him Mr. <PERSON> President </PERSON> sometimes _ when I'm needling him ... to tease him, ` Yes, Mr. President.''' The first lady was asked whether she favored enactment of laws banning sale to the public of military assault guns. Measures to outlaw the manufacture, sale or possession of a variety of rifles are pending in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and dozens of states. It was a Chinese AK-47 assault rifle that a gunman used in the rampage in which five children were killed and 29 others, were wounded in <LOCATION> Stockton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> last month. Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said she thought such weapons already were outlawed. `` They should be, absolutely,'' she said. While refusing to discuss her position on handguns, Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said that she does not like to go hunting, as does her husband, an avid outdoorsman. `` I went hunting with <PERSON> George </PERSON> once,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> recalled. `` He told me to follow the bird, and I followed the bird and his head came right through that little circle -LRB- the rifle scope -RRB-. I put down the gun and said, ` That's it. I'm not going to do that again.'''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-PayRaise-List CORRECTIVE   02-04 0048</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Pay Raise-List, CORRECTIVE,40</SECOND>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> erroneously reported Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>'s position on Wednesday on the proposed 51 percent congressional pay raise. Information provided by Coalitions for <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> incorrectly stated <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>'s position as undecided. The <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> Republican is opposed to the pay raise.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0113EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-S&amp;Ls Bjt   02-04 0544</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-S&amp;Ls, Bjt,540</SECOND>
<HEAD>S&amp;L Crisis Occupies Bush, Advisers at Camp David</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: Camp David meeting 10 a.m. to 1 p.m. EST; tops unlikely.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was using his Camp David mountain hideaway today to work on a plan for solving the savings and loan crisis that aides said was unlikely to embrace a controversial deposit insurance fee. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was meeting at the <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> compound with <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON>, Budget Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> and other key advisers to go over the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s recommendations for S & amp; Ls. White House aides, speaking on condition of anonymity, said they did not expect the president to reach a final decision on the complete S & amp; L package, although a depositors' fee seems to have been ruled out. Administration officials have refused to disavow the fee publicly, but aides conceded privately that the plan most likely would not include it. On Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> summoned congressional leaders to the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> to hear their advice. Just as in a Thursday meeting with industry officials, the president did not reveal his own preference from among the options discussed. From the congressional leaders, participants said, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> heard overwhelmingly one-sided advice against a proposal to charge depositors about 25 cents for every $ 100 in their accounts. `` I do n't recall anybody taking the other side of that issue,'' Sen. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Riegle </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Mich., the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Banking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, told reporters afterward Both he and Sen. <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, the committee's senior Republican, predicted that the bailout package eventually agreed to by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the administration would include an increase in the premium that institutions pay for federal insurance, but no new direct fee on depositors. `` That deposit fee is not a live option,'' <PERSON> Garn </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think it was to begin with. The fees or insurance premium increase would help raise the $ 7 billion to $ 9 billion needed to pay the interest on the $ 85 billion to $ 100 billion in borrowing that the administration believes is needed to bail out insolvent thrifts. The president told the legislators that he hopes to have the administration's plan in place early next week. On Thursday, he addresses a joint House-Senate session on the budget. At the meeting Friday, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told lawmakers: `` Whatever we come up with will not be popular, and I expect that whatever you come up with will not be popular. But we've got to get the problem solved. `` There are no easy answers, and no worrying about blame _ plenty to go around.'' Meanwhile, in another development, federal regulators late Friday announced the resignation of <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Root </PERSON>, the executive director of the fund that insures savings and loan deposits. Root, appointed to head the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> in October 1987, submitted his resignation on Monday. It will be effective Feb. 10. Replacing Root as acting director will be <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Creedon </PERSON>, currently principal deputy director of operations, said the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION>'s parent agency. She had previously served as acting <ORGANIZATION> FSLIC </ORGANIZATION> director from December 1983 until March 1987. Root last year presided over the sales or closings of 205 insolvent institutions and the `` stabilization'' of 18 others at a combined cost of $ 38 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0019EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-JustSweatsProbe     02-04 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Just Sweats Probe,0387</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor, Clothing Chain Founders Charged With Murder In Insurance
Scam</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDA DEUTSCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The owner of the Just Sweats clothing chain, his partner and a doctor were charged with murder Friday in an alleged $ 1.5 million insurance scam involving the faked death of the owner. <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, co-founder of the <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, Ohio-based athletic clothing chain; his partner, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrett </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>; and Dr. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryde </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Glendale </LOCATION> were charged in the murder of <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, 32. <PERSON> Green </PERSON>'s body was found in <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>' office April 16 and was misidentified as that of <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, 47, who was arrested last week carrying <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>'s driver's license, is being held in a <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, jail on grand theft charges under a $ 5 million bond <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON>, 25, who collected $ 1 million in death benefits on <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, remains at large. <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, 56, was arrested Friday and held without bail pending arraignment Monday. <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> was believed dead until mid-1988, when police in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> discovered that a man identified as <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> who died in <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>' office was not <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>. The discovery and the fact that <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> had cashed $ 1 million in life insurance checks prompted authorities to file federal warrants for their arrest. Authorities allege that <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>'s death was faked to collect the insurance money. The murder charges against all three men carry special circumstances that make them eligible for the death penalty. The special circumstances alleged are murder for financial gain and aiding and abetting. Ten charges were filed against each man, including murder, conspiracy to commit murder, insurance fraud, grand theft, and assault with a stun gun. <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, 56, told police he believed the man found dead in his office was <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>. He said the man died after complaining of chest pains. <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> had the body cremated the next day. Police later discovered that a thumbprint from the corpse did not match the one on <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> driver's license. The body, which resembled <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON>, later was identified as <PERSON> Greene </PERSON>, a former Ohioan who lived in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hanson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hawkins </PERSON> also are accused of stealing about $ 2 million from Just Sweats, which they founded in 1985. The company has filed for protection from creditors under Chapter 11 of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bankruptcy code.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0024EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Paraguay 5thLd-Writethru   02-04 0990</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Paraguay, 5th Ld-Writethru,a0413,1013</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stroessner Ousted in Coup, Ordered Out of Paraguay</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 5-6, `The New...Times reported' with report quoting
State Department document on drug involvement. Pick up 7th pvs, `At least...'
^LaserPhotos ASC1,2,3; NY10</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM H. HEATH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ASUNCION, Paraguay (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was sworn in as president Friday after ousting President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> in a coup that reportedly left scores dead. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> ordered the dictator out of the country he had ruled for 34 years. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who had been <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s second-in-command in the army and whose daughter is married to <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s son, took the oath of office and swore in a nine-member Cabinet comprised of seven civilians, an active general and a retired general. Paraguayans poured into the streets to celebrate the military coup and to gape at damage left by hours of heavy fighting between rebel soldiers and police and troops loyal to <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>. `` My government will respect the human rights of everyone to make democracy a reality,'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, five rows of medals on his shirtfront, said during a short speech at the 19th century National Palace overlooking the broad <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Cox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> newspapers </ORGANIZATION>, quoting from a classified <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> report, said Friday that <PERSON> Rodriquez </PERSON> is considered by law enforcement authorities in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> to be the country's No. 1 drug trafficker. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday quoted <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyt </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, a professor of Latin American history at <ORGANIZATION> Indiana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Terre </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Haute </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, as saying, `` <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> has reportedly provided protection, airfields and an air taxi service to people smuggling drugs northward.'' At least 18 soldiers and a handful of civilians were killed during fierce clashes between troops loyal to <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church-run </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Caritas </ORGANIZATION> said, saying that the total could top 200. It gave no source or explanation for the wide fluctuation. Officials at the main military and police hospitals refused to give figures on casualties, and the new government made no estimate. But a police sergeant said on condition of anonymity: `` I'm sad for my 35 dead companions. About 150 soldiers died at the presidential escort batallion, and two civilians.'' <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>, 76, was put under house arrest at an army base, about 30 of his followers and aides detained, and the hierarchy of the government and ruling <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> replaced. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was ordered out of the country, and unconfirmed reports said he was going to <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>. But Gen. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Mardones </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Santiago </LOCATION> police commander, said: `` He is definitely not coming here tonight. He is still in <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>. That's official.'' <PERSON> Mardones </PERSON> said he believed <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was leaving <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION> Saturday morning, `` but we do not know where to. Not necessarily <LOCATION> Chile </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was cheered by several thousand citizens as he took the oath of office and swore in a Cabinet. About 15,000 accompanied him to the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> headquarters and cheered again when he appointed <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Chaves </PERSON>, 87, as party president, replacing pro-Stroessner militant <PERSON> Sabino </PERSON> <PERSON> Montonaro </PERSON>. `` We're going to have a true democracy!'' shouted <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Laino </PERSON>, president of the National Accord group of four opposition parties and <LOCATION> Paraguay </LOCATION>'s best-known human rights advocate. `` I think that the era of terrorism and corruption that affected our country for so long has come to an end, thanks to the armed forces,'' said <PERSON> Aldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Zuccolillo </PERSON>, publisher of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Color </ORGANIZATION>, the country's biggest newspaper at the time <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> closed it down in 1984 for printing news the government did n't like. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, however, said nothing about elections nor how long his provisional presidency would last. He spoke at his swearing-in ceremony and in a nationwide address hours earlier in which he declared he was `` taking command of the country from this moment.'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 64, commands the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, the premier unit of the mostly-conscript, 12,500-man army. Diplomats and political observers said his coup was provoked by <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s attempt to force him to retire, his personal dislike for <PERSON> Montonaro </PERSON> and the growing influence of the military pro-Stroessner wing of the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> took advantage of what observers said was widespread military resentment at the forced, and allegedly politically motivated, retirements of about 130 army colonels and navy captains last month. At about 9:45 p.m. Thursday night, shooting broke out at the corps' base in <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pyta </LOCATION>, four miles north of the capiital. Soon after, 40 to 50 tanks rumbled out of the base heading downtown toward the headquarters of the police and <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>'s presidential guard. `` They did n't even ask us to surrender,'' said a member of the presidential guard, located next to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in a fashionable neighborhood of streets lined by fine homes and old mango trees. `` They just opened fire and battered down the gates with small tanks.'' Army units around the country rallied to <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>' side, and the lack of support for <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> was broadcast throughout the capital by <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Primero </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marzo </ORGANIZATION>, which the rebels took over. The two TV stations in the capital abruptly went off the air after the shooting started, as did all radio stations except Radio Caritas and <PERSON> Radio </PERSON> <PERSON> Primero </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Marzo </PERSON>. As light dawned and Paraguayans ventured from their homes, they saw the main building at the presidential guard roofless and with gaping holes in its brick walls. The modern National Telephone building behind the police station was a mess of twisted metal and shattered glass. Pools of blood that dried quickly into large red stains were beside bullet-riddled cars. In front of the presidential guard, scene of some of the heaviest fighting, were the bodies of a dozen soldiers who died defending <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON>. The coup was as successful as it was sudden and unexpected. By afternoon, <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> was in complete control. There were no apparent pockets of resistence to his authority, no condemnations by foreign governments. <PERSON> Stroessner </PERSON> had been a staunch <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally, but in 1986 the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration labeled his government a dictatorship. He has been reported in poor health since prostate surgery five months ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Coach-Guns     02-04 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coach-Guns,260</SECOND>
<HEAD>High School Football Coach Suspended Over Use Of Guns In Team Photo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OXON HILL, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The head coach of a high school football team was suspended for allegedly staging a photo session on school grounds in which some of his players posed with a machine pistol, an assault rifle and a bayonet, school officials said. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON>, a physical education teacher at <ORGANIZATION> Oxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Prince </LOCATION> <LOCATION> George </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, Md. was placed on administrative leave with pay on Monday after school officials learned that defensive players on the school's football team posed, weapons in hand, for the promotional poster on Jan. 27. A student told school officials that <PERSON> Pearson </PERSON> asked him to bring the weapons to school, officials said Friday. The weapons were not loaded when they were confiscated by school security officers and turned over to police, school officials said. The student, who is enrolled at the school but is not a member of the <LOCATION> Oxon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> football team, was temporarily suspended Monday, school officials said. The players said the poster was intended to be used as a publicity stunt to showcase the team's `` top guns'' and originally was supposed to be staged at the county jail. That did n't work out, so they staged the photo session at the school. `` It was a pretty innocent thing,'' one player, who asked not to be identified, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. `` The idea was to make the guys look tough, that's all.'' The incident occurred one day after four students were shot at another high school in nearby <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0134EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TMIWater     02-04 0363</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-TMI Water,370</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Mile Island Can Boil Away Water Left over From Accident</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The operator of the <LOCATION> Three </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mile </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> nuclear plant has been given clearance to boil away 2.3 million gallons of radioactive water that is part of the legacy of the nation's worst commercial nuclear accident. About 260,000 gallons of the water has been sitting in the reactor building basement since the accident at the <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> plant in 1979. The rest of the water was used in cleanup operations since the accident. General Public Utilities Nuclear, the plant operator, proposed to get rid of all the water by boiling it into steam released from a 100-foot-high stack, and packaging impurities for shipment to a low-level radioactive waste dump. But two <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> citizens' groups challenged the decision, expressing concern about the release of radiation into the atmosphere. The groups asked the <ORGANIZATION> Atomic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Licensing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> _ which is part of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> _ to consider other alternatives, including storing the water in tanks for perhaps 30 years to allow radiation to decay. But after holding hearings in <LOCATION> Lancaster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, the licensing board said in a written decision that the storage plan `` is not obviously superior to the evaporation proposal.'' `` We are convinced that implementation of -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear's -RRB- proposal will have extremely small radiation exposure consequences, both to workers and the general public,'' the board said. Last spring, <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> Nuclear raised eyebrows among local citizens by spending initial $ 800,000 on the evaporation system even before the licensing board had held hearings to decide whether the system could be used. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON>, spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Three </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alert </ORGANIZATION>, an anti-nuclear group, said at the time that it was `` distressing'' that the plant operator had apparently acted prematurely. But <ORGANIZATION> GPU </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> said it was merely trying to plan ahead, and that it would abide by whatever the board decided. The $ 7 million evaporation process is part of the $ 1 billion cleanup of <ORGANIZATION> Three </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Unit </ORGANIZATION> 2. During the accident, uranium fuel was allowed to lose the vital cooling water the normally covers it, causing material in the core to melt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Eastern-Trump     02-04 0450</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern-Trump,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trump Needs Only FAA Approval to Take Over Eastern Shuttle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID BRISCOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> needs only a safety certification from the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> to clear the way for his takeover of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' profitable Northeastern shuttle service. The <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> declared his organization financially fit Friday, giving final approval of an economic certification for the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> real estate magnate. The department had given tentative approval of the planned $ 365 million purchase two weeks ago and it became final after no objections were raised by interested parties, said department spokesman <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> Paris </PERSON>. `` As far as we're concerned, he can fly,'' said <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION>. He said the department determined that <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> had the managerial talent and the financial resources to operate what is to be renamed the Trump Shuttle. <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said there is no deadline for issuing an operating certificate but it could be approved within the month. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> had said he wanted to begin the service under his name this month. <PERSON> Leyden </PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> has to determine whether <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has the ability to run a safe airline by examining all his plans, including pilot training, maintenance and operating procedures. Once the <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> gives its approval, the sale by <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s Houston-based holding company, can become final and <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> can repaint the shuttle's 17 <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727 jetliners with his name and gold, red and black stripes. <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> has been trying to sell off the Shuttle and some other <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> assets, arguing that it needs cash for Eastern to survive. A federal judge approved the sale last December over objections from labor leaders who said it was part of a <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> effort to dismantle <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and reconstruct it as a nonunion company. Judge <PERSON> Barrington </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON>, in his opinion, recognized the union-management struggle but said it was also plausible that the company was trying to rebuild and place itself on sound financial footing. The union has said it would appeal the decision. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> already owns a helicopter service that flies between <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where he owns casinos, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, where he has built up a real estate empire. He announced an agreement to purchase the shuttle service last October. Eastern says the shuttle, which employs 850 people and makes 62 flights a day, made average annual profits of $ 17 million over the last five years while the airline itself lost $ 233.7 million in the first nine months of 1988. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> has vowed to recognize unions representing pilots, flight attendants and mechanics but has not guaranteed current wages. Eastern has offered to retain any shuttle workers who wish to remain with the company.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0029EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-JALCrashAward     02-04 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-JAL Crash Award,0291</SECOND>
<HEAD>Jury Awards Italian Family $1.5 Million In JAL Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A state jury on Friday ordered <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> to pay $ 1.5 million in damages to the family of an Italian man and his son who were among the 520 people who died in the 1985 crash of a <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Attorneys for the Italian widow, <PERSON> Heidi </PERSON> <PERSON> Moroni </PERSON>, 48, and her 18-year-old son, <PERSON> Alessandro </PERSON>, had sought more than $ 6 million in damages from the Seattle-based airplane company, said <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON>. Killed were <PERSON> Giancarlo </PERSON> <PERSON> Moroni </PERSON> and a second son, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> Moroni </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> has admitted liability in the crash, saying improper repairs it made after the plane scraped its tail during a hard landing in 1978 were to blame. The <ORGANIZATION> King </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> jurors deliberated a day and a half before returning their decision. The amount of damages was the only issue to be decided in the <LOCATION> Moroni </LOCATION> case and three others, all involving non-Japanese victims, that are pending in <LOCATION> King </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. Damage suits filed on behalf of 71 Japanese nationals against <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lines </ORGANIZATION> have been moved to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> for trial. According to Japanese press reports last month, there have been out-of-court settlements with families of 377 of the crash victims. <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> described the award as `` reasonable,'' and said the only portion <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> might challenge is $ 200,000 for the suffering endured by the two in the half-hour the damaged plane remained aloft before it crashed into a mountain. The plane lost its tail and rudder 12 minutes after takeoff, and over the next half-hour the pilot fought to regain control of the crippled jet. Four survived the crash.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ComputerVirus-Cornell     02-04 0147</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Computer Virus-Cornell,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cornell Completes Probe of Student Suspected of Creating Computer
Virus</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ITHACA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> has completed its investigation of the graduate student suspected of starting a computer virus that clogged 6,000 computers nationwide in November, a school official said. The university will not make its findings public until the report is actually completed during the next few weeks, <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynn </PERSON>, vice president for <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technologies </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Cornell </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the investigative panel, said Friday. The student, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, 23, is on indefinite leave from the university while federal officials ponder what charges he will face in connection with the Nov. 2 incident. Authorities accuse <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> of developing the virus that replicated itself nationwide in computers using the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s ARPANET computer network Federal authorities are reportedly undecided about whether to charge <PERSON> Morris </PERSON> with a felony or misdemeanor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-EPAConsultants     02-04 0505</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-EPA Consultants,500</SECOND>
<HEAD>Critics Say Consult Arrangement Promotes Conflict of Interest</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> wanted to prepare an annual report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on its Superfund toxic waste cleanup program, it sought out a consultant. <ORGANIZATION> ICF </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> prepared the document for $ 260,000. Congressional critics maintain that little more than the letterhead was changed on the draft received from the private company before it was sent to <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. `` Three words were changed, two ` ands' and a ` the','' complained Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, D-Ark., who held a hearing Friday on the widespread use of private consultants by the federal agency responsible for cleaning up the environment He said one of his major concerns is that many of the consultants working for the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> `` also have private sector clients from the very industries the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is charged with regulating'' raising questions about conflict of interest. <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> and other critics suggested that the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> _ and most likely other federal agencies and departments as well _ are relying too heavily on private contractors to do work, including critical analysis and often decision-making, that the government ought to be doing. <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials acknowledged in testimony before <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>'s Government Affairs subcommittee that they make extensive use of consultants, but maintained that precautions are taken to avoid a conflict of interest. They insisted that decision-making remains in agency hands. `` It comes down to workload. It's a matter of resources,'' <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Longest </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s Superfund cleanup program, where contractors are used widely, told the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> panel. But <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>, who has waged a decade-long fight against the federal government's extensive use of private consultants, did not accept the explanation. `` Consultants do everything from working on enforcing compliance with <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> regulations to writing <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>'s annual reports,'' Pryor declared in opening the hearing. `` It appears that the basic work of <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has been delegated to private consultants.'' The senator cited the case of a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> subcontractor found by congressional investigators to have recommended a particular cleanup method for a toxic waste dump. It turned out that the same company owned the rights for that cleanup method and was given the job, said <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>. <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON> also cited the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> contracts with <ORGANIZATION> ICF </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, including the one for preparing the agency's annual report to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on Superfund, as another example where questions of conflict of interest might be raised. While <ORGANIZATION> ICF </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, has several so-called `` sliding'' contracts with the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> valued for as much as $ 15 million, it also aggressively seeks business with private companies that are subject to <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> regulation and `` boasts of its <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> connection in its promotional literature,'' said <PERSON> Pryor </PERSON>. Earlier this week the <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Technology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assessment </ORGANIZATION>, which is <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' scientific research agency, also criticized the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> for relying too much on contractors in its Superfund cleanup program, suggesting that contractors and not <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> officials are running the program. Superfund is the $ 8.5 billion program through which the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is tackling hundreds of toxic waste cleanup projects across the country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     02-04 0025</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0025</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Friday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 03; 07; 14; 32; 37.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0141EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-LotteryRdp     02-04 0083</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery Rdp,0089</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked so far this week:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>CONNECTICUT</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Lotto: 02; 03; 07; 14; 32; 37.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>DELAWARE</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Play 4: 8-4-7-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 05; 08; 12; 22; 23; 30.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW JERSEY</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Pick 6 Lotto: 20; 22; 24; 29; 40; 41. Bonus: 62180.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Lotto 54 Game: 03; 09; 19; 40; 42; 54. Supplementary 52.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>PENNSYLVANIA</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Big 4 Lottery: 0-5-3-4.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 8-1-0; 4-0-2-2; 8-3-1-8-1; 4-3-0-8-4-6.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0143EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SyringeShortage     02-04 0205</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Syringe Shortage,0210</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shortage of Disposable Syringes Delays Oregon AIDS Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A program to help prevent the spread of AIDS among intravenous drug abusers by distributing free sterile needles has been delayed due to a shortage of disposable syringes, organizers said. The sponsoring agencies, Portland-based Outside In and the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> for AIDS Research, had planned for the program to begin in July but had difficulty insuring the program. The groups found a company in November to provide medical liability insurance, but <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Insurance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> stipulated that the distributed needles must be of such a design that they could not be re-used. Outside In has been negotiating with a British company to supply single-use hypodermic syringes, agency director <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> said Wednesday. Delivery had been promised Jan. 1, but the manufacturer ca n't mass produce them, she said. <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> said the supplier is having 1,500 syringes manufactured each month. Outside In will need a couple of thousand each month for its distribution program, she said. She said she did n't know when the supply problem would be resolved. Epidemiologists have said that direct blood contamination through shared needles is the most rapid way acquired immune deficiency syndrome is being spread.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-AntarcticSpill     02-04 0557</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Antarctic Spill,0575</SECOND>
<HEAD>Seals, Penguins Harmed By Oil Spill In Antarctic</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN NOBLET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PUNTA ARENAS, Chile (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A ship laden with more than 50 tons of equipment headed toward the <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> today to try and contain an oil spill that experts say is killing wildlife and threatening to wipe out a colony of baby penguins. The spill, from a sunken Argentine supply ship, has fouled the once-pure waters of a pristine bay and was endangering more than 24,000 penguins and other nesting birds, said biologist <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON>. `` It's very disturbing. Everything right now is worrisome,'' said <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON>, a researcher at the Palmer Station, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> research outpost on the <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. About 52 tons of equipment flown from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was loaded onto the 219-foot Polar <ORGANIZATION> Duke </ORGANIZATION> here from a giant <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> C-5 Galaxy cargo plane. The Polar Duke departed shortly after 6 p.m. Friday and was expected to reach the area in four days. The oil is leaking from the Argentine research and supply ship <ORGANIZATION> Bahia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paraiso </ORGANIZATION>, which is trapped and nearly submerged on shoals in the <LOCATION> Bismarck </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> just off the <LOCATION> Antarctic </LOCATION> peninsula. Thousands of penguins, terns, gulls and other birds live around the site of the accident, and the waters teem with marine life, including whales. Two areas nearby are set aside by the Antarctic Treaty for scientific study. Punta Arenas is at the windblown tip of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> about 600 miles from the stricken Argentine vessel. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Forhan </PERSON>, ocean projects manager for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, leads the cleanup mission. American scientists, wearing respirators as protection against the smell of oil fumes, are working in open boats to try to limit the damage, but <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> said `` virtually all of the area is exposed to fuel,'' causing young birds to disappear and killing small sea animals `` in large numbers.'' De <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> spoke by telephone with the The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. About 24,000 penguins nest in rookeries in the affected area, and <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> said 38 of the 40 adult birds checked by scientists have been `` fuel-dipped.'' The fear of the experts, he said, is that penguin chicks, due to leave nests within a few days, will swim in the oil-coated water and be sickened or killed. At least three dead penguins have been sighted, said <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON>. `` All of the rookeries are surrounded by oil,'' he said. A number of seals were seen to be covered with oil and were acting in a `` lethargic fashion,'' said the scientist. `` We have a slick 150 meters -LRB- yards -RRB- by 2 miles long going south from the vessel,'' moving `` along and a little bit away'' from the coast, <PERSON> Forhan </PERSON> said in an interview aboard the Polar Duke. He said there were reports of birds smothered by oil and of dead krill, shrimp-like creatures that whales feed upon in large numbers, floating ashore. Scientists and workers at <LOCATION> Palmer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> collected 112 compressed gas cylinders and 15 oil drums from the waters around the wreck, <PERSON> Forhan </PERSON> said, and `` there are more in the water.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Bahia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paraiso </ORGANIZATION> ran aground Jan. 25. The more than 250 people aboard were taken off without injury. Authorities said the ship carried at least 200,000 gallons of fuel oil in its tanks and more in drums lashed to the deck.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Japan     02-04 0463</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Japan,460</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Promises to Work on Opening Japanese Markets</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SUSANNE M. SCHAFER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says U.S.-Japanese relations entail `` some confrontation at times'' and vows to make sure that <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> businesses gain fair access to markets in that nation. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> spoke Friday at a White House luncheon for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> business leaders as Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> wrapped up a two-day visit to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> was leaving Friday night for <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> and a meeting there next week with former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. Speaking of the barriers <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> companies face entering Japanese markets, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> pledged `` to do my level best ... to be sure that we are treated fairly, that we have access, that we ... are not operating under standards that favor one side to the detriment of the other.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> observed that he and <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> `` are realistic men ... and we realize we are going to have some confrontation at times, or certainly differences of opinion.'' The president added that he believes the prime minister `` wants very much to have a cooperative relationship.'' On Thursday, the two men pledged after their 2 -LCB- - hour meeting and lunch to strive to smooth irritations over the $ 50 billion <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> deficit with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and tensions over the Japanese contributions to its defense effort <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did not elaborate on the details of the trade problems he and the prime minister discussed on Thursday, but said they'd `` reviewed the progress that our nations have achieved in bringing the economies into better balance and of further opening our markets to each other's goods and services. He added that the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> carries `` a disproportionate responsibility for the defense requirements of free countries'' and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, `` given its economic standing today, is willing to accept much more in the way of responsibility for helping ... in the whole development aid side of things.'' `` I just wanted to assure you that the visit yesterday had gone reasonably well,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told the businessmen. As the president spoke, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> bid <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> a formal farewell at the end of his two-day <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> visit with a <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> luncheon of champagne toasts, pheasant and ice cream with mangoes. In remarks at the luncheon, the secretary of state also struck a cautionary note, telling <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> the two economic superpowers `` still face a difficult agenda.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> also expressed hope the partnership will grow stronger as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> assumes a broader world role. `` <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is determined to do its utmost to collaborate with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, its strongest ally, for the peace and security of the world,'' the prime minister said, in his toast. `` No problems are unsolvable as long as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> join in an effort to solve them,'' <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AntarcticaShipwreck     02-04 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Antarctica Shipwreck,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Environmental Damage Grows From Antarctica Fuel Oil Spill</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Birds and other wildlife in one of the most remote parts of the world are being injured and killed by fuel oil spilled from a ship wrecked on an <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION> island, and more damage is possible before cleanup crews arrive. Biologist <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON>, chief scientist at <ORGANIZATION> Palmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Antarctica </LOCATION>, said that more than 24,000 penguins and other birds are endangered by an oil spill that threatens to wipe an entire generation of chicks maturing in nests surrounded by the pollution. Some wildlife already has been killed, he said. `` The environment has been compromised in a way that we ca n't even evaluate right now,'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> said in a telephone conference call from <LOCATION> Palmer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> `` It's very disturbing. Everything right now is worrisome.'' Palmer Station scientists, wearing respirators to protect against the eye-stinging fumes of the oil slick, worked in open boats to recover debris littering the fouled bay and to evaluate the damage. But <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> said a more effective effort to contain the spill must await the arrival Monday of a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> oil pollution control team from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. He said the fuel oil is spilling from the Argentine ship <LOCATION> Bahia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paraiso </LOCATION> at the rate of about two gallons a minute and if it continues the vessel could dump about 250,000 gallons into the previously pure, untainted waters nearby. The ship, which doubled as a cruise ship and a supply vessel for an Argentine research station, ran aground near <LOCATION> Palmer </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Station </LOCATION> last Saturday. It later floated free, went aground again 1.1 miles from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> outpost and then turned over on its right side against another island. As it turned, fuel oil and deck cargo spilled into the Palmer Station embayment, home to a number of large bird rookeries. Palmer Station is a <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> research station. Twenty-six scientists and staff are now working at the station under the director of <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON>, the chief scientist. <PERSON> Palmer </PERSON> is about 600 miles south of <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Horn </LOCATION>, the tip of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> reported that krill, a tiny shrimp-like crustacean, have been killed by the thousands and are lining the nearby beaches. Birds feeding on the krill seem sickened, he said. In a nesting area of the Polar Skua, a bird of prey, up to 40 percent of the chicks have disappeared, possibily because parent birds sickened by the oil are unable to protect their young, he said. About 24,000 penguins nest in rookies in the affected area, and <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Laca </PERSON> said that 38 of 40 adult birds checked by scientists have been `` fuel dipped.'' A number of seals were seen to be covered with oil and were acting in a `` lethargic fashion,'' said the scientist. The precise number of animals killed by the oil is difficult to calculate because other animals quickly eat the dead. `` It's pretty depressing,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     02-04 0949</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0986</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAMPA, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Royalty watchers who could n't get enough of Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> can catch a glimpse of Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON> when she comes to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the 1989 Volvo World Cup equestrian competition. Buckingham Palace confirmed Thursday that the 38-year-old princess, fourth in line to the British throne, will visit the competition. It will be held April 12-16 at the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Fairgrounds' <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Equestrian </PERSON> <PERSON> Center </PERSON>. According to <PERSON> Winkie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howell </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Tampa </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, the princess usually appears at the finals. He said her anticipated visit `` points up the magnitude of the World Cup to people who are not familiar with it.'' As many as 160,000 people are expected to attend the equestrian festival, which will be broadcast live by satellite to 250 million people worldwide.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Singer <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> says he prefers the song `` America the Beautiful'' over `` The Star-Spangled Banner'' because it's easier to sing and more graphic. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, commenting in the <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> publication Music World, said the range of `` The Star-Spangled Banner'' extends an octave and a fifth. `` Few people can reach both ends with comfort,'' he said in the winter issue of the publication. Additionally, he described the lyrics as bombastic. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, who has recorded a well-known version of `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> the Beautiful,'' asked, `` Honestly, would n't you rather sing about the beauty of <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>?''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BEDMINSTER, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Publishing magnate <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON> is the new owner of a 1749 document that is believed to be one of the last remaining royal charters in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>, who collects rare documents and purchased the <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION> township charter from a private collector, said Thursday he will display the charter in a climate-controlled case at his <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> office building. The document was originally given to <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> by <PERSON> King </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Bedminster Mayor <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cirona </PERSON> said the asking price for the charter was $ 20,000 to $ 25,000, but the purchase price was not disclosed. The document was believed lost in an 1845 fire that destroyed the home of a town clerk who stored it in a desk. But in 1918, the <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Historical Quarterly revealed that the document had somehow survived. <PERSON> Forbes </PERSON>' son <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> said the relic is one of the last remaining royal charters in the state. He said it grants <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION> the right `` to be and remain a perpetual township and community in word and in deed, to be called and known by the name of the Township of <LOCATION> Bedminster </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Moody </PERSON>'s week did n't exactly follow the classic lines of a <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> script, but it did have a kind of happy ending. The man who portrayed a teacher at the <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Performing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> in the 1980 movie `` Fame'' lost and then regained his real-life job as a drama teacher at the school for aspiring actors and dancers. He holds a temporary teaching certificate and was told Wednesday he was being replaced by a drama teacher with a permanent license and more seniority. But on Friday the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teachers </ORGANIZATION> announced that an agreement had been reached with the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION> to remain in the drama class and team-teach with his replacement, said union spokesman <PERSON> Bert </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanas </PERSON>. Team-teaching puts more than one teacher in the same classroom and takes advantage of each teacher's special skills, <PERSON> Shanas </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Moody </ORGANIZATION> said he chose to teach with a temporary license because it meant he could take acting jobs. He has appeared in eight movies.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet human rights activist <PERSON> Andrei </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> is planning another visit to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, this time with his wife, <PERSON> Yelena </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>, friends and family members said. The Sakharovs are scheduled to fly from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> next week. After five days in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, they plan to visit <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and then fly to <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> to see Mrs. <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>'s children. Mrs. <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Tatiana </PERSON> <PERSON> Yankelevich </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Newton </LOCATION>, said Friday the dates of the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> visit are still uncertain. Although both <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON> have visited the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> before, this will be their first trip here together. <PERSON> Sakharov </PERSON>, 67, won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1975 for his defense of human rights in his homeland. After speaking out against the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> intervention in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> in 1979, he was exiled to the closed industrial city of <LOCATION> Gorky </LOCATION>, about 250 miles from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Bonner </PERSON> was banished there as well in 1984, and the couple remained in Gorky until Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> personally called them back to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> in December 1986.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Premier <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> has publicly scolded his American-born wife for delaying a meeting to discuss their divorce plans. `` I asked and hoped that the divorce procedure would be set into motion before Mrs. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> left for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, but she refused,'' the premier said in a statement Friday. <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> left for a monthlong trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> Friday. The premier's 66-year-old wife is a native of <LOCATION> Elmhurst </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, who heads <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s largest feminist organization, is expected to make a brief stopover today in <LOCATION> Milan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>, to attend a conference of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> and Leftist Women <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> who will celebrate his 70th birthday on Sunday, has been living with his 34-year-old girlfriend, former airline stewardess <PERSON> Dimitra </PERSON> <PERSON> Liani </PERSON>. He is expected to marry Ms. <PERSON> Liani </PERSON>, herself twice divorced, when his marriage is officially dissolved. It would be <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s third marriage. Mrs. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> responded by accusing the premier of distorting the truth and said that `` the premier and I decided to meet after my return from the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0205EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Guyana-USFugitive     02-04 0219</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Guyana-US Fugitive,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fugitive Cult Leader Suffers Second Stroke</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GEORGETOWN, Guyana (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> fugitive and jungle cult leader jailed two years ago for manslaughter, has suffered a serious stroke, his second in three months, doctors said. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, 60, who calls himself Rabbi <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, was transferred from prison to <LOCATION> Georgetown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> earlier this week after a stroke caused partial paralysis to his left side. A stroke in November paralyzed his right side. The former leader of the now-defunct House of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> was convicted in <LOCATION> Guyana </LOCATION> in 1986 and sentenced to 20 years in jail for ordering the killing of one of his followers, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Maion </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>, whose hospital room Friday was heavily guarded by police, is also suffering from diabetes and a heart condition. Visitors were not allowed in to see him. <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> fled to this former British colony on the northeast coast of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> in 1971 after being convicted of extortion and jumping bail in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION>. By the early 1980s, <PERSON> Hill </PERSON> claimed a following of 10,000 and 47 `` synagogues.'' His House of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, which had no connection with <ORGANIZATION> Judaism </ORGANIZATION>, became known for breaking up political opposition meetings. After the death in 1985 of socialist President <LOCATION> Forbes </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Burnham </LOCATION>, President <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyte </PERSON> launched an investigation of the cult leading to <PERSON> Hill </PERSON>'s conviction for manslaughter
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Tower     02-04 0522</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tower,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vote, Delayed by New Allegations, Expected Early Next Week</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 New allegations against Defense Secretary-designate <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> are n't expected to delay further a vote by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on his nomination, says the ranking Republican on the panel. Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>., declined on Friday to say what the information dealt with But other sources indicated it concerned Tower's personal life, and specifically alcohol and women. `` It's just another chapter in an ongoing investigation,'' <ORGANIZATION> Warner </ORGANIZATION> said. `` I do n't attach any more significance to this chapter than to any other.'' He said an <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> report on the subject should reach the committee `` on Monday and ... we can proceed to a vote Tuesday or Wednesday.'' <ORGANIZATION> Congressional </ORGANIZATION> sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> was looking into allegations concerning `` Tower's behavior at a party last year in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>.'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported that the allegations involve an alleged liaison in <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> between Tower and a woman from an Eastern bloc nation, along with an allegation of excessive drinking in the past year. According to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, the new allegations include a report from an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> colonel which said Tower had 14 separate liaisons with women while he headed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> negotiating team in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> after leaving the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>. The committee had been expected to vote Thursday to recommend <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation of Tower, but that was postponed after the emergence of the new allegations. Tower, meanwhile, sought to dispel any impression of an embattled nominee, meeting for about two hours at his Jefferson Hotel residence with five people likely to be named to deputy posts at the Pentagon. He later issued a statement, saying the meeting had been scheduled for a week `` and had nothing to do with the proceedings before the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>.'' Editorials in <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, two widely circulated industry publications, called for Tower to withdraw his nomination. The editorials are scheduled to appear in Monday's editions. <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, a 49-year-old independent publication, said Tower's public position `` has been so compromised by the agonizing process by which he was nominated and is being confirmed ... that he can not be the strong spokesman the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> needs now. <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, also an independent publication, suggested Tower's links to defense consultants is the most troubling aspect of the recent confirmation process, and said, `` There is ample reason to doubt whether Mr. <PERSON> Tower </PERSON> is the man for these times. At the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said: `` Our feeling is he will be confirmed. Whenever you have a candidate who is undergoing this kind of scrutiny there are always things that turn up. We will await the final judgment.'' Rep. <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Aspin </PERSON>, D-Wis., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said he did not think it was `` necessary at this time to withdraw the nomination. Tower was dogged by allegations of drinking and womanizing before his nomination. In divorce papers filed two years ago by his second wife, <PERSON> Lilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Cummings </PERSON>, Tower was accused of `` marital misconduct.'' Tower, who has been divorced twice, is now single.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0209EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial     02-04 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Most Prospective Jurors Had Little Interest in Iran-Contra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 32 people sent into the jury pool this week in the trial of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> have one thing in common: All say they know almost nothing about <PERSON> North </PERSON> and the Iran-Contra affair. Most of the prospective jurors said they simply glance at front-page newspaper headlines and most say they are too busy with jobs or occupied with other interests to have paid much attention to the biggest foreign policy debacle of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Most are blue - or pink-collar workers, several with the government, while several others are unemployed or retired One woman is holding down two jobs. Of the first 25 prospective jurors, a dozen finished the 12th grade, one has a master's degree, two others finished college and another has some college education. Their occupations range from cement finisher to mental health administrator and the focus of their lives is work and family, not politics and controversy. On Friday, one of the prospective jurors, a woman who supervises 50 employees at the <ORGANIZATION> Willard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hotel </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, explained that she circled the name <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Coors </PERSON> on the jurors' questionnaire as a name with which she is familiar because substantial amounts of the brand-name beer are delivered to the hotel. Occasional talk by co-workers about the Iran-Contra affair, said the woman, had bored her during her 10 - to 12-hour workdays Coors, who contributed money to the Contras after meeting with <PERSON> North </PERSON>, is scheduled to testify for the prosecution at <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s trial. North attorney <PERSON> Brendan </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> told the woman that the name on the cans is the same as the name on the questionnaire and that the beer magnate would be pleased to know `` you buy a lot of it.'' North, who took the nationally televised congressional Iran-Contra hearings by storm in 1987, has through smiles and gestures made contact from across the courtroom with the potential jurors who will decide his fate. But it is unclear whether he has made much of an impression with jurors who say they just barely recall having seen pictures of him in uniform a year and a half ago. One man sent into the jury pool thought <PERSON> North </PERSON> might be the man who kept `` blinking'' and `` winking'' at him constantly as the prospective juror underwent questioning from <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>. North signaled that the prospective juror had guessed right by giving him a thumbs-up sign. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said as he concluded Friday's court session that he wants a pool of 45 people to choose a panel of 12 jurors and six alternates. The jury selection process resumes Monday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0213EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SteinbrennerPardon     02-04 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Steinbrenner Pardon,270</SECOND>
<HEAD>Documents Say Steinbrenner's Felony Conviction a Humiliation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1974 felony conviction of <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yankees </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> hurt his business interests and was a source of personal humiliation, according to his successful application for a presidential pardon. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> granted the pardon just before he left office last month. For example, the papers note: Last summer, <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> racing officials denied <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> an owner's license at <ORGANIZATION> Canterbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Downs </ORGANIZATION>, the state's first parimutuel thoroughbred racetrack, because of his conviction; Against his wishes, <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> declined a nomination to serve as a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regents </ORGANIZATION> governing <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s public universities `` because of the adverse publicity to the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> educational system that would likely ensue.'' And he has suffered the indignity of being referred to in articles as `` a convicted felon'' and the `` only convicted felon among baseball's ownership.'' `` The harm suffered by Mr. <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> is far more than economic; it is a symbolic slap in the face for a man who has tried so hard to overcome his conviction and be a good citizen,'' <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON>'s lawyer, former attorney general and senator <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Saxbe </PERSON>, wrote in the application. The documents were obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> after a special application to the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> was pardoned Jan. 19 by <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 17 years after he attempted to `` influence and intimidate'' employees of his shipbuilding company into lying to a grand jury about the nature of a $ 100,000 contribution to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON>'s 1972 re-election campaign. <PERSON> Steinbrenner </PERSON> pleaded guilty to conspiring to violate federal election laws. He was fined $ 15,000 but received no prison sentence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0214EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Deaver     02-04 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Deaver,380</SECOND>
<HEAD>Deaver Abandons Perjury Appeal, Cites Desire to Put it Behind Him</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former White House aide <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> says he is broke and tired of being `` a captive of the system.'' So, on Friday, he dropped the appeal of his conviction of lying to a congressional subcommittee and a federal grand jury, saying he wanted to `` put this period of my life behind me.'' <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON>, a top adviser to former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and a close friend of the former first family, said in a statement issued by his lawyers that he was dropping the appeal `` with the firm belief that I was not guilty of the charges of which I was convicted.'' However, he said, `` to proceed with this appeal means to continue to live in doubt, to continue to wait for a decision, and, if my appeal is successful, to face another trial, a process which could mean another two years of agony and doubt.'' He also said he could not continue the `` financial burden'' of the appeals process. The 50-year-old onetime <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> deputy chief of staff was fined $ 100,000 and ordered to perform 1,500 hours of community service for his three felony convictions in 1987 of lying about his lobbying of former administration colleagues after leaving the White House. `` My decision to withdraw my appeal does not come easily,'' <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> said in the statement issued as his lawyers asked the appellate court here to dismiss his appeal. `` It results from a number of factors, primarily my desire to put this period of my life behind me and get on with whatever lies ahead,'' <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> must now begin performing the community service which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Penfield </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> set as a condition of three years of probation when he sentenced him last September. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> has not yet specified what type of community service he will order. <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> said his `` belief in my innocence has not changed from the day the long and arduous proceedings against me began three years ago.'' <PERSON> Deaver </PERSON> resigned as deputy White House chief of staff in 1985 to start a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> public relations firm. He was convicted in December 1987 of lying under oath to the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> oversight and investigations subcommittee and a grand jury.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890204-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-02-04-89 0215EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Bomb     02-04 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Bomb,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Discovery Of Unexploded German Bomb Prompts Evacuation Of Thousands</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
