<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-UnoProfile     07-23 0476</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Uno Profile,0488</SECOND>
<HEAD>Quick Descent for Japan's Government Head</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Japan-Election, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY THORSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Until June 2, <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> was seen as a successful Japanese politician who had probably reached the pinnacle of his career as foreign minister. Then he became his party's last-ditch choice for prime minister, and his world quickly crumbled amid a welter of accusations about his private life and a crushing defeat suffered by the party he reluctantly led. On Monday Uno said he would resign to take responsibility for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s defeat in elections for the upper house of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, leaving his deeply troubled party in its second leadership crisis in two months. <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>, 66, will remain in office until the party chooses a new leader, which may take weeks. It took more than six weeks before the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> finally chose him to take over from <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>. <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> was not the party's first choice. For weeks its elders had tried to persuade the scandal-free <PERSON> Masayoshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> to become prime minister, but <PERSON> Ito </PERSON> refused. <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> was not a party leader or a previous contender for the premiership, and his name was not mentioned until late in the chase. But when he emerged as the choice, it appeared the party had made a safe but not exciting choice of a competent caretaker. The son of a wealthy sake-brewing family, <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> was untainted by the Recruit bribery scandal that had ruled out all the party's elite He had served in a number of Cabinet posts before becoming foreign minister and he had diplomatic skills to represent <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> at the approaching summit in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> of the seven industrialized democracies. But less than a week after he took office on June 2, published allegations that he kept a paid geisha mistress began to plague him. The allegations about his private life _ he did not quite deny them, saying instead he had done nothing immoral _ became another major problem the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> struggled with as crucial parliamentary elections approached. The party had suffered a steep decline in popularity from the Recruit scandal that embroiled its elite in suspicions of bribe-taking. It also was on the defensive over a new sales tax and agriculture policy. Although prime ministers usually are major campaigners to boost their party's hopes before an election, <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> made few public appearances in advance of Sunday's vote for half the seats in the upper house. Analysts predicted he would resign if the party did poorly. It did, losing its majority in the upper house, and <PERSON> Uno </PERSON> quickly followed by taking the traditional step of resigning to take responsibility. His political epitaph may be the words he reportedly uttered on June 27 in a plea to party leaders to let him step down: `` I did n't become prime minister because I wanted to.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0040EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DC-10Crash 3rdLd-Writethru a0606 07-23 1187</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-DC-10 Crash, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0606,1212</SECOND>
<HEAD>Search for Victims Ends, Some Injured May Face Permanent Disabilities</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with eight grafs to UPDATE with NTSB deferring to United's
death toll of 110; explains decrease to 110 victims in AP compiled list;
and NTSB saying engine parts within replacement requirements. Picks up
6th graf, `In another...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto XSCX7</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON COHEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SIOUX CITY, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The search for victims of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 232 ended Saturday with the death toll tentatively set at 110. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>, meanwhile, announced it is visually inspecting all engines in its DC-10 fleet. `` We feel comfortable enough that ... the search has been terminated for victims,'' said <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Woodbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. While officials were confident that all of the bodies had been recovered, there still was disagreement on how many were killed when the DC-10 jetliner cartwheeled and burned Wednesday at the <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> said it was 110 and the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> said it was 111. But a <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON>, said at a news briefing late Saturday the agency was `` deferring to <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>. That does n't mean we agree United is the authority on this.'' A list compiled by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> of names supplied by <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> and family, friends and employers of the victims had put the toll of dead and missing at 111. But two people listed with the same last name and slightly different first names were determined to be the same person. A doctor at one of the hospitals treating the injured said more patients could die and that the survivors might have permanent injuries. Of the 296 people on board, 186 survived. At the news briefing Saturday evening, <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said the parts of rear No. 2 engine that disintegrated during a flight from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> were well within the limits of time in which they had to be replaced. <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> also said investigators interviewed Flight 232's second officer Saturday, flight engineer <PERSON> Dudley </PERSON> <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON>. <PERSON> Dvorak </PERSON> told inspectors he reported complete loss of fluid in all three hydraulic lines after the rear engine blew apart, leaving Capt. <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> without control of wings or tail surfaces. In another development, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> official said at a news conference here that the airline has initiated `` a visual inspection of all engines in our DC-10 fleet. A prudent person would do some additional looking and we are.'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Guyette </PERSON>, executive vice president of operations for <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>, said the inspections should be completed on Monday. So far, they have uncovered `` very, very minor'' flaws, he said, adding that DC-10 airplanes in the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> fleet </ORGANIZATION> are not being grounded during the check. In <LOCATION> Chariton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, meanwhile, an <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> train carrying survivors of the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> flight struck and killed a 6-year-old boy as the youngster tried to free his bicycle that was stuck on the tracks. <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Howie </PERSON> was struck by <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION>'s eastbound <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zephyr </LOCATION> after the train had picked up several crash survivors at <LOCATION> Omaha </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> Amtrak </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, who added that he did not know how many survivors were on board. In <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, the wreckage of the wide-body jet remained sprawled over the airport Saturday as <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> crews sifted wreckage for clues to what caused the tail engine to disintegrate in flight. <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said four cranes were moved in to steady a giant hunk of fuselage in the cornfield next to the runway. Inspectors were able to determine that no bodies were underneath, he said. So far, the airline has positively identified 19 dead and tentatively identified 29, and hopes to have 80 percent of the bodies positively identified by Sunday, <PERSON> Guyette </PERSON> said. `` Great care has to be exercised to make sure a mistake is not made,'' he said. Forty-five people were still hospitalized Saturday. Nineteen, including four in critical condition, were at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> and 26, including five listed as critical, were at the <ORGANIZATION> Marian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Marian </PERSON> confirmed that one patient had died there overnight but would not give a name. Dr. <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON>, medical director for the burn unit at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION>, said they have 10 patients in the unit, who have burns from 2 percent to 93 percent of their bodies. Most suffered burns on face and extremities. All four members of the flight crew, including one off-duty pilot who left his seat in the cabin and to help in the effort to control the plane, were being treated at <PERSON> Marian </PERSON>. Their injuries were not critical, according to spokeswoman <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Denning </PERSON>. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said there was no need to look for other victims at the airport. `` The numbers match, the numbers balance,'' he said. Dr. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolpert </PERSON>, director of trauma services at <PERSON> Marian </PERSON>, said the five patients in critical condition are still in danger. `` They're not stable by any means,'' he said. `` There are a lot of broken necks and broken backs. Some of them might be permanently disabled. Some of them have definite brain swelling now but it's going to be quite a while before we know if that damage is going to be permanent.'' He said patients listed in serious or guarded condition have multiple fractures but are not in life-threatening condition. A large number of them, he said, have ankle injuries. The airport is open but large pieces of the doomed jet are strewn over the area. Still in a cornfield is the large piece of the fuselage from which survivors were able to crawl to safety, and the charred remains of the tail section, which flipped over the other wreckage as the plane broke up. `` There's a lot of documentation left to be done,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopatkiewicz </PERSON>, declining to predict when investigators would leave the scene. `` It takes a long time to document an aircraft as big as this.'' The drama of the final moments in the cockpit was detailed Friday as <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said the off-duty pilot, hearing the explosion in engine No. 2, bolted to the cockpit to see if he could help. <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said the off-duty pilot, identified as <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitch </PERSON>, found the airplane nearly unmanageable since the tail engine apparently threw wreckage through the airplane's hydraulic systems. Without control of wings or tail surfaces, the pilots' only recourse was to crudely steer the plane by varying the thrust of the two remaining engines. `` The only control mechanism that the crew had was to use engine thrust,'' <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> said. The off-duty pilot `` was on his knees manipulating the throttle.'' `` What you have here is a situation of two men desperately trying to get whatever control they can out of the aircraft,'' he said. Seven minutes before he attempted an emergency landing at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gateway </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, pilot <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> told the control tower, `` Whatever you do, keep us away from the city,'' <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON> quoted <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> as telling investigators during two one-hour interviews on Friday. The airport is about seven miles from downtown. The crew also found that the airplane would only turn right, further hindering efforts to line up with a runway.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Argentina-Caputo     07-23 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Argentina-Caputo,0312</SECOND>
<HEAD>President of U.N. Assembly Denies Charges He Misused Funds</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, on Saturday denied charges he misused public funds while serving as <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION>'s foreign minister from late 1983 until four months ago. On Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> filed charges in criminal court alleging <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> failed to adequately explain how he spent nearly $ 190,000 of the $ 538,200 he received for personal expenses while he was foreign minister. The ministry accused him of misappropriating public funds. `` If there is a charge, the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> should investigate to see what it is about,'' <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> said Saturday in a radio interview. The case against <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> involves the apparent use of the same stamp on receipts allegedly received in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. The stamp was found at the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>, a source there said, along with blank copies of hotel stationery. A ministry official was arrested in connection with the case, police confirmed Saturday. He was not identified, nor were the charges disclosed. In an interview with <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mundo </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> said, `` I do n't know anything about the contents'' of the charges. About his alleged involvement he said: `` The only thing I do with such funds is sign a receipt, and after that I do n't worry about the topic.'' The complaint filed by the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> stated in part: `` <PERSON> Dante </PERSON> <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> acted as though it is up to the government to justify the courtesy expenses that he says were made in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Stockholm </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, presenting papers that were stamped as paid with one and the same stamp.'' `` Documents appear that ... do not meet the mimimal appearance of seriousness,'' the complaint stated. <PERSON> Caputo </PERSON> personally received $ 538,200 for expenses, it said, `` and he has the legal obligation to account for it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BoyPilot 2ndLd-Writethru a0591 07-23 0565</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Boy Pilot, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0591,0578</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boy Pilot Takes Off on Last Leg of World Tour</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS first name in byline to James sted Jim; INSERTS 2 grafs
after 3rd graf, ``I want...' to UPDATE with procedure to certify record,
picks up 4th graf pvs, `Aliengena's father...; SUBS 14th graf to DELETE
reference to meeting with Gorbachev; picks up 15th graf, `Tony said...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COSTA MESA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 11-year-old boy successfully finished his bid Saturday to become the youngest pilot to circle the globe, landing safely at home after a trip that took him across the far reaches of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Aliengena </PERSON> touched down under bright, hazy skies at about 2:30 p.m. and turned off the engine of his plane at <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> John </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, where he started his `` Friendship Flight'89'' seven weeks and 19,000 miles ago `` I want to meet President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and talk with my parents and see if they will take me to <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION>,'' the boy said after landing. Flight observer <PERSON> Gunter </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON>, who accompanied the boy during the entire flight, said he will submit his records to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aeronautic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, which sanctions flight records. <PERSON> Hagen </PERSON> said he will recommend the group create a new category for youngest pilot to fly around the world and grant <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> that status. <PERSON> Aliengena </PERSON>'s father <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, who accompanied his son on the flight, emerged from the plane and then lifted his son from the aircraft, along with his sister <PERSON> Alaina </PERSON>, 10, and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON>'s Soviet pen pal, Roman Tcheremnykh, 10. <PERSON> Aliengena </PERSON> earlier Saturday took off from <LOCATION> Seattle-Tacoma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, stopped for refueling in <PERSON> Reno </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Nev. </LOCATION>, and then headed for <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>. The pilot and his entourage decided to skip a stop at <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, because of a delay in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> that put them a day behind schedule, said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Combie </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, a spokesman for the boy. `` They are all glad to be back in the lower 48,'' Combie said. The final leg was to be about 1,300 miles, he said. After he arrived in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> Friday night, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> said that when he gets home he wants to ride his bike for a while `` and then I'd like to meet President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, maybe.'' The fourth-grader flew a borrowed single-engine plane to <LOCATION> Sea-Tac </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Juneau </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, along with his flight-instructor father, <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, his mother, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON>, 10-year-old sister <PERSON> Alaina </PERSON>, and the rest of his party. The single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Centurion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tony </ORGANIZATION> started with crashed Tuesday while his father was taking off from <LOCATION> Golovin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, 90 miles from <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>, for a fishing side trip. No one was seriously hurt. That crash, which is under investigation by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>, was the only sour note on the 19,000-mile trip with 35 stops in seven countries, <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> said Friday night. `` I really liked the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, especially <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>,'' he said. `` I also liked <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> because that's where all my relatives are.'' <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> and his party, a second plane carrying some of them, made 14 stops in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> alone. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> said aviation will always be just a hobby. `` I want to be an orthopedic surgeon,'' he said. He plans to visit the White House to see President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and present him with the Friendship Scroll, which is more than 1,000 feet long and contains more than 200,000 signatures of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> children.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ChemicalDerailment 4thLd-Writethru a0601thepitcheswhenhehadto
07-23 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Derailment, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0601,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>CSX Train Derails; Evacuation Ordered</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf pvs, `On Saturday..' with 1 graf to UPDATE with
evacuation order in Midland canceled. Picks up 6th graf, `Fumes from...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREELAND, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> freight train derailed Saturday, igniting a fire in a tank car loaded with toxic chemicals and in at least one house, officials said. More than 400 people were evacuated. At least seven people were evaluated at hospitals, apparently because of problems caused by fume inhalation, said <LOCATION> Saginaw </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Caylor </PERSON>. `` They ... appear to be OK at this time,'' he said. Fourteen of 37 cars on the <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> train derailed; seven were empty and seven were chemical tank cars, said <ORGANIZATION> CSX </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ripley </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>. Officials initially believed at least two cars were afire, but later determined only one caught fire and was still burning. A 1-square-mile evacuation area around the derailment site was broadened to 10 miles, forcing more than 400 people from their homes, <PERSON> Caylor </PERSON> said. State Police Sgt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Mynsberge </PERSON> said the evacuation order could remain in effect for two days. An order to evacuate the southeast corner of <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> was canceled late Saturday and those residents were told to stay inside, close their windows and turn off ventilation systems in their homes, said <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> Leo </PERSON> <PERSON> Gay </PERSON>. Fumes from the fire are `` drifting into more populated areas,'' <PERSON> Beeson </PERSON> said. Earlier, a plume of black smoke rose from the burning cars, said Dow spokesman <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>. Winds were calm after the derailment just before noon. At least one house was burning, <PERSON> Black </PERSON> said, but the extent of damage was n't known. It was not clear if the house and the train car were burning in separate fires, officials said after conducting aerial surveys. Heavy smoke and intense heat prevented firefighters from getting closer. Five tank cars were carrying acrylonitrile and styrene, both used in the manufacture of rubber; acrylic acid; naphtha, and <PERSON> Chlorosilenes </PERSON>, a product of <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a joint venture between <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> and Corning Glass Works that produces silicon products. Acrylonitrile is a highly flammable liquid that is toxic if inhaled or absorbed through the skin. <PERSON> Styrene </PERSON> also is toxic if inhaled or ingested. Acrylic acid irritates the skin and is toxic if inhaled. Naphtha is highly flammable. <PERSON> Black </PERSON> said a company emergency team was at the site between <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Saginaw </LOCATION>, about 80 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>. `` They are in the process of separating the cars that are not involved in the derailment and going in with the protective suits to identify which cars are involved in the fire,'' he said Saturday afternoon. He said the derailment involved a load headed for the <ORGANIZATION> Midland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cogeneration </ORGANIZATION> venture, a joint project of <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Consumers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> to convert the utility's never-finished nuclear power plant into a gas-fired generator. The same tracks have been used for more than 10 years to carry toxic chemicals between <ORGANIZATION> Freeport </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION>, on a regularly scheduled run known as the Unit Train.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0117EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HelicopterCrash 1stLd_Writethru a0547 07-23 0251</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helicopter Crash, 1st Ld _ Writethru, a0547,0250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Six Dead in Helicopter Crash at Desert Fort</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS last graf with two grafs to include names of injured and
fatalities.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT IRWIN, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A predawn helicopter crash during training exercises Saturday at this desert post killed six soldiers and injured one other, <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> officials said. The soldiers were aboard a UH-60 Blackhawk helicopter when the aircraft went down at about 4 a.m. 14 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Irwin </LOCATION>'s main garrison, said Maj. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Wagstaffe </PERSON>. All the soldiers involved were from the First Cavalry Division based in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hood </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Wagstaffe </PERSON>. They were at the 1,000-square-mile base 120 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> for a three-week training exercise that ended Saturday. <PERSON> Wagstaffe </PERSON> said no other aircraft was involved in the crash, whose cause was being investigated. The identities of the victims were not immediately available, and likely would not be released until Sunday or Monday, he said. The injured soldier, Corp.. <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON>, suffered a broken right leg and a bruised lung, and was listed in stable condition at <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Linda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bernardino </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Wagstaffe </PERSON> said Sgt. 1st Class <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Carrasco </PERSON>, a public affairs spokesman at <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Irwin </LOCATION>, identified the dead as: Lt. Col. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Whittingstall </PERSON>; Capt. <PERSON> Marlon </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON>; 1st Lt. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>; Chief Warrant Officer 4 <PERSON> Roy </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Westbrook </PERSON>; Chief Warrant Officer 3 <PERSON> Delbert </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrow </PERSON> and Staff Sgt. <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>. Ages and hometowns for the victims were unavailable, <PERSON> Carrasco </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Diplomat-Espionage 2nd-LdWritethru a0595 07-23 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Diplomat-Espionage, 2nd-Ld Writethru, a0595,76o</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spy Suspect Had Top Access, Sources Say</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Adds 2 grafs after 11th pvs to update with LA Times rpt; picks
up 12th graf pvs, The government ...; a0570 stands as 2nd take</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LEE BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A top career diplomat suspected of collaborating with Soviet agents in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> had access to some of the nation's most sensitive non-nuclear secrets and once ran the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> embassy in that espionage-rich city before he was sent home for insubordination, sources said Saturday. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Felix </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, former deputy chief of mission at the embassy in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, has received <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> approval to leave his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> luxury apartment. But the surveillance of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> continues at a new, unspecified location, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> reported Saturday. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, who has not been charged with any crime, is the highest-ranking <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat ever identified as the target of an intelligence investigation involving the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. The government is keeping close tabs on <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> so he wo n't flee but <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said that federal officials also are concerned that he might try to hurt himself. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was last seen by fellow residents of his apartment building on Thursday. Since then, they say, a heavy contingent of government agents, whose surveillance of <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> had been obvious to his neighbors for weeks, apparently has departed as well. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> declined comment Saturday about the status of its investigation, which was brought to light the previous night by an <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> report which said he had been videotaped passing a briefcase to a Soviet <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> agent in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>. That incident, according to sources who declined to be identified, occurred early this year, more than a year after <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was reassigned to a largely bureaucratic post in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. Government sources told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> that, once confronted with allegations of his spying, <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> fell apart emotionally. The report said <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> has been interrogated two times and claimed he would cooperate. But one government analyst told the television network that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>'s cooperation has been `` extremely limited.'' A team of government psychologists, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said, does not believe that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> spied for money. Sources told <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> claimed he spied because he fell into a Soviet sex trap but investigators have discounted that story. The Los Angeles Times, citing an anonymous <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government official familiar with the case, reported Sunday that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was under suspicion of spying `` for a substantial period of time.'' Austrian Foreign Minister <PERSON> Alois </PERSON> <PERSON> Moch </PERSON> was quoted by the Kurier newspaper in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> as saying <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> apparently came under suspicion by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> authorities in the 1970s, the Times noted. The government has not charged <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, hoping that he will voluntarily tell investigators the extent of the information he provided to the East, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> said. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, former Ambassador <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON>, a candidate for the Republican nomination for mayor, said Saturday that he demanded in 1987 that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> be recalled to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> because `` He went outside of channels ... he went around me'' in dealings with the Austrian Foreign Ministry. <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said, however, that he had no indication that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON>, an Austrian native, had been dealing with the Soviets. <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON>, a political appointee as ambassador who himself has been criticized for his service in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, said he inherited <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> as his top deputy when he arrived at the embassy in April 1986. <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> had been there for six years already, and was in charge of the embassy during a lapse between the departure of <PERSON> Helene </PERSON> <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Damm </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON>'s confirmation, <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said. A congressional source, meanwhile, speculated that <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> was the effective day-to-day chief of the embassy throughout the time that Ms. <PERSON> Von </PERSON> <PERSON> Damm </PERSON>, also a political appointee and widely criticized as a social butterfly, was there. <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said he grew increasingly dissatisfied with <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> over `` insubordination'' and demanded that he be recalled in July 1987. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> complied within a matter of `` days or weeks,'' he said. <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said he knew nothing of the current investigation before hearing news reports Friday. He said he has since spoken with the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> about the case, but declined elaboration. `` I thought he was a poor member of the staff. So I got rid of him. If I thought he was a spy, I would have had him arrested,'' <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bloch </PERSON> did have access to `` a great deal'' of classified information, and that he `` could do severe damage.'' But `` At this point we do not know'' whether that has occurred. `` It could have potential impact, a great deal of impact on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Lauder </PERSON> continued. `` He had a great deal of access.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-PapuaNewGuinea-Crash     07-23 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Papua New Guinea-Crash,0120</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sixteen Hurt In Air Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT MORESBY, Papua New Guinea (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A light aircraft crashed east of the gold mining town of <LOCATION> Porgera </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Enga </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Province </LOCATION>, injuring 16 people, the <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. No deaths were immediately reported in the crash, which occurred Saturday. Further details from the crash site were not immediately available. The plane belonging to <LOCATION> Taliar </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Papua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Guinea </LOCATION>'s largest domestic airline, crashed into dense rainforest, the independent news agency said. It quoted the <ORGANIZATION> Papua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guinea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Comapny </ORGANIZATION> as saying helicopters were used to ferry the injured to a hospital in the nearby township of <LOCATION> Wapenamanda </LOCATION>. All the injured were in stable condition, the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BumpyFlight     07-23 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bumpy Flight,0261</SECOND>
<HEAD>American Jet Hits Turbulence, At Least 35 Taken to Hospital</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jetliner was buffeted by turbulence Saturday night near <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and at least 35 people were taken to hospitals after the aircraft landed, a spokesman for the carrier said. The A-300 airbus with 239 passengers and a crew of nine left <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Juan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, and landed at about 11 p.m. at <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Hotard </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Worth </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. `` On his descent into <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, -LRB- the pilot -RRB- said he hit an area of turbulence,'' <PERSON> Hotard </PERSON> said. `` It threw the aircraft up and then down.'' There was no immediate word on the extent of the injuries aboard American Flight 1077. Medical personnel and equipment met the plane, according to an airport official. Several passengers were taken from the aircraft in wheelchairs and stretchers. A spokeswoman for <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> said 20 people were transported there, but she did not know the extent or type of any injuries. Passengers reported hitting the aircraft's ceiling, objects flying around in the cabin and damage to a portion of the overhead baggage compartment. <PERSON> Carmen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pimentel </PERSON>, 48, of <LOCATION> Bayamon </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, said the plane bounced up and down three or four times. `` All of a sudden, everyone was jumping and flying,'' she said. `` My son was hurt in the head and the shoulder.'' <PERSON> Hotard </PERSON> said the pilot was at 35,000 feet and his radar was clear, showing no thunderstorm in the area, when the plane hit the turbulence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 0331EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-SriLanka-Censor     07-23 0367</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Sri Lanka-Censor ,0379</SECOND>
<HEAD>Chief Censor Slain</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chief government censor was shot and killed Sunday, police and witnesses said. <PERSON> Themis </PERSON> <PERSON> Guruge </PERSON>, who also headed the government-owned radio station, was taking a walk near his home at <LOCATION> Polhengoda </LOCATION>, 4 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Colombo </LOCATION> when he was shot by two unidentified gunmen riding in a white car, police said on condition of anonymity. <PERSON> Guruge </PERSON>, 60, a well-known broadcaster, was named head of the government's four-person censorship committee two weeks ago. Censorship on local and foreign press reports was imposed amid escalating ethnic violence and a growing dispute between <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION> over the presence of a 40,000-man Indian peacekeeping force. <PERSON> Guruge </PERSON>, a Sinhalese, was appointed chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Sri </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lanka </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> two months ago. Radio employees have received death threats from Sinhalese extremists in the past. Police gave no indication who may have been responsible for the killing. No one immediately claimed responsibility. Witnesses, speaking on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Guruge </PERSON>'s family rushed him to a hospital and their car was fired on by police at a checkpoint One relative was slightly wounded, the witnesses said. <PERSON> Guruge </PERSON> was pronounced dead on arrival at <ORGANIZATION> Colombo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. On Friday, Agriculture Minister <PERSON> Lalith </PERSON> <PERSON> Athulathmudali </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that censoring the press, both local and foreign, was proving to be counter-productive. Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ranjan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wijeratne </PERSON>, who announced the censorship July 6, said he agreed and promised to lift it soon, at least for foreign media. In the past six years, about 15,000 people have died in <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s ethnic violence. About 11,000 have died in the Tamil separatist war in the northeast, where Indian troops have been deployed since July 30, 1987 in an as yet unsuccessful effort to pacify Tamil guerrillas. About 4,000 people, mostly Sinhalese government officials and supporters, have been killed by Sinhalese extremists who accuse the Sinhalese-dominatd government of making too many concessions to the Tamil minority. Tamils comprise 18 percent of <LOCATION> Sri </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lanka </LOCATION>'s 16 million people and say they are discriminated against by the Sinhalese majority in jobs, education and use of the Sinhala language. Sinhalese, who account for 75 percent of the population, dominate the government and military.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1059EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Japan-Election 2ndLd-Writethru a0630 07-23 0804</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Japan-Election, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0630,0823</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Japan's Governing Party Concedes Defeat In Parliamentary Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to UPDATE on likely result in governing party loses
majority, background on scandals leading to its fall in popularity. No
pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ERIC TALMADGE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> conceded defeat in parliamentary elections Sunday after projections indicated it had lost its upper house majority for the first time in more than three decades. `` This is a big defeat,'' the conservative party's secretary general, <PERSON> Ryutaro </PERSON> <PERSON> Hashimoto </PERSON>, said in a televised interview. `` I am very sorry.'' A major loss for the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> would increase pressure for a general election and for a change of leadership in the scandal-plagued party. The <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> said their projections indicated the Liberal Democrats were certain to lose their majority in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Councillors </ORGANIZATION>, the upper house of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s two-chamber <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. Voters were deciding half of the house's 252 seats in Sunday's balloting. Final official results were not expected until Monday evening. A heavy turnout by <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s 90.3 eligible voters reflected strong feelings over a new sales tax, an unpopular farm policy and stock and sex scandals that have eroded the popularity of the governing party, according to opinion polls. `` The situation is extremely severe,'' <PERSON> Hashimoto </PERSON> said in an earlier interview Sunday. `` Though the final results are not in yet, it appears our old pattern is not working.'' <PERSON> Takako </PERSON> <PERSON> Doi </PERSON>, chairwoman of the main opposition <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which was leading in the projections, told reporters: `` This is the result of the people's choice.'' By late Sunday night, the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> projected the results for 88 of the 126 seats being contested in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Councillors </ORGANIZATION>. It said 25 would go to the Liberal Democrats, 34 to the leftist Socialists, six to the centrist <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, two each to the Communists and the conservative Social Democrats, eight to independents and 11 to minor parties. <ORGANIZATION> Kyodo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> gave similar projections, and both the news service and the <ORGANIZATION> Japan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> predicted that the <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> would not win the 54 seats they needed to maintain a simple majority in the upper chamber. Although the Socialists were doing well in the projections, a majority in the upper house will remain out of their reach because they would need to win 84 seats and they ran only 54 candidates in the election. The Liberal Democrats went into the election with 142 seats, compared to 43 for the Socialists and 23 for the Clean Government Party. A political party needs 127 seats for a simply majority in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Councillors </ORGANIZATION> and 139 seats to control all 16 permanent standing committees in the house. The Socialists have led efforts to create an opposition coalition with the <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Government </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialists </ORGANIZATION> and the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federation </ORGANIZATION>, which now has no seats in the upper chamber. If the Liberal Democrats lose control of the upper house, they will find it harder to pass legislation. But the party holds 293 of the 512 seats in the more powerful lower house, where elections need not be called until July 1990. The Liberal Democrats have produced all of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s prime ministers since it was formed in 1955. But a poor showing by Prime Minister <PERSON> Sousuke </PERSON> <PERSON> Uno </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> could increase pressure on Uno, in office less than two months, to resign and lead to early elections for the lower house of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. A Liberal Democratic loss there could bring <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> a Socialist-led government, since the lower house elects the prime minister. The Liberal Democrats, who represent conservative interests in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, have been hurt by a scandal centering around the <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a publishing conglomerate that was accused of doling out millions of dollars in underpriced stocks and political donations to obtain favors. Disclosures in the scandal led to the resignations of three Cabinet ministers and Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>. Shortly after he succeeded <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON> June 2, reports began to appear that Uno had kept paid geisha mistresses, igniting criticism from women's groups. The geisha scandal forced Uno to keep a low profile during campaigning, strengthening his image as a caretaker who will remain in office only until Oct. 31, when <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>'s term as party president would have expired. Farmers, traditional supporters of Uno's party, also revolted against its moves to open <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s agricultural market wider to imports. The Socialists rallied voters against a new 3 percent sales tax that was heavily backed by the governing party. The Socialists, putting forward a record number of women candidates, took advantage of housewives' anger over the tax, which was bulldozed through <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> by the governing party last year despite an opposition boycott. The tax, part of a sweeping tax reform, took effect April 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Kushnick     07-23 0171</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Kushnick,0177</SECOND>
<HEAD>Entertainment Lawyer Jerrold Kushnick Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Entertainment lawyer <PERSON> Jerrold </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON>, who guided the careers of comedian <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> and other talents, has died of cancer at the age of 58. <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON> died Saturday at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. As a lawyer and personal manager in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, his career spanned 35 years and encompassed Broadway, the music industry, motion pictures and television. <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorman </PERSON> <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON>, were executive producers of the Showtime special `` <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> and the American Dream'' and the <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> late night specials `` The <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON> Show.'' Through their firm <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, they also managed Emmy-winning writer-producers <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Dungan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Stein </PERSON>. <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON> was a founding director of the <ORGANIZATION> Tisch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> Scholarship Fund at <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Kushnick </PERSON> is survived by his wife, three daughters, a brother and his mother. A funeral service was scheduled Tuesday at Hillside Memorial Park in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan-Collision     07-23 0164</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Collision,0168</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two U.S. Servicemen Killed in Car Accident</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> servicemen died and two were injured in a head-on collision between their car and a truck in northern <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, police said Sunday. <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Sgt. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Depperio </PERSON>, 27, and airman <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, 20, died instantly in the accident on a highway Saturday afternoon, said a police officer in <LOCATION> Towada </LOCATION>, 360 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Depperio </PERSON>, the driver, was heading east toward the <LOCATION> Misawa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Air </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Base </LOCATION> with three other servicemen when he attempted to pass a car in a non-passing zone. He crashed head-on into a truck driven by <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Sakata </PERSON>, 61, who was heading west, police said. Airmen <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, 20, and <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Theis </PERSON>, 22, were injured and taken to a nearby hospital, according to the police officer. He said <PERSON> Sakata </PERSON> escaped injury. <PERSON> Theis </PERSON> was seriously injured and <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> was only slightly injured, the police officer said. The hometowns of the Americans were not immediately available.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Genscher     07-23 0119</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Genscher,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Genscher to Be Moved From Intensive Care Unit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Foreign Minister <PERSON> Hans-Dietrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> is improving after suffering a mild heart attack and will be released from intensive care, a spokesman said Sunday. Ministry spokesman <PERSON> Hanns </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumacher </PERSON> said <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON> would be moved from intensive care to a normal care unit on Monday. <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>, 62, suffered a mild heart attack Thursday. He has remained hospitalized in a <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> clinic since the attack. <PERSON> Schumacher </PERSON> said quick treatment had prevented the attack from becoming more serious and that there appeared to be no permanent damage to <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>'s heart. <PERSON> Genscher </PERSON>, the West's longest serving foreign minister, is known for his exhausting work schedule and his globe-trotting diplomacy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Llewellyn     07-23 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Llewellyn,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stars and Stripes Founder Dead at 83</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TACOMA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Retired Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Ensley </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Llewellyn </PERSON>, founder of the military newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Stars </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stripes </ORGANIZATION> and a member of Gen. <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s staff during World War II, has died at age 83. <PERSON> Llewellyn </PERSON> died Wednesday, said <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Riches </PERSON>, funeral director of Dryer Mortuary. Riches said Saturday he did not know the cause of death. At <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>'s request, <PERSON> Lewellyn </PERSON> established the Stars and Stripes for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> and built it into a worldwide chain of 16 dailies with a circulation of 2 million. He retired in 1951 after 30 years in the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> and returned to <LOCATION> Tacoma </LOCATION>, where he became owner of <ORGANIZATION> Llewellyn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Advertising </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> and managed local and state political campaigns. He also served as state adjutant general in charge of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, as state civil defense director, and was a representative to the White House Conference on Aging in 1980. Survivors include his second wife, <PERSON> Vera </PERSON>, two sons, three grandchildren and two great-grandchildren. Services were scheduled Tuesday at <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Place </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Presbyterian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1151EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica     07-23 0473</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa,0482</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tutu Says Government Leader Seeks to Divide ANC and Mandela</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Archbishop <PERSON> Desmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> on Sunday accused the head of the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> of a `` crude attempt'' to create a split between the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and its imprisoned leader, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON>, a black Anglican active in the anti-apartheid movement, challenged an assertion by F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> that the burden was on the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> to renounce its guerrilla campaign against the white-led government as a precondition to negotiations. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, expected to succeed P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> as president after elections Sept. 6, said Saturday the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> should `` follow the lead'' of <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> by committing itself to a peaceful settlement. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> was referring to the meeting between <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> earlier this month in which the two leaders expressed support for `` peaceful development'' in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has his history wrong,'' <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said in a statement. `` Our liberation movements have sought change peacefully since before 1910. It is his government which forced the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> and PAC -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Pan-Africanist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- to turn to violence by banning them, and it his his government which must un-ban them and create conditions conducive to negotiations.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s `` crude attempt to drive a wedge between Mr. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> is deplorable and indicates he is not serious about negotiations,'' <PERSON> Tutu </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, in a brief statement following his meeting with <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, confirmed that he had endorsed `` peaceful development'' but stressed that no peaceful solution could be found unless the government negotiated with the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> and its allies in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> has waged a bombing and sabotage campaign in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> since 1961, a year after it was outlawed. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> was jailed in 1962. He is serving a life sentence for sabotage and plotting to overthrow the government. The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> has rejected <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s recent proposals for a five-year plan to give the disenfranchised black majority a formal voice in national politics without letting it impose its will on the white minority. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> is the overwhelming favorite to retain control in the white election Sept. 6, but a newspaper poll published Sunday indicated that liberal and conservative opposition parties could do well enough to deprive the Nationalists of an outright majority in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. The poll, commissioned by the nationally circulated <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>, said the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> would win 78 seats in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, the far-right <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> 52 and the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> 36 if the election were held this week and there was an 80 percent turnout. Details about how the poll was conducted were not published. A separate poll published Sunday in the Afrikaans-language newspaper Rapport predicted the Nationalists would win about 46 percent of the vote, the Conservatives 25 percent and the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> about 29 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1152EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-InvisibleGuest Bjt   07-23 0870</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Invisible Guest, Bjt,0893</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dissident Couple Haunts American Embassy</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dissident <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON> is the guest who never comes to dinner. He never appears at parties at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>, where he has lived since early June, but somehow he manages to haunt them. Guests inevitably peer down halls and around corners in hopes of glimpsing the man whose invisible presence has helped bring U.S.-Chinese relations to their lowest level since normalization in 1979. But even some high-level embassy staff say they have never seen the short, plump astrophysicist or his wife, physics professor <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Shuxian </PERSON>, who is in hiding with him. The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> disclosed June 6 that the couple, outspoken critics of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rulers, had taken shelter in the embassy after the army moved in on pro-democracy protesters in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. The Chinese government issued arrest warrants for the pair, accusing them of orchestrating the protests. Embassy officials refuse to say even which of the three walled embassy compounds houses the Fangs. They may live in comfort in a guest room at Ambassador <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Lilleys </PERSON>' home. Then again, perhaps they are hidden from Chinese staff in more secure, but less homey, quarters. Do they use the embassy pool at night when everyone has gone home? Do they watch <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> television, now banned elsewhere in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, off the embassy's satellite dish? Embassy staff only shrug. Most change the subject or walk away when someone mentions <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>'s name. But now and then someone makes a joke, as when Counselor <PERSON> McKinney </PERSON> <PERSON> Russell </PERSON> turned to a guest at the embassy's Independence Day picnic and asked if he had met Professor <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>. The guest took the bait and asked eagerly to be introduced. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, of course, did not attend. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> probably would have enjoyed the picnic and the joke. A friendly man with a puckish sense of humor, he often laughs heartily during conversation. But his calls for the all-powerful <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to allow political debate and even formation of new parties are serious. `` Some people think <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> does n't need democracy, but I think human rights are basic. For them to be realized, first of all famous people must take a stand,'' he said in February, during a relative thaw that preceded the April start of the student movement. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> gained fame internationally as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most articulate human rights spokesman, but his initial renown at home came as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first physicist to specialize in black hole theory. He became a hero to many intellectuals in 1987, when the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ousted him for making pro-democracy speeches it said helped incite student marches. The party distributed copies of the speeches to be criticized during political study sessions, but many readers secretly found themselves in agreement. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> was not a frequent visitor at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION>. However, one embassy invitation caused an international stir _ to a banquet given by visiting President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in February. Chinese police stopped <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> en route and refused to let him attend. The Chinese government lodged a formal protest with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> over that invitation, and again when it gave shelter to <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> and <PERSON> Li </PERSON>. But <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> mostly vented its ire in newspaper commentaries that branded <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> a traitor and the `` scum of the nation,'' and accused <PERSON> Li </PERSON> of not having `` a real Chinese heart.'' Newspapers accused the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy of violating international law by sheltering the couple. The embassy was deluged with phone calls from Chinese expressing their indignation. An ambassador who lives near the main <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy compound reportedly complained to the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> that Chinese were standing outside shouting epithets at <LOCATION> Fang </LOCATION> in the middle of the night. Chinese police who normally guard foreign embassies have multiplied outside the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> facilities since <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> and <PERSON> Li </PERSON> took up residence, and the officers now carry automatic pistols. Half a dozen uniformed and plainclothes police camp around the clock outside <PERSON> Lilley </PERSON>'s residence. They sit on low stools, drinking tea and playing cards, and hang laundry from a small guard booth, giving it the look of a squatter camp. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> security also has tightened. The compound where the ambassador lives used to leave its gates open. Now they are locked and even <LOCATION> Americans </LOCATION> must show their passports to enter. The Fangs' options are limited. They can leave the embassy and face arrest, or stay inside as virtual prisoners. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has said it would like to reach a compromise with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> that would allow the couple to leave for a third country, but <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> insists they are criminals who must be prosecuted. Neither side will say if talks are going on. Meanwhile, one scientific research society has expelled <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, and a city district people's congress to which <PERSON> Li </PERSON> was elected in 1987 is discussing expelling her. Staff who answered the telephone at the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Observatory </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> works, said his name remains on the list of employees. It is unlikely he will return to work there, however, as long as the current government is in power. `` I am like a soldier who has already crossed the river. There's no way to turn back,'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> said in an interview last year Never has that been truer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Britain-Burma     07-23 0282</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Britain-Burma,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Concerned About Husband of Burma's Opposition Leader</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is concerned about the whereabouts of the British husband of Burmese opposition leader <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON> <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Aris </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> on Friday and when he arrived in <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION> on Saturday, he was not permitted to see a British diplomat waiting for him at the airport, the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said. A spokesman, speaking anonymously in keeping with <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> custom, said it was possible that Aris, an <ORGANIZATION> Oxford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> professor and an expert on <LOCATION> Tibet </LOCATION>, was under house arrest along with his wife. `` The charge d'affaires from our embassy went to meet him at the airport -LRB- but -RRB- he did n't come through the normal channels,'' the spokesman said. `` Our charge d'affaires then asked if he could see him and was not allowed to. The next step will be for us to take this up with the <LOCATION> Burmese </LOCATION> authorities.'' <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s government announced Friday that Ms. <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Burma </LOCATION>'s top opposition leader, was placed under house arrest Thursday at her family's home in a suburb of <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> It accused her of trying to `` revive anarchy'' in the country. Ms. <PERSON> Suu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kyi </PERSON> is the most vocal critic of Gen. <PERSON> Saw </PERSON> <PERSON> Maung </PERSON>'s military government, which seized power in a coup in September and imposed martial law She is the daughter of <PERSON> Aung </PERSON> <PERSON> San </PERSON>, an independence leader assassinated in 1947. She was thrust into the political arena after returning to <LOCATION> Rangoon </LOCATION> from her home in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in April 1988 to care for her ailing mother. She spoke before hundreds of thousands of people during nationwide pro-democracy protests last year. The military crushed the protests in September and banned demonstrations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Italy-Politics     07-23 0322</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Italy-Politics,0336</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Government Sworn In</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s 49th postwar government was sworn in Sunday after <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> formed a five-party coalition and ended a 65-day political crisis brought on by the resignation of Premier <PERSON> Ciriaco </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Mita </PERSON>. The coalition formed Saturday is comprised of the same centrist parties that have ruled together for most of the 1980s, and no major changes in policy were foreseen. The coalition parties have a comfortable majority in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> and the government was expected to easily win a vote of confidence this week. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is expected to hold its debate on the new government on Wednesday or Thursday, while the <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Deputies </ORGANIZATION>, the lower house, is scheduled to vote on the new government at week's end. On Sunday morning, President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> swore in <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> to his sixth term as premier. Afterward, other Cabinet members took the oath in front of <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON>. After the swearing-in, the 70-year-old premier met with the other 31 members of the Cabinet. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> told reporters his government is like a child: `` It's small at birth but can grow strong and robust. The new premier has said he will concentrate on preparing <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> for 1992, when the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> drops its internal barriers to trade and becomes a single market. Other priorities include fighting crime, tax evasion and pollution, he said. The new government is expected to maintain <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s close ties with the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Many of the key posts in the new government changed hands, but a majority of the new officials had been ministers before. <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> was premier twice in 1972-73 and three times successively in 1976-79. He has served in more than a dozen other ministerial posts and has been dubbed `` minister for life.'' He said he celebrated the creation of his new government by watching an old <PERSON> Audrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Hepburn </PERSON> film on television Saturday night.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-India-Politics     07-23 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-India-Politics,0532</SECOND>
<HEAD>Opposition Resigns from Parliament to Protest Gun Deal</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SHARON HERBAUGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW DELHI, India (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 All 106 opposition members in the lower house of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> resigned Sunday to protest Prime Minister <PERSON> Rajiv </PERSON> <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s refusal to step down over a controversial foreign arms deal. The decision by the 12 opposition parties in the <LOCATION> Lok </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sabha </LOCATION>, the lawmaking branch of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, was sparked by an auditor's report citing inconsistencies in the 1986 purchase of $ 1.4 billion in Swedish artillery guns. Opposition members and news reports allege officials received millions of dollars in kickbacks in return for securing the contract for the Swedish company. The move was not expected to have much effect on <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> since <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> commands a majority, but opposition leaders said they hoped it would call attention to the arms deal and make it a major issue in the next election, due by January. `` Never before has the office of the prime minister been brought into disrepute as under the present incumbent,'' said V.P. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-. `` We were all elected by the people, and now we are going back to them for their verdict on this issue.'' Government officials contend the deal was sanctioned by <PERSON> Singh </PERSON>, who at that time served as finance minister in <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s Cabinet. <PERSON> Singh </PERSON> left the governing party in 1987. The 12 opposition parties controlled 106 seats in the 544-member Lok Sabha. Besides the <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dal </ORGANIZATION>, they include the <ORGANIZATION> Bharatiya </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Janata </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Indian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> -RRB-, the Telugu Desam -LRB- Party of the Telugus -RRB-, the two major Communist parties and other regional groups. The rest of the seats are controlled by <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and independents. After the auditor's report was released Tuesday, opposition members in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> shouted anti-government slogans, called <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> a thief and demanded his resignation. When he refused, they walked out and stalled proceedings for three days. The report said the arms purchase was flawed on technical considerations and cost assessment. The arms purchase has been a major scandal for <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s government because of allegations the Swedish firm <ORGANIZATION> AB </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> paid kickbacks to secure the contract Newspapers and opposition politicians say kickbacks amounting to at least $ 50 million were paid to senior government officials and to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> coffers. The allegations have never been proved. Opposition leaders have previously demanded <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON>'s resignation on the issue, but the 44-year-old prime minister has repeatedly said he was not involved in any wrongdoing. A parliamentary committee that investigated the deal last year said there was no evidence kickbacks or commissions were paid to secure the sale. Opposition parties have been using the <ORGANIZATION> Bofors </ORGANIZATION> issue to try to merge and mount a viable challenge to <PERSON> Gandhi </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in the general election. Their efforts have stalled in squabbling and widely publicized power struggles for nearly a year. But N.T. <PERSON> Rama </PERSON> <PERSON> Rao </PERSON>, leader of the Telugu Desam, said the decision to resign from <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> proved the opposition could unite on major issues. `` We are committed to give a clean government to the country,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-TidalWave     07-23 0110</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tidal Wave,0111</SECOND>
<HEAD>12 Killed, 51 Missing After Tidal Wave</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DHAKA, Bangladesh (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tidal wave roared through the Bay of <LOCATION> Bengal </LOCATION> on Sunday, inundating islands off the coast and killing at least 12 people, authorities said. At least 51 people were missing. Officials at the <ORGANIZATION> Cyclone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preparedness </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Dhaka </LOCATION> said a 6-foot wall of water pounded scores of islands up to 200 miles offshore. The dead included nine fishermen, officials said. Most of the 51 missing were fishermen. The island of <LOCATION> Sandwip </LOCATION> was hit hardest by the wave, which washed away hundreds of mud and straw huts and left an estimated 2,000 people homeless, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-AIDSEpidemic     07-23 0702</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Epidemic,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>AIDS Cases In United States Pass 100,000 Mark</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL RECER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Science Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 At least 100,000 people in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now have AIDS. Some time in recent weeks _ nobody knows just when _ the report for the 100,000 th recorded case of AIDS in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> became part of the data files at Centers for Disease Control That case report joined hundreds of others flowing into <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> computers, where it was combined with thousands of earlier reports to eventually become part of the cumulative number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> AIDS cases. When the monthly total for July is compiled and released in late August, <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> experts are sure that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s official count of total AIDS cases will, for the first time, officially pass 100,000. `` Due to the backlog of reporting, plus the fact that we're retroactively going back and adding cases by the dozens, we probably reached 100,000 already,'' said <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fallis </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> spokesman But <PERSON> Fallis </PERSON>, who declined to arrange interviews with <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> epidemiology experts, said: `` There's really no way to tell which case is the 100,000 th case. Many experts, including some at <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>, have admitted that the AIDS case total is more of a rough estimate than a precise count. But what the official total does emphasize is that there has been no retreat or slowing in the dreadful statistical march of AIDS. The nightmare is following a script of disease, illness and death that <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> epidemiology experts predicted in May 1988. By 1992, the federal agency expects there will be a cumulative total of 365,000 confirmed cases of AIDS. The agency also predicts that within three years the total number of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> residents killed by AIDS will reach 263,000 _ a total almost five times higher than the total number of Americans killed in the Vietnam War. But that's only part of the picture. In order to be counted in the official <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> survey, a patient must have a positive blood test for AIDS, plus other symptoms, such as opportunistic infections, persistent loss of weight or chronically enlarged lymph nodes. Beyond these counted patients, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> estimates that there are 1 million to 1.5 million Americans who are infected with the AIDS virus but have not yet developed symptoms. These people are said to be seropositive. They can spread the disease, but are themselves not yet suffering its deadly effects. `` Fifty to sixty percent of people who are seropositive will develop at least some symptoms of AIDS within five years,'' said <PERSON> Fallis </PERSON>. Federal estimates of the cost of AIDS are staggering. `` Projections indicated that a total of 172,000 AIDS patients will require medical care in 1992 at a cost expected to range from $ 5 billion to $ 13 billion,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> reported in May. The agency said these figures `` are underestimates of the true magnitude'' of the medical costs of the AIDS virus because many clinical treatments for the disease are not reported. Patterns of AIDS infection are slowly changing. Whereas once AIDS was almost exclusively a disease of homosexuals, the rate of discovered cases in that population group is slowing down. In the 12 months ending June 30, homosexual and bisexual males represented 57 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> AIDS cases. This is a 2 percent drop from the previous 12 months. <PERSON> Fallis </PERSON> said experts believe this is because of changes in life style practices and because the population group is becoming `` saturated'' _ the number of uninfected members of this group is becoming too small to maintain the previous rate of new cases. For intravenous drug users, however, the infection rate is rising. For the 12 months ending June 30, 23 percent of the total AIDS cases were among male and female IV drug users. This is an increase of two percent from the previous 12 months. AIDS is a contagious disease that destroys immune cells and renders the body unable to resist disease. It is caused by the human immunodeficiency virus -LRB- HIV -RRB- which is spread most often through sexual intercourse with infected persons or through needles shared by intravenous drug users. Infection can also come from contaminated blood transfusions, which is rare, and babies can become infected from their mothers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Watkins'Worries Bjt   07-23 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Watkins' Worries, Bjt,770</SECOND>
<HEAD>Energy Secretary Struggling to Win Public Confidence in Nuclear Program</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As his struggle to rebuild the nation's nuclear arms industry grows more urgent, Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> may be losing a grip on his most important tool: public belief that the weapons plants can be made safe Since he took office last March, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> and a team of senior department aides have been racing against time to fix decades of neglect in the weapons program before reactor breakdowns and other problems seriously undermine <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> defense strategy. From the start, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> believed the key to success was convincing the public _ including workers at the plants and nearby residents _ that an era of nuclear secrecy was ended, that their government could be trusted to run the plants safely. To his dismay, the cloud of mystery and distrust has only grown darker. No significant accidents have been reported at any of the 17 major weapons facilities in 12 states since <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> took over, but some have been forced to close temporarily and a series of recent incidents has raised new health and safety questions. In just the past week, for example: _ The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>'s own auditors issued a blistering review of management failures and predicted that unless urgent action is taken to correct the flaws <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> will face more pressure to close the plants. It also said department employees may face criminal charges for violating environmental laws. _ The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> dispatched agents to one of the weapons plants in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> to investigate allegations of criminal violations of laws governing the handling, storage and disposal of hazardous wastes. _ The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> disclosed that it is investigating allegations of financial fraud at the same <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> plant, known as the Feed Materials Production Center, near <LOCATION> Cincinnati </LOCATION>. _ The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> added seven major weapons facilities _ in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> _ to its list of the most polluted sites in the nation. _ Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> proposed legislation that would take away from <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> some responsibilities related to the weapons program, including one measure that would transfer to the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> the authority to study and monitor the health effects of radiation on workers at the weapons plants and another that would empower an independent board to shut down any or all of the weapons plants on safety grounds. _ More environmental groups called on <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> to withdraw his choice of <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>, the controversial operations chief of the <ORGANIZATION> Nuclear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, to take over day-to-day administration of the nuclear weapons program. Although the Stello nomination has gained little public notice outside <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, the basis of the opposition runs to the heart of <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' underlying dilemma. `` Secretary <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> has been conducting a public relations effort to convince the public that he is serious about environmental and safety problems at these facilities, but actions like the nomination of <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> just do n't support his words,'' said <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Costner </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a citizen group pushing for closure of the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> weapons plant in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. Stello's critics contend he is not sensitive enough to health and safety issues. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' struggle to erase the impression that environmental and safety problems at the weapons plants are out of control is complicated by the pressure he faces to fashion a strategy for resuming nuclear materials production at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and getting his waste management program off dead center. Public announcements of new waste control measures, nuclear production schedules and a blueprint for reshaping the entire weapons complex are expected sometime in August. The timing and success of <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' grand design is crucial. The Pentagon says it may have to cannibalize some warheads unless the <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> nuclear reactors resume production of tritium soon. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, though, sees risk in overhauling too quickly a program the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> has called `` one of the more potentially dangerous industrial operations in the world.'' Now, with some solutions apparently in sight, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is being forced to fight rear-guard skirmishes with the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION>, whose surprise raids this summer on the Rocky Flats plutonium processing plant in <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION> and the Feed Materials uranium plant in <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> have undercut <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' efforts to sooth public safety concerns. <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, the deputy energy secretary, and other senior department officials have expressed dismay at the unwillingness of the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to coordinate their investigations with <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>. `` What we do n't need is this alarming people'' about health and safety risks by springing surprise raids that create the impression that the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> thinks the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> ca n't be trusted to monitor its own facilities, <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1203EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LotteryLosses     07-23 0254</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lottery Losses,0260</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lottery Winner Now Destitute, Headed for Prison</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WAUKESHA, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Just three years after he won the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery jackpot, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Brownlee </PERSON> is headed back to prison as a destitute and remorseful man. His lawyer says the cash windfall ruined his client's life. `` This is a <PERSON> Horatio </PERSON> <PERSON> Alger </PERSON> story in reverse _ a rags to riches to rags again,'' attorney <PERSON> Craig </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuhary </PERSON> said last week before his client was sentenced to three years in prison for writing bad checks. In 1986, <PERSON> Brownlee </PERSON> appeared ready to shed his past criminal record and drug abuse problem and take on a new life. He applied for a job and pocketed $ 380,565 in the <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> lottery. But $ 80,000 in charity donations, some bad investments and a return to drugs and crime has left the 38-year-old <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> man virtually penniless and headed back to the familiar surroundings of a state prison. `` I accept full responsibility for my unacceptable behavior. I owe society a debt,'' <PERSON> Brownlee </PERSON> told Circuit Judge <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> before he was sentenced Friday to three years in prison and four years of probation. <PERSON> Brownlee </PERSON> was convicted in March on four felony counts and pleaded guilty to a misdemeanor charge Friday. <PERSON> Brownlee </PERSON> donated about $ 80,000 of his winnings to charity, according to court records, but much of the rest was dissipated on drugs, bad investments and unethical confidants. `` When somebody dumps $ 380,000 in your lap, you forget what happened before that and start living in a fantasy world,'' his lawyer said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1212EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-CampusTrends Bjt   07-23 0737</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Campus Trends, Bjt,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Predicted College Professor Shortage Has Arrived, Study Concludes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JILL LAWRENCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Education Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A higher education faculty shortage anticipated for the mid-1990s has already arrived in fields from computing to health, according to an annual survey of colleges and universities issued Sunday. Half the institutions in the survey by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> said it is taking them longer now to find qualified people for full-time faculty positions than it was previously. Half also said they are having greater difficulty getting top applicants to accept positions when they are offered _ up from 25 percent who gave that response in 1987. <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> El-Khawas </PERSON>, an ACE vice president and author of `` Campus Trends, 1989,'' noted that some studies have projected shortages in the next decade but said her research indicates a more immediate problem. `` The labor market for faculty is tightening right now,'' she said. `` The real dilemmas for colleges are going to be starting much sooner than 1995.'' <PERSON> El-Khawas </PERSON> said factors contributing to the problem include an inadequate number of doctorate holders, an increasing number of Ph.D. s going into private industry, a greater proportion of doctoral degrees earned by foreigners, accelerating retirement of faculty members, and expanding student enrollment The sixth annual ACE survey of senior academic administrators at 366 institutions found that 40 percent are having trouble finding qualified people for full-time positions in computer science. One in three institutions reported similar problems in the business area. Mathematics and health professions each were cited by one in four schools. Half the administrators surveyed said they expect the pace of retirement among full-time faculty to increase in the next few years. At the same time, half said the size of their full-time faculty had grown in the last year and 71 percent said they had increased their overall enrollment. <PERSON> El-Khawas </PERSON> said the crunch may result in pressure for higher salaries in certain fields, incentives to keep people from retiring and a highly competitive situation where universities are trying to entice faculty members away from each other. Class size may also be affected, she said. The 1989 survey indicates there may be an impact in that area already. One-third of colleges and universities reported an increase in average class size, up from 20 percent in the 1988 survey. The physical condition of universities is also a pressing concern, according to the survey. Only 32 percent of the administrators felt their physical plant was excellent or very good. Another third said plant renovation and renewal will be a key challenge in the next five years and more than half predicted their facilities will not be adequate to meet school needs over the next decade. On another front, eight in 10 institutions reported at least some activity to increase the enrollment and retention of minority students. However, only 25 percent said their enrollment of blacks, Hispanics and Asians had risen during 1988-89 and only 10 percent reported an increase in American Indian students. `` It's encouraging that there's a tremendous level of activity,'' <PERSON> El-Khawas </PERSON> said. `` But the actual results fall short.'' The same proportion of institutions reported they were making special efforts to increase minority faculty members. But only 17 percent offer incentives to academic departments to hire minorities and only 25 percent reported a net gain in minority faculty over the previous year. The ACE survey found continuing interest in assessments of student learning, with 40 percent of the activity reportedly in response to external mandates. Basic skills testing is in place at 65 percent of schools and an additional 19 percent are planning such tests. Half of colleges and universities now assess writing and 27 percent report that writing assessment is in the planning stages. Close to half are planning to assess students' critical thinking skills and 14 percent already do so. About half the administrators responding to the survey said they believe assessment will `` significantly improve'' undergraduate education. But 37 percent said that so far, the process has resulted mainly in new reporting requirements to the state. ACE is the umbrella group for the nation's colleges and universities. Its campus trends survey, based on responses from 366 campuses, was adjusted statistically to be representative of the country's 2,500 general institutions of higher education. Seminaries, art schools, stand-alone graduate schools and other specialized institutions were not included. The margin of error for the survey was 2 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890723-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-07-23-89 1218EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Soviet-Strike Bjt   07-23 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Soviet-Strike, Bjt,0695</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Says Miners' Strikes Inspiring</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAREY GOLDBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
