<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 2353EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-HUDProbe-Denver     06-21 0481</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-HUD Probe-Denver,0498</SECOND>
<HEAD>Federal Auditors Searching For $7 Million in Denver HUD Probe</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DENVER (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than $ 7 million in proceeds from the sale of foreclosed homes may be missing from the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> and Development's regional office here, federal auditors say. However, <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s regional chief said the files that will account for the money are simply in storage and are being recovered. The <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> office is a major focus of a nationwide inquiry of wrongdoing at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration under then-Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>. The agency has been rocked by allegations that money to rehabilitate run-down housing for the poor and elderly was handed out to developers who hired high-priced consultants with ties to the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> or the administration. In addition, an escrow agent in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> has said she embezzled $ 5 million in money due the government from the sale of foreclosed property and gave most of the proceeds to the poor. Investigators have dubbed <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Harrell </PERSON> `` Robin <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>.'' An auditor's report released Tuesday raised the possibility that the <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> office may not have received $ 7,279,136. Federal auditors have given the office eight days to come up with the missing records on 173 foreclosed homes sold in the past five years, or face sanctions. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> regional officials knew the files were missing as early as Feb. 9, according to the report by the <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> inspector general's office The report indicates the investigation into single-family home sales handled by the office began in January. The report said 471 home sales were chosen by auditors for review, but records on 173 could n't be found. According to the report, documentation that proceeds were transferred to <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> bank accounts was lacking for many other sales. <PERSON> Isaiah </PERSON> `` Ike'' <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, acting <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> administrator in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, said the files, which have been missing since February, are stored in agency's archives. <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON> said the audit covered home sales from 1984 to 1988. `` I do n't know what happened back then, but I can tell you that as acting administrator I will make sure the regional inspector general obtains those files immediately,'' said <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, who took over in April. Earlier this month, a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> accountant in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, was suspended on suspicion of diverting $ 1 million to his own account. The auditors' report accused regional officials of lax record-keeping. Auditors complained they found active and inactive files together and that boxes of records were allowed to sit open at the regional office for indefinite periods before being put in storage. The report also criticized the practice of not requiring private agents who sell foreclosed properties for <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> to confirm that proceeds were deposited in <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> bank accounts. Normally when a <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> home is sold, the proceeds are wired immediately to the agency's <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> office `` Of the 256 sales packages examined, 145 did not have wire transfer confirmations,'' the report said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-MspiElections 1stLd-Writethru a0662 06-21 0483</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mspi Elections, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0662,0490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Blacks Win Judicial Races in Court-Ordered Mississippi Election</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 10 grafs to UPDATE with two blacks winning, other
results; picks up 8th graf, `In 1987...'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>JACKSON, Miss. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two black candidates won races for judgeships Tuesday in an election ordered by a federal judge who said <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s judicial districts discriminated against blacks. One other black candidate was narrowly leading, one was trailing and two others lost election bids. Two blacks were unopposed as a result of the court order that forced the redrawing of judicial districts. Prior to the election, <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> had four black judges. Also on the ballot were three proposed constitutional amendments to repeal outdated and unused provisions. One would eliminate the poll tax, adopted to discourage black voting but struck down by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in 1966. The four blacks among <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION>'s 78 judges are <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Justice <PERSON> Reuben </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, Circuit Judges <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Banks </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lillie </PERSON> <PERSON> Blackmon-Sanders </PERSON> and Chancery Judge <PERSON> Isaac </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>. Each was appointed to fill a vacancy, but <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> went on to win a full eight-year term in 1986. <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON> did not seek election this year. The two others sought regular terms Tuesday. With 79 of 85 precincts reporting Tuesday night, <ORGANIZATION> Blackmon-Sanders </ORGANIZATION> trailed <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> challenger <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON> by 8,265 votes to 10,917. Banks and one other black Democrat, <PERSON> Isadore </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vicksburg </LOCATION>, were unopposed in the general election. The two black winners were <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, a Democrat, who defeated Republican <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keyes </PERSON> for an open <LOCATION> Hinds </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> chancery judge's post by 5,942 votes to 1,638; and <PERSON> Denise </PERSON> <PERSON> Sweet </PERSON> <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>, also Democrat, who defeated Republican <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> in another open family court post in the county, 4,628 votes to 1,259 With only five of 37 precincts reporting in the Fourth District, <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Osborne </PERSON>, a black Democrat, was leading independent incumbent Circuit Judge <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON> in the Fourth District, 395 votes to 348. But <PERSON> Clell </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, a black Democrat, was defeated by independent incumbent Circuit Judge <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Q. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> in the Fourth District, 4,046 votes to 2,063. Another black candidate, <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON>, also a Democrat, ran fourth in a four-way race for two judgeship posts in the 20 Circuit Court District. The winners were incumbents <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Goza </PERSON>, a Democrat, and <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Nichols </PERSON>, a Republican. In 1987, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Barbour </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> ruled that the state's judicial districts discriminated against blacks. The ruling, the first to apply the 1965 Voting Rights Act to judicial elections, was upheld on appeal. <PERSON> Barbour </PERSON> ordered some districts redrawn to create minority subdistricts so that black voters would have a better opportunity to elect black judges. The ruling and appeals put judicial elections in the state on hold until this year, when all 69 <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Chancery </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judgeships are being filled. No Supreme Court judgeships are on the ballot.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Senate-Ambassadors 1stLd-Writethru a0770 06-21 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Senate-Ambassadors, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0770, 660</SECOND>
<HEAD>With AM-Gregg Nomination</HEAD>
<HEAD>Panel Postpones Action on Ambassadorial Nominees</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: CORRECTS Ney's country from Turkey to Canada in 23rd graf, which
is 3rd bullet graf in group at bottom: ``_Edward N,''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAWRENCE L. KNUTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Senate Foreign Relations Committee postponed action on three of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ambassadorial nominees Tuesday after Democrats complained their only visible qualifications are large <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> contributions. Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>, D-Md., initiated the delay when he complained that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassadors should have at least some qualifications for the job The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> is set to close down for the Independence Day recess, so <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>' request for a one-week delay effectively stops until mid July at the earliest any action on the nominations to fill ambassadorships in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. `` In the past we've had to hold our noses'' and let similar nominees with political connections go through, <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said. `` But eventually someone ought to say stop.'' `` If it's going to be a bidding war ... at least we should put it up for public bids so the money goes to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>,'' <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> targeted three. They are: _ <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Zappala </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> land developer and national co-chairman of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s fund raising committee who has been nominated to be <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said he contributed $ 126,000 to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. _ <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Sembler </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> shopping center tycoon who has been named to be ambassador to <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said <PERSON> Sembler </PERSON> was a $ 127,000 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> contributor. _ <PERSON> Della </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>, residential real estate broker who has been nominated to be ambassador to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> She is a long-time personal friend of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and was chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bush </ORGANIZATION> For President Committee. <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said she had no apparent qualifications except her personal and political ties. `` There seems to be a $ 100,000 threshhold'' for ambassadorships, <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> did `` reluctantly'' permit the committee to approve the nomination of <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a $ 115,000 contributor to the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> campaign. <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON> has been named to be ambassador to the <LOCATION> Netherlands </LOCATION> and with the committee's action, an ambassador will be in place when <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> visits the country next month. The full <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> later approved the <PERSON> Wilkins </PERSON> nomination on a voice vote. Sen. <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION>., defended the records of the two Floridians on <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON>' list saying, `` to imply they are not capable is a disservice. Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, said: `` What we're doing is delaying the appropriate representation this country should have overseas.'' And Sen. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Ind </LOCATION>., said the overall composition of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s ambassadorial nominees to date is no different than the choices of the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's two-thirds <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> professionals and one third political appointees `` These nominees are friends of the president, a part of the organization of his coming to the presidency,'' <PERSON> Lugar </PERSON> said. `` They share his ethos, his idealism and they will be so perceived in the nations to which they are being sent.'' <PERSON> Sarbanes </PERSON> said he has no objection to political nominees as such, as long as they can claim some qualifications for the posts to which they are named. He noted he did not object to <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s nomination of former Republican Gov. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> to be ambassador to <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION>. He said <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> had demonstrated his capabilities during his eight years service as governor beginning in 1980. The committee did vote to recommend the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirm <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> and a list of other nominees. They are: _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Niles </PERSON>, named to be <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> representative to the European Community _ <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Abramowitz </PERSON>, to be ambassador to <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ney </PERSON>, to be ambassador to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Solomon </PERSON>, to be assistant secretary of state for East Asian and <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> Affairs _ <PERSON> Melvyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Levitsky </PERSON>, to be assistant secretary of state for international narcotics matters _ Jewel <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lafontant </PERSON>, to be ambassador-at-large for refugee affairs _ E <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Coady </PERSON>, to be <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> executive director for the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reconstruction </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edelman </PERSON>, to be deputy administrator of the Agency for International Development _ <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeder </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, to be president of the <ORGANIZATION> Overseas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Private </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0032EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Ascot     06-21 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Ascot,0235</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ascot Race Goers Collapse Under Sweltering Sun</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fashionably dressed race goers at the opening of the four-day <PERSON> Royal </PERSON> <PERSON> Ascot </PERSON> meet sweltered in 88-degree heat and more than 50 collapsed, first-aid workers reported. `` We've been very, very busy,'' said <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Gates </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ambulance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION>'s volunteer corps. She said most of the victims on Tuesday suffered mild sunstroke or fainted. It was the hottest June day in 13 years and the champagne stalls were busy. The price of a bottle ranged from $ 33 to $ 70. Half a cold lobster cost $ 15.50, a serving of salmon $ 12.40 and strawberries and clotted cream $ 3.10. Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, in a pink and turquoise silk-crepe dress and straw hat, strolled through the crowds between the royal enclosure where the elegant parade and the paddock where the horses are paraded. Rules barring anyone under age 16 from the royal enclosure until Friday, the closing day, were broken to admit the queen's 8-year-old granddaughter, <PERSON> Zara </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, the daughter of Princess <PERSON> Anne </PERSON>. `` After all, the queen makes the rules,'' said a member of the royal household. A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Ascot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> noted <PERSON> Ascot </PERSON> is the monarch's racecourse. Prince <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>, the heir to the throne, left <PERSON> Ascot </PERSON> early to play polo in nearby <LOCATION> Windsor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>. Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> went with him but left after the first match.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0034EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WalkmanAnniversary     06-21 0605</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Walkman Anniversary,0620</SECOND>
<HEAD>10 Years After, the Walkman Runs Wild</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The technology behind the Walkman portable cassette-player might never have developed without these words from <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Akio </PERSON> <PERSON> Morita </PERSON>: `` TURN DOWN THAT MUSIC!'' <PERSON> Morita </PERSON>, seeking to soften his children's blasting stereos, asked his development team for something that would let the kids rock out without deafening dad. Working from a model developed by <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Masuru </PERSON> <PERSON> Ibuka </PERSON>, model TPS-L2 rolled off the assembly line a year later _ the first <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walkman </ORGANIZATION>, unveiled July 1, 1979. In the decade since, the Walkman and its imitators have become ubiquitous, with tiny headphones appearing on millions of heads worldwide _ traffic-bound commuters, long-distance runners and house-cleaning parents as well as their rock' n' rolling kids. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Walkman </ORGANIZATION> has in fact changed the way the world listens to music,'' said <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consumer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Audio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Product </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's changed our lifestyles.'' Go argue. As the Walkman marks its 10th birthday, it has become a cultural phenomenon, as <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> as Toyotas or sushi. Highlights of the Walkman's first decade include: _ Walkman: A Space Odyssey. A specially adapted Walkman was sent into orbit attached to astronaut <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> <PERSON> Garn </PERSON>, recording the sounds of his bowels for posterity. This was a scientific experiment -LRB- really -RRB-. _ Illegal Walkman. Teachers at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> were warned of students using Walkmans -LRB- Walkmen? -RRB- to play `` oral crib sheets'' during tests. _ Walkman: The Movie. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, blasting an <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> van </PERSON> <PERSON> Halen </PERSON> guitar solo through a Walkman, convinced his'50s - bound father there was life on other planets in `` Back to the Future _ The Royal Walkman. Princess <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> owns a gold-plated number that she plays while relaxing in Buckingham Palace. The Walkman was n't an immediate sensation. Initially it was called Soundabout in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, Stowaway in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kingdom </LOCATION>, Freestyle in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> and Walkman in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and other world markets. But <PERSON> Morita </PERSON> argued for uniformity, and sales in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, 37,000 units in 1979, took off after the Walkman name was adopted in May 1980. From then on, the personal stereo cassette deck was up and running. `` Retailers told us, ` You guys are absolutely out of your minds. It does n't even recod, and it costs $ 200. It's never going to go anywhere,''' <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> said. `` The next thing I know, we've got back orders for 1 -LCB- years.'' Dozens of competitors from <ORGANIZATION> Panasonic </ORGANIZATION> to <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> recognized a good thing and began manufacturing their own brands. By 1982, <ORGANIZATION> Time </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION> was hailing the Walkman as the gadget of the year. By 1984, <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> had cranked out 10 million which climbed to 30 million by 1987. Today, there are more than 50 million _ about half of them worn in the U.S.A. While the first model had a retail price of $ 199.95, today's Walkman prices run as low as $ 14.95 for an FM, radio-only model There are 44 <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> models: water-resistant, with AM-FM radios, with recording capability, built for the outdoorsman. Television freaks now have the Watchman, a tiny portable TV set; die-hard audiophiles have the Discman, a portable CD player. Meanwhile, the trademarked Walkman name entered everyday language as a synonym for a personal stereo, just as Kleenex came to stand for a facial tissue. Walkman is even an entry in the dictionary. Birthday celebrations for the Walkman include one of the originals going on permanent display at the <LOCATION> Hard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rock </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cafe </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Tiffany </PERSON>'s will produce 36 special Walkmans to be presented to as-yet-unchosen innovators in music and technology.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Romania-Fence     06-21 0270</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Romania-Fence,0278</SECOND>
<HEAD>Defense Ministry Says Romania Builds Border Wire Fence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government says <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> has nearly completed construction of a 6-foot barbed wire fence along its border with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, but cast doubt on a foreign press report that a brick wall is being built. The Times of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> on Monday reported that <LOCATION> Bucharest </LOCATION> is building a wall along its border with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> to prevent defections. <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s official <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> news agency said Tuesday that its border guards had reported `` no signs of wall construction.'' `` Nevertheless, a 2 -LCB- - meter wire fence is being set up on the Romanian side of the border ... which has been completed along 90 percent of the border length,'' the agency said `` Since it appears to be an ordinary wire fence, the -LRB- Hungarian -RRB- border guards suppose that no electricity will be led into it,'' the agency said. It added that the fence is about 80 feet inside Romanian territory. `` The latest works indicate that ditches have been dug on both sides of the fence to prevent breakthroughs by cars,'' <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> said. <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>'s border with <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> extends 275 miles. An estimated 30,000 Romanians, most of them ethnic Hungarians, have fled to <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> in the past few years seeking refuge from chronic hardships under the regime of President <PERSON> Nicolae </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceausescu </PERSON>. Ethnic Hungarians also claim discriminatory policies toward minorities in <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>. During the first five months of this year, 3,231 Romanians crossed ilegally into <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, deputy Interior Minister <PERSON> Zoltan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gal </PERSON> said last week. He said the Cabinet would soon discuss plans to open three refugees camps in eastern <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> to cope with the influx.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Ivory Bjt   06-21 0845</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ivory, Bjt,0874</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ivory Bans Increasing After Years of Crusades</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL ALEXANDER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of crusades to stop poachers from destroying the African elephant, conservationists are reaping success with a series of national bans on ivory imports. `` It's been a real snowball effect,'' said <PERSON> Jorgen </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomsen </PERSON>, senior program officer for elephant conservation at the World Wildlife Fund. Since June 4, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, the 12-nation <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Switzerland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> have imposed bans on imported ivory. The <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> buy up to 75 percent of the ivory on world markets. <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, the world's major ivory dealer, has announced a moratorium on raw ivory imports. The 102-nation Convention on <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Endangered </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Species </ORGANIZATION> will consider a worldwide ban at a <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION> meeting in October. The conservationists' sweeping success follows June 1 appeals by the World Wildlife Fund and Wildlife Conservation International. The two groups said poachers were wiping out the elephant populations in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> faster than had been thought and the pachyderms could be extinct within 15 years. But conservationists now fear that prospects of a worldwide ban could lead poachers to a frenzy of elephant killings unless interim measures are taken immediately. `` An elephant holocaust across <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is likely unless consumer countries take immediate action,'' the World Wildlife Fund said. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, on June 4, began the string of national actions against importing ivory and it was followed the next day by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Penalties vary for violations. In the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the maximum is a year in jail and a $ 100,000 fine. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, in announcing the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> decision, said: `` We do this out of mounting concern for the rapid decline of the wild elephant, one of nature's most majestic creatures. `` If their populations continue to diminish at current rates, the wild elephant will soon be lost from this Earth.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> are considered critical to any effective reduction in ivory demand. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> is the largest importer, accounting for 40 percent of the world market, and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> is heavily involved in making ivory carvings for export. `` The real victory is <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Thomsen </PERSON> said. `` <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>'s action was very much to save face'' because its two biggest customers _ <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ had outlawed imports. `` This proves that we have taken more responsibility as consumer countries,'' he said. `` We may have prevented a catastrophe. Credit should also be placed with the <LOCATION> African </LOCATION> countries, who previously had opposed a ban but now realize the crisis situation.'' <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> began enforcing its crackdown quickly. On Sunday, it seized 448 tusks and other ivory products worth an estimated $ 2.6 million that officials said were to to have been smuggled to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Several African countries recently reversed their stands and took steps to protect their elephants. Last month, <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION> followed neighboring <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION> and called for a worldwide ban. Delegates at an Organization of African Unity conference that ended Saturday recommended establishing a marketing cartel to ensure that money from the worldwide ivory trade benefits the continent. Conservationists estimate African elephant populations have dropped from 1.5 million in 1978 to between 400,000 and 700,000 today. They say ivory exports have increased from 300 tons a year in the 1950s to more than 800 tons annually in this decade and prices are running at a record $ 91 per pound. An aerial survey last year found about 20,000 elephants in <LOCATION> Kenya </LOCATION>. Fifteen years ago it had 121,000. The number of elephants in <LOCATION> Tanzania </LOCATION> has fallen to 80,000 from 300,000 in 1979, according to government officials. Conservationists say the elephant populations in most other African countries have suffered similar fates, but <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Botswana </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> are the exceptions because of controls. <LOCATION> Zimbabwe </LOCATION> has annual elephant kills and a thriving legal trade in elephant products. In the last 12 months it earned about $ 600,000 in legal ivory sales. Poachers have killed most of the big male elephants in some countries and now their targets are females and young beasts, according to a conservationists' report released this month. The result is that three times as many elephants must be killed to provide the same amount of ivory as 10 years ago. `` The annual ivory haul must be reduced to at least a tenth of its present volume to enable populations to recover,'' the report says. `` The recovery of herds and family structure will take 20 years or more if all poaching were stopped.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION> and other countries with thriving ivory industries and markets would be badly hurt if supplies are reduced to that level. <PERSON> Tamotsu </PERSON> <PERSON> Ishibashi </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ivory </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Craft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said even the current ban will have devastating effects on <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s traditional ivory-carving industry. He said some 25,000 craftsman in about 80 workshops produce $ 13.8 million worth of ivory products every year. `` The majority of ivory craftsmen have passed their techniques of carving ivory from generation to generation, and the new restriction certainly will affect them severely,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Congress-Indictments     06-21 0807</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Congress-Indictments,0826</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressmen, One Delegate, Indicted In Past Decade While In Office</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Rep. <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Swindall </PERSON>, found guilty Tuesday on nine counts of lying to a federal grand jury about a money-laundering scheme, is the 20th person in the last decade to be indicted on criminal charges while serving in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Rep. <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> `` Buz'' <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION>, 58, was convicted May 26 of contributing to the delinquency and unruliness of a minor, a misdemeanor. The <LOCATION> Franklin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, jury found him guilty of having sex with the girl last November. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> faces up to six months in prison and a $ 1,000 fine for his conviction, but conviction on the misdemeanor charge does not automatically preclude him from serving in the House or seeking re-election, and he has said he will remain in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> while appealing his conviction. <ORGANIZATION> Lukens </ORGANIZATION> is in the second term of his second stint in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. He also was in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for two terms from 1967 to 1971. Rep. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>, was indicted in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> on conspiracy charges in the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> corruption scandal. He was the second Democratic congressman from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> to be indicted for allegedly using his influence on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, a minority-owned <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> machine shop that won no-bid <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> contracts. It has since gone bankrupt. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, whose former congressional district abuts <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>'s, was convicted last Aug. 5 of racketeering, mail fraud and accepting bribes from <ORGANIZATION> Wedtech </ORGANIZATION> in exchange for his <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> influence. <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON>, 71, resigned his <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> seat Aug. 6 after nearly 10 terms. He was sentenced to eight years in prison and a $ 242,000 fine. <PERSON> Biaggi </PERSON> also was convicted in November 1987 of accepting an illegal gratuity _ a paid vacation _ for helping an ailing <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> shipyard. He was sentenced to 2 -LCB- years in prison and fined $ 500,000 in that case. In October 1988, Fofo I.F. <PERSON> Sunia </PERSON>, <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>'s former delegate to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, was sentenced to five to 15 months in prison for participating in a payroll-padding scheme that reportedly earned him $ 39,000. <PERSON> Sunia </PERSON>, 51, a Democrat, resigned his congressional seat Sept. 6. Other members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> indicted since 1978: _ Rep <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ford </PERSON>, D-Tenn., charged in April 1987 with bank, mail and tax fraud No trial date has been set. _ Rep <PERSON> Bobbi </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON>, R-Calif., indicted Jan. 23, 1986, along with an aide on charges she tried to buy off an opponent for the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> nomination in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> The charges subsequently were dismissed by a <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> judge in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Fiedler </PERSON> lost the primary. _ Rep <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Idaho </LOCATION>, indicted in April 1983 and convicted one year later on charges of violating the 1978 Ethics in Government Act by failing to report $ 333,978 in loans and other transactions on his financial disclosure forms. <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> was freed in October 1987 after serving nearly one year of a five-to-15-month sentence. _ Sen <PERSON> Harrison </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>, convicted in May 1981 on charges stemming from the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s Abscam investigation, including conspiracy, bribery, conflict of interest, receiving an unlawful gratuity and interstate travel in aid of a racketeering enterprise. <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> resigned from the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in March 1982. He was paroled from a halfway house in January 1986 after serving nearly two years of a three-year sentence. Six House members also were indicted as a result of the undercover Abscam investigation, and all served prison terms. They were: Rep. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Lederer </PERSON>, D-Pa.; Rep. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> `` Ozzie'' <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>, D-Pa.; Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Jenrette </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-S.C. </LOCATION>; Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>; Rep. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>; and Rep. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Fla </LOCATION> <PERSON> Claude </PERSON> `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., was indicted in July 1979 on charges of buying votes in the 1978 election and violating federal campaign finance laws He was acquitted of some vote-buying counts and the others were dropped, and a federal appeals court dismissed the charges of campaign finance law violations. _ Rep <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Eilberg </PERSON>, D-Pa., indicted in October 1978 on federal charges of illegally receiving compensation to help a <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> hospital get a $ 14.5 million federal grant He pleaded guilty in February 1979 and was sentenced to five years' probation and fined $ 10,000. _ Rep <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON>. Flood, D-Pa., indicted in the fall of 1978 on 13 counts of bribery, conspiracy and perjury His trial on 11 counts ended in a mistrial in February 1979. He resiged from the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in January 1980, citing health reasons, after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> ethics committee accused him of 25 rules violations. In February 1980, he pleaded guilty to conspiracy in a plea-bargaining arrangement and was given a year's probation. _ Rep <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Diggs </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, D-Mich., indicted in March 1978 and convicted in October 1978 on 29 felony counts of illegally diverting his congressional employees' salaries to his personal use He resigned from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1980 and served seven months of a three-year prison sentence.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0039EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Palme-Press     06-21 0690</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Palme-Press,0716</SECOND>
<HEAD>Palme Trial Raises Questions About Unusual Swedish Press Ethics</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHAN RAPP</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>STOCKHOLM, Sweden (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Swedes may not learn the name or see the face of the man accused of killing Prime Minister <PERSON> Olof </PERSON> <PERSON> Palme </PERSON> if they read only their national newspapers. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Gustaf </PERSON> <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>, who is on trial for the 1986 shooting, is known in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> only as `` the 42-year-old.'' Under Swedish press law, the identity of a criminal suspect is never published unless he is convicted and sentenced, and even then it must clearly be in the public interest. The regulations are meant to protect the innocent, and a newspaper and its senior editor can be fined for violating them. But the Palme murder trial has put the regulations under a strain, and several provincial papers are disregarding them. `` <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> is a historic person, whether guilty or not,'' said <PERSON> Per </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahlstrom </PERSON>, editor of Nya Norrland, a daily with a circulation of 20,000 in the northern town of <LOCATION> Harnosand </LOCATION>. `` I find that there is evident public interest that the name of the person accused of the murder becomes public knowledge,'' he said. International news agencies and foreign newspapers published <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s identity and his police mug shot when he was charged in December. Swedish papers ran into difficulty when <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>, known as `` the 41-year-old'' at the time, had a birthday in April. For a few weeks he was referred to as `` the 42-year-old former 41-year-old.'' About 20 newspapers have flouted the regulations, arguing it was ridiculous to try to hide his identity when foreign newspapers reporting the trial were available at major newsstands in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. Other ironies also have become evident. Under Swedish freedom of information laws, <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s name was available after prosecutors filed the indictment last month. Anyone who calls the <ORGANIZATION> Stockholm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> can ask the court clerk to read it over the telephone. Papers that have refrained from identifying <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON> have, at the same time, published every detail of his life, including his police record, the location of his home and interviews with former girlfriends. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON>, director of the London-based `` Article 19,'' which monitors press freedom in 50 countries, said the Swedish regulations are `` highly exceptional'' if not unique. `` It is remarkable in that it contradicts the openness of information in so many other areas where <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION> leads the world,'' <PERSON> Boyle </PERSON> said in an interview. He said the restrictions do not violate international law, but they could inhibit the search for witnesses. Because of high public interest in the Palme case, the court let <ORGANIZATION> Swedish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> broadcast the trial with a one-second delay to allow a technician to cover <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s name with an electronic beep. The technician missed the beat the first time <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s name was mentioned, however. The broadcasts have been debated heatedly. Professor <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Magnus </PERSON> <PERSON> Elwing </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lund </ORGANIZATION> said they have turned the trial into `` marketplace theater'' and diminished the stature of the court. `` I would have acted forcefully to stop it,'' <PERSON> Elwing </PERSON> said. Some critics said testimony heard on the radio could influence subsequent witnesses. Presiding Judge <PERSON> Carl-Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Spak </PERSON> ruled the broadcasts were in line with the law and would be stopped only if they disturbed the trial itself. Since then most of the witnesses, many of whom have criminal records, have demanded that the broadcast be halted for their testimony and the court has complied. Press Ombudsman <PERSON> Torsten </PERSON> <PERSON> Cars </PERSON>, who is employed by the newspaper industry, said the caution regarding <PERSON> Pettersson </PERSON>'s name goes beyond the requirements of press ethics. `` It would not change much if the name were printed, considering all the descriptions of his life that already have been published,'' he said. `` And there are thousands of <PERSON> Christer </PERSON> <PERSON> Petterssons </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Sweden </LOCATION>. ... Publishing the picture is more serious.'' Among those publishing the name is the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> Arbetet </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Malmo </LOCATION>, a city across the <LOCATION> Oregrund </LOCATION> straits from <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, where such restrictions do not apply. <PERSON> Arbetet </PERSON> was convicted of libel in 1987 and ordered to pay $ 27,000 in compensation to `` the 33-year-old,'' a suspect who earlier was detained and released without charges.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-APainting'sValue     06-21 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-A Painting's Value,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>Canvas that Cost $8 in 1956 Sells for $150,000</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 19th-century painting set in ancient <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> of a young woman about to bathe has been sold at auction for $ 153,450 _ nearly 20,000 times its 1956 purchase price of $ 8. `` It certainly does reflect an extraordinary change in taste, but that is n't unique in art,'' said <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> after the sale Tuesday of `` Diadumene'' by Sir <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Poynter </PERSON>. The auction house had expected more because of the vogue for once-neglected Victorian works. It had estimated the painting would fetch up to $ 232,500. <PERSON> Poynter </PERSON>, in 1885, had painted the young woman nude but he added diaphanous drapery after it was exhibited at the <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arts </ORGANIZATION> and provoked letters from shocked viewers. One letter to the press, signed `` British Matron,'' said the writer had barred her daughters from going to the the exhibition. Another letter said the painting would produce a `` burning sense of shame'' in any `` modest woman on the arm of father, brother or lover.'' <PERSON> Poynter </PERSON> was known for such paintings but his most famous work, reproduced in the tens of thousands in its day, was `` Faithful unto Death.'' It depicted a Roman sentry staying at his post during the destruction of <LOCATION> Pompeii </LOCATION> by the Vesuvius volcano. The seller and buyer of `` Diadumene'' were not identified. The painting had been auctioned in 1956 at a sale of the contents of <LOCATION> Ashley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Manor </LOCATION>, owned by <PERSON> Lady </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnes </PERSON> <PERSON> Chichester </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon-Hartland </PERSON>. Top price at Tuesday's auction of 19th century European art was $ 2.3 million _ more than double the estimate _ paid anonymously for `` Grandfather's Birthday,'' a family fireside scene by Austrian artist <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Georg </PERSON> <PERSON> Waldmueller </PERSON>. It was a record for his work.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Divorce-Murder 1stLd-Writethru a0775 06-21 0477</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Divorce-Murder, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0775,0489</SECOND>
<HEAD>Husband Kills Wife in Divorce Attorney's Office, Then Shoots Self</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: UPDATES throughout with quotes from lawyer who witnessed shootings,
other details. ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL GEITNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A heartbroken husband shot and killed his estranged wife Tuesday in their divorce attorney's office, then turned the gun on himself as the couple's two young girls sat in the waiting room. <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, 38, shot his wife <PERSON> Josephine </PERSON>, also 38, four times in the head with a .32 - caliber revolver, threatened to shoot the attorney, then shot himself in the head, according to police and the attorney's Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was declared dead at <LOCATION> Jamaica </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> was in extremely poor condition at the same hospital and will likely be declared brain dead after tests are completed Wednesday, said administrative nursing supervisor <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. The couple, who had been married since 1973, had come to the office of <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> on Tuesday afternoon for an initial consultation about a divorce, according to <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON>'s secretary, <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Dasaro </PERSON> They went into the attorney's office and closed the door, leaving their 8-year-old and 6-year-old girls in the reception area. `` The father told them to wait out here,'' <PERSON> Dasaro </PERSON> said. `` She said she no longer loved him; he said he loved her a great deal,'' <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> said afterward. <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> said he served the divorce summons on <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> and told him to get an attorney. `` Then he stood up, put his right hand behind his back and pulled out a gun,'' <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> said. `` She sat down, she pleaded for her life.'' He put the gun, identified by police as a .32 - caliber, against her left temple and fired <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> said <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> then alternated between firing additional shots into Mrs. <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> and threatening him, shoving the gun against <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON>'s chest, head and mouth. `` He then said he was going to kill me and kill himself,'' <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON>, 58, said. After about five minutes, <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> put the gun to his face and shot himself. `` We heard the gunshots and at first we did n't know what it was'' since the office is located near a busy intersection, <PERSON> Dasaro </PERSON> said. `` After the third one that I heard, we realized that it was coming from the office. `` We ran out and we dragged the little girls out.'' <PERSON> Dasaro </PERSON> said they waited outside the office on the street about 10 minutes before <PERSON> Napolitano </PERSON> emerged. `` I thought <PERSON> John </PERSON> was dead too,'' she said. `` Then he came out and he just shook his head.'' The girls `` did not witness the murder,'' she said, but were `` crying hysterically.'' One saw the bodies being carried out. A 12-year-old son was not at the office at the time, said Officer <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, a police spokesman. The children will probably be turned over to child welfare workers, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TavernStrike     06-21 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tavern Strike,0182</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tavern on the Green Strike Settled</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Picket lines in the 7-week-old strike at <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>'s posh restaurant, Tavern on the Green, came down Tuesday after striking workers tentatively accepted a five-year contract. `` We're delighted,'' said restaurant spokesman <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Scanlon </PERSON>. `` We think it's a fair settlement, we're glad that it's over and we want to see all of our regular customers back here as soon as possible.'' Under the offer, wages will increase 27 percent the first year and about 5 percent each of the four years that follow. `` A 27 percent raise the first year is not a bad wage increase,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Turchiano </PERSON>, a spokesman for Local 6 of the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union. The union represented nearly 300 dishwashers, busboys, waiters and other workers who walked off the job April 30. The members are likely to ratify the contract when they vote on it Wednesday, <PERSON> Turchiano </PERSON> said. Tavern on the Green is a tourist mecca, known for its glittering garden, rococo decor and posh banquets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0041EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     06-21 0474</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0486</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Year at the Top for NBC</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> completed a 52-week sweep of Nielsen ratings despite <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' broadcast of the final game of the <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pistons </ORGANIZATION>' sweep of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> for the <ORGANIZATION> NBA </ORGANIZATION> championship <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was the No. 1 show last week, but <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had an average, prime-time rating of 11.6. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had 10.2 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 9.2. The last time <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> lost a week was to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, the week of the seventh game of last year's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Basketball </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> championship, when the <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> beat the <ORGANIZATION> Pistons </ORGANIZATION>. This year, game four ranked fourth in the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> prime-time ratings, with a 17.4 rating and 31 share. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s average rating for the 52 weeks was 14.4. CBS and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> tied with 11.6. The top 10 shows during the past year were: `` Roseanne'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` 60 Minutes'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` Empty Nest'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Dear John'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and `` Murder, She Wrote'' CBS. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> has had eight of the top 10 shows 10 times during the past year. `` Cosby'' was first in the Nielsens for 16 of the 52 weeks, but ranked second behind `` Roseanne'' for the year _ and third behind `` Roseanne'' and `` Cheers'' last week. `` Cosby'' had a lower rating and higher share, because it is on at 8 p.m. EDT, when there are fewer people watching TV than at 9 p.m., when `` Roseanne'' is on. The rating is a percentage of the estimated 90.4 million homes in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> that have televisions. The share is a percentage of sets in use. A show can have a lower rating and higher share than another show by getting a larger percentage of a smaller available audience. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> said another reason `` Cosby'' fell behind `` Roseanne'' for the year was because the newer <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> show did not have to factor in a summer of reruns. The top 10 shows last week were: `` Roseanne'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` The Cosby Show'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pistons </ORGANIZATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION>'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>: The Case of the Murdered Madam'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Empty Nest'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Dear John'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, and `` Unsolved Mysteries'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, tied with `` Newhart'' on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. In a demonstration that time period makes the show, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Have Faith'' tied for 15th when it was on Tuesday behind `` Roseanne.'' But when it was moved into <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s low-rated Sunday lineup, it fell to 76th and was the lowest-rated network show. `` NBC Nightly News'' continued to lag in news ratings, even with anchorman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. `` CBS Evening News'' and `` ABC World News Tonight'' tied for first place with a 9.3 rating each and 20 share each. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> had an average rating of 8.6 and a 19 share.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     06-21 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0771</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of June 12-18. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.1 rating, 17.3 million homes. 2. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.0, 16.3 million homes. 3. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.9 million homes. 4. -LRB- X -RRB- `` NBA Championship: Pistons vs. Lakers,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 5. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Perry </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>: The Case of the Murdered Madam'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 16.7, 15.1 million homes. 6. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.9, 14.4 million homes. 8. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7, 14.2 million homes. 9. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 10. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.7 million homes. 10. -LRB- 47 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1, 13.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0, 13.6 million homes. 13. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.9, 13.5 million homes. 14. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7, 13.3 million homes. 15. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3, 12.9 million homes. 15. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Have Faith-Tuesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3, 12.9 million homes. 17. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9, 12.6 million homes. 18. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.7, 12.4 million homes. 19. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5, 12.2 million homes. 20. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1, 11.8 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 21. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 23. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.8. 24. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 25. -LRB- 18 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 26. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` Doctor, Doctor,'' CBS, 12.1. 26. -LRB- 16 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 28. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 29. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 30. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 11.7. 31. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 32. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Deadly Care'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 11.5. 33. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.4. 34. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 35. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Firefighter'' _ `` CBS Special Movie Presentation,'' 11.1. 35. -LRB- 34 -RRB- `` Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.1. 37. -LRB- 24 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 38. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 39. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 40. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 41. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0. 42. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 43. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` The <ORGANIZATION> Ann </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jillian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Story </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` NBC Monday Night Movies,'' 9.3. 44. -LRB- 87 -RRB- `` Ghost of a Chance'' _ `` CBS Friday Movie,'' 8.8. 45. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 46. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` ` night, Mother'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 8.5 47. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Heartland,'' CBS, 8.4. 48. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 48. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 8.3. 50. -LRB- 71 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: On Strike,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 51. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 52. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Destined to Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.9. 53. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 54. -LRB- 99 -RRB- `` Highway to Heaven,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 54. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 56. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 57. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Mercy or Murder?'' _ `` NBC Movie of the Week-Friday,'' 7.2. 58. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 59. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 60. -LRB- 54 -RRB- `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 61. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty-Tuesday,'' CBS, 6.6. 62. -LRB- 97 -RRB- `` West 57th,'' CBS, 6.5. 62. -LRB- 106 -RRB- `` ABC Thursday Night Baseball,'' 6.5. 64. -LRB- X -RRB- `` North & amp; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, Book II,'' Part 6, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 64. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guilluame </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 66. -LRB- 84 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty-Saturday,'' CBS, 5.9. 67. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 68. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crockett </PERSON>: Warrior's Farewell'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 68. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 5.4. 68. -LRB- 82 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 71. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 72. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 73. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.6. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 76. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` Have Faith-Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.5. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.7.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     06-21 0999</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1040</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FRESNO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> was unharmed after becoming separated from companions in Sequoia National Park and spending the night alone on a mountain, her spokesman said. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> did n't panic when she realized she was lost Sunday, said her publicist, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivers </PERSON>. She wrapped herself in an insulated blanket and ate a sandwich while she awaited help, he said. <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> hiked ahead of her six companions and apparently took a wrong turn, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON>, a spokesman for the park 40 miles east of <LOCATION> Fresno </LOCATION>. Her companions notified park officials when she failed to show up at <LOCATION> Moose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>, their destination, or at their <ORGANIZATION> Pear </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lake </ORGANIZATION> base camp, <PERSON> Tweed </PERSON> said. A helicopter crew found <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> on top of a mountain early Monday and reunited her with her friends at the base camp. The group hiked out together, <ORGANIZATION> Tweed </ORGANIZATION> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SAN MATEO, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rocker </PERSON> <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> donated $ 15,000 to a finacially strapped hospital where a relative was treated last year. The donation by the `` Boss'' amounts to roughly half of the $ 30,000 raised by employees at <ORGANIZATION> Chope </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. `` His agent called and asked us how much was in the fund and he matched it,'' <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> McMurdo </PERSON>, the hospital's chief executive officer, said Tuesday. <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON> asked that his relationship to the former patient not be disclosed. Employees started the fund-raising drive for capital improvements and equipment in the wake of recent county budget shortfalls.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Vanessa </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the deposed Miss America who appeared in Penthouse and went on to a successful recording career, gave birth to a daughter this week. <PERSON> Jillian </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hervey </PERSON> was born Monday at <ORGANIZATION> Cedars-Sinai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' husband, <PERSON> Ramon </PERSON> <PERSON> Hervey </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, said Tuesday. The mother and baby are healthy and doing well, said a spokesman in <PERSON> Hervey </PERSON>'s office. The couple's first daughter, <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynne </PERSON>, will be 2 on June 30. Miss <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the first black Miss <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, was dethroned in a 1984 nude picture scandal. She currently has a hit single titled `` <PERSON> Darlin </PERSON>' I.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> says he almost did n't take a chance on a singing career because he had a secure job as a word processor In 1982, <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s friend, songwriter <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON>, suggested he meet <PERSON> Melba </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> and try for a job as a background singer. `` I told him I think I should stay here and be the greatest word processor in the world,'' <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> went on to sing background for <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lilo </PERSON> <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, <PERSON> Angela </PERSON> <PERSON> Bofill </PERSON> and others on studio cuts and tours. Ms. <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> helped him secure a contract with <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION>, which produced his 1985 debut album `` Rock Me Tonight.'' The album and single `` Rock Me Tonight,'' both reached No. 1 on Billboard's black charts. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'s follow-up, `` Just Like the First Time,'' also was No. 1 on black charts with the hit singles, `` I Do n't Want to Lose Your Love,'' `` Look Around'', and `` Tasty Love.'' His current album, `` Do n't Let Love Slip Away,'' has landed the single `` Crazy For Men'' in the pop Top 20. `` I'm going to stop singing when I'm not happy doing it anymore,'' said <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>. `` Right now, my ballads are things you want when you want to dance romantically with someone, not pop songs. Ballads live on and on.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Country music entertainer <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> will perform five shows for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> next week. <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> USO </ORGANIZATION> tour Monday through June 29 includes performances at <ORGANIZATION> Howard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Espinar </LOCATION>, World USO President <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Hagel </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` Morale may be at a low point now in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> since the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government sent families back to the <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and moved the military troops to the base,'' <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> said. `` So, when the USO asked me to go to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> and give the military community there a little taste of home, I did n't hesitate.'' <PERSON> Greenwood </PERSON> has won seven male vocalist of the year awards, the <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s song of the year award for `` God Bless the U.S.A.'' and a Grammy for best male country performance.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>AUGUSTA, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Adrienne </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, wife of imprisoned soul singer <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, will spend the next five years on probation as a result of her guilty plea to a drug charge. She also was ordered Tuesday to pay a $ 5,000 fine and continue with drug and alcohol screening. Mrs. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 39, was arrested in May 1988 as she got off a plane in <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION> and was charged with possessing the drug PCP. She had been arrested on a similar charge six weeks earlier. One of two charges was dropped when she pleaded guilty to the other. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 56, is serving a six-year sentence at the State Park Correctional Center near <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, for trying to run over two policemen during an auto chase last fall.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: Version moving on sports wire.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>STATE COLLEGE, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Joe </PERSON> <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON> says his autobiography will be a lot more than a story about coaching football at <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>. `` It's the story of my life and where I grew up and the things that have influenced me,'' said the 62-year-old <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> native. `` Paterno: By The Book'' includes the coach's upbringing, his thoughts on ethics in college sports and the Roman poet <PERSON> Virgil </PERSON>'s effect on his life One lesson in the book due out in September: Winning is possible without breaking the rules. `` It tells about some of the problems we've had and how we've been able to succeed without intentionally breaking any rules,'' said <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON>, who co-authored the book with <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> associate English professor <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Asbell </PERSON> In 23 years as <ORGANIZATION> Penn </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION>'s head coach, <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON> has won 212 games and two national championships. Last year, the <ORGANIZATION> Nittany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lions </ORGANIZATION> recorded their first losing season in 50 years. `` I'm not the goody-goody some people think,'' <PERSON> Paterno </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` There are an awful lot of things about me I do n't like.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BusShooting     06-21 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bus Shooting,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grand Jury Refuses To Indict City Bus Driver In Slaying Of Passenger</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DALLAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> grand jury on Tuesday declined to indict a city bus driver accused of killing a passenger by shooting him in the back after an argument. <PERSON> Chauncey </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON>, 37, a <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION> bus driver for 10 years, had been charged with murder in the May 24 shooting of <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, 25. <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> picked up <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> and a woman on a downtown street and told authorities that, through his rearview mirror, he saw the woman hand her bus pass to <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON>, who then tried to use it. The driver told <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> he could not use the pass, an argument ensued and <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> off the bus, police records show. <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> was shot once in the back with a handgun as he exited. <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> told police that <PERSON> Hayden </PERSON> punched him in the jaw before he stepped off the bus. <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> had been assaulted twice on the bus route in the past two years, once breaking his hand and the other time suffering a black eye, <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Area </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Whittington </PERSON> said. DART authorities, meanwhile, have begun proceedings to dismiss <PERSON> Plummer </PERSON> for violating company policy, which forbids drivers from carrying firearms. A decision was expected by Friday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0257EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Tornado-Ticket     06-21 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Tornado-Ticket,0150</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tornado Alert Didn't Stop Parking-Meter Monitors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MADISON, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When sirens sound a tornado warning, people should take cover. And that's why <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Ghilardi </PERSON> says he stayed in the basement of his downtown office. That's also why he plans to fight the $ 5 parking ticket that was placed on his wife's car as they took shelter during the two-hour warning a week ago today. `` On one hand we have government officials telling us not to go out because there's a tornado warning, and on the other hand we have government officials saying go out and plug meters,'' said <PERSON> Ghilardi </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Madison </LOCATION>. During the warning, meter monitors carrying two-way radios were told of the weather conditions but some without radios cotniued writing tickets, said Police Capt. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallden </PERSON>. `` It was a problem of them not knowing how dangerous the situation was,'' <PERSON> Wallden </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-UN-Namibia     06-21 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-UN-Namibia,0316</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.N. Says Namibian Police Threaten Fair Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER JAMES SPIELMANN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNITED NATIONS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A campaign of terror by the South African-led police threatens free and fair independence elections in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> special representative for <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> asserts. Namibian police in armored cars mounted with heavy machine guns reportedly drive through villages destroying crops and terrorizing inhabitants, the official, <PERSON> Martti </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON>, wrote in a letter obtained Tuesday. `` Their activities appear to have created an atmosphere of fear and intimidation among much of the population in the northern region,'' he wrote <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Pienaar </PERSON>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s administrator-general in <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> The letter said a feared counterinsurgency unit called `` Koevoet,'' Afrikaans for crowbar, is behind the terror campaign. <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> sent the letter on June 9. No reply has been received, <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Nadia </PERSON> <PERSON> Younes </PERSON> said Tuesday. <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> is leading a <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> commission monitoring <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>'s cooperation with a U.N.-mediated plan to free <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> from 74 years of South African rule November elections for the territory's first black majority-ruled government are scheduled under the independence plan. Northern <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION> is the homeland of the Ovambo tribe, which supports the <ORGANIZATION> South-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, known as <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION>. The guerrilla movement, which led a 23-year bush war against <ORGANIZATION> South </ORGANIZATION> African rule of <LOCATION> Namibia </LOCATION>, is expected to win the elections. Campaigning begins July 1. Many observers believe <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> is actively trying to prevent <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> from winning a two-thirds majority in the assembly by funding political parties and using the <LOCATION> Koevoet </LOCATION> police to intimidate <ORGANIZATION> SWAPO </ORGANIZATION> supporters. <PERSON> Ahtisaari </PERSON> wrote that: `` the activities in which they -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Koevoet </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- have been engaged render its members ... unfit for continued service in the police during the transition period.'' `` The continuance of the situation ... raises grave doubt in my mind'' as to whether free and fair elections are possible, he wrote.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Census-Minorities     06-21 0543</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Census-Minorities,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hispanic Population Booms, Census Reports</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hispanics flooded into <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and accounted for about one-fourth of the nation's total population growth in the first half of this decade, the <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> reports. Those states and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> each now have more than 1 million Hispanics, the bureau said in its first detailed analysis of minority populations since the 1980 census. Sixteen states, led by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, had more than 1 million blacks as of 1985, while <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> had the most Hispanics and other minorities, the study found. Blacks comprise the nation's largest minority at 28.9 million, the study reported. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> had the largest black population at 2.7 million, followed by <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> with 2.1 million blacks. But the black population of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was growing faster, adding 243,000 between 1980 and 1985, compared to a 219,000 increase for the Empire State. The nation's Hispanic population jumped from 14.3 million in 1980 to 17.5 million in 1985 through a combination of high birth rates and international migration. Although they were only 6.3 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> population in 1980, <PERSON> Hispanics </PERSON> made up about one-fourth of the 12 million national population increase during the next half-decade, the report said. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> has the largest Hispanic population, the report showed, at 5.9 million _ one-third of all Hispanics in the nation. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> was second at 3.7 million followed by <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> at 1.9 million and <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> with 1.1 million. <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> added 1.3 million Hispanics between 1980 and 1985, while <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> gained 700,000. <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> also added more than 100,000 Hispanics each. Among states with a million or more blacks the fastest growth rate for that group, 16 percent, was posted by <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> had the largest proportion of blacks in its population, 36 percent, the report found, followed by <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 31 percent, and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, 30 percent. During the first half of this decade only <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> had a decline in black population. More than four out of five blacks reside in metropolitan areas, the bureau found. And the shift continued to be in favor of cities with blacks migrating out of rural southern regions and into urban areas. The report added that four metropolitan areas have more than 1 million black residents _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- 3.2 million -RRB-, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- 1.6 million -RRB-, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- 1.2 million -RRB- and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> -LRB- 1.1 million -RRB-. Almost 90 percent of all Hispanics live in metropolitan areas, with more than half in seven metro areas, the study found _ <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> -LRB- 3.6 million -RRB-, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> -LRB- 2.3 million -RRB-, <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> -LRB- 815,000 -RRB-, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> -LRB- 775,000 -RRB-, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -LRB- 757,000 -RRB-, <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION> -LRB- 595,000 -RRB- and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION> -LRB- 568,000 -RRB-. The nation also included 7.3 million other minorities, a category that includes Asians, <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islanders </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Indians </ORGANIZATION>, Eskimos and Aleuts. This group jumped 1.9 million over five years, largely a result of international migration. With 2.3 million, <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was the leader in this category, followed by <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, 692,000, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, 516,000. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> had the fastest growing populations in this group, however. <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>' other races increased 67 percent to 314,600 while the group was up 52 percent to 126,800 in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> and 51 percent to 184,000 in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p PM-ChildCare-Politics     06-21 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Child Care-Politics,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Failing to Highlight Family Issues, Consultant Says</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By W. DALE NELSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Democrats are failing to capitalize on family issues such as child care at the polls because they are `` afraid to take on the tax consequences'' of programs that voters say they support, a party consultant says. But a Republican strategist warned women's groups that even though child care has emerged as an important campaign issue in recent years, `` there are a lot of folks who just do n't care about the issue.'' <PERSON> Celinda </PERSON> <PERSON> Lake </PERSON>, a Democratic expert on electing women candidates, and <PERSON> Vince </PERSON> <PERSON> Breglio </PERSON>, a former campaign strategist for <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans before becoming President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s chief pollster for the 1988 campaign, appeared on a panel at a meeting held by child care advocates Tuesday. Panelist <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON>, an associate professor of political science at <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said a February poll by <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> showed 87 percent approval for a joint government and private effort to meet child care needs. She said 55 percent of those responding to a CBS News poll in February said the federal government had a responsibility to help parents pay for child care if they could n't afford it. <PERSON> Breglio </PERSON>, however, said the most recent White House polls show that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s child care program, built around a tax credit, has about 5 percent to 6 percent more support than congressional legislation calling for direct government financing. Ms. <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> told the group that family issues `` ought to work very well for Democrats. They are policy issues where people want spending and they want it now, not later. They want government involvement.'' `` We as Democrats have not drawn strong enough political lines on this issue,'' the consultant said. `` Democrats have tended to talk about small cost ... and all this has done is lose the punch of these issues because we have been afraid to take on the tax consequences, the regulatory consequences, of these programs, and in fact voters think these issues are going to take big programs.'' <PERSON> Breglio </PERSON> said such family issues as child care first surfaced in political campaigns in 1986. `` I had candidates who were beaten on those kinds of issues,'' he said. `` They were beaten because, with my stupid advice, they talked about national themes and ideology. Well, national themes and ideology did n't sell in 1986. Concern over nuclear waste and child care did. We were wrong, they were right, and we lost many <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> seats.'' However, he cautioned the group, `` There are a lot of folks out there who feel strongly about it, but I must tell you this: there are a lot of folks who just do n't care.'' Both consultants agreed that family issues will have significant impact in next year's congressional elections. `` I do n't believe serious political candidates in 1990 can avoid discussing the issue of child care,'' <PERSON> Breglio </PERSON> said. `` I do n't believe they can avoid discussing the issue of long-term health care. However, he said he did not believe parental leave would be an issue. Ms. <PERSON> Lake </PERSON> predicted all three would be major issues, particularly if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passes child care and parental leave legislation and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> vetoes it on top of his veto of the recent bill raising the minimum wage. <PERSON> Breglio </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is `` doing pretty well'' with women voters, but `` If there is a whole series of vetoes on legislation that is of particular importance to women, that could be a different ballgame.'' The panel was sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> Child </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Care </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Action </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION>, a coalition seeking a national system of child care combining public and private resources; the Great American Family Tour, a non-profit, non-partisan organization dealing with family policy issues, headed by Rep. <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroeder </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Colo </LOCATION>.; and <ORGANIZATION> Lifetime </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION>, a venture of <ORGANIZATION> Hearst </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> @ </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> ABC-Viacom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, which produce a documentary entitled `` Hush Little Baby: The Challenge of Child Care.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     06-21 0396</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0410</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MILWAUKIE, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The phrase `` doggie do'' has a different meaning for two sisters who make it their livelihood. <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fenger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Arlene </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinle </PERSON> train canine coiffeurs to handle everything from <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kennel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> show styles to the occasional doggie dye job. The words `` dog groomer'' are taboo at their <ORGANIZATION> Tara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> K-9 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hair </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Design </ORGANIZATION> because the sisters believe that's like saying the Cordon Bleu turns out cooks. `` We are n't teaching basic dog grooming,'' said <PERSON> Fenger </PERSON>, who founded the school 20 years ago with her sister. `` We are teaching all-breed styling, including show work.'' <PERSON> Fenger </PERSON>, a former hairdresser, traded permanents for pooches in 1968. The academy, highlighted in the sisters' book, `` The Standard Book of Dog Grooming,'' draws students from around the country. The school is n't cheap: $ 795 for a four-week groomer's assistant course, up to $ 2,995 for a 16-week master course. Students scrub dogs in tubs, cut their hair and dry it with a blow dryer or a heated cage dryer. The finishing touch includes ribbons, scarves or bells. <PERSON> Fenger </PERSON> said she also teaches students how to handle the dogs, including touching the animals in specific places to control and relax them. She said properly handled dogs are less likely to bite the hand that grooms them.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government handouts have come a long way since the federal government doled out surplus cheese. In <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION>, they're giving away toilets. This summer, the <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Water </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION>, hoping to promote an ethic of water conservation, is handing out 2,500 low-flow toilets to communities for public use. The Municipal Toilet Replacement Program is designed with the hope that after residents try the toilets at their town hall or public library they will buy one for their home, said <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lissack </PERSON>, a spokesman for the program. The toilets cost the authority $ 350,000. The authority needs to save water to continue adequately supplying water to 2.5 million people in the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> area. Toilets consume an average of 38 percent of household water. Conventional toilets use 3.5 gallons to 7 gallons per flush; the model being given away uses 1.6 gallons or less. Starting March 2, the state will require that all new toilets use no more than 1.6 gallons of water per flush, which is expected to save more than 3 million gallons of water daily.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BatmobileWinner     06-21 0297</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Batmobile Winner,0306</SECOND>
<HEAD>Virginian Wins Caped Crusader's Car</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RICHMOND, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Holy <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallbanger </PERSON>, <PERSON> Batman </PERSON>! A bartender won your Batmobile. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> McLynn </PERSON>, who is paying his way through <ORGANIZATION> Virginia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> by tending bar part time, has won the hottest car in <LOCATION> Gotham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> as part of the nationwide hoopla surrounding the opening of the movie `` Batman.'' There's just one problem: The Caped Crusader's vehicle does n't have a motor <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Drebin </PERSON>, a publicist for <ORGANIZATION> MTV </ORGANIZATION>, which gave away the car, explained the empty space under the hood. `` It simply was not streetworthy,'' <PERSON> Drebin </PERSON> said. `` The car was the real prop used in the picture. But its motor was too heavy, the ratio was n't according to regulations. It has only been driven by stunt men.'' Luckily for <PERSON> McLynn </PERSON>, the prize also includes $ 25,000 for bat-gas. He said he will invest the money in certificates of deposit and use the interest to buy a motorcycle. <PERSON> McLynn </PERSON>, an engineering student whose goal is to become a toy designer, will collect his prize Friday at the Ridge Cinema from `` Batman'' co-star <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Wuhl </PERSON>. He said he's not sure what he will do with the car. `` I think it should be shown at theaters where the movie is playing and maybe state fairs around the country,'' said <PERSON> McLynn </PERSON>, who does n't own a car and gets around on a bicycle or skateboard. The Batmobile is 20 feet long and more than 11 feet wide. Its design is derived from <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> Salt Flats racers of the 1930s and Corvette Stingrays of the 1950s. When fully armed, it has retractable armor, machine guns concealed above the front wheels, explosive charges in the wheel hubs, remote voice-activated controls, the latest electronic tracking devices and a `` high fear-inducing factor,'' according to <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> Furst </PERSON>, its designer.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890621-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-06-21-89 0151EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-North Bjt   06-21 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North, Bjt,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Sentencing Postponed; Juror Accused of Lying</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ROWLEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
