<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 2323EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Bundy-Will     01-25 0408</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bundy-Will,0420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bundy Wanted Cremation, Ashes Spread Over Cascades</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STARKE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a will signed the night before his execution, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> asked that his body be cremated and the ashes spread over <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state's <LOCATION> Cascade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, where at least four of his victims' bodies were found, a newspaper reported. The will prepared by <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s civil attorney, <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, was released by <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> officials Wednesday at the request of The <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times-Union </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Jacksonville </LOCATION>, which reported the story in Thursday's editions. `` <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> will contact family and friends as to any services. The ashes are to be spread over the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cascade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> stated in the will. The will did not give a specific location for the ashes, and attempts by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> to reach Ms. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> by telephone were unsuccessful. <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, co-owner of the Williams-Thomas Funeral Home in <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> where <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s body was sent, would not give details about the final disposition of the body because of an agreement with Ms. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>. `` There will be no public funeral as of right now,'' <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> said. `` We do not believe there will be a public funeral in the future.'' <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was executed Tuesday at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison near <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION> for the February 1978 murder of <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, 12, of <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. He also was convicted of two other <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> deaths and is suspected in at least 50 deaths nationwide. He was suspected in as many as 15 rapes and murders of young women in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> while he lived in the <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> area in the mid-1970s. Four of his victims' bodies were found on <LOCATION> Taylor </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> in the foothills of the Cascades. In the typewritten will, <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> gave Ms. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> control over his remains, personal property and assets, including mail sent to him at the prison. Prison records show <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s personal property included a radio with a headphone, a gold-tone chain with a cross, a religious book, stationery, a gold wedding band and a bottle of suntan lotion. He also had $ 709.66 in cash, money donated by family and friends for snacks and other items from the prison canteen. The items were inventoried Tuesday and picked up at the prison by Ms. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Macmaster </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Volusia </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> State Attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, a friend of <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s who visited him often in recent years, was designated to handle the arrangements if Ms. <PERSON> Weiner </PERSON> was unable to do so
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 2357EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Obit-Collins     01-25 0186</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Collins,190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Red Cross President Dies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, a retired <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> general and a former president of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, has died of cancer at <ORGANIZATION> Walter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. He was 83. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON>, who was born in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> and graduated from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Academy </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Point </LOCATION> in 1927, died Sunday. He lived in suburban <PERSON> McLean </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>. During World War II, he served in the Pacivic and was transferred to the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> area in 1946 He joined the faculty at the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in 1950 and later was an executive assistant and special assistant to the assistant secretary of <ORGANIZATION> defense </ORGANIZATION> for manpower and personnel. From 1954 to 1957, <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> commanded two infantry divisions and was commanding general of Army forces in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>. For the next four years, he was assistant deputy and chief of staff for army personnel. He was appointed to the rank of four-star general in 1961 and was named commander-in-chief of <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> forces in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. He retired in 1964 and became president of the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and retired in 1970.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0002EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Heartland-SteelFacts     01-25 0271</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Heartland-Steel Facts,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Figures for Recovering Steel Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Heartland-Steel Town Revival</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are some facts about the steel industry, provided by the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Iron </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>. They represent reports from 25 companies representing 80 percent of the industry. _ Profits-Losses: The nation's steel industry is expected to post a 1988 profit of about $ 2 billion. In 1987, profits were $ 1.02 billion, following losses of almost $ 12 billion in 1982-86. The rising profits are attributed to a general strengthening in the world steel market and a moderate increase in demand. _ Shipments: Domestic steel mill shipments are estimated to have risen from 76.7 million tons in 1987 to about 83 million tons in 1988 _ an 8.2 percent increase. _ Production: Raw steel production jumped from 89.2 million tons in 1987 to almost 100 million tons in 1988 _ a 12 percent increase. _ Employment: Average industry employment in 1988 was 170,000, slightly above the 1987 average of 163,000, the lowest since the institute started keeping records in 1933. The industry posted a record-high employment of 650,200 in 1953. _ Imports: Imports in 1988 will have accounted for about 20.5 percent of the steel shipped to consumers, compared with 20.9 percent in 1987. Imports reached a high of 26.4 percent in 1984, the year when the Voluntary Restraint Agreements set a goal of reducing imports to 20.2 percent of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> market. The agreement expires this year. _ State Production: <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION> leads the nation in steel production, with about 22 percent of the steel made there. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> accounts for 18 percent and <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> 13 percent.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Whitbread     01-25 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Whitbread,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nurse's First Novel Wins Richest British Book Prize</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A psychiatric nurse who turned to writing as a hobby won the Whitbread Book of the Year award for his first novel `` The Comforts of Madness.'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sayer </PERSON>, 33, received the $ 34,000 prize on Tuesday from an 11-judge panel for his harrowing story about long-term psychiatric hospital patients who can not speak. The novelist works with elderly patients at a hospital in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Yorkshire </LOCATION> and his tale has been likened to <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Kesey </PERSON>'s `` One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'' about inmates of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> psychiatric institution. The total prize money of $ 46,750 makes the <LOCATION> Whitbread </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s richest literary award <PERSON> Sayer </PERSON> and four other writers had earlier won $ 2,550 each for being selected as finalists for the Whitbread in five categories, first novel, best novel, poetry, biography and children's novel.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0009EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PulitzerJurors     01-25 0606</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pulitzer Jurors,0613</SECOND>
<HEAD>Columbia Announces Pulitzer Jurors</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> I. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sovern </PERSON> has announced the appointment of 66 nominating jurors for the 1989 Pulitzer Prizes in journalism. The winners, for work published in 1988, will be announced March 30 after they are chosen by the <ORGANIZATION> Pulitzer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. The jurors, announced by <PERSON> Sovern </PERSON> on Tuesday, are: <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> bureau chief, <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Louis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post-Dispatch </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, photographer; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ahearn </PERSON>, executive editor, The Associated Press; <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Ambrose </PERSON>, executive editor, Rocky Mountain News, <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Amsterdam </PERSON>, editor, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Anable </PERSON>, former managing editor, The Christian Science Monitor; <PERSON> Jacqui </PERSON> <PERSON> Banaszynski </PERSON>, reporter, <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Pioneer Press Dispatch; <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Barry </PERSON>, columnist, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Blais </PERSON>, professor of journalism, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION>, and columnist, <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Joann </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, executive editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> Everett </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON>, former executive editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Denver </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON>, editor, <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION> -RRB- Herald-Leader; <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, former consultant, <ORGANIZATION> Harte-Hanks </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspapers </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Colleen </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Conant </PERSON>, managing editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Commercial Appeal; <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Dedinsky </PERSON>, managing editor, -LRB- <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> -RRB- Sun-Times; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> del </PERSON> <PERSON> Olmo </PERSON>, editorial writer and columnist, <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Downie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, managing editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Driscoll </PERSON>, editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Forst </PERSON>, editor, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Newsday </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, chief diplomatic correspondent, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Friendly </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Galvan </PERSON>, editorial board, <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> George </PERSON>, managing editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- News and Observer and The Raleigh -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times; <PERSON> Sig </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissler </PERSON>, editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Milwaukee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Greer </PERSON>, executive editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer; <PERSON> Barrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>, executive editor, -LRB- <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> -RRB- Camera; <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Healy </PERSON>, associate editor, The <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION> -RRB- Sentinel; <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Henry </PERSON>, editor, -LRB- <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Democrat and Chronicle and -LRB- <LOCATION> Rochester </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION> -RRB- Times-Union; <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hess </PERSON>, senior fellow, <ORGANIZATION> Brookings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> High </PERSON>, editor, -LRB- Casper, <LOCATION> Wyo </LOCATION>. -RRB- Star-Tribune; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hilliard </PERSON>, editor, The Oregonian; <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, executive editor, -LRB- <PERSON> Gary </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. -RRB- Post-Tribune; <PERSON> Tonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, assistant managing editor, The <LOCATION> Orange </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Register; <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Kovach </PERSON>, senior fellow, <ORGANIZATION> Nieman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, executive editor, <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON>, senior fellow in journalism, <ORGANIZATION> East-West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hawaii </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lockman </PERSON>, managing editor, The News-Journal newspapers, <LOCATION> Wilmington </LOCATION>, Del.; <PERSON> Austin </PERSON> <PERSON> Long-Scott </PERSON>, reporter, <ORGANIZATION> KRON-TV </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Lovelady </PERSON>, associate executive editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Philadelphia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inquirer </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, editor, <LOCATION> Kenosha </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Wis. </LOCATION> -RRB- News; <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, executive editor, <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, managing editor, <ORGANIZATION> Minneapolis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Medina </PERSON>, former assistant city editor, The Miami News; <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION> -RRB- <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Neavoll </PERSON>, editor of the editorial pages, The <LOCATION> Wichita </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Kan. </LOCATION> -RRB- Eagle-Beacon; <PERSON> Irene </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nolan </PERSON>, managing editor, The -LRB- <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION> -RRB- Courier-Journal; <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Pakenham </PERSON>, editorial page editor, <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearlstine </PERSON>, managing editor, The Wall Street Journal; <PERSON> Rena </PERSON> <PERSON> Pederson </PERSON>, editorial page editor, The Dallas Morning News; <ORGANIZATION> Marty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Petty </ORGANIZATION>, deputy executive editor, The <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> -LRB- Conn. -RRB- Courant. <PERSON> Madelyn </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, managing editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Schrag </PERSON>, editorial page editor, <LOCATION> Sacramento </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> -RRB- Bee; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Seigenthaler </PERSON>, editor and publisher of The Tennessean and editorial director of <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> K. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shanahan </PERSON>, managing editor, <LOCATION> Torrington </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION> -RRB- Register Citizen; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaw </PERSON>, media critic, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shelledy </PERSON>, editor and publisher, Idahonian and -LRB- <PERSON> Pullman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> -RRB- Daily News; <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Shepard </PERSON>, reporter, The <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> -RRB- Observer; <PERSON> Allan </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Siegal </PERSON>, assistant managing editor, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Norma </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sosa </PERSON>, managing editor, Corpus Christi -LRB- <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> -RRB- Caller-Times; <PERSON> Ernie </PERSON> <PERSON> Sotomayor </PERSON>, associate editor, <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> R.L </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sterne </PERSON>, editorial pages editor, the <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> Sun; <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tharpe </PERSON>, managing editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Alabama </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Howard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, managing editor, <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Winter </PERSON>, editor and general manager, the Petosky -LRB- <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION> -RRB- News-Review; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Witke </PERSON>, executive sports editor, The <ORGANIZATION> Des </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Moines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Register </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeeck </PERSON>, managing editor, <ORGANIZATION> Kansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Star </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0012EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-UnlikelyMuseum     01-25 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Unlikely Museum,0537</SECOND>
<HEAD>Masterpieces In Middle Of Nowhere</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GUY COATES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JENNINGS, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> self-portrait seems to be looking down his nose at his unlikely surroundings in a little-known museum tucked away in an old house in this rural south <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> town, not too far from grazing cows. `` A lot of people come in here with -LRB- a puzzled -RRB- expression,'' said <PERSON> Delores </PERSON> <PERSON> Spears </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Zigler </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION>. `` They want to know how all of this got to the middle of nowhere.'' The <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> is in good company, just down the wall from a Rembrandt, a <LOCATION> Whistler </LOCATION>, a Sir <PERSON> Joshua </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> and dozens of other works by noted artists dating from the 17th century. Just off Interstate 10, 40 miles from the southeast <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> border, <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> was the home of <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Zigler </PERSON>, who had a fortune and no heirs. They decided to leave a legacy to the area they loved. <PERSON> Zigler </PERSON>'s father had moved from the landlocked <LOCATION> Dakotas </LOCATION> at the turn of the century and made millions in shipbuilding, real estate, oil and gas and other interests. The <PERSON> Zigler </PERSON> legacy included a museum foundation and a separate foundation which grants full college scholarships each year to deserving students _ one from each high school in the area. That foundation also provides grants to charitable organizations, including the museum foundation, which has a smaller endowment. Since 1960 when <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Zigler </PERSON> died, the education foundation has granted $ 1 million in scholarships. Grants to other organizations total $ 3.5 million. `` That's really an economic boost when you take into account what has happened in this parish,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boisture </PERSON>, a member of the museum foundation. The parish, once fat and sassy from oil, gas and shipbuilding, fell on hard times in 1980 with the decline of the oil patch. Unemployment is over 13 percent. `` The money helps the kids, the community and all I can say is thank God for the Ziglers,'' said <PERSON> Boisture </PERSON>. Before she died in 1974, Mrs. <PERSON> Zigler </PERSON> left the old family home to the museum foundation. Two wings have been added to the two-story columned mansion to handle the growing collection, which now totals more than 150 pieces of art. Thanks to the education foundation, the museum was able to purchase the <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> in 1984 for about $ 125,000. `` We took it out of the crate and it was almost an emotional thing,'' said <PERSON> Boisture </PERSON>. `` His hair looks like you could touch it and feel the softness. He looks like he's almost glancing back with disdain at someone.'' One of the best buys, said <PERSON> Spears </PERSON>, was `` Morning'' by <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, which cost relatively little years ago `` but it's in six figures now. We've loaned it to a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> museum.'' <PERSON> Spears </PERSON> says her favorites are a shoreline canvass by <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Inness </PERSON> and `` The Little Mother,'' painted by <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprague </PERSON> <PERSON> Pearce </PERSON> in the 1880s. `` A lot of school kids tour through here and if just one in each group leaves with an interest in what he's seen, this museum is a success,'' said <PERSON> Boisture </PERSON>. `` Middle of nowhere or not.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0014EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CommoditiesProbe-Valukas     01-25 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Commodities Probe-Valukas,0664</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prosecutor Well-Prepared For Chicago Commodities Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LINDSEY TANNER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In <PERSON> Anton </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>' four years as <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney, he has presided over an office that has indicted more than 270 public officials, government employees and others on corruption charges. <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>, 45, is again in the spotlight for his role in the recent market-fraud investigation of the leading <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> commodities exchanges. Observers say no one in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> is better prepared to tackle it. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> law enforcement officials are investigating allegations that as many as 100 brokers and traders systematically cheated customers out of millions of dollars on the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mercantile </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION>. No indictments have been announced and <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> has declined comment. <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> has a vast knowledge of commodities trading, but it was n't built solely as a prosecutor. He learned much by defending traders. As a private attorney at the <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> law firm <ORGANIZATION> Jenner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Block, <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> represented brokers in criminal cases and in disciplinary proceedings before the <ORGANIZATION> Commodity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Futures </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, the agency that oversees futures trading. <PERSON> Eugene </PERSON> <PERSON> Wedoff </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> bankruptcy judge who worked with <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION> Jenner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Block, recalled at least one instance in which <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> successfully defended a Board of Trade broker accused of breaking commodities laws. `` By the time he left <ORGANIZATION> Jenner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Block, he probably knew a much about commodities law as anyone in the city,'' <PERSON> Wedoff </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Troelstrup </PERSON> agreed Tuesday. `` When he came to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office, <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> was probably one of the most knowledgeable and experienced ... in terms of commodities experience,'' said <PERSON> Troelstrup </PERSON>, who is representing at least one of those subpoenaed in the commodities probe. When <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> native whose father was a judge, was named <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney for the northern district of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> in May 1985, he pledged to make prosecuting white-collar corruption a priority. `` Corruption is an epidemic-proportion problem in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> said. `` It would be hard for me to imagine a city in which there was more corruption.'' He joined the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office as an assistant prosecutor in 1970. He joined <ORGANIZATION> Jenner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Block in 1977 but returned to public service in 1981 when Gov. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> appointed him to head the Metropolitan Fair and Exposition Authority. <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> served as an attorney on <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>'s re-election campaign in 1982, and in 1985, the governor lobbied heavily to make him <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney. Tactics used in the commodities probe _ `` wired'' <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents posing as traders in the exchanges' trading pits secretly taping alleged wrongdoing _ are familiar to <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON>. His office has orchestrated elaborate sting operations with undercover agents paying off crooked police officers, judges and politicians, and taping it all on hidden recorders. When he succeeded <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Webb </PERSON> in 1985, <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> took over one of the most publicized investigations, Operation Greylord, a probe of corruption in the <LOCATION> Cook </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> court system. A key player in the probe was a southern <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> judge brought to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>. The judge hid a tape recorder in his cowboy boot and a microphone in his judicial robes to document wrongdoing. So far, 90 judges, lawyers and other court employees have been indicted in the Greylord probe and 70 have been convicted. Several cases are pending. Operation Incubator, developed by <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> and his assistants, uncovered influence-peddling at <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s City Hall. The key figure was <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> `` mole'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON>, whom the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> taped making payoffs to politicians in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Several former officials charged in the probe are scheduled to go on trial in May. <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> is rumored to be planning to leave the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney's office in the next few months The <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> reported Monday that he's eyeing a partner's position at a major <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> law firm. But <PERSON> Valukas </PERSON> has not publicly disclosed his plans.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Theater 1stLd-Writethru a0794 01-25 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Theater, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0794,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>`The Night Hank Williams Died' By Larry King Opens Off-Broadway</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Subs 4th graf to DELETE reference to talk show host. No PMs
planned.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL KUCHWARA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Drama Critic</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a rundown <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> bar called the <ORGANIZATION> Sundowner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Recreational </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION>, dreams go down as easy as a cold bottle of Pearl Beer and are just as intoxicating. They are the stuff of life for many of the characters in `` The Night <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> Died,'' <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s pungent yet poignant tale of lost loves, missed opportunities, unfulfilled expectations and fatal mistakes. It's not a perfect play, but until it collapses into violent melodrama in Act 2, `` The Night <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> Died'' has enough low-key charm and homespun humor to soften the hardest of hearts. Maybe that's because King, author of `` The Best Little Whorehouse in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>,'' has a jaundiced affection for the folks he has put on stage. It's love but love tempered by the knowledge that most of these people will never amount to very much. Despite its title, the play has nothing to do with the death of country-western star <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, although it is set in 1952 and <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>' music wails from the bar's jukebox. Its main concern is <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> <PERSON> Stottle </PERSON>, a one-time high school football hero in the tiny town of <LOCATION> Stanley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>'s gridiron glories were nearly a decade ago Now he's `` 27 and working on a beer gut'' while he pumps gas at the local service station. Between customers, <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> aspires to be another <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> or at least a songwriter who'll sell his compositions _ which have titles like `` Little Bitty Bit of Love'' _ to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION> stars like <PERSON> Eddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON>. `` Nothin' wrong with dreams, providin' you act on'em,'' counsels <PERSON> Gus </PERSON>, the benevolent barkeep who extends <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>'s beer tab as he tries to rein in the boy's fantasies. <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON> is galvanized by the arrival of <PERSON> Nellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bess </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>, his high school sweetheart. Her marriage to an up-and-coming chiropractor has soured and she has come home `` to think about it.'' Her return rekindles <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>'s adoration as well as his ambition to make something of himself. King takes his time churning up the plot, but the wait has its diversions. His dialogue is peppered with down-home conversation, salty, sly and occasionally very funny give-and-take that is one of the evening's main pleasures. Most of these lines are the property of actor <PERSON> Barton </PERSON> <PERSON> Heyman </PERSON> who plays <PERSON> Gus </PERSON>, the bulky and blustery bartender. It's the play's most fully realized role. By the time the curtain falls, <PERSON> Heyman </PERSON> has revealed the frayed and forlorn humanity behind his coarse <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> humor. <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulhern </PERSON> has a harder time playing Thurmond who, when you get down to it, is n't a very likable fellow. <PERSON> Mulhern </PERSON> also has a sweet, pleasing singing voice, something at odds with his doltish, one-track personality that smacks of loser from the very beginning. At first, <PERSON> Betsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Aidem </PERSON> comes on as too much of a dust-caked <PERSON> Scarlett </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hara </PERSON>, but the caricature fades when she realizes the consequences of her new fling with <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>. Strains show in the play when events turn melodramatic, particularly with the appearance of <PERSON> Nellie </PERSON> <PERSON> Bess </PERSON>' fanatically devout mother who still is `` keepin' in real close touch with <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>.'' Also painted in more black than white is the local sheriff, but actor <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Rankin </PERSON> does an expert job shading in the character with a portrayal that's part good ol' boy and part smarmy <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Haskell </PERSON> of television's `` Leave It to Beaver.'' The direction by <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> meanders through the play's talkier moments and then seems frantic during its action-packed finale Still, <PERSON> Ashley </PERSON> allows time for the audience to savor the people who inhabit designer <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> T. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gianfrancesco </PERSON>'s wonderfully ramshackled bar _ complete with deer head above the door. `` The Night <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> Died'' is a bittersweet song to lives and loves lost, spiced with enough laughs to soften the hurt. Definitely worth a look.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--ChannelTunnel     01-25 0161</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Channel Tunnel,0164</SECOND>
<HEAD>Channel Tunnel Claims First Victim</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A teen-age worker in the undersea Channel Tunnel project was crushed to death by a train in the first fatal accident reported during the tunnel's construction, police said. They said the worker, who was not identified, was hit by the train carrying a load of chalk from the tunnel face one-half mile from the entrance at the port town of <LOCATION> Dover </LOCATION> on Monday night. The government-appointed Health and Safety Executive said it sent inspectors to investigate the accident. The proposed 34-mile tunnel, 24 miles of it under water, consists of two one-way rail tunnels and a smaller service tunnel between them. It is being bored simultaneously from <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> under the English Channel at a cost of $ 8.8 billion. Digging began in December 1987. The tunnel is scheduled to open in May 1993 and would cut the London-Paris train and ferry journey from about nine hours to three.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bundy-Interview-Text 6Takes   01-25 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy-Interview-Text, 6 Takes,0354</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Bundy Interview Released By Broadcaster</HEAD>
<UNK>With PM-Bundy, Bjt</UNK>
<DATELINE>STARKE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a transcript of executed killer <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s interview with religious broadcaster Dr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pomona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. The interview, taped Monday afternoon, was released to the news media Tuesday afternoon after <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was put to death in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s electric chair. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: You are scheduled to be executed tomorrow morning at 7 o'clock if you do n't receive another stay. What is going through your mind? What thoughts have you had these last few days? Bundy: I wo n't kid you to say that it's something I feel I have control of, or something I have come to terms with, because I have n't. It's a moment-to-moment thing. Sometimes I feel very tranquil and other times I do n't feel tranquil at all. What's going through my mind right now is to use the minutes and hours I have left as fruitfully as possible and see what happens. It helps to live in the moment in the essence that we use it productively. Right now I am feeling calm and in large part because I am here with you. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: For the record, you are guilty of killing many women and girls. Is that correct? Bundy: Yes, that's correct. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, how did it happen? Take me back. What are the antecedents of the behavior that we've seen? So much grief, so much sorrow, so much pain for so many people? Where did it start, how did this moment come about? Bundy: That's the question of the hour and one that not only people much more intelligent than I will be working on for years but one that I've been working on for years and trying to understand. Is there enough time to explain it all, I do n't know. I think I understand it though, what happened to me to the extent that I can see how certain feelings and ideas have developed in me to the point that I began act to out certain very violent and very destructive feelings.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0023EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyInterview-Text-1stAdd     01-25 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Interview-Text - 1st Add,0571</SECOND>
<HEAD>STARKE, Fla.: destructive feelings</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Let's go back then to those roots. First of all, as I understand it, you were raised in what you considered to have been a healthy home. You were not physically abused, you were not sexually abused, you were not emotionally abused. Bundy: No. No. And that's part of the tragedy of this whole situation. Because I grew up in a wonderful home with two dedicated and loving parents, as one of five brothers and sisters, a home where we as children were the focus of my parents' lives, where we regularly attended church, two Christian parents who did not drink, they did not smoke, there was no gambling, no physical abuse, not fighting in the home. I'm not saying this was ` Leave It To Beaver.' I do n't know that such a home exists, but it was a fine, solid Christian home and nobody, I hope no one will try to take the easy way and try to blame or otherwise accuse my family of contributing to this because I know, and I am trying to tell you as honestly as I know how what happened. This is the message I want to get across, that as a young boy, and I mean a boy of 12 or 13 certainly, that I encountered, outside the home again, in the local grocery store, in a local drug store, the soft-core pornography that people called soft core. As I think as I explained to you last night Dr. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON> in an anecdote, as young boys do, we explored the back roads and sideways and byways of our neighborhood and often times people would dump the garbage and whatever they were putting out of their house. And from time to time we would come across pornographic books of a harder nature than, of a more graphic, explicit nature than we would encounter at the local grocery store. And this also inclouded such things as detective magazines. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Those that involved violence? Bundy: Yes, yes, and this is something I think I want to emphasize is that the most-damaging kinds of pornography, and again I'm talking from personal experience, ... are those that involve violence and sexual violence. Because the wedding of those two forces is, as I know only too well, brings out the hatred that is just, just too terrible to describe. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Now, walk me through that, what was going on in your mind at that time? Bundy: Before we go any further, I think it's important to me that people believe what I am saying. I tell you that I am not blaming pornography. I am not saying that it caused me to go out and do certain things. And I take full responsibility for whatever I have done, and all the things I have done. That's not the question here. The question and the issue is how this kind of literature contributed and helped mold and shape the kinds of violent behavior ... Dobson: It fueled your fantasies, did n't it? Bundy: In the beginning it fuels this kind of thought process, then at a certain time, it is instrumental, I would say crystalizing, making into something which is almost like a separate entity inside. At that point, I was at the verge of acting out in this kind ...
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyInterview-Text-2ndAdd     01-25 0775</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Interview-Text - 2nd Add,0789</SECOND>
<HEAD>STARKE, Fla.: this kind</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Now, I really want to understand that. You had gone about as far as you could in your own fantasy life with printed material, or printed and film ... and then there was the urge to take that little step, or big step over to a physical event? Bundy: And it happened in stages, gradually. It did n't necessarily, not to me at least, happen overnight My experience with pornography generally, but with pornography that deals on a violent level with sexuality, is once you become addicted to it, and I look at this as a kind of addiction like other kinds of addiction, I would keep looking for more potent, more explicit, more graphic kinds of material. Like an addiction, you keep craving something that is harder, harder, something which, which gives you a greater sense of excitement. Until you reach a point where the pornography only goes so far, you reach that jumping off point where you begin to wonder if maybe actually doing it would give you that which is beyond just reading it or looking at it. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: How long did you stay at that point before you actually assaulted someone? Bundy: Well, yeah. That is a very delicate point, by the way in my own development. We're talking about something ... about having reached the point or gray area that, that surrounded that point over a course of years. I would say a couple of years. What I was dealing with there was very strong inhibitions against criminal behavior or violent behavior that had been conditioned into me, bred into me in my environment, in my neighborhood, in my church, in my school, things that said, ` No, this is wrong. Even to think of it is wrong, but certainly to do it is wrong.' I'm on that edge, I would say the last vestiges of restraint, the barriers to actually doing something are being tested constantly, assailed through the kind of fantasy life that was fueled largely by pornography. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Do you remember what pushed you over that edge? Do you remember the decision to go for it, do you remember you decided to throw caution to the wind? Bundy: When you say pushed, I know what you're saying. I do n't want to infer again that I was some helpless kind of victim in that we're talking about an influence that is an influence of violent types of media, violent types of pornography which had an indispensible in the chain ... of events that led to the behavior ... the assaults, the murders It's a very difficult thing to describe, the sensation of reaching that point where I knew that, that something had say snapped, that I knew that I could n't control anymore, that the barriers I had ... learned as a child, had been instilled in me, were not enough to hold me back in respect to seeking out and harming somebody. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Would it be accurate to call that a frenzy, a sexual frenzy? Bundy: Yes, that's one way to describe it, a compulsion ... a building up of this destructive energy. Another factor here I have n't mentioned is the use of alcohol. What alcohol did in conjuction with exposure to pornography is alcohol reduced my inhibitions at the same time the fantasy life that was fueld by pornography eroded them further. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: In the early days, you were nearly always about half drunk when you did these things, is that right? Bundy: Yes. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Was that always true? Bundy: I would say that that was generally the case. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: All right, if I can understand it, there is this battle going on within, there are the conventions that you have been taught, there's the right and wrong that you learned as a child, and then there is this unbridled passion fueled by your plunge into hard-core, violent pornography and those things are at war with each other? And then with the alchol diminishing the inhibitions, you let go? Bundy: Yes, and it's accurate. It just occurred to me that some people will say that ` Well, I've seen that stuff and it does n't do anything to me.' And I can understand that. Virtually everyone can be exposed to pornography and while they are aroused to one degree or another, they do not go out and do anything wrong. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Addictions are like that. They affect some people more than they affect others. But there is a percentage of people affected by hard-core pornography in a very violent way and you are obviously one of them.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0038EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyInterview-Text-3rdAdd     01-25 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Interview-Text - 3rd Add,0587</SECOND>
<HEAD>STARKE, Fla.: of them.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 Bundy: That was a major component and I do n't know why I was vulnerable to it, all I know is that it had an impact on me that was just so central to the development of the violent behavior that I had reached. ... Dobson: <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, after you committed your first murder, what was the emotional effect on you? What happened in the days after that? Bundy: -LRB- long pause -RRB- Please understand, that even all these years later it is very difficult to talk about and reliving through talking about it is difficult, to say the least, but I want you to understand what happened. It was like coming out of some kind of horrible trance or dream. I can only liken it to after, I do n't want to overdramatize it, but to having been possessed by something so awful and so alien, then the next morning wake up from it, remember what happened and realize that basically, I mean in the eyes of the law and certainly in the eyes of God, you were responsible; to wake up in the morning and realize what I had done and with a clear mind and all my essential moral and ethical feelings intact at that moment, absolutely horrified that I was capable of doing something ... Dobson: You really had n't known that before? Bundy: There is just absolutely no way to describe first the brutal urge to do that kind of thing and then what happens is once it has been more or less satisfied and recedes, you might say, or spent, that energy level recedes and basically I became myself again. I want people to understand this too, and I'm not saying this gratuitously because it's important that you understand this. But basically, I was a normal person, I was n't some guy hanging out at bars, or a bum. I was n't a pevert in the sense that people look at somebody and say I know there is something wrong with him, you can just tell. I was essentially a normal person. I had good friends, I led a normal life, except for this one, small but very potent and very destructive segment of it that I kept vey secret and close to myself and did n't let anyone know about. And part of the shock and horror to my dear friends and family years ago when I was first arrested was there was no clue. They looked at me and they looked at the All-American boy. I was n't perfect, ... but I was OK. I was. The basic humanity and the basic spirit that God gave me was intact, but unfortunately became overwhelmed at times. And people need to recognize it's not some kind of ... those of us who are or who have been so much influenced by violence in the media, in particular pornographic violence, are not some kind of inherent monsters. We are your sons and we are your husbands and we grew up in regular families. And pornography can reach out and snatch a kid out of any house today. It snatched me out of my home 20, 30 years ago and as dedicated as my parents were, and they were diligent in protecting their children and as good a Christian home as we had, and we had a wonderful Christian home, there is no protection against the kind of influences that are loose in society that tolerates. ...
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyInterview-Text-4thAdd     01-25 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Interview-Text - 4th Add,0827</SECOND>
<HEAD>STARKE, Fla.: that tolerates ...</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: You feel this really deeply do n't you? <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, outside these walls, right now, there are several hundred reporters who wanted to talk to you and you asked me to come here from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> because you had something to say. This hour that we have together, is not just an interview with a man who is scheduled to die tomorrow morning. I am here and you are here because of this message that you are talking about here. You really feel that hard-core pornography and the doorway to it, soft-core pornography, is doing untold damage to other people and causing other women to be abused and killed the way you did others? Bundy: Listen. I'm no social scientist and I have n't done a survey, I mean I do n't pretend that I know what <PERSON> John </PERSON> Q. Citizen knows about this, but I have lived in prison for a long time now, and I've met a lot of men who were motivated to violence just like me. And without exception, every one of them was deeply involved in pornography, without question; without exception, deeply influenced and consumed by an addiction. There's no question about it. The <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>'s own study on serial homicide shows that the most-common interest among serial killers is pornography. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: That's true. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, what would your life have been like without that influence? You can only speculate. Bundy: -LRB- tears -RRB- Far better not just for me, and excuse me for being so self-centered here, but it would have been a lot better for me and lots of other people and lots of other innocent people, victims and families, it would have been a lot better. There's no question there would have been a fuller life, certainly a life that would not have involved, I am absolutely certain, a life that would not have involved this kind of violence. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: I'm sure <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, if I were able to ask the questions that are being asked out there, one of the most important as you come down to your final hours: Are you thinking about those victims out there and their families who are so wounded and years later their lives have not returned to normal and will not return to normal? They will never return to normal. Are you carrying that load, that weight. Is there remorse there? Bundy: Again, people will accuse me of being self-serving, but I am just telling you how I feel. Through God's help, I have been able to come to the point where I much too late, but better late than never, feel the hurt and the pain that I am responsible for. Yes, absolutely. In the past few days myself and a number of investigators have been talking about a number of unsolved cases, murders that I was involved in. It's hard to talk about all these years later because it revives in me all those terrible feelings and thoughts that I have steadfastly and diligently dealt with and I think successfully, and yet its reopened that and I felt the pain and I felt the horror and I can only hope that those who I have caused so much grief, even if they do n't believe my expression of sorrow, will believe what I am saying now; that there is loose in the towns and their communities people like me today whose dangerous impulses are being fueled day in, day out by violence in the media in various forms, particularly sexual violence. And what scares me and it's coming to the present now because what I am talking about happened 30, 20, 30 years ago in my formative state. And what scares me, Dr. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>, when I see what's on cable TV, some of the movies and some of the violence in the movies that comes into homes today, the stuff that they would n't show in X-rated adult theaters 30 years ago ... Dobson: The slasher movies is what you're talking about ... Bundy: That stuff is, I'm telling you from personal experience, is the most graphic violence on screen, particularly as it gets into the home to children who are unattended or unaware that they may be a <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> who has that vulnerability, that predisposition to be influenced by that kind of behavior ... There are kids out there switching the TV dial around and come upon these movies late at night, or I do n't know when they are on, but they're on and any kid can watch them. It's scary when I think what would have happened to me if I had seen them, and it's scary enough, I just ran into stuff outside the home. But to know that children are watching that kind of thing today or can pick up their phone and dial away for it or send away for it. ...
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0042EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyInterview-Text-5thAdd     01-25 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Interview-Text - 5th Add,0785</SECOND>
<HEAD>STARKE, Fla.: for it.</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Can you help me understand this desensitization process that took place? What was going on in your mind? Bundy: About the desensitization, I would describe it in specific terms is that each time I'd harm someone, each time I would kill someone, there would be an enormous amount, especially at first, an enormous amount of horror, guilt, remorse afterward, but then the impulse to do it again would come back even stronger. Now, believe me, I did n't ... The unique thing about how this worked, Dr. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>, is I still felt in my regular life the full range of guilt and remorse about other things. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: But you had this compartmentalized. Bundy: This comparmentalized, very well focused, very sharply focused area that was a black hole that was like a crack and everything that fell into that crack hole just disappeared. Does that make sense? <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Yeah, it does. One of the final murders that you committed, of course, was apparently little <PERSON> Kimberly </PERSON> <PERSON> Leach </PERSON>, 12 years of age. I think the public outcry was greater there because an innocent child was taken from a playground. What did you feel after that? Was there normal emotions three days later? Where were you, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>? Bundy: I ca n't really talk about that. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: That's too painful. Bundy: I would like to be able to convey what that experience is like, but I ca n't be able to talk about it. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: OK. ... Bundy: I ca n't begin to understand, I can try, but I'm aware that I ca n't begin to understand the pain the parents of these children ... -LRB- inaudible -RRB- feel, and I ca n't restore really much to them, if anything and I wo n't pretend to And I do n't even expect them to forgive me and I am not asking for it. That kind of forgiveness is of God. If they have it, they have it. If they do n't maybe they'll find it someday <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: Do you deserve the punishment the state is inflicted upon you? Bundy: That's a very good question and I'll answer it very honestly. I do n't want to die, I'm not going to kid you. I kid you not. I deserve, certainly the most extreme punihsment society has and I think society deserves to be protected from me and from others like me, that's for sure. I think what I hope will come of our discussion is I think society deserves to be protected from itself. Because as we've been talking there are forces loose in this country, particularly again this kind of violent pornography where on the one hand well-meaning decent people will condemn the behavior of a <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> while they're walking past a magazine rack full of the very kinds of things that send kids down the road to be a <LOCATION> Ted </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bundy </LOCATION>. We're talking here not just about more, what I'm talking about is going beyond retribution, which is what people want with me; going beyond retribution and punishment because there is no way in the world that killing me is going to restore those beautiful children to their parents and correct and soothe the pain but I'll tell you there are lots of other kids playing in streets around the country today who are going to be dead tomorrow and the next day and the next day and the next month because other young people are reading the kinds of things and seeing the kinds of things that are available when the media took over. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: <PERSON> Ted </PERSON>, as you would imagine there is tremendous cynicism about you on the outside and I suppose for good reason. I'm not sure there is anything that you could say that people would believe, some people would believe. Bundy: Yeah. <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>: And yet you told me last night, and I have heard this through our mutual friend -LRB- State Attorney -RRB- <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tanner </PERSON>, that you have accepted the forgiveness of <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON>, and are a follower and believer in him. Do you draw strength from that in these final hours? Bundy: I do. I ca n't say that ... being in the valley of shadow of death is something that I've become all accustomed to and that I am strong and there is nothing bothering me. Listen, it is no fun. It gets kind of lonely, and yet I have to remind myself that every one of us will go through this some day in one or another and countless millions who have walked this Earth before us have. So, this is just an experience which we all share, and here I am.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0043EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GreekCommissioner     01-25 0586</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Greek Commissioner,0603</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Greek Radical Becomes EEC Commissioner</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DINA KYRIAKIDOU</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Greece (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s new commissioner in the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> is <PERSON> Vasso </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> radical who once wanted <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> out of the organization. She and <PERSON> Christiane </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrivener </PERSON>, 63, of <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> are the first women to serve on the 17-member <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, which is made up of senior executives and now is charged with preparing for the removal of all remaining trade barriers within the 12-nation community by the end of 1992. The 44-year-old Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, a close friend of but not related to <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>'s Socialist premier, <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>, was appointed by <PERSON> Jacques </PERSON> <PERSON> Delors </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>'s president. As with all other commissioners she is expected to act independently of her country in shaping EEC policy. She has been assigned the community's taxation and customs union portfolio. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> recognizes that social affairs have been left behind,'' she said in an interview. `` There is a lot of work to be done and success depends both on Commission policy and my activity.'' A farmers's daughter from southern <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> studied economics at <ORGANIZATION> Athens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Higher </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commercial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> and then earned a Ph.D. at <ORGANIZATION> Reading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>. She belonged to a generation of young leftists who bitterly opposed the 1967-74 military dictatorship in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> and who were inspired by <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s radical socialist policies, including pledges to take <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> out of the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Treaty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>. But after leading his <ORGANIZATION> Panhellenic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Movement </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> PASOK </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- to power in 1981, <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> decided it would be too costly to take <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> out of the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION>. As one of the trade bloc's poorer members, <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> receives more than $ 1.5 billion a year in benefits. Premier <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> and the government are now enthusiastically pro-European. Asked how she reconciles her radical and Marxist past with her new job, the tall, dark-haired Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> said: `` It's not me that's changed but <ORGANIZATION> PASOK </ORGANIZATION>.'' As deputy industry minister while <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION> held the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> presidency during the second half of 1988, Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> chaired meetings on streamlining industrial legislation in the community. In the male-dominated world of Greek politics, Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> and Culture Minister <PERSON> Melina </PERSON> <PERSON> Mercouri </PERSON>, the former actress who starred in `` Never on Sunday,'' have proved the only female high-fliers in the Socialist government. In her first government post as director of the Organization for Small and Medium-Size Businesses for two years from 1981, Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> often was assailed by conservative businessmen, who accused her of trying to impose Marxist policies. But her two-year stint as deputy commerce minister after winning a <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> seat in 1985 impressed even those critics. Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON>'s portfolio on the <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> will be a sensitive one. Socialist <ORGANIZATION> EEC </ORGANIZATION> member-governments, currently in the majority, will be seeking to expand labor laws and increase social security payments. But the conservative governments are likely to oppose more social welfare legislation that might further complicate the 1992 goal of moving services, goods and money freely around the community. Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> says that during her years in government she has learned the art of compromise, crucial in building community policy. `` One always has to compromise,'' she said. `` But I'm taking a positive view and this will be a challenge and a great experience.'' `` She is very intelligent, a very good diplomat and knows how to maneuver,'' said <PERSON> Christos </PERSON> <PERSON> Papoutsis </PERSON>, a Socialist member of the <ORGANIZATION> European </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> who has known Ms. <PERSON> Papandreou </PERSON> for 15 years.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0049EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-History     01-25 0821</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-History,0845</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alleged Involvement In Gas Plant Recalls Past Horrors</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN COSTELLOE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FRANKFURT, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Charges that West German companies helped <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> build what may be a poison gas plant recall horrors from two world wars and images of what a politician called the `` evil, self-deceiving German.'' <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> shocked the world in World War I by wiping out 5,000 Allied soldiers April 22, 1915, with chlorine gas, introducing the era of chemical warfare. The Nazis later use Zyklon B gas to kill millions of prisoners, most of them Jews, at the <LOCATION> Auschwitz </LOCATION> death camp. In addition to lessons of the past, the current debate dwells on moral standards in a nation that has developed an arms export industry in the last 15 years that ranks fifth in the world. `` German profits have grown much more quickly than ethical standards,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Friedhelm </PERSON> <PERSON> Hengsbach </PERSON>, a social sciences professor at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Georgen </LOCATION> theological university in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. `` The Germans are very smart in the sense of economic realities, but they're not that shrewd when it comes to ethical responsibility and political realities,'' the 51-year-old Jesuit priest said in an interview. <PERSON> Norbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Gansel </PERSON>, a member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> for the opposition Social Democrats, put the problem succinctly: `` Now, our history has caught up with us again. The evil, self-deceiving German is back.'' In its current issue, the left-leaning magazine <PERSON> Der </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> said the attitude of West German industry is `` export at all costs'' to guarantee prosperity at home and `` tens of thousands of people pay for the exporters' prosperity with their lives.'' `` First comes the food, and then morals?'' it said, referring to a line by the German author <PERSON> Bertolt </PERSON> <PERSON> Brecht </PERSON>. `` Not even that: many deals are made completely without morals.'' Government statistics say West German companies legally sell about $ 16.6 billion worth of guns, submarines, munitions and other arms overseas each year. That puts the country in fifth place behind the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. Several state and local investigations are under way to determan the amount of arms and arms-related goods sent abroad illegally. Included are inquiries into reports of West German involvement in Iraqi poison gas production in addition to allegations that West German companies helped build the plant at <LOCATION> Rabta </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, that <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> says makes medicines and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> says is for producing chemical weapons. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> acknowledged using poison gas during its war with <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>, in which a cease-fire was reached in August, and has been accused of using it on minority Kurds. Reports arise frequently of West German companies evading export restrictions, as <PERSON> Gansel </PERSON> reminded a noisy parliamentary debate on the Libyan matter last week. `` The string of arms-export scandals is long,'' he declared, including sales of sensitive nuclear technology to <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Gansel </PERSON>, 48, said <PERSON> Zyklon </PERSON> B gas killed `` countless defenseless Jews'' and reminded fellow legislators the image of the `` evil, self-deceiving German'' had become a theme for both newspaper cartoons and editorials. Many newspaper stories, magazine articles and TV programs about the chemical plant scandal point out the German history of poison gas dating to World War I. <PERSON> Der </PERSON> <PERSON> Spiegel </PERSON> called poison gas part of the `` horrifying tradition of the German chemical industry'' and said, after describing the 1915 attack at Flanders: `` When the fog lifted, 5,000 Allied soldiers were dead and 10,000 seriously injured. The <ORGANIZATION> German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> had launched chemical warfare.'' In <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, the <PERSON> Suedeutsche </PERSON> <PERSON> Zeitung </PERSON> reminded readers in an editorial Jan. 13: `` Not everyone may like the Germans; no one has forgotten their past. Whoever has as much power as the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republic </ORGANIZATION> must also bear responsibility.'' <PERSON> Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Perels </PERSON>, a political science teacher at <ORGANIZATION> Hanover </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said in an interview: `` It is a question of current-day morality and the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> past. You just ca n't lose sight of that second point. It would be better if <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> did n't supply <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION> with any materials that could be used for war.'' <PERSON> Friedrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Justus </PERSON> <PERSON> Perels </PERSON>, the professor's father, was executed by the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> along with thousands of others for alleged involvement in the unsuccessful attempt to kill <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> in 1944. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, spokesman for <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>'s Jewish community, said of the Libyan scandal: `` German companies should be more conscious of what's taking place in <LOCATION> Libya </LOCATION>,'' an enemy of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. `` It's part of the special responsibility of the Germans, and a special responsibility is n't just something to pray about on Sundays.'' <PERSON> Andreas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hillgruber </PERSON>, a conservative historian on the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cologne </ORGANIZATION> faculty, said attempts to link the scandal with the Nazi era are an example `` of the past that wo n't go away.'' `` You can view everything that the Germans do today against that background,'' <PERSON> Hillgruber </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hillgruber </PERSON> and other conservative historians have tried to compare the extermination of 6 million Jews with other atrocities to show the Nazi genocide does not stand alone in history.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0052EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Britain-Trains     01-25 0133</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Britain-Trains,0135</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Toll in London Crash Rises to 35</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The death toll from the collision of three trains near a busy south <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> junction six weeks ago has risen to 35 with the death of a 61-year-old man. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Philipson </PERSON>, a passenger aboard a London-bound commuter train traveling from his hometown of <LOCATION> Bournemouth </LOCATION> in southern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, died of his injuries at a <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> hospital on Tuesday, the hospital said. Rail officials said the train <PERSON> Philipson </PERSON> was aboard slammed into the rear of another passenger train that had stopped for a malfunctioning signal about 400 yards south of <LOCATION> Clapham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Junction </LOCATION> on Dec. 12. A freight train traveling in the opposite direction then plowed into spillover wreckage and apparently hit some passengers who had scrambled onto the tracks, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0540EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--HomelessAds     01-25 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Homeless Ads,0159</SECOND>
<HEAD>Vietnam Veterans Launch Ad Campaign About Their Homeless</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group of Vietnam Veterans has created a series of advertisements narrated by <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> and designed to focus attention on the estimated 80,000 homeless veterans on <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s streets The announcements for the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> Veterans Workshop are shot in grainy black and white film using professional actors who are all <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> combat veterans, said <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, president of the workshop. The spots were unveiled Tuesday and will be broadcast on television and radio and shown in movie theaters. The ads ask viewers to offer a pledge or volunteer to help the workshop, which hopes to provide counseling or outreach centers for homeless veterans. `` Two and a half million Americans went to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>,'' it says. `` All any of them ever wanted was to come home. For 80,000, home has become the streets, home has become a cardboard box, an abandoned car.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0022EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BeringBridge     01-25 0462</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bering Bridge,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trek to Reunify Eskimo Cultures</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARJORIE ANDERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Soviet-American dog sledding team announced plans Tuesday to symbolically break the ice between Siberian and Alaskan Eskimos during a 1,200-mile goodwill trek that will include the first sanctioned crossing of the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> since 1948. Ten men and two women, comprising six Soviets and six Americans, plan to depart March 1 from <LOCATION> Anadyr </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION>, on a two-month journey visiting 30 native settlements along an old Arctic trade route. The expedition is an attempt to call attention to the common cultural heritage of the indigenous peoples of the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> region, expedition co-leader <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, said at a news conference at the <LOCATION> Russian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Tea </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Room </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>. `` Some of the team members have relatives on the other side,'' <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said, so it could be a very emotional experience. Because visitors are rare in villages so close to the top of the world, he predicted that the expedition would be met with `` spontaneous celebrations and jamborees'' and that schools would be let out so that the children could ski along with the team for a while. A veteran of Arctic travel who made an unassisted trek to the North Pole in 1986, <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said the journey was `` an opportunity to combine my interest in travel in the north with playing a part in the process of improving Soviet-American relations.'' Speaking through an interpreter, Soviet co-leader <PERSON> Dmitry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shparo </PERSON>, 47, of <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>, praised <ORGANIZATION> Du </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pont </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, the major American corporate sponsor of the Bering Bridge Expedition. <PERSON> Shparo </PERSON> also put in a plug for the main Soviet sponsors, Pravda's youth newspaper, the tourist bureau known as Sputnik and <ORGANIZATION> Novosti </ORGANIZATION>, a news agency. Although he is a mathematics professor at <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Steel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alloys </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Shparo </PERSON> is best known as a writer and adventurer. In 1979, he won the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>'s highest honor, the Order of <PERSON> Lenin </PERSON>, for successfully leading a ski expedition to the North Pole. Last year, he was a member of a Soviet-Canadian trek across the polar ice cap from the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. Sen. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Alaska </LOCATION>, who also attended the news conference, called the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> Expedition `` another step toward melting the ice curtain.'' <PERSON> Murkowski </PERSON> noted that the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government is working on a new treaty with the Soviets that would permit American Eskimos to visit and trade with their counterparts in <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> without visas. In 1938, the two countries signed an agreement that regularized travel in the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> region, but that agreement was abrogated in 1948 during the iciest days of the Cold War. In the spirit of adventure diplomacy, the team hopes a new agreement can be signed at a ceremony at the U.S.-Soviet border around April 1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BundyExecutioner     01-25 0291</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bundy Executioner,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anonymity of Executioner Protected</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bundy, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STARKE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The hooded executioner who electrocuted <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was a civilian who received $ 150, a chauffeured escort to and from the prison and a guarantee of anonymity. The executioner was chosen from a list the state has been using since it advertised for executioners in 1976, when the death penalty was reinstated. `` If we did n't take precautions, there are enough crackpots inside and outside this prison that'd be threatening them,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Burton </PERSON>, superintendent of <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison. `` They threaten me every day.'' Only <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> knows who's on the list. He is also the only person who handles the arrangements. <PERSON> Jon </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON>, a spokesman for Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, said he did n't know the identity of <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s executioner but added it could have been a woman, which was speculated by some witnesses to <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>'s execution. <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON>, who confessed to killing more than 20 women, was put to death in the electric chair Tuesday for raping and murdering a 12-year-old girl. While security is paramount for the executioner's job, skill is incidental. `` All the executioner does is start the cycle by turning a switch or pressing a button _ I wo n't say which _ and the thing is programmed from there,'' <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> said. The executioner stands in a booth behind and to the right of the electric chair, watching through a 9-inch-by-4-foot opening in the wall as the condemned prisoner is buckled into the chair. A light on a panel of dials before the executioner indicates that the current is sufficient. When <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> gives the signal, the executioner activates the machine, which pumps up to 3,000 volts and 20 amps of electricity through the chair and into the body.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0026EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Eastern-Cocaine     01-25 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Eastern-Cocaine,0334</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cocaine Discovered On Eastern Jet</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 About 47 pounds of cocaine was discovered Tuesday on an <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> jet that had stopped at Miami International Airport en route from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, officials said. No arrests were made by late Tuesday and <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Customs </ORGANIZATION> officials are considering whether fines will be levied against the financially troubled carrier, fined $ 1 million last fall after cocaine was discovered on two flights within a two-week span, said Customs spokesman <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>. Before the cocaine was found, the plane had been cleared by Customs inspectors following a routine search, said <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON>. Eastern spokeswoman <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Ceremsak </PERSON> said a flight attendant found a plastic packet containing cocaine inside one of the exit doors, leading to an extensive search of the L-1011 aircraft that arrived from <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION>, at about 4 p.m. EST. The cocaine was between the panels of the door and above the lavatories of Flight 50, she said. But <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said several packets of cocaine were discovered by a member of the cleaning crew in the rest rooms. He said vibrations apparently dislodged the cocaine, which was concealed behind ceiling panels above the rest rooms. <PERSON> Stallings </PERSON> said the manner the cocaine was hidden suggests it was placed by someone with extensive access to and knowledge of the plane. The search was completed about 9:30 p.m. EST, he said. All passengers were accommodated on other flights, Ms. <PERSON> Ceremsak </PERSON> said. Since Sept. 13, Customs agents have seized five loads of cocaine on Eastern flights from <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, including 68 pounds of cocaine hidden in a box of ground coffee in November and 56 pounds of cocaine found in a mail bag in October. Eastern says it spends more than $ 3 million a year fighting drug trafficking. Avianca, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s national airline, banned cargo from its flights last June after paying $ 8 million in federal fines linked to drug seizures.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Notebook Bjt   01-25 0640</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Notebook, Bjt,630</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: A President Who Stops for Stop Lights</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> stops at red lights. Sometimes. In a city used to seeing dignitary-bearing motorcades screeching through traffic lights, sirens wailing, at all times of day and night, the sight is more than a little unusual. There was <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s 15-car motorcade, waiting for a traffic light to change, right along with other backed-up traffic on a busy downtown <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> street. No sirens. No flashing police-car lights. The president was on his way to a local <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> base, <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> McNair </PERSON>, for a Tuesday afternoon jog and did n't want to disrupt traffic any more than was necessary. It's not as though anyone would write him a traffic ticket. He was simply following a pattern he'd established in his eight years as vice president, said aide <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Zanca </PERSON>. `` Mr. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s preference as vice president was to stop at lights, keep things as normal as possible,'' <PERSON> Zanca </PERSON> said Of course, as vice president, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> did n't require 15 cars to go jogging. He just stepped outside his door and ran. The vice president's residence is on the sprawling grounds of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION> Naval Observatory, and there's lots of space for jogging and other outdoor activities. There is n't as much room at the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, forcing the new president to seek out new jogging trails. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> once suggested that he might return to the vice presidential grounds from time to time to do his jogging, joking that he had already sought _ and obtained _ permission from the man who would be living there next, Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, 64, jogs at a relatively sedate pace, about a mile every 10 minutes. He usually runs for 20 minutes, two or three times a week. The chief executive's decision to observe traffic signals apparently only applies to personal trips, not when he's going somewhere on official business. Then, it's the regular presidential motorcade _ which gets an elaborate police escort and travels on streets where traffic has already been cleared. Such motorcades completely ignore traffic signals along the way.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, who is trim at 6-foot-2 and 190 pounds, may jog to help counter the waistline-expanding effect of another presidential passion: deep-fried pork rinds. When <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> held his first Cabinet meeting on Monday, gone was the crystal jar of jellybeans that predecessor <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> used to have sitting before him. By Tuesday, there was a large jar again _ only this one was filled with pork rinds. It was a gift of House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, one of a group of <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> leaders that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had invited to meet with him in the Cabinet Room to discuss the budget. <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> also presented fellow Texan <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> with a large bottle of `` Texas Pete'' hot pepper sauce. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is known to love to smother all manner of food with hot sauce. During his campaign, a standard meal for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> aboard Air Force Two was tuna fish sandwiches drenched with hot sauce. `` We want to give a very warm welcome to the president,'' said <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> picked up the bottle of hot sauce and closely examined the label. `` How come <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> hot sauce is made in <LOCATION> Winston-Salem </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>?'' <PERSON> Wright </PERSON> retorted: `` Same way that some Texans were born in <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>.'' The room erupted in laughter, even though <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>'s citation of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> origins was off by a few states. While his family maintains a vacation home in the seaside resort town of <LOCATION> Kennebunkport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was born in <LOCATION> Milton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, and grew up in <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION>. `` I'm just overwhelmed by both the pork rinds and the <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> hot sauce,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said. `` You talk about cooperation, ecumenical spirit, outreach. Just lovely.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-ElectedOfficials     01-25 0686</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Elected Officials,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elected Officials Top Half-Million Mark</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Big government in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> may get the most publicity, but a new <ORGANIZATION> Census </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> report shows that government is big business in the rest of the country as well, with more than a half-million Americans holding elective office. From school board president to the nation's president, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to county commissioner, public officials total 504,404, the bureau reported Tuesday in a study based on its 1987 census of governments. That's up from 490,807 elected officials counted a decade earlier, the bureau said. `` It's quite a statement about the extent of democracy, particularly the grassroots democracy, in the country,'' said <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Cull </PERSON>, a census statistician who compiled the figures. It means the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> now has more officeholders than bank tellers. The <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Statistics </ORGANIZATION> estimated there were 467,000 tellers in 1987. But while the report found that holding public office is widespread, it also shows officeholders do n't necessarily represent a cross-section of the nation. Only 20 percent were women, while 2 percent were blacks and 1 percent were Hispanic. Nationally, women make up just over half the population while the nation is about 12 percent black and 7 percent Hispanic. Most of the growth in elected officeholders since 1977 results from the growth of special districts around the nation, Ms. <PERSON> Cull </PERSON> said. These include independent water and sewer districts, housing authorities, transit administrations and similar independent bodies with elected boards. Special districts accounted for 80,509 elected officials on 29,532 governmental bodies in the 1987 study. That's up from 72,377 officeholders running 25,962 special districts in 1977. That increase of more than 8,000 officials was well ahead of any other group, although special districts were only fourth in the total number of officeholders. Municipalities, towns and school districts continue to have larger totals of officials elected to public office. The leading group is municipalities, with 137,688 officials serving 19,200 communities in 1987. That's up from 134,017 officeholders in 18,862 municipalities in 1977. Townships came in second in both years, totaling 120,790 officials in 1987 and 118,966 a decade earlier year. During that period the total number of township governments declined from 16,822 to 16,691. School districts were the nation's third largest job source for elected officials, providing offices for 86,772 people in 1987. That was down from 1977, however, when 87,062 people held elected school board positions. That drop occurred in parallel with a decline in the number of school districts in the nation, slipping from 15,174 to 14,721. The nation's 3,042 counties _ the same in both studies _ provided somewhat fewer elected offices in 1987 than in 1977. The total fell from 62,922 to 59,932. The states, meanwhile, increased their number of elected offices. They harbored 18,171 elected officials in 1987, up from 15,294 in 1977. The 1977 report did not include figures for federal officeholders. The new study put that number at 542, a total which Ms. <PERSON> Cull </PERSON> said was unchanged. Elected federal officials include 435 members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, 100 senators, five congressional delegates from territories and the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> and, of course, the president and vice president. The 1987 report looked at the characteristics of local government officials for the first time, <ORGANIZATION> Cull </ORGANIZATION> said. It found that women were most likely to be on school boards, making up 26.5 percent of elected school officials. Women constituted 23.1 percent of township officials and 20.8 percent of county officers. They were 18.5 percent of the municipal officials and only 11.5 percent of those serving on special districts. Blacks, on the other hand, were most often represented on municipal governments, holding 3.3 percent of those posts. Blacks made up 2.6 percent of the county officials and 2.4 percent of school district officeholders. They were 0.6 percent of the special district officials and 0.4 percent in town offices. School districts were the most common spot for Hispanics, at 1.8 percent. They held 1.3 percent of municipal offices and 1.2 percent in special districts. Hispanics comprised 1 percent of county officials and 0.2 percent of town officers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890125-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-01-25-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StateIncomes     01-25 0604</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-State Incomes,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Income Growth Slowest in Energy States</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARTIN CRUTSINGER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Economics Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
