<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 2338EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DeathAppeal 1stLd-Writethru a0804 05-03 0479</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Death Appeal, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0804,0487</SECOND>
<HEAD>Convicted Child Killer Presses Final Appeal As Execution Looms</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 6 grafs to UPDATE with Supreme Court rejecting Adams'
appeal; picks up 5th graf pvs: `Adams, 31, ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RON WORD</BYLINE>
<UNK>Associated Press</UNK>
<DATELINE>JACKSONVILLE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> refused Wednesday to stay the execution of a convicted child killer scheduled to die Thursday morning, after his attorneys lost similar appeals in three lower courts. The emergency request by <PERSON> Aubrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> was denied by the high court in a 7-2 vote. The justices also turned down his formal appeal to review his death sentence. Justices <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Brennan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thurgood </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, who oppose the death penalty in all circumstances, voted to spare <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>. Earlier Wednesday, the 11th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> denied a request for a stay of execution for <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, saying it did n't `` find merit in any of the claims raised.'' The 11th Circuit's decision Wednesday night followed rejection of <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' appeal by the <ORGANIZATION> Florida </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in the morning and by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON> II in the afternoon. The <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> appeal was filed in anticipation of the lower court rejections, said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Spalding </PERSON>, head of the state agency that handles final appeals for inmates facing execution. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, 31, a former officer at <ORGANIZATION> Marion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institution </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ocala </LOCATION>, was originally scheduled to die Tuesday for the murder of an 8-year-old <LOCATION> Marion </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> girl, but the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> issued a 48-hour stay Monday. He is scheduled to die in the electric chair at <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> State Prison near <LOCATION> Starke </LOCATION> at 7 a.m. EDT Thursday. If <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> is put to death, he will be the second man executed in the state this year and the 21st since <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> resumed executions in 1979. In January, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Bundy </PERSON> was executed for killing a <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> schoolgirl _ the last in a string a serial killings that started in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> is under his fourth death warrant for the Jan. 23, 1978, murder of <PERSON> Trisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornley </PERSON>, a third-grader last seen on her way home from school. The girl's mutilated and naked body was found in a plastic bag March 15, 1978, by hunters in a remote area about three miles from her home. An obscene phone call to the girl's home was traced to <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>' home, and he eventually admitted picking her up He said he recalls that she screamed at some point, he placed his hand over her mouth to silence her and she suffocated. <PERSON> Adams </PERSON> and his wife, a teacher's aide, were friends of the victim's parents. He had been scheduled to die in 1984 and twice in 1986 when three psychiatrists ruled him mentally competent to be executed. State law requires that inmates be able to understand why they are being punished before they can be executed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ChemicalFire     05-03 0248</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chemical Fire,0256</SECOND>
<HEAD>19 Hospitalized After Chemical Fire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FREMONT, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A chemical fire in an electronics plant Tuesday released an acid gas, and 19 people were hospitalized, authorities said. The fire that started in chemical processing equipment at <ORGANIZATION> Advanced </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dielectrics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s circuit board plant filled the sky with hydrogen bromide fumes before being brought under control around 4:30 p.m., said <PERSON> Cathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Shonk </PERSON> of the Fremont Fire Department. Hydrogen bromide is an acid gas that is extremely irritating to the nose and throat when inhaled, <PERSON> Shonk </PERSON> said. The cause of the fire was being investigated. Orange smoke filled the plant's halls. The fire department evacuated about 100 employees and 225 workers from the <ORGANIZATION> Sequoia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, a training center next door to the factory in an industrial park. The 19 injured were taken to hospitals in <LOCATION> Fremont </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Hayward </PERSON>, cities along the eastern shore of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> north of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION>. Four people were listed in stable condition at <LOCATION> Kaiser </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hayward </LOCATION>. The hospital would not disclose the nature of their injuries. Nine patients were taken to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Fremont </LOCATION>, where they were given 15-minute decontamination showers and awaited examinations for possible respiratory damage, said spokeswoman <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> McAuliffe </PERSON>. Six people treated at <LOCATION> Saint </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rose </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hayward </LOCATION> for irritation to their eyes and throat were in stable condition and were expected to be released Tuesday evening, said spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorn </PERSON>. Another 16 people were treated at the scene for smoke irritation, said <PERSON> Shonk </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-OilExplosion     05-03 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Oil Explosion,0239</SECOND>
<HEAD>Truck Driver Critically Injured In Explosion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATHENS, Ga. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire that started while a tank truck was loading gasoline destroyed a fuel storage facility and 275,000 gallons of oil, burning the vehicle's driver critically, officials said. The fire sent up a column of smoke that could be seen for at least 20 miles. Five hours after the blaze broke out, flames still were shooting 50 feet in the air, but fire officials said the fire was under control and would be allowed to burn itself out overnight. Firefighters planned to be on the scene into the morning, said <LOCATION> Clarke </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Fire Chief <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON>. The fire at Lay's Petroleum Products, a <ORGANIZATION> Shell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> facility which has four above-ground storage tanks, apparently was started by the truck, <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON> said. The driver, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Coile </PERSON>, apparently gunned his engine several times as he backed toward a filling area, sucking fumes into his exhaust pipe and touching off the blaze, <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Coile </PERSON>, 48, of <LOCATION> Danielsville </LOCATION> was taken to <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marys </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in critical condition and airlifted to <ORGANIZATION> Humana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Augusta </LOCATION>, said a <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marys </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON> said the tank truck exploded, but all of the storage tanks held. Also destroyed were a motor home, a warehouse containing 5,000 55-gallon drums of oil and the company's office building, <PERSON> Hansford </PERSON> said. There was no immediate damage estimate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0001EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-AuctionSeason 2ndLd-Writethru a0790 05-03 0740</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Auction Season, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0790,0756</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spring Art Auctions Could Net $600 Million</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 5th graf, `Among the ...,' to UPDATE that
price paid for Pollock painting a record, comment from buyer; picks up
6th graf, ```Triptych May-June ...;' SUBS 7th graf, `Five sculptures ...,'
to CORRECT spelling of artist's name to Oldenburg, sted Oldenberg; SUBS
11th graf, `A Sotheby ...,' to CORRECT spelling of artist's name to Gauguin,
sted Gaugin.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY33</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KILEY ARMSTRONG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Picasso self-portrait, a town house by <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s `` Shot Red Marilyn'' are among the 4,529 artworks going on the block here during a 12-day, $ 600 million auction frenzy that got under way Tuesday night. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s, the city's biggest auction houses, hope to ring up $ 572 million in sales, and <LOCATION> Habsburg </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Feldman </PERSON>, a Geneva-based auctioneer, was expecting to bring in up to $ 30.5 million for 57 Impressionist and modern paintings. `` There is a tremendous amount of interest and purchasing power around the world,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Marion </PERSON>, chairman of <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> `` There is heavy buying from Europeans and tremendous interest from the <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, especially <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. Korean buyers are now emerging. And I would not count the Americans out, either.'' <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s and <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s were to auction 4,472 works, starting with contemporary art sales this week. Among the paintings sold Tuesday night at <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION>'s were two major drip paintings by <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON>: `` Number 8, 1950,'' which went for $ 10.5 million, and `` Number 19, 1949,'' which fetched $ 3.6 million. The price paid for `` Number 8, 1950'' broke the record for a Pollock painting, $ 5.72 million last year for `` Frieze.'' <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Deitch </PERSON>, who bought `` Number 8'' for an anonymous collector, called the price `` very advantageous ... Sometimes you just get lucky.'' `` Triptych May-June,'' done by <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Bacon </PERSON> in 1973 and inspired by the suicide of the artist's close friend, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyer </PERSON>, sold for $ 5.7 million. Five sculptures by <PERSON> Claes </PERSON> <PERSON> Oldenburg </PERSON> were sold: `` Ice Cream Sandwich,'' $ 370,000; `` Plate of Meat,'' $ 360,000; `` Bacon and Egg,'' $ 450,000; `` Cheesecake from Javatime,'' $ 47,500; and `` Green Beans,'' $ 240,000. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON>'s `` Red <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON>,'' which portrays a ruby-lipped <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> <PERSON> Onassis </PERSON> as first lady in 1963, sold for $ 750,000 _ more than twice the presale estimate. `` Red <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>,'' a 1964 depiction of <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, will be offered at <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s on Wednesday. The estimate for the signed, synthetic polymer silkscreen on canvas is $ 1.5 million to $ 2 million. Other <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s offerings include `` Colored Alphabet,'' a 12-by-10 -LCB- inch oil and paper collage by <PERSON> Jasper </PERSON> <PERSON> Johns </PERSON>, estimated at $ 1.5 million. The theme `` is, in fact, the alphabet. But it's in vivid, overlapping colors: various shades of blue, yellow and red with some black,'' said <PERSON> Roberta </PERSON> <PERSON> Maneker </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s spokeswoman. A Sotheby sale next Tuesday features <PERSON> Gauguin </PERSON>'s `` Mata Mua,'' circa 1892, completed during the artist's first trip to <LOCATION> Tahiti </LOCATION>. Estimated at $ 20 million to $ 25 million, it is being sold by <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz-Patino </PERSON>, heir to a Bolivian tin fortune, and <PERSON> Baron </PERSON> <PERSON> Hans </PERSON> <PERSON> Heinrich </PERSON> <PERSON> Thyssen-Bornemisza </PERSON>, a member of the advisory board of <ORGANIZATION> Sotheby </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holdings </ORGANIZATION>. The same day, `` <PERSON> Yo </PERSON> <PERSON> Picasso </PERSON>,'' a 1901 self-portrait done in <LOCATION> Paris </LOCATION> during the artist's `` blue period,'' is expected to command $ 15 million to $ 20 million. The seller is <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherry </PERSON>, president and chief executive officer of <ORGANIZATION> Humana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION> Louisville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ky. </LOCATION>, hospital management corporation. A <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> <PERSON> Pollock </PERSON> triptych, a series of three drip paintings on three canvasses in black, red and yellow, is expected to fetch $ 1.5 million to $ 2.5 million. A Sotheby's sale of 20th century decorative arts Saturday will include the only town house designed by architect <PERSON> Philip </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. The two-story minimalist house was commissioned in 1950 by Mrs. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Warhol </PERSON> called it `` the original <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> loft.'' Real estate taxes on it in 1988 came to $ 14,414. A Christie's impressionist sale on May 10 and May 11 is expected to bring in $ 109 million to $ 149 million. The paintings include five Monets, including `` The Trees, Autumn,'' estimated at $ 6 million to $ 8 million; seven Picassos; 10 Renoirs, including `` The Logue,'' -LRB- $ 2.5 million to $ 3.5 million -RRB-, which depicts a model and <PERSON> Renoir </PERSON>'s brother, <PERSON> Edmond </PERSON>, a journalist, peering through opera glasses, and four by <PERSON> Degas </PERSON>. The private collection of late movie producer <PERSON> Hal </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallis </PERSON>, including two Monets, will be auctioned next week. <PERSON> Sotheby </PERSON>'s is shooting for total sales of $ 260.9 million to $ 340.8 million; <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s aims for $ 169.9 million to $ 231.3 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0003EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 2ndLd-Writethru a0628 05-03 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0628,0828</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Rejects Students' Demand To Recognize Union</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: LEADS with 11 grafs to UPDATE with government rejecting demands
to recognize student union. Pick up 5th pvs, `The protest...' Edits thereafter
to trim.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BEJ2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The government on Wednesday rejected student protesters' demands that it recognize their new independent unions, setting the stage for more pro-democracy demonstrations. On Tuesday, student leaders gave the government 24 hours to recognize their student union or they would take to the streets again. Thousands demonstrated for democracy and freedom in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>. The developments added new tension to a situation the government has been trying to calm by holding talks with officially sanctioned student unions. Last week's activism crested with a march of 150,000 students and their supporters in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s capital. The official student unions took no part in the marches, the biggest in communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s history, and student activists say the talks wo n't satisfy their yearnings for a freer and more open <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> police announced they would close central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s Tiananmen Square on Thursday, the 70th anniversary of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first student protests, in what appeared to be an effort to head off a new student march The government also said unidentified non-students who oppose <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rule have been advising the student protesters from behind the scenes, and suggested that leading dissident <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON> might be one of them. Government spokesman <PERSON> Yuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mu </PERSON> told a news conference that these people `` try to accomplish during disturbances goals that they can not attain in circumstances of political stability.'' Yuan stopped short of directly accusing <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, an internationally renowned astrophysicist, of advising the student protesters. But he questioned <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>'s patriotism and said, `` The role Mr. <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> wants to play in the current disturbances will be decided by his words and deeds.'' <PERSON> Fang </PERSON>, who previously has called Marxism a failure and called for multi-party democracy, has not taken part in any of the student protests that began April 15. Speeches he made on campuses in 1986 were blamed for stirring up 1986-87 pro-democracy marches, and he was ousted from the party. Yuan refused to say what the government will do if students try to march Thursday. The protest in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s most important trading and industrial city, began in the early afternoon when about 6,000 students, carrying banners reading `` give us democracy and freedom,'' blocked traffic in front of city government offices. Student leaders presented petitions demanding political reform and the <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> said the protest ended about 10 p.m.. An American teacher said a class boycott, which started in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and spread earlier this week to <LOCATION> Tianjin </LOCATION>, has moved to <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION> About half of the students at <ORGANIZATION> Fudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, the city's leading school, are striking, said <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurtado </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, Ore. He quoted student activists at <LOCATION> Fudan </LOCATION> as saying that student leaders from <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> helped organize the strike and the march. Student leaders have also been sent to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for more coordination, he said. Earlier, students from <LOCATION> Tianjin </LOCATION> came to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> for guidance with their movement. In <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, 65 student leaders from 33 universities bicycled more than 7 -LCB- miles to deliver an ultimatum to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s legislature; the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, its cabinet; and the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> of the ruling <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> In a handwritten letter, the students demanded the government recognize and hold talks with the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Universities </ORGANIZATION>, an independent association set up during their 2-week-old campaign for democratic reform. They want a free press, freedom of assembly and publication and an end to official corruption. Thursday marks the 70th anniversary of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first student demonstration, which turned into a movement for democratic and scientific reforms. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> students already have marched five times to Tiananmen Square since April 17, defying police warnings. An estimated 70,000 students at 41 colleges in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> also have been boycotting class since April 24. After a march April 27 drew cheers and applause from tens of thousands of bystanders, the government held a series of meetings with invited students. However, most of those invited have been members of the officially established student unions. The government has declared the students' new association illegal. For its part the association has rejected the talks with the government as a sham, accusing officials of trying to placate students without agreeing to democratic reforms. Despite student complaints, however, the government does seem to be responding to public pressure. On Saturday, Sunday and Monday, ministers of three government bureaus along with the government's leading spokesman and the mayor and party secretary of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> met with students. The meetings were unprecedented in a society whose leaders hide from public scrutiny. The state-run press has softened its shrill editorial stance on the movement and several in-depth reports on the talks and the demonstrations have appeared.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BeirutBar     05-03 0910</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beirut Bar,0941</SECOND>
<HEAD>In West Beirut, Backstreet Bar An Oasis During Shelling</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Behind the red door on Makhoul Street in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, there's a watering hole where the regulars huddle to share a drink, seek shelter from the shelling, and maybe sing along to a Sinatra tune. Here's what the `` war clientele'' were up to on a recent night:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DONNA ABU-NASR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hunched over a beer in the Backstreet Bar, the only tavern in west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> that has stayed open throughout the <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> fighting, a doctor was decribing the horrors of the casualty ward after recent ferocious shelling. Around the Lebanese doctor, a veteran of more bad nights than he can recall in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s relentless bloodletting, the tavern was filled with about 40 people drinking from <PERSON> Habib </PERSON> <PERSON> Ne'aimeh </PERSON>'s well-stocked bar during a lull in the shelling Ne'aimeh has kept his bar open six nights a week during the fighting. `` When the shelling gets heavy I turn up the music,'' he said, standing behind his red and black bar on a recent night. `` These people are not as relaxed as they try to appear. They're drinking more.'' The doctor works at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, once one of the best medical centers in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. Now, after 14 years of civil war, it's short of medicine and trained staff. It has taken several direct hits in recent fighting. `` One night 15 people were brought in,'' he said, clutching his beer tightly. `` Four of them were dead. `` There was a baby. We thought its mother was among the dead and we did n't know what to do with it,'' said the doctor. `` Suddenly, this woman appears out of nowhere as one of our people is trying to soothe the baby. Turns out it's the mother.'' That story had a happy ending. But for thousands of other Lebanese, the last seven weeks have brought only death, injury, devastation or confinement in bunkers and basements. Nearly 300 people have been killed and nearly 1,000 wounded since March 8 in almost non-stop battles between army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s mainly Christian forces and an alliance of Syrian troops and Druse Moslem militiamen. Ne'aimeh's coterie of customers, what he calls his `` war clientele,'' regularly make it to the Backstreet through the darkened alleys, past packs of dogs scavenging through rotting, rat-infested garbage, to the red door in <LOCATION> Makhoul </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>. Shortages have forced Ne'aimeh to trim his menu to cold cuts, cheeses and grilled steaks. His customers, flung together by the war, are a bizarre group of people who for their own reasons have hung on in the Lebanese chaos and the kidnappings. As more than 150,000 people have fled the city amid the carnage in recent weeks, the Backstreet has become an oasis for this disparate group. There are Swiss from the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, Spanish and Belgians from the French-based Medecins Sans Frontiers agency, a couple of Russians, the odd Bulgarian or two and some Lebanese. Ne'aimeh is a <ORGANIZATION> Greek </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orthodox </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION>, one of several thousand who live in the Moslem sector. Most are leftists, with little in common with the Maronite Catholics, who make up the vast majority of the Christians trapped in their enclave in east <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> and the mountains and coastal strip running north. His only waiter is a Sunni Moslem _ the others refuse to leave their underground shelters to go to work _ and the cook's a Shiite Moslem. Despite their different religious preferences, they're a tight team, a microcosm of what's possible in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> if the warring sects and factions could only get their act together. This night at the bar, everyone's having a good time, letting it all out. But there's an undercurrent of apprehension. The laughter sometimes has a brittle edge to it. Everyone knows someone who's been killed or wounded or lost a relative, or whose home has been hit in the bombardments. They've all wondered whether the next rocket or shell to fall will have their name on it Most are skeptical things will get better, and many are trying to leave <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. As the sound system belted out <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON> singing `` <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>,'' everyone joined in the line `` I want to wake up in a city that never sleeps'' _ enjoying the irony that the shelling makes sleep a luxury few get in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. At that moment, the bar's generator sputtered and gave out About 11 p.m., rockets began to arc across <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>'s dividing Green Line, three miles of unrelieved devastation, where Christians and Moslems have faced each other from sandbagged positions and gutter apartment buildings for 14 years. `` Incoming or outgoing?'' a young woman asked as an explosion thundered nearby. `` Incoming, I think. I saw the flash,'' a young man answered hesitantly. `` Anybody got a radio?'' someone said. `` What's it say?'' A Lebanese reporter working for a <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> news organization tuned his transistor radio to the Christian-run Voice of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. `` Shells hitting the Christian side,'' the reporter said. `` It's outgoing. `` That's OK then,'' the young man replied. Then the radio said the source of the shelling had been pinpointed to west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>. The young man lost his poise, told Ne'aimeh he'd pay his tab later, and left. He knew the Christian army gunners were probably at that moment training their 155mm howitzers on the area around the Backstreet Bar to retaliate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0059EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-IranRearms     05-03 0891</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Iran Rearms,0919</SECOND>
<HEAD>Iran Buys New Weapons, Rebuilds Battered Military</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ED BLANCHE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Despite severe economic problems, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> is spending up to $ 5 billion a year to rebuild its military now that a cease-fire has been reached in the 8-year-old war with <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, analysts report. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s relations with <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> also are warming and the fundamentalist Moslem regime is turning to the Soviet bloc increasingly for arms, apparently paying for tanks, artillery and other weapons with crude oil. On Monday, Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> soon would buy weapons from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> and was negotiating with countries he did not identify for advanced fighter bombers. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> must broaden its source of arms, he said, because `` if we depend on one particular country or bloc, then they take advantage of the situation. ... They want to impose their own ideology on us.'' <PERSON> Besharati </PERSON> did not say what kind of Soviet weapons <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would buy or what the cost would be. `` Strengthening the <LOCATION> Islamic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>'s defense capabilities is one of the major tasks we face during the reconstruction period,'' President <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Khamenei </PERSON> told senior military commanders at a recent conference. Both belligerents have large forces along the cease-fire line and, with peace talks deadlocked eight months after they began, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s rapid buildup is causing concern among Western officials. `` It's very worrisome. They're rebuilding much faster than we expected,'' a senior official of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, on condition of anonymity. <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION> also is seeking new weapons to modernize its armed forces, and both countries have been developing their own arms industries, including missile production, since the cease-fire Aug. 20. Earlier this month, the <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> daily <PERSON> Payam </PERSON> <PERSON> e-Enqelab </PERSON> said the missile firepower of the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> will `` increase five-fold in the near future'' using domestically produced weapons with ranges of up to 100 miles. The American source said of the Iranian rearmament program: `` It appears they're talking in the range of $ 20 billion over the next 4-5 years. They've got serious economic problems and yet they're spending this kind of money on rebuilding their military The question is: to what end?'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and other Western officials said <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s major arms suppliers in the latter stages of the gulf war, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, still are its main sources. Diplomatic sources in the <LOCATION> Persian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> region reported recently that the Chinese are helping <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> build a plant to produce surface-to-surface missiles. Al-Ittihad, a daily in <LOCATION> Abu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dhabi </LOCATION>, quoted military sources last month as saying <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> would provide 40 new Silkworm anti-ship missiles, a reconnaissance satellite and batteries of HQ-2J surface-to-air missiles, the Chinese version of the Soviet SAM-2. Evidence increases, however, that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> also is turning to <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> for Soviet-designed weapons. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources said most of the equipment is tanks, trucks, artillery and small arms rather than high-technology weapons. Gulf newspapers have said <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION> would supply nearly 500 tanks, armored vehicles and tank transporters; help build a naval base on <LOCATION> Qeshm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hormuz </LOCATION>, and convert a tractor factory in <LOCATION> Arak </LOCATION> to produce armored vehicles. <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> will supply <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> with 180 T-54 and T-55 tanks and help build a plant to make anti-tank weapons, the papers have reported. No independent confirmation of the reports was available, but <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> has made trade agreements with several Soviet bloc states, including <LOCATION> Romania </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, providing for payment in crude oil. It has a similar pact with <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, now the world's sixth largest arms exporter. <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s official media, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said only that the deals involve `` products and services,'' but analysts believe arms are involved. `` The <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> bloc will be swimming with T-54s and T-55s because of <LOCATION> East-West </LOCATION> force reductions and it makes a lot of sense that <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would be getting a lot of hardware from this quarter,'' said <PERSON> Hans-Heino </PERSON> <PERSON> Kopietz </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> specialist with the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Strategic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. In the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> source's view, arms deals with the Soviet bloc `` have obvious advantages, including all-land transportation through <LOCATION> Russia </LOCATION>,'' <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s northern neighbor. <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> also has strengthened military links with its eastern neighbor <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION>, a Moslem nation. The Pakistanis are developing their own arms industry and are advanced in the production of missiles and some other high-tech weapons. Both Brig. Gen. <PERSON> Mansour </PERSON> <PERSON> Sattari </PERSON>, the air force commander, and <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamkhani </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Revolutionary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guards </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> minister, visited <LOCATION> Islamabad </LOCATION> in recent weeks to meet with senior Pakistani military officials. `` We'll soon see the fruits of these talks, which have defense and other objectives,'' <PERSON> Shamkhani </PERSON> said without elaboration. Official Iranian media have reported a defense allocation equivalent to $ 5.85 billion in this year's budget, described as about half last year's total. Reselat, a <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> daily, said <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> also approved a secret budget bill in which defense spending was considerably higher. Exiled opponents of the regime claimed to have a copy of the secret budget. They said it included $ 4.9 billion for the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> and $ 3.6 billion for Revolutionary Guards. The <ORGANIZATION> Mujahedeen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khalq </ORGANIZATION>, based in <LOCATION> Iraq </LOCATION>, also told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> those figures did not represent <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s `` entire planned military spending,'' Analysts have estimated that, on the basis of such needs as combat jets, tanks, radars and missiles, <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION> would spend about $ 5 billion a year on new weapons.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0005EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-UprisingGame Bjt   05-03 0635</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Uprising Game, Bjt,0652</SECOND>
<HEAD>Israeli Children Play At The Uprising On Computer Screens</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Palestinian uprising has produced a new game that has Israelis battling stone-throwing Palestinians on computer screens and getting burned _ either by firebombs or world public opinion. Computer buff <PERSON> Shahar </PERSON> <PERSON> Melamed </PERSON> said the game is being passed around by computer enthusiasts and is popular among children in <LOCATION> Rehovot </LOCATION>, a town near <LOCATION> Tel </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Aviv </LOCATION> housing <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s prestigious <ORGANIZATION> Weizman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Science </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Melamed </PERSON> is a photo editor at the Israeli daily <ORGANIZATION> Yediot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ahronot </ORGANIZATION>, which printed a story on the game Tuesday. He said the program was signed only by `` Mike'' and added: `` Some details of the program indicate it was done in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> ... I do n't know who wrote the program but he seems to be a very good programmer.'' The game is titled `` The Intefadeh,'' the Arabic word for `` uprising'' that is commonly used for the nearly 17-month revolt against <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s occupation of the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION>. Palestinian children have made up their own street game on the uprising in which they take turns playing soldiers and stone-throwers, shoot with plastic guns and even hold mock funerals for `` martyrs.'' `` The Intefadeh'' is much more sophisticated, with players getting points for inflicting casualties _ but only with specific weapons allowed by changing rules. These mirror real life, since Israeli soldiers face a complex set of regulations on using tear gas, rubber or plastic bullets and live ammunition in putting down riots in the occupied lands. The game has political implications. Players gain points for helping to elect right-wing politicans. Players can lose points for upsetting world public opinion, again reflecting reality. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> has drawn international criticism over the more than 450 Palestinian deaths in the revolt. One set of instructions for the game begins: `` You can use the wooden club you were issued on any rioter. Use tear gas any time you feel it is needed. You are authorized to shoot any rioter with rubber bullets. Shoot rubber or plastic bullets at any rioter who throws Molotov cocktail. You are not allowed to use live ammunition under any circumstances.'' The screen then shows a typical street in a Palestinian village or town, with a lone <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> soldier facing protesters. The trooper is pelted with rocks and firebombs and may respond with gunfire or chase the protesters along narrow `` streets.'' But the rules can change according to who is the `` defense minister in charge,'' randomly chosen by the computer and listed at the top of the screen. Under <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s real-life foreign minister, live ammunition can not be used. But under <PERSON> Ariel </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> _ a hawk forced to resign as defense minister in 1983 during <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s invasion of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> _ live ammunition is a must. Points are scored by inflicting as many casualties as possible within a given time limit by using proper ammunition. An injured soldier is evacuated by an ambulance or bursts into flames and is declared dead. The computer labels him `` just another victim of Arab terrorism.'' Palestinians injured by tear gas move in dizzy circles, but intensify stone-throwing attacks later. At the end of the game, an `` Israeli Defense Forces evaluation form'' is displayed on the screen, featuring the number of protesters injured, killed or captured. A successful player is congratulated for helping Israeli right-wingers win the national elections. The game is made even more complex, however, by the presence of the `` public opinion index.'' Indiscriminate shooting of protesters can lead to a chilling judgment on the screen. One example: `` Performance: You have gone wild. Public opinion index: zero. Your inefficiency in supressing the violence is appalling. You must be sleeping on the job. The government lost the elections mostly as a result of your inaction.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0006EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-BorderSpat     05-03 0829</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Border Spat,0855</SECOND>
<HEAD>India And Nepal Fuss and Feud at Border Point</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 SIRISIAR BRIDGE, On the <LOCATION> Indian-Nepalese </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Border </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ A friendly sort of friction has set in at this crossing point between <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, the political and military giant of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, a tiny and landlocked kingdom. For more than a month, <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> has been defying and exasperating <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> by refusing to renegotiate trade agreements on <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s terms. As a result, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has imposed a partial blockade and <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> is suffering severe shortages of fuel needed to operate motor vehicles, provide electrical power and cook food. Medicines, baby food and other essential goods also are in short supply. The problem is as tangled as the traffic jam of bullock carts, horse-drawn carriages and bicycle-powered rickshaws trying to negotiate the narrow wooden bridge over the <LOCATION> Sirisiar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> without getting stuck in the cracks between the creaking planks. The bullocks' long, pointed horns scrape and snag on the rickshaws' cloth canopies, much as the government officials in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION> are scraping and snagging in the political impasse. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, population 880 million, perceives <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> as an ungrateful neighbor, seeking preferential treatment for itself while refusing to grant <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> reciprocal privileges. <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, population 17 million, sees <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> as a bit of a bully, trying to thwart Nepalese efforts to diversify its trading partners. Officially speaking, the Indian blockade is not total. Practically speaking, its effects come close to being total. `` This is not a blockade. You can see the trucks are moving,'' customs collector <PERSON> Asit </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitra </PERSON> said in the Indian border town of <LOCATION> Raxaul </LOCATION> as a score of vehicles lumbered over the bridge to <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>, hauling burlap bags of salt, cases of baby formula and brand new _ but empty _ tanks for cooking gas. `` The goods are coming in, but not as they were,'' said Mayor <PERSON> Vimal </PERSON> <PERSON> Srivastav </PERSON>, three miles up the road in the Nepalese town of <LOCATION> Birganj </LOCATION>. At the <LOCATION> Birganj </LOCATION> customs yard, the goods are unloaded from Indian trucks. But the porters are sleeping in the midday heat atop the cartons they normally would be transferring to Nepalese trucks. The diesel and gasoline to run the trucks 75 miles north to <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION>, the Nepalese capital, no longer arrive from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, itself a net importer of petroleum products. `` It's like you get the torch -LRB- flashlight -RRB-, but not the battery,'' said <PERSON> Pashupati </PERSON> <PERSON> Shaha </PERSON>, a hotel owner in <LOCATION> Birganj </LOCATION>. When the bilateral trade and transit treaties expired March 23 with no replacements in the offing, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> closed 13 of the 15 official crossing points on the 1,095-mile border. Only Raxaul and <PERSON> Jogbani </PERSON> remain open. <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> wanted to renegotiate the two treaties separately, one governing trade with <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, the other covering vital transit rights from <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> to the border for non-Indian imports. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> sought a single treaty to safeguard its own trade with <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> has little to offer foreign trading partners, apart from goatskins and a few spices. But it imports machinery, housewares, textiles and food in addition to pharmaceutical and petroleum products. For the last two years, about 40 percent of <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>'s imports were Indian. Fifteen years ago, more than 80 percent were Indian. Especially of concern to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> are recent Nepalese efforts to expand trade with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s longtime regional rival and the only other country with direct land access to <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s pique heightened last fall when <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> purchased anti-aircraft guns and other weapons from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, prompting two questions in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Delhi </LOCATION>: Why was <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> making purchases from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and why did the tiny <LOCATION> Himalayan </LOCATION> monarchy, which has about 35,000 men under arms compared to <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>'s 1.4 million, need anti-aircraft guns, anyway? <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> considers its trade and defense needs its own business. `` Trade has its own nature,'' Foreign Minister <PERSON> Shailendra </PERSON> <PERSON> Kumar </PERSON> <PERSON> Upadhyaya </PERSON> told a reporter in <LOCATION> Katmandu </LOCATION> this week. `` Trade will increase normally with any country with which we receive a fair deal.'' One more nettle is <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>'s decision requiring the 150,000 Indians in <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> to obtain work permits, while <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> has made no similar requirements of the estimated 5 million Nepalese in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>. In addition, <PERSON> Birganj </PERSON> had long been a shopper's delight for Indians, whose own country prides itself on self-sufficiency and imports little of the Western and Japanese goods widely available in <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION>. The Nepalese joke about their ability to sell just about anything with a foreign label to Indian visitors. <PERSON> Shaha </PERSON>, the Birganj hotel owner, remarked, `` You can blame <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> for this. The Indians can find some of these things cheaper in <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Madras </LOCATION>, but they want to come to <LOCATION> Nepal </LOCATION> and buy. Some merchants import saris from <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>, stamp ` Made in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>' on them, and the Indians are very happy to buy.'' `` The Nepalese will buy seven or eight times what they need of something, import it through <LOCATION> Calcutta </LOCATION>, then smuggle it back across the border to sell it in <LOCATION> India </LOCATION>,'' an Indian government official said, speaking on condition of anonymity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0100EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Sudan-Analysis     05-03 0795</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sudan-Analysis,0822</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebel Cease-Fire Gives Government A Reprieve</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP News Analysis</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DALIA BALIGH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The surprise declaration by Sudanese rebels of a monthlong cease-fire reprieves the <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> government's beleaguered troops and boosts an international effort to save 100,000 people facing starvation It also raises hopes for an end to six years of civil war that drains $ 1 million a day from the coffers of one of the world's poorest countries Monday's announcement by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Garang </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Sudan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, comes at the height of his greatest success of the war _ a six-month string of victories that has government forces reeling. Rebel fighters also have been intensifying pressure on the strategic southern capital, <LOCATION> Juba </LOCATION>. Its fall could have determined the war's outcome by forcing the government from its largest stronghold in the embattled south. But at least as important, the cease-fire could boost the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>' struggling operation to transport more than 100,000 tons of food and supplies to the south before heavy rains start this month. Last year, relief officials say up to 500,000 southerners died in the fighting or from war-induced disease and famine in villages isolated by flooded roads and airstrips. <PERSON> Garang </PERSON>, a U.S.-educated renegade army colonel, said the unilateral truce will hold only so long as the government refrains from redeploying or reinforcing its troops. He said it could be extended. Prime Minister <PERSON> Sadek </PERSON> <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> welcomed the move. `` Each step taken by <PERSON> Garang </PERSON> toward peace will be reciprocated by two steps from the government,'' he said in a May Day speech. Only last month, <PERSON> Garang </PERSON> rejected a U.N.-proposed `` month of tranquillity'' to allow the $ 132 million relief operation easy access to 2.3 million war-affected southerners. Instead, he guaranteed safe conduct for specific relief convoys. But attacks by unidentified armed groups, bureaucratic hassles, inadequate transport infrastructure and bad planning have hampered the operation. Only 37,000 tons of food was delivered in April. <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> officials say they will continue until the rains cut transport routes. `` I think the overriding reasons behind this decision are political, but they are bound to be connected with the relief effort,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, the regional director of <ORGANIZATION> UNICEF </ORGANIZATION> who conducts most <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> negotiations with the rebels. `` We're keeping our fingers crossed, but it ought to help the operation if only by easing things and reducing the level of anxiety,'' <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> said in a telephone interview from <LOCATION> Amman </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>. Military experts in <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> interpreted the rebels' rejection of the original truce as evidence of unwillingness to impede their battlefield winning streak. Since then, <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON> has come under army pressure and approved a tentative peace plan, which the rebels welcomed with cautious optimism. The cease-fire `` was the next logical step in the peace process,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON>, a lecturer at <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Reading </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> and a specialist on <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION> who returned from <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> last week. `` Now it's up to the government to arrange for further steps,'' <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON> said in a telephone interview. <PERSON> Garang </PERSON>'s broadcast said all his forces will remain in their positions `` to wait for the government to implement the requirements of the Sudanese peace initiative.'' A joint technical military committee then would work out a comprehensive cease-fire, he said. The agreement's most politically sensitive clause calls for the suspension of harsh Islamic laws in force since late 1983. The mainly animist and <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> rebels took up arms against the Moslem-dominated government a few months earlier, demanding autonomy for the south. <PERSON> Mahdi </PERSON>, the leader of a Sudanese Moslem sect, approved the suspension last month, leaving the way clear for a constitutional conference. In the two years that the rebels have won an upper hand in the war, southern civilians have suffered as both sides used food as a weapon. <LOCATION> Juba </LOCATION>, a city of dusty streets and thatched-roof mud huts whose population is swollen by refugees to five times its normal 30,000, has been besieged for more than two years. Rebels intensified their attacks these past few months. `` The <ORGANIZATION> SPLA </ORGANIZATION>'s military successes created a very difficult political situation for them,'' said <PERSON> Woodward </PERSON>. `` If they took over the major towns in the south ... it would mean a de facto separation of <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>, and it would be much more difficult to try and negotiate a peaceful settlement for a united <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>. Now, they negotiate from a position of strength.'' Military sources in <LOCATION> Khartoum </LOCATION> say about 20,000 troops are holed up in the middle of <LOCATION> Juba </LOCATION>. One source estimated the army's strength at 75,000 and the rebels at 57,000. But government troops are outnumbered in the war because only 10,000 soldiers remain in major southern towns other than <LOCATION> Juba </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Cairo-based correspondent <PERSON> Dalia </PERSON> <PERSON> Baligh </PERSON> recently returned from an assignment in <LOCATION> Sudan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0101EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TroubledMayor     05-03 0654</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Troubled Mayor,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Just Three Weeks After Election, LA Mayor Faces Political Crisis</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUDY FARAH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 When Mayor <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> won a fifth term three weeks ago, it should have been a time of celebration for the 71-year-old sharecropper's son. Instead, he found himself facing what's become the political crisis of his career. After 16 years of an administration free of personal scandal, the usually bland and steady <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> is the subject of a conflict-of-interest probe for accepting thousands of dollars in consulting fees from banks that did business with the city. He says he was unaware of the business ties when he accepted the money. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> also is under fire because his daughter was employed by a project to which he helped funnel nearly $ 400,000 of city money, the Task Force for Africa-Los Angeles Relations. He said he was unaware she had been hired. The allegations, which began surfacing at the end of the campaign, have tarnished the nice-guy image of <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, a former police lieutenant dubbed the Teflon Mayor for his ability to escape blame for the city's gang, growth and pollution problems. Other mayors have had bigger problems. Political allies of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Koch </PERSON> have committed suicide or gone to prison. <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Antonio </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cisneros </PERSON> admitted a close personal relationship with a woman not his wife. <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Coleman </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> has been slapped with a paternity suit by a former city employee. But for <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, probably the blandest of big-city mayors, it's a major embarrassment For politically dull <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> it's a rare taste of a scandal at the very top. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> has scrambled to defuse the controversy by placing his investments _ which range from an estimated $ 101,000 to $ 1 million _ in a blind trust. He has established an ethics panel _ which announced Monday it wo n't investigate <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> and will instead rewrite the city ethics code to restore public trust in city government. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> also has retained lawyers from <LOCATION> Manatt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Phelps </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Rothenberg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, a law firm of <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> political insiders that is handling the ethics defense of House Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>. He is refusing comment until a city investigation is completed. But allegations surface daily. On Tuesday, the <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Examiner </ORGANIZATION> reported that <ORGANIZATION> Far </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> East </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> was allowed to hold $ 600,000 in city money for three months in 1987 without paying interest. It said the account was set up by <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. Two months after the situation was discovered, <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> started earning $ 18,000 a year as a consultant to the bank. He has since returned the money, saying he was unaware <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> had business ties with the city. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, the city's first black mayor, won a fifth term April 11, barely escaping a runoff with challenger <PERSON> Nate </PERSON> <PERSON> Holden </PERSON> and drawing the lowest turnout in decades. `` Unquestionably the issues that have been raised over the course of the last three weeks have raised some doubts in the minds of some people,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. Supporters predict, however, he will survive the controversy. `` He's a super-quality guy. He has never done anything the least bit questionable on anything,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Riordan </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coliseum </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> and a Republican who supports the Democratic <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>. `` He's so perfect that people want to knock him off his hill and find his imperfections,'' he added. <PERSON> Holden </PERSON>, who made headlines by buying back semi-automatic weapons from the public, said: `` I think the quicker we get to the bottom of this matter the better everything's going to be. Business at City Hall is stopped. It's at a standstill.'' In addition to examining <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s relationships with Far East and the African task force, investigators are focusing on <ORGANIZATION> Valley </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> was paid at least $ 71,000 to serve on its board while it did business with the city. He resigned the post the day after his election.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0103EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     05-03 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0329</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bionic Duo Win Battle of Sunday Movies</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s bionic reunion garnered some bionic ratings, outrunning <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s critically praised `` My Name is Bill W.'' and the first installment of CBS' two-part <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> saga. The Sunday showdown was the first big movie faceoff of the May sweeps, one of four months when network affiliates' local ratings are measured to determine advertising rates. According to <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Bionic Showdown: The Return of the Six Million Dollar Man and the Bionic Woman II'' ranked 11th among prime-time shows for the week, with a rating of 17.6 and a 28 share. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` My Name is Bill W.,'' the story of the founder of Alcoholics Anonymous, had a 15.2 and 24 and ranked 24th. `` Guts & amp; Glory: The Rise and Fall of <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'' got a 14.0 and a 23 share to rank 31st. The rating is a percentage of the nation's 90.4 million homes with television. The share is a percentage of sets in use. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne,'' even though a repeat, edged a new episode of <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Cosby Show'' for first place. `` Cosby'' had a slightly lower rating, but a higher share. That apparently was due to daylight-saving time's disadvantage for earlier shows. There are fewer viewers in front of the set at 8 p.m. EDT when `` Cosby'' is broadcast. `` Roseanne'' is on at 9 p.m. The rest of the top 10 last week were: `` Cheers'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` A Different World'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Murder, She Wrote'' CBS; `` Golden Girls'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` Dear John'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` L.A. Law'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>; `` The Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>; and `` Empty Nest'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> racked up its 45th weekly victory in a row, with an average rating of 13.7 to <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' 11.7 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 11.4. The `` CBS Evening News'' tied `` ABC World News Tonight'' in news ratings, each getting a 9.8 rating and 21 share. `` NBC Nightly News'' had an 8.7 rating and 19 share.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0104EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     05-03 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0700</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Year-to-date rankings not available.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of April 24-30. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, rating for the week, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.3 rating, 20.2 million homes. 2. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.2, 19.2 million homes. 3. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.8, 18.8 million homes. 4. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.0, 18.1 million homes. 5. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.6, 17.7 million homes. 6. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.7, 16.9 million homes. 7. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 7. `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 7. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 10. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.0 million homes. 11. `` Bionic Showdown'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.6, 15.9 million homes. 12. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.3, 15.6 million homes. 13. `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 14. `` Have Faith,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.4 million homes. 15. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 15.2 million homes. 16. `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 14.9 million homes. 17. `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 16.3, 14.7 million homes. 18. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.5 million homes. 19. `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 15.9, 14.4 million homes. 20. `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.3 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 21. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 23. `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.3. 24. `` CBS News Special: <PERSON> Lucille </PERSON> <PERSON> Ball </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.2. 24. `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 15.2. 24. `` My Name is <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> W.'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.2. 27. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 28. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 29. `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 30. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.1. 31. `` Guts & amp; Glory: The <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' Part 1, _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 14.0. 32. `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 13.8. 32. `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 34. `` Tough Guys'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 13.4. 35. `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.3. 36. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 37. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1. 37. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.1. 39. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 40. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.3. 41. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.2. 42. `` Nearly Departed,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 43. `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 44. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 45. `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.2. 46. `` NBC News Special: Black Athletes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 47. `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.8. 48. `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 49. `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 10.4. 49. `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 10.4. 49. `` <PERSON> Gideon </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 10.4. 52. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.0. 53. `` Diet America Challenge,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 54. `` Nick & amp; <PERSON> Hillary </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 55. `` One of the Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 55. `` Beauty and the Beast,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 57. `` Disney-MGM Studios Theme Park Grand Opening'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 57. `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.1. 59. `` 48 Hours: Lottery Fever,'' CBS, 9.0. 60. `` Garfield in Paradise,'' CBS, 8.9. 61. `` Koppell Report: Drugs,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.7. 62. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Road </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Raiders </ORGANIZATION>'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 8.5. 63. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 63. `` Miami Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 63. `` Heartland,'' CBS, 8.2. 66. `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.1. 67. `` <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawkes </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.4. 68. `` Dream Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.3. 69. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.1. 69. `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 71. `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.9. 72. `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 73. `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 73. `` Over the Edge,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 75. `` Living Large,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 76. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> Hour,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 76. `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 78. `` Heart and Soul,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 78. `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 80. `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.9. 81. `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 82. `` Code One,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.6. 83. `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.4. 84. `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RaceSchool     05-03 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Race School,0242</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pittsburgh School a Model Against Racism</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Educators hope a new program will make a middle school a model for race relations and improved academics. The restructured school _ to be called the <ORGANIZATION> Prospect </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multiracial </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multicultural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Multiethnic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION> _ is to offer programs to encourage students to respect other races and teach staff members how to instruct students of other races, officials said Tuesday. `` Perhaps it will improve race relations throughout the entire city,'' said Principal <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Pipkin </PERSON>. `` It will be the model where we develop programs, policies and practices for district-wide use,'' <ORGANIZATION> Pittsburgh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> said. Ms. <PERSON> Crawford </PERSON> said no new students or staff members would be added to the present <ORGANIZATION> Prospect </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in the city's <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> neighborhood. She said the new programs are to begin next fall. School Superintendent <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said the idea came from principals and consultants who studied city schools last fall. He said concerns about racism stemmed from occasional fights in schools and the disproportionate number of black students who are suspended or referred to special education classes. `` I would n't say it's at this point a serious problem, a crisis situation, but we do n't want it to get to that level,'' <PERSON> Wallace </PERSON> said. Of about 39,600 public school students in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, 52 percent are black and 48 percent are white, officials said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0106EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--MoneyRots     05-03 0167</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Money Rots,0170</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmer's Life Savings Rots Underground</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The old Chinese habit of shunning banks has caused an 82-year-old farmer to lose most of his life savings to mildew, an official newspaper reported today. When <PERSON> Zhang </PERSON> <PERSON> Dexiang </PERSON>, who had buried his life savings of about $ 1,200 in his courtyard five years ago, dug up the money recently he discovered it was moldy `` almost beyond recognition,'' the <ORGANIZATION> China </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reported. The farmer in northeastern <LOCATION> Liaoning </LOCATION> province was only able to salvage $ 400, which he exchanged for new bills at a local bank, it said. <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, which has a surplus of cash in its overheated economy, is suffering from a shortage of funds for investment because many people, fearing runaway inflation, traditionally refuse to put their money in the bank. Personal caches like <PERSON> Zhang </PERSON>'s account for an estimated $ 133 billion. The interest rate on one-year deposits was raised last year from 7.2 percent to 8.64 percent, but fails to keep pace with 36 percent inflation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0056EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--WelfareBlunder     05-03 0159</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Welfare Blunder,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Double-Stuffed Welfare Checks in the Mail</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LITTLE ROCK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Some of the state's poor opened their monthly benefit checks this week and got a surprise _ an extra check. But they ca n't cash in on the windfall because the extra checks belong to another recipient of the Aid to Families with Dependent Children program. The program sends out 23,000 checks totaling $ 4.5 million a month. The problem likely was caused by a mail-sorting machine at a company that has the contract for sorting mail and stuffing envelopes for the program, said <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitlock </PERSON>, who directs the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> division that administers the program. If the suction cups of the mail-sorting machine come down on computer holes on the checks, the suction picks up not only the intended check but also the one behind it, <PERSON> Whitlock </PERSON> said. The problem has surfaced in at least six counties, but may be more widespread, said <PERSON> Whitlock </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0048EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-StudentProtests 1stLd-Writethru a0797 05-03 0743</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Student Protests, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0797,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Students Across Nation Protest Budget Cuts, Concert Bans, Coca-Cola</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to UPDATE with Cuomo vetoing tuition increase;
SUBS grafs 8-10, `New York ...,' with 4 grafs to ADD details on veto, edit
for transition; picks up 11th graf, ``At Mount ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DOUGLAS J. ROWE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Student protests from <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> took aim Tuesday at proposed budget cuts, tuition increases and union recognition, and student pressure at a prestigious college led to a ban on <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> products. In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, thousands of protesting <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students skipped classes and marched through lower <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> as a deadline approached on a state spending bill that would reduce money for higher education and force a tuition increase. Hours later, Gov. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON> vetoed the tuition hike. In <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hadley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Mount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holyoke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> administrators, under pressure from students to boycott Coca-Cola products because of the company's ties to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, announced a monthlong ban of the company's soft drinks. In the central <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> town of <LOCATION> Granby </LOCATION>, nearly 400 students walked out of high school and into a heavy rain to protest budget cuts the principal says could cost the school at least three teachers and several programs. In <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, students and others who met to discuss a decision to ban a rap music concert Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> were released without bond Tuesday after a hearing on felony trespassing charges. Twenty-seven people, including students from several <ORGANIZATION> Atlanta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> colleges and some non-students, were arrested Monday for refusing to leave a student center, said <PERSON> Cynthia </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Morris </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman. At the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, teaching and research assistants on Wednesday were to begin a two-day walkout and picket the four major campus entrances to protest the school's refusal to recognize their union In <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, about 4,000 students stepped up protests that began last week. Placard-carrying, chanting students from the university system assembled in front of the World Trade Center, where <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office is located. They blocked traffic for several hours, then paraded through the streets past City Hall to the <LOCATION> Wall </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION> financial district. `` It's not just a matter of this tuition hike. If we let them go, it will be more,'' said <PERSON> Armando </PERSON> <PERSON> Howard </PERSON>, a 29-year-old physics student at <ORGANIZATION> Hunter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION>. `` It will cut out the opportunity for people to rise.'' <PERSON> Cuomo </PERSON>, who had until midnight to sign or veto the tuition increase measure, had given no indication what his decision would be. But one hour before the deadline, it was announced he had vetoed the legislation, saying university officials had n't proven the need for the extra money. At <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Holyoke </LOCATION>, officials outlined immediate steps to replace <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> products with beverages from companies with little or no business interest in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. The announcement came in a one-page release that gave no explanation for the move. Students at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Holyoke </LOCATION> and several other colleges in western <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> have pressed administrators for two months to remove <ORGANIZATION> Coca-Cola </ORGANIZATION> products because, they say, the company is reaping profits that benefit racially segregated <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. `` I think it's a monumental step. I think it shows some responsibility on the part of the adminstration in terms of listening to students,'' said <PERSON> Kuhusu </PERSON> <PERSON> Wanzu </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Coke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, which organized the campus boycotts. In <LOCATION> Granby </LOCATION>, students who comprise virtually the entire population of the little school stood for 45 minutes in heavy rain before returning to class, said Principal <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Cullinan </PERSON>. `` The students felt this was the only way they could get their message across in a way that people would notice,'' the principal of the Granby Junior-Senior High said. At <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, neither the 3,200-member Association of Graduate Student Employees nor university officials would predict how many assistants would join the walkout. `` So far, our indications are that this could be more symbolic than a significant disruption,'' said university spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Debley </PERSON>. The dispute is over the university's view that the assistants' work can not be considered employment because it is so intertwined with educational experience, said <PERSON> Debley </PERSON> Assistants receive annual stipends from the university or research institutions averaging about $ 10,000. The association has been seeking recognition since 1983 as a union, but the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Employement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> recently ruled students do not have to be considered employees for the purposes of collective bargaining. The association is appealing the decision.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0051EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ComicBurnout Bjt   05-03 0502</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Comic Burnout, Bjt,0516</SECOND>
<HEAD>Breathed Latest To Take A Deep Breath</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Say bye-bye to <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> The </PERSON> <PERSON> Cat </PERSON>, the drug-addled feline who's smooched <PERSON> Jeane </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON> and swapped brains with <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> and the other residents of `` Bloom County'' are soon to be history, the latest victims of funny-page flameout. Cartoonist <PERSON> Berke </PERSON> Breathed pulled the plug on the Pulitzer Prize-winning `` Bloom County'' earlier this week, becoming the third comic-page fixture to leave fans hanging in recent years. But while <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> and <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> put their characters on vacation when cartooning became a grind, Breathed opted to off his. `` A good comic strip is no more eternal than a ripe melon. The ugly truth is that in most cases, comics age less gracefully than their creators. ` Bloom County' is retiring before the stretch marks show,'' Breathed said in explaining his decision. Readers of nearly 800 newspapers now will learn to live without big-beaked penguin Opus, his buddy <PERSON> Milo </PERSON> and motley party animal Bill The Cat; no longer will their lives intersect those of <PERSON> Kirkpatrick </PERSON>, <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> or <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> _ three public figures frequently skewered by Breathed. But such bad news is becoming all too common for the discerning comic reader, who in the recent years has lost <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>'s `` The Far Side'' and <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON>'s `` Doonesbury'' for extended periods while their creators escaped the day-to-day drudgery. `` I need a breather. Investigative cartooning is a young man's game,'' said <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> in announcing his hiatus from January 1983 to September 1984 _ a move that was questioned by veteran cartoonists such as <PERSON> Milton </PERSON> <PERSON> Caniff </PERSON> of `` Steve Canyon. `` Another guy is waiting in the wings, and once you're out you often ca n't get back in _ the space is filled,'' said <PERSON> Caniff </PERSON>, who has since died. Similarly, <PERSON> Larson </PERSON>'s syndicate editor, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Salem </PERSON>, explained the cartoonist `` felt he needed to get away from the deadline situation for a while so he could try to regenerate his cells.'' `` The Far Side'' is due back in 1990. While <PERSON> Trudeau </PERSON> and <PERSON> Larson </PERSON> took breathers to escape burnout, Breathed will resume his career with an entirely new Sundays-only strip. Others in the business say they understand his decision; penning a daily strip is anything but a million laughs for its creator. `` It's like pedaling a bicycle above a rotating blade, knowing that if you stop you'll fall and get cut up,'' said `` Peanuts'' cartoonist <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schulz </PERSON>, whose strip is in its fourth decade. `` You ca n't plan like a novelist, where you have three or four years to work,'' said <PERSON> Schulz </PERSON>. `` A cartoonist does n't have time to stop. It's go, go, go continuously.'' Breathed's strip says sayonara Aug. 6, although there is hope that one resident of `` Bloom County'' _ nobody's saying which one _ may survive its doomsday. The cartoonist's new characters will not resemble the old ones `` with maybe one exception,'' said <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON>, general manager and editorial director of <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, which syndicates the strip. Opus, anyone?
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0017EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GoldTax 1stLd-Writethu a0769 05-03 0354</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gold Tax, 1st Ld-Writethu, a0769,0359</SECOND>
<HEAD>Nevadans Vote on $52 Million Tax, State Bond Debt Limit</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 2 grafs to UPDATE with gold tax passing; minor editing
elsewhere to conform.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nevadans voted 3-1 Tuesday to approve a $ 52 million mining tax hike, but balloting was close on a plan to double the money <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> can borrow for new state construction. With 25 percent of 609 precincts counted, the mining tax proposal was favored 26,692-7 ,966 The vote on the construction measure was 18,363 for and 17,051 against. Election officials around the state predicted low voter turnouts, ranging from 30 to 40 percent of the more than 383,000 people eligible to vote. `` It's nothing great but it's steady,'' <ORGANIZATION> Carson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> Clerk-Recorder <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover </PERSON> said of early voter turnout, which he estimated at about 30 percent. Recent polls indicated the mining tax would win approval. Gov. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> and key lawmakers warned that without approval of the plan, the state would face fiscal chaos. Had the measure lost, officials said, the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> would be in session an extra month slashing budgets and raising taxes to make up for the loss of the anticipated mining tax revenues, expected to be $ 52 million over a two-year period. The law would allow the state to impose a 5 percent tax on the net proceeds of mines. The ballot question was the result of an agreement struck during the 1987 Legislature between the mining industry, lawmakers and then-Gov. <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Bryan </PERSON>. The other question on the ballot would double the money <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> can borrow for new state construction. The governor's proposed budget includes money generated by state bond sales for new prison and university construction projects. Officials have argued that without doubling the constitutional limit on bond debt to 2 percent of the assessed value of all taxable land, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> will have to pay cash for such projects. But opponents argue that while <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> needs the bond money, lawmakers who wrote supporting and opposing arguments for the proposal intentionally neglected to mention that the state must repay new bond sales through higher property taxes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-TankerSpill     05-03 0673</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tanker Spill,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dramatic Evidence of Wildlife Damage In Wake Of Spill</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Spill-Protests, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PAUL JENKINS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALDEZ, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thousands of dead birds, snared in a giant glob of sticky oil, line a beach 300 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, victims of the spreading crude that has devastated <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s coast for weeks. While enviromentalists, government and <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> officials trade barbs over blame, the oil drifts inexorably, fouling the shoreline and leaving dead, dying or dirtied birds, fish, otters, seals and sea lions. Even <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s lumbering, powerful brown bears have been seen prowling on oil-caked beaches. The oil is selective: It leap-frogs large stretches of coast, then hits others with contamination ranging from a light film to ankle-deep goo. `` We landed along a wide tidal basin, about six miles of beach,'' said <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Bane </PERSON>, superintendent of Katmai National Park. `` We found oil debris in large quantities throughout the tidal zone. We saw 2,000 to 3,000 dead birds. ... You ca n't really tell what they are. They're one big blob of oil.'' Since March 24, when the tanker <PERSON> Exxon </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> smashed into <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> and leaked 10.1 million gallons of crude through its shattered hull, the reports of destroyed wildlife have multiplied steadily. The spill has reached <LOCATION> Chignik </LOCATION>, 525 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION>, and residents there are fearful the oil may interfere with their salmon season, which begins next week. `` What we found, say in every 100-foot distance, was four to eight dead murres on the average,'' <PERSON> Bane </PERSON> said of the sea birds. `` We also saw fresh bear tracks going back into the impacted areas. There was evidence of foxes and other scavengers. We observed one bear _ a sow and three yearlings _ that was in the contaminated area, feeding on dead birds. ... We saw eagles carrying oil-covered birds. We saw one eagle so coated in oil that it could n't fly.'' One state scientist said wind-whipped oil `` mousse'' was pounded into a beach by wave action and buried a yard below the surface. Another reported seeing otters surrounded by floating oil. Late Monday, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> offered a revised plan to clean up 364 miles of tainted coastline by September, but environmentalists and <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Adm. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, the federal government's top official monitoring the spill, immediately criticized it as inadequate. <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelso </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>'s commissioner of environmental conservation, said the proposal was `` a few pages of wishful thinking ... -LRB- that -RRB- makes it appear as though cleaning those areas is little more than a Sunday stroll on the beach.'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON>, who must approve the plan before it can go into effect, called <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s strategy `` very thin.'' <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> briefly toured part of the spill area Tuesday, visiting the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Juneau </ORGANIZATION>, the Coast <PERSON> Gaurd </PERSON>'s command ship for the cleanup Today, <PERSON> Yost </PERSON> was scheduled to take <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Transportation Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> on an inspection of the spill zone. At a speech Tuesday in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> called the spill `` the most significant environmental disaster this nation has ever faced.'' On Thursday, he meets with Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, who is expected in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> after a 12-day tour of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> also faced a day of boycott Tuesday, as groups around the country urged consumers to stop buying <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> products. Consumer activist <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Nader </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> `` should not be allowed to forget'' the spill and that a boycott would send the oil giant a message. <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Surette </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Bay </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gasoline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retailers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Billerica </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, said it was too early to assess the boycott's impact. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> said 10,000 of its 7 million credit cards have been cut up and returned since the spill. In <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, 400 chanting and sign-waving protesters rallied in front of <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> headquarters, calling for a boycott. The Exxon Valdez is undergoing preliminary repairs in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON> and is to be towed next month to <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, home of the only drydock on the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> capable of handling the 987-foot ship.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890503-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-03-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names     05-03 0919</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0953</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names In The News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SIMI VALLEY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pop superstar <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> donned a disguise to do a little shopping and all it managed to do was attract attention. Police were called to a jewelry store after employees reported a suspicious person was casing the joint. The suspicious person turned out to be the Grammy Award-winning singer wearing a wig, fake mustache, false teeth and eyelashes. <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> and an unidentified 12-year-old boy had gone into the store Monday to look at rings. `` I asked him ` Why are you wearing a false mustache?''' said H.N. <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, a security guard for the Sycamore Plaza shopping center. `` He said ` I have to _ I'm in disguise _ I'm <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>.' When he told me this, my first thought was this guy had gotten off the elevator between floors.'' Police Sgt. <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Tacke </PERSON> and Officer <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Weeks </PERSON> said they questioned <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>, and asked him to remove his disguise and show his identification. `` He told the police he has to wear a disguise when he goes shopping or he would be mobbed by the crowds,'' <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BATON ROUGE, La. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The voices of the late Gov. Earl Long and lawmakers from three decades ago reverberated through the Capitol _ courtesy of actor <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> and company. The cast and crew of the movie `` Blaze'' _ a portrayal of <PERSON> Long </PERSON>'s relationship with stripper <PERSON> Blaze </PERSON> <PERSON> Starr </PERSON> during the late 1950s _ took over the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> chamber shortly after lawmakers recessed at midnight Monday Although the chamber was sealed off to visitors, <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> was heard all over the Capitol through the House sound system. Most of the day was spent on a scene in which Long, portrayed by <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>, made an uninvited appearance on the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> floor and demanded the microphone to discuss black voting rights.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SEVILLE, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
