<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0004EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BulgerProbe     04-01 0390</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bulger Probe,0399</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Attorney Declines to Prosecute Senate President on Corruption
Charges</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER B. DALY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>'s top federal prosecutor announced Friday he would not file criminal charges against <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> after a 2 -LCB- - year investigation, but he hinted broadly that corruption persists in <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> Outgoing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jeremiah </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON>, as one of his last official acts, told a crowded news conference that he had decided not to indict <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> or his associate, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> attorney <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Finnerty </PERSON>, who was accused of extortion in a development project. `` There is simply not sufficient evidence to ask a grand jury to indict either of these two individuals for violation of the federal extortion statute or the federal tax laws,'' <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> said. After a two-month review of a 2 -LCB- - year-long federal investigation, <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> said the final decision was `` not a close call'' based on the admissible evidence in the exhaustively researched case The review had been ordered by <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>. But in reply to reporters' questions, <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> indicated his personal belief that the development business is rife with tactics that are questionable, although not indictable. `` Power-brokering is not necessarily a federal crime,'' he said. At another point, <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> said the tactics involve `` influence-peddling.'' The decision by <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> helps lift a cloud of suspicion from <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON>, one of the state's most powerful politicians, who was rocked by allegations made by <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> landlord and developer <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> in a civil suit. In a civil suit filed in <ORGANIZATION> Suffolk </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> charged that <PERSON> Finnerty </PERSON>, a long-time associate and law partner of <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON>, extorted $ 500,000 from him by suggesting that he could hamper governmental approval of an office building development in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> unless he was cut in on the deal. <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> accused <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> of benefiting from the pay-off. <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> and <PERSON> Finnerty </PERSON> denounced those allegations, but <PERSON> Bulger </PERSON> has largely refrained from defending himself in public. An aide said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> president would make no comment on the prosecutor's decision not to press charges <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, who pleaded guilty in 1986 to bribing a City Hall official to expedite another of his projects, was apparently the government's key witness in the case. <PERSON> O'Sullivan </PERSON> said <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> may have sincerely believed <PERSON> Finnerty </PERSON> was trying to extort him, but the prosecutor said the criminal issue was <PERSON> Finnerty </PERSON>'s actions _ not <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s perceptions.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0142EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CropAcreage     04-01 0524</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Crop Acreage,550</SECOND>
<HEAD>Farmers Plan to Grow More Corn, Soybeans, Most Other Crops</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> survey shows that farmers intend to boost corn plantings this spring, with easier federal curbs and higher market prices helping them bounce back from last year's drought. The survey, announced on Friday, showed that farmers intend to plant 73.3 million acres to corn, up 8 percent from last year. Soybean plantings are expected to rise 5 percent from 1988 to 61.7 million acres. Officials said the report was based on an annual <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> survey of about 65,000 farmers in early March. Increases from last year were also indicated for grain sorghum, wheat _ including winter, durum and other spring varieties _ tobacco, dry edible beans and sweet potatoes. Farmers indicated they would plant fewer acres this year of oats, hay, cotton, rice and peanuts. If farmers follow through with their plans, the corn acreage would be the most since 76.7 million acres were planted for the 1986 crop. In 1985, plantings reached 83.4 million acres. The planted corn acreage dropped to 60.2 million acres in 1983, another year of severe drought. Last year, of the 67.6 million acres planted, 58.1 million were harvested for grain, yielding 4.92 billion bushels, down 30 percent from the 1987 crop. Average yields dropped to 84.6 bushels per acre from a record of 119.4 bushels in 1987. There was no indication of 1988 production in the report. Winter wheat output will be indicated by the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> for the first time on May 11 and corn figures in August, along with soybeans, cotton and other spring-planted crops. Total wheat plantings for this year's harvest was indicated at 74.3 million acres, up by more than 13 percent from last year. Winter wheat was reported at 54.7 million acres, up 12 per cent; durum, 3.86 million, up 16 percent; and other spring-planted wheat, 15.7 million acres, up 17 percent. Officials cautioned that the actual acreage planted by farmers this spring `` may vary from intentions because of the effects of weather, availability of production inputs, changes in market conditions prior to planting'' and the impact of the <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> report itself. With production cut by last year's drought, market prices of grains and soybeans rose sharply. The <ORGANIZATION> USDA </ORGANIZATION> also relaxed acreage-reduction requirements under wheat and feed grains programs for 1989. Preliminary price figures for March showed on Thursday that the average farm price of wheat was $ 4.16 per bushel, up from $ 2.74 a year ago. Corn was reported at $ 2.61 against $ 1.86 in March 1988, and soybeans were $ 7.57 per bushel, compared with $ 6.05 a year earlier. Other crops included in the survey report: _ Cotton plantings, 11 million acres, down 12 percent from 1988 _ Sorghum, 11.8 million acres, up 14 percent _ Barley, 9.62 million acres, down 1 percent _ Oats, 13.2 million acres, down 5 percent _ Hay, 63.1 million acres, down 4 percent _ Rice, 2.86 million acres, down 2 percent _ Peanuts, 1.64 million acres, down 1 percent _ Tobacco, 713,000 acres, up 13 percent _ Dry edible beans, 1.67 million acres, up 11 percent _ Sweet potatoes, 94,000 acres, up 2 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0118EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial Bjt   04-01 0574</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial, Bjt,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reagan Won't Testify When North Puts on Defense</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former White House aide <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s defense that he carried out administration orders by covering up his work for the Nicaraguan Contras was crippled when a federal judge refused to compel former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to testify In denying a request to call <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as a defense witness in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION>'s trial, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said Friday he could n't find any evidence that the former president authorized <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s activities. `` The trial record presently contains no proof that defendant <PERSON> North </PERSON> ever received any authorization from President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> to engage in the illegal conduct alleged, either directly or indirectly, orally or in writing,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> wrote in a five-page order. `` Nothing there even remotely supports an authorization claim,'' <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> where he now lives, said Friday he had been determined to fight any attempts to force him to testify. `` I made up my mind I was n't going,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told KESQ-TV. `` I think it would have set a precedent that the next president does n't have a right to impose on other presidents No president has ever been subpoenaed.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> would have been the first former president to be compelled to testify in a criminal proceeding concerning his conduct while in office had <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> agreed to make him appear. The defense is scheduled to begin presenting its case Monday, the seventh week of North's trial. Defense attorney <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> refused to identify the first witness. The prosecution had put on 29 witnesses, and on Friday the judge denied a defense motion to dismiss remaining counts against <PERSON> North </PERSON>. The defense argues that <PERSON> North </PERSON> was simply following <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s orders when he lied to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 and 1986 about the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>'s involvement in helping the Nicaraguan Contras North's attorneys had subpoenaed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> so they could ask him what he knew about the <ORGANIZATION> NSC </ORGANIZATION>'s role in raising money for the Contras at a time <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had barred <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military assistance to the rebels. The 12-count indictment against <PERSON> North </PERSON> accuses him of obstructing <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and making false statements in connection with letters he drafted and a meeting with <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> intelligence committee members. The judge said he reached his decision about <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s testimony after studying the trial record, thousands of pages of classified and unclassified documents, portions of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s personal diaries and written answers <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> provided to the grand jury. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said no presidential privilege prevented him from ordering the former president to testify, but the defense failed to prove <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s testimony was crucial to provide North a fair trial. <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Olson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s personal attorney, said he was pleased with the order. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> declined comment. The <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> had opposed <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s court appearance on the grounds it could have opened the door for questioning about sensitive national security matters. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> acknowledged there is `` understandable public interest'' in what <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> `` may have known or may have done.'' But he said <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s trial does not involve such a broad inquiry. He noted that three conspiracy charges against <PERSON> North </PERSON> involving presidential matters had been dropped. North also is accused of illegally accepting a $ 13,800 security system at his home from co-defendant <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, converting to his own use at least $ 4,300 in travelers checks from <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> leader <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Calero </PERSON> and conspiring to defraud the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> of tax revenue in connection with charitable contributions supporting the Contras.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0117EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AIDS-AZT Bjt   04-01 0616</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AIDS-AZT, Bjt,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Extends AZT Program for Six Months</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is diverting $ 5 million from AIDS research, prevention and education programs so states can continue providing the costly drug AZT to AIDS patients who can not afford it. <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said the action Friday, hours before the federal AZT program expired, was in response to a request from Sen. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., and other senators But <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said that while he agreed with the `` compassionate purpose'' of the transfer, `` a series of ` one-time' appropriations is not the most desirable way to address the issue of support for purchase'' of AIDS drugs. The funds, which <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said are being diverted from AIDS research, prevention and education, should continue the program for six months. The administration says federal support for AIDS research, prevention and treatment will exceed $ 2.1 billion this fiscal year, which ends Sept. 30. Nearly 7,000 of the estimated 30,000 AIDS victims using AZT are receiving the drug under the program, created by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1987 and extended for six months last September. The drug, which has been shown to extend the lives of many AIDS patients, costs about $ 8,000 a year when taken at full dosage. It is currently the only drug approved by the government to treat acquired immune deficiency syndrome. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, who spearheaded the drive to continue the temporary grants for state AZT programs, commended <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration `` for recognizing the urgency of the situation and moving so quickly to avert a gap in this lifesaving program.'' <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> had already run out of federal funds allocated to them under the program and <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> were due to run out Friday, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION>, an AIDS patient advocacy group. Programs in other states _ including <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, which account for about one-third of all those in the program _ were due to run out of federal funds by the end of June. Other states have enough money to last through August. <PERSON> Carlton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Campaign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fund </ORGANIZATION> said that, `` while we do n't want to see the money come from already existing AIDS efforts, we believe the financial crisis faced by so many people with AIDS is urgent enough to warrant such measures.'' <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> had tried to get a bill to extend the program through September approved in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> two weeks ago, before lawmakers left for the Easter recess, but the measure was blocked in a parliamentary move. In a letter Tuesday, <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, Sen. <PERSON> Orrin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatch </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Utah </LOCATION>, and 11 other senators called on <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> to transfer $ 5 million in AIDS funds to the AZT program. They said <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> had been authorized by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in September to redirect $ 15 million to the program, but had provided only $ 10 million. They said <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> had intended that the entire amount be redirected. When <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> agreed to extend the program last September, giving final approval only hours before the program was to expire, the manufacturer of AZT, <ORGANIZATION> Burroughs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wellcome </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, agreed to provide $ 5 million worth of the drug free. <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> plans to introduce legislation this year that would address the issue of care for AIDS patients and `` end the haphazard Band-Aid approach to provision'' of drugs such as AZT to patients, a <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON> aide said. Medicaid covers about 40 percent of people with AIDS and <ORGANIZATION> Medicare </ORGANIZATION> covers about 3 percent, but many low-income people with AIDS do n't qualify for either program, according to the Human Rights Campaign Fund. Also, many private health insurance plans do n't cover the drug or do n't cover its entire cost, the group said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FCC-Minorities     04-01 0528</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-FCC-Minorities,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Minority-Preference Rules Held Unconstitutional</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAY ARNOLD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> is being forced to review its policy of favoring minorities in the sale of `` distressed'' radio and TV stations because a court says the program is unconstitutional. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s 1978 `` distress sale'' rules, which allow quick sales at reduced rates of defunct or disenfranchised stations to blacks, Hispanics and other minorities, violate the equal protection provisions of the Fifth Amendment to the Constitution, a federal appeals court said Friday. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION>, in a 2-1 vote, overturned a purchase after a <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Conn. </LOCATION>, broadcaster said he should have been able to try to buy a station being offered in a distress sale. The ruling is at odds with <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, which in December 1987 refused _ with then-President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> concurring _ to allow the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> to consider changing the policy. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> had said it wanted to review the policy after the appeals court in 1986 rejected a sale based on the agency's `` comparative preference'' program of giving special treatment to women seeking FM station licenses But after <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> acted, the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> voted 3-0 in February 1988 to reaffirm the distress sale and female preference policies. It was not clear Friday how the commission would react to the latest remand. <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Diaz </PERSON> <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> said she strongly supported minority entry into broadcasting and that the court had struck down a program mandated by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. `` We are now between the proverbial rock and a hard place,'' she said. <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> also said he supported ensuring minority participation in broadcasting, but also that `` race alone should not control the licensing of broadcast stations.'' The Media Access Center, which filed a friend-of-the-court brief in the case, said the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> policy had worked well and the court `` made a mistake.'' <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartzman </PERSON>, the center's executive director, said `` we expect that <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> or the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> will reinstate the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION>'s policy. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> in 1984 denied <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shurberg </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Shurberg </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> a chance to compete for the purchase of WHCT-TV in <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> from the station's owner. The <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> also affirmed that a rival for the <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION> station, <ORGANIZATION> Astroline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Limited </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Partnership </ORGANIZATION>, was a minority enterprise and not a sham, as <PERSON> Shurberg </PERSON> contended. The appeals court Friday said the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> policy did not meet previous <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> tests of minority set-aside programs, including one that preferences be given to minorities only after race-neutral efforts to increase minority ownership had failed. `` The distress sale policy is not narrowly tailored to remedy past discrimination ... and it provides no procedures for ensuring that the policy's beneficiaries have actually suffered from the effects of past discrimination,'' Judge <PERSON> Laurence </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Silberman </PERSON> said in the majority opinion. Chief Judge <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wald </PERSON> dissented, saying the distress sale policy legally worked to ensure diversity in programming and ownership and that it was `` narrowly tailored to address the critical entry barriers to minority participation in media ownership while imposing only minimal burdens on innocent third parties.'' <PERSON> Shurberg </PERSON>, speaking by phone from <LOCATION> Hartford </LOCATION>, said he was `` delighted'' with the court's ruling.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gorbachev-Cuba     04-01 0879</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev-Cuba,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev's Vist to Cuba Could Signal Tougher Times For Castro</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAVANA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, on his first visit to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> on Sunday, may seek to defuse conflicts in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> and tell <PERSON> Fidel </PERSON> <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> is weary of financing <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> adventurism. Both Soviet and Western analysts interviewed in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> predict the reformist Soviet leader will be outwardly friendly toward the doctrinaire <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> president. But they expect <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to use the island as a platform for a major speech signaling his desire for a peaceful settlement of regional strife. President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has urged <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to use his influence with <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to further peace efforts. `` We would like to see the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> withdraw their resources and support in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Thursday. In a speech in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION>, Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> urged the Soviets to show `` signs of new thinking'' in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. He said the region was `` not a dumping ground'' for arms and failed ideologies of outsiders. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s four-day visit to <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>, to be preceded by a brief stop Sunday in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and followed by a visit to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> for talks with Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and <PERSON> Queen </PERSON> <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON>, had been set for December. After addressing the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and meeting <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, however, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> broke off his trip and flew home after the devastating earthquake in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Armenia </LOCATION>. `` We are not going to worsen our relations with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>,'' one Soviet specialist on Latin American affairs said of the visit to <LOCATION> Havana </LOCATION>. `` But <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is a very persuasive man and he will try to explain his intentions.'' The expert said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> will inform <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> that <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is no longer interested in financing class struggle and wars of national liberation abroad. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>, who just celebrated the 30th anniversary of the Cuban revolution, has supported armed struggle not only in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> but in <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as well. After years of backing leftist forces in <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> troops recently began a withdrawal from southern <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> as part of a Soviet-backed negotiated settlement between <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>. A senior Western analyst, who like the Soviet expert spoke on condition of anonymity, said <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> also is likely to tell <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> privately that the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION> ca n't afford to subsidize <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s economy indefinitely `` <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> has been protected from his mistakes by Soviet aid,'' the Western diplomat said, citing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> calculations that Soviet economic assistance account for perhaps 20 percent of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s gross national product. While <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s program of perestroika seeks to decentralize the communist-controlled economy, open markets and create financial incentives for improved production, <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s `` correction of errors'' campaign has clamped tighter government controls on production while shutting down peasants' markets and seeking to eradicate pay differences among workers. <PERSON> Castro </PERSON>'s determination to follow communist doctrine in the face of widespread evidence that his island's economy is in shambles prompted the Western analyst to observe, `` It's easy to talk about ideological purity when somebody else is paying for it.'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> sources say there already have been substantial reductions in <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> aid to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as evidenced in the marked decline in the purchase of sugar, which the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> buys from <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> at prices substantially higher than world market levels as a form of subsidy. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> has embarked on a major overhaul of its own ailing economy and has taken steps to extract itself from regional conflicts that have drained its resources while threatening to blow up into superpower confrontation. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> announced to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> on Dec. 7 his plan to pare a half-million men from the Soviet armed forces, withdraw thousands of tanks and other offensive military units from <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and ease tensions on the Chinese border by drawing down Soviet forces in <LOCATION> Mongolia </LOCATION>. The Kremlin completed its promised military withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> on Feb. 15. Three weeks later, it entered talks with the West in search of a negotiated reduction of all conventional forces in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. But Soviet intentions are less clear in <LOCATION> Centeral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, where the Sandinista government in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> continues to receive substantial Soviet military aid _ much of it channeled through <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> _ and Salvadoran rebels press their civil war with East bloc weaponry. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, meanwhile, has backed the Salvadoran government and Contra guerrillas in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, the Western diplomat noted, `` is one of the last remaining really hot regional conflicts outside the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> in which there's a strong superpower presence.'' In his address to the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> rejected `` the use or threat of force'' as an instrument of foreign policy, calling instead for new world order based on `` universal human consensus'' and respect for individual differences. `` As the world asserts its diversity,'' he said, `` attempts to look down on others and to teach them one's own brand of democracy become totally improper to say nothing of the fact that democratic values intended for export often very quickly lose their worth.'' Adhering to that policy, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is unlikely to lecture <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> on how to run his own country, but it remains to be seen how much the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is prepared to subsidize <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s longstanding deficit economy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0148EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AT&amp;TRates     04-01 0380</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AT&amp;T Rates,400</SECOND>
<HEAD>Long-Distance Rates Going Down</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Telephone users will be charged less for their interstate phone calls starting today as a result of rate reductions by <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telephone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Telegraph </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> said Friday its interstate long-distance rates will drop by $ 637.5 million annually, for a 1.9 percent overall reduction in its residential and small business prices <ORGANIZATION> MCI </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday it would cut its rates by $ 200 million a year starting today. The cuts represent a pass-along to customers of savings that result from a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> order that local companies cut the charges to the long-distance carriers for connecting with local phone systems. The local companies had proposed a $ 489 million cut, but the <ORGANIZATION> FCC </ORGANIZATION> ordered them last week to cut back by $ 705 million. But the savings also reflect a 30-cent increase in the charge that customers pay to help maintain the local telephone networks. That increase is effective today as well. And while most long-distance rates will go down under the new rates, prices for basic long-distance calls under 292 miles will increase an average of 4.5 percent. That's a change from <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T's proposed 4.7 percent price increase in February Also, daytime price cuts will be larger than evening price cuts, 4.2 percent and 0.7 percent, respectively; and night-weekend prices will drop 0.3 percent. Consumer groups had complained in February that <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T was not cutting prices significantly in the night and weekend long-distance time periods used by residential customers, while making big cuts in the highly competitive daytime arena. Under the new <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T rates: _ Basic long-distance prices will drop an average 1.9 percent _ Rates for <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WATS </ORGANIZATION> calls will drop an average 3.9 percent _ PRO WATS rates will drop an average 3.9 percent _ <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> T </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> MEGACOM </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> WATS </ORGANIZATION> rates will drop 1.1 percent, and <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T MEGACOM 800 prices will be 5.2 percent lower _ Reach Out <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> will drop an average 2.6 percent _ Basic <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T 800 service, down 0.9 percent; 800 Readyline service, down 3.3 percent Beginning July 1, <ORGANIZATION> AT </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; T 800 service will be billed according to distance, and there will be additional price reductions of 1.9 percent for 800 service and 2 percent for 800 Readyline. _ <ORGANIZATION> Software </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defined </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> prices will decline an average 6.1 percent
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lite     04-01 0191</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lite,0197</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHESWICK, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Farmer <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Panza </PERSON> does n't understand why local tax officials wo n't let him pay back taxes with a little piggy that has yet to go market. <PERSON> Panza </PERSON> said he'll try to pay the debt again Tuesday by offering his pig, Art, to the city. Earlier this week, <PERSON> Panza </PERSON> donned his overalls, placed Art in a pickup truck and parked it outside the office of District Magistrate <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Sabulsky </PERSON>. `` Them pigs are my net profit,'' he told the magistrate, insisting it's legal to pay with pork. A <LOCATION> Harmar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION> ordinance allows him to pay with his income, which happens to be pigs, he said. <PERSON> Sabulsky </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Panza </PERSON> to release his personal records so tax collectors could calculate how much he owes the township and the area school district. `` I've been fighting this for 13 years,'' <PERSON> Panza </PERSON> said. `` First of all, they're being a pig about all these taxes. You've got to pay property tax, school tax, township tax, and then they want to tax your net profit. There's nothing left for you.'' <PERSON> Sabulsky </PERSON> would n't say whether he'll accept the pig as payment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0149EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ColorClash     04-01 0247</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Color Clash,0257</SECOND>
<HEAD>Philosophers To Debate On The Existence Of Color</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANN ARBOR, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Roses are red, violets are blue. ... Or are they? Philosophers from around the country will gather in <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Arbor </PERSON> next week to discuss whether color is only in the eye of the beholder. The eighth annual colloquium in philosophy April 6-7 at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> will include presentations by professors from <LOCATION> Princeton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Syracuse </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION> universities, as well as <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. `` What's at issue is whether we have color in the world in the same way that we have shape in the world,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darwall </PERSON>, the philosophy department chairman at <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>. When it comes to color, philosophers tend to fall into two camps. Some argue that colors have an objective existence independent of our perception of them, <PERSON> Darwall </PERSON> said. Others argue that color is an illusion; that an object's characteristics cause it to reflect light a certain way, making people believe they are seeing a certain color, he added The question of color is recognized as a primary element in the debate between philosophers supporting a realistic outlook and their counterparts advocating an anti-realist point of view, <PERSON> Darwall </PERSON> said. `` It's a litmus test for different philosophical points of view,'' <PERSON> Darwall </PERSON> said of the color clash. Not much is expected to be resolved at the conference, <PERSON> Darwall </PERSON> said. `` It's not the case in philosophy that we get discoveries that are recognized instantly by all credible philosophers,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BeerBreaks     04-01 0242</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Beer Breaks,0248</SECOND>
<HEAD>Brewery Ends Employee Beer Breaks</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SMITHTON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Jones </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brewing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> has shut the tap on twice daily beer breaks for its employees. `` When you get 20 minutes and drink a couple beers, grab one here, grab one there, you're less than 100 percent,'' said <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> `` <PERSON> Gabby </PERSON><PERSON> '' </PERSON> <PERSON> Podlucky </PERSON>, who became president when his family bought the 82-year-old brewery in southwestern <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION> from actress <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> in June. `` It also goes along with what we believe should be responsible drinking. I could never face the family of one of our workers if they got hurt because of it,'' <PERSON> Podlucky </PERSON> said. Thirty-one of the brewery's 75 employees voted unanimously earlier this week to discontinue the practice, he said Friday. Workers enjoyed scheduled 20-minute breaks in the morning and afternoon, during which they could visit the brewery's taproom and drink up to two glasses of <PERSON> Stoney </PERSON>'s, <PERSON> Stoney </PERSON>'s Lite, <ORGANIZATION> Esquire </ORGANIZATION> Extra Dry or <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pitt </LOCATION> beer. They also were allowed to drink during lunch and after work. `` Essentially they were allowed to drink at any time,'' he said. Workers still will be welcome in the taproom after work and to compensate for the lack of beer breaks they have been offered their choice of uniforms provided by the company, two free cases of beer per month or the cash value of the two cases. <PERSON> Podlucky </PERSON> said the vote was in response to a consensus that the practice was no longer appropriate.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-Wash-Primary     04-01 0252</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wash-Primary,0259</SECOND>
<HEAD>Washington Lawmakers Approve Presidential Primary</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID AMMONS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Political Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OLYMPIA, Wash. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state on Friday became <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s 36th state with a presidential primary, setting up hopes for a regional set of primaries that would attract candidates to the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted 38 to 10 for an initiative submitted by the people after the <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION> had balked for years at the idea of eliminating the state's much-maligned caucus system of choosing national convention delegates. As drafted, the legislation would enable <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> to join <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> on the date <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> uses, the fourth Tuesday in May. Supporters of the measure said evangelist <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s victory in last spring's caucuses embarrassed the state into accepting a primary <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, usually seen as a moderate, politically progressive state, carried the nation's largest <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> delegation to the national GOP convention in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION> last August. The measure already had cleared the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by an even greater margin. Since Gov. <PERSON> Booth </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>'s signature was not required, Initiative 99 was delivered directly to the secretary of state minutes after passage. Champagne corks popped at an impromptu celebration staged by Secretary of State <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Munro </PERSON>, a long-term sponsor who exulted, `` It's finally over!'' The state will have a primary every presidential year, beginning in 1992. Oregon is toying with changes in its primary date, and there's no definite agreement for a four-state Super Tuesday, but the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> legislation gives the secretary of state flexibility to set a mutually agreeable date
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0155EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Soviet-Rights     04-01 0427</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Soviet-Rights,0441</SECOND>
<HEAD>Amnesty International Says Soviet Rights Abuses Continue</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAGGIE JACKSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soviet authorities have released hundreds of dissidents from confinement, but at least 100 remain in prisons, labor camps and psychiatric hospitals, <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> reported. The group released its latest Soviet human rights report on Friday, two days after the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>'s executive committee voted to readmit a Soviet organization. Many psychiatrists in that association were reported opposed to the decision, which must be approved by its general assembly later this year. However, <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> officials declined comment on that vote. The human rights organization said it had asked to speak with Soviet officials about the cases during the three-day visit of President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, which begins Wednesday. They said they had received no response. Amnesty also said in its report that <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> citizens still could be prosecuted for exercising free speech or religion. `` Although there has been much improvement and discussion of human rights in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, and the rhetoric of human rights will no doubt dominate next week's visit, the reality is that there are still serious human rights concerns there,'' said <PERSON> Marie </PERSON> <PERSON> Staunton </PERSON>, director of the group's British section. She and the coordinator for <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> affairs, <PERSON> Mick </PERSON> <PERSON> Venables </PERSON>, spoke to reporters about <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION>'s most recent briefing paper on Soviet human rights, dated March 1989. It says <ORGANIZATION> Amnesty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> knows of at least 100 prisoners known or thought to be dissidents, including 25 in psychiatric hospitals, but that 300 have been freed since 1987. Although some prisoners have been transferred to better facilities since 1987, those still in labor camps and prisons `` are kept on monotonous, meager rations with only rudimentary medical care, and have to meet excessively high work targets, often involving heavy physical labor,'' the report said. <PERSON> Venables </PERSON> added: `` There has been no major improvement in the condition of prisoners. Cruelty and degrading treatment still continues.'' Psychiatric patients are given unnecessary drugs, a treatment `` meted out as a form of intimidation,'' he said. Most of the 100 prisoners are people who tried to emigrate without permission or conscientious objectors to mandatory military service, <PERSON> Amnesty </PERSON> said. It said others are held for violating laws that restrict freedom of expression, religion, assembly and association. It welcomed elements of the new Soviet criminal code that recognize international rights agreements, abolish internal exile and reduce the number of capital crimes from 18 to six. A delegation from Amnesty is currently in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> for a nine-day visit that is scheduled to end Sunday.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0201EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-WashingtoninBrief     04-01 0615</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Washington in Brief,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Campaign May Have Accepted Illegal Money</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The 1988 presidential campaign of Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> may have unknowingly accepted up to $ 15,000 in illegal corporate contributions that were channeled through individuals. <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., issued a statement Friday saying the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> had contacted him last week asking assistance in an investigation and that he has ordered the filing of a complaint with the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Election </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> The complaint will ask the commission for advice on who should receive refunds of such contributions to the Dole for President Committee. `` As part of <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> for President's cooperation with a federal investigation into matters totally unrelated to my presidential campaign, it became apparent that DFP may have received tainted money,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` My campaign is not the subject of this investigation, nor did it have any knowledge of these allegations,'' he said. `` If true, I strongly condemn the illegal activities.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>FMac Changes Mortgage Rules</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mortgage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is changing some mortgage rules to help some homeowners to get rid of their private mortgage insurance earlier. When a home buyer puts less than 20 percent down on a house, the agency, known as <ORGANIZATION> Freddie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION>, requires the buyer to get mortgage insurance to guarantee mortgage payments. But the insurance fee boosts the monthly payment required until the homebuyer builds up equity representing 20 percent of the home's value. Previously, <ORGANIZATION> Freddie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mac </ORGANIZATION> required that a mortgage be held at least seven years before the insurance could be lifted even if the value of the home soars and the owner's equity rises above 80 percent. Under the change announced Friday, the insurance can be lifted in two to five years, depending on circumstances and provided that mortgage payments have been made on time.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>Picnic to Mark Opening of White House Horseshoe Pit</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> invited several governors and nine top players from the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Horseshoe </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pitchers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> to a picnic today to mark the official opening of the White House's horseshoe pit The president, an avid player, had a pit set up near the swimming pool on the west side of the Executive Mansion. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> invited Govs. <PERSON> Kay </PERSON> <PERSON> Orr </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Blanchard </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carroll </PERSON> <PERSON> Campbell </PERSON> of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Castle </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>; Guy Hunt of <LOCATION> Alabama </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Judd </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Madeleine </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>; <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaefer </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Cowper </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<NOTE>HUD Gives City One Week to Clean Up Housing</NOTE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> has given the <LOCATION> District </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Columbia </LOCATION> one week to improve its long-troubled public housing program or face the potential loss of federal home modernization funds. `` The <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION> government has purported to be getting a handle on public housing for nearly a decade,'' wrote <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> field manager <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON> in a recent letter sent to city officials. `` But sadly, the effort expended has been virtually to no avail. ... Concrete results are significantly overdue.'' Ms. <PERSON> White </PERSON>'s order set a Friday deadline for having the city speed up its repair schedule for vacant units. <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> can not deny payment of the city's operating subsidy, which was $ 28 million last year, because of poor performance. But <PERSON> White </PERSON> said her office reviews requests from the city to make recommendations to regional housing officials on whether to award modernization funds sought by the city. White's order sets deadlines for the district to meet several federal standards used to measure the proficiency of housing authorities. She cited the District for slow `` turnaround time'' in filling vacated units, ineffective maintenance, low financial reserves, excessive vacancies and slow rent collection.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0204EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-01 0819</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0851</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Melanie </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffith </PERSON> and her mother, <PERSON> Tippi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hedren </PERSON>, were tapped to emcee a star-studded fund-raiser today to benefit the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION>'s AIDS research unit. Also scheduled to take part in the two-hour revue were <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Caron </PERSON>, <PERSON> Cliff </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON>. The money will go to the university's AIDS research unit in <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. The county hospital plans to tear down the facility to expand its trauma center. `` The plans have been made to build a totally new building,'' said <PERSON> Gloria </PERSON> <PERSON> Danovtiz </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alliance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION>. The project needs about $ 5 million. Last year, the group's fund-raiser featuring <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> raised $ 150,000.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress <PERSON> Meryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Streep </PERSON>, who has criticized the use of the farm chemical Alar, declined an invitation to visit an apple processing plant to watch how the fruit is tested. The <ORGANIZATION> Natural </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resources </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> said Friday the actress was invited to tour <ORGANIZATION> Tree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Top </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>'s plant in <LOCATION> Selah </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Ms. <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> has served as a spokeswoman for the private environmental group's report warning that Alar-treated apples create an increased risk of cancer in children <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Bloom </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> NRDC </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> Tree </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Top </ORGANIZATION> that Ms. <PERSON> Streep </PERSON> would be unable to tour the plant because she starts filming a new movie on Sunday. The <ORGANIZATION> NRDC </ORGANIZATION> report on apples and chemicals has been disputed by the apple industry and several federal agencies have issued statements saying apples are safe to eat. But the report has hurt sales of apples and apple products.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>OXFORD, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Civil rights activist <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> says blacks have not learned to exercise their economic power to bring about social change. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON>, speaking Friday at <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said that if blacks in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> constituted a separate nation, `` we would be the fifth or sixth economic power in the world. We spend more in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> than all of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.'' Blacks buy 28 percent of the Cadillacs sold `` and do n't have the nerve to ask for 28 percent of the jobs'' making Cadillacs, he said. <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> also said that although blacks make up the largest block of Americans without cable television, `` we never demand that the networks cater to us.'' His speech was part of a weekend marking the 25th anniversary of a project that trained workers to go to <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> and register blacks to vote. The training took place at <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Women </ORGANIZATION>, now a part of <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. Two such workers were among three people killed in a shooting on which the current movie `` Mississippi Burning'' is based.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>COPENHAGEN, Denmark (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Danish parliament voted to boost state support to the film industry the day after <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> Director Bille August's `` Pelle the Conqueror'' was awarded an Oscar for best foreign language film. `` Pelle the Conqueror,'' the story of a boy and his father who move to the harsh conditions of a 19th-century Danish farm, won the Academy Award on Wednesday. `` Babette's Feast,'' by Danish director <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Axel </PERSON>, received an Oscar last year. Culture Minister <PERSON> Ole </PERSON> <PERSON> Vig </PERSON> <PERSON> Jensen </PERSON> praised August's achievement, saying the Oscar and <ORGANIZATION> Golden </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> awards for `` Pelle'' had put <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> `` on the map of world film history.'' Despite their success abroad, Danish feature films often get bad reviews and play to small audiences at home.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION>, famed for his bow ties, will have to _ horrors _ wear a clip on if <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION> fails to beat the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> in today's <ORGANIZATION> NCAA </ORGANIZATION> basketball semifinal. <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> has made a bet with Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>, and if <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> loses, <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> will wear a clip-on bow tie dotted with <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION>'s `` M'' logo. If <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> wins the game, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> will wear an Illini straight tie. To make things even more interesting, the senators also have added soda to the stakes, throwing in two cases of <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> Vernor's ginger ale and two cases of Illinois-bottled <ORGANIZATION> Orange </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Crush </ORGANIZATION>. `` I've never worn a clip on, and I'm confident I never will have to wear a clip on,'' <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> said. Retorted <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>: `` Senator <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> will make history in wearing a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> clip-on bow tie after the ` orange crush' is made into ` blue' slush Saturday night.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> is taking <LOCATION> Egyptian </LOCATION> President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> out to the ballgame. In an unusual windup to a day of diplomatic talks, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> will fly together by helicopter Monday night to <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION> for the season opener between the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sox </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> will throw out the first ball. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> is the first in a string of visitors to discuss prospects for peace in the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> will meet with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Thursday and <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON> will be at the White House on April 19.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Eastern Bjt   04-01 0593</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eastern, Bjt,0610</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trump Finally Poised to Take Controls of Eastern Shuttle</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCY GORDON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Real estate tycoon <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> is taking control of strike-torn <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' Northeast shuttle, and some union officials say the sale of the rest of the carrier is a foregone conclusion. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> announced late Friday that he had completed a restructured deal to buy the three-city shuttle for $ 365 million, the same price he agreed to pay in October in a tentative accord with <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s parent. But the final deal gives <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> four more <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 727s for a total of 21. Eastern's unions, which have crippled the airline by honoring a strike by its <ORGANIZATION> Machinists </ORGANIZATION> union since March 4, have made the purchase of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> a priority in their battle against <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>. Some union officials said Friday the shuttle deal and signs that a group led by former baseball Commissioner <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> V. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ueberroth </PERSON> might still try to buy the rest of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> could indicate the carrier's sale is inevitable. The unions long have claimed that <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> _ whom they revile as a union buster _ has been trying to strip Eastern of its assets and funnel them to sister company <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, a non-union carrier. Before and since Eastern filed for bankruptcy protection March 9, the unions vigorously have opposed any separate auctions of Eastern assets such as planes, airport gates and landing rights. The recent talks could indicate a sale is likely, and that it would be a single deal for the entire airline, minus the shuttle, the unions say. `` I believe that Eastern vis-a-vis <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> is now in a sale mode ... that's what we would favor,'' said <PERSON> Skip </PERSON> <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Line </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pilots </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. A used 727 fetches $ 4.5 million to $ 6 million, indicating <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> was getting $ 18 million to $ 24 million more in assets for the same price. `` I am delighted to complete this transaction and very much look forward to building an airline that provides superior service for all consumers,'' <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said Friday. The agreement still must be approved by the federal bankruptcy court in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, where Eastern is reorganizing under protection from creditors. The <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> said it hoped to close the deal within 60 days. `` This agreement proves that the value of <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s assets remains high and continues to be attractive to various parties,'' Eastern President <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakes </PERSON> said. The pilots' union, which has been highly critical of <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON>, also expressed approval of the deal. `` The money that Mr. <PERSON> Lorenzo </PERSON> gets for the shuttle has to come here, to <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> ... That's a positive,'' said <PERSON> Stokes </PERSON>. Before the strike, the shuttle serving <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> was <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s only profitable operation. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> had agreed to pay $ 365 million for the Eastern shuttle in October in a tentative accord with <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION>. But last week he sought to cut the price by a third because the continuing strike by <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION>'s machinists, supported by its pilots and flight attendants, had eroded the shuttle's value as <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> passengers started switching to the rival <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> shuttle. <ORGANIZATION> Texas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> countered by telling <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> it would look for other buyers, and <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, an aggressive Phoenix-based regional carrier, expressed interest. <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> said he still planned to recognize the Eastern unions as bargaining representatives for <ORGANIZATION> Trump </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shuttle </ORGANIZATION> employees, as in his October accord, and to negotiate separate labor agreements with the shuttle workers. `` We have absolutely great relations with all three unions,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0131EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Egypt-US     04-01 0471</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Egypt-US,0486</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mubarak Wants United States To Increase Pressure On Israel</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MAURICE GUINDI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAIRO, Egypt (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Buoyed by support from key <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders, President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> leaves for <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> today to tell <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials they must move quickly to persuade <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to talk to the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, Egyptian officials said. The four-day <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> visit, <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s seventh since taking office in 1981, follows six weeks of intensive diplomatic exchanges initiated by the Egyptian leader. The activity brought leaders from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> will meet with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on Monday. `` <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> is carrying to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> for the first time a unified Arab position for the achievement of <LOCATION> Arab-Israeli </LOCATION> peace,'' said a senior government official, speaking on condition of anonymity. `` This gives <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> greater credibility.'' The unified position was forged in <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s Egyptian talks during the past week with <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>'s King <PERSON> Hussein </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> and King Fahd of <LOCATION> Saudi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Arabia </LOCATION>. The official said <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> will argue a need for speedy movement by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to persuade <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to accept an international peace conference and negotiations with the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> fears it would be pressured into concessions as a result of such a conference, and it rejects <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON>'s group as terrorists. The conference, under <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> auspices, would group parties to the conflict, including the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>, and the permanent members of the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>: the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The Egyptian official also said <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and his Arab backers would like to see <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> use his influence with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to convene an international conference before the end of this year. <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Wisner </PERSON>, in prepared remarks for the local media on <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s visit, dampened hopes for quick breakthrough as a result of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> efforts. `` It will not be easy to arrive at quick results,'' the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> diplomat said. `` What we should do is build confidence to bring the parties to the negotiating table.'' He seemed to be referring to a desire by <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for reciprocal moves by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> to stop violence in the Israeli-occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stip </LOCATION>. A Palestinian uprising in those territories has killed more than 415 Palestinians and 18 Israelis since it began in December 1987. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> talks also will deal with <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic and military aid to <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and ways of easing <LOCATION> Cairo </LOCATION>'s foreign debt burden. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has held up $ 230 million in cash aid for <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> in 1988 and 1989, saying <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> failed to adopt `` significant'' economic reforms. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> says he agrees on the need for economic reforms but disagrees with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on the pace of such steps. He fears austerity measures might trigger street violence. <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION>'s foreign debt totals about $ 44 billion.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0211EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FourSlain     04-01 0246</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Four Slain,0253</SECOND>
<HEAD>Four Bodies Found Stuffed in Car In Norfolk, Va.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEAN McNAIR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The bodies of four young men were found stuffed in the a parked car in what police said was the city's worst murder case in 13 years Police called by an apartment building resident discovered one body Friday in the car's back seat with its sneaker-clad feet sticking out of the rear window, said Cpl. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, a police spokesman. A second body was found underneath the first victim, and two other corpses were found in the trunk of the silver <ORGANIZATION> Volvo </ORGANIZATION> with <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION> license plates, <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> said. The car was left in the building's parking lot, he said. The victims were black and in their late teens or early 20s, he said. They had yet to be identified, and police did not have suspects. `` There were signs of violence, blood,'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> said. A witness who asked not to be identified said stuffed teddy bears were piled around one victim in the back seat. Police said violent crime is unusual in the <LOCATION> Norview </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> neighborhood with frame cottages and ranch homes, but the parking lot is within blocks of the low-income Lakeland Apartments, a frequent destination for police. <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> said the crime was the city's worst mass murder since May 1976, when a 21-year-old man walked into a crowded downtown nightspot and opened fire, killing four people and wounding three before killing himself.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0216EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Mummy-Sentencing 1stLd-Writethru a0417 04-01 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Mummy-Sentencing, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0417,0341</SECOND>
<HEAD>Man Sentenced for Forgery in Mummy Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 5th graf, `It was...' to restore dropped words. Edits to
trim.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>GALESBURG, Ill. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A dentist has been sentenced to 30 months' probation for forgery in a bizarre case involving a dead man whose mummified remains were tended by his family for nine years. <LOCATION> Knox </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Judge <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Roberts </PERSON> opted for probation for <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON>, 57, who lived for two years with the family of the dead man, <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>. State's Attorney <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Kimbell </PERSON> had recommended a three-year prison term. <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON>, who has lost his license to practice dentistry, was convicted recently of witnessing a forgery of <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' signature, which was placed on a document by the widow, <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>. The judge noted at Thursday's hearing that Mrs. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> was sentenced to 24 months of probation after she pleaded guilty to two counts of forgery in the case last year. During the hearing, both sides recalled how <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' body was tended by his family and <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> as if he were still alive. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, a diabetic, died in 1979 after joining a holistic health cult and halting his daily insulin injections. In January 1988, authorities discovered his body in the <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> home. <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> lived at the home from summer 1986 until the body was discovered. <ORGANIZATION> Kimbell </ORGANIZATION> argued that <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> should be given a stiff sentence because he harmed Mrs. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>' two teen-age children by promoting the `` strange idea'' that <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> was alive as his mummified corpse remained in the home. <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> said he signed as a witness to the 1984 document that gave Mrs. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> her husband's power of attorney because she wanted to refinance her home. <PERSON> Kunce </PERSON> said his immediate plans are to return to <LOCATION> Corpus </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Christi </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, to live with his sister, and perhaps teach nutrition or practice dentistry if he can renew his license. `` I've got to get on with my life,'' he said. `` I think I'll start by going fishing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0217EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--OperaDeath     04-01 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Opera Death,0122</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stagehand Killed In Accident At Royal Opera House</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A cart carrying heavy scenery fell on a stagehand after a rehearsal at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Royal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, fatally injuring the man, management said. The wagon full of scenery was being moved across the stage Friday when it toppled over onto 31-year-old stage technician <PERSON> Greg </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballamy </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Ewen </PERSON> <PERSON> Balfour </PERSON>, opera house spokesman. He said <PERSON> Ballamy </PERSON> died soon afterward in <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. That evening's performance of <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Verdi </PERSON>'s `` <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlo </PERSON>'' was canceled in sympathy for the man's family. <PERSON> Balfour </PERSON> said it was the first fatality since the current opera house was completed in 1858. A management statement said there would be an inquiry into the accident.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GeorgeWashington     04-01 0240</FIRST>
<HEAD>George Washington's Ancestral Home Robbed</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thieves stole antiques worth more than $ 1.7 million from <LOCATION> Sulgrave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Manor </LOCATION>, the English ancestral home of <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, police said. <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, who lived seven generations before the first <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president, bought the property in <LOCATION> Sulgrave </LOCATION> <LOCATION> village </LOCATION>, 70 miles northwest of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, in 1539. Its manor house is now run as a museum and contains much memorabilia from early <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. The stolen items include a spoon, a chandelier, three clocks of the 17th and 18th centuries, and a rare Breeches Bible, police said Friday. The bible is named after a 1560 edition that called the fig-leaf coverings made by <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> and Eve `` breeches.'' Detective Inspector <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said burglars took the antiques, which he called `` irreplaceable,'' after breaking into the Tudor manor house through a second-floor window. He gave no day on which the burglary occurred. But <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Walpole </PERSON>, who runs the Thatched House Hotel opposite the manor, said he believes it happened Thursday night. The Sulgrave Manor house was completed in 1558, the year Queen <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> I </PERSON> came to the English throne. Descendants of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> family lived there for 120 years. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>'s great-grandfather, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>, left <LOCATION> Sulgrave </LOCATION> in 1657 and settled in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. The museum is owned by an Anglo-American trust. It has been open to the public since 1921, when it was established as a goodwill gesture between <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0235EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EmpireCampers Bjt   04-01 0545</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Empire Campers, Bjt,0561</SECOND>
<HEAD>Girl Scouts ``Camp Out'' Atop Empire State Building</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RAUL REYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It was n't exactly a country outing, but 57 Girl Scouts went on a camping trip very few people will ever top. They camped out Friday night on the 86th floor of the Empire State Building and even got a late night visit from movie monster King <PERSON> Kong </PERSON>, known for his climb up the landmark edifice when it was still the world's tallest. Although a cloudy evening obscured usually spectacular nighttime views of <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>, the girls did n't seem to mind as they played games, sang songs, pledged allegiance to the flag and recited the Girl Scout promise. And the girls, mostly from the city's boroughs of <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION>, were oblivious to the rainy, busy streets 1,050 feet below as they arranged sleeping bags and blankets for the night. Some people are bothered by ants and other bugs on camping excursions, but 9-year-old <PERSON> Lenata </PERSON> <PERSON> Bristow </PERSON> was unconcerned by the insectlike things she saw. `` I looked down and everything looked like bugs,'' she said as she looked out of an 80th-floor window before the girls went up to the 86th-floor observatory. <PERSON> Stephine </PERSON> <PERSON> Knight </PERSON>, 9, presented an urban perspective on the merits of sleeping high up in the 102-story building that would be lost on people whose idea of camping out is a bit more down to earth. `` Out in the country when we went one time, we could get lost,'' she said. `` It's nice here and it's a big place. It's exciting.'' The idea to camp out high in the Empire State Building was the Rev. <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Rafter </PERSON>'s. He's been the unofficial chaplain of the Empire State Building since the mid-1960s. The building opened in 1931. The nearest campgrounds for Girl Scouts, he said, are in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> and the city's <LOCATION> Staten </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> borough; so he approached the building's officials. They agreed to an annual November trip for Boy Scouts and a yearly March outing for the Girl Scouts. `` The idea is for the girls from different troops to make new friends and learn that whether they're black, white, green, blue or whatever, they're all Americans,'' <PERSON> Rafter </PERSON> said. The `` hike'' to the campsite consisted of a leisurely stroll around the lobby as <PERSON> Rafter </PERSON> led a tour of the first floor. But getting to the top of the campsite could be daunting, 9-year-old <PERSON> Shunte </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> pointed out. `` In the elevator, it felt like my stomach was dropping and my ears stopped up,'' she said. For those who might think the girls are being deprived of a true camping experience, troop leader <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Waszak </PERSON> was quick to point out the girls often camp outdoors in more sylvan settings. <PERSON> Waszak </PERSON> recalled how a freak snowstorm nearly buried the girls in their sleeping bags in <LOCATION> Brewster </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, in October 1987. She looked around the enclosed area on the 86th floor where the girls would sleep Friday and said: `` This is quite milder with no chance of being snowed in.'' But not everyone was ecstatic about spending the night at the building. <PERSON> Alice </PERSON> <PERSON> Crowley </PERSON>, 9, would have preferred a more natural environment. `` I'd rather be camping out in the countryside,'' she said. `` I think that would be more fun.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0310EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Mexico-US     04-01 0488</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Mexico-US,0507</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mexico Plans Major Anti-Drug Operation Along U.S. Border</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JAMES ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MEXICO CITY (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Mexican officials today plan to launch one of the largest crackdowns ever on drug trafficking along the 2,000-mile border from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Felipe </PERSON> <PERSON> Flores </PERSON>, spokesman for the federal Attorney General's Office, said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> will share intelligence information and <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> will deploy army troops, police reinforcements and extra drug agents for the project The operation will run from <LOCATION> Tijuana </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, all the way to <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, south of <LOCATION> Brownsville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in an interview Friday. `` It is possibly the largest of its kind. There are more arms, more vehicles, more personnel,'' he said. He gave few specifics. However, Deputy Attorney General <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Coello </PERSON> <PERSON> Trejo </PERSON>, who heads <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>'s anti-drug efforts, recently said a special narcotics interdiction group of 1,200 people would be ready by April. <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Jornada </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> newspaper, said at least a dozen federal helicopters and 30 airplanes have been sent to <PERSON> Hermosillo </PERSON>, the capital of <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION> state, for the project. The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> referred questions about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> participation to the <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Enforcement </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where officials were not available for comment. <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said the new program will be permanent. He said it is styled after Operation Alliance, a U.S.-Mexico effort begun in August 1986. Operation Alliance involved hundreds of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> federal agents and millions of dollars worth of surveillance equipment to detect drug-ferrying airplane flights across the border. <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Meese </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, who was the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney general at that time, called Operation Alliance `` the most widespread interdiction program on our land borders in law enforcement history.'' The new campaign `` is similar, but much bigger,'' <PERSON> Flores </PERSON> said. U.S.-Mexican relations have been strained by the flow of drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON>, who took office Dec. 1, promised to increase manpower and other resources to combat the drug trade. Drug trafficking and related violence along the Mexico-U.S. border have increased as the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> pressed its anti-drug efforts in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION>. Mexican authorities believe the torture-killings of nine people this week in a town across the border from <LOCATION> Douglas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, were drug-related. The mutilated bodies of two men and three women were found in a well, and four other bodies were found in a nearby septic tank on an abandoned ranch two miles west of <LOCATION> Agua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Rodolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Amaviezca </PERSON>, chief of the state police in <LOCATION> Agua </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Prieta </LOCATION>, said seven people were under arrest, including a Mexican federal customs agent. <ORGANIZATION> Agua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prieta </ORGANIZATION> has emerged as a major drug channel the past two years. Some police call it `` cocaine alley.'' <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Imparcial </ORGANIZATION>, a newspaper in <LOCATION> Sonora </LOCATION>'s capital of <PERSON> Hermosillo </PERSON>, reported two suspects in the killings told police the victims were slain in retaliation for the disappearance of 220 pounds of drugs. <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> newspapers said the drug was cocaine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0324EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Obit-Dupaya     04-01 0154</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Obit-Dupaya,0158</SECOND>
<HEAD>Congressman Dies Of Heart Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANILA, Philippines (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Dupaya </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Philippine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> and ally of President <PERSON> Corazon </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>, died today of heart attack in his northern home province of <LOCATION> Cagayan </LOCATION>, authorities said. He was 67. <PERSON> Dupaya </PERSON> was en route to the <LOCATION> Cagayan </LOCATION> airport to meet <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Sedfey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ordonez </PERSON> when he complained of chest pains, said <PERSON> Thelma </PERSON> <PERSON> Maceda </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesperson. He was rushed to the <LOCATION> Cagayan </LOCATION> hospital where he died of heart attack at 8:30 a.m., <PERSON> Maceda </PERSON> added. <LOCATION> Cagayan </LOCATION> is about 210 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Manila </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dupaya </PERSON> is a member of the Struggle of the Democratic Filipino party, the main political group supporting President <PERSON> Aquino </PERSON>. He served for two terms under former President <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' administration <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> fled to <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> where he is in exile in 1986. <PERSON> Dupaya </PERSON> is survived by his wife <PERSON> Teresa </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Cagayan </LOCATION> governor, and two sons and three daughters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0331EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Khrushchev     04-01 0118</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Khrushchev,0121</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soviet Newspaper Publishing Excerpts of Khrushchev's Memoirs</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The memoirs of former Soviet leader <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, published in the West after he was ousted in 1964, are being excerpted for the first time in the Soviet press. The weekly newspaper Argumenti i Fakti, or Arguments and Facts, began publishing the excerpts Friday. The article quoted <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> as saying his predecessor <PERSON> Josef </PERSON> <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> `` does not trust anybody, including himself.'' <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> exposed <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s crimes to the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leadership in a `` secret speech'' in 1956 that still has not been published in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>. After he was removed from power in October 1964, <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON> lived in obscurity outside <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> until his death in 1971.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0341EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-CentralAmerica Bjt   04-01 0614</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Central America, Bjt,0634</SECOND>
<HEAD>Foreign Ministers' Talks End Without Contra Agreement</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JUAN MALTES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The foreign ministers from five Central American countries broke off two days of talks after they were unable to agree on how to disband the army of U.S.-backed Nicaraguan rebels in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. However, the ministers said they will meet again in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> on April 13-14 to continue their negotiations. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> has pushed for quick disbanding of the rebels, most of whom live in border camps in neighboring <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. Deputy Foreign Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> told reporters that the diplomats could not `` arrive at an accord for demobilization of the Contras.'' The Central American presidents agreed Feb. 14 to come up with a plan by mid-May for disarming the rebels. They would either be repatriated with their families or relocated. In exchange, <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> said it would adopt domestic democratic reforms. The agreement took <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials by surprise. They have said the rebels should remain in place as an army to put pressure on the leftist Sandinista government of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> to make reforms. The foreign ministers disagreed. `` It is the collective responsibility of the five governments to look for paths to obtain the demobilization,'' Honduran Foreign Minister <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> told a news conference after talks ended. <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> has been a strong <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ally, but it has recently objected publicly to the presence of the rebels, known as Contras, on its territory. However, the foreign minister said his government did not have a specific plan for demobilization. `` What we have are ideas, reflections,'' he said. The foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> met in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jose </LOCATION> to lay groundwork for a regional summit at which their presidents are to decide how to disband the Contras. <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> <PERSON> Contreras </PERSON> said earlier Friday that the summit would be put off from May 15 to June 15 to allow <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s new president, <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON>, to take office. At the San Jose meetings, Nicaraguan Foreign Minister <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> D'Escoto </PERSON> also gave his colleagues a proposal for a regional fight against drug trafficking that would include <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> assistance. The foreign ministers said they will try to meet in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> April 11-12 to discuss the proposal. They also agreed to meet in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> in early May to prpare for the presidential summit. The exact dates of the second <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> meeting are to be decided later. Although no accords were reached, the foreign ministers said the talks were fruitful. `` If we did n't believe peace in <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> was possible, we would n't be fighting for it,'' Costa Rican Foreign Minister <PERSON> Rodrigo </PERSON> <PERSON> Madrigal </PERSON> <PERSON> Nieto </PERSON> said. The Contras fought the Nicaraguan government for eight years. However, the fighting has trailed off since early last year, when the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> cut off military aid to the rebels. President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> said Thursday that $ 45 million in non-military aid under consideration by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> should be used to disband the Contras. As now envisioned, the package would provide the Contras with $ 4.5 million a month through Feb. 28, 1990, four days after what <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> pledged will be free and democratic general elections. <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> says <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> would be violating regional peace accords by maintaining the Contras as a potential fighting force. The Contras and their families in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION> number 10,000 to 11,000. The ministers on Thursday formally approved deploying a small group of unarmed <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> military observers to monitor Central American border conflicts. <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> agreed to contribute to the force. Costa Rican President <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> said he asked <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> to send observers also. The <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> has made no decision on such a force.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890401-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-01-89 0502EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Afghanistan     04-01 0325</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Afghanistan,0333</SECOND>
<HEAD>22 Killed By Rocket Attack On Sikh Temple In Jalalabad</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By EARLEEN FISHER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KABUL, Afghanistan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
