<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0120EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BrokerageShooting     08-19 0452</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brokerage Shooting,0465</SECOND>
<HEAD>Settlement Reached in Post-Crash Shooting of Broker</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Attorneys said Friday they had reached a settlement of the wrongful death lawsuit filed against the widow of <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, who killed a <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> manager and himself after the 1987 stock market crash. <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, financially wiped out by `` Black Monday,'' walked into the <ORGANIZATION> Merrill </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lynch </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on Oct. 26, 1987, one week after the crash, killing office manager <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Argilagos </PERSON> and paralyzing his broker, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON>. Attorneys R.W. `` Buddy'' <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> and <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Areces </PERSON>, representing <PERSON> Argilagos </PERSON>, announced the case was settled, but that <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Circuit Judge <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenbaum </PERSON> ordered that the amount of damages not be disclosed. <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>, 53, was actually <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Katz </PERSON>, a disbarred lawyer and federally protected witness relocated to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. His testimony in <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> helped convict mob figures in a 1977 stock fraud case, which drew death threats from organized crime figures. In testimony Thursday, <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>'s depression grew steadily worse. `` After the crash, he was really depressed _ in a state of shock,'' <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> said. `` As the week wore on, he talked about wanting to kill himself.'' <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON>, his wife <PERSON> Wanda </PERSON> and <PERSON> Argilagos </PERSON>' survivors filed the civil suit against <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>'s wife, <PERSON> Judith </PERSON>. The settlement Friday resolved a lawsuit by <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON>, one by the family of <PERSON> Argilagos </PERSON>, and on Thursday that he had listened to <PERSON> Kane </PERSON>'s increasingly desperate talk about overdosing on drugs or carbon monoxide and tried to convince him he could bounce back `` It was money; it was n't his life,'' <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> recalled telling him. `` He just would n't listen to anything.'' The day before the shooting, a week after the market crash, <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> called <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> at home, the broker said. <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> assured him that he was a valuable customer and that <PERSON> Merrill </PERSON> <PERSON> Lynch </PERSON> would work with him. However, when <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> came in Monday planning to pay $ 60,000 to $ 70,000 to keep his account open, he was told he needed $ 130,000. <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> said he would return with the money. He came back later, went into <PERSON> Argilagos </PERSON>' office with <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON>, and pulled his gun. `` Mr. <PERSON> Kane </PERSON> took out the gun and said: ` Take this, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON>,' and fired one shot,'' <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> said. `` And that's the last thing I remember.'' Now a paraplegic, <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> said his life is dominated by pain. His income has dropped to $ 45,000, compared to 1987 when he was on track to earn $ 295,000, he said, and his medical bills exceeded $ 324,000. <PERSON> Kolokoff </PERSON> said he overcame early depression with determination to live. `` I want to live,'' he said. `` I have a really good family. I ca n't even think about losing them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CouponFraud     08-19 0330</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coupon Fraud,0340</SECOND>
<HEAD>Coupon Redemption Fraud Couple Get Stiff Sentences</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A couple who were the only two of 62 defendants who went to trial in a $ 12 million coupon-redemption fraud have received stiff prison sentences. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Winokur </PERSON> refused to plead guilty for his part in the scheme but was sentenced Thursday to 17 years. His wife, <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, who turned down the state's offer of five years' probation, was sentenced to seven years. <ORGANIZATION> Broward </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Leroy </PERSON> <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> gave <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Winokur </PERSON> the maximum sentence under the state's guidelines. That was more than triple the time the coupon fraud mastermind, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Krasnick </PERSON>, received after admitting his guilt in a plea deal. <PERSON> Florence </PERSON> <PERSON> Winokur </PERSON> faced a maximum penalty of nine years. Besides serving prison time, <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> ordered the Winokurs to pay $ 230,000 in restitution and each serve 10 years' probation. The state offered <PERSON> Winokur </PERSON> a 2 -LCB- - year sentence when he was arrested more than a year ago `` I would have loved to give him 2 -LCB- years,'' <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> said before he sentenced the Winokurs. `` All he had to do was say he did it. And he'd probably be walking the streets now'' because prison overcrowding means that most inmates serve only about a third of their sentences. `` I do n't think there was n't a person associated with the case that did n't urge them to take a deal,'' <PERSON> Moe </PERSON> said. `` I'm not responsible for their choices.'' The Winokurs were convicted three weeks ago on charges of racketeering, grand theft and conspiracy. They operated stores in <LOCATION> Dade </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Broward </LOCATION> counties in 1986-88 solely to illegally redeem coupons. The stores had products on their shelves but the Winokurs seldom made a sale, according to prosecutors. The shops were set up as facades to redeem $ 200,000 worth of coupons for products never sold. The enterprise, which involved 81 stores, bought coupons in bulk from charitable organizations and had other people clip, sort and crumple coupons to make them look handled by consumers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NoseArrest     08-19 0278</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nose Arrest,0286</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woman With False Nose Arrested for Resisting Cop</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ORLANDO, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A police officer got his nose out of joint and arrested a budding professional clown for wearing a plastic nose and failing to get out of her car during a recent drug crackdown. <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cherrington </PERSON>, a 47-year-old mother of two, spent 5 -LCB- hours in jail and faces up to 18 months behind bars and $ 1,500 in fines. But that wo n't stop her from wearing a plastic nose when she appears in court. She was arrested Aug. 4 when she and her 20-year-old son visited a friend. Deputies investigating for drugs had set up a roadblock and were stopping all cars entering an apartment complex. She had popped on one of her favorite dime store noses with bright yellow glasses attached. But the fake nose failed to tickle Deputy <PERSON> Jimmie </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, who ordered her to take it off and get out of the car. When she refused, she was arrested and charged with wearing a mask in public and resisting arrest without violence. The nose was confiscated as evidence. `` She was being a real smart aleck,'' the officer said. `` It was n't a situation to make jokes in.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Cherrington </PERSON> said Thursday that the time spent in the Orange County Jail taught her a lesson. `` You get a headache laying your head on those hard wood seats that everyone uses as a bed,'' she said. `` Now maybe if a police officer says get out of the car I wo n't take so long.'' Still, she plans to be herself when she appears in court. `` I'll definitely pop my nose on for the judge,'' she said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-ToplessDoughnuts     08-19 0382</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Topless Doughnuts,0397</SECOND>
<HEAD>Topless Doughnut Shop Opens For Business</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT COLLINS, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Threats by protesters failed to keep truckers away from <ORGANIZATION> Debbie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Duz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Donuts </ORGANIZATION>, which has topless waitresses, adult videos, doughnuts and coffee. As a dozen protesters stood across the street carrying signs with slogans such as, `` Welcome to the Pit of Iniquity,'' a thin but steady stream of customers ventured inside Friday to pay $ 2 for a doughnut and cup of coffee served by one of six waitresses wearing only shorts and shoes. Shop owner <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Cortese </PERSON> hustled around the store coordinating waitresses and workers. He opened for a sneak preview about three weeks ago, but many truckers stayed away, waiting for the publicity to die down, <PERSON> Cortese </PERSON> said. On Friday, the first trucker pulled into the parking lot off Interstate 25 a half-hour after the shop opened about noon. Two others arrived a few minutes later. `` I just kind of wondered what was going on,'' said <PERSON> Jeb </PERSON> <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON>, driving an 18-wheel truck for a <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> company. `` I dropped some lambs off, I had to make a phone call and I thought I'd have a doughnut and a cup of coffee.'' The trucker said he was n't concerned about the protesters who were filming customers. Opponents have promised to notify trucking companies of their drivers' whereabouts. `` They wo n't care,'' <PERSON> Hansen </PERSON> said. `` They'll get a kick out of it.'' Patrons chatted with English topless model <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Trent </PERSON>, hired by <PERSON> Cortese </PERSON> for the shop's opening, or spent $ 5 for a photograph with her. <PERSON> Debby </PERSON> <PERSON> Duz </PERSON> <PERSON> Donuts </PERSON> also has an adult entertainment room with magazines, videos and posters. Opponents have gathered 7,000 signatures on a petition against the shop. `` Our ultimate goal is to shut <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Duz </PERSON> Donuts down,'' said <PERSON> Cheri </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>. She complained that county commissioners, `` because they fear a lawsuit from Cortese, ca n't make a law to get him out of the state.'' `` To get him out of the state, we have to go through the state <ORGANIZATION> Legislature </ORGANIZATION>,'' she said. Protests would continue, she promised. A few supporters of the doughnut shop plan to picket, too. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Curley </PERSON> of <PERSON> Fort </PERSON> <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> said he will carry signs because `` I do n't like a small vocal minority telling us what shops can open.'' He said he has not visited <PERSON> Debbie </PERSON> <PERSON> Duz </PERSON> Donuts.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IRAArrests     08-19 0268</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-IRA Arrests,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Charged In IRA Weapons Conspiracy Plead Innocent</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANIEL BEEGAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two men accused of trying to export weapons, including anti-helicopter missiles, to the <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> have pleaded innocent to charges of conspiring to violate federal arms export regulations. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, an electrical engineer from <LOCATION> Harwich </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON>, a computer scientist from <LOCATION> Easton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, were among five people accused in a grand jury indictment handed up last week. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> pleaded Friday before <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazzone </PERSON>, who set a $ 25,000 bond for <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> and took his passport. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> already had been released on bail by a federal magistrate. Two other defendants, <PERSON> Christina </PERSON> <PERSON> Leigh </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON>, an electrical engineering student from <LOCATION> Sunnyvale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON>, a citizen of the <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> who is in federal custody in <LOCATION> Pennsylvania </LOCATION>, will be arraigned Tuesday, <PERSON> Mazzone </PERSON> said. A fifth defendant, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Eamon </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>, is a fugitive believed to be in <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mazzone </PERSON> said the trial probably would be early next year. Federal investigators allege the five worked for the Provisional <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION>, the guerrilla wing of the nationalist group fighting to end British rule in the six counties of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>. Federal prosecutor <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Stearns </PERSON> said the case includes <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> telephone taps and evidence including radar and missile parts. <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> is charged with developing for illegal export `` remote control detonation systems to facilitate a bombing campaign.'' <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> is accused of working with <PERSON> Quigley </PERSON> to `` develop, test and export a missile and rocket system to be used against <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> helicopters in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-HelicopterEscape 5thLd-Writethru a0401 08-19 1135</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Helicopter Escape, 5th Ld-Writethru, a0401,1165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Escapees, Women Captured After Nebraska Shootout</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 4-7, `Holdrege Police ..., with 9 grafs to UPDATE
with details of pursuit, quotes from county prosecutor, identity of wounded
fugitive, disposition of arrested suspects; picks up 8th graf pvs: `Another
witness ...; SUBS 18th graf, `The inmates ..., to conform.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos COL1-2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENIS SEARLES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ORDWAY, Colo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two women hijacked a helicopter at gunpoint Friday, snatched two inmates from a prison yard and fled the region in a waiting van, but all four were captured after a shootout in <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, authorities said. `` We can confirm they were taken into custody, all four of them,'' said <PERSON> Juanita </PERSON> <PERSON> Novak </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION>. The wild shootout in <LOCATION> Holdrege </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, involved a gunfire-punctuated pursuit of a rented van through a residential neighborhood, said a witness to the final showdown. `` They crossed a median and hit a tree,'' the witness, a woman who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` We could definitely see they had guns and were shooting. The police tried to arrest them by swerving in front of the truck but they ran up into a yard.'' The nine-minute chase began when a <LOCATION> Holdrege </LOCATION> police officer spotted the yellow van at 6:18 p.m. and the pursuit wound through town until it ended at 6:27 p.m., said <LOCATION> Phelps </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>. The shooting started after the van struck a police car head-on, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` After the first encounter they went down the street shooting houses and at people,'' he said. About eight officers were involved in the chase and about five were shot at, he said. At least eight shots penetrated the car's windshield, police said The van stopped and the four were arrested without further resistance after one of the men was shot, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` One of them was hit and was bleeding pretty bad,'' <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` He's fine. He just got hit in the hand.'' <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> was at <ORGANIZATION> Good </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Samaritan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kearney </LOCATION> with a shotgun pellet possibly lodged in a finger on his right hand, said <LOCATION> Phelps </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Holdrege </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Chief <PERSON> Ken </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON> said there were no other injuries, despite indiscriminate shooting by the suspects as police converged on them in this farming town of about 5,600 people in south-central <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, about 40 miles north of the <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> line. Deputy County <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said police confiscated a 9mm automatic and a .22 - caliber <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said the other man and woman were being held at the <LOCATION> Phelps </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION>, the other woman was being held at <LOCATION> Holdrege </LOCATION> police headquarters. The prosecutor said he expected the four would be in court Monday. None of the four was formally charged, <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` We've got plenty to hold them on,'' he added. Another witness, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON>, said he and his neighbor <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Brenn </PERSON> ducked ducked behind <PERSON> Brenn </PERSON>'s pickup truck when the shooting began about two houses away. `` I saw the gun come out of the passenger side of the van and then they never stopped shooting,'' <PERSON> Swenson </PERSON> said. `` It was just like on TV. These were big guns, not little ones.'' Mayor <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON> said the town was quiet again at about 9 p.m. `` There's probably some pretty excited people,'' she said. `` We're not accustomed to this.'' In the brazen, daylight prison break, frustrated guards held their fire because they could not get a clear shot at the helicopter and feared that the pilot was being held hostage, said <PERSON> Liz </PERSON> <PERSON> McDonough </PERSON>, a corrections spokewoman. Nevertheless, authorities ordered an investigation to determine why a guard refused three orders from prison superintendent <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> to open fire on the helicopter. `` From the time the helicopter came into view, from the point of touchdown to takeoff, was 10 to 15 seconds,'' <PERSON> Brittain </PERSON> said. `` My recollection was that as the inmates were diving headfirst into the helicopter, it was lifting off.'' The pilot was found bound and gagged about 35 miles north of the medium-security state prison and the helicopter was found nearby after authorities received an anonymous telephone call. Authorities said the women were believed to be wives of the escaped inmates, even though one of the women gave the name of a former deputy sheriff who had been fired for fraternizing with inmates. The two escaped inmates were cellmates. The women and the escapees apparently transferred to a rented van and eluded police. Authorities set up roadblocks on highways leading from the prison and the <ORGANIZATION> Colorado </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> provided helicopters for the search. The inmates were identified as <PERSON> Freddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzales </PERSON>, 21, who was serving a four-year sentence for robbery, and <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, 21, who was sentenced for sexual assault, theft and criminal impersonation in a bad check charge. <PERSON> Gonzales </PERSON> would have been eligible for parole in September 1991, while <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>'s parole eligibility date was October 1996. One of the woman who rented the helicopter identified herself as <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Quinn </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> Arapahoe </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> deputy fired for fraternization, but from descriptions given by the pilot, authorities now believe the hijacking was carried out by <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Gonzales </PERSON> and <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>, wives of the two inmates. The women apparently had planned to hijack a helicopter earlier in the week, but their plans had to be delayed for several days due to bad weather, <PERSON> McDonough </PERSON> said. The women rented the helicopter from <ORGANIZATION> Helicopter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION>, saying they wanted to take some photos of real estate near the prison, said <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kautzky </PERSON>, director of the state <ORGANIZATION> Corrections </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Once near the prison, one woman pulled a gun and ordered the pilot to land, <PERSON> Kautzky </PERSON> said. The <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> Correctional Facility in <LOCATION> Crowley </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> is about 50 miles east of <LOCATION> Pueblo </LOCATION>, on the plains of southeastern <LOCATION> Colorado </LOCATION>. After the escape, the helicopter flew north and the pilot was forced to land near a farmhouse and the rental truck. The pilot, <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Graves </PERSON>, was taken to the farmhouse where he was bound and gagged. Graves later was taken to the <LOCATION> Lincoln </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jail </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Hugo </LOCATION> for security, authorities said. He was being interviewed by police. The incident was the latest in a rash of helicopter prison escapes and attempts. In April, a helicopter crashed after its tail rotor snagged on a fence at the federal <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. The pilot and the prisoner survived. In July 1988, a woman hijacked a helicopter and forced the pilot to land in the prison yard at the Penitentiary of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Albuquerque </LOCATION>. Three convicts escped but later were captured. In November 1986, an inmate escaped from the minimum-security federal prison in <LOCATION> Pleasanton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif </LOCATION>. He later hijacked a helicopter and returned to the prison to free a woman inmate who worked with him in the prison business office. They were captured 10 days later while buying wedding rings.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0209EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-WhiteSquirrels     08-19 0760</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-White Squirrels,0782</SECOND>
<HEAD>Missouri Town Nuts About Albino Squirrels</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY NACHTIGAL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MARIONVILLE, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They're nuts about white squirrels in <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION>. Just ask the folks at the White Squirrel Furniture Store, the White Squirrel Car Wash or the White Squirrel Hollow Bed & amp; Breakfast. And watch where you're driving: A 21-year-old city ordinance imposes a $ 500 fine for deliberately injuring or killing one of the rare albino squirrels. Motorists must yield right of way to them. No one has ever been arrested for violating the law, but that does n't mean it's taken lightly. `` If I catch somebody killing a white squirrel, I will issue a citation,'' said Police Chief <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Merritt </PERSON>, who wears a squirrel-emblazoned shoulder patch on his uniform. `` It's no joke.'' Some people even go so far as to trap the albinos' gray cousins and banish them from the small southwest Missouri town to give the white squirrels first crack at the nuts. <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION>, home to 2,000 people and nearly half that many white squirrels, has a billboard welcoming visitors to the `` Home of the White Squirrel.'' Only one other community in the nation _ <LOCATION> Olney </LOCATION><LOCATION> , </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION> _ is known to have a sizable concentration of the snow-white squirrels, but <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION>'s colony is much larger, says <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Smart </PERSON>, a local authority and booster of the animal. `` We've blown <PERSON> Olney </PERSON> off the map,'' he boasts. <PERSON> Olney </PERSON> has a measly few dozen squirrels, he figures. Wildlife experts say finding any albino animal colony the size of <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION>'s is rare. `` Normally you see an albino show up occasionally in a population such as squirrels or birds or deer, but entire populations are not something you come across all that frequently,'' said <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Kurzejeski </PERSON>, a state wildlife research biologist. Signs of <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION>'s affection for the white squirrel, which mates and otherwise interacts normally with its gray cousin, are everywhere. The <ORGANIZATION> Lions </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> sells white squirrel T-shirts and pins to raise money to buy redwood boxes that are placed in trees as homes for the squirrels. More than 500 dens have been put up, and volunteers have planted hundreds of nut trees. `` We've had orders for T-shirts from <LOCATION> Kalamazoo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>,'' says Smart, a Lions member. `` <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION> is a small town, but people who grew up here and moved away still remember their roots and want to help the white squirrel.'' White squirrels first appeared in <LOCATION> Marionville </LOCATION> around 1860, Smart says. According to local legend, a couple of the critters escaped from a traveling circus and began multiplying, or were the product of a weird experiment by a local scientist. Smart became fascinated by white squirrels when one showed up on the deck of his home about 12 years ago. He set out to increase the population by trapping the more numerous gray squirrels in the woods around his home and releasing them several miles away to provide more room for the whites. `` We trapped 110 gray squirrels in a year and a half,'' he said. `` It was just amazing what the whites did then.'' Smart estimates that about three dozen albino squirrels live in 30 den boxes and in trees on his heavily wooded property. `` I have one picture at home with 17 white squirrels in it,'' he said. Retirees <PERSON> Johnie </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> spend hours on their back porch watching the white squirrels munch corn and walnuts placed at their feeders. The couple had no white squirrels until Smart transplanted some there a few years ago. `` They'll play just like a little kitten,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> said. `` There will be five or six in the yard looking for something to eat and I'll say, ` Do n't leave, <PERSON> Johnie </PERSON>'s bringing you something.' I swear they can understand me.'' <PERSON> Diana </PERSON> <PERSON> Wise </PERSON>, who runs the <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Squirrel </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hollow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; Breakfast with her husband, <PERSON> Clint </PERSON>, says people come for miles to see the animals. `` A lot of people do n't really believe we have white squirrels because they stop at noon and do n't see them,'' she said. `` The best time to see them is 6:30 or 7 in the morning and around 7, 7:30 at night when they're feeding. They do n't like the heat and I think the light hurts their pink eyes.'' Smart used to hunt gray squirrels -LRB- `` Young squirrel, fried, with biscuits and gravy _ you ca n't beat it'' -RRB-, but not anymore. `` The squirrels are a hobby, a challenge for me now,'' he says. `` I guess I'm paying back for all the hunting I used to do.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0044EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-TropicalWeather 1stLd-Writethru a0707 08-19 0184</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tropical Weather, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0707,0185</SECOND>
<HEAD>Tropical Depression Forms Off West Africa</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf, `At 6 p.m. ..., with 10:30 p.m. position.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The seventh tropical depression of the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season formed Friday off the African coast, forecasters reported. At 10:30 p.m. EDT, the depression's poorly defined center was near latitude 17.6 degrees north and longitude 28.5 west, about 200 miles west of the <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Verde </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Sal </LOCATION>, according to the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>. The depression, moving west-northwest at about 18 mph, is expected to slow during the weekend and turn toward the northwest, the center reported. Maximum sustained winds were estimated at 35 mph. The depression would become a named tropical storm if maximum sustained winds reach 39 mph. A tropical storm becomes a hurricane once its top sustained winds reach 74 mph. Two of the previous six depressions this year have become hurricanes. The second, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, dissipated earlier this month in the <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> after causing minor damage in <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> hurricane season runs from June 1 to November 30.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-SiberiaPark     08-19 0172</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Siberia Park,160</SECOND>
<HEAD>Trans-Bering Park Studied</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> is negotiating with its counterparts in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> to establish a park spanning the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>, according to Saturday editions of the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Post. Park officials will visit Siberian areas across the strait from <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> next month and return with Soviet officials who will inspect Alaskan sites, the newspaper said. The service already administers the <ORGANIZATION> Bering </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Preserve </ORGANIZATION>, a 2.7-million acre wild area just north of <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION>. There is no comparable preserve on the Soviet side. Such a park could make it easier for scientists to conduct research on both sides of the border and make it easier for wildlife biologists to track migratory species like walrus moving between the two countries. In the last Ice Age, the strait was dry, which permitted people and animals to move between <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The newspaper said the park project, still embryonic, is known around the headquarters of the park service as `` glasnost and the glaciers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RiteAid-Grass     08-19 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Rite Aid-Grass,0358</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rite Aid President Pleads Innocent to Bribery</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KRISTI UMBREIT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The president of the nation's largest pharmacy chain pleaded innocent Friday to charges of bribing an <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmacy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> member and of possession of criminal tools. <ORGANIZATION> Rite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> L. </PERSON> <PERSON> Grass </PERSON>, 35, entered the plea in <ORGANIZATION> Cuyahoga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Common </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pleas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> before Judge <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Villanueva </PERSON>. Grass is free on $ 100,000 bond. He declined to comment on the case after the hearing. His <LOCATION> Shiremanstown </LOCATION>, Pa.-based company later released a three-page statement saying the indictment against Grass and the company is `` bizarre.'' `` They -LRB- Grass and Rite Aid -RRB- have indicated that the charge of bribery is a vicious attempt to blemish the corporation and its president and have called the charge absurd,'' the release said. The indictment alleged that Grass and the company used an aircraft as the criminal tool last March and April. Grass was arrested April 27 at a hotel near <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> Hopkins International Airport. Prosecutors said the arrest came after the alleged bribe was videotaped. On June 14, a grand jury handed up a secret indictment accusing Grass of offering a $ 33,000 bribe to <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilczynski </PERSON>, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pharmacy </ORGANIZATION>, in exchange for his stepping down from the board. Prosecutors have said the company and Grass wanted to get control of the board and fire its executive director, <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON> <PERSON> Z. </PERSON> <PERSON> Wickham </PERSON>. Rite Aid said <PERSON> Wickham </PERSON> had been harassing the company in enforcing pharmacy regulations. The indictment was unsealed Aug. 1. Both charges are felonies. The bribery charge carries a maximum prison term of 10 years and a $ 5,000 fine. Possession of criminal tools is punishable by a maximum five years in prison and $ 2,500 fine. Rite Aid has said a $ 33,249 corporate check Grass gave <PERSON> Wilczynski </PERSON> was a legal buyout of <PERSON> Wilczynski </PERSON>'s consulting contract with <ORGANIZATION> Lane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, a division of <ORGANIZATION> Peoples </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stores </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> that Rite Aid acquired April 10. On May 17, Grass and Rite Aid filed a defamation lawsuit in <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> against <PERSON> Wilczynski </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0231EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     08-19 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0752</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>, the son of actor <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>, was sentenced to clean up gang graffiti and perform other community service after pleading no contest to a drunken driving charge. <PERSON> O'Neal </PERSON>, 24, who was not present at the hearing Friday, was sentenced to three years' unsupervised probation, fined about $ 800 and ordered to attend an alcohol education program, said Deputy City Attorney <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Eyk </PERSON>. He was not required to attend the misdemeanor sentencing, she said. The aspiring actor was arrested Oct. 2, 1988, after police officers in the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fernando </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> observed him straddling lanes in his brown-and-pink 1957 <ORGANIZATION> Chrysler </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Eyk </PERSON> said. Blood tests revealed a blood alcohol level of 0.13 percent, 0.03 percent above the legal limit, she said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s manager is questioning <ORGANIZATION> MTV </ORGANIZATION>'s decision to restrict the airtime of <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s video `` If I Could Turn Back Time,'' which <ORGANIZATION> MTV </ORGANIZATION> says shows more of <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> than some people want to see. The clip features <PERSON> Cher </PERSON> _ wearing a thin, carefully-placed V-shaped outfit and sheer stockings _ performing on the deck of a troop ship. `` When we accepted it, we felt it was borderline,'' <PERSON> Abbey </PERSON> <PERSON> Konowitch </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> MTV </ORGANIZATION> vice president for programming, said Friday. `` We received a great deal of negative feedback from our audience.'' The video will only be aired from 9 p.m. to 6 a.m., said <PERSON> Konowitch </PERSON>. <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>'s manager, <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Sammeth </PERSON>, said <ORGANIZATION> MTV </ORGANIZATION>'s decision was like closing the barn door after the horse was gone: `` They think it shows too much of her, but they allowed it for eight weeks.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>BARCELONA, Spain (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Band leader <PERSON> Xavier </PERSON> <PERSON> Cugat </PERSON> has recovered from a heart ailment and left a hospital after a monthlong stay. <PERSON> Cugat </PERSON>, 89, was `` in perfect shape'' Friday when he was released from the Quiron Clinic, said spokeswoman Isabel Mas. He entered the hospital with a problem in his left ventricle. <PERSON> Cugat </PERSON>, who is generally credited with introducing tropical rhythms into American dance music, has suffered four heart attacks and a stroke since 1980. The band leader became a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> star in the 1930s. He was born in <LOCATION> Spain </LOCATION> and moved with his family to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> as a child. In 1970, he turned over his band to <PERSON> Tito </PERSON> <PERSON> Puente </PERSON>, and a decade later returned to <LOCATION> Barcelona </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MINEOLA, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The daughter of artist <PERSON> Willem </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON> is looking for a gallery to represent his works after gaining control of the painter's estate. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, 85, was declared mentally incompetent Friday by a judge who gave control of the estate, including $ 150 million in art, to <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>, sole heir to <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>'s fortune, and family attorney <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Eastman </PERSON>. The artist was one of the first leaders of the abstract expressionist movement. He paints daily in his East Hampton studio despite suffering from Alzheimer's disease. His daughter, 33, lives next door. <PERSON> Eastman </PERSON> said he and <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> will audit and inventory the artist's collection, which may include up to 300 paintings covering his entire career `` This is going to be a very big undertaking,'' said <PERSON> Eastman </PERSON>, an associate of <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Kooning </PERSON>'s for the past 20 years. `` This is the first time that a living artist as great as this has had such a volume of work gathered.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> says he has hit a fellow actor and worn high heels to gear up for performances. The star of the movies `` Salvador'' and `` The Onion Field'' said he `` whacked'' <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> `` across the side of the head and knocked him over, knocked his glasses across the room.'' <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> told Smart magazine in its September-October issue that during filming of `` True Believer,'' <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> `` was missing the magic that I knew he was capable of.'' A stunned <PERSON> Downey </PERSON> finished the scene, then laughed. `` I just woke him up for a second,'' <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> recalled also that `` <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Niro </PERSON> once sent me a pair of red high-heeled pumps from <PERSON> Frederick </PERSON>'s of <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> before I did a scene in ` Once Upon a Time in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,''' `` So I just walked in, wearing my tux and my old-rubber-head makeup and these big, fluffy, feathery, high-heeled, blazing-red spiked heels. I think maybe I was being too serious or something, and that kind of lightened me up a bit.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0232EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Chronology     08-19 0496</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Chronology,0519</SECOND>
<HEAD>Important Dates in Post-War Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a brief chronology of major events in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s post-war history: Sept. 1, 1939 _ <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> invades <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> attacks from the east 16 days later. <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> spends rest of war under German and Soviet occupation. April 1943 _ <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> breaks relations with exiled Polish government in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. July 22, 1944 _ Soviets install `` Polish <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION>.'' Six months later they recognize this committee as Polish government. June 28, 1945 _ Following <LOCATION> Yalta </LOCATION> conference, Soviet-dominated Polish Provisional Government of National Unity formed. 1947-1953 _ Communist-controlled elections give party full control of government. Non-Communist parties are abolished and Communists force merger with pre-war Socialists to form Polish <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Workers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. Period of Stalinist consolidation and purges until <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON>'s death in 1953. 1956 _ Shakeup in government after `` de-Stalinization'' <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and `` bread and freedom'' riots at <LOCATION> Poznan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Wladyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Gomulka </PERSON>, former head of <ORGANIZATION> Polish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> ousted during <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> era, returns to power. <PERSON> Gomulka </PERSON> opens period of increased freedom that lasts until late 1960s when he reverts to more rigid policies. 1968 _ Purges and attacks on students and Jews led by party hardliners. December 1970 _ Rapidly increasing food prices and deep dissatisfaction with living and working conditions lead to riots on Baltic coast. <PERSON> Gomulka </PERSON> is replaced by <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Gierek </PERSON>. June 24, 1976 _ Announcement of food price increases sparks riots and strikes. Increases are quickly rescinded. Workers' <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- KOR -RRB- formed. 1980 _ Recession in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s debt burden, inflation, and market problems contribute to spiraling economic decline. Aug. 14, 1980 _ Electrician <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> leads occupation strike at <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lenin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipyard </ORGANIZATION> and starts worker revolt. Aug. 31, 1980 _ Authorities agree to make Solidarity Soviet bloc's only legal independent union. Sept. 1980 _ Discontent underlying strikes intensified by revelations of government and party corruption and mismanagement. <PERSON> Gierek </PERSON> ousted. Dec. 13, 1981 _ Workers threaten general strike and Gen. <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> declares martial law, interning thousands of Solidarity members, including <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>. Oct. 8, 1982 _ Solidarity is banned and official trade union alliance is created to take its place. Nov. 11, 1982 _ <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> is freed. July 22, 1983 _ <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> lifts martial law but leaves many restrictive edicts in place. 1984-1987 _ Amnesty is approved for political prisoners and eventually all Solidarity prisoners are freed. Aug.-Sept. 1988 _ Strikes spread across <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>, creating worst labor strife in seven years Strikes end when <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON> asks for time to talk with the government. Feb. 6, 1989 _ `` Roundtable'' negotiations begin with government. Apr. 5, 1989 _ Deliberations conclude with endorsement of new `` social contract,'' including overhaul of legislative system and partly democratic elections. June 4, 1989 _ Solidarity is overwhelming winner over <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> in legislative elections. Aug. 16-18, 1989 _ Peasant and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> parties endorse <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>'s plan for non-Communist coalition. <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> approves coalition and chooses journalist and Solidarity activist <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> to be prime minister.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DrugPlea     08-19 0267</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Drug Plea,0273</SECOND>
<HEAD>Accused Heroin Kingpin Pleads Guilty to Drug Charges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 72-year-old <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION> businessman pleaded guilty in federal court on Friday to charges that he led a drug ring that dealt hundreds of pounds of heroin into the city. <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Woo </PERSON>, an influential leader in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Chinese community, told <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dearie </PERSON> that he conspired with his codefendants to possess heroin and distribute it in <LOCATION> Queens </LOCATION> and other parts of the city. Woo served as a broker who brought wholesale heroin buyers and sellers together, said Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>. He faces up to 20 years in prison and a $ 1 million fine when he is sentenced by <PERSON> Dearie </PERSON>. No sentencing date had been set. Woo, owner of a <LOCATION> Chinatown </LOCATION> liquor store, was arrested in February when federal and city authorities broke up the drug ring, seized 820 pounds of high-grade Asian heroin worth $ 1 billion and confiscated $ 3 million in cash. At the time of the arrests the <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> director in charge of the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> office, <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>, said the heroin bust was the largest ever in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Federal authorities have charged 29 others with participating in the organization. Woo, alleged leader of the ring, was the first to enter a plea, <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said. He remained in custody on $ 2 million bail. Woo, a naturalized <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> citizen, was born in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>, and came to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> about three decades ago. He owned a liquor store on <PERSON> Mott </PERSON> <PERSON> Street </PERSON> and ran the <ORGANIZATION> Chinatown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> in the same building.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0233EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CustodyBattle     08-19 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Custody Battle,0313</SECOND>
<HEAD>Judge Orders Children Returned to New Hampshire</HEAD>
<DATELINE>EXETER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two children who were spirited from <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> by their mother after her ex-husband was acquitted of sexually molesting their daughter must be returned to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>, a judge ruled Friday. <ORGANIZATION> Rockingham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Douglas </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> ruled that <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON>'s 4-year-old son and 6-year-old daughter be placed in a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> foster home pending a hearing Sept. 1. Mrs. <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenfeld </PERSON>, criticized <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s decision on a petition by <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON>, and said he would try to obtain an emergency order to keep the children in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Denton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> Mrs. <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON>, 40, contends the children would be in danger if they lived with her 34-year-old ex-husband at his home in <LOCATION> Derry </LOCATION>. In November, after <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON> was found innocent in the sexual abuse case, his ex-wife disappeared with the children and began an eight-month journey to <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> via an `` underground railway'' that helps women in such situations. <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON> later was awarded custody. Last week, <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> authorities, tipped that Mrs. <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON> was living in <LOCATION> Loma </LOCATION> under a false name, took the children from her. Montana District Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON> ordered on Thursday that the children be kept in a state foster home until <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> courts called for their return. <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> said Friday that <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> authorities must deliver the children to <LOCATION> Exeter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's officers at <LOCATION> Logan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. They then will be taken to a foster home in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>, where all parental visits will be supervised. The children, who are in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Denton </LOCATION>, will not be placed with either parent pending the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> hearing next month. <PERSON> Murabito </PERSON> did not return telephone calls from The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, and his lawyer, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Kellett </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Salem </LOCATION>, could not be reached for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0234EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RudenessRecalled     08-19 0392</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Rudeness Recalled,0403</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rudeness the Issue in Recall</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROCKLAND, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Two officials facing a recall election today said the town was wasting money on petty politics, but their opponents said rudeness by officials was a bona fide issue. `` For one thing I think it's ridiculous because we're both up for election in six months,'' said <PERSON> Selectman </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON>, who estimated the special election's cost at $ 10,000. Today, just more than a year after this town's citizens adopted a bylaw allowing for recall elections, voters face the question of whether the current five-member board has been ill-mannered and unresponsive. The election features five candidates, including the two incumbents, running for two seats. `` What it comes down to is there's been a small group of people in the town hall who have been trying to operate the place like it's their private club,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who helped lead the recall campaign that's pushing three alternative candidates <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said the selectmen betrayed the public in a variety of ways, including at one point locking townspeople out of the town hall during a meeting and snickering at people with whom they disagreed. `` There's just been abusive treatment. Laughing at people, making comments. It's happened to me and it's happened to other people,'' said <PERSON> Ward </PERSON>, who lost a seat on the board in March by a narrow margin. Selectman <PERSON> Geraldine </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Noonan </PERSON>, who like <PERSON> Gagnon </PERSON> could be forced from her post, disagreed. `` I ca n't remember any incident where any member on the board was rude to people,'' she said. `` We listen to all the issues that come before us. We certainly would n't degrade a person if we did n't agree with an issue.'' Residents in this town of 15,500 people south of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> say the bickering began in April when the board opted against renewing the contract of Police Chief <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who has since been demoted. The selectmen's decision was broadcast live on local cable television and many people were bewildered because during the chief's tenure crime had subsided. `` There was no debate, no discussion. And then when it was asked why they were n't renewing his contract they refused to give a reason,'' <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. Within days, 600 citizens had gathered to discuss the turn of events, <PERSON> Ward </PERSON> said. Within months, more than 1,800 signatures had been placed on a recall petition.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0235EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Mazowiecki     08-19 0839</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Mazowiecki,0866</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mazowiecki: From Prison to Prime Minister?</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DRUSILLA MENAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>'s opposition to the Communist government once brought him a year in prison. Now, the general who put him behind bars appears poised to appoint him prime minister. The tall, taciturn 62-year-old Solidarity journalist is the least publicly known of the three candidates the labor movement offered to communist President <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>. But his links to Solidarity date to the August 1980 strikes that created the union. And his activism goes back to the days after World War II, when the Communists began consolidating power. Now, he is ready to accept <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>'s expected offer to be the first non-Communist head of an East bloc government, a circumstance wrought by Solidarity's burgeoning political power. `` There have been several historical moments that show Poles can strive for new solutions and unusual ones, really innovative ones, and that we can get somewhere,'' he said Friday after meeting with <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>. `` My hope is that such a moment is now arriving pyschologically _ that people will feel there is such a situation.'' A close adviser to Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> edits the movement's weekly newspaper, <ORGANIZATION> Tygodnik </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solidarnosc </ORGANIZATION>. He also is closely linked to the Roman Catholic church, and in 1957 helped found the <ORGANIZATION> Warsaw </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Club </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligentsia </ORGANIZATION>, an influential forum that served as a bulwark for <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> opposition to Communist ideology. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was a key negotiator during the pivotal talks earlier this year that resulted in the legalization of Solidarity and opposition participation in elections. The talks were initiated by authorities unable to control <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s sinking economy and disgruntled populace. He led the negotiating team that focuses on trade union freedoms, participated in political discussions and fought for press freedoms in a nation where the government controls all publications. Trained as a lawyer, he submitted the court application for restoration of Solidarity's legal status provided for in the accords reached with authorities. When the petition was granted on April 17, he stood on the courthouse steps grinning broadly, arms raised and a bouquet of red tulips in one hand. `` Today for me means the restoration of justice,'' he said then. Recalling that he had been on hand when the union was first legalized in 1980 _ it was outlawed 16 months later _ he added: `` I hope I will not have to come here a third time.'' On other days, though, he appears dour and even cold. Some express concern that his Catholic faith and legal training have made him overly deliberative and unable to react quickly. A widower who lost his young wife to cancer and still wears his wedding ring, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> raised three sons alone in a small apartment on <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>'s main commercial street. Born on April 18, 1927, in the small central <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> city of Plock, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was raised in a family of intellectuals. By 21, he had been dismissed from his Academic Editing House job for keeping close ties to the church during the early years of Communist <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. He began to work with <ORGANIZATION> PAX </ORGANIZATION>, an organization set up by the government to dilute church-based opposition. But by 1955 he was so at odds with the mix of politics and religion that he was suspended. In 1958, he founded the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> monthly magazine Wiez, or Link, which he edited until 1981, when he began <ORGANIZATION> Tygodnik </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Solidarnosc </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> magazine reflected, and to a degree preceded, the modernization of Catholicism put forth by the second <ORGANIZATION> Vatican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>. He became aligned with ZNAK, a group supporting regeneration of <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> based on Catholic values. Officially condoned under the protection of the church, <ORGANIZATION> ZNAK </ORGANIZATION> had a Sejm delegation and <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> became a parliament deputy in 1961. By 1970, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>'s agitation for democratization of public life and social justice had run afoul of official tolerance and he was not allowed another term. As the opposition began organizing in the mid-1970s, especially after worker riots in 1976, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> went to <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in search of support and aid. Mention of free trade unions in a West German newspaper interview resulted in withdrawal of his passport for four years. <PERSON> Wiez </PERSON> became a more radical forum, publishing articles by <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Michnik </PERSON> and other strong opposition voices. <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> initiated a letter by more than 60 intellectuals urging authorities to find a peaceful solutions to the strikes that erupted on the Baltic coast in August 1980 and led to Solidarity's founding On Aug. 22, he arrived at the strikebound Lenin shipyard in <LOCATION> Gdansk </LOCATION> and after a nightlong talk with <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> became the head of a group of experts to help the workers organize the union and negotiate with government officials. With the martial-law crackdown announced by <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> on Dec. 13, 1981, <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON> was jailed. He was released on Dec. 23, 1982, and resumed as a union adviser. After historically democratic elections were scheduled in June, he did not run for office, preferring to edit the union's new legal and independent weekly.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0236EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Poland-Names     08-19 0089</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Poland-Names,0099</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pronunciation Guides to Polish Names</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Poland, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WARSAW, Poland (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pronunciation guide to Polish names in the news:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>: lek va-WHEN-sah. President <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON>: VOY-chek yah-roo-ZEHL-skee. Solidarity journalist and apparent nominee for prime minister, <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>: tah-DAY-oosh mah-zoh-vee-ET-skee. Outgoing Prime Minister <PERSON> Czeslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Kiszczek </PERSON>: CHES-wahf KEESH-chahk. Solidarity parliamentary leader <PERSON> Bronislaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Geremek </PERSON>: bron-ih-SWAF gehr-EH-mek. Solidarity lawmaker <PERSON> Jacek </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuron </PERSON>: YAHT-sehk KOOR-on. <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peasants </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Roman </PERSON> <PERSON> Malinowski </PERSON>: ROH-man ma-lin-AHF-skee. <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Jerzy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jozwiak </PERSON>: YEH-zhih YUZH-vee-ak. Communist Party leader <PERSON> Mieczyslaw </PERSON> <PERSON> Rakowski </PERSON>: myeh-CHIH-swahf rah-KAHF-skee.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0244EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Escapes     08-19 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Escapes,0796</SECOND>
<HEAD>East German Refugees Tell of Dramatic Escapes</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Saturday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TERRENCE PETTY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>GIESSEN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ralf </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> made it easily, strolling to freedom in <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>, but escape from communist <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> for <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Birgitt </PERSON> was a desperate crawl through fields and mosquito-infested woods. `` We had no food or water, and sometimes we had no more strength,'' <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON>, 27, said Friday after he and his wife arrived in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, still tired and sunburned from the three-day ordeal. Thousands of East Germans are flocking to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to escape the strict East German regime. Many go through liberal <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, which is clearing the barbed wire from its border with <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. About 100,000 East Germans are expected to reach <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> this year, by escape or with permission. One of the places they are taken first is the overflowing camp in this city an hour's drove northeast of <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Birgitt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON>'s 22-year-old wife, displayed cuts on her forearm and said, `` I got these climbing over the barbed wire'' in a stretch of the Hungarian border that had not been cleared. Like most of the others, <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> and <PERSON> Birgitt </PERSON> fled because of the East German government's resistance to the political and economic reforms now spreading through the Soviet bloc with the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>'s blessing East Germans have difficulty getting permission to travel to the West, but need no special permission to visit communist <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>, so it became an escape route when barricaded frontier was opened earlier this year. More than 1,500 are believed to have used it successfully. The young couple and other refugees interviewed at <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION> asked that their surnames be withheld to avoid trouble for relatives at home. `` We tried it a first time last week, but Hungarian border guards caught us,'' <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> said. `` They were nice. They just asked us to promise never to do it again.'' On the second try, a farmer with whom they hitched a ride dropped them about six miles from the frontier on Aug. 13. <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> said they did n't know where border controls were weakest, so they crawled through scorching cornfields, brush and woods searching for the right time and place. `` We knew some border fences had been removed, but we did n't know where,'' he said. `` There are a lot of escapees who get help and have access to information.'' He and <PERSON> Birgitt </PERSON> hid in a cornfield the first night and in woods the second, <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> said. `` We lay low during daylight, carefully observing everything,'' he said. `` Then, at night, we would go inch by inch, very carefully, to make sure we were n't noticed. There were millions of mosquitoes, it was really hot and we had nothing to drink.'' Birgitt remembered the exhaustion and fear of being separated. `` Sometimes we lost each other and could only find one another by calling out,'' she said. `` There were times when I thought I just could n't go on.'' They climbed the fence Tuesday near <LOCATION> Deutschkreutz </LOCATION>, about 90 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, and had a welcome drink from a brook. West German authorities arranged passage to <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>, then to the <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION> camp, where they will be fed and housed until they can start a new life. Because up to 500 East Germans arrive at <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION> on a single day, the government announced Friday it was opening another camp. East Germans were lined up Friday outside the stucco camp buildings at <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION>, waiting to fill out documents or for lunch in the cafeteria. Others leaned through windows of their temporary lodgings to talk with fellow refugees. Those who find lodgings with relatives usually leave <LOCATION> Giessen </LOCATION> in three or four days, but others remain a week or more. Many recent escapees are young people who left jobs to go West, like <PERSON> Ralf </PERSON>, a 20-year-old electrician, and his friend, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON>, an auto mechanic, who is 21. <PERSON> Ralf </PERSON>, from <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>, said they just walked across the border into <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION>. `` It took about three hours,'' he said. `` We had planned the whole thing. Everything went according to our plans.'' <PERSON> Jeannette </PERSON>, a 22-year-old from <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, said it took her 13 hours to reach <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> through woods, brush and thorny bushes, and she brought wire-cutters to snip through the fence. She said she said she found at least 25 other East Germans in an Austrian border village. All those interviewed said they fled <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> because they were fed up with conditions there. `` There is no freedom to protest, no freedom of the press, no freedom of opinion, and things are not going to change anytime soon,'' <PERSON> Joerg </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-GenericDrugs Bjt 590 08-19 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Generic Drugs, Bjt, 590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Announces New Generic Drug Steps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Government health officials hope that more inspectors, tougher laws and other regulatory changes will assure the public that the scandal-tainted generic drug industry sells safe products. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> and its parent agency, the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Human </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, announced a broad plan of attack Friday aimed at serving notice to pharmaceutical manufacturers _ and consumers _ that corrupt and fraudulent practices must stop. `` I stand ready to work cooperatively with the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to meet the legislative and budgetary requirements that are pivotal to assuring full confidence in the generic drugs program,'' <ORGANIZATION> HHS </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said in a written statement. The plan comes in the wake of months of revelations of gratuities paid by companies to federal regulators and of false information provided to the government by applicants for new drugs. There have been no indications of unsafe generic drugs reaching the market. <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> Commissioner <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON> announced they will increase federal oversight of drug manufacturers and their products and revamp procedures used to review drug applications. Two sources, speaking on condition they not be identified, said the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> would spend $ 18 million to hire additional inspectors. Agency spokesman <PERSON> Jeff </PERSON> <PERSON> Nesbit </PERSON> said the final figure had not been determined. But he said an undetermined number of new employees would be hired for field work such as inspections of manufacturing plants, and to check applications submitted to <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> by developers of new drugs. To pay for the additional work, <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Young </PERSON> proposed fees that would be levied on companies applying for permission to market new generic drugs. There currently are no application fees. The government has the power to ban the sales of drugs that it learns were approved after companies provided fraudulent information to regulators. Sources said the proposed legislation would give the government authority to remove a drug from the market if investigators prove other types of fraud, such as gratuities to regulators for checking one company's application before another's, in the approval process. Companies wishing to obtain federal approval to sell a new drug test it and submit the results to the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION>, which checks the records of the work. Producers must satisfy the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> that their product functions equivalently to the drug they are mimicking. The government also said it would create an ombudsman within <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> to hear complaints from the pharmaceutical industry, consumers and agency whistle blowers. The division within <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> that currently oversees generic drugs would be raised a notch in the agency's structure, giving it more clout And <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON> said drug review procedures would be `` reorganized and strengthened.'' On Wednesday, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> said it had started collecting thousands of samples of the 30 most commonly used generic drugs so it could conduct safety tests on them. The $ 5 billion generic drug industry is ferociously competitive, as dozens of mostly small and mid-size companies vie to market copies of brandname drugs after patents expire. The first such generic drug to hit the market generally gets and keeps the lion's share of sales The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> has been under pressure from <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, principally from Rep. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Dingell </PERSON>, D-Mich., whose <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> investigations subcommittee has conducted its own probe of the problems Staff investigators have shared information with the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney's Office in <LOCATION> Baltimore </LOCATION>, which has obtained guilty pleas from three <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> officials, two drug companies and three drug company executives. This spring, <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> began investigating 11 companies for possible violations of federal safety and production regulations.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0251EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Wilson Bjt 660 08-19 0668</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Wilson, Bjt, 660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Top Pierce Aide Refuses to Comply with Congressional Subpoena</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN KING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The man former Housing Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> once called his `` right hand'' is refusing to cooperate with congressional investigators, citing his right against self-incrimination in snubbing a subcommittee's subpoena that he testify. <PERSON> Lance </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s one-time executive assistant, told a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee Friday that he was asserting his Fifth Amendment rights because the conduct of panel members convinced him he would not receive a fair hearing. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> said attacks last month by several panel members after he failed to appear as scheduled `` made it clear that the subcommittee members have prejudged me and have no intention of affording me a fair and evenhanded hearing.'' <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON>, lashed out at subcommittee Chairman <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, other panel members and its staff, saying in a separate letter that all had made knowingly inaccurate statements about <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> during televised hearings, which <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON> called a `` charade.'' Attempts to reach <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., and subcommittee staffers were unsuccessful There was no answer at the subcommittee office when the <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON> letters were obtained late Friday. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>' home office in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, said the Democratic congressman was on vacation and unavailable for comment. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> was <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s top aide for several years and after leaving the agency invested in several projects that received lucrative subsidies from <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>. His successor as <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s executive assistant, <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Gore </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, appeared before <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in May but refused to answer questions, also asserting her Fifth Amendment rights. The subcommittee, in recess until after Labor Day, has been investigating influence-peddling, mismanagement and fraud at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration. Testimony and other evidence indicates that former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials and prominent Republicans received special treatment from the agency that helped them reap millions of dollars in government financing and subsidies. The hearings and other sources of information also have shown that <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION>'s internal controls were so poor that millions of dollars can not be accounted for and that the total of Reagan-era fraud might surpass $ 2 billion. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, a senior vice president at <PERSON> Paine </PERSON> <PERSON> Webber </PERSON>, had been scheduled to appear before the subcommittee July 28 but asked for a continuance because <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON> had to undergo emergency surgery three days before. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> refused to grant a continuance and ordered <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> to appear without counsel or with another attorney. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> refused, but <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> nonetheless called him to the witness table at the hearing, then launched into a lengthy attack on him when he failed to appear. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> said <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> had `` joined a lucrative fraternity of former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> employees'' that had `` cashed in so spectacularly on moderate rehabilitation programs.'' Other panel members joined in criticizing <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, and the committee later issued subpoenas requiring <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> to produce myriad records of his HUD-related dealings by Friday. <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON>, in the letter to <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, said the chairman and the subcommittee members and staffers had ignored <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>'s right to counsel and instead grandstanded for the television audience. `` You went through the charade of calling Mr. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> to the witness table in front of live television cameras knowing all along that he had courteously informed you that he would not appear,'' <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON> said in the letter. `` The conduct of certain members of the subcommittee and of its staff in dealing with Mr. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> ... have made it abundantly clear that they have adversely prejudged Mr. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> and have no intention other than to publicly vilify him in order to achieve their own personal motivation,'' the letter said. `` This fact is further buttressed by the vindictive subpoenas issued to Mr. <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON> said the subpoenas included demands for numerous documents the subcommittee has access to and a demand that he appear before the panel Sept. 27 _ an appearance that would be a month later than <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON> sought when he asked for the continuance. `` This raises a question as to the urgency which prompted the denial of his initial request for a short continuance,'' <PERSON> Banoun </PERSON>'s letter said
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0255EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DC-10-Controller Bjt 880 08-19 0805</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-DC-10-Controller, Bjt, 880</SECOND>
<HEAD>Controller Cries After Helping Bring Down DC-10</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-DC-10-Controller-Excerpts</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT YANCEY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> was cool, calm and unflappable during the 36 minutes that fate teamed him with a veteran pilot trying to land a damaged DC-10 at the <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, airport last month. But the 27-year-old air traffic controller who had completed his training just three months earlier broke into tears after <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> Flight 232 touched down, cartwheeled and burst into flames. Of the 296 people aboard the jetliner en route from <LOCATION> Denver </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION>, 111 were killed. That 185 survived is widely credited to the performance of pilot <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> and rescue-response efforts on the ground. Listening Friday to a <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> tape of his radio interchanges with <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> recalled his thoughts at the time as alternating between pessimism and optimism. `` Right after it happened, I had to turn away, because I did n't think anybody would come away from it,'' <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> said `` And then I went downstairs and cried.'' While he had heard reports of some survivors, <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> said it was n't until five hours after the crash _ and after he had left work _ that he learned watching the news on television that more than half those aboard had survived. `` You just try to wonder what you could have done differently,'' <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> said. `` The first couple of days afterward, I did n't sleep at all.'' Later, he concluded he would not have done anything differently. Neither, apparently, would any of his bosses. `` There was not a controller there that was not doing his job,'' said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> air traffic manager at <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. `` There's no sign that anyone failed to do their job. While an investigation into the crash is continuing and officials have yet to pinpoint its cause, <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Skinner </PERSON> was so satisfied with <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON>'s role that he presented him with a medal Friday for outstanding job performance. It was 3:23 p.m. CDT on July 19 when air traffic controllers in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> notified <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> that a stricken jetliner 40 miles away was headed for the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> airport. Three minutes later, <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> were having their first conversation. `` OK, so you know we have almost no control ability, very little elevator and almost no aileron,'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON>. `` We are controlling the turns by power. ... We can only turn right, but we ca n't turn left.'' Ten minutes later, the pilot, with a gasp in his voice, tells <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON>: `` I have serious doubts about making the airport. Have you got some place near there that we might be able to ditch? Unless we get control of this airplane, we're going to put it down, wherever it happens to be.'' While <ORGANIZATION> FAA </ORGANIZATION> officials on the ground scrambled to pinpoint possible highways where the jetliner could land, <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> several times directed <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> to change his course to keep away from populated areas. `` Widen out just slightly to your left ... to take you away from the city,'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> is told just eight minutes before the crash. `` Whatever you do, keep us away from the city,'' the pilot radios back. Three minutes later, <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> asks for possible alternatives to the airport. `` We're going to have to put it down on something solid, if we can.'' At 3:57 p.m., <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> says, `` Ah, United 232, if you can not make the airport, sir, there is an interstate that runs north to south to the east side of the airport. It's a four-lane interstate.'' `` We're just passing it right now,'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> responds. `` We're going to try for the airport. At 3:58 p.m., <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> to <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON>: `` Have runway in sight. We'll be with you very shortly. Thanks a lot for your help.'' <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> gives <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> figures on wind speed and direction and tells him, `` You're cleared to land on any runway.'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> chuckles, breaking the tension for a brief moment. He quips, `` You want to be particular, and make it a runway, huh?'' <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> tells <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> about a runway on the same path as the plane that has been closed because of lack of use. `` We're pretty much lined up on this one, or we think we'll be,'' <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> says. At 3:59 p.m., <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> asks <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> for the length of the unused runway and is told it is 6,600 feet. He's also told assembled rescue vehicles are being cleared from it. `` At the end of the runway, it's just a wide open field,'' <PERSON> Bachman </PERSON> says. `` So, sir, the length wo n't be a problem.'' Four seconds later, <PERSON> Haynes </PERSON> replies: `` OK'' Eight seconds later _ at 45 seconds after 3:59 p.m. _ a ground proximity warning horn on the plane goes off. A voice says, `` Pull up, pull up.'' The tape goes silent. United 232 is down.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0256EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Bush     08-19 0465</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush,490</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Says It's Premature to Consider Increasing Aid to Poland</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Lead prospects uncertain. Boat inspection planned for 1:30 p.m.
EDT</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RITA BEAMISH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENNEBUNKPORT, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration says it's premature to consider increasing economic aid to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> as the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bloc </LOCATION> nation moves to install its first non-communist government in more than 40 years The traveling White House of vacationing President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> issued a guarded reaction Friday to news that a Solidarity activist would be named prime minister. `` It's going to take a good deal of patience and determination, persistence -LRB- for any government -RRB- to carry out an economic reform program that will turn things around there,'' said press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` We will continue to watch the process and will increase aid as appropriate and as we can,'' he said about the possibility of more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to encourage pluralistic leanings. `` It's really premature to think along those lines,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, adding that <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> budget constraints mean `` we do n't have a lot of money to offer.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> announced an aid package totaling $ 119 million during his trip to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> last month. The president was keeping abreast of the situation in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and elsewhere while on his vacation in this resort town. Today, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was to have his speed boat, <ORGANIZATION> Fidelity </ORGANIZATION>, inspected by the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>. The White House arranged a high-profile inspection, with the president receiving a safety certificate and making remarks as a public service announcement on boat safety. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said the administration was still waiting to see how events unfold in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. `` It's too early at this point to know how they -LRB- <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s leaders -RRB- are going to make it work, let alone how it will work,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> told reporters Without delving into specific analysis of the events, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> for the second consecutive day indicated the administration is pleased with the general direction of events in <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. On Thursday, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> had described <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>'s move toward a non-communist government as `` remarkable and history making.'' Privately, administration officials said they were pleased that Polish President <PERSON> Wojciech </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaruzelski </PERSON> had chosen Solidarity journalist <PERSON> Tadeusz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mazowiecki </PERSON>, a close associate of Solidarity leader <PERSON> Lech </PERSON> <PERSON> Walesa </PERSON>, to be prime minister. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> continued to vigorously enjoy his vacation, which began Wednesday. He went boating and golfing with family members visiting the family compound on <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>'s Point. All of <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s five children and his grandchildren were on hand or were expected this weekend. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was cheery as he practiced his trademark rapid-fire golf style, finishing 18 holes in 1 hour and 51 minutes. As he teed off on the first hole, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> joked to watching reporters: `` The crowd is hushed. They sense that ` Mr. Smooth.' is back.'' `` Mr. Smooth'' is a favorite name <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> uses for himself when playing golf and horseshoes.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0259EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Ethiopia     08-19 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Ethiopia,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Relations on Upswing as Soviets, Cubans Loosen Ties</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration's campaign to improve ties with <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> is getting a lift from reports that some 2,000 Cuban troops are preparing to leave the African nation. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> also is loosening its ties to <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>, but hundreds of Soviet advisers and East German military and security personnel apparently will remain after the <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> withdrawal. The death in an airplane crash last week of Rep. <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Leland </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> Democrat who was a strong friend of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> in his crusade against hunger, sparked a cooperative search that also is helping to improve <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations. Senior <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials said they wanted to see the process accelerated. But, they said, two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> conditions must be met. Those conditions are a continuing improvement in human rights and a serious effort by <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION> to reconcile with separatists in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Eritrea </LOCATION> region and an autonomous movement in <LOCATION> Tigray </LOCATION>. But in a brief statement Friday, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said it `` continues to support the territorial integrity of <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>.'' That means the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is opposed to a separate Eritrean state. The prospect of Cuban troops leaving <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> is also welcome news to the administration. The Cubans are stationed in the <LOCATION> Ogaden </LOCATION> region, along the border with <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>. In 1978 and 1979, <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> used a force of 12,000 to 17,000 Cubans along with Soviet advisers to expel troops from <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION>. The remaining Cubans mostly are on sentry duty. There is no sign that <LOCATION> Somalia </LOCATION> intends to become embroiled again in a conflict with <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION>. Diplomatic sources, declining to be identified, said all the Cubans apparently would be withdrawn. While <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> does not receive foreign aid, it is eligible for humanitarian assistance. During a 1988 famine, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> provided about $ 120 million _ the largest outlay to any African country that year. The fact that there are about 2,000 political prisoners in <LOCATION> Ethiopia </LOCATION> is considered a much larger obstacle to friendlier <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> relations than the governing Marxist philosophy in <LOCATION> Addis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ababa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890819-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-08-19-89 0302EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PhoneStrikes     08-19 0648</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Phone Strikes,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bell Atlantic, Pacific Telesis Report Progress</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
