<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PrisonCrash     04-19 0230</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Crash,0236</SECOND>
<HEAD>Charges Filed In Miami Helicopter Escape Attempt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A convict serving a life sentence for drug smuggling and the helicopter pilot who tried to spring him from prison but crashed were charged Tuesday with conspiracy and attempted escape. <PERSON> Ben </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, a nationally known powerboat racer serving a life sentence for marijuana smuggling, and sea-urchin diver <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, both 34, were charged Tuesday afternoon as they recuperated at <ORGANIZATION> Jackson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Memorial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> crashed Monday as his two-seater Bell helicopter snagged on a 14-foot wire security fence around the <ORGANIZATION> Metropolitan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> during an attempt to take <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> out of a recreation yard. <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> suffered a compound fracture to his left ankle and was listed in satisfactory condition. <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, with two broken legs and injuries to the head, neck and back, was in good condition. A court appearance has not been scheduled yet. `` <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> started to take off from the compound with <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON> hanging to the helicopter skids attempting to enter the cockpit,'' marshal <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Figmik </PERSON> wrote in the arrest affidavit. `` The helicopter's blades became entangled in a security fence and the helicopter crashed.'' Authorities say <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>, who most recently lived on the <LOCATION> Oregan </LOCATION> coast, was an amateur pilot just learning to fly helicopters. In December, he paid $ 35,000 in cash for the chopper from a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> flight instructor and got four hours of flying instruction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0126EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-DartmouthReview     04-19 0288</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Dartmouth Review,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Dartmouth Students Appeal Federal Lawsuit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HANOVER, N.H. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Three <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> students have appealed the dismissal of their lawsuit against the college, which they claim discriminated against them because of their race and conservative beliefs, a lawyer said Tuesday. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Shane </PERSON> <PERSON> Devine </PERSON> last month dismissed a lawsuit filed by the three white students, who were suspended after a February 1988 classroom confrontation with <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON>, a black music professor. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Hinsdale </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ill. </LOCATION>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sutter </PERSON> of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION> and <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Quilhot </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Wayne </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, worked for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Review </ORGANIZATION>, a conservative off-campus weekly newspaper that had described <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> as part of `` <ORGANIZATION> Dartmouth </ORGANIZATION>'s Dynamic Duo of Mediocrity.'' They accused Cole of grabbing Quilhot by the arm and breaking the flash on his camera during the encounter, but a campus disciplinary board found them guilty of harassing Cole, and they were suspended in March 1988. `` It's in our best interest to go through with the appeal,'' <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> said Tuesday. The student's lawyer, <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, said the three disagreed with <PERSON> Devine </PERSON>'s ruling that, even if the students demonstrated that they were treated unfairly because of their conservative politics and affiliation with the Review, they would not have a case under the racial discrimination statutes they cited. The appeal was filed Monday in the 1st U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Sutter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> successfully sued the school in state court to have their suspensions lifted in December, but <PERSON> Sutter </PERSON> dropped out last month, four months before he was to graduate. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Mohl </PERSON> ordered <PERSON> Baldwin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sutter </PERSON> reinstated on the ground that one member of the panel that disciplined them had been biased against the Review.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ValedictorianSnub     04-19 0393</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Valedictorian Snub,0402</SECOND>
<HEAD>Principal Vetoes Article About Pregnant Valedictorian</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A high school principal has pulled a story from the school newspaper about the senior class valedictorian, a straight-A honors student who is pregnant with her second child. <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, principal of <ORGANIZATION> Jack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Yates </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, vetoed an article by a student reporter about <PERSON> Carrie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mae </PERSON> <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, who is five months pregnant and carries a full load of classes, including physics, calculus and economics. The story, titled `` Against all odds ... Student becomes valedictorian despite motherhood,'' details Miss <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>'s first pregnancy, how she was shuffled among relatives after her mother died and her stepfather deserted her and eight siblings, and her dream of a `` middle-class home and a middle-class life.'' Miss <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, who spends two to five hours a night with her books, has no one to baby-sit her 18-month-old daughter, <PERSON> Terrisha </PERSON> <PERSON> KeAndrea </PERSON>. She keeps the child occupied with paper and a pencil, and `` she writes while I write.'' Miss <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON>, 17, has been accepted to the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> and has two scholarships. She plans to major in chemical engineering. A school reporter first tried to do a story about Miss <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> last year after she was spotted on a cold, rainy day standing at a bus stop, holding an umbrella over her daughter, while studying a math text. A school official blocked the story. According to newspaper editor <PERSON> Shuronda </PERSON> <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> rejected the story Thursday when she submitted the newspaper for approval. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> told reporters Tuesday that he thought the article was too personal to be printed in the newspaper, and <ORGANIZATION> Houston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> Superintendent <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> agreed. `` In his judgment, the article was too highly personal, sensitive to the young lady, and he did not permit it to be published,'' she said. `` I have read the article myself, and I will further tell you that I would have made the same decision.'' Miss <PERSON> Robinson </PERSON> said the newspaper staff offered to edit the story to satisfy <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, but the offer was rejected. He also rejected a request to run a blank space or the word `` censored'' in place of the story. Although Miss <PERSON> Dixon </PERSON> has worried the school officials will bar her from giving her valedictory address on graduation night June 10, Ms. <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> said she will be allowed to speak and participate in any graduation activity.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0136EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Cambodia-France     04-19 0273</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Cambodia-France,0281</SECOND>
<HEAD>France Sends Arms To Cambodian Resistance For The First Time</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BANGKOK, Thailand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> for the first time has sent arms to guerrillas fighting <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s occupation of <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, newspapers today quoted a senior Thai officer as saying. The shipments are going to the forces of Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>, president of the three-party guerrilla coalition, said Gen. <PERSON> Sunthorn </PERSON> <PERSON> Kongsompong </PERSON>, the armed forces chief of staff. The latest shipment arrived a few days ago, <PERSON> Sunthorn </PERSON> was quoted as saying Tuesday, according to <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bangkok </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>, Thai <PERSON> Rath </PERSON> and other newspapers. The arms are being shipped through Thai territory to the guerrillas on the Thai-Cambodian border, the newspapers said. The reports said <PERSON> Sunthorn </PERSON> dismissed concerns the aid may affect <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s plan to and withdraw all its troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> by Sept. 30, ending a 10-year military occupation. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> has demanded a simultanous halt in outside military aid to the guerrillas. <PERSON> Sunthorn </PERSON> said the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s main source of foreign aid, will continue to pressure <LOCATION> Hanoi </LOCATION> for a pullout. The resistance receives the bulk of its weapons from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The strongest <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> resistance group, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, seized power in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in 1975 and over the next four years killed hundreds of thousands of people as they tried to create a primitive agrarian society. <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> invaded in December 1978 and ousted the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> has been a strong diplomatic supporter of the resistance and has played host to talks between <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hun </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, the prime minister of the Vietnamese-installed government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>. The French made <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> a protectorate in 1864 and granted independence in 1953, with <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON> as its leader.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-JetTurnsBack     04-19 0194</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Jet Turns Back,0199</SECOND>
<HEAD>United Jet Turns Back With Engine Problems</HEAD>
<DATELINE>AUCKLAND, New Zealand (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 en route to <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> turned back to <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION> today when an engine overheated soon after takeoff, the airline said. The plane landed normally with one of its four engines shut down, said <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodge </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s manager for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>. He said the pilot shut down the engine down when he realized it was overheating. The plane was carrying 173 passenger and 18 crew members. The passengers were transferred to an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zealand </ORGANIZATION> flight, which left soon after. `` It was a non-emergency. The pilot did n't have to dump fuel,'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Merlini </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION>'s manager for <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. United has had a rash of problems in recent weeks. In February, a cargo door blew out on a jumbo flying the 811 route from <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION>, sweeping nine people to their deaths. Late last month, a <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> 747 turned back to <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION> 45 minutes after takeoff when an engine failed, and earlier this month a jumbo damaged its undercarriage during a heavy landing at <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> on the flight from <LOCATION> Auckland </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0218EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Thatcher     04-19 0218</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Thatcher,0224</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcher Says She Survived Assassination Attempt By Chance</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was quoted today as saying an aide who demanded a policy decision at 2 a.m. probably saved her life in 1984 when the <ORGANIZATION> IRA </ORGANIZATION> blew up the hotel where she was staying. She was quoted as saying in an interview with Readers Digest that she was about to go bed after working in her hotel suite until 2:45 a.m. when her private secretary, <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>, insisted upon a decision. She had been up polishing her keynote address to her <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s annual conference. `` He thrust a set of papers into my hand and while I was reading them, the explosion went off,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was quoted as saying. `` Had I not been reviewing those papers, I would have gone straight into the bathroom. Another person whose bathroom was a few floors above mine had done exactly that and was virtually blown to bits.'' The Oct. 12, 1984, explosion wrecked the hotel where Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> and most of her Cabinet were staying for the convention in <LOCATION> Brighton </LOCATION>, killing five people and injuring 30. The <ORGANIZATION> Irish </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> is fighting to push the British out of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION>, join it with the <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ireland </LOCATION> and set up an all-Ireland socialist state.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0221EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:MovieAds     04-19 0927</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Movie Ads,0949</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Movie Ads People Love To Hate</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRETEL WIKLE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>DETROIT (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Put some racy, glittery commercials with lots of naked bodies on movie screens in <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> and the audience goes wild. But do the same thing in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> _ with the glitz but without the nudity _ and the ads go over as big as sticky floors, stale popcorn and overpriced candy. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dodderidge </PERSON>, senior vice president for corporate marketing at <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mo. </LOCATION>, said when <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION> tried the ads in theaters, audiences went beserk. `` There was public displeasure indicated by throwing popcorn boxes at the screen and people wanting their money back,'' he said. `` They left home to avoid commercial television. They paid money and expected relief.'' `` I've been in theaters where people booed,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Lippert </PERSON>, advertising critic for Ad Week magazine. `` On paper they sound great ... but they can only be successful if they're really artfully done and surprising.'' In <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, audiences get about 30 minutes of commercials, which must by law be 90 percent entertainment. In American theaters, though, audiences who are often asked to pay as much as $ 10 a ticket, resent the intrusion. The ads would have more staying power if they helped lower ticket prices, said <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Swanson </PERSON>, senior vice president of sales and marketing for <ORGANIZATION> Modern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Talking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, which distributes corporate-sponsored films. He recalled a recent movie outing with his family in which he paid $ 22 for four tickets _ after a $ 50 dinner check. `` If I'd have sat there and seen a commercial I'd have been peeved.'' `` Nobody likes commercials,'' said <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Laughren </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Screenvision </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cinema </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION>, a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York-based </LOCATION> company that distributes commercials. `` But there's a tremendous fascination in this country for good advertising.'' The clutter of commercials on television has been one force behind the advertisers' quest for a more captive audience. <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motors </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, 7-Up, Dr Pepper, <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> jeans, <ORGANIZATION> Pepsi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, Memorex and the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marines </ORGANIZATION>, have reeled out dollars to give movie advertising a try. `` It seems to be growing pretty steadily,'' said <PERSON> Larissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexandra </PERSON>, vice president of <LOCATION> Screenvision </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. `` With TV, what you are trying to do is talk through clutter to get some attention. There's no chance to get the emotional aspects of the product.'' Creators insist the ads are distinctly different from typical TV commercials, and some of them can be edited for television. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Danzer </PERSON>, national advertising manager for <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION>, said the directors hired to do the ads often have experience with feature films and stunts such as car chases. He refused to divulge how much <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> spends on theater ads. One of <LOCATION> Screenvision </LOCATION>'s most recent commercials features <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION>. `` It is hard to find anybody who reacts negatively,'' said <PERSON> Laughren </PERSON> about the ad. `` To the concept, yes, there is negative reaction, but then they say, ` Oh god! That was a great commercial.''' In the <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> ad, which <PERSON> Danzer </PERSON> likens to the adventure formula of `` Raiders of the Lost Ark,'' a man dreams he's being chased through a jungle in his <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> four-wheeler by an imaginary threat. There's no dialogue until he wakes up, looks out his window and sees his <ORGANIZATION> Toyota </ORGANIZATION> sitting outside. Then an announcer says: `` Toyota's new V64X4 Get it ... before it gets you.'' <PERSON> Danzer </PERSON> did n't know if the ads helped sales, but he said they were especially good at reaching males 18 to 34 years old, who are typically light TV viewers. `` In the theater 95 percent of the people see your ad,'' <PERSON> Danzer </PERSON> said. `` They might be eating popcorn, but they see the ad. With television you have no idea whether they are going to look at it.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernacchi </PERSON>, a professor of marketing at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Detroit </ORGANIZATION>, has studied theater advertising and thinks companies increasingly will want to see their products featured on the big screen. `` Right now it's an outstanding way to communicate with consumers,'' he said. `` Viewers will tend to ... receive them with more interest and maybe chagrin. They may reject them in their hearts, but they are probably going to stay in the saddle and witness them.'' The reason is a moviegoer's state of mind. <PERSON> Bernacchi </PERSON> said the expectation is much different when people actually seek entertainment. `` Few people go to the movies with the idea of just sitting and casually attending. You go there with a purpose,'' he said. <PERSON> Bernacchi </PERSON> thinks the ads will thrive because in theaters there is much less competition for a viewer's attention, and because the cinema, unlike VCRs, do n't offer the option of hand-held controls. However, some theater chain executives are less optimistic. They say reaction from audiences has been so overwhelmingly negative they risked losing business if they did n't pull the ads. `` We've tried it from time to time in different parts of the country,'' said <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> regional manager for General Cinema. `` The company felt the good will between the patrons and the company was somewhat compromised, and we valued the good will of the patrons more than running the ads.'' <PERSON> Duncan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Dodderidge </PERSON> said they were n't aware of any plans by their respective companies to try the ads again, but that's not to say their theaters are without commercials. Both General Cinema and <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION> feature ads on slides. `` The slides are very low key,'' said <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Katcher </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> district manager for <ORGANIZATION> AMC </ORGANIZATION>. `` You do n't have to watch them if you do n't want to. Nobody complains about them.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0222EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-JapaneseSchool     04-19 0773</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Japanese School,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>First Fully Accredited Japanese High School in America To Open</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM SHARP</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SWEETWATER, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many Japanese workers transferring to their companies' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> branches have a problem: American schools do n't prepare their children for the tough competition to get into a Japanese university. <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s solution _ and a testament to the growing Japanese presence in this country _ is <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Meiji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gakuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> High </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION>, which will be the first fully accredited Japanese high school in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> when it opens May 10. `` Our goal is to give education to the children of overseas assigned business people,'' though the first class of 25 includes only one student whose family lives in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said director <PERSON> Hiroshi </PERSON> <PERSON> Jo </PERSON>. `` Although we said it will be for American-based people, it will be two to four years before we have enough enrollment to operate that way,'' <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said. He said families in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> may have been more familiar with the parent school, <ORGANIZATION> Meiji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gakuin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, than workers already in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Nothing is more important to Japanese families than the education of their children,'' said former Gov. <PERSON> Lamar </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tennessee </ORGANIZATION> and scheduled keynote speaker for the opening. `` College entrance is very competitive and determined almost exclusively by results. `` If they fall behind while they're in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION>, that is a very dramatic problem for a Japanese family.'' Owned and operated by the <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> university with the support of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Education </ORGANIZATION>, the coed school will open with grades 10, 11 and 12 on the Japanese school year, April through March with 250 days of class. School was to start Saturday, but students and teachers ran into problems getting visas, <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said. `` I think maybe because this is the first Japanese high school, -LRB- immigration officials -RRB- are carefully handling reviewing this matter.'' Sending a student to <ORGANIZATION> TMG </ORGANIZATION>, as it's called, will cost about $ 19,000 a year. `` It may be more expensive than some can afford, but many send kids to colleges that are quite expensive,'' <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said. `` I also think some companies will begin to subsidize overseas education. That need is more and more confirmed by both the people of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and the government.'' The academic life will be pretty restrictive, he said. `` They will have to check out of the dorms if they want to leave. And they will have a lot of study requirements that will take a lot of their time.'' But the students, expected to number around 200 within two years, will be encouraged to take advantage of being in another country. They will go to class six days a week, as in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, but the sixth day will be for outside activities. `` The students will certainly have a lot of contact with the community,'' <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said. `` The students can do regular high school studies, plus have such a valuable experience as living in this country.'' For <LOCATION> Sweetwater </LOCATION>, a town of 5,310 between <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Chattanooga </LOCATION>, it could be sort of a stay-at-home cultural exchange program. `` It will be a culture shock both ways, for the Japanese coming here and for the community. Their philosophies of education and living are different, so I think it will be an educational experience for all of us,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Sweetwater </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamberlain </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> Meiji </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gakuin </ORGANIZATION> paid $ 2.4 million for 144 rolling acres and 13 buildings, including two gymnasiums, a library and three dormitories that can house a total of 220 students. It spent $ 1.5 million on renovation. <ORGANIZATION> TMG </ORGANIZATION> recruited in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and hired 12 teachers, four of whom _ two single people and a married couple _ will live on campus. The teachers will be paid what their counterparts in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> are paid. `` There were many applications for every subject,'' <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>, who as governor from 1979-1987 heavily recruited Japanese businesses, said the school `` could be a magnet for industry, and I think it will be a wonderful thing for our own educational system because it will give us a basis for comparison. I think it's healthy to have. It means we do n't have to go half way around the world to discover what the competition is doing.'' There are 71 Japanese-owned businesses in <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> employing 12,600. The largest is the <ORGANIZATION> Nissan </ORGANIZATION> truck plant in <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>. Others include <ORGANIZATION> ACOM </ORGANIZATION>, which makes <ORGANIZATION> Panasonic </ORGANIZATION> electric components in <LOCATION> Knoxville </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>; <PERSON> Matsushita </PERSON>; and <ORGANIZATION> Komatsu </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> TMG </ORGANIZATION> will employ 12 people from <LOCATION> Sweetwater </LOCATION> and the surrounding area, eight of them full-time _ including two cooks. `` They are in <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Jo </PERSON> said, `` So they should eat some American food. Spaghetti. Cheeseburgers.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0225EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SkinheadRecruits     04-19 1201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Skinhead Recruits,1237</SECOND>
<HEAD>Elder Statesman of Hate Passes Torch to Young Skinheads</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HAYDEN LAKE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 After years of preaching racism and hatred, the Rev. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> has lost some of his fire and brimstone. At 71, he walks slowly and breathes with difficulty, still weak from a heart attack suffered two years ago while awaiting trial on charges of scheming to overthrow the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. Many followers of his white supremacist Aryan Nations church have been jailed, or scared off by <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> investigations and publicity from civil rights organizations. But this aging `` Aryan warrior'' hangs onto his dream of an all-white homeland in the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION>, seeking inspiration from an unlikely source _ skinheads. `` They're the last hope, the only hope, of the white race,'' he said in an interview with The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Where others see menacing young thugs who shave their heads and tattoo their bodies with swastikas, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> sees the next torch-bearers of racism. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> is sponsoring the first national neo-Nazi skinhead conference here this weekend to mark the 100th birthday of <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>, on April 20. The meeting worries law officers and rights activists, who until recently were noting with satisfaction that membership in racist hate groups seemed to be declining nationwide. `` Now, with skinheads, you have a pool of violence-prone, ideologically sympathetic people who are being courted to join the mainstream of the right-wing movement,'' said <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Stern </PERSON>, northwest regional director for the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. The Jewish group notes that many skinheads band together without racist motivation. Those who can be classified as neo-Nazis, however, number about 2,000 in 21 states, with the greatest concentrations in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said. In <LOCATION> Portland </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ore. </LOCATION>, skinheads are awaiting trial in the death last November of an Ethiopian man, who was fatally beaten with a baseball bat. Another skinhead is accused of stabbing a black man in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION>. Swastikas painted on synagogues and assaults on Jews, homosexuals and other minorities have additionally been linked to skinheads in the region <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> is not alone in courting skinheads. He's competing with groups such as the <ORGANIZATION> Ku </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klux </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Klan </ORGANIZATION> and the White Aryan Resistance, led by <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Metzger </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Fallbrook </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` Until now, skinhead groups have been mostly autonomous and localized,'' <PERSON> Stern </PERSON> said. `` Any network <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> puts together bears watching.'' The network-building was visible last week as <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> and his followers prepared for this weekend's conference at his northern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> compound, 20 wooded acres tucked away on a gravel road near the resort town of <LOCATION> Hayden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. Two men hammered away in one of several rustic guest cabins. A barefoot young woman leaned over a long canvas banner, stenciling in `` Aryan Nations Now.'' Taking time for an interview in the compound's modest church, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> resembled not at all the tough, urban youths he is wooing. Dressed in a sweater vest, wool slacks and loafers, the gray-haired, bi-focaled <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> played the part of a kindly country preacher. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> shrouds his racist message in religion, using scripture to support his claims of white supremacy. He conceded that Biblical quotations may turn off skinheads, not known for steady church attendance. Many skinheads listen to the racist lyrics of <PERSON> Skrewdriver </PERSON>, an industrial-grade British rock band. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> wishes they would listen to <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>. `` We want them to be able to think,'' he said. `` You ca n't think if you're listening to the hard-rock jungle beat.'' Despite the generation gap, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> feels he offers something these alienated youths can understand: a call to power in the name of racial pride. `` The white male, through affirmative action, has been made a non-citizen,'' he said. `` This is why you have skinheads. They're beginning to wake up to the fact that they've been conquered and that the land their fathers bled and died for has been taken away. His little church in the pines has a guard tower that's higher than the steeple. Inside, sunlight filters through stained glass onto a huge Nazi flag. A poster showing a young man with an assault rifle exhorts, `` Join Us, Aryan Freedom Fighters.'' `` Kids like that kind of stuff _ it gives the idea that they're in battle,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said, quickly adding that talk of battle was only talk <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> moved to <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> in 1973 and over the years built up a following based on his dream of a `` territorial imperative'' for whites. He considered the Northwest an ideal homeland: rural, conservative and lacking many blacks, Jews and other minorities. His dream was blocked not only by resistance from local authorities but also by the violence of his own followers. Some former members, impatient with waiting for revolution, formed a group known as The Order. The group's founder, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathews </PERSON>, died in a fiery shootout with <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> agents in 1984 on an island in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Puget Sound. Ten Order members have been convicted of racketeering, and 12 more pleaded guilty to various crimes in a scheme that included murder, armored-car robberies and plots to overthrow the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government. Two years ago, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> and 14 other white supremacists were charged with plotting to overthrow the government. They were acquitted last April, but <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s arrest and the costly trial crippled his already-weakened organization. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said weekly church attendance, which once peaked at 60, now hovers around 40. Outside observers put the number even lower. An Aryan Nations computer billboard, once touted as a high-tech communications network for white supremacists, was discontinued after the computer was stolen, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. But just when his opponents figured he was washed up, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> announced plans for this weekend's skinhead conference. At first, officials expected up to 250 skinheads, and <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> promised a march down the streets of nearby <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION>. In the face of fierce opposition from locals, <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> backed off. He said he did n't want his supporters catching AIDS from counter-demonstrators. And now he says he's expecting just 75 to 100 skinheads. He's planning a weekend of lectures, karate workshops and campfire `` fellowship.'' He said lawyers will offer the skinheads tips on how to build power legally. `` I hope to keep them from going to prison or getting killed. They can do a lot more for the cause on the streets,'' <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said. `` I want them to become a political force. That can come when they have knowledge. When you have knowledge, you have power.'' The idea of a white homeland in the <LOCATION> Northwest </LOCATION> is little more than rhetoric bandied about by ideologues doomed by their own extremism and violence, said <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Kootenai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Human Relations. The group is among several planning civil rights activities this week to counter the skinhead gathering. `` These people are their own worst enemies,'' <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON> said. `` Now they're down to a church that has about 10 members and a handful of kids.'' But <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> warns against writing off the racist cause. `` The old men like myself are going to die off very soon,'' he said. `` But this is the first time that I've seen a spirit of regeneration.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0227EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SkinheadRecruits-Opposition     04-19 0536</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Skinhead Recruits-Opposition,0552</SECOND>
<HEAD>Town Stands Up to Racist Neighbor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Skinhead Recruits</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID FOSTER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>COEUR D'ALENE, Idaho (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 This quiet resort town may have been slow to recognize the racist threat of <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s neo-Nazi sect, but civil rights leaders say their vigilance is now wide-eyed and alert. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> targeted the Northwest for an all-white <ORGANIZATION> Aryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> homeland partly because of the region's conservative politics and tradition of tolerance. `` The Aryan Nations miscalculated,'' said <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Against </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Malicious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Harassment </ORGANIZATION>. `` They did not find acceptance in the Northwest.'' This week, as <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> prepares for a neo-Nazi skinhead conference at his compound a few miles from <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION>, civic leaders in northern <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> are planning a march, a picnic and an inter-faith church service to celebrate cultural diversity. <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s activities did not always provoke such responses. His Aryan Nations church, established in 1973, was all but ignored for years. `` You have a lot of kooks and nuts anywhere you go,'' said <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Kootenai </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Task </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> on Human Relations. `` In north <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>, especially, the sentiment is that you leave your neighbor alone if he wants to be left alone.'' That started to change in 1981, when swastikas appeared on a Jewish-owned restaurant in <LOCATION> Hayden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION>. The task force was formed, but community participation remained low until 1985, when court trials revealed ties between <PERSON> Butler </PERSON>'s Aryan Nations and The Order, a violent group that masterminded murder, bombings and armed bank robberies. <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION>'s live-and-let-live demeanor changed forever the morning of Sept. 29, 1986, when three bombs exploded in town, planted by white supremacists as a diversion during a foiled bank robbery. The next summer, when <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> held his annual <ORGANIZATION> Aryan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for about 200 white supremacist leaders, a civil rights rally in <ORGANIZATION> Coeur </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> d'Alene </ORGANIZATION> drew 1,000 people. The task force on human relations has served as a model for about a dozen watchdog groups now operating in the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON> said. The coalition <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> heads is another offshoot, monitoring hate crimes throughout the region. State lawmakers have also joined the fight against racism. `` <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> now has the most comprehensive anti-hate crime legislative package in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> is one of 18 states, and the only one in the <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION>, with laws against paramilitary training. A `` malicious harassment'' law makes it a felony to assault someone on the basis of race, religion or ethnic background. And that law will be strengthened by another measure passed last month. It calls for an annual report on hate crimes and requires law officers investigating any crime to note whether harassment was involved. Civil rights leaders are confident the white supremacists will never find their `` promised land'' in the Northwest. But they do not plan to relax their vigilance. `` As long as they exist in any organized form, there is going to be harassment to people of color, Jews and other minority groups,'' <PERSON> Gissel </PERSON> said. `` We're going to do whatever we can to hasten the day when those types of activities cease to occur.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Foster </PERSON> is the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> regional reporter, based in <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0712EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--BridgeCollapse     04-19 0123</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Bridge Collapse,0127</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fed Agency Backs Tennessee Bridge Inspection Program</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal agency defended the state's bridge inspection program, despite the collapse of two <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> bridges in two weeks `` They have a good program with solid routine,'' <PERSON> Ira </PERSON> <PERSON> Deggs </PERSON>, assistant director of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Highway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>'s state office, said Tuesday. Eight persons died in the collapse of a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 51 bridge over the <LOCATION> Hatchie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Memphis </LOCATION> on April 1. A teen-ager was killed when a railroad bridge collapsed near <LOCATION> Oliver </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> in east <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> on Saturday. An inspector four years ago urged repairs to the east <LOCATION> Tennessee </LOCATION> bridge, but authorities never recommended that it be closed. An inspection of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 51 bridge also warned of problems.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0232EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-PreciousWoodcarving     04-19 0347</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Precious Woodcarving,0355</SECOND>
<HEAD>Woodcarver Is Famous At Last</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A little-known early 16th-century German sculptor, <PERSON> Niclaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Weckmann </PERSON> the Elder, became a major figure in art history when a woodcarving of his sold at auction for $ 423,000, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s said `` The price was a very high one for such a work,'' said <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Wrey </PERSON>, a spokesman for the auction house, after the sale Tuesday of the Weckmann's Adoration of the <ORGANIZATION> Magi </ORGANIZATION>. The seller was described only as a continental nobleman. The buyer was anonymous but <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Avery </PERSON>, the firm's head of sculpture, said the work `` may be going back to south <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, which would be appropriate as that was <PERSON> Weckmann </PERSON>'s homeland.'' The limewood carving, more than five feet tall and four feet wide, was once part of an altarpiece and depicts the wise men presenting their gifts to the infant <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON>. `` It had been in the private chapel of a noble family in <LOCATION> Styria </LOCATION> -LRB- <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> -RRB- for 100 years or so and probably no one else saw it,'' <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> said. `` If we knew where it had been for the 300 years before that it would been even more costly as a complete antique provenance adds to value,'' he said. <PERSON> Weckmann </PERSON> lived from about 1460 to 1520. His works were attributed to other artists until 1968, when he was identified as one of the greatest sculptors working in the town of Ulm around 1500. <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> said he was so impressed by the unsigned carving when it arrived for auction that he asked for a study of it from <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Schaedler </PERSON>, chief curator of sculpture at the National Bavarian Museum in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>. `` Schaedler is the expert on <LOCATION> Weckmann </LOCATION> and he attibuted it to him on grounds of style and type. It is one of the largest and most splendid pieces of Gothic German wood sculpture to be auctioned in recent times,'' <PERSON> Avery </PERSON> added. As nothing identified as <PERSON> Weckmann </PERSON>'s work had been auctioned before, <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>'s said they were uncertain how to estimate the carving's price, at first setting it at $ 172,000 and then thinking it might go up to $ 344,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SatanSeminar     04-19 0349</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Satan Seminar,0358</SECOND>
<HEAD>Devil Worship Expert Teaches Police To Spot The Signs</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BOB McKNIGHT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A Satanism expert is teaching police at a five-day seminar that has drawn about 80 participants to recognize signs of devil worship. The State Police-sponsored seminar on cults and the occult was planned before the discovery earlier this month of a ritual mass slaying blamed on drug smugglers in <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. Even before that discovery, `` we had inquiries from law enforcement groups from throughout the state wanting to know if we had any seminars on the topic,'' <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> Lt. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Ducote </PERSON> said by telephone from <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, where the seminar is being held. `` There's a lot of interest. A lot of officers had read in the news media about areas with animal mutilations and such. They wanted some knowledge on how to recognize the signs,'' said <PERSON> Ducote </PERSON>. The five-day seminar, which began Monday and involves law enforcement officers from around the state, is taught by <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Wedge </PERSON>, author of `` The Satan Hunter.'' He has been a guest on several national television talk shows. `` I wanted to know the difference between fact and fiction, what's rumor and what's fact in what's occurring in Satanism,'' said Trooper <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON>, a homicide investigator. `` I have felt that on two or three major crimes, there was a possiblity the suspects were involved in Satanism. I want to be able to go to a scene and tell,'' <PERSON> Buckley </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Ducote </PERSON> said devil worship is not illegal. `` But most of the activity is a front for dealing in drugs,'' he said. Some ministers and businessmen recently announced plans to ask the Legislature to outlaw Satanism. Businessman <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Huenefeld </PERSON>, a bankruptcy trustee from <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON>, said the interest in satanic worship stems from drugs and <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>'s poor economy. `` I'm handling 600 bankruptcies and I can tell you the impact on the family unit,'' he said. `` The poor are looking for a way out and a few misguided ones are looking to these cults. And, drugs tend to get kids involved in these things.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0240EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     04-19 0916</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0953</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Burt </PERSON> <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>, who could n't make it to a weekend barbecue for Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON>, is n't really a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> after all. In fact, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Beach </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> reports he has n't voted since 1980 and is a registered Democrat. `` The issue is: What does a person consider himself?'' said <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON>' agent <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Gershenson </PERSON>. `` If he's technically registered as a Democrat, I know he considers himself a Republican.'' <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> was invited to the Quayle barbecue in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> but sent his regrets because he was taping his `` B.L. Stryker'' television series. Despite a Post story saying <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> was a Democrat, he told <ORGANIZATION> Jupiter </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Hinton </PERSON> that he was a Republican. Publicist <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reynolds </PERSON> registered in <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> as a Democrat in 1980 to vote for <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> because he got to know the former governor while making movies in <LOCATION> Georgia </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Sinatra </PERSON>, <PERSON> Liza </PERSON> <PERSON> Minnelli </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> received a rapturous welcome from a star-studded audience at <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>'s Royal <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> for the first of five sell-out concerts. Police outside the hall had to erect barriers to hold back crowds jostling for a glimpse of the stars at Tuesday night's show. Inside, the audience of 5,200 including <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoskins </PERSON>, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Caine </PERSON>, <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Windsor </PERSON> and many other British show business personalities sat toe-tapping and cheering in near continuous applause. The five Royal <PERSON> Albert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> concerts by the three American stars are the start of the British leg of a 23-concert world tour billed as `` The Ultimate Event.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Impressionist <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Kirby </PERSON> says he usually imitates the stars of yesteryear because the voices of today's celebrities lack character and can not be easily distinguished. <PERSON> Kirby </PERSON> said method-acting has replaced the melodrama that actors once lent to their speech. `` There are no more <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> Greenstreets, <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorres </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Cagneys </PERSON> or <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewarts </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Kirby </PERSON>, who is appearing in <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> through May 1. `` If you took three of the old-timers and put them behind a door and let them talk you can tell which is which,'' <PERSON> Kirby </PERSON> said. `` But today you put three actors in that room and you ca n't tell them apart _ except for <PERSON> Arnold </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwarzenegger </PERSON>.''
</TEXT>
<NOTE>Eds: A version of the following item moving on sports wires.</NOTE>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Cincinnati </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> manager <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> insists he has kept most of his baseball memorabilia, but admits he sold the bat he used in 1985 to break <PERSON> Ty </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>'s record. Rose sold the bat, along with a Corvette he received from <ORGANIZATION> Reds </ORGANIZATION> owner <PERSON> Marge </PERSON> <PERSON> Schott </PERSON>, to his insurance agent, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolter </PERSON>, for $ 175,000. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> still owns the bat he used for his 4,256 th and final hit, which he said he considers more significant than the one he used for No 4,192, which broke <PERSON> Cobb </PERSON>'s record. `` I've got the bat that broke the record _ it's 4,256,'' said <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>. `` The last hit I got is the record. And it will be the record until somebody gets 4,257.'' <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> put his three World Series championship rings on display Monday to counter what he says are erroneous reports that he gave his 1975 World Series championship ring to a convicted <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> bookmaker. A <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> newspaper reported Sunday that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> gave the ring to bookmaker <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Cambra </PERSON>, of <LOCATION> Somerset </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, as payment for a gambling debt. <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> said the 1975 ring that <PERSON> Cambra </PERSON> has is a replica that <PERSON> Rose </PERSON> had authorized for him. The baseball commissioner announced last month he was investigating allegations involving <PERSON> Rose </PERSON>, reportedly his gambling activities and whether he has bet on baseball games.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> is getting married next month after a long romance with a woman he met at a gas station. `` He said he liked my truck,'' said <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, 26, of their chance meeting at a <ORGANIZATION> Chevron </ORGANIZATION> station on <LOCATION> Sunset </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Boulevard </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> several years ago. <PERSON> Woods </PERSON>, 42, a rising star of movies and television, pulled up in his black Porsche while Miss <PERSON> Owen </PERSON> said she drove her `` old pickup truck with a bale of hay in the back.'' `` He said he was thinking of getting a truck and he liked mine ... a really bad line,'' said Miss <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, a co-owner of an import business. `` I mean I had about as much need for a truck as a platypus has for jumping shoes,'' <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> recalled during a stop in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week to preview `` My Name is <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> W </PERSON>,'' a made-for-TV movie about the founder of Alcoholics Anonymous that will be broadcast April 30 on <ORGANIZATION> ABC-TV </ORGANIZATION>. The couple already has moved the date of the wedding several times and has yet to commit to an exact date or location. It will be the second marriage for <PERSON> Woods </PERSON> but the first for Miss <PERSON> Owens </PERSON>. `` I always let my car go right down to empty now because its good luck to me, obviously,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Minnie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pearl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> is moving to <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Opryland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> theme park from the city's Music Row area. The new museum will open Saturday, <LOCATION> Opryland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION> officials said Tuesday. The comedian and country music star is known for her high-pitched greeting, `` Howdeee!'' and her hat, which sports a $ 1.98 price tag. Pearl, whose real name is <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Cannon </PERSON>, is a native of <LOCATION> Centerville </LOCATION>. She has been a cast regular in <LOCATION> Nashville </LOCATION>'s Grand Ole Opry since 1940.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0031EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i PM-Israel'sMorals Bjt   04-19 0818</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Israel's Morals, Bjt,0843</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reserve Officers Say They Feel Like `Stone Fodder' In Uprising</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SERGEI SHARGORODSKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JERUSALEM (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Israeli army officers serving in the occupied lands complain of feeling like `` stone fodder'' thrown into a futile battle with Palestinians and say settler and army brutality have corrupted <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s morals. `` I am reaching the end of my thoughts about Zionism in this country. My next war will be against Jews. That's what I feel,'' said one officer, <PERSON> Uri </PERSON> <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>. His comments and those of 10 other reserve officers appear in `` Commanders' Reflections,'' a 34-page booklet published by the <PERSON> Kibbutz </PERSON> <PERSON> Artzi </PERSON> movement that unites 85 of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 160-odd kibbutzim, or communal farms. The booklet, released on Tuesday, quotes remarks made by the officers, members of kibbutzim, in a February conversation with Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Amram </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitzna </PERSON>, head of the army's central command. Their ranks were not given. The officers single out army regulations on opening fire, lack of proper ammunition, pressure of increased reserve duty and their feeling of futility in dealing with the Palestinian revolt. The 16-month uprising _ known to <LOCATION> Arabs </LOCATION> as the `` intefadeh'' _ in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> has claimed at least 439 Palestinian and 18 Israeli lives. `` Once in four, five months you are called to intefadeh, and you see that nothing has changed, maybe it only got worse. I can even say that ... in a certain way, you feel like stone fodder,'' said <PERSON> Omri </PERSON> <PERSON> Frish </PERSON> of the kibbutz Mesilot. Army rules on opening fire, which forbid troops to shoot live ammunition unless a danger to life exists, still `` leave the final, last and only consideration to the lonely soldier in a side alley,'' Frish said. <PERSON> Frish </PERSON> said that as to the alternative plastic or rubber bullets, these may be hard to find. `` The means we have at our disposal ... are very poor. A soldier asks his commander, why we have no rubber bullets, or helmets, or this, or that, and it's a problem,'' he said. Other officers criticized even the use of plastic bullets. <PERSON> Avi </PERSON> <PERSON> Ofer </PERSON> of kibbutz Maanit in central <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> said rules allowing such bullets to be fired for riot dispersal were `` illegal.'' `` There are so-called ` plastic bullet ambushes.' One soldier provokes the residents, one of the duped residents hurls a stone, and another -LRB- soldier -RRB- is ready with a plastic bullet,'' said <PERSON> Dani </PERSON> <PERSON> Gal </PERSON> of the Kfar Menahem kibbutz. <PERSON> Elisha </PERSON> <PERSON> Shapira </PERSON> of <PERSON> Ein </PERSON> <PERSON> Hashofet </PERSON> said he complained to army authorities who took action against two lieutenant-colonels posted in <LOCATION> Nablus </LOCATION>, the largest <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> town. `` They engaged in manhunting ... they were just driving around, looking for a possibility to harm an Arab,'' <PERSON> Shapira </PERSON> said, without elaborating. Some officers said they reached a breaking point during night search-and - arrest raids `` I do n't think I can enter at 2 o'clock at night into a house where 10 small children are crying, and take people away, their father or somebody ... This is not my job, this is not what I was trained for in the army,'' said <PERSON> Yehiam </PERSON> <PERSON> Yogev </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Kfar </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Menahem </LOCATION>. `` I just can not do this.'' An army spokesman, asked for comment, said the military had `` no opposition to the expression of officers' opinion, as long as it's done by proper channels. He said no official statement on the booklet was expected. The spokesman, who commented anonymously in keeping with military rules, said that in specific cases, when the reservists `` see something that is not acceptable in society or in the framework of army rules, they can complain through the many existing channels, and many have done so.'' However, one senior officer indicated the army establishment was worried by the appearance of groups `` that used their military ranks for political statements.'' The booklet was especially painful for the military. Although <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s kibbutz movement is traditionally leftist, many of its members volunteer for service in elite army units, seeing it as a supreme value. The booklet also contains strong attacks on some of the 70,000 Jewish settlers living in the occupied territories among 1.7 million Palestinians. `` We have encountered ... several events in which the settlers took the law in their hands, made a real pogrom, beat the Arabs,'' said one participant, identified only as <PERSON> Yair </PERSON>. Others spoke of the existence of armed settler militias. `` I know these exist. I personally spoke to a man who told me he was organizing 40 boys with ammunition belts and radios, so they respond properly,'' said <PERSON> Dan </PERSON>, of Nir Oz kibbutz. The commanders said they opposed refusal to serve in the occupied territories, but expressed fear about the implications of the continuing conflict there on the army and on <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> society as a whole. `` They make us kill them. The Jewish people will not be able to withstand this,'' said <PERSON> Elie </PERSON> <PERSON> Ben-Gal </PERSON> of <PERSON> Baram </PERSON>. `` I am telling you, they will not be able to withstand this.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0241EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-SeasonList     04-19 0688</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-Season List,0792</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Season's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: FOX season averages not available.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the 1988-89 season. Top 20 listings include the season ranking, average rating for the season, and total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes 1. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.6 rating, 23.1 million homes. 2. `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.8, 21.5 million homes. 3. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.0, 20.8 million homes. 4. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5, 20.3 million homes. 5. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.7, 19.6 million homes. 6. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.4, 19.3 million homes. 7. `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.8, 18.8 million homes. 8. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.0 million homes. 9. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.2, 17.4 million homes. 10. `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.0, 17.2 million homes. 11. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.7 million homes. 12. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.4 million homes. 13. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.0 million homes. 13. `` Matlock,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.0 million homes. 15. `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.9 million homes. 16. `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Football,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 17. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 17. `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.4, 15.7 million homes. 19. `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.3, 15.6 million homes. 20. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.1, 15.5 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.7. 22. `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.4. 23. `` One of the Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 23. `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 23. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3. 26. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2. 26. `` NBC Monday Night at the Movies,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2. 28. `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 16.1. 28. `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' CBS, 16.1. 30. `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 15.4. 30. `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.4. 32. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3. 33. `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 15.2. 33. `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 15.2. 35. `` Nearly Departed,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 36. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.9. 37. `` ABC Monday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 38. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 38. `` ABC Sunday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 40. `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 41. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 41. `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 43. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 43. `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 45. `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 46. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 47. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 48. `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.1. 49. `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 50. `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.8. 51. `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 51. `` Father Dowling Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 51. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 51. `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 55. `` Falcon Crest,'' CBS, 12.5. 55. `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 12.5. 57. `` Hooperman,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.1. 58. `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 58. `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' CBS, 11.9. 58. `` CBS Monday Movie,'' CBS, 11.9. 58. `` Baby Boom,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 62. `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 63. `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 64. `` Miami Vice,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 64. `` Coming of Age,'' CBS, 11.1. 66. `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.0. 67. `` Paradise,'' CBS, 10.6. 67. `` Almost Grown,'' CBS, 10.6. 69. `` Beauty and the Beast,'' CBS, 10.5. 69. `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 71. `` UNSUB,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 71. `` Live-In,'' CBS, 10.3. 73. `` 48 Hours,'' CBS, 10.2. 74. `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 75. `` Heartland,'' CBS, 10.0. 76. `` ABC Saturday Night Movie,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 77. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 77. `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 9.3. 77. `` Tattinger's,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 80. `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 80. `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 82. `` Incredible Sunday,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 82. `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 84. `` Dolphin Cove,'' CBS, 8.7. 85. `` <PERSON> Sonny </PERSON> <PERSON> Spoon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 86. `` Something Is Out There,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 87. `` Police Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 88. `` Smothers Bros. Comedy Hour,'' CBS, 8.0. 89. `` ABC Family Classic,'' 7.9. 90. `` West 57th,'' CBS, 7.8. 90. `` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> <PERSON> McGuire </PERSON>,'' CBS, 7.8. 90. `` <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Dyke </PERSON> Show,'' CBS, 7.8. 93. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> Hour,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 94. `` High Risk,'' CBS, 7.6. 95. `` Dirty Dancing,'' CBS, 7.4. 96. `` <ORGANIZATION> Simon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 96. `` Knightwatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 98. `` Great Circuses of the World,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 99. `` Heartbeat,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 100. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>'s Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.3. 101. `` TV 101,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 102. `` Raising Miranda,'' CBS, 6.0. 103. `` A Fine Romance,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.4. 104. `` Studio 5B,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0242EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     04-19 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0774</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of April 10-16. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 25.4 rating, 23.0 million homes. 2. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.0, 20.8 million homes. 3. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.3, 20.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 21.5, 19.4 million homes. 4. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 21.5, 19.4 million homes. 6. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.5, 18.5 million homes. 6. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.5, 18.5 million homes. 8. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.5 million homes. 9. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 18.5, 16.7 million homes. 10. -LRB- 10 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.2, 16.4 million homes. 11. -LRB- 37 -RRB- `` A Deadly Silence'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 17.9, 16.2 million homes. 12. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.7, 16.0 million homes. 13. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 15.9 million homes. 14. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.2, 15.5 million homes. 15. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.9, 15.3 million homes. 16. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.8, 15.2 million homes. 17. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` One of the Boys,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 14.7 million homes. 17. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Country Music Awards,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.3, 14.7 million homes. 17. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 16.3, 14.7 million homes. 20. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 16.1, 14.5 million homes. 20. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` Love and Betrayal'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 16.1, 14.5 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.7. 23. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5. 23. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.5. 23. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Around the World in 80 Days,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.5. 26. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.1. 26. -LRB- 35 -RRB- `` Newly Departed,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.1. 28. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 28. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 15.0. 30. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 31. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 14.3. 32. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 33. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 13.8. 34. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 34. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 34. -LRB- 43 -RRB- `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.5. 37. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 37. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 39. -LRB- 49 -RRB- `` Kate & amp; <PERSON> Allie </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.3. 40. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 41. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Nightingales,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 42. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Dream Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 43. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 12.8. 44. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.5. 45. -LRB- 56 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 11.8. 46. -LRB- 67 -RRB- `` The Equalizer,'' CBS, 11.7. 47. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.5. 48. -LRB- 40 -RRB- `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 49. -LRB- 30 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Gideon </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON>'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 11.1. 50. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Coach,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.7. 51. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Dynasty,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 51. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Guillaume </PERSON> <PERSON> Show </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.6. 53. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Beauty and the <LOCATION> Beast </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.5. 53. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Tarzan in <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION>'' _ `` CBS Special Movie,'' 10.5. 55. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Kiss Shot'' _ `` CBS Tuesday Movie,'' 10.2. 56. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Dying Wish,'' CBS, 10.0. 57. -LRB- 52 -RRB- `` Day By Day,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 58. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Parent Trap III,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.8. 59. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.7. 60. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 9.6. 61. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Heartland,'' CBS, 9.5. 62. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.2. 63. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` UNSUB,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 64. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' 8.9. 64. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Live-In,'' CBS, 8.9. 66. -LRB- X -RRB- `` Burning Questions: Kids,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 67. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.3. 68. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 69. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` A Man Called Hawk,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 70. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Hard Time on Planet Earth,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 8.0. 71. -LRB- 94 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Henson </PERSON> Hour,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.7. 72. -LRB- 90 -RRB- `` The Return of the Shaggy Dog,'' Part 1, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Family Classic,'' 7.2. 73. -LRB- 50 -RRB- `` Moonlighting,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 74. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 75. -LRB- 99 -RRB- `` Great Circuses of the World,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.6. 76. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.1. 77. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.8. 78. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Men,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 4.2. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 79. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.0. 81. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.8. 82. -LRB- NA -RRB- `` Duet,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.3.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0251EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Nicaragua-Attack     04-19 0185</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nicaragua-Attack,0190</SECOND>
<HEAD>Three Killed In Rebel Attack</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MANAGUA, Nicaragua (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Contra rebels attacked a rural house in southeastern <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, killing three people and injuring two, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> announced. The attack, announced by the government Tuesday, occurred Monday night in the <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kama </LOCATION> area in the <LOCATION> Zelaya </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sur </LOCATION> <LOCATION> province </LOCATION>, 400 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Managua </LOCATION>. A military source said the attack was launched by `` mercenary forces loyal to the terrorist policies of former <ORGANIZATION> Somoza </ORGANIZATION> colonel <PERSON> Enrique </PERSON> <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON>, head of the Miami-based <ORGANIZATION> Nicaraguan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Resistance </ORGANIZATION>, said during talks with Nicaraguan opposition political leaders last week in <LOCATION> Guatemala </LOCATION> that he had ordered his forces to observe a cease-fire. <PERSON> Gustavo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tablada </PERSON>, a Socialist leader in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> who met with <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> last week, said <PERSON> Bermudez </PERSON> told him some rebels might be working in concert with common criminals. The Nicaraguan Resistance, which heads up the <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels, has received <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> backing to fight the leftist Sandinista government since 1981, but the Contras now receive only non-lethal aid and are mostly in Honduran camps. The Sandinistas came to power in a 1979 popular revolution by defeating former President <PERSON> Anastasio </PERSON> <PERSON> Somoza </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0258EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     04-19 0677</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0703</SECOND>
<HEAD>On The Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> is urging Californians to listen to their mothers. The governor joined <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Holt </ORGANIZATION>, the mothers of actors <PERSON> Sylvester </PERSON> <PERSON> Stallone </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cher </PERSON>, in kicking off a campaign on Tuesday to promote ride sharing and van-pool programs to help unclog freeways. But he was a little late because of traffic congestion. The campaign will feature the theme of rather universal motherly sayings. One advertisement depicts a woman who says: `` We're not the first one to try to talk some sense into you about sharing.'' Other celebrity moms taking part include <PERSON> Laurie </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, mother of comic <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, mother of <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lakers </ORGANIZATION> basketball star <PERSON> Earvin </PERSON> `` Magic'' <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>. `` Your mother, as this -LRB- campaign -RRB- says, always told you to share and it was good advice then and I think it's very good advice now, and it's going to help us to meet our transportation challenges,'' <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> said <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> is the sixth-largest economic power in the world but each day workers lose about 400,000 hours of productivity while stuck in traffic. Last year, 22.4 million vehicles were in the state and there will be 23.8 million by the century's end. There is an average of 1.2 persons per vehicle in peak hours, but congestion could be eliminated if that improved to just 1.4 per vehicle, <PERSON> Deukmejian </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>RALEIGH, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> got little attention when he introduced a bill to designate an official state dog, but now the `` Plott'' has thickened. The Senate Rules Committee quickly endorsed the bill to make the <PERSON> Plott </PERSON> hound <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>'s official dog. <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON>, a 10-year-old <PERSON> Plott </PERSON> owned by former Rep. <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, wagged her tail in silent approval. `` All other breeds pale in comparison,'' said <PERSON> Swain </PERSON>, a Democrat who said the hound is the only dog indigenous to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>. It's a favorite of mountain bear hunters, he said. `` It's the only dog I think would be proper for a state dog,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> told reporters after the meeting Tuesday. `` You talk about a <PERSON> Plott </PERSON>, you're talking about the <ORGANIZATION> Kit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carsons </ORGANIZATION>, the <PERSON> Davy </PERSON> <PERSON> Crocketts </PERSON> and the <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Boones </PERSON> of the dog world,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. `` They were frontier people, they went out hunting and lived by their instincts ... and they were from western <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>.'' The Plott hound is a descendant of a German breed used for boar hunting, <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> said. An immigrant named <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Plott </PERSON> brought it to <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> in the mid-1700s. The Plott hound is an officially registered breed, <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> said. The typical <PERSON> Plott </PERSON> has brown-black coloring and weighs about 75 pounds. `` I think without any question it has all the qualities of a good <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolinian </LOCATION>,'' <PERSON> Swain </PERSON> said. `` He's loyal, he is fearless, he has perseverance.'' The Rules Committee approved <PERSON> Swain </PERSON>'s bill without dissent. It now goes to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>JEFFERSON CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Missouri <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed a bill making the 250-million-year-old remains of a plantlike animal the official state fossil. But some senators objected to spending time on the matter with a May 12 adjournment and several major bills pending. `` Is it any coincidence that you are trying to make the state fossil a spineless animal?'' Sen. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> asked Tuesday. `` What's next Perhaps the bat will be the state bird because it's blind.'' The state bird is the bluebird. <PERSON> Nixon </PERSON> said the crinoid fossil bill `` reflects the quality of legislation so far this session.'' He said he was concerned the headlines would read, `` <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> spends afternoon making spineless wimp the state fossil.'' But the bill's sponsor, Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, called the measure an important civics lesson for an eighth-grade science class in his district that first proposed it. `` Now they've seen an idea from their classroom go through both chambers for a possible signing by the governor,'' he said. Crinoids, commonly known as sea lillies, flourished 250 million years ago when most of <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> was covered by shallow seas. They are found throughout the state, mainly in limestone deposits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0116EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PapLab     04-19 0356</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pap Lab,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Closed Lab told To Pay For Millions Of New Pap Tests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State health officials ordered a laboratory to offer to pay for repeat Pap smear tests for more than 3 million women diagnosed as cancer-free after learning the lab's error rate was greater than 20 percent. <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pathology </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Tarzana </LOCATION>, which has performed 3.3 million Pap smears over the past five years, was ordered closed last week after a state audit showed an error rate of 21.2 percent among 1,103 tests selected at random. `` It was a sloppy operation,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON> <PERSON> Kizer </PERSON>, state health services director. `` It was totally unacceptable that they had such a high error rate.'' The lab, which also worked under the name <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Diagnostic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION>, processed nearly 700,000 smears last year, more than half of all of the tests in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. Pap smears from <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Philadelphia </LOCATION> were processed at the company's <LOCATION> Tarzana </LOCATION> area lab. In its order delivered to the lab Monday, the health department said all women in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and other states who had received reports indicating no abnormalities from either Central Pathology or Central Diagnostic within the last five years needed to be offered the opportunity for a repeat Pap smear. The lab, which closed Monday, was given 30 days to contact the women and recommend they see their doctors about retaking the tests elsewhere. Central Pathology said in a statement it was `` a 27-year-old facility with a perfect inspection record to this point'' and that it had recently instituted what it called `` the most stringent quality-control standards in the nation.'' The Pap smear, which costs about $ 25, is a routine test used to detect cervical cancer and other medical abnormalities. The industry average for misdiagnosing Pap smears is about 5 percent, but some pathologists said top labs make even fewer mistakes. <PERSON> Kizer </PERSON> said state officials plan to inspect 10 other Pap smear laboratories within the next six weeks. He did not identify them. `` We need to get an idea of the other labs' error rates and set some kind of standard,'' <PERSON> Kizer </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0311EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e BC-Manilow     04-19 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Manilow,0308</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barry Manilow Opens for Month on Broadway</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON>, master of the big ballad, brought his talent for showmanship to <LOCATION> Broadway </LOCATION> on Tuesday night for a month-long engagement. Mixing show-biz sophistication with pure corn, `` <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON> at the Gershwin'' is strong entertainment. The production is sleek, with costumed backup singers and projections on the back wall. <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON> inserts a rock beat in a few numbers, tackles the Motown sound a couple of times, and does one superfast <PERSON> Lambert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hendricks </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ross </PERSON> jazz number, `` Cloudburst,'' that he admired early. Though he's no slouch with those styles, the lengthy romantic ballad, given a big buildup to an emotional finish, is his strongest suit. He started the second half of the evening with three new songs of that type, pointing up once again that his style is grounded in a performance tradition older than rock. In an autobiographical portion of the show, the singer-pianist picked up the accordion, which he said he learned -LRB- and hated -RRB- at age 11, two years before he learned piano. In front of a set representing the <LOCATION> Brooklyn </LOCATION> apartment where he grew up, he demonstrated that even <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Springsteen </PERSON>'s `` Born in the U.S.A.'' sounds old-fashioned on an accordion. He also talked about being a pianist for singers auditioning for Broadway, but did n't mention his hitch as musical director on <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Midler </PERSON>'s 1973 tour, after which he got a recording deal and had his first hit, `` <PERSON> Mandy </PERSON>.'' <PERSON> Manilow </PERSON> ended the evening with a medley of many hits, including `` One Voice,'' `` The Old Songs,'' `` I Do n't Want To Walk without You,'' `` <LOCATION> Copacabana </LOCATION>,'' `` This One's for You,'' `` Tryin' To Get the Feeling Again,'' `` It's a Miracle,'' `` Somewhere in the Night,'' and `` I Write the Songs.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0312EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-AirToxics     04-19 0598</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Air Toxics,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Air Pollution Bill Aims at Broader Variety of Toxics</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY MARGASAK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> sponsors of a compromise bill to control airborne toxic chemicals say they expect stiff opposition, despite growing information on poisons in the nation's air. `` This bill will be critized by some for going too far, and by others who do n't think it has gone far enough,'' <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, said Tuesday after he and 11 other senators introduced the legislation. The bipartisan and diverse group said their language remains subject to hard bargaining, but emphasized they have a consensus on how to control the estimated 2.7 billion pounds of poisonous chemicals released into the atmosphere each year. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, in its first such compilation, said April 12 that the toxic air emissions are among more than 22 billion pounds of toxic wastes sent into the air, water and land each year. The legislation to control toxic emissions into the atmosphere represents a major compromise for lawmakers pushing for new clean air legislation this year. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> clean air sponsors said they will introduce the other components of their legislation in coming months: proposals to bring metropolitan areas in compliance with air quality standards, and language to control acid rain. The air toxics compromise would require companies emitting 10 tons or more of any airborne toxic chemical to install the best available control technology. The <ORGANIZATION> Environmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Protection </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> would set emissions standards for industries releasing the chemicals. But to encourage polluters to make immediate and large-scale reductions, they would be granted exemptions if they used technology that achieves a 90 percent cutback in emissions by the end of 1992. If technology did not achieve the required reduction, a company would have to meet tough emissions limits based on a chemical's risk of causing cancer or other illnesses The legislation would replace a system that has regulated only seven toxic chemicals out of nearly 300 emitted into the air. The <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> is currently required to assess the risk of each chemical, and then develop chemical-by-chemical emissions standards designed to protect public health, with an ample margin of safety. The assessment for each chemical takes several years. And when the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> has made proposals, the agency has been sued on grounds it went too far _ or not far enough. The bill also would direct <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to establish a national urban air toxics program to reduce the release of toxic chemicals from motor vehicles, wood stoves, dry cleaners and gas stations. In a provision to prevent catastrophic accidents, the bill would require <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> to list 50 extremely hazardous substances. Facilities handling those materials would have to complete reviews to identify potential accidents. A <ORGANIZATION> Chemical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> would be established to investigate accidents and make recommendations for preventive measures. Sen. <PERSON> Max </PERSON> <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>, D-Mont., the manager of <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> clean air legislation this year, told reporters, `` There is a public health crisis that will worsen if we do n't act. <PERSON> Ed </PERSON> <PERSON> Barks </PERSON>, spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coalition </ORGANIZATION>, said the environmental groups in the organization believe the bill needs improvements. He said that under the bill the <ORGANIZATION> EPA </ORGANIZATION> could take between five and 13 years to set standards for emission reduction for polluters who fail to qualify for the exemption. That timetable is too long, he said. Announcing the compromise were Sens. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Durenberger </PERSON>, R-Minn.; <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Lautenberg </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.J. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Breaux </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Baucus </PERSON>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Chafee </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-R.I. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Quentin </PERSON> <PERSON> Burdick </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.D. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Moynihan </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION>; <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>; <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Warner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Va </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Fla </LOCATION>.; <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Lieberman </PERSON>, D-Conn., and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890419-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-04-19-89 0326EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BaseClosings-List     04-19 0920</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Base Closings-List,1050</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Military Installations Affected by Commission Recommendation</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Base Closings Bjt</HEAD>
<TEXT>
