<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 2342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-SFQuake-FederalAid 4thLd-Writethru   10-25 0734</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake-Federal Aid, 4th Ld-Writethru,a0835,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>House, Senate Reach Agreement on Earthquake Aid Package</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 4th graf, bgng: White House xxx and INSERTS 1 graf following
to UPDATE with White House saying bill would be signed Thursday morning.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALAN FRAM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> Wednesday sent President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a $ 3.45 billion relief package, the largest ever for a single disaster, to help Northern Californians rebuild homes, businesses and roads shattered by last week's earthquake. Final approval in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> came on a vote of 303-107, hours after the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> voted its consent 97-1. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> had sweetened a $ 2.85 billion version of the bill passed Tuesday by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> by making an additional $ 600 million of <ORGANIZATION> Small </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Business </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> disaster loans available to companies hurt by the quake. `` This is a tremendous amount of good will,'' Rep. <PERSON> Vic </PERSON> <PERSON> Fazio </PERSON>, D-Calif., who helped lead his state congressional delegation's efforts to win federal aid, told his `` We thank all of you.'' White House spokesman <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> would sign the bill first thing Thursday morning. That was virtually a necessity, largely because the measure was attached to legislation allowing the government to continue functioning through its latest fiscal crisis. Even though the government's authority to spend money technically expired at midnight, all federal employees were to report to work as usual on Thursday morning, <PERSON> Hall </PERSON> said. The assistance was directed at what appears to have been the costliest natural disaster in American history, with damage estimates now exceeding $ 7.1 billion. The Oct. 17 quake _ measured at 7.1 on the Richter scale _ killed 63 people, with 9 unaccounted for, 3,000 injured, and nearly 14,000 homeless. The earthquake measure comes on the heels of a $ 1.1 billion relief package approved last month to help victims of Hurricane Hugo, the previous federal assistance record for a single disaster. `` It is very likely that the ultimate federal cost ... may be higher as the damage estimates continue to grow,'' warned Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, D-Calif. `` But this is a very good, very important allocation for a community that has been very badly shaken. The aid was part of a must-pass bill to keep federal agencies in business for the next three weeks. Because only two of the 13 annual appropriations bills for fiscal 1990 have been enacted, the government's authority to spend money would otherwise expire at midnight Wednesday. Fiscal 1990 began Oct. 1. The earthquake relief portion provides $ 1.1 billion for housing, families' losses, damaged public property and other assistance through the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>. It makes available $ 1 billion for highway and bridge repair, creates a $ 250 million fund for <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to distribute, and pours an additional $ 500 million into the <ORGANIZATION> SBA </ORGANIZATION>'s emergency loan pot, which previously contained $ 1 billion. It also increases by $ 600 million, to a total of $ 1.8 billion, the maximum amount of emergency loans which the <ORGANIZATION> SBA </ORGANIZATION> is authorized to make. Though the <ORGANIZATION> SBA </ORGANIZATION> would start with about $ 1.5 billion in its emergency pool, it could issue loans up to the $ 1.8 billion figure as the pool is replenished by repayments. `` People who are dislocated from their homes and businesses need that assistance now,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilson </PERSON>, R-Calif. At the insistence of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> lawmakers, the measure also clears away several bureaucratic hurdles that would have restricted the assistance It makes the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco-Oakland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>, where a section of road collapsed, eligible for federal assistance. Because it is a toll road, it would not have otherwise qualified. It also extends from 90 to 180 days the period in which <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> would not have to provide state funds to be eligible for federal assistance. In addition, $ 20 million of the funds would be used to study earthquakes and techniques to prepare for them. The quake was centered on the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Andreas </LOCATION> fault, in the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION> 56 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Some money in the bill could be used to help victims of <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> and about 19 other disaster areas that still qualify for federal assistance. The lion's share, however, is intended for victims of the earthquake. Sen. <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Humphrey </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, cast the sole vote against the bill in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, saying he did so because it exceeded the $ 2.5 billion sought by the administration and would fuel the nation's deficit Sens. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>, D-Mass., and <PERSON> Claiborne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-R.I. </LOCATION>, did not vote
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PrisonDisturbance 3rdLd-Writethru a0882 10-25 0652</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Prison Disturbance, 3rd Ld - Writethru, a0882,0669</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Prison Disturbance Erupts; Fires Set</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with riot declared over, quotes,
details. No pickup.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto HX2, HX3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID MORRIS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CAMP HILL, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 State prison inmates took eight guards hostage and set four fires in a seven-hour riot touched off when a prisoner assaulted a staff worker, officials said. At least 42 people, mostly prison employees, were injured. The disturbance at the medium-security <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Correctional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> began at 3 p.m. and ended shortly before 11 p.m., Superintendent <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said. `` The incident at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> is over. We are fully in control of the institution,'' he said. The injured included 35 guards or staff people, five inmates, including one who had been stabbed with a screwdriver, one firefighter and one state trooper, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Palakovich </PERSON>, assistant to the prison superintendent. The hostages were released by 9 p.m., but prison officials did not say how long they had been held. Formal negotiations between the inmates, who carried home-made weapons, and a team of prison guards began at 6 p.m. and the first hostages were released at 8 p.m., <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said. The inmates had demanded a press conference, changes in medical care and family visit rules and amnesty, <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said. In response to the demands, the superintendent said he plans to meet with a group of inmates on Wednesday. <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said some of the hostages had been beaten and received medical treatment, but he had no details on their condition. All cell blocks were secure and all but one fire was extinguished by 10 p.m., <PERSON> Palakovich </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Palakovich </PERSON> said the disturbance began after a staff member was assaulted by an inmate at the E gatehouse. The incident carried over to two nearby cellblock areas. Fires were started at the prison furniture factory, a commissary and another food service area, <PERSON> Palakovich </PERSON> said. A reporter for The Patriot-News said she saw a number of inmates try to crash a truck through a rear gate. There was no official confirmation of that account, but witnesses said the truck did not get through the fence. <PERSON> Freeman </PERSON> said the riot was apparently ignited by inmate anger over a recent prison ban on inmates' families bringing in homemade food, out of fears it was being used to hide contraband. The prison has 2,607 inmates, about 45 percent over capacity. The 52-acre complex about three miles from <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION> was opened in 1941 as a youth detention center and converted to adult population in 1976. The Camp Hill riot came only two days after a disturbance at the <LOCATION> Huntingdon </LOCATION> state prison injured 29 staff members and 19 prisoners. Inmates took over a cellblock Monday night for three hours, breaking windows, destroying furniture and setting several small fires, authorities said. Huntingdon is about 100 miles west of <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. State Police Deputy Commissioner <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Walp </PERSON> said 200 troopers from several barracks had been sent to help quell the disturbance at <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>. Eight people, including six guards, a prison worker and a state trooper, were taken to <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, said spokeswomen <PERSON> Claire </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>. Four of the patients were released. <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilhelm </PERSON>, 46, of <LOCATION> Harrisburg </LOCATION>, a prison guard, was admitted with an eye injury in fair condition. Fifteen prison employees were taken to <LOCATION> Holy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Spirit </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Camp </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> with minor lacerations and one broken ankle, according to spokeswoman <PERSON> Tamara </PERSON> <PERSON> Reisinger </PERSON>. Fourteen were treated and released. Two patients were transported by helicopter to the <ORGANIZATION> Milton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hershey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, where spokeswoman <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Saline </PERSON> said both were in fair condition. One patient, a guard, had injuries to the face, eye, ear and blows to the chest, Ms. <PERSON> Saline </PERSON> said. The other was an inmate who had a stab wound to the shoulder, she said. One guard was in intensive care at <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Osteopathic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> with multiple injuries, said <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Witkowski </PERSON>, nursing supervisor.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 2359EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-DoubleShooting 2ndLd-Writethru a0823 10-25 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Double Shooting, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0823,0599</SECOND>
<HEAD>Boston Riveted by Slaying of Pregnant Woman</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with seven grafs to CORRECT spelling of Caesarean in lead
and UPDATE with Mass held Wednesday night. Picks up 6th graf, `It hit...'.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ARLENE LEVINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Outrage grew Wednesday over the robbery-killing of a pregnant suburban lawyer and the wounding of her husband, while their baby born by Caesarean section struggled for survival. In housing developments, in posh hotels, in student haunts and in the streets, the talk was of the attack on <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> and her husband, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, who were abducted as they left a childbirth class at <LOCATION> Brigham </LOCATION> and Women's Hospital Monday night. Their assailant forced them to drive into the inner city area bordering the hospital. There the assailant robbed the couple and shot <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> in the abdomen, his 33-year-old wife in the head. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, 29, remained in critical condition Wednesday, a <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> spokesman said. Late in the day, Police Superintendent <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Saia </PERSON> said detectives had been able to narrow the list of suspects `` down to a chosen few'' after speaking to <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> at his hospital bedside. More than 400 people gathered Wednesday evening for a memorial Mass at a church in the same inner-city neighborhood were the attack occurred. `` The community wanted to pray for the families. We thought a Mass would be the best way to do that,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Krastel </PERSON>, rector of the <ORGANIZATION> Mission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. `` It hit home,'' <PERSON> Beryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, a prominent <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> attorney, said Wednesday as he made his way through the downtown shopping district, miles from the site of the crime. `` It's not a suburban story. It's not about rich and poor. It's not made-for-television fiction. I just called my son, who takes guitar lessons on Tremont Street -LRB- near the shooting -RRB- and told him to be careful.'' In the <LOCATION> Mission </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> area, where police found the couple shot and slumped in their car, 23-year old <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> was standing outside a liquor store with a friend Wednesday. `` The man who did it should be taken out. We got to get the death penalty back. The guy was foul. He had no heart,'' said <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON>. At a downtown cutlery store, proprietor <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Marks </PERSON> said his employees could talk about nothing but the crime and its brutality. `` It's almost too hard to look,'' the 73-year-old merchant said, `` because of its enormity and the fact that it's so needless.'' <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, 29-year-old general manager of a fur store, used a car phone to call police. Family members said the telephone was installed in Mrs. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>'s car after she became pregnant so she could remain in touch with her husband. Several hours after the shooting, a son, <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON>, was born. The mother died shortly after the birth. Hospital spokeswomen would only say Wednesday that the infant was alive. Family members said the baby had suffered seizures and there was diminishing hope for his survival. Neonatal experts said an infant delivered by Caesarean section 32 weeks after conception, as <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> was, should have a 98 percent chance of surviving. But Mrs. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>'s loss of blood in the shooting was said to harm the child's chances. `` He looked perfect. They told us to stroke his face because they said he would need a lot of love,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>'s aunt, <PERSON> Rosemary </PERSON> <PERSON> Leone </PERSON>, said after seeing the baby. `` <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> had been having a wonderful pregnancy. She wanted this baby so badly. But they do n't think there's much hope for him.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BakkerSentencing-Thumbnails     10-25 0817</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bakker Sentencing-Thumbnails,0848</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thumbnail Sketches of Figures in Bakker Trial</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bakker Sentence</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CHARLOTTE, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are descriptions of principals in the <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> fraud and conspiracy trial in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Court:
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>JIM BAKKER</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Michigan </LOCATION> native, dropped out of <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bible </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION> after less than one year of study to marry schoolmate <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> LaValley </PERSON>. He began his ministry as a traveling evangelist in the Assemblies of God and was ordained in 1964. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> was host of a Christian television show for children, which led to a regular puppet show on <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON>'s <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Network </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> started `` The 700 Club'' on <ORGANIZATION> CBN </ORGANIZATION> but left the network and eventually landed in <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> in 1974 with a Christian talk show on a UHF station. He built the single station into the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> satellite network, which grew to a $ 129 million-a-year empire, relocated his ministry in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mill </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, just outside <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, and built <ORGANIZATION> Heritage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION>, a Christian theme park. <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> resigned as <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> president in March 1987 after confessing to a sexual encounter with <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> church secretary <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON>. He turned over <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> _ which stands for Praise The Lord or People That Love _ to <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON>, who failed to keep it out of bankruptcy court. He and his wife have two children, daughter <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Sue </PERSON>, who married former <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> worker <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> Chapman </PERSON> in 1987, and son <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Charles </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>TAMMY FAYE BAKKER</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> became her husband's partner on the <ORGANIZATION> CBN </ORGANIZATION> puppet show and was his co-host on <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>. She and <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> separated briefly in 1981, and their reconciliation led to <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> marriage workshops at <LOCATION> Heritage </LOCATION> <LOCATION> USA </LOCATION>. She was treated for drug dependency in 1986 as an outpatient at the <ORGANIZATION> Betty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> after becoming addicted to tranquilizers. A self-professed chronic shopper, she was known for her sprawling closets at the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> parsonage and her heavy hand with make-up. Although she received substantial bonuses at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, she was not indicted with her husband. Recently, she has been co-host of `` The Jim And Tammy Show,'' which originates in a rundown mall in <LOCATION> Orlando </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, and is carried on eight cable channels.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>RICHARD DORTCH</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s second-in-command at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON> was a former district superintendent for the Assemblies of God in <LOCATION> Illinois </LOCATION> and was considered a top candidate to head the denomination. <PERSON> Dortch </PERSON>, who joined <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> in 1984, negotiated the $ 265,000 hush payment to <PERSON> Jessica </PERSON> <PERSON> Hahn </PERSON> and was fired at <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> after <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Falwell </PERSON> took over in 1987. He was indicted with <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, but pleaded guilty to four counts of conspiracy and fraud three weeks before their trial. He was sentenced to eight years in prison and fined $ 200,000, but his sentence could be reconsidered after <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s trial He was defrocked by the Assemblies of God along with <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> in 1987 and later moved to <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, where he started a counseling ministry for executives facing personal crises.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>DAVID and JAMES TAGGART</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Detroit </LOCATION> natives <PERSON> David </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Taggart </PERSON>, who both testified for the prosecution at <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s trial, started as piano players with <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> but soon moved up the ladder. <PERSON> David </PERSON> became <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s personal assistant, handling travel arrangements and schedules, and served as the bank for the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> entourage whenever <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> traveled. His brother became <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION>'s interior designer. Prosecutors said the pair diverted more than $ 1 million in ministry funds for their personal uses, including expensive wardrobes, jewelry and a <LOCATION> Manhattan </LOCATION> apartment. They were convicted in July of tax evasion. <PERSON> David </PERSON> was sentenced to 18 years, five months and <PERSON> James </PERSON> to 17 years, nine months in prison. The brothers were also fined $ 500,000 each.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>THE PROSECUTION</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> handled <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s case through the grand jury and trial. He was joined by <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, a fraud expert with the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>THE DEFENSE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>, relieved as defense lawyer Tuesday at his own request so he could prepare for other cases, is a noted <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> attorney whose clients have included the late Prime Minister <PERSON> Zulfikar </PERSON> <PERSON> Bhutto </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Pakistan </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Krupp </PERSON>, the German munitions manufacturer who was convicted of war crimes at <LOCATION> Nuremburg </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> has been the defense lawyer in more than 200 death penalty cases and was one of the first lawyers to use hypnosis in a criminal trial. <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Bender </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s second lawyer, is a former assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> attorney from <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> and has served as defense lawyer in several highly publicized local cases.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>THE JUDGE</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Potter </PERSON>, a conservative judge nominated by Sen. <PERSON> Jesse </PERSON> <PERSON> Helms </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.C. </LOCATION>, is known in courthouse circles as `` Maximum Bob'' for the sentences he hands down. <PERSON> Potter </PERSON> imposed a gag order on the case before it started, forbidding anyone associated with the trial from discussing it outside the courtroom. He frequently sparred with <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> during the trial, warning him about his questions and comments before the jury.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0020EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BakkerSentence-Glance     10-25 0201</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bakker Sentence-Glance,0223</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bakker Sentencing At a Glance</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Bakker Sentence, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here, at a glance, are details of the sentence given <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>, founder of the <ORGANIZATION> PTL </ORGANIZATION> television ministry:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 PRISON SENTENCE: 45 years. PAROLE POSSIBLE: After 10 years. FINE: $ 500,000. CHARGES: Eight counts mail fraud, 15 counts wire fraud and one count conspiracy to commit mail and wire fraud. MAXIMUM POSSIBLE SENTENCE: 120 years. TRIAL: Nearly six weeks long, more than 100 prosecution witness, 75 defense witnesses.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Here is a breakdown on the prison sentence: Counts 1 and 2, mail fraud, 5 years. Counts 3 and 4, mail fraud, 5 years. Counts 5 and 6, mail fraud, 5 years. Counts 7 and 8, mail fraud, 5 years. Counts 9, 10, 11, wire fraud by telephone, 5 years. Counts 12, 13, 14, wire fraud by television, 5 years. Counts 15, 16, 17, wire fraud by television, 5 years. Counts 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, wire fraud by television, 5 years. Count 24, conspiracy to commit mail and wire fraud, 5 years.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Here is a breakdown on the fine: Count 2, mail fraud, $ 100,000. Count 3, mail fraud, $ 200,000. Count 24, conspiracy, $ 200,000.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0021EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-China-Movies     10-25 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-China-Movies,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Government Reins in Newly Creative Film Industry</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Uncertain times lie ahead for <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s movie industry, which faces new political constraints just as a generation of young, ambitious directors strives to compete on international screens. Like others in the art world, studio heads and directors are waiting to see the full impact of the crackdown on liberalism that has followed the June crackdown on student-led demonstrations for democratic reform. The early signs have not been encouraging. The central government's <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, which supervises all movies, has fired the head of the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Film Studio for unspecified political errors, and sent in a special team led by bureau director <PERSON> Teng </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingxian </PERSON> to `` rectify'' the studio. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> <PERSON> Cheng </PERSON>, in charge of censorship at the bureau, said he sent `` urgent telegrams'' this fall to <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s two most innovative studios, the <ORGANIZATION> Xian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studio </ORGANIZATION> in western <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Film </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Studio </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>, warning them to `` pay special attention to problems in ideological tendencies.'' Asked what that meant, <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> laughed and said, `` When they see -LRB- the warning -RRB-, they understand.'' Film officials did not even try to select this year's best movie in the Golden Rooster competition, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s politically charged version of the Academy Awards. The selection was hard enough in past years, when awards were sometimes delayed for months while officials debated the political merits of films nominated for artistic reasons. This year, officials said no movies were acceptable. All studios, like other work units, have been ordered to hold special classes to study recent <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> documents on the battle against `` bourgeois liberalism,'' or anti-socialist ideas, and the need for art to serve socialism. <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> said at the <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>, the classes take up two half-days a week _ far more than ordinary work units. Two of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s leading film directors were overseas when the crackdown began, and one, <PERSON> Chen </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaige </PERSON>, has said he wo n't return. He plans to make a documentary about the June army attack on <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> protesters, in which hundreds and possibly thousands were killed. The other, <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> studio head <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tianming </PERSON>, has not been in touch with his studio since he left for <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> in April to attend the opening of a joint Chinese-Canadian movie about <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s first emperor. Studio officials say they do n't know if <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> will return, and <PERSON> Liu </PERSON> acknowledged it was `` hard to say'' if <PERSON> Wu </PERSON> would be allowed to keep his job if he did. <PERSON> Wu </PERSON>'s blunt criticisms of government censors long have gotten him in trouble, and his studio's movies have angered some officials by depicting rural poverty and mindless bureaucracy. But the debt-ridden studio in arid, impoverished northern <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> also has won more international prizes than any other studio, beginning with <PERSON> Wu </PERSON>'s 1987 `` Old Well,'' which won awards in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>. The movie's frank depiction of rural poverty and daring story of a love triangle set off a small storm within the Chinese movie industry, more accustomed to socialist morality tales. Young directors at other studios joined the movement to make realistic movies of modern life, adopting film techniques from abroad, and critics said <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s film industry had finally matured. No movies of the new school have been released since the June crackdown, only epics of the Communist revolution timed to celebrate the 40th anniversary of its victory in October 1949. But <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> <PERSON> Jin </PERSON>, vice president of the <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> studio, said in an interview that the <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> recently approved a movie the studio shot before June depicting smuggling and other illegal activities. Last spring, <LOCATION> Pearl </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> released what it billed as <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s `` first sex movie,'' a story of love and marriage in a 1940s fishing village `` I think we can still make this kind of movie,'' <PERSON> Wang </PERSON> said. But the studio will no longer test the censors by sending them love scenes it thinks likely to be cut _ it will make the cuts itself, he said. Directors <PERSON> Yan </PERSON> <PERSON> Xueshu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Zhou </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaowen </PERSON> at the <LOCATION> Xian </LOCATION> studio also said they hope to continue their experimental work. `` Movements happen. We are used to them,'' <PERSON> Zhou </PERSON> said. If the government insisted on changing a movie he made, he added boldly, `` I'd resign.'' `` And start your own studio?'' <PERSON> Yan </PERSON> asked him sarcastically.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-SAfrica-Thatcher     10-25 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SAfrica-Thatcher,0483</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Leader's Anti-Sanctions Stand Elicits Strong Reactions</HEAD>
<HEAD>By DAVID CRARY</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> provokes outrage, admiration, bewilderment, and few <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africans </LOCATION> who follow foreign affairs are neutral about the <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> prime minister. From the <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> summit meeting in distant <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> this week, Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> consolidated her status as a dominant figure in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s political disputes. Her determined opposition to tougher economic sanctions against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> was praised by conservative whites and denounced by anti-apartheid leaders. `` Thank you, <PERSON> Maggie </PERSON>,'' said an editorial Tuesday in The Citizen, a pro-government <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> daily. `` We South Africans appreciate your brave, honest and lone battle against sanctions.'' President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, in a speech Monday night, lauded the leader of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and said intensified sanctions would undermine his proposals for political reform. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Morobe </PERSON>, a senior spokesman for the anti-apartheid movement, said with understatement that Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s position `` does not coincide with ours.'' <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayekiso </PERSON>, a black trade union leader, said Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> went to the summit `` to defend the apartheid regime.'' The 49-nation <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION>, composed of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and its former colonies, adopted a declaration Sunday calling for tougher financial measures against <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> and giving the white-led government six months to fulfill promises to dismantle apartheid. The declaration incorporated Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s objections but an hour later, to the dismay of other participants, she issued a separate statement outlining her reasons for dissent. She said tougher sanctions will hurt <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s blacks and increase white resistance to <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>'s reform program. On Tuesday she told a news conference in <LOCATION> Kuala </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lumpur </LOCATION>, `` I am in step with the people of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, a former British colony, withdrew from the <ORGANIZATION> Commonwealth </ORGANIZATION> in 1961 as other members increased their demands that it end its policies of racial separation. Business Day, a Johannesburg-based financial newspaper often critical of the government, said Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> performed more honorably at Kuala Lumpur than two pro-sanctions advocates, Prime Ministers <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON> `` have found in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> a rare opportunity for moral posturing,'' Business Day said. `` They do n't know or care what harm they do. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> has `` the good sense to recognize fundamental changes when they occur, sufficient faith in human nature to dare to hope for better times, and the courage to back her judgment,'' the editorial said. `` That is why she towers over men like <PERSON> Hawke </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mulroney </PERSON>; even if she turns out in the end to be wrong, at least she is not a pygmy.'' By law and custom, apartheid establishes a racially segregated society in which the 28 million blacks have no vote in national affairs. The 5 million whites control the economy and maintain separate residential districts, schools and health services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vatican-Politics Bjt   10-25 0730</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vatican-Politics, Bjt,0753</SECOND>
<HEAD>Catholic Church Drawing Fire For Stepping Into Rome Elections</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY BETH SHERIDAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A century after the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> lost control of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, politicians are accusing it of still trying to control the city's politics The charge stems from a speech by a top church administrator, the papal vicar for <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, suggesting that the city's voters choose the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> _ <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s only church-linked party _ in mayoral elections this weekend. The appeal by Cardinal <PERSON> Ugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON> has sparked a national outcry about <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> involvement in Italian politics. `` We seem to have returned to the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> of the popes,'' commented <PERSON> Bettino </PERSON> <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON>, leader of the Socialist party. The debate underlines how powerful religion is considered even in a city that appears overwhelmingly secular, with low Mass attendance, porno movie houses and condom ads on buses. It has overshadowed such pressing concerns as traffic, pollution, social services and housing. <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON> came under attack particularly for saying voters should make `` courageous'' choices `` even at the expense of personal sacrifice or repugnance.'' His statement was interpreted as calling for support for the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> despite the fact that successive city governments led by the party have been embroiled in scandal. `` It is worrying ... that Cardinal <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON> invites people to vote for the -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- even when they feel repugnance,'' said <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> <PERSON> La </PERSON> <PERSON> Malfa </PERSON>, leader of the small Republican party. Since July, <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> has been run by a special commissioner named by the national government after <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Pietro </PERSON> <PERSON> Giubilo </PERSON> resigned. <PERSON> Giubilo </PERSON> had been accused of steering contracts for school lunches to friends. He denied he did anything wrong. While the elections are simply to choose a city council, which in turn elects the mayor, they have major symbolic significance both for the church and the Italian political parties. The Oct. 29-30 ballot is the first since the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> won back control of city hall in 1985 after nine years of rule by the Communists, <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s second-biggest party. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> was embarrassed by <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> rule in the city of popes and unhappy about several Communist policies, such as extension of abortion services. Consequently it is anxious to see a party espousing Catholic values returned to city hall. Political parties, meanwhile, see the <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> elections as a barometer of their popularity nationwide and a chance to land a high-profile post. The importance of the vote has prompted several parties to send top politicians including Premier <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON>, a Christian Democrat, to stump for mayoral candidates. <PERSON> Craxi </PERSON> sailed down the <LOCATION> Tiber </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to promote his man, Tourism Minister <PERSON> Franco </PERSON> <PERSON> Carraro </PERSON>. The <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> controlled the city of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> for 400 years until Italian unification hero <PERSON> Giuseppe </PERSON> <PERSON> Garibaldi </PERSON>'s troops entered the city in 1870. But the church has long kept a hand in Italian politics, and its support of the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrats </ORGANIZATION> has been credited with helping keep the Communists out of national government for more than four decades. Much of the church's traditional influence, however, has waned in <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> as Western European society has become more secular. Less than 25 percent of the population attends Mass regularly in the city that is the world center of Catholicism. Only about 72 percent of marriages in the Italian capital this year were in church, even though around 90 percent of the population calls itself <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>, according to figures from city hall and the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> organization <LOCATION> Caritas </LOCATION>. Still, the <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> is considered a powerful political force in the <LOCATION> Eternal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>. The Turin-based newspaper <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stampa </ORGANIZATION> recently surveyed the strength of <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>'s religious orders and lay <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> organizations and concluded they comprised around 60,000 people. <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> has 2.3 million eligible voters. More than 39 percent of Romans questioned in a survey in the Italian newsmagazine <ORGANIZATION> Panorama </ORGANIZATION> felt Cardinal <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON>'s appeal would have `` a lot'' or `` some'' influence on the votes of Catholics. The latest controversy came as the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> has been sparring with <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democrat </ORGANIZATION> politicians over conditions in the capital. In February, Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> urged city officials to stop squabbling among themselves. He described <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> as a `` city of two faces,'' where wealth and poverty exist side by side. Both <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON> and the <LOCATION> Vatican </LOCATION> newspaper Osservatore Romano were critical of <PERSON> Giubilo </PERSON>, the mayor who resigned. The fact that <PERSON> Poletti </PERSON> urged support for the party he had been criticizing was not lost on politicians.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0047EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NielsensList     10-25 0632</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens List,0714</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Season-to-date rankings unavailable from source this week.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Oct. 16-22. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with a rating for total homes. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 90.4 million TV homes. 1. `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.7 rating, 22.3 million homes. 2. `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.6, 22.2 million homes. 3. `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 22.5, 20.3 million homes. 4. `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.6, 18.6 million homes. 5. `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.4 million homes. 5. `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 20.4, 18.4 million homes. 7. `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.7, 17.8 million homes. 8. `` Do You Know The Muffin Man?'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 8. `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.4, 16.6 million homes. 10. `` NFL Monday Night Football: <ORGANIZATION> L.A. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rams </ORGANIZATION> vs. <ORGANIZATION> Buffalo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bills </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.8, 16.1 million homes. 11. `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.5, 15.8 million homes. 12. `` Roxanne: The Prize Pulizter'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movies,'' 17.3, 15.6 million homes. 13. `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.5, 15.0 million homes. 14. `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2, 14.6 million homes. 14. `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.2, 14.6 million homes. 16. `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.5 million homes. 17. `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.8, 14.3 million homes. 18. `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 18. `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.3, 13.8 million homes. 20. `` 20-20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9, 13.5 million homes. 20. `` Knots Landing,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 14.9, 13.5 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 22. `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.5. 23. `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.3. 24. `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.2. 24. `` Designing Women,'' CBS, 14.2. 26. `` Wonder Years Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 26. `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 14.1. 28. `` Just the Ten of Us,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.8. 29. `` 48 Hours: Fire,'' CBS, 13.7. 30. `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 13.5. 31. `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 31. `` <ORGANIZATION> Nutt </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 31. `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.4. 34. `` ABC News Special - Earthquake,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 35. `` Mancuso, <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION> Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.0. 36. `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.8. 37. `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 37. `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 37. `` Famous Teddy Z,'' CBS, 12.6. 40. `` Roseanne Special,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.4. 41. `` <PERSON> Newhart </PERSON>,'' CBS, 12.3. 42. `` Trenchcoat In Paradise,'' _ `` CBS Wednesday Movie Special,'' 12.2. 43. `` NBC News Special,'' 12.1. 44. `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 44. `` World Series Preview,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.9. 46. `` The Color Of Money'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.7. 46. `` CBS News Special,'' 11.7. 46. `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.7. 49. `` Class Cruise'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 11.4. 50. `` Falcon Crest,'' CBS, 10.7. 51. `` Totally Hidden Video'', <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.5. 52. `` My Two Dads,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.4. 52. `` People Next Door,'' CBS, 10.4. 54. `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 55. `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.2. 56. `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 10.1. 57. `` Women Of The 21st Century,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 58. `` Sister <PERSON> Kate </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.3. 59. `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.0. 60. `` Paradise,'' CBS, 8.9. 60. `` Stuck With Each Other'' _ `` Friday Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 60. `` <ORGANIZATION> NFL </ORGANIZATION> Football,'' Game 2, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.9. 63. `` Free Spirit,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.8. 64. `` Magical World of Disney,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.2. 65. `` Snoops,'' CBS, 7.9. 65. `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.9. 67. `` Homeroom,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 67. `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.8. 69. `` Stuck With Each Other'' _ `` Tuesday Movie of the Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. -LRB- pre-empted for earthquake, shown in entirety as Friday Movie of the Week -RRB- 69. `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.1. 71. `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 72. `` ABC Mystery Movie: B.L. <PERSON> Stryker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 72. `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.7. 74. `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.4. 75. `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 6.1. 75. `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.1. 77. `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.9. 78. `` The Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.8. 79. `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 80. `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.7. 81. `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4. 81. `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.4.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0049EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-FEMAReserves Bjt   10-25 0710</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-FEMA Reserves, Bjt,0734</SECOND>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0414 to make slug conform to PM-News Digest.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Retired People Help Disaster Agency Stretch</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JEFF BARNARD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> likes to be where the action is when disaster strikes. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>'s wife wanted him out of her kitchen. Both retired, they are reservists for the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> who help the agency stretch when the pressure is on. Last month they were helping victims of Hurricane Hugo. Now they're pulling 12-hours shifts at the Veterans Memorial Building in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>, where <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> set up its disaster assistance center to handle applications for grants and low-interest loans. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, 61, retired in June from the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> office in <LOCATION> Redding </LOCATION>, but has been a <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> reservist for three years. Before she retired, she saved up vacation time to work disasters. `` It's an organization that's there quickly and we like to be part of the action,'' said <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, who is assistant manager of the disaster assistance center here. <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>, 78, of <LOCATION> Tempe </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, a retired associated professor of agricultural engineering, has been a reservist 12 years. `` My wife said she married for better or worse, but not for lunch,'' said <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON>. `` She wanted to know, ` What are you going to do to stay out of my kitchen?''' Until recently, neither one had been sent to a disaster in more than a year and a half. On Sept. 1, <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> was sent to <LOCATION> Baton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rouge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, to a flood. Three weeks later, he was sent to <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> S.C. </LOCATION>, for Hurricane Hugo. A day at home and he was in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> to help open an earthquake disaster assistance center. <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> was packed and ready to go to the Grand Canyon on vacation with her husband, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON>, another <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> reservist now working in <LOCATION> Monterey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, when the call came Sept. 24 for <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON>. `` We split our clothes into two suitcases and off we went to <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>,'' she said. Three weeks later, they both were sent to help out with the quake. `` We had a beautiful spring and summer at home,'' she said. `` I have n't been home at all this fall.'' Both find getting their laundry done one of the biggest challenges. `` If you go to a Laundromat, that's an hour you could be sleeping,'' <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> said. Coast-to-coast diasters have stretched <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION>, but it has n't snapped yet, said spokesman <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> `` I sure do n't want to see it strained much more, though,'' <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` Right now I have laying on my desk a request for a disaster declaration from the state of <LOCATION> Kentucky </LOCATION>,'' where flood damages are estimated at $ 12 million, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` We're about to find out whether we can -LRB- meet more demands -RRB- or not.'' The agency has 3,000 people assigned to Hurricane Hugo and the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> earthquake, he said. Of them, only 200 are full-time <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> employees. Six hundred are regular reservists who have been trained in advance and are called up in time of need. The remaining 2,200 are hired locally and get one day of training before being thrown in the breach. Hurricane damage has accounted for 350,000 disaster aid applications from <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, 8,000 from the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION>, 51,000 from <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> and 2,800 from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. A week after the earthquake struck <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area, 10,000 applications have come in from the 12 disaster centers in seven counties, said <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Rhoda </PERSON> <PERSON> Brooks </PERSON>. More than 400 people of various specialties from the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> have been dispatched from around the country to verify disaster claims before <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> signs checks. The total number of applications from <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> and the earthquake alone amount to more than three years' worth under normal ccircumstances, <PERSON> McAda </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think our people would ever admit they have reached their limit. Somewhere down the line you will run out of manpower, but I do n't know where that is,'' he said. `` Do you put together an agency that is big enough to handle the current situation, then sit around and do nothing for a year? That's not very effecive.'' Instead, <ORGANIZATION> FEMA </ORGANIZATION> lets people like <PERSON> Smith </PERSON> and <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> do the sitting around. `` I just sit at home and rock slowly'til they call me,'' <PERSON> Lytle </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0449EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--EasternArrests     10-25 0156</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Eastern Arrests,0158</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eight Airline Employees Arrested in Airport Theft</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> employees were arrested on charges of stealing things such as drugs and jewelry at <LOCATION> Palm </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, authorities said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON> Dexter </PERSON> <PERSON> Lehtinen </PERSON> announced the indictment Tuesday against 15 Eastern employees on charges such as conspiracy to steal from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mail, theft from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> mail and conspiracy to steal credit cards. The charges resulted from a one-year investigation into the theft of Express Mail aboard <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> aircraft. According to the indictment, the employees were instructed by a co-conspirator on how to take the contents from Express Mail envelopes. One Express Mail shipment contained 14 spools of 25-foot and 50-foot lengths of gold chains. Officials said the conspirators split the proceeds when the chains were sold. Several defendants were charged with removing marijuana and cocaine from the mail and distributing it to others.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0126EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-25 0809</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0837</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ROME (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McCartney </PERSON> says his better relations with other former Beatles has made it possible for him to play the legendary group's songs in public again. `` My relations with former members of the band have improved. Those songs are wonderful memories for me and that is why I am playing them again,'' he told reporters Tuesday before his <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> concert, part of a world tour promoting his latest album `` Flowers in the Dirt.'' Those songs include `` Ca n't Buy Me Love,'' `` <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Rigby </PERSON>,'' `` Back in the <ORGANIZATION> USSR </ORGANIZATION>,'' `` Hey Jude'' and `` Yesterday,'' which he called his favorite.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 17-year-old high school senior will preside as queen of the 101st Tournament of Roses on New Year's Day. `` My reaction was very surprised, and I'm very excited,'' <PERSON> Yasmine </PERSON> <PERSON> Begum </PERSON> <PERSON> Delawari </PERSON> said Tuesday after she was named by <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Fedde </PERSON>, president of the <ORGANIZATION> Tournament </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roses </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Miss <PERSON> Delawari </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Pasadena </LOCATION> area resident, was chosen from seven finalists who constitute the tournament's royal court. The queen and six attendants were chosen from more than 800 applicants following four interviews, said <PERSON> Kristin </PERSON> <PERSON> Mabry </PERSON> <PERSON> Tranquada </PERSON>, a tournament spokeswoman. Judges made their selections based on the candidates' public speaking ability, poise, academic achievement and personality. `` This is the start of a new century for the Tournament of Roses, so I just plan to do the best I can to represent them,'' said <PERSON> Miss </PERSON> <PERSON> Delawari </PERSON>, who hopes to attend the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gov. <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> says he wants to get back to running the state after a judge issued a no-fault divorce award ending his 23-year marriage to former Miss America runner-up <PERSON> Dee </PERSON> <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON>. The governor did n't attend Monday's brief proceedings during which <ORGANIZATION> Kanawha </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Herman </PERSON> <PERSON> Canady </PERSON> approved the divorce on the grounds of irreconcilable differences. The action halted a tandem $ 12 million fraud suit Mrs. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> had filed in federal court against the governor and two others. `` I'm pleased to have it behind us,'' the governor said in a statement. `` I think it's time to move forward.'' No details were released on the settlement, but Mrs. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON>'s attorney, <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Preiser </PERSON>, said as he left <PERSON> Canady </PERSON>'s office: `` Both cases have been settled Everybody's happy and she's extremely satisfied.'' `` You can underline extremely,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> added. In July, Mrs. <PERSON> Caperton </PERSON> filed for divorce and in August followed it up with her fraud suit, alleging she had been duped into selling her stock in the family insurance business for $ 2.98 million when the stock was worth far more.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>CLEVELAND (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Who, The Four Tops, the Four Seasons, the Kinks, the Platters, <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Ballard </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Darin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Simon </PERSON> and <PERSON> Garfunkel </PERSON> have been selected for induction Jan. 17 to the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame. The selections bring to 43 the number of recording acts chosen for the hall and represent `` a good cross section'' of musical style, rock historian <ORGANIZATION> Norm </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nite </ORGANIZATION> said Tuesday. It also represents an effort to honor people long overdue for recognition, he added. `` We're trying to get caught up on a lot of people owed getting in. As years go by, it will get tighter and tighter,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Nite </ORGANIZATION>, who has two syndicated radio rock' n' roll oldies shows. Besides the recording artists, three `` early influencers'' were selected to be honored at the as-yet unbuilt hall of fame and museum _ jazz singer-trumpeter <PERSON> Louis </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON>, jazz guitarist <PERSON> Charlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> and blues pioneer <PERSON> Ma </PERSON> <PERSON> Rainey </PERSON>. Two songwriting teams will be inducted in the non-performing music industry category, although some have been important performers as well. The writers include the teams of <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lamont </PERSON> <PERSON> Dozier </PERSON> and <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Holland </PERSON>, and <PERSON> Gerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Goffin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carole </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ANAHEIM, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Hockey's great one was escorted down Main Street U.S.A. by the squeaky one, the incoherent one and the goofy one as the Magic Kingdom paid tribute to <PERSON> Wayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON>. <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON>, 28, wife <PERSON> Janet </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON> and their 10-month-old daughter participated in a parade Tuesday to the Town Square Train Station. Also in the parade were <PERSON> Mickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Mouse </PERSON>, <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Duck </PERSON> and <PERSON> Goofy </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Disneyland </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said. Disney has produced many commercials featuring athletes who have just won a Super Bowl or World Series saying they plan to go to <LOCATION> Disneyland </LOCATION> next, but <PERSON> Roth </PERSON> said there are no plans to ask <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON>, `` ... what are you going to do now?'' The <ORGANIZATION> Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kings </ORGANIZATION>' center last week became the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hockey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION>'s all-time scoring champion, eclipsing <PERSON> Gordie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howe </PERSON>'s record `` This is special in that with most honors you get a trophy or a plaque and you can just enjoy those by yourself,'' <PERSON> Gretzky </PERSON> said. `` But this way I can enjoy the day with my wife and daughter. Just to spend the day here is quite an honor.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0127EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-EatingDisorders     10-25 0222</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Eating Disorders,0228</SECOND>
<HEAD>Disorders Affect Nutritional Needs, Study Shows</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A study suggests the nutritional needs of women with eating disorders differ from those of normal women. A study by <ORGANIZATION> Western </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Psychiatric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Clinic </ORGANIZATION> found that women recovering from bulimia needed only 73 percent of the normal intake of calories. Conversely, women recovering from anorexia needed two-thirds more calories than normal. Bulimia is the disorder of gorging and purging. Anorexia is an avoidance of food. The study of 23 recovering bulimic women who were trying to maintain normal weight found that the women required only 10 calories per pound of body weight, or 73 percent of the 13.8 daily calories per pound that healthy women need. Separate studies involving 31 recovering anorexic women found they needed 22.3 calories per pound of body weight to maintain their normal weight. `` These findings have led to new treatment methods in our program ... and they help us to understand the physiological factors that complicate the psychological issues of eating disorders,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON>, director of the institute's Center for Overcoming Problem Eating The findings were published in a recent issue of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nutrition </ORGANIZATION> and released to the public Tuesday in conjunction with Easting Disorders Awareness Week. The studies were conducted during the last three years, <PERSON> Kaye </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0128EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FavoriteBureaucrat Bjt   10-25 0529</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Favorite Bureaucrat, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>Keep Those Cards and Letters Coming, Folks</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Please, does n't anybody out there love a bureaucrat? Last June, entrepreneur <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> launched `` My Favorite Bureaucrat'' contest and invited people around the country to submit `` a brief, verifiable story of 250 words or less about how a government bureaucrat helped you.'' <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> offered a $ 5,000 cash prize for the winning entry and figured he'd be swamped with nominations. After all, he says, there are plenty of federal, state and local bureaucrats to choose from _ about 15 million altogether. Today, <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> is flabbergasted. In the past four months, he has received exactly one entry. Even worse, it was submitted by a woman employee of the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Taxation </ORGANIZATION> and Finance who nominated her boss. `` My God, I just ca n't believe the lack of response,'' said <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON>, the author of books and newsletters on where to get free advice from government experts on everything from playing the stock market to curing a backache to buying a new refrigerator. <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> says he plugged the contest in thousands of news releases mailed from his suburban <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, office, on <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> King </PERSON>'s radio show, <PERSON> Pat </PERSON> <PERSON> Sajak </PERSON>'s television show and the <ORGANIZATION> C-SPAN </ORGANIZATION> cable TV network, and in speeches around the country promoting the dozen books he has written Besides the $ 5,000 prize for the contest winner, <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> promised $ 500 to each of two runners-up, a plaque for the winning `` favorite bureaucrat'' and a free list of the government's two dozen best sources of information for every contest participant. `` I ca n't believe how this idea fell so flat,'' <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> complained. He suspects the problem runs deeper than any lack of publicity. `` The government is the biggest source of information and help on anything you could want,'' he said. `` All the millionaires, like <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Iacocca </PERSON> and <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON>, use it. I even got free legal advice from the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> on how to run this contest. `` But the average guy in the street probably just hates the government, is intimidated by it and does n't think there's anything there but waste, fraud and abuse,'' <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> said. `` The only contact most people have with the government is dealing with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> and the division of motor vehicles, which are probably the two worst experiences anybody can have.'' The public's antagonism toward the government apparently is so virulent, <PERSON> Lesko </PERSON> said, that a contest to nominate the biggest bureaucratic bunglers probably would produce a flood of entries. `` I would n't do that to the Post Office,'' he said. Someone who understands the public's reluctance to identify helpful, competent bureaucrats is <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> official and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> humorist who is president of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureaucrats </ORGANIZATION>. `` People are rather fearful of making such information public,'' <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said. `` If they say a bureaucrat has helped them, it's like saying they've seen a UFO in the sky. People might think they're not totally balanced.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>EDITORS' NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 The contest deadline is Dec. 31. Nominations may be sent to My Favorite Bureaucrat, Box 15700, <LOCATION> Chevy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chase </LOCATION>, Md. 20815.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0043EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-ConneautExplosion 2ndLd-Writethru a0782 10-25 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Conneaut Explosion, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0782,0373</SECOND>
<HEAD>Explosion Destroys House; At Least Two People Killed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with five grafs to UPDATE with fire chief now saying only
two people died, increase injured to 13. Picks up 4th graf, `Orrenmaa said...'.
SUBS 10th graf, `At least...', to update number of injured.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By THOMAS J. SHEERAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CONNEAUT, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Explosions that may have been caused by illegal fireworks leveled one house and set two others on fire Tuesday, killing at least two people and injuring 13 others, authorities said. Crews worked into the night, searching the rubble for other possible victims of the blast, said Fire Chief Bim Orrenmaa. He said illegal fireworks were suspected as the cause of the explosions which rocked this city of 13,000 on <LOCATION> Lake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> at the northeast corner of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. The fire chief initially said the explosion killed three people, but later revised the number to two, saying he had been incorrectly told that one injured person had died. <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Hubbard </PERSON>, an investigator with the <LOCATION> Ashtabula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> coroner's office, confirmed two deaths. <PERSON> Orrenmaa </PERSON> said firefighters found devices that looked like fireworks in the home where the explosion and two subsequent blasts occurred just before noon. `` We had a lot of small bangs,'' before the big explosion and two subsequent blasts, <PERSON> Orrenmaa </PERSON> said. Students were evacuated from a nearby elementary school, but there were no other evacuations. Patrolman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Strine </PERSON> said the explosion blew out windows of at least 20 homes in a six-block area. The victims were not immediately identified. A 46-year-old woman who lived at the house where the explosions occurred was taken to <ORGANIZATION> Hamot </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, 25 miles east of <LOCATION> Conneaut </LOCATION>, said hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> DePalma </PERSON>. She was in satisfactory condition. Twelve people were taken to <LOCATION> Brown </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Memorial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Conneaut </LOCATION>, then released, said hospital administrator <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON>. He said most of the injuries did not appear serious. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kingsolver </PERSON>, an agent with the <ORGANIZATION> federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Alcohol </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> , </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tobacco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Firearms </ORGANIZATION>, said 10 agents were at the scene. <PERSON> Kingsolver </PERSON> said that tubes, resembling parts of fireworks, were found. The state <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Ashtabula </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> said it was investigating.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0159EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shooting-Transcript 2Takes   10-25 0752</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shooting-Transcript, 2 Takes,0822</SECOND>
<HEAD>Text of Husband's Desperate Call to Police</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Double Shooting, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is an edited transcript of the 10-minute conversation Monday night between state police dispatcher <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> McLaughlin </PERSON> and <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, who had been abducted and shot along with his wife after leaving a birthing class at <LOCATION> Brigham </LOCATION> and Women's Hospital <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> was communicating on his automobile telephone as he and his wife lay wounded in the front seat of their car. The wife later died, but the baby, a boy, was saved by Caesarean section.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 `` My wife's been shot, I've been shot. ...'' `` Where is this, sir?'' `` I have no idea, I'm off, I was just coming from Tremont ... <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> and Women's Hospital.'' `` Try to give me an indication of where you might be, a cross street or anything else.'' `` Hello?'' `` Yes, go ahead.'' `` Hello. I got into the car at <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> ... drove straight through <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>.'' `` Where are you right now, sir, can you indicate to me?'' `` No, I do n't know, I do n't know, he drove us, he made us go to an abandoned area.'' `` OK, sir, can you see out the windows, can you tell me where you are, please?'' `` No. I do n't know, I do n't see any signs. Oh, God.'' ... `` What kind of car do you have, sir? What kind of vehicle do you have?'' `` Toyota <PERSON> Cressida </PERSON>.'' `` Toyota <PERSON> Cressida </PERSON>?'' `` <PERSON> Cressida </PERSON>. It's, it's a ...'' `` You're in the city of <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, though?'' `` Yes.'' `` Can you give me any indication wher you might be, any buildings?'' -LRB- Groans -RRB- `` No.'' `` Okay, has your wife been shot as well?'' `` Yes, in the head.'' `` In the head?'' `` Yes, I ducked down.'' `` How far, how long ago did you leave <ORGANIZATION> Brigham </ORGANIZATION> and Women's, sir, and what direction did you go?'' -LRB- Groans -RRB- `` Two minutes, three minutes ...'' `` OK, sir, bear with me now, stand by, stay on the phone with me.'' `` Should I try to drive or should I stay where I am?'' `` No. ... The people that shot you, are they in the area right there?'' `` No, they, they took off, they left.'' `` OK, can you look out, can you get out of the vehicle and look around to see where you are, sir? I'm trying to get some assistance to you.'' `` Should I drive up to the corner of the street?'' `` If you can drive, sir, without hurting yourself, yes, if you could. Just try to give me a cross street. If you can drive give me any street indication and stay there, I'll get someone right to you.'' `` I'll start the car. He took the keys but I have a spare set. Oh, man. I'm starting the car.'' `` OK, sir. What's your name, sir?'' `` <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>. Ahh, man.'' `` Bear with me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, I'm going to get someone to you, hang in with me, now.'' `` All right. ... I'm at a place, but I ca n't read it.'' `` Just try to read it, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. Just calm down, just stay with me, I'm gon na get help to you, help is gon na be on the way.'' `` I'm coming up to a, an intersection, but there's no ...'' `` What color is your car, buddy?'' `` Blue.'' `` Blue Toyota Cressida?'' `` Yeah, ahh!'' `` OK, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, try to give me a street.'' `` I'm coming to an intersection.'' `` OK, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, help's gon na be on the way, bear with me. Is your wife breathing?'' `` She's still gurgling. There's a busy street up ahead. Ahh, man. I ca n't see where I am.'' `` Bear, hang in with me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. Just try to give me any indication of where you might be, hospitals, if you see a building.'' `` I'm turning onto a busy street ... my lights are out.'' `` Chuck, just pull over, pull over, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' `` Are you there?'' `` I'm here, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' `` Oh. I'm driving with my lights off, I ca n't reach forward, it's too painful.'' `` Is it <LOCATION> Francis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, are you near <LOCATION> Francis </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Street </LOCATION>?'' -LRB- unintelligible -RRB- `` OK, why do n't you pull over. Is there someone there you can ask where you are?'' `` Ahh, I'm coming up a busy street. Oh, man, ahh!'' `` Hang in there with me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' `` I'm turning onto a busy street. I recognize where I am now, should I drive to the hospital?'' `` Just tell me what the, what the street is, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' `` Ahh, man! I'm pulling over. Tremont Street.'' `` You're at Tremont?'' `` Oh, man, I'm gon na pass out.'' `` Hang in with me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. Tremont street where? Help's gon na be on the way. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> ... <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>?'' `` Yeah.'' ...
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MORE</NOTE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0200EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Shooting-Transcript-1stAdd     10-25 0548</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Shooting-Transcript - 1st Add,0597</SECOND>
<HEAD>BOSTON: ``Yeah.''</HEAD>
<TEXT>
 `` Tremont Street where?'' `` I do n't know. I'm in front of -LRB- unitelligible -RRB-. Oh, man.'' ... `` I'm blanking out.'' `` You ca n't blank out on me, I need you, man. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>?'' ... `` Oh, man, it hurts and my wife has stopped gurgling, she's stopped breathing. `` Chuck, I'm gon na get assistance to you, buddy. Open the door, talk to someone on the street.'' `` I'm gon na try to drive straight to the hospital.'' `` Can you drive?'' `` Ah! I'm trying.'' ... `` Are you driving now?'' `` Yeah, I'm driving.'' `` Can you indicate to me exactly where you might be? I got Tremont Street, we got assistance on the way to you.'' `` I got ta pull over.'' `` Is there anyone on the street, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? Stop a passerby in the street so they can tell me where you are.'' `` Ahh!'' `` Chuck, pull over on the side of the street and talk to any passerby so I have an indication of where you are.'' `` I ca n't move. Oh, God.'' `` Chuck, can you see anyone on the street?'' `` My car died. Oh, man!'' `` Chuck, pull anyone over on the street, anyone you see on the street, pull over.'' `` I'm looking, I'm looking, there are n't that many people.'' `` OK, calm down, just hang in with me, I'm gon na have assistance right there to you.'' ... `` Chuck. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? Can you give me anything. Just look out the window. Can you see anything?'' `` Ohh!'' -LRB- long pause -RRB- `` Chuck, can you hear me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? ... Do you hear a siren? I can hear a siren. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, pick up the phone, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>?'' -LRB- long pause -RRB- `` Chuck, can you hear me? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> ... <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, pick up the phone, I can hear you breathing there, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, come on, buddy.'' -LRB- long pause -RRB- `` <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? I do n't know on a definite location, we heard the siren, though. `` <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? ... <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, come on, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, I can hear you breathing. Can you hear me, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? Pick up the phone. `` Chuck, can you hear me, buddy? ... I need a little better location to find you right away. Come on, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>. Damn! <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? Hello <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, can you hear me?'' -LRB- long pause -RRB- -LRB- In the background other police officers can be heard discussing whether sirens can be heard. After more pleas for <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> to respond the officers can be heard in the background ordering patrol cars to individually flick on their sirens so it can be determined which car is nearest the open phone line. -RRB- `` <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, stay with me buddy, I can still hear you moving. Can you pick up the phone, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, come on <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>, can you pick up the phone? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON>, are you there? <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>? Hello, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' -LRB- Long pause. <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> is implored again to pick up the phone. Finally, he does. -RRB- `` I hear the police.'' `` Chuck!'' `` I hear the police.'' `` Chuck! Where are you, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>?'' `` Help, help. Get in touch with the state police, my wife and I've been shot.'' `` Chuck!'' `` Right here there's <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> police.'' `` Put the <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION> police officer on the phone, <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON>.'' `` <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>, hello <LOCATION> Boston </LOCATION>. Hello?'' -LRB- Background voice calls `` We've located him!'' -RRB- `` I do n't want to terminate until someone can hear me. Want me to terminate, <PERSON> Sarge </PERSON>?'' -LRB- The tape becomes a jumble of voices and activity. Then <PERSON> Stuart </PERSON> can be heard. -RRB- `` Get my wife out.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0201EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SheppardCase     10-25 0429</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Sheppard Case,0442</SECOND>
<HEAD>Son Says Father Feared Re-Imprisonment in Wife's 1954 Slaying</HEAD>
<DATELINE>YOUNGSTOWN, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dr. <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>, acquitted in the murder of his wife after the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> reversed his conviction due to pretrial publicity, always feared he would be put back in prison, his son said. Ending 20 years of silence on the case, <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> said in a speech that he is speaking out in hopes of clearing his father's name `` Every reference to that -LRB- landmark <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- decision 23 years ago calls my father a convicted murderer,'' he said Tuesday, 35 years after his father was first brought to trial. `` That's not fair. That conviction was thrown out.'' The elder <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>, an osteopath who was well known in the <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> suburb of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Village </LOCATION>, was convicted of murder in the 1954 bludgeoning of his pregnant wife, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>. He served nine years in prison before the nation's high court reversed the conviction. <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> was acquitted after a second trial. He died in 1970 at age 46. The case remains unsolved. The younger <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>, 42, had been long silent on the case until this week's speaking tour. On Tuesday, he spoke at <ORGANIZATION> Youngstown </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>. He was 7 years old at the time of the slaying, and lived with an uncle after after his father was imprisoned. After the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision, the elder <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> feared constantly that he would be forced to return to prison, his son said. His exoneration in 1966 eased those worries but created new ones. `` There is still this stigma in our society that if you're accused, you're guilty,'' he said `` He could n't cope with society. ... He was a great guy, but, I kept my distance. I did n't want to go down with him. That was the agreement between us.'' <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> said the person he believed responsible for his mother's killing was the same person who broke into his family's house two days before the slaying That person, he said, later was convicted in an unrelated slaying. He said he knew the identity of the alleged killer, but would not reveal the name to the audience. Last summer, police indicated they might consider re-opening the investigation into Mrs. <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>'s slaying following the murder conviction of the <ORGANIZATION> Sheppards </ORGANIZATION>' one-time window washer. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Eberling </PERSON> was arrested in 1959 after being found with a large amount of jewelry belonging to <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON> and her husband's brother, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>. In August, <PERSON> Eberling </PERSON> told The -LRB- <LOCATION> Cleveland </LOCATION> -RRB- Plain Dealer from prison that he was familiar with the circumstances surrounding Mrs. <PERSON> Sheppard </PERSON>'s death.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0135EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PuppyStolen     10-25 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Puppy Stolen,0163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Valued Pup $30,000 Stolen, Pumpkin Left Behind</HEAD>
<DATELINE>HINGHAM, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Thieves who stole a specially bred golden retriever and left behind a pumpkin wo n't face criminal charges if they return the puppy unharmed, its owner says. While stealing the 9-week-old female Monday, the thieves also painted the words `` Happy Halloween. Thanks for the dog. Sorry no money ... Do n't worry, be happy,'' police said. The 18-pound pup, named <PERSON> Penny </PERSON>, is a top-of-the-line show dog, the product of 17 years of breeding, said owner <PERSON> Lynda </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>, a breeder and veterinarian. She said the puppy is worth $ 30,000 to her but would not be worth as much to thieves because they lack documentation that it is a purebred. She said she would drop all charges and ask no questions if <PERSON> Penny </PERSON> was returned. `` They've taken away my future on top of breaking my heart,'' said <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON>. `` This puppy is like one of my babies. She's part of my family.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Bush-Veto     10-25 0442</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Veto,450</SECOND>
<HEAD>Line-Item Veto Would Prompt Court Case: Edwards</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM RAUM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Any effort by President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to exercise a line-item veto will prompt a lawsuit by members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> subcommittee </ORGANIZATION> says. The line-item veto `` is an idea that many of us would resist very diligently,'' Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chairman of the civil and constitutional rights subcommittee of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said Tuesday after <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was considering such a move <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, is prepared to take such a step despite lack of specific constitutional authority `` to see if it works.'' Although <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has called for a constitutional amendment to give him the ability to veto just one item in a bill while leaving the rest intact, such a proposal has never made much headway in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> tried unsuccessfully for eight years to persuade <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to propose such a constitutional change to the states for ratification. Some legal scholars contend that line-item veto powers are implied in a president's overall veto power. However, the concept has never been tested. Such a notion, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said in an interview, comes from `` chit chat in conservative circles'' and has little constitutional legitimacy. `` We are looking for a vehicle that might be a suitable test case, but at this point we do n't have one,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said, adding that it was anticipated such a move would provoke a court challenge. Were <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to cast such a veto, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> said, `` a majority of the members of the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>'' would promptly take him to court. However, <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> conceded the issue could remain in limbo for years until it makes its way to the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. `` Conservatives could have a field day,'' he said. `` They think they could get several years of line-item vetoes.'' Administration sources said it was unlikely the test case would come soon because there is nothing before the president that is a likely candidate. The sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said a tentative target had been selected by <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> counsel <PERSON> Boyden </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> _ a provision once in the <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> appropriations bill to ban a requirement that members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> keep a log of contacts with lobbyists. However, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> stripped the provision from the bill before the president could decide whether to exercise a line-item veto. White House officials are keeping a sharp eye out, however, for another candidate. Sources said they are looking for a provision that is unrelated to the main bill, and on which a veto would not disrupt public policy or important services.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891025-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-25-89 0112EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-PlantExplosion 2ndLd-Writethru a0789 10-25 0831</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Plant Explosion, 2nd Ld - Writethru, a0789,0852</SECOND>
<HEAD>Phillips Officials Survey Damages, Deaths at Explosion Site</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: RETRANSMITTING to fix editor's note: SUBS grafs 4-5, `Company
officials...', with three grafs to UPDATE with Phillips officials in Oklahoma
saying total 23 missing or dead, sted 24, but unable to explain discrepancy.
Picks up 6th graf, `Fires that...'. ^LaserPhoto HT3</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GRACYZK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PASADENA, Texas (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
