<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2326EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-InfantTossed     10-20 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Infant Tossed,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mother Throws 3-Week-Old Baby From Third-Floor Window</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 3-week-old girl survived being thrown out of a third-floor window by her mother Friday when she landed in mud left by days of steady rain, authorities said. `` She has a skull fracture, she appears to have a femur fracture and we're concerned about intra-abdominal injuries,'' Dr. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Klein </PERSON> said. `` I think she is a very, very lucky baby.'' <PERSON> Salonda </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> originally was listed in critical condition at Children's <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, but her condition was later upgraded to serious. The child's mother, <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ray </PERSON>, 22, was led out of the apartment complex smiling and talking to herself as neighbors jeered. As she was placed in a police squad car, she turned toward television cameras and said `` My, I feel good.'' She was to be arraigned in <ORGANIZATION> D.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Saturday on charges of assault with intent to kill, officials said. `` She has not indicated why'' she threw the infant out of the window, Capt. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ritchie </PERSON>, a spokesman of the district police department said. `` But we believe that she has some very strong religious beliefs. We are still in the process of investigating that particular aspect.'' A security guard at the apartment complex initially thought the baby had been killed in the fall and put a coat over the body. The little girl was rushed to the hospital after a neighbor lifted the coat and the baby cried.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-IowaBlast-Media     10-20 0554</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Iowa Blast-Media,0572</SECOND>
<HEAD>Attorney: News Organizations Facing Legal Action From Iowa Blast
Stories</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL GRACZYK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HOUSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 News organizations that used unidentified sources to erroneously link a sailor to the explosion that killed 47 crewmen on the USS Iowa will be challenged in court to identify those sources, the sailor's attorney said Friday. `` We are going to name several media outlets as defendants for the untrue and defamatory accusations that came out immediately after the explosion,'' attorney <PERSON> Ellis </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>' annual convention. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> represents <PERSON> Kendall </PERSON> <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, who the attorney said was identified in stories following the April gun turret explosion aboard the battleship as a homosexual friend of one of the sailors, <PERSON> Clayton </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> died in the blast. Last month, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> report citing circumstantial evidence said <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> was the most likely person to have caused the explosion. Stories on the Hartwig-Truitt link cited unidentified sources. `` We know who the sources are,'' <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said. `` The sources will deny. It'll be an interesting exercise.'' He said the news organizations, which he would not identify, would refuse to name the sources or invoke First Amendment protections. <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said defendants who do n't reveal a source will have to pay damages because under the law that means there is no source and `` they just made it up.'' `` They're going to have a tough choice,'' he said. <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON>, who also appeared on the panel to discuss whether the press went too far in covering the investigation of the <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> explosion, said <PERSON> Hartwig </PERSON> was a friend but denied any homosexual relationship. `` I understand the public has a right to know and the press a right to print,'' he said. `` But whatever happened to innocent until proven guilty? Incredible. It's as if the press has immunity. `` Through leaks in the press, my life has been ruined forever.'' <PERSON> Truitt </PERSON> said as recently as the past week, he has been written about in newspapers as being dead. `` We all want to be fair,'' <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> said. `` But there is supposed to be a balance.'' <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Otto </PERSON>, a board member of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Newspaper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Editors </ORGANIZATION> and chairman of the group's <ORGANIZATION> Bar-Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said a key question in developing such stories is whether reporters can trust the government. `` I think that question can be answered very clearly,'' she said. `` I think the government has a natural interest in lying.'' <PERSON> Rubin </PERSON> contends <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> negligence, outmoded technology, unstable gunpowder and an untrained crew were responsible for the explosion. `` From the point of view of the government employee who was leaking the information, I believe the sources that leaked to the media did it intentionally to take the focus away from the fact that the battleship is an armored dinosaur and is no longer an effective weapon of war,'' he said. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McMasters </PERSON>, deputy editorial page editor for USA Today and national freedom of information chairman for the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professional </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalists </ORGANIZATION>, defended pursuit of stories by using unidentified sources. `` Some things will never come to fruition if there is n't public pressure to know the whole story,'' he said, adding that reporters need to know the motive for government leaks. `` You have a responsiblity as a journalist to let the audience know what side of the street your leak is on,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2349EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Universal     10-20 0644</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Universal,0667</SECOND>
<HEAD>SF Quake Veterans, Others Left Unshaken by Studio Tour's Simulated
Temblor</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN ROGERS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>UNIVERSAL CITY, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As northern Californians added up earthquake repair bills in the billions of dollars, <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Californians </ORGANIZATION> lined up to plop down $ 21 apiece to be shaken and scared by a fake shake. The attraction: the <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tours </ORGANIZATION>' simulated earthquake, which officials had closed for two days after Tuesday's deadly temblor devastated the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area When the attraction reopened Friday morning, thousands braved a light, chilly rain to clamber aboard trams and see what they might have missed. Or, in the case of northern Californian <PERSON> Ruth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitchcock </PERSON>, to be shaken again. `` It bounced me all over my driveway,'' she said of Tuesday's quake that rattled her <LOCATION> Livermore </LOCATION> home `` I've lived in that house for 32 years and it's the strongest one I've ever felt.'' But it was n't enough to keep her from canceling a trip to <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> and a long-planned visit to the <ORGANIZATION> Universal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studios </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tour </ORGANIZATION> and its simulated earthquake ride. `` I came clear down here to see this,'' Ms. <PERSON> Hitchcock </PERSON> said excitedly afterward. `` If they had canceled it, I would have been very disappointed.'' None of those interviewed Friday seemed bothered that the fake quake is supposed to happen in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, or that they had just witnessed a giant tanker truck hurled through the air as a roadway fell in a staged scene similar to Tuesday's deadly collapse of <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s Nimitz Freeway. <PERSON> Francis </PERSON> <PERSON> McClaskey </PERSON>, who went through <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>' <LOCATION> Sylmar </LOCATION> quake in 1971, dismissed the irony with a wave of his hand. `` Nah, it's all in fun,'' said the retired trucker who now lives in <LOCATION> Boulder </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION> `` This place is all make-believe. People can separate reality from fantasy.'' `` I thought it was great, especially when the -LRB- freeway -RRB- bridge came down,'' said <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Tolent </PERSON>, one of a group of teen-agers who bounded from the tour tram talking excitedly about the ride. `` But I do feel sorry for the people of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>.'' <PERSON> Curtis </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> of <PERSON> Tracy </PERSON> said he was `` kind of sad'' he had n't been home in northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for the real thing He was at <LOCATION> Disneyland </LOCATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> Surin </PERSON> <PERSON> Hutawaniatana </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bangkok </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>, said he would have missed the attraction if the real quake had n't hit. `` We were going to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>,'' he said of his tour group. `` But when they canceled that part of the trip we got to come here instead.'' He added he was thrilled with the ride. `` I had heard it's great, and it was,'' he said. Even so, tour operators were taking no chances at offending anyone. While visitors were threatened by a robotic giant shark from the movie `` Jaws,'' shot at by actors dressed as space aliens, and buried in a make-believe avalanche, the comic patter of tour guides ran apace. But it halted as the tram was about to enter a sound stage made to look like a <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Area </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rapid </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transit </ORGANIZATION> subway tunnel. `` For those of you who do not want to experience this, we perfectly understand,'' a tour guide said solemnly over a microphone as he gave any of the more than 200 tram riders an opportunity to get off. One woman did. `` That is not a regular thing,'' Universal spokeswoman <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullard </PERSON> said of halting the tram before the fake quake. `` We are doing it today and perhaps this weekend.'' When the tram finally entered the set, several people braced themselves. `` It's only make-believe,'' one woman cautioned her son. Several riders applauded when the quake was over, but some veterans of real quakes expressed mild disappoint. They noted the ride did n't last long enough or shake violently enough to match the real thing. `` I liked the avalanche better because it really gave you the feeling you were falling,'' Tolent said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Relief     10-20 0691</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Relief,0710</SECOND>
<HEAD>Crayon Money, Blood, Food Donated To Quake Victims</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL FLEEMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 From elementary school students who gave $ 60 in crayon money to a foundation that donated $ 1 million, the world rallied to help <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area residents dig out and get on with their lives. People gave blood, a home improvement store donated shovels, trash cans and gloves, a cruise service sent passenger boats, a bank bought tons of meat, and a trade group collected a truckload of fruits and vegetables. `` Amazing is a pretty good word for all this,'' said <PERSON> Kim </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. By Friday evening, the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> alone had received at least $ 8 million in pledges. A relief drive that started after Tuesday's quake with a brewery filling beer cans with drinking water and radio stations asking listeners for donations escalated through the week to a scale that <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> charities called unprecedented for a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> disaster. One of the biggest donations came Friday from the Los Angeles-based <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Parsons </PERSON> foundation, funded by the estate of the late engineer, which gave $ 750,000 to the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and $ 250,000 to the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. `` This is n't something we do every day,'' said Executive Director <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisley </PERSON>. `` It was a desire to show the people of northern <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> that the private sector and people in <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> care about their needs.'' <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> and its subsidiary, <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION>, also offered $ 1 million, and the <ORGANIZATION> Ford </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> said it was donating $ 300,000 to the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> and $ 200,000 to the <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Clara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Way </LOCATION> <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco-based </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wells </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fargo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> announced a $ 1 million grant program to help communities rebuild. The bank also planned to give a $ 250,000 grant to the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>. Other donations measured up in heart, if not dollars. First - and second-graders at <ORGANIZATION> Tierra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oxnard </LOCATION> decided that the $ 60 they raised in a recycling drive for crayons, felt pens and chalk should go to the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> for earthquake relief Two <LOCATION> Bloomington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, radio stations raised $ 40,120 in an all-day pledge-a-thon. And a <LOCATION> Tucson </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz </LOCATION>, hairstylist announced she would hold a cut-a-thon Sunday and donate the $ 5-a-head proceeds. The <ORGANIZATION> Michigan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiropractic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> offered its services, too. But relief officials worried that the aid was insufficient to fill all of the immediate needs of what could be the most expensive natural disaster in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> history. One estimate put the damage total at as high as $ 10 billion. `` We need cash, first and foremost. Because of who we are, we can stretch your dollars,'' said <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrett </PERSON>, spokeswoman for the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> chapter in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. People left homeless or displaced by the earthquake need things that only money can buy, such as new glasses, prescription medicines and false teeth. By Friday morning, 5,000 people were housed in 30 shelters in the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area. An estimated 12,550 people were displaced in all, according to the state <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>. Although aid came from around the world _ including offers of help from the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> _ some of the most enthusiastic responses came from Californians, especially quake-nervous Southern Californians. Fullerton-based <ORGANIZATION> HomeClub </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, a chain of home improvement stores, donated about 200 shovels, 600 trash cans and 2,500 canvas gloves to the <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>. The parent company of <ORGANIZATION> Catalina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cruises </ORGANIZATION> sent four of its 700-passenger ships from <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area to ferry people and supplies between <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> purchased more than 1,200 pounds of meat from the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Joaquin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Fair </LOCATION> and had it transported from the bank's <PERSON> Stockton </PERSON> headquarters to the <ORGANIZATION> Moscone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. Food also was sent to the quake victims by the Fresh Produce Council. The trade group's officials phoned around to <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area wholesalers and were able to collect 4,500 pounds of fruits and vegetables, enough to fill a tractor-trailer. `` The response was just phenomenal,'' said council Executive Vice President <PERSON> Jan </PERSON> <PERSON> DeLyber </PERSON>. `` The wholesalers all rallied around the cause. And in one hour we had the shipment.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2350EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--DogShootsMan     10-20 0130</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Dog Shoots Man,0133</SECOND>
<HEAD>Spaniel Wings Master with Shotgun</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MAYVILLE, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hunting dog was so excited after retrieving a pheasant that it danced into a shotgun trigger, and the blast injured the dog's master. <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON>, who had to have shotgun pellets removed from his foot, does n't bear his pet any ill-will. `` The dog is a good dog,'' <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON> and a friend, <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Coch </PERSON>, bagged two birds during the expedition near <LOCATION> Mayville </LOCATION>, northwest of <LOCATION> Milwaukee </LOCATION> on Wednesday. After returning with the second bird, the dog triggered a 12-gauge shotgun lying on the ground, <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON> said. The noise `` did n't bother the dog at all,'' said <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON>, 77. `` It's a funny thing, you know: ` Dog attacks man.' But it was a freak accident,'' <PERSON> Dobberpuhl </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2352EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-RedArmyBanned     10-20 0318</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Red Army Banned,0327</SECOND>
<HEAD>Joint Appearance of Red Army, Navy Bands Nixed</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATIA BLACKBURN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SEATTLE (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> nixed two joint performances by the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> bands, but promoters say they do n't see the concerts causing a security breach and are fighting to reverse the decision The 200-member Red Army Song and Dance Ensemble, including the 40-piece band, is scheduled to perform Oct. 24 in the <ORGANIZATION> Seattle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Arena </ORGANIZATION> during its first tour of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. Easterday Promotions suggested that the 35-piece <ORGANIZATION> Sand </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> appear in a free <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> performance with the <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Band </ORGANIZATION> the same day, said owner <PERSON> Kris </PERSON> <PERSON> Easterday </PERSON>. She also worked to arrange a joint appearance of the Soviet band with the 35-piece <ORGANIZATION> Fairchild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> band in <LOCATION> Spokane </LOCATION> on Oct. 26. Both Sand Point and Fairchild authorities were enthusiastic, <PERSON> Easterday </PERSON> said, but Cmdr. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> at Sand Point said officials had to submit the proposal to the Pentagon. On Wednesday, about two weeks after <PERSON> Easterday </PERSON> started promoting the events, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> rejected the joint appearances. <PERSON> Britt </PERSON> said he did n't know why the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> rejected the idea. <PERSON> Easterday </PERSON> said a <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> official, Capt. <PERSON> Doug </PERSON> <PERSON> McUrrach </PERSON>, told her the two countries had restrictions on the movement of military personnel in each other's countries. The promoters were baffled. `` It's just an innocent half hour for the bands to get together,'' said <PERSON> Easterday </PERSON> spokeswoman <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Coughlin </PERSON>. `` It seeme really strange.'' Easternday asked the office of Sen. <PERSON> Slade </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON> for help and the Republican lawmaker's <LOCATION> Seattle </LOCATION> office started contacting <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> officials on Friday. `` Slade is convinced that this is a good event to have and we're seeking to have the decision reviewed at the least and at best reversed,'' said <PERSON> Gorton </PERSON> aide <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Nordhoff </PERSON> `` We're hoping that message has gotten through but we do n't know.'' McUrrach could not be reached for comment Friday evening.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2356EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-SFQuake-Arts Bjt   10-20 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Arts, Bjt,840</SECOND>
<HEAD>The Shows Will Go On _ Somewhere, Eventually</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RICH CARTIERE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opera singer <PERSON> Enrico </PERSON> <PERSON> Caruso </PERSON>, asleep in the Palace Hotel when the Great Earthquake struck in 1906, was so unnerved by the shaker that he ran into the streets in his nightie shouting, `` I'll never come back.'' He caught a ferry to <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION> and never did return. But the artists, actors, musicians and performance managers who experienced Tuesday's big quake vowed their shows would go on _ eventually, somewhere. Some of the promises could n't be kept. `` The music or the arts, what they're about is the spirit of life. ... It imparts something uniquely human; it kind of reminds people that there a great richness to being alive,'' said singer-performer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> of the Talking Heads, who is touring to promote his new solo album `` Rei Mommo.'' After watching television reports of the earthquake while backstage in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Diego </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Byrne </PERSON> canceled this week's shows at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'s <PERSON> Warfield </PERSON>. The concerts were rescheduled to Saturday night and moved to the Greek Theater in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, but the likelihood of rain later forced a cancellation there. Ticketholders were offered refunds. Elsewhere in the city, the cultural center of <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, performers struggled through traffic jams and cordoned-off sections of the city to attend rehearsals. All 106 members of the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Symphony </LOCATION> made it to a 7 p.m. rehearsal Thursday, including 17 who battled enormous traffic snarls on the east side of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION>. `` We have a big responsibility to the community to energize, give them the impetus to get on with their lives,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuman </PERSON>, a 31-year-old clarinetist with the symphony. `` The show in general must go in, meaning life.'' On the rock scene, <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Clinton </PERSON>'s weekend concerts were postponed until December; <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Harry </PERSON>'s Sunday concert was indefinitely postponed; <PERSON> Oingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Boingo </PERSON>'s concert Sunday in <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> was canceled, and <PERSON> Stevie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nicks </PERSON>'s concert Friday night was opened to ticketholders from Tuesday's canceled performance. `` It does n't seem quite right to produce an event in the middle of a catastrophe, having people walk by buildings that have just been condemned,'' said rock impresario <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, who canceled nine concerts after the quake. Theatrical productions were disrupted, but most shows were to resume early next week. Mayor <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnos </PERSON> encouraged <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area art institutions to reschedule performances soon, but cautioned them not `` rush to open before people are ready, otherwise it would e a distraction rather than a relief.'' The Friday and Saturday night premieres of the traveling musical `` Les Miserables'' were canceled after a water tank atop the Curran Theater broke and drenched the stage. At the landmark Geary Theater, the American Conservatory Theater's production of `` Right Mind,'' a multi-media presentation, was ended after a giant light rack crashed onto the stage and large plaster chunks fell from the ceiling. A recording for people holding ACT tickets warned theater-goers: `` Be careful out there.'' The troupe's upcoming production of a `` Tale of Two Cities'' may be postponed, said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sullivan </PERSON>, ACT managing director. Classes for 200 students at ACT's prestigious drama school were postponed through Monday. Stairwell damage to the Golden Gate Theatre forced cancellation of the musical `` Durante'' through Tuesday. The <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Opera </LOCATION>'s performance of <PERSON> Mozart </PERSON>'s `` Idomeneo'' on Tuesday was canceled after windows and the glass front door blew out of the War Memorial Opera House. The opera moved out of the baroque War Memorial Opera House while structural engineers continued to check the building, whose seats were littered with chunks of ceiling plaster. Performances were moved at least through the weekend to the <ORGANIZATION> Masonic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Auditorium </ORGANIZATION>, where only soloists would be in costume. Productions there would have no scenery and a minimum of props. `` If the mundane things are not going on, at least the spiritual things are continuing,'' said <PERSON> Lotfi </PERSON> <PERSON> Mansouri </PERSON>, general director of the opera, which in its 57-year history had never had a change of venue. `` We want to rally the people, and get them to look to rebuilding. Our function is to prove to everybody that the spirt of the city goes on.,'' The opera and the symphony will give a free joint concert in Golden Gate Park on Sunday, performing <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s Ninth Symphony `` It's a work that contains every emotion; despair, happiness, tragedy, hope and joy,'' said <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Pastreich </PERSON>, executive director of the symphony. `` We think all of those feelings of a disaster are there in this music.'' Most of the art museums in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> suffered only slight damage to priceless collections, but at least 33 pieces at the Asian Art Museum were damaged, for a loss estimated in the millions, according to <PERSON> Clarence </PERSON> <PERSON> Shangraw </PERSON>. At the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Art </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION>, spokesman <PERSON> Phil </PERSON> <PERSON> Mumma </PERSON> said a 4-foot-tall jade figurine toppled in its case and was broken into several hundred pieces. He did not have a loss estimate. `` A lot of the pieces, even if they have a dollar value, you ca n't replace,'' he said. `` You may have the money, but you do n't have the object.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2358EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Glenn-Dukakis     10-20 0518</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Glenn-Dukakis,0533</SECOND>
<HEAD>Book: Political Contribution Questions Cost Glenn Spot on Dukakis
Ticket</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DAYTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> lost his chance to be <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON>' presidential running mate last year because he gave unconvincing answers about his connection to a campaign contributor in the savings and loan industry, says a new book. The book, `` All By Myself: The Unmaking of a Presidential Campaign,'' says <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> was leaning toward the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> Democrat as his vice presidential candidate until aides warned the <LOCATION> Massachusetts </LOCATION> governor that <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s finances could be a political liability. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Oliphant </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Boston </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Globe </ORGANIZATION> reporter who wrote the book with colleague <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, said this week that the contributor, who was n't named in the book, was <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION> `` No one suggested that Senator <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> had done anything illegal or even ethically questionable, but the hard time he had answering questions forcefully was potentially troublesome,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Dayton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> quoted the book as saying in a story in Saturday's editions The newspaper said it obtained a copy of the book, which has not been released. Federal investigators last month accused <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> of stealing more than $ 1.1 billion from his savings and loan through illegal loans and phony real-estate and tax transactions. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and four other senators have come under criticism for intervening with federal regulators two years ago during an investigation of <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>. <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> has made donations to <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> totaling $ 234,000. <PERSON> Oliphant </PERSON> said, `` It had to do with a judgment as to which person would stand up better in front of a battery of 500 microphones if it ever came to that.'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> refused through an aide to comment on the book and a book on the savings and loan scandal, `` The Big Fix,'' that recounts <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s involvement on <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>'s behalf. `` The senator has n't read these books,'' <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> press secretary <PERSON> Rebecca </PERSON> <PERSON> Bell </PERSON> said. `` We just are not going to comment on excerpts from a book.'' <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> chose Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, as his running mate after campaign aides argued <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> was a less reliable candidate because of questions about his finances, the book says. At the time, news organizations were reporting <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> as the front-runner for the No. 2 spot, citing sources in the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign. <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> has acknowledged a long relationship with <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>, but denied any wrongdoing. The senator said he met twice with federal regulators in April 1987 at <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>'s request after <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> complained the investigation of his business was taking too long, but backed off after learning the probe could lead to criminal charges. Chairman <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON>, the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign chairman who conducted the final interviews with both <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, disputed the book's assertion that <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON>'s demeanor under questioning threw the nomination to <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>. `` I disagree with the author and if he got it from a top aide, I disagree with the top aide,'' <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> said. But <PERSON> Brountas </PERSON> acknowledged the <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> campaign throughly reviewed what he called `` the strengths and weaknesses of the candidates, what they would add to the campaign, what kind of vice presidents they would be.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 2357EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Deputies-Shot 2ndLd-Writethru a0854 10-20 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Deputies-Shot, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0854,0276</SECOND>
<HEAD>Sheriff's Deputy Killed, Another Wounded, By Gunman</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 3rd graf to UPDATE with Manzella charged with murder.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN F. BONFATTI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CLARENCE, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A sheriff's deputy was killed and his partner wounded Friday as they tried to arrest a man on a drug charge, and the suspect held police at bay for nearly nine hours, authorities said. <PERSON> Rudy </PERSON> <PERSON> Manzella </PERSON>, 30, whose home in this <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION> suburb was surrounded by more than 100 law enforcement officers, surrendered at 10:20 p.m., ending a standoff that began at 1:30 p.m. <PERSON> Manzella </PERSON> was charged with first-degree murder, said <LOCATION> Erie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> sheriff's Sgt. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fox </PERSON>. <PERSON> Manzella </PERSON>, who was inside the house alone, had been talking by telephone with police negotiators, but contact was broken off at 8 p.m., said county Undersheriff <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Payne </PERSON>. As the standoff continued, power to the neighborhood was shut off. The dead deputy was identified as <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Dillemuth </PERSON>, 45, of <PERSON> Depew </PERSON>. His partner, Deputy <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON>, 34, of <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>, was in serious condition with a gunshot wound at <ORGANIZATION> Millard </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fillmore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Suburban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, hospital officials said. Both officers were shot at while trying to arrest <PERSON> Manzella </PERSON> for possession of marijuana in the city of <LOCATION> Tonawanda </LOCATION>, according to <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Staebell </PERSON>, chief of patrol for the sheriff's department. Both deputies were apparently hit by gunfire outside the house, <PERSON> Payne </PERSON> said. While <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> was able to get away from the home, <PERSON> Dillemuth </PERSON> fell on the driveway. Authorities say it was some time before officers, fearful of being shot themselves, were able to remove <PERSON> Dillemuth </PERSON>'s body. <PERSON> Staebell </PERSON> said <PERSON> Manzella </PERSON> had faced drug charges in the past.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0018EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BridgeJumps     10-20 0320</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bridge Jumps,0332</SECOND>
<HEAD>High Waters May Cancel Bridge Jumps</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID WILKISON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>FAYETTEVILLE, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Parachutists' plans to jump off the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gorge </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION> are up in the air while the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> considers whether to ban this year's Bridge Day leaps. <PERSON> Ranger </PERSON> <PERSON> Rick </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said Thursday the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> would have to drop 6 feet for the jumps to go off as scheduled on Saturday in the 10th annual event. <PERSON> Tim </PERSON> <PERSON> Velie </PERSON>, a board member of the <ORGANIZATION> Fayette </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chamber </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION>, said he still hopes the river will subside in time for the jumps off the bridge, 876 feet above the river. But he said even if the jumping is canceled, Bridge Day events such as an arts and crafts exhibit would be held. Bridge Day attracts divers worldwide and is the largest event of the year for parachutists belonging to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> BASE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. State police will reroute the northbound lanes of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 19 during the event and allow pedestrians to walk on the highway. Bridge Day is the only time parachutists can legally jump from the bridge. `` It's relatively safe,'' said <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Boenish </PERSON>, executive director of BASE _ which stands for people who jump off buildings, antennas, spans and earth forms. `` Our volunteer staff is experienced BASE jumpers and they help divers chose the right gear and show them the right techniques,'' said <PERSON> Boenish </PERSON>, who also coordinates the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> jumps. Three people have been killed in parachute leaps from the bridge, two during the Bridge Day festivities. The last death was in 1987. Some state officials talked of banning the event following the accidents, but event organizers say Bridge Day provides the divers with a safe outlet. The event began in 1980 with a handful of jumpers. Last year, more than 100,000 people turned out to watch 300 divers perform 600 jumps from the center of the bridge.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0022EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-DeathCount     10-20 0227</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Death Count,0231</SECOND>
<HEAD>Death Toll Likely to be Lower, Officials Now Say</HEAD>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Early estimates that more than 250 people were killed under the collapsed Nimitz Highway were proving to be high, but no new estimates were offered, authorities said. Rescue workers found cars separated by as much as 60 feet, rather than bumper-to-bumper as feared. Authorities had said more than 270 people were killed by Tuesday's earthquake _ 250 of them during the Nimitz cave-in. That was based on an estimate of how many vehicles would have been crushed when the upper level of the freeway collapsed onto the lower level and an estimate of one person per car. `` Now they are going lower, much lower in fact,'' <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Covington </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the state <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Emergency </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, said Thursday. `` What's happening is that they are finding fewer vehicles under the bridge than they thought.'' Reaching the vehicles has been painstakingly slow because of a fear that huge sections of the interstate could collapse further on rescue workers. `` We're not going to give any estimate,'' said Sgt. <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> of the <LOCATION> Alameda </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> coronor's office. `` I do n't know how many people are there We're not going to know until they dig them out.'' Coroners and other officials in the seven counties affected by the quake said 35 bodies have been recovered.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0027EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-IllegalLegal     10-20 0269</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Illegal Legal,0277</SECOND>
<HEAD>Florida Supreme Court Outlaws Legal-Size Paper in Court Documents</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CURT ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> has decided long briefs are on the way out for <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> attorneys and court clerks. But the high court was n't making a fashion statement Thursday. Beginning in January 1991, the state's court system will no longer use legal-sized paper _ 8 -LCB- by 14 inches _ in any documents, including lawsuits, pleadings, notices, opinions, judgments and motions. The change mirrors rules in the federal courts and at least 36 other states. The new rule actually takes effect in January 1990, but the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decided to allow a one-year grace period during which the state's courts can accept either the legal size or standard 8 -LCB- - by-11 paper For years, a group called Eliminate Legal-Size Files _ or <LOCATION> ELF </LOCATION> _ has campaigned to get government to use the standard size. <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Mullarkey </PERSON>, a retired certified records manager for the state <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Library </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION>, was chairman of <ORGANIZATION> ELF </ORGANIZATION> for five years. `` It's just standardization. If everybody in the army fired a different size weapon, they'd have a hell of a time fighting a war,'' <PERSON> Mullarkey </PERSON> said. He said advantages to using just one size include having uniform filing cabinets and savings from buying a single size in bulk rather than two sizes. When the state <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> first proposed the rule in April, there was some understandable criticism, said <PERSON> Sid </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, clerk of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. `` It seems like most of the opposition came from people who were selling legal-size paper and cabinets,'' <PERSON> White </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0029EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Korea-BlackMarket Bjt   10-20 0602</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Korea-Black Market, Bjt,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Scotch, SPAM and Rice are Big Black-Market Sellers in South Korea</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DONNA CASSATA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> buy six times as much Chivas Regal scotch as the much larger <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> force in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ but instead of drinking it, they're selling it on the Korean black market, a study says. SPAM, Aqua Net hair spray and rice are among other favorites selling in huge quantities at <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military commissaries in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>, apparently bound for the black market, the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday. Such sales far exceed what would normally be consumed by the 70,000 authorized buyers stationed there, and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> taxpayers are footing part of the bill, <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> witnesses said at a <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> hearing. The <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION> is <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' investigative arm. The <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> exports duty-free goods to bases in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and other countries for sale at cut-rate prices in the commissaries and exchanges. In 1988, commissaries in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> sold 1.1 million cans of SPAM, or almost 12 pounds per person per year; 34 pounds or 816 American cheese slices for every man, woman and child, and 170 pounds of rice for every consumer. `` If one person consumed 170 pounds of rice a year, that would be a little over 14 pounds of rice a month or just under a half a pound of rice a day,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, D-Mich., chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Governmental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on government oversight and management `` There would be little room in a person's diet for anything else but rice,'' he said. Black marketeers recruit <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> service members or their dependents to buy the products for later resale or enlist the help of cashiers and sales clerks, mostly Koreans. The investigators concluded that most of the Chivas Regal scotch purchased for sale, including the 12-year-old bottle and 21-year-old bottle, ends up in the black market. In 1988, service members in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> bought 314,748 liters of the scotch. `` Fewer military members in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> _ 15 percent of the total in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> _ purchased more than six times the number of Chivas Regal bottles purchased in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>,'' the investigators said. In addition, the meat merchant who services the <ORGANIZATION> Osan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION> told investigators that 70,000 pounds of oxtails are supplied per month to the commissary. <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Heivilin </PERSON>, director of logistics issues for the <ORGANIZATION> GAO </ORGANIZATION>, said Korean tariffs make the price of legally imported <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> goods very expensive. <PERSON> Heivilin </PERSON> told the subcommittee the cost of serving the black market was about $ 7 million a year, assuming that 20 percent of the $ 250.4 million worth of items sold in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> in 1988 ended up in the cupboards of unauthorized individuals. `` This is totally abhorrent, totally unacceptable,'' said <PERSON> Levin </PERSON>, who has called for a reduction of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> forces in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Sandra </PERSON> <PERSON> Kristoff </PERSON>, an assistant <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade representative for <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION>, acknowledged that <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>'s restrictive import practices have fueled the black market. But she stressed that the Korean black market has been in existence for some time, and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is taking steps to reduce the illegal sales. `` In July of 1988 our cigarette agreement with <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> went into effect, permitting the importation of cigarettes without restraint,'' she said. `` Black market activity in this product has dropped off significantly since then.'' To solve the problem, <PERSON> Levin </PERSON> has suggested elimination of the ration control system in which service members with no dependents are limited to $ 500 per month and those with dependents $ 800 per month. Another option is convincing <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> `` to open its doors to these high-demand consumer goods,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0031EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ColombianSentence     10-20 0256</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombian Sentence,0262</SECOND>
<HEAD>Colombian Drug Trafficker's Sentence Overturned on Nationality Issue</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A federal appeals court overturned the 12-year prison sentence of a Colombian drug trafficker on grounds that a lower-court judge wrongly considered the man's nationality in determining punishment. The three-member appeals panel on Thursday returned the case of <PERSON> Mauricio </PERSON> <PERSON> Borrero-Isaza </PERSON> to <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> for resentencing. The 9th U.S. <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> ruled that a sentence may not be based even partly on a defendant's nationality, noting that <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> penalized <PERSON> Borrero </PERSON> more harshly than a non-Colombian co-defendant. <PERSON> Borrero </PERSON> was convicted of conspiracy and possession with intent to distribute cocaine after he was arrested in 1986 with more than two pounds of the drug in his car. During sentencing, <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> repeatedly told the defense attorney that he wanted to show people in cocaine-exporting countries that they would be harshly punished if they shipped drugs to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` Somehow the people who are selling narcotics, particularly from source countries, have to know that we in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> mean business, and we are going to put a stop to this,'' <PERSON> Keller </PERSON> said at the time. `` I want people in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> to know it is not going to be tolerated.'' The appeals court said that while it is appropriate to consider `` the fact that a criminal has trafficked in drugs originating from a source country like <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>,'' a defendant's nationality is irrelevant. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lind </PERSON>, a co-defendant who pleaded guilty in the case, received a seven-year sentence from <PERSON> Keller </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0034EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FlagBurning Bjt   10-20 0701</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Flag Burning, Bjt,680</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senators Say Concern About Bill of Rights Grew as Passions Cooled</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX8</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senate concern about freedom of speech and a cooling of the summer's political passions combined to defeat the proposed constitutional amendment to ban flag burning, lawmakers say. `` I do n't know that public interest has faded; I think that public interest has changed,'' Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON>, R-Mo., said Thursday after the proposed amendment failed in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Opponents of the measure said Americans are having second thoughts about the notion of changing the Constitution. White House lobbying appeared minimal despite a strong public campaign that last summer took President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to the foot of the Iwo Jima Memorial. The measure did win a bare majority in the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION>, 51-48, but fell 15 votes short of the required two-thirds of senators present and voting. Eleven Republicans joined 37 Democrats to oppose the measure. Thirty-three Republicans and 18 Democrats voted for the proposal, which would have authorized the state and federal governments to outlaw flag desecration. Following the vote, <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Alixe </PERSON> <PERSON> Glen </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> was `` disappointed'' and believes such an amendment represents `` the only ... real protection for the flag.'' She said a bill sent to the president last week to ban flag-burning by statute `` would not survive constitutional scrutiny.'' Critics of the amendment, in contrast, said the bill would satisfy concern in the country about flag-burning. `` I think when the statute passed, it made it much easier to focus on the Constitution,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Leahy </PERSON>, D-Vt. `` But this amendment should fall anyway because of the danger it poses to the Bill of Rights. Sen. <PERSON> Strom </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurmond </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-S.C. </LOCATION>, a strong supporter of the amendment, told reporters that `` the public was confused on this.'' `` They were led to believe a statute would do the job and produce results,'' he said. `` Now we do n't know what we've got if anything.'' Supporters of the amendment claimed it was the only sure way to prevent a recurrence of the <ORGANIZATION> Supreme </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> decision in June that overturned the conviction of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> flag-burner <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON> on grounds his right to free speech was violated. `` We all lose with this action,'' said <PERSON> Miles </PERSON> <PERSON> Eplin </PERSON>, national commander of the American Legion, after the vote. `` Today, I feel like my friends have been let down, as well as those from other generations who died believing that our nation would always remember their sacrifices and respect the foremost symbol of all they held dear.'' Critics said there would be a political price to pay at election time for opposing the measure. At the same time, though, they seemed increasingly emboldened to attack the amendment as a threat to the Constitution. `` We face no sudden or uncontrollable burst of flag destruction,'' Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, declared. `` ... Yet we are being asked to believe that the flag which neither <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON> nor <PERSON> Stalin </PERSON> could defeat is now threatened by a single misguided person who most Americans never heard of and do n't care about. Minority Leader <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Dole </PERSON>, R-Kan., took the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> floor on Thursday morning to make one last appeal for approval of the measure He painted a colorful panorama of flag history from Iwo Jima to the lunar landing and said the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> was too bogged down in technicalities. `` The need for this amendment will not be found in a textbook or a treatise on constitutional law,'' <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said. `` No, it will be found in the emotions of the heart, emotions deeply rooted in the real-life experiences of millions of Americans, and emotions that are crying out today to give the flag real and lasting protection.'' Afterward, <PERSON> Dole </PERSON> said: `` I think the flag should be flown at half-staff after this vote.'' <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> <PERSON> Rudman </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-N.H. </LOCATION>, initially co-sponsored the proposal, but both did an about-face on Tuesday and became opponents. `` When I was originally asked to support it, I thought, I want to protect the flag,'' <PERSON> Danforth </PERSON> said. `` ... But as the vote got closer and as I started reflecting on it and getting more serious about it, my opinion became one of the greatest reluctance to change the Constitution.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0038EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-20 0846</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0882</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Arista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> plans to record <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON> and other big-name artists at a new recording studio that company officials hope will make <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> `` the Motown of the South.'' The studio will be part of a new label, LaFace, and will be run by <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> and <PERSON> Kenny </PERSON> <PERSON> Edmonds </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Arista </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Clive </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said Thursday. The pair, who have written or produced songs for artists such as <PERSON> Paula </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul </PERSON>, <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sheena </PERSON> <PERSON> Easton </PERSON>, recently moved to <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> from <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. In a memo to <ORGANIZATION> Arista </ORGANIZATION> employees in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> this week, <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said <PERSON> Reid </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edmonds </PERSON> `` will produce a limited number of outside projects _ including, at my specific request, <PERSON> Whitney </PERSON> <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>.'' Ms. <PERSON> Houston </PERSON>'s first two LPs, `` <LOCATION> Whitney </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Houston </LOCATION>'' and `` Whitney,'' have total sales of about $ 15 million. `` <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> is an easy place to come to, and this is a consideration when you're working with artists from all over the country and the world,'' <PERSON> Davis </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> Arista </ORGANIZATION>, owned by <ORGANIZATION> BMG </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION>, has reported gross sales of $ 120 million so far this year. <ORGANIZATION> BMG </ORGANIZATION> also owns <ORGANIZATION> RCA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Records </ORGANIZATION> and the Jive recording label.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 More than 240 relatives of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military personnel hitched a free ride with <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> on a jumbo jet carrying the former first couple to <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> left Thursday on a trip to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> aboard a <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> 747 chartered by the <ORGANIZATION> Fujisankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spokesman <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Weinberg </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> and I promised ourselves that if we ever had a chance to bring families together, we would,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in a statement. `` When we learned we would have so many extra seats on the airplane being provided to us, we knew immediately what to do.'' The people who accompanied the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> were visiting relatives based in the Orient. The Reagans are expected to receive $ 1 million for several charitable and public appearances in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> before returning Oct. 28.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former House Speaker <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> `` Tip'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> says the Democrats in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> who surrendered their ideals to <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s popularity are the same ones who pushed for a get-tough policy in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> said Democratic ideals have suffered this decade, adding: `` I had so many Democrats run away from me, their promises and policies, mostly because they were frightened of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s popularity. He said he disagreed with those same Democrats who are criticizing President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for failing to intervene in the failed coup attempt against the Panamanian leader, Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. `` I just think that <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is going to fall on himself. I'm glad we did n't send any troops in there,'' <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON> said <PERSON> O'Neill </PERSON>, who left the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> in 1987, invited reporters to his hotel room late Wednesday after speaking before the <ORGANIZATION> Pennsylvania </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Certified </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accountants </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> chapter
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ROGUE RIVER, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Jimmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Rosalynn </PERSON>, are spending a four-day fishing trip on the <LOCATION> Rogue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> <PERSON> Helfrich </PERSON>, an outfitter from the <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION> area, took the <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> party down the wild river in southern <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> on Thursday, said another outfitter, <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Norrick </PERSON>. `` It's good for the area to have someone like that come here to go on the river,'' said <PERSON> Norrick </PERSON>, who guided then-Vice President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> on a one-day fishing trip on the Rogue in 1988. `` Carter fishes a lot,'' <PERSON> Norrick </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> previously fished the middle fork of the <LOCATION> Salmon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION>. It has been a good season for area outfitters, <PERSON> Norrick </PERSON> said. `` The weather has been good, but we need a little rain,'' <PERSON> Norrick </PERSON> said. `` I hate to see someone like Mr. <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> rained on, though.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Derek </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobi </PERSON>, whose stage roles have included a prince of <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION>, became a Danish knight in recognition of his achievements as an actor and director, especially his interpretations of <PERSON> Shakespeare </PERSON>. Queen <PERSON> Margrethe </PERSON> II of <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> authorized the knighthood for the actor, who played <PERSON> Hamlet </PERSON> at <LOCATION> Elsinore </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Denmark </LOCATION> in 1979 and directed the play when he returned in 1988. Danish Ambassador <PERSON> Rudolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorning-Petersen </PERSON> presented <PERSON> Jacobi </PERSON> with the Royal Order of Knight of the Dannebrog, First Class, at a reception Thursday.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>EDGARTOWN, Mass. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A black warm-up jacket owned by actor <PERSON> Gregory </PERSON> <PERSON> Peck </PERSON> brought $ 530 at the fifth <PERSON> Martha </PERSON>'s Vineyard Celebrity Hat Auction. The auction, where more than hats were sold, obviously, was held over the Columbus Day weekend and raised $ 7,500 for a child-care program on the island off <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cod </LOCATION>, organizers said this week. <PERSON> Joan </PERSON> <PERSON> Baez </PERSON> contributed a worn and battered straw hat with the singer's signature on the brim. `` You're really getting an oldy but a favorite,'' <PERSON> Baez </PERSON> wrote in a letter that came with the hat. <PERSON> Judy </PERSON> <PERSON> Belushi </PERSON>, an auctioneer, held up the hat noting bent and worn places. `` It did n't get this way in her closet,'' <PERSON> Belushi </PERSON> said. The hat sold for $ 150. Singer <PERSON> Emmy </PERSON> <PERSON> Lou </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON>' hat brought $ 210, according to the Vineyard Gazette. And the original score for <PERSON> Johnny </PERSON> <PERSON> Mathis </PERSON>' song `` Chances Are'' brought $ 410.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0028EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SFQuake-Watsonville 2ndLd-Writethru a0832 10-20 0828</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake-Watsonville, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0832,0851</SECOND>
<HEAD>Frightened Residents Afraid to Go Indoors, Aftershocks Heap More
Damage</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS grafs 9-10, bgng, `Twenty miles ..., to UPDATE with reports
of 10,000 homeless in Santa Cruz, sewage spill, further quake damage; pick
up 11th graf pvs, `The discovery ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRUCE V. BIGELOW</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WATSONVILLE, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Earthquake-damaged homes collapsed under the prodding of powerful aftershocks Thursday, renewing fears among hundreds of residents already too horrified to go indoors. `` The whole neighborhood went outside. It's too scary inside when these things hit,'' resident <PERSON> Lucy </PERSON> <PERSON> Hernandez </PERSON> said hours after the series of aftershocks struck this quiet agricultural community 70 miles south of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>. More than 150 homes in the narrow coastal valley will likely be condemned, many of those dealt the ultimate blow during the aftershocks to Tuesday's destructive 6.9-magnitude temblor, said City Clerk <PERSON> Lorraine </PERSON> <PERSON> Washington </PERSON>. Preliminary estimates place damage at nearly $ 100 million _ some $ 24 million to homes and up to $ 75 million to industrial and commercial buildings. <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION> is about 20 miles south of the epicenter of the quake. `` Some stores on Main Street probably have to be demolished,'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said. The older brick and unreinforced concrete structures took the brunt of the latest shaking. The quakes were too much for the historical <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Patrick </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>, which withstood the 1906 quake With its underpinnings crumbling, demolition is considered a certainty. The violent rumbles sent chills through the 30,000 residents in the predominantly Hispanic community, part of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>'s so-called `` salad bowl'' region, where much of the nation's lettuce, asparagus and artichokes are Twenty miles northwest of <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION>, in the seaside city of <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION>, authorities said as many as 10,000 people were believed to be homeless Thursday night. Also Thursday, <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> officials closed all beaches in the city because of a sewage spill, and a strong aftershock that struck in the late afternoon caused more damage to a major highway already closed after Tuesday's temblor. Earlier in the day, a rescue team pulled the body of 23-year-old <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> from under two tons of rubble that rained down on her when a downtown <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> coffee store collapsed during Tuesday's deadly earthquake The discovery brought a tragic end to an emotional conflict between searchers and the woman's friends, who had insisted that Ms. <PERSON> Ortiz </PERSON> might be alive and criticized rescue efforts as too slow. Police said at least five people were arrested Wednesday night when they broke through a barricade at the site of the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cruz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Coffee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Roasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> after being told that the search was being halted at dark. In <LOCATION> Watsonville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said 400 to 500 residents sought refuge in shelters and another 500 were camping outside on lawns, in back yards, parks and empty fields. `` These people do n't want to go back home and do n't want to go to the shelters. They feel safer outdoors than in a building,'' <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said. <PERSON> Marcelina </PERSON> <PERSON> Toussaint </PERSON>, a 73-year-old woman wearing purple gloves and a felt beret, said she slept uneasily in a chair next to her front door and made frequent dashes outside whenever the earth moved. `` I ca n't stop shaking,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Toussaint </PERSON> said. `` I guess I'm surviving, but I'm scared. Many residents who emptied out of their broken homes spread across lawns and vacant lots like refugees. `` We're talking about people with no resources, no money for food and no money for health care,'' said <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, executive director of <ORGANIZATION> Salud </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pera </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> La </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gente </ORGANIZATION>, a state-funded community clinic. `` I think the big thing now is that the aftershocks are really scaring people,'' Ms. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said. Hundreds of people spent the night at local <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> shelters and churches and more than 100 camped in a vacant downtown lot designated as the future site of the <ORGANIZATION> Watsonville </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. `` We have no place to live. The building cracked,'' said <PERSON> Raoul </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON>, 36, who works in the lettuce fields. Thirty children romped on a pile of clothing nearby as <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> added, `` It's hard, especially for the kids, because we have no gas, water, special things for kids.'' At a shelter set up at a National Guard armory near the airport, scores of families sat on steel folding chairs and cots with blankets and clothing strewn everywhere. Earthquake victims also found food and shelter at St. Patrick's. Even though the red brick church was shattered by the quake, the Rev. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Miller </PERSON> voiced optimism during his Thursday sermon. He reminded his congregation gathered in another church building, `` The foundation of the church is Christ, and that's an unshakeable rock. ... We've just lost a house -LRB- the church -RRB-. We'll have to build a new house. <PERSON> Miller </PERSON>, who also conducted prayer services at local shelters, said he found quake victims `` at peace and glad to have each other.'' `` I guess what I'll remember most about the shelters were the people clinging to each other _ they were clinging to the right things,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0042EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-MeasuringQuakes     10-20 0720</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Measuring Quakes,700</SECOND>
<HEAD>Measuring Earthquakes, From Chinese Dragon Bowls to Laser Precision</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RANDOLPH E. SCHMID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Today sensitive instruments detect every tiny movement of the earth's crust, recording in detail disastrous earthquakes like the one in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> on Tuesday. These geological tools represent the ultimate refinement in a line that began almost 2,000 years ago with the ancient dragon bowl that dropped a ball when shaken. The first earthquake recording device was credited to the Chinese philosopher <PERSON> Chang </PERSON> <PERSON> Heng </PERSON> in the year 132. He developed a bowl with dragon-shaped heads located at eight points around the outside. Each had a small ball balanced in its mouth; during an earthquake the ball dropped out, landing in the mouth of a toad statue located below. The location of a quake was supposed to determine which dragon dropped its ball, and the instrument was said to have recorded a quake 400 miles away that could not be felt by people near the bowl. J. de la Haute <PERSON> Feuille </PERSON> developed a similar device to record quakes in the year 1703, filling his bowl to the brim with mercury. In a quake, some mercury would spill on the side toward the quake. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Russ </PERSON>, assistant chief geologist at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Geological </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Survey </ORGANIZATION>, said that in modern measuring devices, instruments near the center of an earthquake are knocked off their recording scale in a violent temblor, but readings can be calculated from the waves reaching more distant machines. Agency scientists at <LOCATION> Menlo </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Park </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, near the site of Tuesday's deadly quake, are now collecting all available information on what happened. The basic tool today is a seismograph, an instrument developed in the late 19th century. Basically, it is a box with a frame attached to the ground that includes a suspended weight, which is able to swing. When an earthquake causes the frame to move, inertia forces the mass to lag behind and its swing is recorded by a pen and ink sweeping back and forth over paper. That pen trace is the commonly shown seismogram. These machines can be set for vertical or horizontal shaking and in modern machines the shaking produces an electrical signal which is amplified to drive a pen, allowing them to be much more sensitive than in the past. Over the years scientists have learned that earthquakes produce more than one type of wave, and that the different kinds move through the earth's crust at different speeds. By comparing the time of arrival of the different wave forms at a seismograph, scientists can determine how far away a quake occurred. Comparing the results at several locations allows them to calculate the exact position of the quake. While these are still the primary instruments used to measure quakes, geologists also have developed an array of other machines. For example, <PERSON> Russ </PERSON> pointed out that in parts of <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> along the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Andreas </LOCATION> fault, laser beams are used to measure land movement. The laser is placed on a hill and shines on a target located on the other side of a fault. Regular flashes of light allow the scientist to compare the time it takes for the light to travel between the two spots and thus calculate whether the light and target are moving relative to one another. Other instruments buried in the earth can sense the stresses placed on rocks. Measurements are also made of radon and other gases released by the earth and sensitive meters can even trace changes in the strength of gravity beneath the spots where they are located. A pendulum was first used to record a quake in <LOCATION> Naples </LOCATION> in 1731, with <PERSON> Nichomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Cirillo </PERSON> reporting that the amplitude of the swing decreased with distance from the quakes. Using a magnifier trained at the image of a cross hair, focused on a bowl of mercury, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mallet </PERSON> was able to measure the speed of waves in the earth following dynamite explosions in <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> in 1851. <PERSON> Luigi </PERSON> <PERSON> Palmieri </PERSON> installed a seismograph at <LOCATION> Mount </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vesuvius </LOCATION> in 1856, but the instruments were brought into general use toward the end of that century by a group of British geologists headed by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Milne </PERSON>, working in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Milne </PERSON> eventually managed to get seismograph stations set up around the world, collecting data at a central observatory for analysis.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Abortion Bjt   10-20 0431</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Abortion, Bjt,420</SECOND>
<HEAD>Senate Vote Puts Abortion Matter in Sight of Bush Veto</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The stage is set for a presidential veto of a bill allowing government-paid abortions for poor women who are victims of rape or incest. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> put the matter in President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s hands Thursday when it gave final congressional approval to a spending bill including the new provisions for Medicaid abortions. The 67-31 vote drew little debate after the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>'s surprise vote last week to approve the broader provisions. The <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> passed the measure before, but final agreement on a compromise spending bill was needed to send the bill to the president. The measure would allow federal money to be spent on abortions for poor women who are victims of rape or incest and who `` reported promptly'' to law enforcement or public health authorities. Medicaid restrictions in the law since 1981 permit federal money for abortions only in cases where the life of the mother is endangered by her pregnancy. `` The president has told us he will veto this bill because he wo n't accept language that allows poor rape and incest victims access to abortions,'' said Sen. <PERSON> Brock </PERSON> <PERSON> Adams </PERSON>, D-Wash. `` I'm sorry the president of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the most powerful man in the world, has chosen to veto this bill ... and thereby cause enormous additional suffering for some of the world's most unfortunate and powerless victims,'' he Rep. <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Green </PERSON> of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, a Republican moderate, said 30 House Republicans have sent <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> a letter urging him to sign the bill. <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s opposition to the measure puts `` him and us in a really indefensible position.'' `` I would strongly urge the president to recognize that poor women have the right to make that same moral choice ... as rich women do,'' <PERSON> Green </PERSON> said. The abortion provision is part of a $ 156.7 billion measure to finance labor, health and education programs for fiscal 1990, which began Oct. 1. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> had said last week he was looking for `` room for flexibility'' and did not wish `` conflict'' on abortion _ an issue that has been troublesome for him throughout his political career. But this week he hardened his stand and promised the veto, saying government financing of the abortions `` would compound a violent act with the taking of an unborn life.'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> says he supports permitting abortions in cases of rape, incest or danger to the life of the mother but opposes having the federal government pay for the abortions in cases of rape or incest.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0054EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--Hungary-Samizdat     10-20 0142</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Hungary-Samizdat,0145</SECOND>
<HEAD>Interior Ministry: Confiscated Samizdat To Be Returned</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BUDAPEST, Hungary (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Interior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> says it will return all samizdat materials and printing machines that police seized from independent writers and publishers between 1983 and 1988. The ministry did not say how much equipment or samizdat had been confiscated. It said, however, that just one copy of each confiscated samizdat work remained in the archives as the rest had been destroyed. Many of <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s long-time leading dissidents are members of opposition groups that have in the past 18 months gained full legal and political recognition as the country transforms itself into a Western-style democracy. One of the best known underground or samizdat journals, Beszeloe, is now legally sold on Hungarian newsstands and published regularly. The announcement was made Thursday in a communique carried by the official <ORGANIZATION> MTI </ORGANIZATION> news agency.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PerestroikaBeckons     10-20 0620</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Perestroika Beckons,610</SECOND>
<HEAD>WASHINGTON TODAY: American Businesses are Ready to Cash In</HEAD>
<BYLINE>An AP News Analysis</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>By BARRY SCHWEID</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Diplomatic Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration does n't share the enthusiasm of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> businesses eager to jump in for profit and excitement as Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seeks to reform a Marxist system lagging in productivity and consumer goods. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>, speaking this week to the private <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Policy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, again stressed the view that lasting economic change must come from within; it can not and should not be provided by the West. Consumer shortages are unlikely to be relieved nor productivity increased without a stable currency, free and competitive markets, private property and real prices, <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> said. `` The very logic of perestroika requires that the Soviets themselves must solve their own problems in a comprehensive, organic way,'' he said. But American businesses are charging in nonetheless. Fifty new posts are being added to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> to assist them in grappling with Soviet bureaucracy and a legal system that is in such flux that entrepreneurs are having a rough time seizing capitalistic opportunities. <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> may be changing the way Soviet bureaucrats and ordinary citizens think about the marketplace, but historically people who have lived all their lives under Marxism are not risk-takers. The Soviets also do not have the cash to pay for American-built enterprises, nor the goods to barter for them _ with the exception of such items as oil, gold, diamonds and furs that the Soviets prefer to sell for themselves on world markets. And yet about 4,000 American companies are trying to do business in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, compared to less than 100 before <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> assumed power in 1985. A thousand joint ventures have been signed and registered, but only a dozen or so deals have been struck. The most picturesque: McDonald's and Pizza Hut soon will be selling fast food to Russians. The foreign investment is relatively small, averaging about $ 1 million a venture. Still, American businessmen look at the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as the last great untapped market, said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> N. </PERSON> <PERSON> Dean </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Coudert </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brothers </ORGANIZATION> lawyer who last year opened the first <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> office for an American law firm. <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> said Thursday that under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> the Soviets have bent over backwards to liberalize their joint venture laws. But he described other laws that govern American investors as `` very uncertain territory.'' Often, he said, Soviet laws are not available to the public. `` Either they are state secrets or nobody can find them,'' <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> said at a forum on U.S.-Soviet trade relations. Getting approval for projects also is a huge problem for Westerners. `` This is a business culture that is sort of fused with a political culture,'' <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> said. Moreover, the general atmosphere in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is hazy. Soviet law is in the midst of a major overhaul. The right to strike, ownership of property, freedom of assembly and speech are among the fundamental issues being debated in the Supreme Soviet. This carries a risk for American businesses, which prefer stability and certainty. And yet, there is a trend under <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to promote domestic benefits for the Soviet people. The <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is prepared to give up a hotel site if the foreign partner is willing to arrange financing to rebuild a factory outside the capital, <PERSON> Dean </PERSON> said. `` This is a good thing, and it offers some opportunities,'' said the American lawyer. `` It gets at an awful problem that they have. The deterioration in the standard of living of the Soviet people is becoming a greater and greater concern.''
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 EDITOR'S NOTE: <PERSON> Barry </PERSON> <PERSON> Schweid </PERSON> reports on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> foreign policy for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0106EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-StudentsRally     10-20 0290</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Students Rally,0298</SECOND>
<HEAD>After Rally, Damage to Statehouse and, Possibly, Students' Cause</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KEVIN GALVIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Opponents of cuts in education funds said a huge <ORGANIZATION> Statehouse </ORGANIZATION> demonstration showed the strength of their cause, and students volunteered to replace mums that were trampled when the rally turned unruly. About 15,000 state college and university students gathered at the Capitol Wednesday, but organizers lost control of the protest. Four people were arrested and two injured in the melee. `` The fact that so many people came out was extraordinary and sent a very clear message that they care about the quality of their education,'' <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Tsongas </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regents </ORGANIZATION> in Higher Education, said Thursday. `` But, like I remember during my youth, the excesses of a handful always get more attention than what I believe was the remarkably good -LRB- behavior -RRB- of the vast, vast majority.'' Horticulture students from the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Amherst </LOCATION> volunteered Thursday to plant chrysanthemums to replace the ones trampled by students in front of the Capitol, said state Rep. <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenberg </PERSON>. Doors and windows inside the building were broken and a drainpipe was knocked down by students who climbed to the roof. The maintenance office said the front lawn would need to be reseeded. Rep. <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Lewis </PERSON> was caught in the crunch of students and shaken up as she tried to enter the chamber to answer a roll-call vote. But she said she would n't hold the `` ill-behaved and outrageous'' minority against the students' cause. The higher education budget, already strapped by earlier cuts, is set to be stripped of $ 25 million more during the next round of budget reductions. The protesters were calling for the programmed cuts to be restored.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0107EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NuclearPriest Bjt   10-20 0689</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nuclear Priest, Bjt,0712</SECOND>
<HEAD>Test-Site Minister: `The Only Priest I Know Who Fires Nuclear Weapons'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM DAHLBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Many priests are called upon at the hour of death, but the Rev. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> may be the only priest with his finger on the button of the bombs that could one day obliterate mankind. As a nuclear test controller at the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> Test Site, his job is to safely detonate the most powerful and horrifying weapons. As an ordained Episcopal priest, he prays those weapons will never be used. Actually, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> says, it is n't buttons that set off the bombs. `` It's all done by computers now,'' he explained in a recent interview. But with priests generally among the protesters at the underground test site where he works, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> says he is forced daily to reconcile the differences between his occupation and his calling. He admits to being `` the only priest I know who fires nuclear weapons.'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a 48-year-old father of two children, became a priest two years ago and, as he explains it, almost against his will. `` With my family, work and other commitments, I thought becoming a priest was something that just could n't happen,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. But he finally heeded a bishop's advice that a true calling would not go away. `` The way God works, he just does n't follow the rules at all,'' he said. As deputy manager of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> operations for the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and one of three rotating controllers at the test site, he has given the final authority for the detonation of more than 30 underground nuclear tests in the 1980s. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> often is asked to go before anti-nuclear groups and explain the government's position that nuclear testing is vital to the nation's security. `` I do n't think in any of these discussions I change anybody's mind or they change mine, but we come away from honest and direct discussions the better for it,'' he said `` The best comment I ever got from one anti-nuclear activist was ` I do n't agree with what you're doing, but I'm glad you're the one doing it.''' He added that he would like to be in a situation where there are no nuclear weapons. `` But I would also like a situation where we maintain the system of freedom and justice we have in our country,'' he said. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, a lifelong <PERSON> Episcopalian </PERSON>, was nominated into the priesthood by the congregation at <ORGANIZATION> All </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Saints </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> under a church canon that allows the elevation of parishioners to priests in remote parishes. `` Bob is just an exceptional priest and a very humble person,'' said the Rev. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Zabriskie </PERSON>, the church's <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> bishop. `` I wish I had more like him.'' <PERSON> Nick </PERSON> <PERSON> Aquilina </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>'s boss and the manager of the sprawling nuclear testing facility northwest of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>'s honesty had gained him the respect of co-workers as well as that of protesters on the other side of the fence `` He's the kind of guy I admire and respect whether he worked for me or was on the other side,'' <PERSON> Aquilina </PERSON> said. `` I believe he comes across in a very credible way because he's so honest. I've never second-guessed his motives on anything. <PERSON> Zabriskie </PERSON>, who said the <ORGANIZATION> Episcopal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> has taken no firm stand on nuclear testing, views <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> as a `` bridge builder'' who is able to communicate with both sides on an emotional issue. `` I think he's a peacemaker; I really do,'' <PERSON> Zabriskie </PERSON> said. `` He takes a lot of risks and is very vulnerable when he stands up before the hostility of some people.'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> does not criticize anti-nuclear protesters who often congregate at the gates of the test site. Many are his friends, including the wife of another Episcopal priest in <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> and the priest's wife are founding board members and work closely together on a project to build a shelter for homeless women and children. `` We just do n't talk about nuclear weapons when we're working together,'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> said. `` She and I have the same ultimate aim. We'd both like not to have nuclear weapons. The difference is how we get there.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-20-89 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StateIncomes     10-20 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-State Incomes,410</SECOND>
<HEAD>Plains States Lag Behind in Income Growth</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN D. McCLAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The states in the center of the country are falling behind the rest of the nation in the rate of nonfarm personal income growth, the government says. `` In the Plains region, nonfarm income grew 6.9 percent ... 1.5 percentage points below the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> average,'' the <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> reported Thursday. `` Durable manufacturing payrolls grew slower than in any other region. `` Construction and nondurable manufacturing also were weak,'' according to the report by the department's <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Analysis </ORGANIZATION>. `` In each <LOCATION> Plains </LOCATION> state _ <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Missouri </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Minnesota </LOCATION> _ nonfarm income grew slower than the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. average.'' States in the interior regions generally continued to lag behind both coasts in income growth. The interior regions averaged a 7.5 percent rate, while the coastal regions averaged 8.9 percent. Besides the Plains, the growth rate in other interior regions was 7.5 percent in the <LOCATION> Rocky </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountain </LOCATION> states; 7.7 percent in the <ORGANIZATION> Southwest </ORGANIZATION>, and 7.9 percent in the Great Lakes. The average growth for the country was 8.4 percent, the department said. The inflation rate for the 12 months ending in June was 5.2 percent. The Far West led the coastal growth, up 9.6 percent, bolstered by strength in construction and manufacturing, particularly aircraft production. The <ORGANIZATION> Boeing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is headquartered in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state and the <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> McDonnell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Douglas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> is in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>. The Far West also includes <LOCATION> Oregon </LOCATION> and the national income growth leader, <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. In each of the other coastal regions, however, growth was only somewhat above the national average _ up 8.7 percent in the Southeast, 8.6 percent in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> and 8.5 in the <LOCATION> Mid-Atlantic </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>, with its tourism and mining industries, continued to lead the country in income growth, up 12.8 percent. <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> ranked last with a 3.6 percent growth rate. Following <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> in income growth were: <LOCATION> Delaware </LOCATION>, 10.9 percent; <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>, 10.5 percent; <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, 10.4 percent; <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, 10.3 percent; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 10.1 percent; <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>, 10 percent; <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, 9.9 percent; <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, 9.7 percent; and <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, 9.6 percent. Ranked with <LOCATION> Wyoming </LOCATION> at the bottom of the list were: <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, up 4.3 percent; <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION>, 5.9 percent; <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Dakota </LOCATION>, 6 percent; <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, 6.3 percent; <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, 6.4 percent; <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION>, 6.4 percent; <LOCATION> Nebraska </LOCATION>, 6.6 percent; <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION>, 6.7 percent, and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, 6.8 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> focuses on changes in nonfarm income as a better indication of a region's prosperity because of the often erratic nature of farm income.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891020-0025 </DOCNO>
