<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0509EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a AM-BRF--BotchedBurials 1stLd-Writethru a0855 10-28 0153</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Botched Burials, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0855,0151</SECOND>
<HEAD>Funeral Director Sentenced in Improper Burial Case</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: FIXES typo in burying in lead; ADDS county to judge's title
in 2nd graf.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SPRINGFIELD, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A former funeral director was sentenced Friday to 28 years and 11 months in prison for burying the dead with trash in their coffins or without prepaid vaults. <ORGANIZATION> Robertson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circuit </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Peay </PERSON> sentenced <PERSON> Bobby </PERSON> <PERSON> Wilks </PERSON> less than three weeks after <PERSON> Wilks </PERSON> pleaded guilty to 48 counts of burial fraud. <PERSON> Wilks </PERSON>, 53, entered the pleas to a 71-count indictment on Oct. 11 and opted for sentencing by a judge rather than face a jury trial, prosecutors said. Relatives of the burial victims had called for a harsh sentence for the Millsdale mortician. Exhumations last fall revealed more than 25 bodies buried by <PERSON> Wilks </PERSON>' business had been buried improperly in <PERSON> Robertson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Sumner </PERSON> counties, and <LOCATION> Simpson </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION>, Ky.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0007EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HazelwoodTrial     10-28 0283</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Hazelwood Trial,0290</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hazelwood Trial Moved to Anchorage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The trial of former <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> skipper <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> will be held in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> despite defense claims that it will be hard to field an impartial jury in this port city. `` If <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON> can get a fair trial, I'm sure Capt. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> can get a fair trial, too,'' <ORGANIZATION> Anchorage </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> Judge <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnstone </PERSON> said at a hearing Friday. Prosecutors had earlier agreed that <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON>, where the tanker picked up its load before causing the nation's worst oil spill March 24, was an inappropriate site for the trial. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s lawyer, <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Madson </PERSON>, of Fairbanks, argued that an opinion poll showed that inland Fairbanks was the city most likely to offer a fair trial. He said people in <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>, which lies on the coast about 350 miles south of <LOCATION> Fairbanks </LOCATION>, were more likely to be influenced by ties to maritime industries affected by the spill. <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION> prosecutor <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Cole </PERSON> pushed for his city, saying it offered a much bigger pool of potential jurors. The city's population of 250,000 is about five times the size of Fairbanks <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> faces misdemeanor and felony charges stemming from the crash of the tanker in Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. Exxon fired the skipper soon after the ship struck a charted reef and spilled nearly 11 million gallons of crude oil, polluting miles of shoreline and killing wildlife. The trial on charges of recklessness, negligent discharge of oil and operating a vessel while intoxicated is scheduled to open Jan. 22 and is likely to last at least three weeks. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, who lives in <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, listened to Friday's hearing by telephone from a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> law office
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0012EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-HalloweenTrends     10-28 0457</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Halloween Trends,0472</SECOND>
<HEAD>Batman, Bakkers Big Hits at Halloween</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARK PAXTON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHARLESTON, W.Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> will be going places this Halloween, even though he's in prison. <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tammy </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> costumes are among the most popular get-ups for tricksters this Halloween, says the owner of a costume shop. `` We put <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON> in a convict suit and everybody likes that,'' said <PERSON> Lisa </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Balloon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Express </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Clarksburg </LOCATION>, which is 100 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. `` <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Bakker </PERSON>'s rented out for the rest of the week.'' Elsewhere, <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> proved to be more than just a hit at the box office, overwhelming some costumers who could n't keep up with the demand for Caped Crusader Halloween outfits. `` Batman _ he's the top dog,'' said <PERSON> Joel </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, assistant to the general manager at Masters Tuxedo in <LOCATION> Charleston </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Wickham </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Costume </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in the northern <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> community of Wheeling is n't renting Batman outfits and was even unable to find any to sell, said <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON> <PERSON> Materkoski </PERSON>, a receptionist pressed into duty as a saleswoman during the seasonal crunch. `` We had a couple of people who were willing to buy, but when we called the supplier who would have sent them to us, they were out, and that was in September,'' she said Friday. Masters Tuxedo found a licensed supplier in <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION>, but not even <LOCATION> Gotham </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s most famous do-gooder could defeat the weather. `` Batman was delayed by Hurricane Hugo,'' <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> said Friday. `` They were manufactured, and the hurricane knocked down their computers, so they could n't bill or ship.'' He still hoped for a pre-Halloween shipment. Being the Caped Crusader costs an arm and a bat-leg. A Batman costume rental goes for $ 85, and buying the cape and accessories will -LRB- POW! -RRB- set you back -LRB- BAM! -RRB- $ 450, <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> said. Other popular outfits include `` sexy types for women,'' <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said, including belly dancers and <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> bunnies. In <LOCATION> Huntington </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Magic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Makers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Costumes </ORGANIZATION> has turned off its telephones until November because of the Halloween crunch, but a taped answering machine message provides a glimpse of what's popular there The recording says the company has some masks of <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON>, the razor-fingered star of the Nightmare on Elm Street movies, but no more masks of two other popular slashers _ <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Myers </PERSON> from the `` Halloween'' series and <PERSON> Jason </PERSON> from `` Friday the 13th.'' `` Freddy is still popular this year, but he's being overtaken by Friday the 13th,'' <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> said. `` In the adult rentals, it's running about the same as last year, from the French maid for women to <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> sheiks for men. <PERSON> Batman </PERSON> may find fame fleeting. One year's most popular outfits can become the next year's dust collectors. `` <PERSON> Alf </PERSON> was in last year,'' <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said. `` It's gone now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-BRF--DC-10Crash-Reward     10-28 0146</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--DC-10 Crash-Reward,0149</SECOND>
<HEAD>GE Ending Rewards for Flight 232 Engine Parts</HEAD>
<DATELINE>DES MOINES, Iowa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Dozens of engine parts from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> DC-10 jumbo jet that crashed July 19 are still missing, but <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aircraft </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engines </ORGANIZATION> says it is giving up the search for the parts. Company investigators still are unsure if the parts recovered to date will tell them enough to determine what caused the <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> crash, which killed 112 people, said <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>. But GE attorney <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON> said Friday the company has decided to end its three-month old reward program. <ORGANIZATION> GE </ORGANIZATION> will only pay rewards for parts turned in to county sheriffs' offices by 5 p.m. Nov. 3, said <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON>. Farmers near <LOCATION> Alta </LOCATION>, 60 miles east of <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, are nearly finished with their fall field work, which has turned up most of the recovered engine pieces.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0014EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TritiumSearch Bjt   10-28 0569</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Tritium Search, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Shipments of Weapons Materials Again Suspended in Probe</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> is suspending commercial shipments of tritium for the second time in four months because of another unexplained loss of the material used in nuclear warheads. Rep. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Markey </PERSON>, D-Mass., lambasted the department Friday, saying it had bungled the investigation at the <ORGANIZATION> Oak </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ridge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Laboratory </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tenn. </LOCATION> `` You have to wonder what kind of <ORGANIZATION> Keystone </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kops </ORGANIZATION> operation the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> has down at <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> when they lose more than 22,000 curies of tritium in a test designed to find out why <PERSON> DOE </PERSON> keeps on losing track of tritium,'' he said A curie is the unit used to measure radioactivity. The department usually sells about $ 5.6 million of tritium a year to private companies that use it in research and the manufacture of luminous lights and dials. Most tritium, however, is used as a vital component in nuclear warheads. `` For now, we're on hold on making further shipments,'' said <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> spokesman <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON>. <PERSON> Murray </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON>, deputy director of the lab, said in a telephone interview that investigators had not ruled out the possibility the material was stolen. He said, however, that there was no evidence of theft and that a more likely explanation was that the equipment that handles the gas had developed an air leak. <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> said shipments were suspended Oct. 5, shortly after it was discovered that a small amount of tritium shipped to a commercial customer in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> was missing. No date has been set for resuming shipments, <PERSON> Rosenthal </PERSON> said. Spokesmen at department headquarters in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> said they had no firm information about the situation at <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION>. They said questions about missing tritium and the Oak Ridge operation were being reviewed by Energy Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>. Senior officials directly involved in the issue declined to accept a reporter's phone calls. The department announced a halt in shipments from <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ridge </LOCATION> in July after an inconclusive search for about 5 grams of tritium that lab records said had been shipped to commercial customers but that buyers said never arrived. Shipments resumed in August, although not all of the lost material had been recovered. An internal lab report on efforts last summer to account for the missing material said theft was possible but unlikely. A copy of the confidential report and related Oak Ridge documents were obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> earlier this week under a Freedom of Information Act request. Investigators for <ORGANIZATION> Martin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Marietta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Systems </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which runs Oak Ridge under an <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> contract, said in the July report that a significant amount of tritium was lost during a test shipment between lab buildings. Based on figures in the report, it appeared the loss amounted to about 2 grams. That's about half the amount needed to make a single atomic warhead, according to private analysts. The test shipment was arranged as part of a broader effort to find reasons for the shipping discrepancies. Workers loaded tritium into a container, sent it across the lab to another building, unloaded part of it for sampling, reloaded it, sent it back to the original building and unloaded it again. For reasons not yet publicly explained, three-quarters of the tritium was lost in the round trip. Leakage from the containers and other procedural problems were ruled out.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0016EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-HUD-Pierce Bjt   10-28 0562</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-HUD-Pierce, Bjt,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Lawmakers Want Special Prosecutor in HUD Probe</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By WILLIAM M. WELCH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The chairman of a <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> panel investigating allegations of wrongdoing at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration says its inquiry is likely to end soon, but that the subcommittee has shown there was a `` colossal scandal'' at the agency. `` I have high hopes the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> will do its duty,'' subcommittee chairman Rep. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, D-Calif., said Friday after former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> R. </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> again refused to testify <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> excused <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> from a subpoena requiring another appearance next week and said the panel, faced with a refusal to testify from three other former top <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> officials, would soon end its inquiry. The subcommittee, <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> said, had `` demonstrated a colossal scandal'' existed at the <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> during the <PERSON> Reaga </PERSON> administration. The panel is investigating allegations of fraud, influence-peddling and mismanagement. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> said the subcommittee does n't plan to offer immunity from prosecution to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> or his former aides as a way of compelling them to testify, though that remains an option. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> invoked his Fifth Amendment right against self-incrimination for a second time Friday, and some lawmakers called for a special prosecutor. `` Now it's clear that <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> is stonewalling,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-N.Y. </LOCATION> `` Our only choice now is to take the process from the legislative arena and move it into the arena of an independent counsel.'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he wants to tell his story but refused to answer any questions, saying he had been made a target of the subcommittee's investigation and `` unfairly accused of alleged lies and dishonesty. `` I look forward to the time when innuendoes and rumors to the contrary are put to rest,'' he said. `` I look forward to the time when I can tell my story, and I can assure you I do have a story to tell.'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> testified voluntarily before the panel in May. But he refused to testify last month when the panel subpoenaed him to answer questions about what members say are inconsistencies and contradictions between his and other witnesses' testimony. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> put a series of questions to <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, including one about a former <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> official's contradiction of the former secretary's testimony that he did not influence the selection of <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> subsidy awards <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> called the question `` unfair'' and refused to answer. Rep. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Shays </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Conn </LOCATION>., said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s earlier testimony on that point `` could be perjury'' and told <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> it was `` in your best interest'' to answer After <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s latest refusal, <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> and Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>., both members of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, said they would seek a vote to formally ask the <ORGANIZATION> Justice </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> to name a special prosecutor to investigate <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> Only a majority of the members of either party on the <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> is required to initiate a formal process requiring a review of the request and response by Attorney General <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Thornburgh </PERSON>, <PERSON> Schumer </PERSON> said. `` I think it's clear from these hearings ... that there is criminal activity at <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> in the area of defrauding of the federal government, conspiracy to defraud the government, and we may well have perjury,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrison </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Conn </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON>, meanwhile, disclosed that <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> had asked <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> to pay his legal expenses stemming from the congressional probe <ORGANIZATION> HUD </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Kemp </PERSON> rejected the request, <PERSON> Lantos </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-US-Panama     10-28 0375</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-US-Panama,390</SECOND>
<HEAD>U.S. Names Noriega Agent of Cuba</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVE SKIDMORE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Americans doing business with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> could face up to a 12-year prison sentence under a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration declaration naming him an agent of <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, his wife <PERSON> Felicidad </PERSON> <PERSON> Sieiro </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and 32 companies, including several hotels and airport duty-free shops, are being added to the list of 134 businesses and individuals already identified as Cuban agents in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> announced Friday. `` This action is another step in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' efforts to halt the channeling of funds to the illegal regime of Gen. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and to neutralize Cuban commercial activities in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> that serve to circumvent the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade embargo against <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>,'' the announcement said. Fourteen names, including <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> associate <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Duque </PERSON>, were added to the list Sept. 20. Under a World War I statute, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has banned trade by Americans with <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> since 1960. Violations of that embargo or similar bans against trade with <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> can result in fines up to $ 500,000 against <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> corporations and up to $ 250,000 against individuals, who can also be imprisoned for a maximum of 12 years. The latest action `` serves to underscore the administration's resolve to undermine the extensive network of commercial and financial collusion between the <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and <PERSON> Castro </PERSON> regimes. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials, speaking on condition of anonymity last week, had revealed that the designation was imminent. The officials said they had begun examining ways to bring new pressure to bear on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> even before an abortive coup attempt Oct. 3. But the administration has been reluctant to use extreme measures such as a trade embargo out of concern that hundreds of American companies in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> would go bankrupt. The new sanction is narrowly targeted at <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and his business partners and is not expected to do major damage to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s economy. It is not clear how extensive American business dealings are with the companies linked to <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION> has found these companies useful to import high technology U.S.-made items which otherwise would be beyond <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>'s reach because of the trade embargo. The companies also have served as conduits for illegal Cuban exports to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-StandardTime     10-28 0093</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Standard Time,90</SECOND>
<HEAD>Back to Standard Time Again</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tonight's the night to fall back to standard time. That means an extra hour of sleep, or partying or whatever. Officially, clocks should be turned back one hour at 2 a.m. Practically, however, the simplest thing to do is to set the clock back before retiring. A few Americans, who did n't switch to daylight time last spring, do n't have to worry about going back. They include residents of <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>, parts of <LOCATION> Indiana </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Puerto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rico </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Virgin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Samoa </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0050EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Watkins-Weapons     10-28 0575</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Watkins-Weapons,590</SECOND>
<HEAD>Watkins Shakes Up Leadership of Nuclear Weapons Office</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Turmoil appears to be growing at top levels of the <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, spurred in part by Secretary <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> D. </PERSON> <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>' frustration at ineffective leadership in the office overseeing production of nuclear weapons. In an internal memorandum obtained by The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> on Friday, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> told the department's No. 3 official, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuck </PERSON>, to assume temporarily the added title of head of defense programs, which runs the nuclear weapons system. The defense programs office has been without a permanent director for more than a year. `` The vital national security mission of the department can no longer be carried out under the current management arrangement,'' <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> wrote, adding that Tuck's assignment was designed to give the office `` leadership and direction.'' The central problem for <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> is that his choice to be permanent head of the weapons office, <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Stello </PERSON>, has been unable to gain <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> confirmation. Stello was nominated by the White House in July, but a confirmation hearing by the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Armed </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> has not been scheduled. Stello has been sharply criticized by environmentalists and some members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> for being lax on nuclear safety, although he calls the charge unfair. <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> said he hoped the Stello nomination would be acted upon soon, but one environmental group opposed to <PERSON> Stello </PERSON> said it appeared <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> was anticipating the possibility that Stello either would be blocked by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> or dropped by the White House. `` He's doomed,'' said <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Schwartz </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> Greenpeace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> U.S.A. </ORGANIZATION> Also Friday, <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> announced the resignation of <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> O </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> as director of the office of energy research. <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON> had drawn criticism in some scientific circles for his efforts to restructure the department's fusion research program. No replacement was announced. In a related development, advisers told <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> on Friday that the department may be moving too quickly in its plans for restarting the three idled <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> nuclear reactors that produce a gas needed in nuclear warheads. In a letter to <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON>, members of the <ORGANIZATION> Advisory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> on Nuclear Facility Safety said that while prospects for a safe resumption of production at <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> had improved in recent months, a number of serious problems remained. The chief concern was that training of <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION> workers who operate the reactors has not included `` reactor fundamentals'' learned by operators of commercial nuclear reactors. <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> runs <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> under a government contract. The <LOCATION> Savannah </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> reactors, built for the government in the early 1950s, were closed down more 18 months ago because of mechanical problems and safety concerns. Among the major issues in planning a restart is whether the operators are adequately trained and whether <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION> puts enough emphasis on safety. The advisers told <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> that while restart planning was generally good, the absence of operator training in reactor fundamentals was a serious problem. `` That this omission will remain through restart may belie <ORGANIZATION> Westinghouse </ORGANIZATION>'s claim that safety is their primary concern and that early restart of the reactors is not the driving factor in training,'' the letter said. In addition, the committee members said <PERSON> Watkins </PERSON> may be biting off more than he can chew in trying to get all three idled reactors back in operation within a six-month period starting next summer or fall. It might be wiser, they said, to focus all the best available talent on restarting one reactor before focusing on another.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0053EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-Exxon-Wildlife     10-28 0491</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exxon-Wildlife,510</SECOND>
<HEAD>Exxon Resigns from National Wildlife Federation Board</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By H. JOSEF HEBERT</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0017EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SFQuake 6thLd-Writethru a0836 10-28 1136</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-SF Quake, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0836,1163</SECOND>
<HEAD>Back to Bays Ball; `We Need a Respite'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with five graphs to UPDATE with Athletics' victory. Picks
up 5th graf pvs, `The first...'.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos FXP3, OAS2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTOPHER SULLIVAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fans stood for a moment of silence, then let out a whooping cheer Friday as the World Series resumed 10 days after a devastating earthquake. Rescue workers threw out the first ball and the crowd joined in singing the 1936 song `` <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>'' in opening ceremonies that began with a moment of silence for those killed and injured in the quake. `` We've had enough time for mourning. Now it's time to celebrate life,'' said <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Alvers </PERSON>, 62, who wore a yellow hard hat. `` This series needs to be played. If they canceled it it would have been a lot harder to do other things.'' `` It was OK to be excited,'' said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Verhorst </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> defeated the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> 13-7, giving the <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> a 3-0 advantage in the best of seven series. The first cheer went up when the scoreboard lit up with, `` Welcome Back to Game 3'' _ and the stadium shook again, not from the quake but the roar of the fans. Some less fortunate fans watched the game from <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION> shelters where televisions were set up for the thousands of people left homeless. `` It takes your mind off the earthquake, and that's good for the nerves,'' said <PERSON> Winston </PERSON> <PERSON> Presley </PERSON>, 54, as he sat with a cluster of A's fans in the gymnasium of <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Lowell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Middle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> For many, the resumption of the Bay Bridge World Series, its symbol now fractured by the quake, was a kind of therapy in the wake of the deadly tremor. `` Time heals all wounds,'' said <PERSON> Ray </PERSON> <PERSON> Torres </PERSON>, another fan. He and a friend, <PERSON> Alphonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON>, had seats two rows from the top of the stadium, and <PERSON> Castaneda </PERSON> had made a banner that read, `` Upper deck parachute rental.'' As fans filed in, the public address system periodically said, `` In the event of an aftershock, do n't panic ...'' `` I think it's my attempt to conquer my own fears,'' said <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Walch </PERSON> of his decision to attend the game. Having seen Candlestick shudder and crack, he added, `` I want to be at the World Series, and I do n't think it's more unsafe ... than any other place. And I want to get back to my normal life.'' The organizers of the game tried to help. Throwing out the first balls were 12 representatives of <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area agencies who assisted in relief efforts. They included workers from the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Highland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Pacific </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> ; </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Police </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> California </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conservation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fire </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cruz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Red </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cross </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Santa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cruz </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Salvation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bell </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, and the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> Highway Patrol. `` We've realized we need all this. Baseball can be part of this area's mental therapy,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> manager <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>. `` Baseball is the most resilient of all American institutions,'' said Commissioner <PERSON> Fay </PERSON> <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON>, who announced a $ 1.4 million gift from baseball to earthquake relief. Mail <PERSON> Vincent </PERSON> received from around the country after the quake urged that the series be called off, he said Friday, adding that he understood the feelings. `` But I do n't think there is any disrespect in going on with the World Series,'' he said. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, starting pitcher for the <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION>, said the players have had difficulty preparing for the game. `` We've all been through a national tragedy. I'm sure I'm not alone, but the earthquake had a deep psychological effect on me,'' <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> said. <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> outfielder <PERSON> Brett </PERSON> <PERSON> Butler </PERSON> said the game gave 62,000 fans `` a chance to let out all that frustration and hurt and trauma. This is <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s game. It's going to bring all of us in this area back together again.'' <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Art </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnos </PERSON> agreed. `` We all need a respite,'' he said. `` We can enjoy the World Series and still remember those we lost and those who are still affected by this tragedy.'' Six people remained unaccounted for, authorities said, and the death toll rose Friday to 64, including an 88-year-old <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mateo </LOCATION> woman who was pronounced dead of a heart attack shortly after the quake but who had not previously been listed among the dead. Thirty-nine of those killed were in the collapse of double-decked Interstate 880 in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. As demolition there continued, the search for more bodies was delayed because the road was too shaky. In other quake developments: _ <ORGANIZATION> Dockworker </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Buck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Helm </ORGANIZATION>, rescued after four days in the rubble of I-880, remained in serious condition in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>'s Highland General Hospital. He was said to be conscious most of the time. _ <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Berumen </PERSON>, the 6-year-old whose leg was amputated during rescue from the I-880 rubble, was listed in good condition and improving at <LOCATION> Children </LOCATION><LOCATION> 's </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> Oakland </LOCATION>. His sister <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON>, 8, was in serious but stable condition following surgery Wednesday. They lost their mother in the freeway collapse. About $ 48,000 has been donated to a fund for them. _ On Friday, 150 relatives and friends gathered at an <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cerrito </LOCATION> cemetery for the funeral of a woman killed on the collapsing portion of the <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridge </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Anamafi </PERSON> <PERSON> Filoli </PERSON> <PERSON> Moala </PERSON> was buried in a ceremony typical of the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Tonga </LOCATION>, with dirges and many of those present wearing palm grass skirts. _ In <LOCATION> Santa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cruz </LOCATION> on Friday, a wrecker's ball crashed into the imposing <ORGANIZATION> Cooper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, a downtown landmark and centerpiece of the heavily damaged <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Garden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mall </LOCATION>. Some who watched the demolition, which began Thursday, dabbed at tears. For 94 years the huge brick building was a gathering point for the seaside tourist town. `` We will come back, better than it was,'' said 86-year-old <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Davidson </PERSON>. _ Lawyer <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> on Friday filed $ 22 million worth of claims against the state on behalf of 10 victims of the collapse of I-880. If the claims _ $ 3 million for each of two wrongful deaths and $ 2 million for each of eight injured survivors _ are rejected by the state, civil lawsuits would be filed, <PERSON> Belli </PERSON> said. _ A convention of traumatic stress experts that coincidentally came to <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> a few days after the earthquake held a seminar on the disaster Friday, with experts saying everyone in the area needed to talk about the experience and to use jokes to relieve stress. `` The use of humor is good,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Aurora </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Society </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Traumatic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stress </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Studies </ORGANIZATION>. `` There's so much irony.'' People in the area have swung through a gamut of emotions including shock, excitement and euphoria at being alive, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0100EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FirstAmendment     10-28 0454</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-First Amendment,440</SECOND>
<HEAD>Balancing of First Amendment, Privacy Rights Debated</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KAREN BALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Journalists should do a better job of balancing privacy and First Amendment rights, says a woman who accused the media of badgering her family after her daughter was murdered. However, reporters and editors who participated in the same free speech seminar said most journalists are sensitive about how their story might affect the private lives of people they write about. Reporters and editors in the past tended to `` go with it and worry about the consequences tomorrow,'' said <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> McCord </PERSON>, senior editor at the <ORGANIZATION> Arkansas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gazette </ORGANIZATION>. `` It does n't seem to be like that anymore.'' About 60 journalists, media lawyers and others attended Friday's seminar sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amendment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, an umbrella organization for 16 national media and communications groups The organization tries to educate the public about First Amendment issues. <PERSON> Patsy </PERSON> <PERSON> Day </PERSON>, who founded a victims' support group after her 14-year-old daughter was murdered in 1985, criticized the media for publishing her address and camping outside her home with television crews. She said she was badgered by a reporter who wanted to film her daughter's bedroom and the media questioned whether she and her husband had violated child labor laws by letting her daughter work in the donut shop where she was abducted. `` One of the big gripes I have with the press is that they apply the same standards to -LRB- crime -RRB- victims as to public officials who are derelict in their duties,'' Mrs. Day said. The journalists said there were no clear guidelines for deciding when privacy concerns outweighed the need to have a fact in the story. `` For years and years, that collision of privacy needs and the need to know has been occurring on every level and it comes down to a judgment call,'' said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> McMasters </PERSON>, deputy editorial director of <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Today </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McMasters </PERSON> said reporters have to be careful not to have a nonchalant attitude about privacy rights. <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> McGonigle </PERSON>, a reporter for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dallas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Morning </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, said he seeks colleagues' opinions when he has qualms about invading someone's privacy. `` It's foolish and arrogant of us to make decisions that affect people's lives in a vacuum, and hopefully, most of us do n't,'' <PERSON> McGonigle </PERSON> said. The group also discussed hurdles reporters face in trying to gain access to government documents and potential changes to <ORGANIZATION> Freedom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> laws that are supposed to guarantee the public's access to information. For instance, <LOCATION> Arkansas </LOCATION>' open meetings and records law was recently changed to seal certain corporate tax documents and another effort at a `` crippling amendment'' is under way, <PERSON> McCord </PERSON> said. `` Powerful politicians are still out there and they're still our enemy,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0105EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BRF--StoreFire     10-28 0136</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Store Fire,0137</SECOND>
<HEAD>Department Store Fire Injures One, Sends Shoppers Fleeing</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAO PAULO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A fire in the largest department store in southeastern <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION> sent thousands of panicked shoppers and employees fleeing into rush-hour traffic and injured one fireman, officials said. The fire Friday started on the 7th floor of the 13-story <ORGANIZATION> Mappin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Store </ORGANIZATION>, in the heart of <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>'s business district, when mattresses caught fire, said store security chief <PERSON> Luiz </PERSON> <PERSON> Matias </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>. <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> said the fire spread to five floors before it was extinguished two hours later by about 180 firemen. One fireman suffered from smoke inhalation and was rushed to a nearby hospital, he said. He said 4,000 employees were inside the building when the fire broke out. Officials did not yet know why the mattresses caught fire, he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0108EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-28 0949</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0984</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Deborah </PERSON> <PERSON> Norville </PERSON>, the successor to <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Today'' co-host <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, says she's relieved the uproar over the show appears to be ending, but she's also offended it started in the first place A skit on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Saturday Night Live'' last week compared the situation at the show to `` All About Eve,'' the movie about a young actress scheming to oust an aging theater star, played by <PERSON> Bette </PERSON> <PERSON> Davis </PERSON>. `` It's sexism, pure and simple,'' said <PERSON> Norville </PERSON>, 31, who began in TV news 11 years ago while attending the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Georgia </ORGANIZATION> and anchored at NBC-owned WMAQ-TV in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> before joining <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> news </ORGANIZATION> in January 1987. `` As a woman and a reporter, I'm offended that the suggestion would be made, that two capable, competent women ca n't work in a collegial way on the same program. In 1989, that's nonsense.'' <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON>, 39, told `` Today'' viewers Friday she will leave the program at year's end, but her contract at <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> extends through 1992. <PERSON> Pauley </PERSON> has co-hosted the program for 13 years. She hugged <PERSON> Norville </PERSON> and gave her an alarm clock.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW ORLEANS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, the blue-collar husband on the hit sitcom `` Roseanne,'' has a real-life bride _ model <PERSON> Annabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Hartzog </PERSON>. The couple were wed Friday night at a church on fashionable <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>. They ducked reporters. A fleet of limousines, one of them containing TV series co-star <PERSON> Roseanne </PERSON> <PERSON> Barr </PERSON>, queued up for the ceremony at <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Presbyterian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Church </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>'s publicist refused to discuss the wedding, but Ms. <PERSON> Hartzog </PERSON>'s family rented an entire floor of the Hotel Inter-Continental and hotel staff confirmed a special meal was prepared for Friday night. <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON>, 37, and Miss <PERSON> Hartzog </PERSON>, 21, were introduced two years ago when <PERSON> Goodman </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> filming the movie `` Everybody's All-American. A native of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Louis </LOCATION>, he starred in `` The Big Easy'' and is now featured in `` Sea of Love,'' starring <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Pacino </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON>, who resigned recently as artistic director of the American Ballet Theatre, is beginning to feel gravity's tug on his 41-year-old legs. `` I worry a lot about the future,'' <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> Life </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> magazine </ORGANIZATION>'s November issue. `` When will I dance my last ballet? ... Maybe I already did. I still can dance parts much better than a lot of people, but I set a standard for myself. And once I stop reaching that standard, I ca n't _ I wo n't _ allow myself to do it.'' He remains fit. His orthopedic surgon, Dr. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>, said that <PERSON> Baryshnikov </PERSON> `` may be in the best shape of any 41-year-old person in the world.'' But the dancer thinks a lot about his mortality. `` I catch myself watching old people now and then, and thinking, ` Well you know, <PERSON> Misha </PERSON>, this is how it is going to be.' It really hits me that my life is ... almost over!''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiske </PERSON>, the 7-year-old girl whose liver transplant helped spur a change in the nation's organ transplant policy, will have a wish come true: She's going home for Halloween. The girl and her mother, <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON>, are scheduled to go to their home in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bridgewater </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, this afternoon after <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> showed progress from spleen removal surgery at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minnesota </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION>, hospital spokeswoman <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Stanik </PERSON> said Friday. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> was admitted to the hospital Oct. 5 after suffering three bouts of internal bleeding within a month. Doctors removed <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON>'s spleen, which doctors said was seven or eight times the normal size for a child her age In 1982, <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiske </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON>'s father, made an emotional and successful appeal for a donor. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON>'s case raised questions about the procedures for determining who should receive organ transplants. One result was the National Transplant Act, which created a national computer system that matches donors to recipients. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Fiske </PERSON> said his daughter had been asking whether she would be home in time for Halloween, her favorite holiday. <PERSON> Jamie </PERSON> plans to dress as the Queen of Hearts.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Zsa </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> says she's ready to start her three-day jail term for slapping a police officer. `` I would like to see the inside of a slammer, because if people are as innocent as I am, then I would like to meet those people,'' Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> said on the `` Donahue'' show on Friday. `` They're probably very nice, nicer than the <LOCATION> Beverly </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION> people in some of the restaurants. Miss <PERSON> Gabor </PERSON> was convicted Sept. 29 of misdemeanor charges of battery on a police officer, driving without a valid driver's license and having an open container of alcohol in her car She was sentenced Tuesday to serve the jail time by Dec. 29.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NASHVILLE, Tenn. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The country music group Highway 101 is denying reports of a breakup, saying concert dates for 1990 are being set, including a tour of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in June. Published reports two weeks ago said the four were breaking up because singer <PERSON> Paulette </PERSON> <PERSON> Carlson </PERSON> was planning a solo album. `` Her solo album is still in the talking stages and <PERSON> Paulette </PERSON>, along with the rest of the group, is heavily committed to Highway 101 and their priorities for the coming year,'' <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> McMullen </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for the group, said Friday. The group's concert tour of <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> next summer will be their first overseas. Other 1990 concert appearances are being arranged with country stars <PERSON> Hank </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Reba </PERSON> <PERSON> McEntire </PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION> Judds </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> McMullen </PERSON> said. Highway 101 has been voted group of the year for the past two years by the <ORGANIZATION> Country </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Music </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Their hit records include `` Cry, Cry, Cry'' and `` -LRB- Do You Love Me -RRB- Just Say Yes.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0032EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Japan-Reagan 1stLd-Writethru a0650 10-28 0739</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan-Reagan, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0650,0758</SECOND>
<HEAD>Japan-Reagan Love Affair Seen as Way to Smooth Bilateral Ties</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 3rd pvs, `Reagan in...' to UPDATE with
Reagan comment. Pick up 4th pvs, `Officials here...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELAINE KURTENBACH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Behind the fanfare surrounding the visit of former President <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON>, there is a clear message: <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> values harmonious ties with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and sees <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> as the catalyst. The <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION>' hosts, the huge <ORGANIZATION> Fujisankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communications </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> and the Japanese government, showered their guests with lavish praise during their nine-day, $ 7 million visit, which ends Saturday. Fujisankei reportedly paid <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> $ 2 million. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, in turn, glossed over serious trade disputes in his speeches with expressions of affection for the Japanese people. However, in a speech scheduled to be delivered at the end of his visit, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Americans did not think their products had fair access to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and that trade barriers must be lowered to avoid rising anger in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. `` As a friend, I tell you that Americans are not as patient as the Japanese,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said in his speech, according to the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. Officials here have welcomed the opportunity to emphasize positive aspects of sometimes rocky U.S.-Japanese ties. `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> symbolizes U.S.-Japan friendship,'' said <PERSON> Yukio </PERSON> <PERSON> Okamoto </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION>'s North American Division. As Emperor <PERSON> Akihito </PERSON> looked on, the government showed its appreciation for <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s role in promoting good ties with <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and in fighting trade protectionism in office by awarding him one of its highest honors, the Grand Cordon of the Supreme Order of the Chrysanthemum. The only other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president to receive the award was <PERSON> Dwight </PERSON> <PERSON> Eisenhower </PERSON>. Mrs. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has been honored during the visit for her anti-drug program and for her support for her husband. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, 78, is the only former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> president to receive such regal treatment, officials said, because unlike his predecessors who either left office in disgrace or after losing elections, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> served the two full terms and left office as a popular leader. `` There is nothing controversial about inviting <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> still carries high prestige among the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people,'' <PERSON> Okamoto </PERSON> said. The Reagans enjoy enormous prestige in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s dignified demeanor, coupled with the image of the two former movie stars standing hand-in-hand, captures romantic imaginations in a country that revels in the pomp of lavish wedding ceremonies and royalty. At concerts, banquets and other gatherings of <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s rich and powerful, the <ORGANIZATION> Reagans </ORGANIZATION> have received trumpet fanfares, standing ovations and warm smiles. `` You'll never know, <PERSON> Ron </PERSON>, how much we need you. Please come here with <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> to stay,'' audience and performers sang to the tune of `` You Are My Sunshine'' on Sunday at a concert to benefit the <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Presidential Library. A capacity crowd of 56,000 cheered as <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> tossed the ceremonial first pitch in a Japanese championship baseball game Tuesday. Rather than criticizing <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> for trade barriers, which <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> says contributed to <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s $ 52 billion trade surplus with the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> last year, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> spoke of a `` golden age for <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'' in his speeches. Trade issues, he said, were `` a few little itchy things here and there that we still need working on from both sides.'' Americans, as the world's largest foreign investors, should welcome Japanese investments in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said. He said <ORGANIZATION> Sony </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>'s takeover of <ORGANIZATION> Columbia </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> could help `` bring back decency and good taste to some of the pictures that are being made.'' A <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION> survey following the takeover indicated that Americans view <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s economic power as a greater threat than Soviet military might. While <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> has occasionally reminded listeners here that having retired, he no longer speaks for the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government, officials of the Japanese government have welcomed his words of praise, his optimism and his playing down of economic disputes. `` We need a communicator of <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s prestige and ability,'' said <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Taizo </PERSON> <PERSON> Watanabe </PERSON>. `` We respect him and we love him.'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s conservative, pro-business ideology and his opposition to protectionist trade policies have enormous appeal in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, particularly with the couple's host, the <ORGANIZATION> Fujisankei </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, which is known for the conservative, nationalist outlook of its chairman, <PERSON> Nobutaka </PERSON> <PERSON> Shikanai </PERSON>, and of its media outlets. A Fujisankei official said <PERSON> Shikanai </PERSON> wanted to `` bring <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> in and give him a chance to talk to the Japanese people,'' in hopes the visit would smooth over some problem areas.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0111EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SalvadorDeathSquads     10-28 0509</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Salvador Death Squads,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Administration Investigating Death Squad Allegations</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is trying to distance itself from allegations made by a Salvadoran army defector that top <LOCATION> Salvadoran </LOCATION> military leaders ordered death squad killings and <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> advisers ignored the activity. The White House said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Embassy in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> is looking into the charges made this week by <PERSON> Cesar </PERSON> <PERSON> Vielman </PERSON> <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, 28, who admits to taking part in eight death squad murders from April to July. He claims to have seen reports from <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Joint </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chiefs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Staff </ORGANIZATION> ordering 72 executions during the same period. <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> also said two <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> advisers assigned to the intelligence unit at the 1st Infantry Brigade in the capital of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> `` obviously had to know what was going on.'' `` We're concerned about it,'' <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said Friday. `` Ambassador -LRB- <PERSON> William </PERSON> -RRB- <PERSON> Walker </PERSON> is looking into it.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, deputy spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> departed from normal procedure of not commenting on investigations in progress. He strongly denied any <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> complicity and said a Salvadoran government probe into human rights abuses by its military `` has not revealed any evidence substantiating -LRB- <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>'s -RRB- statements.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Pentagon </ORGANIZATION> called the statements about <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military involvement `` patently absurd.'' The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> declined to comment, saying: `` As a matter of policy we do n't comment on intelligence matters.'' The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> armed forces have 55 military advisers assigned to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> has an unknown number of agents in the Central American nation. On Friday, <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> and his attorney, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Wyke </PERSON>, walked from office to office on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, volunteering to testify about the death squads. Among others, he spoke with staff members of Sen. <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cranston </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Calif </LOCATION>, an outspoken critic of death squad activity in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. The staff members declined to comment pending a report to the senator. The accusations could complicate upcoming congressional debate on new aid to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, which so far this decade has received more than $ 3 billion in <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic and military assistance. Lawmakers made earlier aid contingent on human rights improvements by the Salvadoran military, which has been blamed by church groups for murdering thousands of suspected leftists and leftist sympathizers. The Salvadoran military denies <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>'s claims and any other involvement in the death squads. `` My work was to execute these people,'' <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON> said, adding that he was part of a seven-man group that operated out of the Salvadoran army's 1st Infantry Brigade in the capital of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>, who is seeking asylum in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said he went public to stop the killing. The Salvadoran army says he is wanted for two murders in July in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. In <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, testimony obtained Friday said some of <PERSON> Joya </PERSON> <PERSON> Martinez </PERSON>'s comrades told a judge investigating the murders of two civilians that the army deserter was the most zealous of torturers who beat, drowned or suffocated prisoners. Marxist-led guerrillas have been fighting the U.S.-backed government in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> since 1979.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0051EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 2ndLd-Writethru a0782 10-28 0820</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0782,0847</SECOND>
<HEAD>Leftist Leader Slain Despite Increase in Security After Bombings</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 2 grafs after 5th pvs, `Earlier Friday...' to UPDATE
with bomb killing policeman; Pickup 6th, `Three other...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A man walked into a government building in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> Friday, whipped out a submachine gun and killed a leftist leader of the <LOCATION> Antioquia </LOCATION> state assembly before being slain by guards, police said. The victim, <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON>, was state leader of the leftist <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, whose ranks have been decimated the last four years by death squads believed to be operated by drug traffickers. The slaying came less than 24 hours after the <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> refused to support a proposal by drug traffickers to negotiate an end to the violence that has plagued <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> since mid-August. The leftist party said it could never condone amnesty for traffickers implicated in the murders of hundreds of its members, including its president, <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Pardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Leal </PERSON>, in 1987. Earlier Friday, hundreds of policemen and soldiers with automatic weapons had manned checkpoints in major cities after a bomb killed five policemen and injured 16 others in the cocaine center of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>. Also, a police officer died in a bomb explosion at a private airport at a police air base six miles north of <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, the national radio network <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> reported. Unidentified terrorists fled after placing the dynamite bomb in a bathroom of the Guaymaral airport terminal, <ORGANIZATION> Caracol </ORGANIZATION> said. Three other bombs exploded in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> late Thursday and early Friday, injuring one person, and two bombs were deactivated in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION>, the police said. <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON> was sitting at his desk in the Apuajara government building in the heart of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> when he was killed at 3:30 p.m., the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> police said in a telephone interview. <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, 150 miles north of this capital, is the hub of the most powerful Colombian cocaine cartel. The government building includes the offices of the <LOCATION> Antioquia </LOCATION> state governor, many of the state assembly members and the mayor of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, a city of 2 million residents. The gunman was killed in a hail of gunfire from guards who belong to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s secret police, a spokesman for the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> police told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>, speaking on condition of not being named. The assassin was about 20 years old, the police spokesman said. Three persons believed to be accompanying the gunman were arrested, he said. <PERSON> Santamaria </PERSON> was the 737th member of the <ORGANIZATION> Patriotic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> to be killed since the party was organized in 1975 as part of an attempt by the federal government to reach a truce with leftist guerrillas. The traffickers are believed to have set up the death squads after leftist guerrillas kidnapped the sister of three <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> cartel leaders and were paid $ 10 million for her return. A survey by a Colombian polling company showed that Colombians heavily favor the government starting talks with drug traffickers to end the violence. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> has rejected such talks. The bomb in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> exploded Thursday night as a police bus carried patrolmen to their posts in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>. The driver and four other policemen were killed as chunks of shrapnel tore through the bus, said the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> police chief, Col. <PERSON> Humberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Camero </PERSON>. Afterward, the most rigid security measures seen since the government declared war on drug traffickers Aug. 19 were put into force in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>'s five largest cities _ <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Cali </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Cartagena </LOCATION>. An AP reporter on his way to work Friday in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> was stopped at three checkpoints by soldiers and police searching cars for explosives and guns. Jeeps mounted with machine guns patrolled parts of the capital. Extra troops and policemen guarded police stations and army bases. The bomb in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, an estimated 65 pounds of dynamite, was set off by remote control about 7:30 p.m. as the police bus passed by, <PERSON> Camero </PERSON> said. With the driver fatally wounded, the bus careened out of control and smashed into a taxi, the colonel said. No one in the car was injured. No one claimed responsibility for the bombing, but suspicion fell on drug traffickers. `` The traffickers are the only criminals with the means and the desire to carry out an attack of this size,'' said a police lieutenant in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, speaking on condition he not be identified. Government security forces have assumed that the scores of bombs that have exploded in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> in the last two months are part of the drug traffickers' campaign to persuade the government to stop extraditing trafficking suspects to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. The government has extradited four Colombians, and nine more are awaiting extradition. In the last two months there have been 169 bombings, which have killed 21 people and injured 219. In <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, a poll by the private <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consulting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> indicated 61 percent of Colombians aged 18 to 60 want the government to negotiate a truce with drug traffickers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0122EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TradeReview     10-28 0513</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Trade Review,530</SECOND>
<HEAD>Treasury Skeptical About Deficit</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration says in a pessimistic assessment of trade prospects that the trade deficit may grow next year. The current account deficit, the broadest measure of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade measuring investment flows as well as payments for goods and services, narrowed sharply in 1988 to $ 126.6 billion, down from a record $ 143.7 billion in 1987. But progress has stalled this year, with the gap running at only a slightly better $ 122.8 billion annual rate from January through June. The administration, in a report prepared by the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> released Friday, warned that the current account deficit may start widening again unless the <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seven </ORGANIZATION> industrial nations _ the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> _ do a better job of coordinating economic policies, including currency exchange rates. `` It would appear further improvement in the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> current account position in 1990, if any is to occur at all, is likely at best to be very modest,'' <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> said in its semiannual `` Report to the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> on International Economic and Exchange Rate Policy.'' `` Furthermore, the possibility of deterioration in the current account next year can not be excluded.'' A key element in the fight to reduce the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> trade deficit has been Group of Seven efforts this year to check a rise in the value of the dollar. A strong dollar can hurt the trade deficit by making <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> goods more expensive overseas and foreign imports cheaper on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> report acknowledged that skepticism among currency traders is hindering the effort. <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Seven </ORGANIZATION> launched a new effort to contain the dollar in mid-September, which included dollar selling and interest rate increases in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. However, the report noted that it took the Oct. 13 stock sell-off in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to subdue the dollar. The report was prepared under a provision of the Trade Act of 1988 that requires the administration to look for currency manipulation by American competitors in world trade and to negotiate to halt such practices. Under the law, the administration has singled out <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>. Friday's report expressed approval of <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s effort to boost its currency and lower its trade surplus, but sharply criticized <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>. The two countries have for many years used part of the money earned through their trade surpluses to buy and sell currencies on the open market to keep their own currencies weak in relation to the dollar, making their products cheaper for Americans than they would otherwise be. However, the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> report noted that the Taiwanese dollar has appreciated 12 percent over the past year against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> dollar. It said <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> put in place a new exchange rate system in April and took other significant steps to curb its trade surplus. `` We are encouraged by -LRB- these -RRB- significant steps,'' it said. Despite an appreciation of the South Korean currency won in 1988, the report rebuked <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> for the 0.75 percent decline in the value of that currency since April.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0144EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-28 0302</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0312</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TRAVERSE CITY, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Twice a week, <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> greases his 12-pound pig with hand lotion. It's the price of keeping a Vietnamese potbellied pig named Ham from drying out. `` We have weird animals,'' admitted <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON>'s daughter, <PERSON> Kelli </PERSON>. Ham is n't exactly pretty. He shrieks. His back is swayed. His belly scrapes the floor. His black-bristled snout looks smashed in. But he is housebroken. <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> wo n't say how much he paid for <PERSON> Ham </PERSON> at an <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> auction last month. `` I just think all our friends would think we were stupid if I told you,'' he said. Male Oriental pigs go for anywhere from $ 750 to $ 1,500 each, said <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Beeman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Potbellied </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pig </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Registry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Lakeville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ind </LOCATION>. Ham does n't sit up or fetch or play any of the other usual domestic-pet games. But he does root. For family protection during dinner, the <ORGANIZATION> DeWitts </ORGANIZATION> must lock Ham up in his pet carrier or he will root at their ankles until they feed him. `` I guess that's why they call them pigs,'' <PERSON> Kelli </PERSON> <PERSON> DeWitt </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ALLIANCE, Neb. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A group called <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carhenge </ORGANIZATION> says it has raised enough money to pave an approach road to the junk car sculpture that spoofs <LOCATION> England </LOCATION>'s prehistoric Stonehenge. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Phaneuf </PERSON>, a city councilman and <ORGANIZATION> Friends </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carhenge </ORGANIZATION> board member said Friday the group had raised $ 2,400 for the road, one of several improvements needed to bring the off-beat artwork up to cty zoning standards. Work will begin early in November, <PERSON> Phaneuf </PERSON> said. Sculptor <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Reinders </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> built Carhenge two years ago during a family reunion. It consists of 16 cars buried trunk down with their front ends sticking about 11 feet in the air and six more cars sitting atop the upright cars.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-MontanaJerks Bjt   10-28 0584</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Montana Jerks, Bjt,0602</SECOND>
<HEAD>Historians Steal Sunset from `Jerks of the West'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM LACEKY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HELENA, Mont. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Calamity <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> was an `` uneducated, uncultured woman,'' and some frontier heroes were shameless bigots, according to an iconoclastic conference titled `` Speaking Ill of the Dead: Jerks in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> History.'' Nearly every event in the life of the true <ORGANIZATION> Calamity </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jane </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Martha </PERSON> <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Canary </PERSON> _ is clouded by contradictory evidence, <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Gallacher </PERSON> told the annual <ORGANIZATION> Montana </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> History </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> on Friday. Even her birth date and parents' names are suspect. Much of the legend of Calamity <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> as a swashbuckling frontier woman who rode with General <PERSON> Custer </PERSON> and captured <PERSON> Wild </PERSON> <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Hickock </PERSON>'s killer was built by Canary herself, who fed lurid stories to newspapers that did n't care if they were true, he said Friday's panel on jerks in the state's history also featured the `` Golden Hatchet Award,'' which went to <PERSON> Lyndel </PERSON> <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON>, whose research showed that many of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s founding fathers were racist and sexist. The panel drew a crowd of nearly 200, and may become an annual part of the conference. Conference organizer <PERSON> Jennifer </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffries </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> was pleased, but also distressed that the scholarly work of the meeting would go unnoticed. The same sort of thing happened in September, she said, when a society program was upstaged by the <LOCATION> Great </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Centennial </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cattle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Drive </LOCATION>. `` This is the cattle drive of the history conference,'' <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Gallacher </PERSON>, a historian with <ORGANIZATION> Historical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Missoula </LOCATION>, said much of the legend of Calamity Jane can be flatly disproved. Her claim to have been a Cavalry scout for <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Armstrong </PERSON> <PERSON> Custer </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> is easily debunked, he said, because <PERSON> Custer </PERSON> never served in <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>. And despite the many tales about her and <PERSON> Hickock </PERSON> _ including that she was married to him _ the only verifiable fact is that both were in Deadwood, <LOCATION> S.D. </LOCATION>, when <PERSON> Hickock </PERSON> was shot to death in 1876. `` It was pure fantasy that she captured <PERSON> Hickock </PERSON>'s killer, <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> McCall </PERSON>,'' <PERSON> Gallacher </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON>, a ranger at the Grant-Kohrs Ranch National Historic Site southwest of <PERSON> Helena </PERSON>, dug into official records that revealed the prejudices of delegates to <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s original constitutional convention in 1889. <PERSON> C.J </PERSON>. <PERSON> Hartman </PERSON>, one of <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>'s founding fathers, wanted a requirement that anyone allowed to vote should be able to read English. He saw that as a safeguard against `` the scum of foreign nations'' who were being admitted to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON> said. Delegate <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> would have allowed only some foreigners to vote, but not Italians. The official transcript, <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON> said, notes that delegates laughed and applauded as <PERSON> Warren </PERSON> read an article that he said voiced his feelings: `` It is somewhat uncomfortable to reflect that a citizen of intelligence, property, good moral character and a keen sense of responsibilities and dignities of his duties as an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> citizen may have his ballot offset by an Italian.'' <PERSON> Warren </PERSON>'s prejudice against Italians was not unusual, and similar racism was aimed at the Chinese, <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON> said. Women faced different barriers, she said: `` They were not considered people.'' When a proposal to let women vote was introduced at the 1889 convention, a Mr. <PERSON> Collins </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Cascade </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> requested that its supporters first introduce a motion `` that a woman is a human being or person in the language of the court.'' `` To their credit,'' <PERSON> Meikle </PERSON> said, `` the delegates devoted a tremendous portion of their time to the debate on woman's suffrage. It is not to their credit, however, that they did n't grant it.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0148EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CapitalGains     10-28 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Capital Gains,580</SECOND>
<HEAD>Democrats Say Bush's Drive for Tax Cut Imperiling Credit Rating</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The long-running squabble on the proposed capital gains tax cut that continues to stymie <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on several bills has led Democrats to accuse the administration of undermining the nation's credit rating abroad by doggedly pursuing the issue. `` There apparently is no limit to what they'll do'' to get a capital-gains cut, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>, told reporters Friday. White House Budget Director <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> responded to the criticism with a lecture about the need for statesmanship. `` We need people in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to get back to their better selves in all of this,'' <PERSON> Darman </PERSON> said. The issue is blocking <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> action on bills to provide economic assistance to <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION> and to raise the federal debt limit so the government can continue to borrow money. It also is slowing work by <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> negotiators on a compromise bill to reduce the budget deficit. The <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> stepped in Friday with a plan to ensure that Social Security checks will go out next week even if <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the president are unable to agree on a higher debt limit. The department announced it will borrow $ 17.6 billion on an emergency basis Monday. Friday's announcement was considerably less dramatic than <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION>'s disclosure 24 hours earlier that it was taking the unprecedented step of emergency borrowing. The earlier statement had been read as indicating $ 17 billion in new borrowing would be required Monday. In fact, <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> will be raising its credit needs by only $ 2 billion Monday. The remaining $ 15.6 billion will be raised in the usual Monday auctions of 3 - and 6-month securities The only difference is that buyers will have to pay for those securities Tuesday, rather than Thursday as usually would be the case. That money will be used to keep the government going after Tuesday night, when federal credit authority drops from $ 2.87 trillion to $ 2.8 trillion. The extra $ 17.6 billion from securities sales is expected to carry the government for another week, through Nov. 7. Sen. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> <PERSON> Bentsen </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Finance </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, described the emergency borrowing as an unprecedented gamble. `` I do n't see how such an action can fail to undermine confidence in our financial operations,'' he said. He said there was no danger <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> would fail to raise the debt ceiling or would do anything else to jeopardize government checks for 38.9 million Social Security recipients. The chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ways </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Means </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, Rep. <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Rostenkowski </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Ill </LOCATION>., asked <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Brady </PERSON> to explain his actions in writing by Monday on the unusual borrowing action `` I view this as a serious matter,'' he said in a letter to <LOCATION> Brady </LOCATION>. At <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s urging, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> voted last month to tax capital gains _ profits from the sale of stocks and other investments _ at a lower rate than applies to wages and other income. The House attached the cut to a bill designed chiefly to reduce the budget deficit. <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Republicans have developed, with <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s backing, a new plan for cutting capital-gains cuts. The chief sponsor, Sen. <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Packwood </PERSON>, R-Ore., says as many as 44 Republicans and 12 Democrats _ a majority of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> _ favor his bill, but he acknowledges he does not have the 60 votes that would be required to end a Democratic filibuster against it
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-SolomonIslandsQuake     10-28 0336</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Solomon Islands Quake,350</SECOND>
<HEAD>Earthquake Measuring 7.2 Hits Solomon Islands</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROSE ANN ROBERTSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A major earthquake registering 7.2 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale shook the <LOCATION> Solomon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> in the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> today, the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Geological Survey says. The preliminary reading of 7.2 is slightly stronger than the 7.1 magnitude earthquake that hit the <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> area Oct. 17. The earthquake struck the islands at 8:05 a.m. today, or 5:05 p.m. EDT Friday, said <ORGANIZATION> USGS </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Finley </PERSON>. It was the largest earthquake in the Solomons since a 7.4 quake on Nov. 5, 1978. There were no immediate reports of injury or damage. Major earthquakes in the Solomons usually do n't cause much damage or many casualties because the area is sparsely populated and not extensively developed. The Pacific Tsunami Warning Center in <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> said no Pacific-wide tsunami _ popularly called a tidal wave _ was generated by the quake, but some areas might see small changes in sea levels. Saturday's earthquake was the strongest in the world in five months, <PERSON> Finley </PERSON> said. An 8.3 quake hit the <LOCATION> Macquarie </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Islands </LOCATION> south of <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> on May 23. The survey's earthquake monitors in <LOCATION> Golden </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colo. </LOCATION>, said early seismograph readings placed the epicenter of Saturday's earthquake about 200 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Honiaria </LOCATION>, which is on <LOCATION> Guadacanal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> and is the capital of the Solomons. That places the earthquake just east of <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Cristobal </LOCATION>, the easternmost island in the Solomons chain and about 1,300 miles northeast of <LOCATION> Brisbane </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. The <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale is a measure of ground motion as recorded on seismographs. Every increase of one number means a tenfold increase in magnitude. Thus a reading of 7.5 reflects an earthquake 10 times stronger than one of 6.5. An earthquake of 3.5 on the <PERSON> Richter </PERSON> scale can cause slight damage in the local area, 4 moderate damage, 5 considerable damage, 6 severe damage. A 7 reading is a `` major'' earthquake, capable of widespread heavy damage; 8 is a `` great'' quake, capable of tremendous damage.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Bush-OrtegaPhoto     10-28 0235</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bush-Ortega Photo,220</SECOND>
<HEAD>White House Refuses to Release Bush-Ortega Photo</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SAN JOSE, Costa Rica (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The White House says there were some `` technical difficulties'' getting a photo of President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> meeting with Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>, but <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s aides made one available _ for a price. The price was $ 150, but it did n't show <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> shaking hands. The White House said the two leaders shook hands briefly Friday as they headed into the opening session of a two-day conference of heads of government from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>, but declined to release a photo of the event. `` If there were a picture, we would not release it,'' said White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON>. `` It's not our story.'' Besides, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> added with a grin, `` We had a lot of technical difficulties.'' Later, <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> had inspected his film and determined that he did n't have a picture of the handshake. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has spent hundreds of millions of dollars to support the Nicaraguan Contras in their efforts to topple <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s communist-backed government <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> has made pointed efforts during the meeting here to embrace <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON>'s opponent in the Feb. 25 presidential elections, <PERSON> Violeta </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamorro </PERSON>. `` Everybody knows we have a tense relationship so I do n't want to act like we're waltzing around there in great harmony -LRB- with <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> -RRB- because we're not,'' <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> said in advance of his trip.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891028-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-28-89 0155EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SFQuake-Highway     10-28 0461</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-SF Quake-Highway,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>Engineers Discovered Flaw on Other Double-Deckers Over Summer</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-SF Quake, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By HAL SPENCER</BYLINE>
