<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2325EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-US-Panama 2ndLd-Writethru a0715 10-11 0735</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-US-Panama, 2nd Ld-Writethru, a0715,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Panama Crackdown Concerns U.S.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS grafs 8-11: ``Wednesday night,'' with Bush comments</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> expressed concern Wednesday about a new crackdown by Panamanian authorities on civil liberties, while President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> tried to end the recriminations with key members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> that followed last week's failed coup attempt. Department spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said a `` package of war laws'' is being decreed by the the Panamanian government as part of an effort to `` eliminate the last vestiges of democracy and rule of law.'' As an example, she said civil servants could be fired for disloyalty under the new measures being planned and the right of habeas corpus is to be eliminated. `` These war laws purportedly will strip Panamanians of their remaining civil liberties and human rights,'' she said. Meanwhile, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> summoned Sen. <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Boren </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Okla </LOCATION>., the chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, and Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON> <PERSON> R-Maine </PERSON>, the vice chairman, following a week of congressional criticism about the way the administration handled the abortive uprising In a statement issued afterward, <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> indicated that the meeting was designed, in part, to avoid a repeat of the snafus that occurred during the abortive uprising last week in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. `` I feel that our discussion, which focused on intelligence matters, will be of great help to our country if we ever confront crises like the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> situation in the future,'' <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> said. Afterward, <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> flew to <LOCATION> Oklahoma </LOCATION> and was unavailable to elaborate on his statement. Wednesday night, <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> brushed off any hint of bad feeling over the congressional criticism he got on the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> matter, saying criticism was to be expected always, and said he had an amiable meeting with <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. `` There was never any bad blood,'' he told reporters at a state dinner in honor of Italian President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON>. `` I'm not angry,'' he said in response to reports that he heatedly chastised his staff and laid down the law that there was to be no more second-guessing. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> predicted that as the smoke clears people will agree with him. `` I have no second guesses at all, `` he said. Administration officials have said that poor communications and confused signals contributed to the failure of the coup attempt. Wednesday's meeting occurred three days after <PERSON> Boren </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> adviser <PERSON> Brent </PERSON> <PERSON> Scowcroft </PERSON> clashed over whether <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> restrictions inhibited the administration's ability to fulfill its goal of ousting <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> said the meeting with the senators concluded with everyone `` on the same wave length. I believe it was a very good, productive meeting.'' But on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> Majority Leader <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON> aimed new criticism at the administration for seeking to blame its inaction on congressionally imposed constraints. `` The efforts by some within the administration to shift responsibility for decisions ... to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Intelligence </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> are ill-founded, unfair and counterproductive,'' said <PERSON> Mitchell </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Maine </LOCATION>. It is legitimate, he said, for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to inquire into `` how the administration could have been so unprepared when what it had long been urging took place.'' At the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> denied assertions by some rebel leaders who have been given sanctuary in <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> that the insurgents were promised much more support by the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> than was actually given. She specifically denied that the rebels had asked for <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air support to prevent the airlifting of pro-Noriega reinforcements to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> after the coup attempt got under way. Ms. <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said that Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> was disturbed by unnamed <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> officials quoted in newspaper accounts as being critical of other agencies involved in the events last week in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. She said <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> told a staff meeting last Friday he wanted to see a stop to such criticism. Meanwhile, seven Latin American presidents, meeting in <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, discussed the proposed expulsion of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> from an eight-member hemispheric consultative group. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s membership was suspended in 1988 after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> arranged the dismissal of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, who had tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as military commander. <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> are among members pushing for <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s expulsion `` We can not permit a country like <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> that scoffs at and ridicules the democratic system to contnue with us,'' said <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Larco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cox </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>'s foreign minister. Diplomatic sources said <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and some others felt expulsion would amount to interference in the internal affairs of another country.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2327EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-UNESCO-PLO     10-11 0353</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-UNESCO-PLO,0365</SECOND>
<HEAD>Board Recommends Delaying PLO Request Until 1991</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PARIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The executive board of <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> recommended Wednesday that the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>'s request for admission to the agency be put off until 1991. The recommendation goes to <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>'s highest decision-making body, the General Conference, which begins a monthlong meeting Tuesday. If the conference takes the board's advice, as appears likely, <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> will be following the footsteps of the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION>, which decided in May to put off considering whether to admit <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s parliament-in-exile from its headquarters in <LOCATION> Tunis </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Tunisia </LOCATION>, last Nov. 15 declared <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> as an independent state without giving specific boundaries. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which withdrew from <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> nearly five years ago, had said it would not consider returning if Palestine were admitted as a member state. At the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Organization </ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION> Geneva </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> had threatened to withhold paying its contribution to the budget, which amounts to 25 percent. The resolution approved by the <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> board without debate or a vote called for close involvement of the Palestinians in activities of the 159-nation <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Educational </ORGANIZATION>, Scientific and Cultural Organization. The Palestinian observer at <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Massalha </PERSON>, said the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> decided to accept the recommendation for postponement in order to spare the agency any political confrontation over the issue. <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> Director-General <PERSON> Federico </PERSON> <PERSON> Mayor </PERSON> has made a determined effort to get the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> to rejoin the world body. The Americans and British left because they said the organization had become too political, spent too much money and was poorly managed. <LOCATION> Singapore </LOCATION> pulled out saying it could spend its dues better elsewhere. The resolution calls for the `` closest possible participation of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION> in the action of <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION>, in particular through its programs and full benefits of the scholarship programs.'' It says the Palestine observer mission now can make requests to participate in <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> programs directly instead of going through the <ORGANIZATION> Arab </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> League </ORGANIZATION> as it has in the past. Mayor has drawn up an 82-page study for the board outlining ways the Palestinians can become involved more closely in <ORGANIZATION> UNESCO </ORGANIZATION> activities.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2337EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Panama-Miami 1stLd-Writethru a0781 10-11 0672</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama-Miami, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0781,0689</SECOND>
<HEAD>Rebel: Coup Participants Never Intended To Kill Noriega</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 3rd, ``We're working ..., to UPDATE with
comment from coup leader's widow; picks up 4th graf pvs: `Franken said
...; INSERTS 2 grafs after 9th, `When asked ..., to UPDATE with her confirmation
that officers did not intend to kill Noriega.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Panamanian rebels involved in last week's failed coup attempt never intended to kill Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> when they held him captive briefly, said one of the coup leaders seeking political asylum here. Among 42 Panamanians the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> flew to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> on Saturday was Capt. <PERSON> Javier </PERSON> <PERSON> Licona </PERSON>, believed to be the highest-ranking coup participant to escape capture, said a <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration official speaking on condition of anonymity. `` We're working with the immigration service so that they can remain here, _ those that want to file for asylum,'' <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Franken </PERSON>, a refugee coordinator for the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION>, said Wednesday. `` I expect that will take about a week.'' <PERSON> Adela </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>, widow of the major who led the unsuccessful coup, also was among those airlifted to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. She told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> the coup was betrayed by another officer who switched sides at the last minute. She said her husband, Maj. <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, had worked with Maj. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON>, commander of the elite Battalion 2000, in planning the coup. Battalion 2000, instead of fighting <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, was airlifted 55 miles from the fighting and led <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s troops to crush the coup. `` Everything was ready. But <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON> was playing a winner's game and he failed to come through because of his cowardice,'' she told the Times in a <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> interview. <PERSON> Franken </PERSON> said the Panamanians flown into <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> have told him they want to remain in seclusion for now. But administration officials are said to be attempting to get more information from the leaders secluded here. One rebel leader said that during the daylong coup attempt on Oct. 3, the rebels held <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> hostage for several hours and could have killed him at any time, The <ORGANIZATION> Miami </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Herald </ORGANIZATION> reported Wednesday. The rebel, who spoke on condition that neither his name nor the location where he was interviewed be disclosed, said his troops knew him as `` Commandante Trueno'' _ Commander Thunder. He said junior officers who took part in the coup attempt turned <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> over to their superiors, but that leaders of the rebellion had no desire to kill the general. `` There was no intention at any time to kill the man,'' Commander Thunder said. When asked why, he said it may have been because a soldier would find it hard to execute his top commander. `` It may have been their military discipline,'' he said. Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> told the Times that three captains who were supposed to persuade <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> to surrender `` did n't do it because they were cowards.'' `` My husband could have killed <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, but he would not do that. He thought the commander's fate should be decided by the people,'' not the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, she told the paper. In their public proclamations, the rebels said they had staged the coup to `` retire'' <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> and five senior colonels of the Panamanian <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION>. With Commander Thunder were about a dozen other rebel troops seeking political asylum. He said they would make no statement as they waited to hear what their fate would be. `` We do n't want to say anything at this time,'' Commander Thunder said. `` We are awaiting orders.'' Family members of slain coup leader Maj. <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> also were in the group, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanders </PERSON> said. He would not confirm whether the group included <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>'s widow, <PERSON> Adela </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON>, a key intermediary between <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials and the coup plotters. Earlier, one of the group said the soldiers feared for their relatives at home. `` <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> is a beast,'' said the man, who also asked not to be identified. `` He wo n't stop at anything. He's going to take reprisals against our wives, our children and our parents back in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2338EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Panama 1stLd-Writethru a0744 10-11 0776</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Panama, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0744,0799</SECOND>
<HEAD>Noriega Blasts U.S. Government As Assembly Installed</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 9 grafs to UPDATE with report that coup failed because
general changed his mind. Picks up 4th graf pvs, `She represents ...'</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ELOY O. AGUILAR</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PANAMA CITY, Panama (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> accused the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> on Wednesday of trying to keep its forces in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> to maintain control over <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The widow of the Panamanian major who led an unsuccessful coup against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> says it failed because her husband was betrayed by another major who switched sides at the last minute, according to a published report. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who blamed last week's coup attempt on the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, said <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> must be prepared `` because they can not catch us by surprise again, and even if the commander -LRB- <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> -RRB- falls, the people will not fall.'' Countering what <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials have been saying, <PERSON> Adela </PERSON> <PERSON> Bonilla </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> was quoted by the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> in Thursday's editions as saying the coup was `` very well organized and coldly calculated.'' She said her husband, Maj. <PERSON> Moises </PERSON> <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> <PERSON> Vega </PERSON>, worked with Maj. <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON>, commander of the elite Battalion 2000, in planning the coup. Instead of being used to oust <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, however, Battalion 2000 was airlifted 55 miles from the scene of the fighting and led <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s troops in crushing the coup. `` Everything was ready. But <PERSON> Olechea </PERSON> was playing a winner's game and he failed to come through because of his cowardice,'' she told the Times in an interview in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>. Mrs. <PERSON> Giroldi </PERSON> was not at military headquarters during the coup attempt on Oct. 3 and her information came from officers who took part in the coup and, as she did, fled shortly afterwards to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, the Times said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> spoke in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> assembly </ORGANIZATION>. Before he addressed the crowd, he introduced <PERSON> Sarah </PERSON> <PERSON> York </PERSON>, 11, a <LOCATION> Negaunee </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mich. </LOCATION>, girl on her second trip to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> at <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s invitation `` She represents the truth of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people, purity and not hatred,'' he said as he brought his young pen pal to the podium to wave to the crowd. The assembly is comprised of precinct representatives appointed by the government to act as a legislative body. It replaces the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION>, which was abolished when the provisional government of President <PERSON> Francisco </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> took office on Sept. 1. The government annulled May 7 elections, which foreign observers say the opposition won by a 3-1 margin. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, who commands the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Forces </ORGANIZATION> and controls the government, said <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s intention was not just to eliminate him, `` but to install in power the enemies of the people.'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> spoke after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>. He called for reconciliation and said his government was open to dialogue. On Tuesday, the government announced tough new measures aimed at suppressing dissent, firing public employees considered to be disloyal, freezing wages and suspending year-end bonuses. Members of the assembly demanded dismissal of `` seditious'' elements still working for the government. But <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, who was frequently rumored to have opposed the laws during Cabinet meetings, said the measures should not be used for personal revenge. `` The preservation of the country as our home is and must be the paramount goal of our government,'' <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> said. Opposition leaders and members of professional associations expressed concern over impact of the new laws, which the government said were meant to `` protect the economy and national security in the face of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. aggression.'' `` It is the first step in the creation of a police state,'' <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Ricardo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> <PERSON> Calderon </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Tutwiler </PERSON> said in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Wednesday that <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> was decreeing a `` package of war laws'' as part of an effort to `` eliminate the last vestiges of democracy and rule of law.'' <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> blames <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> for its troubles. The <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> government imposed economic sanctions on <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> after <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was indicted in February 1988 on <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> drug charges. He denies the charges. Wednesday was the 21st anniversary of the military coup that brought to power the late <PERSON> Omar </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON>, the man <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> considers his political and ideological mentor. The coup deposed President <PERSON> Arnulfo </PERSON> <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> 11 days after <PERSON> Arias </PERSON> took office. <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> banned political parties, exiled scores of politicians and ruled with the help of a <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> instead of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Torrijos </PERSON> signed treaties with President <PERSON> Carter </PERSON> that committed the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to a new relationship with <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gave up its territory in the Canal Zone in 1979. Under the treaties, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> must close its <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> bases at the end of the century, when <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> will take over the Canal's administration.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2340EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a PM-Names CORRECTIVE   10-11 0117</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names, CORRECTIVE,0116</SECOND>
<UNK>Eds: Members who used the 2nd item in a0426 PM-Names of Monday, Oct.
9, with a Kansas City, Mo., dateline, are asked to use the following story.</UNK>
<DATELINE>KANSAS CITY, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> reported erroneously on Oct. 9 that <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> `` stood up'' <ORGANIZATION> Paramount </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pictures </ORGANIZATION> and dozens of television reporters by failing to appear for interviews on Oct. 7 regarding his new movie `` Fat Man and Little Boy.'' Paramont notes that the television reporters had been informed in advance that <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> would be unable to give interviews that day because he was working on another film. <PERSON> Newman </PERSON> met the next day, as planned, for interviews with newspaper, magazine and radio reporters.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-LatinSummit 4thLd-Writethru a0774 10-11 0843</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Latin Summit, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0774,0862</SECOND>
<HEAD>Venezuelan President Urges U.S. Action Against Cocaine Demand</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 11th graf `The three-day ...' with 1 graf to UPDATE with
officials now saying conference to end day earlier. Picks up 12th graf,
`An army ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto ICA5</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MONTE HAYES</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ICA, Peru (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Police action against cocaine suppliers is futile unless the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> reduce the demand that drives the illicit trade, President <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Andres </PERSON> <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> said Wednesday. Perez spoke on opening day of a summit of seven Latin American presidents in this desert city that also is to consider expelling <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> as the eighth member of the Group of Eight regional organization. <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s membership was suspended in 1988 after Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Antonio </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> arranged the dismissal of President <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Delvalle </PERSON>, who had tried to fire <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> as military commander. The Venezuelan leader called <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s military rule a `` masked dictatorship.'' President <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> used his opening remarks to `` express publicly the Peruvian people's and the Peruvian government's repudiation and condemnation of the military dictatorship.'' <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION> were expected to push for expulsion of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, but diplomatic sources said <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and some other members felt that would amount to meddling with the internal affairs of another country. Among items on the summit's agenda besides drug trafficking are <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s conflicts, foreign debt and environmental damage to the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle. In his remarks on the drug trade, <PERSON> Peres </PERSON> said: `` The more demand grows in the north, the more production will grow in the south. Police actions will be useless unless demand is reduced.'' Other opening statements also expressed support for <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION>, which argue that President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s emphasis on attacking the cocaine traffic at the source is not enough. The summit began the day after Presidents <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON>, <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Jaime </PERSON> <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> <PERSON> Zamora </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> invited <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> to attend a drug summit in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> within 90 days. <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> accepted immediately. <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> did not remain for the Group of Eight meeting because <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> is not a member. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> were joined by <PERSON> Perez </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Venezuela </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Salinas </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Gortari </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Carlos </PERSON> <PERSON> Menem </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Argentina </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Julio </PERSON> <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> at the third summit since the regional organization was formed in 1987. The meeting is being conducted in closed session at the Hotel Las Dunas on the outskirts of <ORGANIZATION> Ica </ORGANIZATION>, a city of 350,000 people 185 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>. Officials said earlier that the meeting would last three days, but late Wednesday shortened the meeting to two days without giving a reason. An army battlion of 300 soldiers guarded the hotel and 3,000 plaincothes policemen circulated in the city in case of attacks by <ORGANIZATION> Shining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Path </ORGANIZATION>, a Maoist guerrilla group that began fighting Peruvian governments in 1980. The insurgency has cost 15,000 lives by government count. A car bomb police blamed on Shining Path exploded Tuesday night outside an auto parts store in residential <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, wounding a guard and blowing out the windows of the shop and nearby buildings. Police said rebels also shot and killed a woman candidate for deputy mayor of a <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION> district Tuesday night, firing three bullets into her head as she stood behind the counter of her pharmacy. Official reports said 26 other people were killed in seven incidents Tuesday night and Wednesday, including nine policemen, two mayors and two rural mayoral candidates. Diplomatic sources at the summit said the presidents were expected to give full support to <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> in their fight against traffickers. <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> began a crackdown on cocaine gangs Aug. 19. On Tuesday, <PERSON> Barco </PERSON>, <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> and <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> promised `` all-out war'' on cocaine in their countries, which produce 90 percent of the world's supply Their communique stressed that stopping the cocaine trade must be accompanied by vigorous efforts against production and consumption. That reflects reservations in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> about <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s emphasis on police and military actions to stop trafficking in the Andean nations President <PERSON> Sanguinetti </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Uruguay </LOCATION> told reporters before the summit began Wednesday: `` The problem is not only in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>. It is also in the streets of <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>.'' His reference was to the <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> drug cartel, which has been at war with the <LOCATION> Colombian </LOCATION> government since the crackdown began in August. The three-nation communique did not elaborate on differences of approach, but <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Bolivia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> have requested more <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> economic aid to provide alternative sources of income for hundreds of thousands of peasants who live by growing coca, the raw material for cocaine. `` It's not a problem of donating some helicopters, sometimes very old helicopters, or donating rifles or bullets,'' <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> said recently. `` It would be enough to offer a good price and a guaranted market for the products that could substitute for coca.'' He, Barco and <PERSON> Paz </PERSON> also said <LOCATION> European </LOCATION> leaders should attend the drug summit. <PERSON> Garcia </PERSON> has said that, if the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> is successful in slowing the flow of cocaine across its borders, traffickers will shift their focus to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-KnightsofMalta     10-11 0723</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Knights of Malta,0739</SECOND>
<HEAD>Knights of Malta Returning to Island They Once Ruled</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report. The knights return Oct. 17-22.</HEAD>
<HEAD>By TERRY LEONARD</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>VALLETTA, Malta (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Nearly two centuries after <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON>'s forces routed them, the Knights of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> are returning to the island they got from an emperor in exchange for a falcon and ruled for 268 years The `` monks in armor'' will be here Oct. 17-22 for a gathering their leadership hopes will help bolster <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>'s economy. Officially named the Sovereign Military Order of the <ORGANIZATION> Hospital </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> John </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jerusalem </ORGANIZATION>, of <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> and of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, the knights are the oldest order of chivalry and the fourth oldest religious order in the <ORGANIZATION> Roman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION>. They ruled this rocky and almost barren <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> archipelago from 1530, when Emperor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> V </PERSON> gave it to them for the price of one trained falcon a year, until 1798 when <PERSON> Napoleon </PERSON> sent them packing without the treasures they acquired during centuries of plundering the Ottoman Empire. Fra <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Bertie </PERSON>, the 78th grand master of the 900-year-old order, has summoned the knights back and has urged them to help <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> improve its economy. For centuries, membership in the knights required proof of generations of nobility. Although some ranks today are open to those without noble ancestry, the rolls are still crowded with the wealthy and influential. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> financier <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Grace </PERSON> is a member, as are former <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Secretary of State <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> M. </PERSON> <PERSON> Haig </PERSON>, Premier <PERSON> Giulio </PERSON> <PERSON> Andreotti </PERSON> and President <PERSON> Francesco </PERSON> <PERSON> Cossiga </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Giovanni </PERSON> <PERSON> Agnelli </PERSON>, chairman of the Italian automobile company <ORGANIZATION> Fiat </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Bennett </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> attorney and owner of the <ORGANIZATION> Baltimore </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Orioles </ORGANIZATION> major league baseball team who died in August 1988, also was a member. Such men are one reason the order's Maltese association asked <PERSON> Bertie </PERSON> to call the knights back to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, which in 25 years of independence from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> has found the economic road as rocky as its coastline. <PERSON> Bertie </PERSON>, a long-time former resident of <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>, encourged knights worldwide to attend the first world gathering of the order and openly solicited their help. `` I also urge those of you who are directly or indirectly interested in facilitating contacts with the development of the economic life of the island to do so,'' <PERSON> Bertie </PERSON> told the knights earlier this year in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON>, president of the Maltese association of the ancient order now based in <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION>, said about 500 of the 10,000 members are expected to travel to <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. `` We want knights from around the world to exchange ideas about our hospital work and to rediscover <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON>. `` During the 268 years the knights were here, they introduced new thinking in architecture, law, medicine and merchant shipping.'' The knights made <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> a thriving center of Christianity and trade. <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Giorgio </PERSON> said the knights also gave <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> the legal codes that are the basis for much of its modern law. In 1575, they built and then operated what then was one of the largest hospitals in <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. They gave <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION> an architectural heritage of massive fortifications and magnificent palaces and churches. The knights today operate about 200 hospitals and first aid centers in 90 countries, especially in the Third World and war zones. The order was founded in the late 11th century with the opening of a hospice for pilgrims in <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION>. Its centuries-old dedication to hospital work began when it treated the sick and wounded after the army of the First Crusade captured <LOCATION> Jerusalem </LOCATION> in 1099. It first took up arms in the 12th century to defend the pilgrim routes to the Holy Land. In the late 13th century, after the Holy Land fell to the Moslems, the knights moved first to <LOCATION> Cyrpus </LOCATION> and then to <LOCATION> Rhodes </LOCATION> where they built a navy to fight the Moslem Ottoman Empire. <PERSON> Sultan </PERSON> <PERSON> Suleiman </PERSON> the Magnificent defeated the knights and forced them to leave <PERSON> Rhodes </PERSON> on Jan. 1, 1523, although with huge losses to his troops. Seven years later, the knights resumed the fight from <LOCATION> Malta </LOCATION>. Once again <PERSON> Suleiman </PERSON> attacked. This time 600 knights, 1,230 mostly Spanish soldiers and about 6,000 Maltese militia defeated an Ottoman army of 40,000. That victory in 1565 marked the beginning of the end for Ottoman seapower and earned the knights the gratitude of a threatened <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2344EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Vietnam-Chinese     10-11 0927</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Vietnam-Chinese,0955</SECOND>
<HEAD>Economic Policies Allow Chinese Resurgence in Vietnam</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOHN POMFRET</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HO CHI MINH CITY, Vietnam (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 On March 24, 1978, students and soldiers burst into <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thi </PERSON>'s factories, ordered them closed and confiscated all the goods in the name of the socialist transformation of south <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Now, more than 10 years after he was left a pauper, <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> heads a private savings and loan association and runs a chicken farm, a food processing plant and six foodstores. <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> is an ethnic Chinese. His own resurgence parallels the change in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s policies toward its Chinese minority, the most dynamic ethnic group in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Eleven years ago, uniformed men broke down doors and dragged away shopkeepers throughout the Chinese quarter, arresting thousands as the Communist government of the north sought to bring revolution to the recently conquered south. The brutal policy left the Chinese community in ruins and proved a major factor in the deterioration of relations between <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. It also led to an exodus of tens of thousands of Chinese. Vietnamese government officials got rich on the deal, demanding bribes for safe passage to port towns in the south. To this day, many of the escapees still languish in refugee camps around <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>. Now the government, faced with growing poverty and falling production, has turned to the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> community for help in building <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. Chinese have been coming to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> since the 3rd century B.C. In the two milleniums since then, <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> ruled <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> for 900 years. In other times, defeated Chinese armies, criminals, starving peasants and persecuted monks all made their way to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. About 400,000 ethnic Chinese live in <LOCATION> Ho </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Minh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, mostly in the <LOCATION> Cholon </LOCATION> suburb. Estimates of Chinese nationwide vary from 600,000 to 1 million. `` Our recent treatment of the Chinese has not always been completely perfect,'' acknowledges <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON> <PERSON> Doan </PERSON>, chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ho </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Chi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Minh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION>'s 5th District, which includes <LOCATION> Cholon </LOCATION>. `` But now we are even accepting that their businesses will undertake a certain level of exploitation, as long as it benefits production.'' These are radical words for a dedicated Communist. <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON>, himself an ethnic Chinese, has been a party member for 43 of his 61 years. During the Vietnam War he did underground work against the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and South Vietnamese governments. In some cases, property confiscated from <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> has been returned. Starting early this year, businessmen were allowed to open private banks. An ad hoc stock market has formed among Chinese traders. Government officials turn a blind eye to the black market, and privately owned factories have been encouraged. Even big businessmen like <PERSON> Ly </PERSON> <PERSON> Sen </PERSON>, an ethnic Chinese who was named one of <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s three `` super-capitalists'' in a show trial in 1975, have been released from jail and encouraged to add their expertise to <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s development. `` The Commies are our slaves now,'' said one <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> merchant who learned his colloquial English from American GI customers during the war. `` They need us more than we need them.'' But the change has not completely satisfied the Chinese. Chairman <PERSON> Nghi </PERSON> estimates that production for District 5 has yet to reach half of what is was during the Vietnam War years, when little factories, bars and restaurants served an international clientele of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> soldiers and Southeast Asian businessmen. Chinese community leaders estimate that tens of thousands still want to leave <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>. And many Chinese businessmen say they are worried the government's policies might turn radical again. `` I'm not doing anything big right now,'' said the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> merchant. `` I do n't know when Big Boss is going to crack down. Most of us are just watching.'' But others, like <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuan </PERSON> <PERSON> Thi </PERSON>, are going full steam ahead. Several years ago as reform policies began, <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> scraped together some capital from friends and started a food processing factory. Then he rented out storefronts to sell his goods. Impressed with his success, the government contacted <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> and offered him land to start a chicken farm. Tran jumped at the chance for a joint venture with the state,. `` I've got a lot of guts,'' he said. `` But I also figured the more I work with the government, the less chance there is of them taking things away from me.'' Six months ago, <PERSON> Tran </PERSON> started a private bank, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> City </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. Together with <PERSON> Ly </PERSON>, who was a top banker during the war, he amassed hundreds of thousands of dollars worth of investments. Loans are made at 8 percent to 10 percent a month. And deposits pay 7 percent a month, compounded quarterly, or 125 percent a year, <PERSON> Ly </PERSON> says. The rates, which battle <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>'s annual inflation of at least 30 percent, are higher than the government's monthly rate of 5 percent for deposits and 8 percent for loans. `` They trust us, they trust me,'' <PERSON> Ly </PERSON> said, explaining his success. `` I've been a banker all my life so they have confidence.'' Another reason is that customers can withdraw their money freely. State banks still demand a list of reasons, and often substantial bribes, to approve withdrawals. <PERSON> Ly </PERSON>'s son and daughter both escaped to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> as boat people. His wife also left several months before he was let out of jail in 1987 after 12 years. Despite the changes in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION>, he said he still hopes to leave. `` I'm an old man and miss my family,'' says the 64-year-old. `` I was once part of this country's future but now I'm part of its past.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-ExiledSouthAfrican     10-11 0719</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Exiled South African,0741</SECOND>
<HEAD>Adjustment Takes Time After 7,904 Days in a South African Prison</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-South Africa</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Thursday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BEN DOBBIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Denis </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> no longer feels uneasy in a crowd. But whenever he sits down to write his memoirs, the recollections of 21 years in a South African prison still overwhelm him. He served the longest prison term imposed on a white militant, and now is in his fifth year in British exile. But he says the ideals that got him, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and six other black nationalists locked up for plotting to overthrow the white-led minority government made his life sentence bearable. `` I did n't count every day I was in prison, but I calculated it,'' <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, now 56, says in an interview. `` I was there 7,904 days. I do n't regret one day, it was worth it. `` I certainly do not repudiate my past actions. I do not repudiate the armed struggle _ I think it's essential.'' At 29, <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> was an engineer turned bomb-maker for the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the banned black nationalist movement. He was arrested at an <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> hideout in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> and given three life sentences in June 1964 for `` campaigning to overthrow the government by violent revolution.'' Deported in 1985 after undertaking not to participate in political violence, he now runs the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>'s mail order business in north <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> selling mostly T-shirts and posters. He lectures occasionally in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> and abroad. On Tuesday, President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> said he will free five of <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s co-defendants, including <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> political strategist <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, but not <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. The other co-defendant, <PERSON> Govan </PERSON> <PERSON> Mbeki </PERSON>, was freed in 1987. <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> calls their release `` a public relations exercise to show <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> is amenable to change.'' It took <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> two years to adjust to freedom in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. Finally, one morning, `` suddenly I felt at ease; The crowds did n't bother me. `` There's a lot of softness and gentleness outside that is enriching,'' he says. `` It sounds corny but it's very, very true. I find life incredibly exciting, fulfilling and worthwhile.'' His wife <PERSON> Esme </PERSON>, 60, says: `` Prison made him tender.'' But the memories of prison run deep. `` I find that when I do sit down to write about it, I simply do n't sleep,'' he said. `` A recollection of one incident brings back a whole chain of incidents and events, and I find that this just overwhelms me.'' The former engineer said he gradually was driven to violence by revulsion for apartheid, the race-separation system under which 5 million whites disenfranchise 28 million blacks. He's chubbier now and losing his hair, and his quirky humor masks a deep hurt at having missed seeing his two children grow up. His son, <PERSON> David </PERSON>, was 8 and his daughter, <PERSON> Hilary </PERSON>, 5 when he left <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION> in May 1963, intent on fleeing abroad. A bomb had exploded in his garden, obscenities were painted on his car and police were clamping down on dissidents. He stayed on briefly to organize arms production for the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>. `` Had I not been arrested, I would have gone on to start production of land mines and grenades and timing devices and so on,'' he says. `` Bomb-maker is a pejorative term. My people said that what I was doing was just and justified.'' <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> served most of his sentence in the whites-only <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION> Prison. `` In a country where prison is the norm in the lives of most black South Africans, it was perhaps a way of identifying,'' he said. `` That we could survive and come out relatively whole people is really a victory over people who try to smash us.'' After a reunion with his family, who had moved to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> during his trial, he said his son, then 29 and married with children, `` needed me to tell him I had n't left him.'' `` I told him I did n't see how I could ever make my family above all other families,'' he says. `` Kids suffer and starve not because their parents are politically active, but that's the nature of apartheid, and I felt I had to do something.'' His eyes reddened with emotion behind horn-rimmed glasses. `` I've had some suffering. So! Lots of people have died. People are getting hanged, people are getting shot. I'm alive. Life's great.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2347EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lottery     10-11 0049</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lottery,0051</SECOND>
<BYLINE>By The Associated Press</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the winning weekly state lottery numbers picked Wednesday:
</TEXT>
<NOTE>MASSACHUSETTS</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday Megabucks: 06; 14; 19; 26; 33; 34.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>NEW YORK</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Wednesday 54 Lotto Game: 14; 24; 36; 37; 47; 49. Supplementary 07.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>RHODE ISLAND</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 Grand Lot Game: 6-1-4; 7-1-1-0; 3-5-2-8-1; 1-1-9-2-3-2.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-GoldMudslide     10-11 0294</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gold Mudslide,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Mudslide in Amazon Gold Pit Kills Eight</HEAD>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight miners were killed and five injured when a hill of loose earth gave way at a gold mining pit in the northeastern <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> state of <LOCATION> Para </LOCATION>, officials said. The disaster occurred around Wednesday morning in the remote mountain range of <LOCATION> Serra </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pelada </LOCATION>, some 1,900 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, when a 50-foot wall of loose earth collapsed and swallowed the men alive, said <PERSON> Manoel </PERSON> <PERSON> Candido </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Serra </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Peleda </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mining </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooperative </ORGANIZATION>. `` A wall of earth completely smothered them,'' <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> said by telephone. <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> said the victims were among a group of some 40 men working at the time of the mudslide in the mine, known as the `` Deep Hole.'' Some 25,000 miners work in the region, he said. `` The earth is very loose in the region. Those miners were warned not to mine in the area but there are not enough police to keep them away,'' <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> said. He said a similar accident occurred near the mine site two weeks ago, killing three miners. Rescue teams of civil and state police arrived at the site hours after the disaster and pulled a number of men from the earth, he said. `` We've saved some but there could be others still buried,'' <PERSON> Candido </PERSON> said. He said the rescue workers would search for more victims through the night. Such accidents have grown more common since an estimated 1 million prospectors invaded <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s vast <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle after rich deposits of alluvial gold were discovered there in 1979. Since then, thousands of people, mostly unskilled peasants, have been lured to mine sites where they dig with their hands and carry bags of mud on their backs and up precarious rope ladders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2355EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--LATimes     10-11 0135</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--LA Times,0136</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Look for Los Angeles Times</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times made major changes in its format for the first time in a decade, trying to make the newspaper easier and faster to read. Among other things, the Timeson Wednesday added page-long indexes on the left front of every section except the main one; revised its main briefs page to include more photos, a more open look, and page numbers indicating where readers can turn for complete stories; and added `` quick-scan subheads,'' sentences set in big type beneath headlines, on many stories to give readers a quick preview of the articles. The Times, the nation's fourth-biggest newspaper, said it wanted to be better organized, more accessible and faster to read without sacrificing its strengths in reporting and writing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2351EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-GunneryAccident     10-11 0214</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Gunnery Accident,0219</SECOND>
<HEAD>One Dead, One Hurt In Gunnery Accident Aboard USS Iwo Jima</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NORFOLK, Va. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An officer aboard the amphibious assault ship USS Iwo Jima was killed and another wounded Wednesday by shrapnel or projectiles fired by another ship during a gunnery exercise in the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> said. The accident occurred about 5:30 p.m. EDT while the Iwo Jima took part in an exercise with the amphibious cargo ship USS El Paso about 80 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, said Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>. The two officers were struck by objects fired from the <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paso </LOCATION>'s close-in weapons system, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> said The Iwo Jima sustained no apparent damage and no one else was injured, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> said. The injured officer, whose identity was withheld until relatives could be fied, was treated on the Iwo Jima then flown to <LOCATION> Portsmouth </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Naval </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION>, where he was in stable condition Wednesday night, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> said. The dead officer's identity was not released until his family could be reached. <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> said further details were not immediately available on the accident, which is being investigated by the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>. Both vessels had left <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> earlier in the day to conduct exercises as part of the <ORGANIZATION> Mediterranean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Amphibious </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ready </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Group </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Lloyd </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-LlamaSale     10-11 0192</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Llama Sale,0195</SECOND>
<HEAD>Llama Auction Disappoints</HEAD>
<DATELINE>STONELEIGH, England (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s first public auction of llamas did little for the long-eyelashed beast of burden's new status as a fashionable pet. Of the 24 llamas and three alpacas on auction Wednesday at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, one-third were sold but the remainder were withdrawn because bidders did not offer the minimum reserve price, said <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON>, a spokesman for the center. The South American livestock have been gaining in popularity both as pets and for their highly prized fleece. The highest price paid was $ 8,000 for a 4-year-old female llama, but a final bid of $ 11,200 for two alpacas came in below the reserve price. Several male llamas were sold for less than $ 300, <PERSON> Wheeler </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> Walker </PERSON>, secretary of <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Camelids </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ltd. </ORGANIZATION>, an owners and breeders group, estimated there are 700 and 1,000 privately owned llamas and alpacas in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. `` They are lovable, intelligent creatures and you can get very attached to them,'' she said. `` They are resilient to the cold winters, do not need particularly lush pastures for grazing and small children can ride them without fear of any aggression.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 2354EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-GunsmokeWarriors Bjt   10-11 0753</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gunsmoke Warriors, Bjt,0770</SECOND>
<HEAD>`Gunsmoke' Warriors Work to Keep Fighting Edge in Peaceful Times</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto LA2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS ANDERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NELLIS AIR FORCE BASE, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The pilot zoomed low between the pink, craggy peaks of the <LOCATION> Sheep </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, suddenly twisting his F-16 Falcon vertically into the desert sky before diving on the target, a railroad bridge. Capt. <PERSON> Kevin </PERSON> `` Omar'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>'s plane plunged toward the bridge as he pushed his `` pickle'' button, simulating bombs away. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> pointed the Falcon's nose up, climbed radically and turned, eliciting groans from his reporter passenger as the `` Gs'' increased to seven times the force of gravity. The lean, 30-year-old pilot from <LOCATION> Binghamton </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.Y. </LOCATION>, did n't seem bothered. `` We have to do a lot of things to keep in condition,'' he said. <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> pushed the fighter past <ORGANIZATION> Mach </ORGANIZATION> 1, through the sound barrier, and with a sonic boom for salute, headed back toward the <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fighter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Weapons </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION> Nellis </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, known in the <ORGANIZATION> Tactical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> as `` The Home of the Fighter Pilot.'' Despite improved superpower relations, with hopes high for general world peace, professional warriors are still working to keep a combat edge. `` Gunsmoke'' a biennial competition, decides the `` best of the best'' in <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> precision gunnery and bombing. `` Peace is breaking out all over, so why maintain the edge?'' asked Maj. Gen. <PERSON> Billy </PERSON> <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>, a 6-foot-4 Texan who flew 223 missions in <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> and commands the fighter training center at <LOCATION> Nellis </LOCATION>. `` Every kid -LRB- competing in Gunsmoke -RRB- will tell you today that we have always dickered best from a position of strength. ... We ought to have a pair of Russian generals out here. I'd host'em for the whole two weeks,'' said <PERSON> McCoy </PERSON>. As <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> soared away from the target area in his fighter, a formation of A-10 Thunderbolt pilots from the <ORGANIZATION> Connecticut </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> swept by, completing bombing and strafing runs that were part of the two-week shooting competition, which ends Saturday. The <LOCATION> Connecticut </LOCATION> fliers are joined by guard units from Terre Haute, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Sioux </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Kirtland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> N.M. </LOCATION>, and by reserve units from <ORGANIZATION> Luke </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ariz. </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Grissom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ind. </LOCATION>, and <ORGANIZATION> Bergstrom </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. They are competing against regular <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> units from as far away as <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. The fliers at <LOCATION> Nellis </LOCATION> already have won competitions in their home units and are vying to be `` Top Guns,'' an Air Force-wide honor held for two years. Maj. <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Neb. </LOCATION>, who was `` Top Gun'' in his A-10 Thunderbolt two years ago, said, `` I do n't think any rational individual would wish to be at war, but it can be difficult being a warrior when peace is breaking out. `` The biggest problem the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> has to deal with when we are not in conflict is complacency. ... If you have a garden and you leave it for a few days, the weeds begin to grow.'' During competition, Capt. <PERSON> Angus </PERSON> <PERSON> Simpson </PERSON>, an A-10 pilot from <ORGANIZATION> Eielson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Base </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, put all 200 rounds in the white target panel sitting on the arid wasteland that is fighter pilot heaven north of <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION>. It was the first such perfect score, said Capt. <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Christie </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> spokesman. For <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON>, becoming a fighter pilot was a childhood dream nurtured by an uncle who took him to air shows. He started flying single-engine propeller planes when he was 17. Now, piloting the super-sophisticated F-16 over the <LOCATION> Sheep </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mountains </LOCATION>, he is at the top end of the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> dream sheet. `` For me, there is nothing else,'' <PERSON> Bradley </PERSON> said. `` Everything else is a zero. My family has a business. I had no aptitude whatsoever for it. The only thing for me was flying.'' The flier, nicknamed `` Omar'' for the World War II general, faces the possibility he will never fire a shot in anger. `` The slogan for tactical aviation is ` Readiness is our profession,''' he said. `` The military needs to detach itself from the emotions'' about hopes for relaxed tension between the superpowers. Without the ordeal of combat to provide the ultimate warrior's test, the fliers use competitions such as `` Gunsmoke,'' the biggest of its kind, to maintain their adrenaline levels `` Next to my marriage and the birth of my children, it was the most exciting moment of my life to be able to sit back in a moment of quiet reflection and realize that on that day, I was the best,'' <PERSON> Hoy </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0045EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EastGerman-Elite Bjt   10-11 0705</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-East German-Elite, Bjt,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prominent Figures Speak Out For Reforms</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NESHA STARCEVIC</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 It is not only the tens of thousands of ordinary workers, students, housewives and shopkeepers who are complaining about conditions in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and berating its leaders. Even privileged <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> members, some of them world renowned figures in the sports, musical and theater worlds, have joined the chorus. Many of them risk jeopardizing the special status they enjoy if their criticisms get too loud. Still, authors, entertainers, artists and sports personalities have urged the hard-line leadership to re-examine its policies and open a dialogue with opposition groups. The calls have ranged from a joint appeal by as many as 300 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> artists to individual statements by such prominent authors as <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>. <PERSON> Katarina </PERSON> <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, the two-time Olympic figure skating gold medalist and possibly the best-known East German abroad, said the Communist government must think about the causes for the exodus of its people to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. About 50,000 East Germans have fled West in recent months, either crossing <LOCATION> Hungary </LOCATION>'s recently opened border to <LOCATION> Austria </LOCATION> or after seeking refuge in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>'s embassies in <LOCATION> Prague </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Czechoslovakia </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Warsaw </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION>. The exodus deeply embarrassed the government last weekend during 40th anniversary festivities that were overshadowed by nationwide demonstrations unseen since Soviet tanks crushed a workers' uprising in 1953 `` It makes me sad, it hurts me that so many people have left the country,'' Ms. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> told reporters in <LOCATION> Munich </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where she was touring this week with a show. `` Something will change -LRB- in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB-,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON>, herself a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> and a beneficiary of the perks bestowed on major athletic stars. Ms. <PERSON> Witt </PERSON> has been a glamorous ambassador of goodwill and previously limited her political statments to praise for the benefits of a socialist system. The brutal force used by security police against demonstrators over the weekend caused some public figures to call for restraint. <PERSON> Christa </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>, a well-known author who is widely read in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, urged both sides to show `` prudence, calm and patience.'' In a statement broadcast by West German radio stations, she criticized Communist authorities for outlawing the New Forum opposition group, calling the move a `` fatal'' mistake. The author, whose daughter and son-in-law were arrested during weekend demonstrations in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, called for a broad dialogue over the future of the country. <PERSON> Kurt </PERSON> <PERSON> Masur </PERSON>, chief director of the famed <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> Gewandhause orchestra, and cabaret star <PERSON> Berndt </PERSON> <PERSON> Lutz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lange </PERSON> joined three local <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> officials in calling for a dialogue between the opposition and authorities. After their statement was read on <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> radio about 70,000 people demonstrated in the city Monday evening. Unlike the weekend clashes, the biggest demonstration in the current wave of protests ended peacefully with no intervention from massive security forces. Actors in two <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> theaters have posted statements calling for dialogue between the state and the opposition. A similar statement was read by the cast in the <LOCATION> Dresden </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION> after a recent performance. After authorities warned the actors not to read the statement again, they stood silently on the stage after the next performance and distributed it to the public. A group of 300 <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> painters, sculptors and other artists have passed a resolution calling for a broad public discussion of the country's problems. They also urged the state-controlled media to open up to all forces seeking democratic reforms. A statement by 44 entertainers, including well-known East German rock bands such as <PERSON> Pankow </PERSON> and City, criticized the `` unbearable ignorance'' of the Communist leadership. The statement, published in a <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> newspaper, called for reforms `` that will not remove socialism but continue to make it possible'' in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hermann </PERSON> <PERSON> Kant </PERSON>, president of the official <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> and a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, wrote an open letter to the <ORGANIZATION> Junge </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welt </ORGANIZATION> newspaper criticizing censorship in the media. The letter, published on Monday by the official youth newspaper, said it would be wrong to abscribe `` our current defeat'' to the `` evil class enemy.'' <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s state-run newspapers have bitterly denounced Western, particularly West German media, blaming them for triggering the exodus and instigating the protests.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--FakeNewspapers     10-11 0157</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Fake Newspapers,0160</SECOND>
<HEAD>L.A. Times Replaced With Phony Copies Criticizing El Salvador Coverage</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Vandals wrapped thousands of <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Times newspapers with fake front pages criticizing the newspaper's coverage of <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> involvement in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> The crudely fashioned cover sheets were discovered in Times newsracks from <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>. The phony front pages with a `` Los Angels Times'' masthead included front-page stories with such headlines as `` U.S. Wages Kinder, Gentler War in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>'' and `` We Must Have Been Asleep, Times Editors Declare.'' Salvadoran peace activists have used similar bogus newspaper covers in other cities, including <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, although no one claimed responsibility for Tuesday's <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> incident. `` We feel the perpetrators' view of our coverage is erroneous,'' said Times Editor <PERSON> Shelby </PERSON> <PERSON> Coffey </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON>. `` They are perfectly free to have their opinions, but they are wrong in vandalizing our news racks to express those opinions.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     10-11 0870</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,0902</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>ANNAPOLIS, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Ex-CBS anchorman <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> says he misses television journalism, but has kept busy sailing and working occasionally since retiring eight years ago. `` Every time there's a big breaking story, I wish I were sitting there at the desk making decisions on how we're going to cover it, who ought to cover it,'' said the man once considered <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s most trusted newsman <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON> was in <LOCATION> Annapolis </LOCATION> on Monday for a meeting of the Board of Visitors of the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maryland </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> College </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Journalism </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Cronkite </PERSON>, an avid sailor, said he is still busy with work as a special correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION>, remains on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' board of directors and has been involved with numerous projects for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. But the part-time work fails to take the place of the hectic day-to-day pace of broadcast journalism. `` Right now, the developments in <LOCATION> Eastern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>, gee, I'd like be on top of that story,'' he said.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Rip </PERSON> <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> may dress in star-spangled jackets, wield a mean noisemaker and cover his audiences in confetti, but he says he's also an actor. But <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> has n't managed to convince the producers of films, television shows and commercials that he presents more than his act. `` When I go in for a reading they say ` Where's the confetti?''' said <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON>, who is performing at Resorts International Casino Hotel. `` It's very hard to be taken seriously. I just want to branch out because, you know, all the best actors are comedians.'' <PERSON> Taylor </PERSON> was asked to play himself in `` Repossessed,'' his latest film. The movie is a spoof of `` The Exorcist'' and stars <PERSON> Leslie </PERSON> <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> and original `` Exorcist'' actress <PERSON> Linda </PERSON> <PERSON> Blair </PERSON>. `` I said to the director, ` What's my motivation?' He said, ` I do n't know. Just do what you do.' I can see I wo n't be getting any awards for this one.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actor <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, the cowpoke-detective in the 1970s TV series `` <PERSON> McCloud </PERSON>,'' is riding to the rescue of the hungry. `` It's simple,'' <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> said Tuesday. `` You see a problem, you try to help fix it. There were times we were just overwhelmed with red tape and problems, and I wanted to run and hide. `` It is a frightening problem.'' <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, with actress <PERSON> Valerie </PERSON> <PERSON> Harper </PERSON> and others, created L.I.F.E., or Love Is Feeding Everyone, about six years ago. According to the county <ORGANIZATION> Healh </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Services </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, L.I.F.E. feeds about 60,000 people each week. The organization collects food from store chains and delivers it to other groups that dispense it to the needy. The program has been so successful that <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON> and others want other cities to start more L.I.F.E. chapters. `` We are one people in this country and on this planet, and there is no use pretending that other people's hunger does n't touch those of us who are well fed,'' said <PERSON> Weaver </PERSON>, who won an Emmy for portraying <PERSON> Chester </PERSON> <PERSON> Good </PERSON> in the television series `` Gunsmoke.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LEE'S SUMMIT, Mo. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An 11-year-old girl who once said she wanted to sing better than Barbra Streisand has been selected to star on Broadway in a sequel to the hit musical `` Annie.'' <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON> <PERSON> Findley </PERSON> of <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s Summit will play the lead role in `` Annie 2,'' a $ 7 million musical opening in March. She beat out more than 400 girls who auditioned in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> D.C. </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>, it was announced Tuesday in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. `` This has been a lifelong dream for her,'' <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON>'s mother, <PERSON> Brenda </PERSON> <PERSON> Lasater </PERSON>, said Tuesday. `` When she was 4, she went to the <LOCATION> Midland </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theater </LOCATION> -LRB- in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> -RRB- and saw ` <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>.' She said, ` I want to be <PERSON> Annie </PERSON> someday.''' <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON> is described as highly motivated. Told once that she was a good singer, she replied, `` I want to be better than Barbra Streisand.'' The press agent for `` <ORGANIZATION> Annie </ORGANIZATION> 2,'' <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Powers </PERSON>, said <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON> best met the attributes that Director <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Charnin </PERSON> was looking for: a girl with the qualities of the original <PERSON> Annie </PERSON>, <PERSON> Andrea </PERSON> <PERSON> McArdle </PERSON>, with an `` <PERSON> Ethel </PERSON> <PERSON> Merman-like </PERSON> voice,'' acting talent, spunk, tap-dancing ability, and no fear of dogs. The new production, subtitled `` Miss <PERSON> Hannigan </PERSON>'s Revenge,'' goes into rehearsal next month and begins an out-of-town tryout Dec. 22 at <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s Kennedy Center. It opens March 1 at the Marquis Theatre in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> after several weeks of previews. This will not be <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON>'s first Broadway appearance. When she was 8 she spent seven months appearing in `` Coastal Disturbances,'' playing one of several children vacationing at a <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> beach. <PERSON> Danielle </PERSON>, a student at <ORGANIZATION> Pleasant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lea </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Elementary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> in <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>'s Summit, starred in a production of `` Annie'' at <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>'s Starlight Theater in She began performing in <LOCATION> Kansas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> area talent competitions when she was 5. She has taken voice, acting and flute instruction and studied jazz, tap and ballet dancing. The original `` Annie'' was a Broadway smash, opening in April 1977 and running for 2,377 performances. In the sequel, the lead character's dog, <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, is being replaced by a mixed-breed named <PERSON> Beau </PERSON>, who was adopted at a tender age by trainer <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Berloni </PERSON>. <PERSON> Berloni </PERSON> trained the original <PERSON> Sandy </PERSON>, who is now 16 or 17 `` and quite arthritic,'' said Powers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--Turrentine     10-11 0106</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Turrentine,0110</SECOND>
<HEAD>Saxophonist in Critical Condition</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Jazz saxophonist <PERSON> Stanley </PERSON> <PERSON> Turrentine </PERSON> was hospitalized in critical condition with an accumulation of fluid in his lungs. The 55-year-old <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> native, who has a history of high blood pressure, was taken to <LOCATION> Mercy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hospital </LOCATION> on Tuesday morning by paramedics after his wife was unable to awaken him in their hotel room, said hospital spokesman <PERSON> Eric </PERSON> <PERSON> Hofmann </PERSON>. He was semi-conscious by afternoon and was attached to a respirator in the hospital's intensive care unit. <PERSON> Turrentine </PERSON>'s publicist, <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Lucoff </PERSON>, said he was unaware of any performances the player may have scheduled in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Turrentine </PERSON> lives in <LOCATION> Kensington </LOCATION>, Md.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0030EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Colombia 4thLd-Writethru a0756 10-11 0865</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Colombia, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0756,0892</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Two Newspaper Employees Killed in Attacks Linked to Drug Gunmen</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with four grafs to UPDATE with another journalist slain,
four shot to dead in bar, details. Picks up graf 2 pvs, `The shootings
...' Edits thereafter to trim</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TOM WELLS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOGOTA, Colombia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Gunmen on motorcycles Tuesday killed two employees of the newspaper <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> in an attempt by cocaine traffickers to force the <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily to end its anti-drug crusade. Later Tuesday, the spasm of violence in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> worsened as assailants shot to death a journalist on a downtown street and killed four people in a working-class neighborhood bar. Police said the unidentified assassins killed <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarasty </PERSON>, the 55-year-old director of <ORGANIZATION> Cronista </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratica </ORGANIZATION> magazine, while he was walking with another journalist. His companion was slightly wounded. At about the same time, another group fired at a crowd at a bar in Manrique, a northern <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> barrio, killing four in a spray of bullets before fleeing. <PERSON> Manrique </PERSON> is a known recruiting ground for `` sicarios,'' or hitmen used by drug traffickers. The shootings in <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION>, where only 11 <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> employees remain, followed 13 bombings in three other Colombian cities overnight. It was the largest outbreak of bomb attacks since drug lords, blamed for slaying a presidential candidate, went to war with the government nearly two months ago. Tuesday's violence came during a visit to <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> by <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> Gen. <PERSON> Maxwell </PERSON> <PERSON> Thurman </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Southern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Command </ORGANIZATION> based in <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>. Killed within an hour of each other Tuesday afternoon were <PERSON> Marta </PERSON> <PERSON> Luz </PERSON> <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> and <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Soler </PERSON>, a spokesman for <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> in this capital told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Miss <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> was administrator of the paper's <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> office, and <PERSON> Soler </PERSON> was the daily's circulation manager in the city of 2 million people. In a telephone call to the paper's <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> office, a man who did not identify himself said a group known as the Extraditables had killed the two and he said they would kill other <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> workers who did not leave <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> within three days, an editor at the newspaper said on condition of anonymity. The Extraditables are suspected drug traffickers sought for extradition to stand trial in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. A senior <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> reporter, who also spoke on condition of anonymity, told <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in a telephone interview that none of the paper's 1,200 employees had quit, though many have received death threats in the past. However, one of the paper's owners, speaking in <LOCATION> Monterrey </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, at the annual conference of the <ORGANIZATION> Inter </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>, said <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> may close its <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> office. `` I do n't know if we'll be able to continue operating in the city of <LOCATION> Medellin </LOCATION> under the circumstances,'' said <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Gabriel </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON>, president of the paper's editorial board. He also said the 102-year-old newspaper may have to close eventually because of financial problems caused by the bombing of the main offices last month. The car bomb at its <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> building caused heavy damage and forced the newspaper to cut operations. About 50 soldiers now guard that building 24 hours a day. <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> publisher <PERSON> Guillermo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cano </PERSON> was assassinated by drug traffickers in a spray of submachine gun fire Dec. 17, 1986, as he was leaving the newspaper in his car. <PERSON> Soler </PERSON> was killed in front of his house Tuesday by a man who rode by on a motorcycle, <ORGANIZATION> El </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Espectador </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Alfonso </PERSON> <PERSON> Bernal </PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. Miss <PERSON> Lopez </PERSON> was killed by a shot in the neck, and her mother was wounded in a leg while the two women sat in their white sedan at a traffic light, the paper's spokesman in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> said. Nineteen people were injured by explosions in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Barranquilla </LOCATION> and <PERSON> Pereira </PERSON>, the police said. No one claimed responsibility, but authorities assume the scores of bombs set off since August were planted by the drug gangs, who supply 80 percent of the cocaine sold in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. There were no indications whether the overnight bombings were connected with <PERSON> Thurman </PERSON>'s visit. No <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> troops are stationed in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION>, but the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> has delivered $ 65 million worth of military aid to help in the fight against drug traffickers. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> technicians arrived last month to help train Colombians to operate or repair some of the equipment, but were here only a few days and none remained behind. President <PERSON> Virgilio </PERSON> <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> has said he does not want <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> soldiers in <LOCATION> Colombia </LOCATION> even as advisers. <PERSON> Thurman </PERSON>'s 24-hour visit included a meeting Monday with <PERSON> Barco </PERSON> and Gen. <PERSON> Miguel </PERSON> <PERSON> Maza </PERSON>, commander of the <ORGANIZATION> Administrative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, the government investigative police, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said. The embassy described the meeting as routine. <PERSON> Thurman </PERSON> left <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> on Tuesday. <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Tiempo </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> daily usually well-informed about the government, said <PERSON> Thurman </PERSON> also met with Gen. <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Botero </PERSON>, the defense minister. The bombings Monday night and early Tuesday included nine in <LOCATION> Bogota </LOCATION> that injured eight people, and three in <LOCATION> Pereira </LOCATION>, wounding 11, the national police said. Police said a man who planted one of the bombs was killed in a shootout with officers. Authorities have reported 161 explosions since Aug. 19 and give the casualties as 11 dead and 183 wounded.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0101EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Lites     10-11 0333</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Lites,0344</SECOND>
<HEAD>On the Light Side</HEAD>
<DATELINE>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A truck thief was apparently stopped dead in his tracks when he discovered the vehicle was marked `` Human Remains, Extreme Care.'' The 24-foot rental truck, stolen early Monday from a casket company, was abandoned with its cargo, an empty shipping container for a corpse. `` I think they saw ` Human Remains' and said, ` Oh, Lordy!''' said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON>, owner of <ORGANIZATION> Flite-Rite </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>. `` A lot of people for some reason are scared of dead bodies.'' Pointing out that his company makes caskets, <PERSON> Allgood </PERSON> wondered about the thief's motivation: `` What ... did they think it would have in the back? Dead fish?'' Two similar trucks stolen from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION> this month were stripped of their tires and radios, said <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Shipway </PERSON>, safety manager for <ORGANIZATION> Ryder </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Truck </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rental </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Fort </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lauderdale </LOCATION>. `` Probably because of the cargo, they left it,'' <PERSON> Shipway </PERSON> said. `` They must have seen the -LRB- casket -RRB- and gotten scared.''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON> <PERSON> Rubach </PERSON>, diehard <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cubs </ORGANIZATION> fan and mayor of <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION>, says she is signing up for singing lessons to make good on a bet with <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON> Herb </PERSON> <PERSON> Drinkwater </PERSON> The two last week wagered on whether the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> would defeat the <ORGANIZATION> Cubs </ORGANIZATION> in the best-of-seven National League playoffs. The <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> won the final game 3-2 Monday, winning the series 4-1. Ms. <PERSON> Rubach </PERSON> now has to sing the national anthem in <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION>'s ballpark during the Cactus League spring season The <ORGANIZATION> Cubs </ORGANIZATION> play at <ORGANIZATION> HoHoKam </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Park </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Mesa </LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> train at <LOCATION> Scottsdale </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Stadium </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Drinkwater </PERSON> said he plans to be at the game to record her singing. `` I'm going to tape it and save it to use against her as blackmail when I want something,'' he said. Ms. <PERSON> Rubach </PERSON> said: `` In order to ensure proper noise-abatement procedures and to guarantee that my voice lifted in song will not contribute to any noise pollution, I pledge to take singing lessons between now and the game.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0248EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--ChildHero     10-11 0158</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Child Hero,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Little Boy Calls 911 to Save Mother</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 3-year-old boy calmly called 911 to get help for his mother, who lay on the living room floor choking on a cough drop, authorities said. <PERSON> Jameson </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON>, whose 4th birthday is Thursday, had been taught to dial 911 in the event of an emergency. So he ran to the telephone his parents had mounted low on the bathroom wall for his use, said his father, <PERSON> Michael </PERSON>, 26. <PERSON> Jameson </PERSON> told fire dispatchers Tuesday night his 32-year-old mother, <PERSON> Peggy </PERSON>, was on the floor and could n't breathe, said fire Battalion Chief <PERSON> Lon </PERSON> <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON>. `` She ca n't come to the phone because she's choking,'' the child said. He did n't know his address, but dispatchers were able to trace the call and paramedics arrived within a minute, <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Rodgers </PERSON> was unconscious, but paramedics were able to dislodge the cough drop and restore her breathing, <PERSON> Pursell </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891011-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-11-89 0118EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-DiplomatSuit Bjt   10-11 0521</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Diplomat Suit, Bjt,520</SECOND>
<HEAD>State Department Bows to Union Demand on `Competence' Certificates</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
