<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 2335EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Brazil 3rdLd-Writethru a0820 11-15 0946</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Brazil, 3rd Ld-Writethru, a0820,0977</SECOND>
<HEAD>Conservative Leading 1st Direct Presidential Election Since 1960</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS with 6 grafs to UPDATE with later figures from TV, details.
Picks up 4th pvs, `More than...' Minor editing thereafter</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos MA1,NY15</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETER MUELLO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Early unofficial returns Wednesday night showed conservative <PERSON> Fernando </PERSON> <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON> leading <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s first free and direct presidential election since 1960 With about 8 percent of the votes counted, <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON>, who led most exit polls with 30 percent, had 2,225,909 votes, followed by left-wing populist <PERSON> Leonel </PERSON> <PERSON> Brizola </PERSON> with 1,628,735 votes, said <ORGANIZATION> Globo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> TV </ORGANIZATION>, the nation's largest network. Late Wednesday the government announced a 12-hour delay in the official count, reportedly because of computer problems. In third place was <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Inacio </PERSON> <PERSON> Lula </PERSON> <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON> of the Marxist-oriented Workers' Party with 1,561,739 votes, trailed by Sen. <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Covas </PERSON> of the left-of-center <ORGANIZATION> Brazilian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Social </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democracy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> with 1,345,248 votes but with surprising leads in two of the country's largest cities, the network said. <PERSON> Covas </PERSON>, a dark-horse candidate, held a strong lead in <LOCATION> Sao </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paulo </LOCATION>, the nation's most populous city, and was a solid second in <PERSON> Belo </PERSON> <PERSON> Horizonte </PERSON>, the TV network said. The network said some 130,000 people voted for popular TV game-show host <PERSON> Silvio </PERSON> <PERSON> Santos </PERSON>, who tried to enter the race two weeks before the election but whose candidacy was thrown out by the <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION>. More than 82 million people were eligible to vote for a successor to President <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>, who was chosen by an electoral college when the generals relinquished power in 1985 after two decades' rule. Voting was mandatory for Brazilians aged 18-69. The chief of <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s federal police, <PERSON> Romeu </PERSON> <PERSON> Tuma </PERSON>, said there were `` no significant incidents to mar the voting. We are very pleased with how calm the day was.'' Final results are not expected until Saturday and, on the assumption no one gains a majority, a runoff between the two leaders is planned for Dec. 17. The first official results announced were from a relative handful of Brazilians who cast ballots in embassies and consulates in 19 countries, with Collor de Mello leading followed by <PERSON> Covas </PERSON> and <PERSON> da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>. <PERSON> Collor </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Mello </PERSON>, a 40-year-old former state governor, has been a harsh critic of <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>. Leading in the polls since April, his dapper good looks and anti-corruption platform made Collor de Mello popular with the poor, a majority in the Brazilian electorate. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON> is widely blamed for official corruption and an annual inflation rate of at least 1,300 percent. The <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> first announced results would start being released at 8:00 p.m. local time, just three hours after the polls closed. However, that time was pushed back to 11:00 p.m. and then to Thursday. An election official, speaking on condition of anonymity, told a reporter there was a problem with computer links between <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> and far-off voting precincts. Parties ranged from the Communists to one formerly backed by the military entered candidates. Fully 73 percent of the Brazilian electorate had never voted for president. Lines lines of voters began forming before dawn, hours before polls opened at 8 a.m., from the <LOCATION> Amazon </LOCATION> jungle in the north to the southern pampas. The results showed the candidates leading in their regional strongholds _ <ORGANIZATION> Collor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> de </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mello </ORGANIZATION> led in the federal capital of <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, in northeastern <LOCATION> Maceio </LOCATION> and southeastern <LOCATION> Curitiba </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Da </PERSON> <PERSON> Silva </PERSON>, an ex-labor leader, held wide leads in southeastern <PERSON> Belo </PERSON> <PERSON> Horizonte </PERSON> and the two northeastern <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION> coastal cities of <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Recife </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Brizola </PERSON>, of the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, led in the southern capital cities of <LOCATION> Porto </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Alegre </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> de </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Janeiro </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s second-largest city Promotional spots on nationwide television said that whereas in 1960 it took three months to count the votes, this year, with modern computer technology, the results would be announced as quickly as possible. The federal electoral court promised results by 8 p.m. but that was postponed several times for reasons not explained. Election officials directed that ballots cast at the 250,000 voting stations in the nation's 4,445 counties be flown to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> after local counting. Several candidates raised the possibility of fraud. <PERSON> Roberto </PERSON> <PERSON> Rosas </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Superior </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electoral </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> responded on Wednesday: `` Many candidates are setting up parallel vote-counting, for fear of fraud, but fraud is impossibe and there is no ` virus' or ` microbe' that can affect our computers.'' Collor de Mello voted early in <LOCATION> Maceio </LOCATION> and flew back to <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION> to follow the count for president, who will serve five years and can not seek re-election. The election took place on a national holiday, the 100th anniversary of the republic that ended the reign of Emperor <PERSON> Pedro </PERSON> II. In <LOCATION> Rio </LOCATION>, many <PERSON> Brizola </PERSON> sympathizers wore red bandannas, the candidate's trademark. In <LOCATION> Brasilia </LOCATION>, election officials delayed voting for two hours and ordered the bandannas removed. The penalty for not voting is a fine of up to 20 new cruzados, about $ 3.30. A 1988 constitutional reform also enfranchised citizens aged 16 and 17, but voting is not compulsory for them. Liquor sales were forbidden from midnight Tuesday to 6 a.m. Thursday. <PERSON> Janio </PERSON> <PERSON> Quadros </PERSON> won <LOCATION> Brazil </LOCATION>'s last free and direct presidential election, in 1960. He resigned after seven months and the ensuing confusion led to a military coup in 1964. The army canceled direct presidential elections, although they permitted some regional elections. <PERSON> Sarney </PERSON>, 59, said this election `` concludes the transition to democracy.'' `` There has never been so much freedom in the country,'' he said Tuesday night. `` In homes, at work, in the streets, opinions are divided and no one is afraid, because we know democracy exists.'' He did not publicly support any candidate, and described his role in the election as a `` magistrate.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 2336EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-TechnologyLetter     11-15 0243</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Technology Letter,240</SECOND>
<HEAD>Reported Plan to Cut Research Protested</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> have written to President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> asking about industry reports that the administration plans heavy cuts in research in high technology financed through the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>, a congressional aide said Wednesday night. A White House spokesman, <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>, said he was not sure the letter had been received and could give no response. `` I have nothing for you on that,'' said <PERSON> Hart </PERSON>. Among the signers of the letter were Reps. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gephardt </PERSON>, D-Mo., the Democratic majority leader in the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION>, and Rep. <PERSON> Mel </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, D-Calif., according to <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Wessel </PERSON>, an aide to An aide who spoke on condition that he not be identified said sources in the semiconductor industry with access to classified documents had been alerting congressional offices to what they described as an administration plan for sharp cuts. Among programs that might be affected, he said, were <ORGANIZATION> Sematech </ORGANIZATION>, the consortium now conducting semiconductor research with the aid of $ 100 million in federal money every year; a planned program in X-Ray lithography that could increase the capacity of computer chips, and high-definition television or HDTV. <ORGANIZATION> Commerce </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosbacher </PERSON> lost a bid in September inside the administration to launch a major effort to capture world leadership in HDTV. As the aide described the letter, the members were `` asking information about what they heard about possible cuts in high-tech research and urging that no cuts be made.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 2344EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Sandinista-ContraTalks 4thLd-Writethru a0836 11-15 0675</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sandinista-Contra Talks, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0836,660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Talks in Disarray</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 7-8th grafs bgng: ``An hour,'' with Contras announcing
recess; graf 12: ``Earlier, Tinoco,'' edited to clarify sequence, making
it read: ``Still earlier,''</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE GEDDA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Peace talks between <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s leftist government and the <ORGANIZATION> Contra </ORGANIZATION> rebels fell into disarray Wednesday night with the two sides offering sharply differing assessments on the progress of the negotiations. The Contra delegation stunned the Sandinista negotiators in early evening by asking for a week-long recess just when, Sandinista officials said, an agreement seemed within reach. The chief Nicaraguan government negotiator, Vice-Foreign Minister <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Hugo </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON>, described the Contra proposal as `` a total surprise'' because he said the two sides had made `` a lot of progress'' earlier in the day. The talks took a bizarre twist when, according to <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> delegation disappeared at 8 p.m. after members said they wanted to talk among themselves. `` We do n't know where they are,'' <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> told reporters shortly after 10 p.m. `` They are somewhere in this building.'' <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> and other members of the Sandinista delegation then returned to their hotel. An hour later, the <LOCATION> Contra </LOCATION> delegation reappeared and told reporters they planned to return late Thursday morning to discuss with the Sandinistas the timing for the resumption of the negotiations. They left the impression that they might rescind their earlier request for a seven-day recess. Earlier, rebel spokesman <PERSON> Bosco </PERSON> <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON> disagreed strongly when he was informed that an American member of the Sandinista delegation, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON>, had given an upbeat account of the discussions. `` Unfortunately there was not any flexibility on the part of the government to reach a cease-fire,'' <PERSON> Matamoros </PERSON> said. Informed that <PERSON> Reichler </PERSON> had said that the two sides were on the verge of an agreement, <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION> replied, `` I would say Mr. <PERSON> Rickler </PERSON>'s perception is not accurate.'' Still earlier, <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said his government offered a major concession in cease-fire talks with the Contras by dropping its demand that the rebels demobilize. As its price for restoring the cease-fire the government allowed to lapse Nov. 1, <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> said the government is insisting only that Contra forces in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> return to their base camps in <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>. `` We think that is a very important change in our position,'' <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> told a news conference at the Nicaraguan Embassy a few hours before the peace talks reconvened at the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Tinoco </PERSON> maintained that while the <ORGANIZATION> Sandinistas </ORGANIZATION> are willing to make concessions, the Contras have shown `` not an inch of flexibility'' in four rounds of talks starting last Thursday at the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION>. There was no immediate response by the rebels but administration officials said the Contras have told them evacuation from Nicaraguan territory is not feasible. As part of a cease-fire agreement, the rebels would be willing instead to relocate in designated `` enclaves'' in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION> where their activities could easily be monitored by international observers, the Contras have told <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials. If they return to <LOCATION> Honduras </LOCATION>, it is possible they could be prevented by international monitors from returning to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, the Contras have argued. In addition, they said, since the Contras are Nicaraguans, it makes more sense for them to remain inside their own homeland rather than in a neighboring country. There are an estimated 5,000 rebels in <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>, about 2,000 of whom have infiltrated from the Honduran base camps in recent weeks. Nicaraguan President <PERSON> Daniel </PERSON> <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> declined to renew the cease fire on Nov. 1, drawing widespread international condemnation. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> said Monday that the suspension of the truce had created `` a militarized election atmosphere.'' <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> defended his decision by saying the rebels had been engaging in terrorist activity. While allowing the truce to lapse after 19 months, <PERSON> Ortega </PERSON> simultaneously called for a resumption of discussions with the resistance. Hoping to prod the negotiators toward a settlement were representatives from the <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nations </ORGANIZATION> and the Organization of <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. They are members of the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Support </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Verification </ORGANIZATION>, which was set up to oversee the peace process.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 2351EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Bush-Salvador 1stLd-Writethru   11-15 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bush-Salvador, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0772,250</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bush Commends El Slavador's President</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 5th graf: ``In Friday,'' with report munitions deliveries
accelerated</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> called <PERSON> El </PERSON> <PERSON> Salvador </PERSON>'s president Wednesday to express solidarity with the rightist government in the face of a fierce guerrilla attack that has left upwards of 500 people dead and more than 1,000 wounded. White House press secretary <PERSON> Marlin </PERSON> <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> commended President <PERSON> Alfredo </PERSON> <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> for the efforts of the Salvadoran armed forces `` to avoid causing casualties to the civilian population.'' The spokesman said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> also pledged the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> would continue to speak out about <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> and Nicaraguan support for the guerrillas, `` which flies in the face'' of regional peace accords. The four-day-guerrilla offensive appeared stalled as government troops drove the rebels from working-class neighborhoods in fierce combat. The armed forces' air power and numerical superiority combined with lack of popular support for the guerrillas appeared to tilt the battle for the capital in favor of the government. In Friday editions, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials were accelerating deliveries of munitions and other aid scheduled for delivery to <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> told <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> he stands behind the Salvadoran government. `` The president said that the -LRB- rebel force -RRB- bears full responsibility for this tragedy and that he wanted to express the solidarity of the <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> people for the great suffering in <LOCATION> Sal </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION> and elsewhere.'' The press spokesman said <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> thanked <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his support and reported that the armed forces were having increasing success against the guerrillas. Further, <PERSON> Cristiani </PERSON> told <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> that the government `` would continue to give the highest priority to protecting the civilian population in military operations against those guerrillas that remained,'' <PERSON> Fitzwater </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0007EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-NortheastForests-Glance     11-15 0271</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Northeast Forests-Glance,0289</SECOND>
<HEAD>A Look at the Northeastern Forests</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Northeast Forests</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORTLAND, Maine (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here is a breakdown of the 25.8 million acres included in the <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>' Northern Forest Lands Study: Private Lands: _ <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>: 7.7 million acres private industrial; 3.1 million acres large non-industrial; 3.4 million acres other private _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION>: 500,000 acres private industrial; 50,000 acres large non-industrial; 350,000 acres other private _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>: 1.2 million acres private industrial; 500,000 acres large non-industrial; 3.1 million acres other private _ <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION>: 300,000 acres private industrial; 50,000 acres large non-industrial; 1.55 million acres other private _ Total private: <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> 14.2 million acres; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> 900,000 acres; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 4.8 million acres; <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> 1.9 million acres; total 21.8 million acres Private industrial land is defined as land owned by companies that have processing facilities in the area, such as the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Great </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Northern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paper </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. Large non-industrial land is generally parcels of 5,000 acres or more that are owned by land-management companies that do not have processing facilities, such as <ORGANIZATION> Seven </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Islands </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Land </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>, and various estates and hunting clubs in the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>'s Adirondacks Other private land is defined the amount of land left over which does n't fall into the other two categories. Public Lands: _ <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION>: 700,000 acres state owned; 80,000 acres federally owned _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> 50,000 acres state owned; 200,000 acres federally owned _ <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 2.8 million acres state owned _ <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> 90,000 acres state owned; 6,000 acres federally owned _ Total public: <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> 800,000 acres; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hampshire </LOCATION> 300,000 acres; <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> 2.8 million acres; <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> 100,000 acres; total 4 million acres
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0008EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Chalk'sClosing     11-15 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Chalk's Closing,0659</SECOND>
<HEAD>Financial Troubles Threaten Nation's Oldest Air Passenger Service</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN MURPHY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The nation's oldest air passenger service, whose seaplanes carried celebrities, outlaws and at least one fleeing dictator in its 70 years, may be grounded by financial losses and competition from modern jets. Unless a buyer is found, the final island-hopping Chalk's <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>' flight will splash down Dec. 15 on <LOCATION> Biscayne </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bay </LOCATION> off <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> `` It's a very sad moment. This is an item of living history that may bite the dust,'' said <PERSON> Harold </PERSON> <PERSON> Rifas </PERSON>, an attorney for financially troubled <ORGANIZATION> Resorts </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, which has owned Chalk's since 1974. `` It was an exciting, thrilling way to move people,'' said <PERSON> Rifas </PERSON>. `` It's really a depressing thing for me to handle this.'' <PERSON> Rifas </PERSON> said losses have been `` very, very substantial'' at Chalk's, whose 17-seat seaplanes were featured on the opening credits of the former hit series `` Miami Vice.'' Resorts reported losses of $ 2.3 million for the first half of 1989 for its airline operations, including Chalk's and <ORGANIZATION> Paradise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, which carries travelers to Resorts' Bahamian casino complex. Chalk's dropped its <LOCATION> Paradise </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> route last month and now operates three daily flights between <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> Bahamian </LOCATION> island of <LOCATION> Bimini </LOCATION>. Resorts itself is struggling with mounting debt and falling values of junk bonds used by <PERSON> Merv </PERSON> <PERSON> Griffin </PERSON> to finance acquisition of the company from developer <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Trump </PERSON> last year. The possible demise of Chalk's would end a direct link with <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION>'s flamboyant past as a mecca for such pioneer aviators as <PERSON> Amelia </PERSON> <PERSON> Earhart </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Eddie </PERSON> <PERSON> Rickenbaker </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> founder <PERSON> Juan </PERSON> <PERSON> Trippe </PERSON> and <PERSON> Glenn </PERSON> <PERSON> Curtiss </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Curtiss </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION>. In 1919, barnstormer and stunt pilot <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> `` Pappy'' Chalk took a Curtiss F flying boat to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> and tied up along the bayfront, where he pitched an umbrella and began offering $ 5 sightseeing flights. During the next decades, Chalk's <LOCATION> Caribbean </LOCATION> island flights carried everyone from sunburned tourists to shady Prohibition-era rumrunners. Passenger manifests also included names such as <PERSON> Ernest </PERSON> <PERSON> Hemingway </PERSON> and <PERSON> Errol </PERSON> <PERSON> Flynn </PERSON>. In 1933, a hail of bullets followed a Chalk's plane whisking deposed <LOCATION> Cuban </LOCATION> dictator <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Machado </PERSON> into exile. In 1972, a Chalk's crewman and pilot were wounded by two gunmen who commandeered an aircraft to <LOCATION> Cuba </LOCATION>. The crew and passengers returned to <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> the next day. Five years later, 88-year-old Chalk died after falling from a tree he was trimming. The only accident involving a Chalk's aircraft and resulting in an injury occurred in 1985, when a <ORGANIZATION> Grumman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mallard </ORGANIZATION> crashed after takeoff from Cat Cay south of <LOCATION> Bimini </LOCATION>. One the 12 passengers was injured. `` When you talk about amphibious aircraft you are going back to the origins of international air travel,'' said <PERSON> Donna </PERSON> <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION> Smithsonian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> and Space Museum in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. `` It's really a look back to the beginnings. The museum is exhibiting a former Chalk's Grumman Goose, the forerunner of the Mallards now operated by the airline. Ms. <PERSON> Corbett </PERSON> said 63-year-old <ORGANIZATION> Northwest </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Eagan </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, outside <LOCATION> Minneapolis </LOCATION>, is officially the nation's oldest passenger `` airline,'' a designation that requires posted schedules and a federal license. But she said Chalk's, which received airline status in the 1940s after years without firm, posted schedules, may lay claim to being the oldest passenger `` service'' and the last surviving scheduled seaplane operation in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Catalina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Flying </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Boats </ORGANIZATION> discontinued seaplane service last year from <LOCATION> Long </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, to <LOCATION> Catalina </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION>. Like other seaplane services, Chalk's has been unable to compete with faster and larger jets. Several airlines, including <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Eastern </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Midway </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION>, have service to the <LOCATION> Bahamas </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Paradise </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Island </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airlines </ORGANIZATION> now uses 50-seat Dash 7 planes to its private airstrip. Resorts reported it lost $ 48.5 million for the first six months of 1989 on revenue of $ 223.7 million.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0016EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PregnantHeroine     11-15 0361</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pregnant Heroine,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Waitress, Pregnant With Twins, Chases Stabbing Suspect</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto MP1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LAURA BAENEN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MINNEAPOLIS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A `` little half-pint'' size waitress pregnant with twins chased and helped catch a man who police say stabbed one of her regular customers at the restaurant. `` I did n't know what I was going to do if I caught him,'' said <PERSON> Karen </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>, who is 4 -LCB- months pregnant and just shy of 5 feet tall. She did n't have to worry because her screams during Tuesday afternoon's four-block chase alerted a police officer, who caught the man. The 49-year-old suspect, a drifter from <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>, was being held pending a charge of aggravated robbery, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Adelmann </PERSON>, a St. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> police spokesman. The victim, 86-year-old <PERSON> Bernard </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, who was in fair condition Tuesday night following surgery at <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Paul </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ramsey </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>, identified the man as his attacker, said police and hospital officials. Young stumbled out of a restroom at Tin Cup's Place in <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Paul </LOCATION> after he was attacked. `` He kind of fell into my arms and said he had been stabbed and mugged,'' said a cook, <PERSON> Carolyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON>, 45. Ms. <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON> asked which way the attacker had gone. `` That's when she took off, the little half pint and her twins,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON>, who added she did n't have time to stop Ms. <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>. `` It was just an instant reaction to get this guy,'' said Ms. <PERSON> Hoyle </PERSON>, 24. She said when she spotted the man outside, he was walking casually, until she started screaming at him. A restaurant patron joined her in the chase but he could n't keep up, she said. She said once police caught the suspect, `` I looked at him in the car and said I hope you did n't kill this guy. He just glared at me. He never said anything to me. He did n't have a chance. I was screaming the whole time.'' She returned to the restaurant in time to tell Young the suspect was in custody and help <PERSON> Young </PERSON>'s wife into the ambulance to join him. After that, she went back to waiting tables. `` That's <PERSON> Karen </PERSON>. It's like the show must go on,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Lenihan </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0033EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Obit-Graham     11-15 0155</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Obit-Graham,0162</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former AP Writer Dillon Graham Dead at 81</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MYRTLE BEACH, S.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Dillon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lorentus </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, a former <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> bureau chief and reporter who spent much of his career in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, has died at age 81. A memorial service was held Tuesday at the Covenant Towers retirement center, where <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> died Sunday. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON>, a native of <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Fla. </LOCATION>, was a reporter for The <LOCATION> Gainesville </LOCATION> Sun before joining the wire service in 1929. <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> worked for the <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> from 1934 to 1937, when he transferred to <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. He became features editor in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, and in 1943 was named chief of the <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION>, bureau. In 1947, <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> returned to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, where he worked until his retirement in 1973. He is survived by his wife, <PERSON> Gilbert </PERSON> `` GiGi'' <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Myrtle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>; a daughter, <PERSON> Betty </PERSON> <PERSON> Graham </PERSON> <PERSON> Mooney </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Arlington </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>; three grandchildren and a great-grandchild. No funeral was planned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0035EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-PenthouseSuit     11-15 0323</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Penthouse Suit,0330</SECOND>
<HEAD>Penthouse Accuses Religious Group of Extortion</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Penthouse magazine sued a religious organization in federal court Tuesday, accusing the group of using extortion and racketeering to suppress the sale of adult magazines. The lawsuit filed in <ORGANIZATION> U.S </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> District </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> names the <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION> chapter of the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Family </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION>. It seeks to recover at least $ 25,000 the magazine claims it lost when a grocery store chain stopped selling Penthouse, according to a statement from Penthouse International. A similar lawsuit was filed against the association two weeks ago by retailing and publishing companies, including <ORGANIZATION> Playboy </ORGANIZATION> magazine and the Waldenbooks book store chain. `` These people represent the worst possible element in a free society,'' Penthouse publisher <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Guccione </PERSON> said in the statement. `` They will not rest until the public, through its inaction, allows them to regulate and approve our reading, viewing, listening and other educational and entertainment activities.'' A call late Tuesday to the group's state headquarters in <LOCATION> Tampa </LOCATION> seeking comment was not immediately returned. A home phone number for the group's state director, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Caton </PERSON>, was unlisted. The lawsuit accuses the association and <PERSON> Caton </PERSON> of distributing a letter in September to store chains `` threatening them with legal action and public ridicule unless they agreed to stop selling the magazines,'' the statement said. The letter claimed the stores were violating <LOCATION> Florida </LOCATION>'s obscenity statute and promised to name those stores as violators and demand enforcement. The publishing companies have said the statute applies only to publishers. The association acknowledged in a news release that was included in the earlier lawsuit that the pornography statute applies only to publishing companies. The association has campaigned for years against the sale of magazines such as Penthouse and Playboy. The association, which has also backed boycotts of TV programs it considers offensive, most recently persuaded Matchbox to cancel sale of a <PERSON> Freddy </PERSON> <PERSON> Krueger </PERSON> doll, based on the ghoulish killer in `` Nightmare on Elm Street'' movies.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0037EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Media     11-15 0623</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Media,0642</SECOND>
<HEAD>East German Media Try to Come to Grips with New-Found Freedoms</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GEORGE JAHN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Senior editors at <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s state news agency used to dread the daily phone call from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, telling them what to write. Such calls are just a memory now. `` Nobody tells us what to report and what not to report anymore,'' said <PERSON> Ralf </PERSON> <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON>, assistant director general of the <ORGANIZATION> ADN </ORGANIZATION> news agency. `` It's as if someone had removed the brakes on us.'' <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON>, 59, and others said Tuesday that decades of restrictions on reporting have been lifted over the last three weeks in the course of radical changes that toppled the hard-line leadership of <PERSON> Erich </PERSON> <PERSON> Honecker </PERSON> and culminated in the opening of the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall. <PERSON> Bachmann </PERSON> says he sees ADN evolving from a mouthpiece of the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> into a non-partisan news service `` that is there for all readers, for all parties, for all newspapers.'' Acting Chief Editor <PERSON> Hans-Joachim </PERSON> <PERSON> Koppe </PERSON> of the daily <ORGANIZATION> Neue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION> also perceives the news media moving toward `` a real pluralism of opinions and parties,'' after shaking off constraints that resulted in some of the world's most slanted and boring reporting. His paper is run by the <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION> _ one of four parties allowed to survive after the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> assumed sole control in 1949 in exchange for acknowledging Communist supremacy. For decades, that tradeoff was reflected in <LOCATION> Neue </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zeit </LOCATION>'s reporting With the exception of sports on the last page, the eight-page edition on Oct. 9 was devoted to celebrations of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s 40th anniversary and the visit of <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>. A headline from that edition: `` The Idea of Socialism Becomes More Enriched and is Conducive to Joint Action.'' Since then, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s peaceful revolution has swept <ORGANIZATION> Neue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Zeit </ORGANIZATION>'s pages clean of such subservience. `` The Issue is True Pluralism, of Letting the People Decide,'' read one front-page headline. `` Ninety-Three Percent -LRB- of Respondents -RRB- Want a New Election Law,'' read another. An editorial criticized the Communists in a way that would have been unthinkable just three weeks ago, urging `` those who are guilty to be made accountable to the people.'' `` It is just that party leaders and ministers are made accountable to us,'' the editorial continued. `` It is just when property and privileges gained illegally are confiscated. One should be made to take responsibility for political mistakes. And crimes have to be punished.'' State television also is n't what it used to be. Over the past three weeks: _ Chief editor <PERSON> Klaus </PERSON> <PERSON> Schickhelm </PERSON> of the main news program went on the air to apologize to the public for biased and false reporting and pledged `` quick and honest'' news presentation _ `` The <ORGANIZATION> Black </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Canal </ORGANIZATION>,'' a rabidly anti-West propaganda program that enraged East Germans for nearly 30 years, was abruptly canceled. _ A <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> session was transmitted live for the first time, giving viewers a chance to see suddenly enlivened legislators call for free elections and criticize the Communist leadership Such changes are appreciated by East Germans, many of whom used to watch West German television to get a feel of what was happening in their country and the world. `` I never used to watch the <PERSON> Aktuelle </PERSON> <PERSON> Kamera </PERSON>,'' taxi driver <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Schimansky </PERSON> said of the main evening news show. `` But now, I watch it all the time, because I find it keeps me better informed about what is happening here than West German TV does.'' The new-found boldness in reporting also has made reading the newspaper more rewarding. `` I used to be through the newspaper in five minutes,'' said the 46-year-old Schimansky, as he dropped off a passenger near the Checkpoint Charlie crossing point to the West. `` Now, I need about two hours.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0044EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Germany-Opposition     11-15 0862</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Germany-Opposition,0888</SECOND>
<HEAD>For Opposition, Opening of Berlin Wall a Bittersweet Victory</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-East Germany</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ALISON SMALE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LEIPZIG, East Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In the grimy birthplace of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s peaceful revolution, the opening of the <ORGANIZATION> Berlin </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Wall </ORGANIZATION> was a bittersweet victory for the opposition. `` We're really afraid of a sellout to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Falk </PERSON> <PERSON> Hocquel </PERSON>, a leader of <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s branch of New Forum, the biggest opposition group. `` This opening of the border came too quickly, it was chaotic,'' <PERSON> Hocquel </PERSON> said. `` We see a real danger that the big firms move in here and <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> becomes the poorhouse of <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION>. Our people will go and work illegally in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> for six months to get hard currency, then come back. We have no interest in being bought out by big business.'' <PERSON> Hocquel </PERSON>'s ideals strike a chord among many in this polluted industrial center, <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s second-largest city and the throbbing heart of its astounding popular revolt. Many East Germans are proud of what they have achieved in 40 years of communism and are uneasy at the thought of being taken over by their rich brothers in the West. In recent weeks, they have been strongly politicized, but `` they are nonetheless susceptible to Western wealth. This economically strong nation is our great danger,'' <PERSON> Hocquel </PERSON> said. The opposition thus counted it a victory that, after a weekend in which 3 million East Germans went West _ many for the first time in 28 years, at least 200,000 marched in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> Monday night to demand free elections and shout anti-Communist slogans. But the real test of popular belief in New Forum as a political movement will come Saturday, when the group is host to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s first legal opposition assembly on <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>'s market square. `` Before the opening of the borders, I would have said half a million people would come,'' <PERSON> Hocquel </PERSON> said. `` Now, I do n't know. I hope at least 300,000.'' New Forum, formed only in September as a national movement, has said it plans to contest the free elections promised by the Communists and due in 1991. But the group, which is far more organized in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> than in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, is trying to put the brake on calls for a vote next spring. It argues that fall 1990 is the earliest point it and other parties could stand on meaningful platforms. To a foreigner, the call for an orderly, slower reform may sound typically German. To East Germans baffled by the stunning changes of one short month, it sounds like a sensible breathing space and a chance to avoid mistakes. Reunification, they feel, should not be high on the political agenda. `` That's not a theme until the people here have really created something new,'' said <PERSON> Christian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fuehrer </PERSON>, vicar of the <PERSON> Nikolai </PERSON> church whose weekly prayers for peace became the kernel of a mass pro-democracy demonstration. `` For 40 years,'' Fuehrer said, `` our identity was only three initials _ DDR -LRB- <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> -RRB-. `` Now, we have to learn our history which for years in schools here started with the revolution in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> in 1917. We must know what is German. Then, maybe you can talk about reunification. But it's not something that can just be ordered, then administered. We've seen where that led for 40 years.'' The deep disillusionment with four decades of false promises and hardship comes through far more strongly in <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> than in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. `` Pure frustration drove these people onto the streets,'' said <PERSON> Uwe </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreilich </PERSON>, 32, a <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> member who has taken part in every Monday demonstration of the past two months. `` People were simply sick of being told what to do in every little thing,'' <PERSON> Dreilich </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION> added a special factor to that despair. As second city, it has always had a great rivalry with <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> and resented the resources poured into the capital and denied the provinces. Residents complain of polluted air and decrepit, peeling buildings. Side by side with a vibrant intellectual community are hundreds of thousands of workers toiling in outdated, polluting factories and thoroughly discontent with the rewards. `` For 28 years, we allowed ourselves to be oppressed,'' said <PERSON> Maria </PERSON> <PERSON> Mueller </PERSON>, 43, from a small town outside <LOCATION> Leipzig </LOCATION>. She has been marching for more democracy for the past eight Mondays. `` They exploited us,'' she said of the Communists. `` They grumble about capitalism, but they are much worse. And when I saw the police lined up here Oct. 9, I thought we got another 1938 -LRB- when the <ORGANIZATION> Nazis </ORGANIZATION> assumed power -RRB-. The only difference was the uniforms.'' Such strong sentiments feed opposition hopes that the peaceful revolution can achieve much more than last weekend's massive East-West border bash. `` After 40 years in the ghetto, the lid is off, and of course the people want out,'' Fuehrer said. `` But for me as a churchman, things like the promise to an alternative to military service, something we fought for for 28 years, are more important than drinking beer on the Kudamm,'' he said, referring to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>'s main street. `` The beer goes, but these real changes remain. Every hand and thinking head is needed here now.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0046EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-German-Economy     11-15 0882</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-German-Economy,0911</SECOND>
<HEAD>Open Borders Mean New Economic Hazards for Both Germanys</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Wednesday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BERLIN (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The opening of <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s borders has exposed troubling economic hazards for both Germanys. The sight of millions of East Germans visiting <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> gives a hint of the onslaught that could result if living standards fail to rise to meet the growing expectations of East Germans. <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> fears being further impoverished by West Germans using hard-currency clout to buy up property or subsidized goods in an accessible Eastern market. But <ORGANIZATION> Deutsche </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Herrhausen </PERSON> predicts that with market-oriented reforms, `` I'm convinced that <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> can reach our Western living standards within the next five to 10 years.'' <PERSON> Herrhausen </PERSON>'s forecast and <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>'s promise of massive aid in the style of the postwar <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> Plan demonstrate the strength of West German interest in rebuilding the East German economy. But even with the best of intentions, the East German problems may be insurmountable. East Germans can rarely be reached by phone from the West because the hopelessly insufficient network is subject to breakdowns and equipment shortages. Consumers wait years to buy smoke-spewing Trabant and <ORGANIZATION> Wartburg </ORGANIZATION> cars that are the butt of jokes in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, where the wheels of preference are the luxury Mercedes and BMW. Fresh fruit is seldom more than a memory in winter. Refrigerators, TVs and VCRs can cost several months' salary and break down two weeks later. Euphoria over travel freedom could quickly give way to frustration as East Germans discover firsthand the vast difference between their meager, burdened lifestyles and the prosperity of Western neighbors. And <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s constitutionally mandated practice of granting citizenship to ethnic Germans keeps the door wide open to permanent settlement in the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION>. More than 200,000 East Germans have fled to <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> this year, emptied of hope their nation could ever provide them with the life available next door. The deluge has ebbed considerably since the Stalinist controls on travel fell Thursday, but <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION> recognizes the risks involved if reforms should fail. Economics Minister <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Haussmann </PERSON> on Tuesday offered an aid package for <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> if the new leadership converts to a market system. But a leading East German economist, <PERSON> Karl </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgenstern </PERSON>, said a free-market system is not the goal of his socialist state. Reform-oriented leaders in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> have not indicated how or when they will consider the critical step toward conversion to a hard-currency system. Even the most optimistic economists doubt a convertible East German mark could be achieved before the end of the century. Because the state needs to generate enough hard currency to buy priority equipment and commodities, it is forced to sell goods for export at only 15 percent of the cost of production, Finance Minister <PERSON> Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoefner </PERSON> disclosed Monday. Limited hard currency also puts up an effective ban on travel to the <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> in the place of the physical one removed. `` In principle the people are free to travel, but in reality without the funds to do so they are still behind the barriers,'' said <PERSON> Manfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Milzer </PERSON>, an economist with the West German federal <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economics </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>. He said the West German government must kick in billions of marks to a travel fund to take the pressure off <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> while it reforms industries. Major West German firms have long eyed the potential for joint ventures, but most plans hinge on changes that are to far from socialist principles to be acceptable to the East German authorities. <PERSON> Erwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Flick </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Siemens </ORGANIZATION>' <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> division said the electronics giant would love to work with <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> to revamp the antiquated phone system. `` But the conditions that have long hindered investment remain. Absolutely nothing in a legal or economic sense has changed,'' <PERSON> Flick </PERSON> said. On the side of optimism, however, the automotive giant <ORGANIZATION> Daimler-Benz </ORGANIZATION> plans to send a delegation to <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> within a few days to discuss the prospects for joint production of passenger cars, said spokesman <PERSON> Matthias </PERSON> <PERSON> Kleinert </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION>. Some investors fear the exodus of young workers _ a body blow to the already labor-short state _ further damages the prospect for improving productivity. `` <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> already had a critical demographic problem of an over-aged population, and the refugees have sharpened this development,'' said <PERSON> Wolfgang </PERSON> <PERSON> Stinglwagner </PERSON>, an economist with the <ORGANIZATION> Inter-German </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Affairs </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Bonn </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hoefner </PERSON>, the <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> finance minister, disclosed the national debt was the equivalent of more than $ 70 billion, worse than Western economists had imagined. East German officials and opposition activists alike have expressed fears that a hard-currency hunger could result in a two-class system in <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>: those with foreign money and those without. West German marks already command the best goods on the shortage-plagued market, and East Germans are worried they could be `` bought out'' unless customs controls are invoked. Prime real estate in central <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> may be opened up on the East side if the Communist government dismantles the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall's security zone That could ease the shortage of building land in both sectors of <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>. But the East has too little money to embark on major new capital investments, and Western investors still lack the confidence in the stability of East German reforms to commit funds for construction.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0047EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-EthnicAlbanians CLARIFICATION   11-15 0169</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Ethnic Albanians, CLARIFICATION,0169</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eds, papers that published a story slugged PM-Yugoslavia-Protest,
a0546 of Nov. 2, may wish to publish the following.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In a dispatch Nov. 2, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> identified 15 ethnic Albanians on trial in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> province as `` separatists'' but neglected to attribute the term to certain authorities. The 15, who include former <ORGANIZATION> Kosovo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> leader <PERSON> Azem </PERSON> <PERSON> Vlasi </PERSON>, are charged with `` counterrevolutionary activities'' in connection with ethnic Albanian protests in <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>. The term separatists has been applied to the 15 by some authorities in the Yugoslav republic of <LOCATION> Serbia </LOCATION>, of which <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION> is part, who claim the ethnic Albanians sought to make the province part of neighboring <LOCATION> Albania </LOCATION>. The term should have been attributed to those authorities. About 85 percent of <LOCATION> Kosovo </LOCATION>'s population are Albanians and most are described as favoring a restoration of the autonomy the claim they lost with recent constitutional changes. But there is no evidence that the majority favors separating from <LOCATION> Yugoslavia </LOCATION> to become part of <LOCATION> Albania </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Names     11-15 0956</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Names,1009</SECOND>
<HEAD>Names in the News</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto NY14</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress and comedian <PERSON> Whoopi </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> turned 40 and became a grandmother _ all in one day. Her 15-year-old daughter, <PERSON> Alexandria </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON>, gave birth Monday to a 6-pound, 15-ounce girl at a hospital in <LOCATION> Berkeley </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, said <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Cafarelli </PERSON>, Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s publicist. Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> was at her daughter's side when <PERSON> Amarah </PERSON> <PERSON> Skye </PERSON> <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> came into the world, said <PERSON> Cafarelli </PERSON>. `` They are all doing fine,'' he said. Last month, Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON> said she thought the decision of her unmarried daughter to have a baby was `` the absolute wrong thing.'' But she said she was happy that her daughter was `` confident enough in me to tell me'' that she was pregnant. Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>'s disclosure came on `` The Joan Rivers Show,'' according to a news release from the talk show's producers. Miss <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, nominated for an Academy Award for her role in `` The Color Purple,'' recently finished the movie `` Ghost'' with <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Swayze </PERSON> and <PERSON> Demi </PERSON> <PERSON> Moore </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The other actresses performed risque, off-camera gags to make <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> laugh during a scene in `` Steel Magnolias,'' according to <PERSON> Sally </PERSON> <PERSON> Field </PERSON>. `` There was one scene where <PERSON> Dolly </PERSON> was by herself, and she was supposed to be looking off-camera and giggling,'' <PERSON> Field </PERSON> said in December's Redbook. `` To help her laugh, we did things that would have caused us to be blackmailed forever! ... They should have filmed us and released the footage to porno shops. The crew crawled away in mortification,'' she said. <PERSON> Parton </PERSON> said the director, <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Ross </PERSON>, seemed to have a hard time adjusting to the predominantly female cast, which also includes <PERSON> Shirley </PERSON> <PERSON> MacLaine </PERSON>, <PERSON> Olympia </PERSON> <PERSON> Dukakis </PERSON> and <PERSON> Daryl </PERSON> <PERSON> Hannah </PERSON>. `` I think he was really scared working with all these women _ scared that we'd all have PMS -LRB- premenstrual syndrome -RRB- at the same time!'' said <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>. `` <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> was hard on me because I was n't as skilled in acting as the others. He told me I could n't act.'' <PERSON> Parton </PERSON>, characteristically, handled the criticism with aplomb. `` I said, ` Well, hell, I know I ca n't act. It's your job to teach me how. You hired me to make money for you.'''
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>SANTA MONICA, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Actress-exercise guru <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> is leading a celebrity entourage at a benefit tonight for an environmental protection initiative. `` We have to find a way to reverse this trend of pollution in our water and food and air, not to mention in the rest of the world,'' Miss <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> said. The sold-out event for the Environmental Protection Initiative of 1990 features performances by <PERSON> Bonnie </PERSON> <PERSON> Raitt </PERSON> and <PERSON> Ry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooder </PERSON>. Those willing to plunk down an extra $ 250 will be able to rub elbows with Miss <PERSON> Fonda </PERSON> and the performers during a post-concert reception. The statewide initiative would ban certain pesticides, reduce the use of gases that deplete the Earth's protective ozone layer, and prevent oil drilling near the coast.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Planned Parenthood President <PERSON> Faye </PERSON> <PERSON> Wattleton </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> West </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Point </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cadet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brigade </ORGANIZATION> Commander <PERSON> Kristin </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> are among the dozen 1989 `` Women of the Year'' named in December's Glamour magazine. <PERSON> Wattleton </PERSON> was chosen for defending the rights of women, `` especially poor ones, who would not have the money to travel for a safe abortion if terminating a pregnancy were illegal in their state.'' <PERSON> Baker </PERSON>, 21, was honored for `` breaking through one more bastion of maleness'' by becoming the first female cadet brigade commander in West Point's 187-year history. The others are: _ <PERSON> Candice </PERSON> <PERSON> Bergen </PERSON> and <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> English </PERSON>, the star and executive producer of TV's `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>. _ The `` Central Park jogger,'' who was nearly killed by marauding youths April 19 but since has made a slow recovery _ <PERSON> Takako </PERSON> <PERSON> Doi </PERSON>, leader of the <ORGANIZATION> Japanese </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Socialist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Arlie </PERSON> <PERSON> Hochschild </PERSON>, sociologist and author of `` The Second Shift. _ <PERSON> Iris </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON>, pharmaceutical chemist and expert in AIDS drug testing _ Dr <PERSON> Elizabeth </PERSON> <PERSON> Morgan </PERSON>, who spent two years in jail to rather than hand over her daughter in a custody fight. _ <ORGANIZATION> Euzhan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palcy </ORGANIZATION>, director of the movie `` A Dry White Season. _ <PERSON> Diane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sawyer </PERSON>, the TV newswoman _ <PERSON> Wendy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wasserstein </PERSON>, Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former porn movie star <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Reems </PERSON> was placed on five years' probation and ordered to pay back taxes after pleading guilty to failing to pay income tax on $ 35,000 in movie earnings. The star of such films as `` Deep Throat'' and `` The Devil in Miss <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>,'' also must cooperate with the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> in paying fines and interest on the taxes owed, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Consuelo </PERSON> <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> ruled Monday. <PERSON> Reems </PERSON>, 41, must take part in an alcohol detoxification program and undergo psychological counseling, <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Reems </PERSON>, whose real name is <PERSON> Herbert </PERSON> <PERSON> Streicher </PERSON>, said he already has made progress in an alcohol treatment program in <LOCATION> Utah </LOCATION> where he now works as a real estate salesman. <PERSON> Reems </PERSON> was indicted in June for failing to file adequate tax returns for the years 1982, 1984 and 1985.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told troubled teen-agers that everything happens for a purpose _ even bad things. `` I know you have n't had it easy,'' <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> said Tuesday to more than 120 teen-agers at Covenant House. `` There must have been times when you wondered if anyone cared.'' `` People do care,'' he assured them. `` I care about you and that's why I'm here.'' Covenant House shelters about 25,000 runaway, homeless or neglected children each year. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> told the youths that when he was young his family was poor and his father was an alcoholic. `` There were nights when I was angry and frustrated and wondered, ` Why?''' But he said he was helped by his mother, who insisted `` everything happens for a reason. ... Down the road something good will happen, and you'll realize it was for the best.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0127EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens-List     11-15 0699</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens-List,0786</SECOND>
<HEAD>List of Week's TV Shows Ratings</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Nielsens</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Here are the prime-time television ratings as compiled by the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> for the week of Nov. 6-12. Top 20 listings include the week's ranking, with full season-to-date ranking in parentheses, rating for the week, and total homes. An `` X'' in parentheses denotes one-time-only presentation. A rating measures the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million TV homes. 1. -LRB- 2 -RRB- `` The Cosby Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 26.5 rating, 24.4 million homes. 2. -LRB- 3 -RRB- `` Cheers,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.3, 22.4 million homes. 3. -LRB- 4 -RRB- `` A Different World,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 24.1, 22.2 million homes. 4. -LRB- 1 -RRB- `` Roseanne,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 23.3, 21.5 million homes. 5. -LRB- 5 -RRB- `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.8, 19.2 million homes. 6. -LRB- 7 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 20.1, 18.5 million homes. 7. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` Empty Nest,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.3 million homes. 7. -LRB- 8 -RRB- `` Dear <PERSON> John </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 19.9, 18.3 million homes. 9. -LRB- 9 -RRB- `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 19.4, 17.5 million homes. 10. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` Unsolved Mysteries,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.4 million homes. 10. -LRB- 6 -RRB- `` Wonder Years'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.9, 17.4 million homes. 12. -LRB- 14 -RRB- `` NFL Monday Night Football: Saints vs 49ers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Small Sacrifices'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Sunday Night Movie,'' 18.1, 16.7 million homes. 12. -LRB- 12 -RRB- `` Who's the Boss?'', <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 18.1, 16.7 million homes. 15. -LRB- 11 -RRB- `` Murder, She Wrote,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 17.6, 16.2 million homes. 16. -LRB- X -RRB- `` When He's Not A Stranger'' _ `` CBS Monday Movie Special,'' 17.2, 15.8 million homes. 17. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Matlock </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 17.0, 15.7 million homes. 18. -LRB- 15 -RRB- `` In the Heat of the Night,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 16.0, 14.7 million homes. 19. -LRB- 17 -RRB- `` Growing Pains,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.9, 14.6 million homes. 20. -LRB- 45 -RRB- `` Manhunt: Search For Night Stalker,'' _ `` NBC Sunday Night Movie,'' 15.4, 14.2 million homes.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 21. -LRB- 21 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2. 21. -LRB- 13 -RRB- `` Chicken Soup,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.2. 23. -LRB- 20 -RRB- `` Head of the Class,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 15.0. 24. -LRB- 23 -RRB- `` Full House,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.8. 25. -LRB- 19 -RRB- `` Cross of Fire,'' Part 2, _ `` <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Movie,'' 14.7. 25. -LRB- 22 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Doogie </PERSON> <PERSON> Howser </PERSON>, M.D.,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.7. 27. -LRB- 32 -RRB- `` ALF,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.6. 28. -LRB- 33 -RRB- `` Amen,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 28. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` Midnight Caller,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.4. 30. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Jake </PERSON> and The Fatman,'' CBS, 14.2. 31. -LRB- 62 -RRB- `` Polly'' _ `` <ORGANIZATION> Magical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.1. 32. -LRB- 29 -RRB- `` The <PERSON> Hogan </PERSON> Family,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 14.0. 33. -LRB- 26 -RRB- `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.9. 34. -LRB- 27 -RRB- `` Knots Landing,'' CBS, 13.8. 35. -LRB- 28 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON>,'' CBS, 13.7. 36. -LRB- 31 -RRB- `` Major Dad,'' CBS, 13.6. 37. -LRB- 36 -RRB- `` 20 @ 20,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 13.2. 38. -LRB- 38 -RRB- `` Family Matters,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.9. 38. -LRB- 25 -RRB- `` The Return of <PERSON> Sam </PERSON> <PERSON> McCloud </PERSON>,'' _ `` CBS Sunday Movie,'' 12.9. 40. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Dallas </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 12.7. 40. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` Perfect Strangers,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.7. 42. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` MacGyver,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.6. 43. -LRB- 41 -RRB- `` Anything But Love,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 12.0. 44. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` 227,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 44. -LRB- 39 -RRB- `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.8. 46. -LRB- 46 -RRB- `` Just The Ten Of Us,'' 11.7. 46. -LRB- 51 -RRB- `` Rescue 911,'' CBS, 11.7. 48. -LRB- 55 -RRB- `` My Two Dads - Wednesday,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.6. 49. -LRB- 53 -RRB- `` Married ... With Children,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 11.3. 50. -LRB- 42 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.1. 51. -LRB- 59 -RRB- `` Baywatch,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 11.0. 52. -LRB- 48 -RRB- `` 48 Hours: Sex Under 17,'' CBS, 10.7. 53. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Paradise,'' CBS, 10.6. 54. -LRB- 61 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> Falcon </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Crest </LOCATION>,'' CBS, 10.4. 54. -LRB- 57 -RRB- `` Wiseguy,'' CBS, 10.4. 56. -LRB- 66 -RRB- `` Quantum Leap,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 10.3. 57. -LRB- 65 -RRB- `` Hardball,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 57. -LRB- 68 -RRB- `` <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>'s Most Wanted,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 9.9. 59. -LRB- 64 -RRB- `` Mancuso: <ORGANIZATION> FBI </ORGANIZATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.6. 60. -LRB- 60 -RRB- `` Young Riders,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 9.5. 61. -LRB- 63 -RRB- `` Top Of <LOCATION> The </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>, 9.4. 62. -LRB- 74 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromwell </PERSON>'' _ `` ABC Mystery Movie,'' 9.0. 63. -LRB- 70 -RRB- `` Totally Hidden Video,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 8.6. 64. -LRB- 77 -RRB- `` Mission: Impossible,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.3. 65. -LRB- 75 -RRB- `` Snoops,'' CBS, 8.1. 65. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Life Goes On,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 8.1. 67. -LRB- 58 -RRB- `` Island Son,'' CBS, 7.9. 67. -LRB- 80 -RRB- `` Tour of Duty,'' CBS, 7.9. 69. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Mr. <PERSON> Belvedere </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 69. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Open House,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 7.0. 71. -LRB- 72 -RRB- `` Primetime Live,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 6.8. 72. -LRB- 76 -RRB- `` Peaceable Kingdom,'' CBS, 6.7. 73. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Booker </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.6. 74. -LRB- 83 -RRB- `` Saturday Night With <PERSON> Connie </PERSON> <PERSON> Chung </PERSON>,'' CBS, 6.5. 74. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` COPS,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.5. 76. -LRB- X -RRB- `` ABC News Special - Freedom Week,'' 6.3. 77. -LRB- 89 -RRB- `` 21 Jump Street,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 6.0. 77. -LRB- 78 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Wolf </PERSON>,'' CBS, 5.7. 78. -LRB- 81 -RRB- `` Living Dolls,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>, 5.7. 80. -LRB- 86 -RRB- `` Alien Nation,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.3. 81. -LRB- 90 -RRB- `` Reporters,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 5.0. 82. -LRB- 91 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Tracey </PERSON> <PERSON> Ullman </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 4.3. 83. -LRB- 92 -RRB- `` <PERSON> Garry </PERSON> <PERSON> Shandling </PERSON> Show,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 3.1. 84. -LRB- 93 -RRB- `` Beyond Tomorrow,'' <ORGANIZATION> FOX </ORGANIZATION>, 2.9.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0130EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Nielsens     11-15 0406</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Nielsens,0418</SECOND>
<HEAD>Cosby Leads NBC to Another Big Ratings Victory</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JERRY BUCK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The latest weekly <PERSON> Nielsen </PERSON> ratings were filled with smiles as eight comedies, six of them <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s, were at the top. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> took a big lead for the week, in which the ratings chart looked like a virtual rerun of the previous week. Eight shows in the top 10 were repeats from the week before. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> also had the three top-rated shows with `` The Cosby Show'' first, `` Cheers'' second and `` A Different World'' third. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Roseanne'' was fourth <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> survey with an average prime-time rating of 15.4 to <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s 12.7 and CBS' 11.8. Each point represents the percentage of the nation's 92.1 million homes with televisions. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> also took a lead in the November sweeps. Month-long sweeps occur three times a year and result in tough competition between networks. Advertising rates are based on the audience levels during the periods. The ratings for the first 11 days of sweeps: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 15.2, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.2, tied. After `` Roseanne,'' the rest of the top 10 were: <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <LOCATION> L.A. </LOCATION> Law,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Dear John'' and `` Empty Nest'' tied, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` 60 Minutes,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Unsolved Mysteries'' and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` The Wonder Years'' tied <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Small Sacrifices,'' in which <PERSON> Farrah </PERSON> <PERSON> Fawcett </PERSON> played a woman convicted of killing one of her own children, was the top-ranked non-regular show. It tied for 12th place with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Monday Night Football and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Who's the Boss?'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Manhunt: The Search for the Night Stalker,'' up against `` Small Sacrifices'' and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>' `` The Return of <PERSON> McCloud </PERSON>,'' on Sunday, was 20th. `` McCloud'' tied for 39th place with <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Family Matters.'' In its final broadcast, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` Chicken Soup'' tied for 21st place with <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` <PERSON> Hunter </PERSON>.'' `` Chicken Soup,'' which starred comedian <PERSON> Jackie </PERSON> <PERSON> Mason </PERSON>, will be replaced next week by the return of `` Coach.'' The time period is pre-empted this Tuesday by the final chapter of `` Small Sacrifices.'' The last part of the revolving wheel of the <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Saturday Mystery Movie, `` <PERSON> Christine </PERSON> <PERSON> Cromwell </PERSON>,'' made its debut last week in 43rd place. The show stars <PERSON> Jaclyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s `` World News Tonight'' kept its lead among the evening news shows. On Thursday, when the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> Wall was opened and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Brokaw </PERSON> was the only anchorman there, the ratings were <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 12.0, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 10.3, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 10.1 The ratings for the week: <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> 11.1, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> 10.3, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> 10.0.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NavyAccidents-List     11-15 0453</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Navy Accidents-List,430</SECOND>
<HEAD>Navy Has 10 Serious Accidents in Three Weeks</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Navy Accidents, Bjt</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>'s order to suspend most training activities for 48 hours over a three-day period for a safety review follows 10 serious accidents in less than three weeks. The order was issued Tuesday, about six hours after fire broke out on the <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inchon </ORGANIZATION>, an amphibious assault ship undergoing maintenance at the shipyard in <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, headquarters of the <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION>. Also Tuesday, an F-14 crashed into the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> 60 miles northwest of Key West, <LOCATION> Fla </LOCATION>. The two-man crew bailed out and was not seriously injured. At the same time, a technician at the Naval Surface Weapons Testing Center in <LOCATION> White </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Oak </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Md. </LOCATION>, was slightly injured when two grams of an experimental explosive detonated in a laboratory. Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, an <ORGANIZATION> Atlantic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Fleet </ORGANIZATION> spokesman, said 23 sailors and eight civilians were injured and were taken to six hospitals from the <LOCATION> Norfolk </LOCATION> fire. At least one victim was listed in serious condition. Since the run of mishaps started Oct. 29, 10 people have been killed or lost at sea and at least 53 people have been injured. Between Jan. 1 and Nov. 1, the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> counted 101 `` operation and training related'' fatalities in the service, including 47 in the explosion aboard the USS Iowa on April 19. The most serious of the recent accidents occurred Oct. 29 when a jet pilot making his first landing on an aircraft carrier crashed into the <LOCATION> USS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> in the Gulf of <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>. The pilot and four others on deck the ship were killed. Other incidents include: _ A <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> reserve pilot flying an A-7E jet crashed Nov. 9 into an apartment complex in <LOCATION> Smyrna </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Ga. </LOCATION>, killing two civilians and injuring two others, including himself _ Three sailors and a reported $ 4 million worth of non-nuclear missiles were swept by a wave from the aircraft carrier USS Eisenhower near <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hatteras </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> N.C. </LOCATION> on Nov. 1 One sailor was presumed dead. _ Nine sailors were treated for burns or smoke inhalation when fire erupted in the boiler aboard the <LOCATION> USS </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Monongahela </LOCATION>, some 500 miles west of <LOCATION> Gibraltar </LOCATION> on Nov. 1 _ An F-A-18 pilot dropped a 500-pound bomb on the guided missile cruiser USS Reeves in the <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION>, causing minor injuries to five sailors and blowing a 5-foot hole in the ship's bow Oct. 30 _ A sailor aboard the aircraft carrier <ORGANIZATION> USS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carl </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Vinson </ORGANIZATION> fell into the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> about 620 miles north of <LOCATION> Wake </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> Oct. 30 and was presumed lost _ Over the Nov. 11-12 weekend, one man was killed and five were injured when the USS Kinkaid, a destroyer, collided off the coast of <LOCATION> Malaysia </LOCATION> with a 430-foot freighter
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Congress-Cambodia     11-15 0315</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Congress-Cambodia,0323</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bill Would Restrict U.S. Military Aid to Cambodian Rebels</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> has acted to restrict the use of <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> money to arm the non-communist guerrillas fighting the Vietnamese-backed government in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, according to a published report. A bill awaiting final passage would prevent President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> from using the agency's contingency funds to send weapons to the guerrillas unless he first gets approval from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported in its Wednesday editions. Ordinarily, the administration does not need such approval to use <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> contingency funds. The restriction is part of a secret appendix to the military appropriations bill for the current fiscal year, <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> said. The bill has emerged from a <ORGANIZATION> House-Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> committee </ORGANIZATION> and is awaiting final action by both houses. The non-communist guerrillas in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> belong to two groups that are linked in a loose coalition with the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION>, which murdered up to 2 million people when it ruled <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> between 1975 and 1979. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> opposes a return to power by the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> but favors the non-communist resistance, which Vice President <PERSON> Dan </PERSON> <PERSON> Quayle </PERSON> has called `` the best hope to see a political settlement occur in <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>.'' The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration has been providing food, medicine and other non-military aid to the non-communist guerrillas. In September, the <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> said the non-communist forces should be strengthened as a means of encouraging the <LOCATION> Phnom </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Penh </LOCATION> government to agree to share power. At that time, <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Boucher </PERSON> declined to say whether the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> was attempting to strengthen the rebel groups with military aid. Key members of the congressional appropriations committees strongly oppose any <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> military aid to the guerrillas, The Times reported. It quoted Sen. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> C. </PERSON> <PERSON> Byrd </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, as saying such aid could lead the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> into `` a major new military involvement in the wars of <LOCATION> Southeast </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0138EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-CivilRights     11-15 0564</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Civil Rights,560</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Lease on Life for Strife-Torn Civil Rights Panel Clears Committee</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE ROBINSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION>, torn by internal feuding and under fire in <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, would gain a six-month extension under legislation approved by the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Judiciary </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>. `` The time has come in this country to put the petty bickering and the waste of the taxpayers' money on the <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commission </ORGANIZATION> behind us,'' Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, <LOCATION> R-Wis </LOCATION>., told committee members Tuesday The commission will go out of business Nov. 30 unless <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> extends it. Republicans and Democrats critical of the strife that has wracked the panel have so far been unable to agree on the length of the extension. Approved by the committee, 25-9, was a Democratic-sponsored, six-month extension that would keep on the front burner the question of how to reshape the commission and end its long-running internal feuds. The committee turned down a Republican plan to allow the commission to go out of business for one day only, thus allowing the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration to dump any members it opposes. It then would be reconstituted for six years. The Republican plan, offered by <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON>, was similar to a version recommended to the committee by the <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration. `` We should not ram through a six-year bill in the closing days of this <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Rep. <PERSON> Don </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON>, D-Calif., chief supporter of the Democratic version He said he had initially sought a one-year extension but bowed to a proposal by Sen. <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Simon </PERSON>, D-Ill., to cut that time in half Twenty-five years ago, civil rights forces hailed the commission's hearings across the <LOCATION> South </LOCATION>, its ringing reports on racial injustice and its bold legislative proposals. `` It served as the conscience of the nation,'' says <PERSON> Ralph </PERSON> <PERSON> G. </PERSON> <PERSON> Neas </PERSON>, executive director of the <ORGANIZATION> Leadership </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Conference </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> on </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Civil </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rights </ORGANIZATION>. Over the last six years, however, the commission has been snarled in fierce internal fighting. Lately, Democrats and Republicans on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> have joined in slashing its budget. Controversy has dogged commission member <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, its former chairman. He most recently came under fire for a speech to a conservative group. The title was: `` Blacks? Animals? Homosexuals? What is a Minority?'' <PERSON> Allen </PERSON>, who is black, calls himself the only conservative on the commission and says he does `` not believe in coddling people.'' In a 6-1 vote, the commission branded the speech `` thoughtless, disgusting and unnecessarily inflammatory.'' `` Frankly, it is a waste of the taxpayers' money to continue the prattle that has been coming out of the commission for another six months,'' <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> said. `` We would be better off with no civil rights commission than with this civil rights commission.'' Hostile exchanges between <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> commission member <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> have been at the heart of the controversy, he said. Rep. <PERSON> Barney </PERSON> <PERSON> Frank </PERSON>, D-Mass., however, told the committee that `` anyone who was committed to the cause of civil rights who did not spend a lot of time disagreeing with chairman <PERSON> Allen </PERSON> would be derelict in his or her duty, since he is one of the more bizarre public officials in my memory. <PERSON> Sensenbrenner </PERSON> retorted that <PERSON> Berry </PERSON> `` has come up with some bizarre statements of her own.'' He said it was urgently necessary to take action to turn around the course of the commission. `` They have frankly made themselves into a national laughingstock,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0147EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-PensionRights     11-15 0592</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pension Rights,570</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pension Groups Encourage Workers to Know Their Rights</HEAD>
<HEAD>With PM-Pension Probe, Bjt</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDS: Addresses at end of article</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRYNA BRENNAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 `` Better safe than sorry'' is the motto of a public interest group that says Americans should act as watchdogs for their own pension plans. `` Like millions of Americans, a large part of your savings may be in a pension fund,'' says the Washington-based Pension Rights Center. `` But a Great Dane or a German Shepherd ca n't protect the money in your pension fund.'' The center publishes a booklet, which costs $ 6, titled `` Protecting Your Pension Money.'' It outlines your rights, as well as the rules that your pension plan's administrator must follow. Free pamphlets on the same subject are available from the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Retired </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Persons </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Whether or not you have a pension plan is up to your employer. Only 46 percent of the nation's privately employed, full-time workers are covered by private pension plans. And only 40 million of the 76 million people covered by those plans are insured by the government's <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guaranty </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>. Pensions for employees working in offices or shops with fewer than 25 employees are not insured by the federal government. Retirement benefits are most commonly based on the number of years worked and final salary. Most plans have age and service requirements before an employee can participate, and similar rules for when the pension can be collected. The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, known as ERISA, sets rules for pension plans. All pension plans differ, but overall you have the right to: _ Find out the overall status of your plan by requesting in writing from your employer a `` Summary Plan Description'' outlining your company's plan _ Ask your plan administrator for a copy of your employer's Summary Annual Report, which details your company's _ Obtain a copy of the company's Form 5500, a more detailed financial report, available on written request from the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> Those running your plan must follow a number of rules. Among the most important: _ Your plan managers are required to invest the money with your best interests in mind They may not make investments to benefit themselves or your employer, if these conflict with your interests. _ Administrative costs of running your plan must be reasonable _ To hedge against risks, managers ca n't put all the pension money into one investment, such as a single stock or one piece of real estate If it appears the rules have been broken, you should notify the <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION>. If you suspect the administrators have taken loans from the plan or had conflicts of interest, you should contact the Employee Plans Division of the <ORGANIZATION> Internal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Revenue </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investigation </ORGANIZATION> handles cases of kickbacks and embezzlement. `` The most effective way to convince government investigators to take a look at your problem is to provide them with a short summary of the problems you have found together with the supporting documents,'' the Pension Rights Center says. `` If you can not convince a government agency to investigate your plan, you might want to consider contacting a lawyer,'' it says.
</TEXT>
<NOTE>___</NOTE>
<TEXT>
 EDS: here are addresses for the groups named in this article: Pension Rights Center 918 16th Street NW Suite 704 <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> D.C. 20006 <ORGANIZATION> AARP </ORGANIZATION> Fulfillment 1909 K Street NW <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> D.C. 20049 <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pension </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Welfare </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Benefit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Division </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Information </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> 200 </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Constitution </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ave. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> NW </ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> D.C. 20210
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891115-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-11-15-89 0206EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-FarmScene     11-15 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Farm Scene,750</SECOND>
<HEAD>Holiday Turkey Prices Down; Hams More Expensive</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DON KENDALL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Farm Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Prices of holiday turkeys will be down from a year ago, but hams are going to be more expensive, the <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> says. `` Consumers will find adequate supplies of turkey and ham for the holiday season,'' the department's <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> reported Tuesday. `` Prices likely will be lower for turkeys but higher for hams than last year.'' <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> production in the fourth quarter may be up about 12 percent from a year ago, with frozen inventories up slightly. Ham supplies are expected to decline slightly despite an increase in cold-storage stocks. `` Total red meat and poultry production is expected to set a record in 1989 and again in 1990,'' the report said. `` Among the major components, only beef production may decline in 1989, reflecting the reduced cattle inventory.'' Looking to 1990, the report said beef production may increase somewhat because of more cattle going into feedlots before slaughter, resulting in more `` fed'' beef. `` In both years, pork output could remain relatively large,'' the report said. `` Broiler output will continue to grow'' because of improved profits in recent years. `` <LOCATION> Turkey </LOCATION> production also is expected to grow, but at a lower rate than broilers because returns are being squeezed.'' For producers, the report said more meat and poultry in 1990, along with `` weaker growth in per capita income,'' could put downward pressure on market prices. `` Increased red meats will be about offset by population growth,'' the report added. `` As a result, prices of choice-grade steers and -LRB- market hogs -RRB- should be a little above 1989's average. However, with higher per capita output, wholesale poultry prices are expected to decline moderately.'' Exports of beef and veal in 1989 could rise to a record of 1 billion pounds, up 46 percent from 1988 due largely to liberalization of the Japanese market, the report said. An additional increase of 12 percent to 15 percent is expected in 1990. Comparatively, total <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> beef production in 1989 is forecast at 22.8 billion pounds, and pork at 15.8 billion pounds. Imports of beef and veal, mostly from <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION>, are expected to decline about 8 percent this year from their 1988 level, mostly due to smaller supplies in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>. Declines are likely in 1990 because of smaller <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> shipments. Pork imports in 1989 are indicated at about 950 million pounds, down 16 percent from 1988, but those may rise to about 1 billion pounds in 1990 if Danish production continues to increase, the report said. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pork exports, mostly to <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>, are expected to be about 240 million pounds this year, up from 195 million in 1988. Those may decline to around 205 million pounds in 1990. Broiler exports may rise to a record of around 937 million pounds this year, up 22 percent from 1988. Most of the sales are commercial rather than under foreign aid and subsidy programs. Exports could decline slightly in 1990.
</TEXT>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
