<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 2341EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-Markets 4thLd-Writethru a0773 10-15 1041</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Markets, 4th Ld-Writethru, a0773,1065</SECOND>
<HEAD>Stock Prices Drop in Early Tokyo Trading, Then Stabilize</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 13 grafs to UPDATE with end of Tokyo morning session.
Picks up 12th graf, `The Federal...' A version moved on financial wires.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARIANN CAPRINO</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Wall Street braced for a possible battering Monday as aftershocks from its Friday the 13th plunge sent stocks and the dollar tumbling in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and other foreign exchanges before they steadied in later trading. The Nikkei Stock Average of 225 issues finished the morning session on the <ORGANIZATION> Tokyo </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> down 407.84 points, or 1.16 percent, from Friday's finish at 34,708.18. The average opened down about 600 points but later rose in light-volume trading. The dollar opened in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> at 139.95 yen, down sharply from Friday's closes of 144.00 yen in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and 142.05 yen in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>, but by late morning was quoted at 141.30 yen. <PERSON> Yozo </PERSON> <PERSON> Asai </PERSON>, an analyst with the brokerage <ORGANIZATION> Yamaichi </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Securities </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>, said there was some panic selling at the start of trading but the stock market was returning to stability. `` Market players in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> learned their lesson from Black Monday two years ago, so there will be no panic selling any more,'' <PERSON> Asai </PERSON> said. Market and government officials in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> continued their weekend-long huddle Sunday, mapping out strategies to prevent a financial disaster paralleling the events of two years ago, when the <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> plummeted 508 points on Oct. 19, Black Monday, after a 108-point drop the preceding Friday. `` After what happened ... the powers that be will do a lot to avoid a major sell-off,'' said <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tierney </PERSON>, a vice president at <ORGANIZATION> Shearson </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Lehman </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hutton </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc </ORGANIZATION>. The <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> activity was the first in a major foreign market following Friday's plunge on Wall Street and was expected to help set the tone for trading as it opened in other markets around the world. Share prices in <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> also fell, but not drastically, in opening trading Monday. On the <ORGANIZATION> Hong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Kong </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION>, prices declined about 6 percent, or 163 points to 2,619 in the first 10 minutes of trading. On the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Zealand </LOCATION> exchange, blue-chip stocks tracked by the Barclays Index ended the morning off 265 points _ 11.79 percent _ at 1984.85, the biggest fall since the 505 points of the October 1987 crash. <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION>'s main stock price index fell 8 percent in the first 20 minutes of trading but finished the morning down about 7 percent from Friday. In <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>, the market's weighted index was down about 1.3 percent in late morning activity, after initially declining by 2 percent. The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> stock market suffered its worst setback since the Black Monday crash when prices plunged in the final hour of trading last Friday and the <ORGANIZATION> Dow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Jones </ORGANIZATION> industrial average lost more than 190 points to finish at 2,569.26. Since 1987, takeover rumors and leveraged buyouts had pushed the market higher. But trouble with one of those deals Friday, the employee-management buyout of <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airines </ORGANIZATION> parent <ORGANIZATION> UAL </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, raised fears of problems in the `` junk bond'' financing market and sparked Friday's sell-off. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> sent signals over the weekend that it will move quickly to meet any demands for cash on Monday, when a deluge of sell orders is expected to hit the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets. `` We will be there with all the liquidity demand that is needed,'' said a senior <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> official who spoke on condition of anonymity. `` If there are any doubts about liquidity being available, there is no reason to be concerned.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s action could keep bankers from cutting off credit to brokerage houses and securities firms suffering heavy losses from a plunge in stock prices. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> official said the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> central bank had been in touch with central banks in <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> and had received assurances from them that those officials stood ready to supply needed cash in their countries to counteract any possible fallout from Friday's plunge in stock prices Officials at both the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Treasury </ORGANIZATION> were closely monitoring developments in the overseas markets, primarily <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Hong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Kong </LOCATION>. Developments in those markets could set the tone for how <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> markets perform when they open Monday morning. The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Stock </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Exchange </ORGANIZATION> planned to open its computers to receive orders at 7:30 a.m. EDT, an hour earlier than usual. Thousands of worried investors called sell orders into their brokers over the weekend, setting the stage for a flood of activity when Wall Street opens for business. The exchange plans to institute a service at the opening, which puts individual orders of up to 2,099 shares in front of big, institutional orders, said the <ORGANIZATION> NYSE </ORGANIZATION>'s chief spokesman <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Torrenzano </PERSON>. Normally, the service is offered only after the Dow moves up or down 25 points. `` You go on a red alert when there's a situation like Friday,'' said <ORGANIZATION> NYSE </ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman <PERSON> Sharon </PERSON> <PERSON> Gamsin </PERSON>. `` We want to pave the way for the system to operate as smooth as possible. We're not anticipating any problem.'' Once the market opens, a system of `` circuit breakers'' installed following the 1987 crash will automatically halt trading if the Dow rises or falls 250 points. <PERSON> Gamsin </PERSON> said the exchange intends to let the market `` go,'' rather than step in before the circuit breakers have a chance to work. Insiders say a drop on Wall Street might be cushioned if corporations and brokerages step in to buy stocks. After the crash two years ago, companies stepped in to purchase their own shares to bolster prices. Observers said the same thing could happen this time, with brokerages joining in to support the stocks they have been touting through the market's recent record-setting runup. Experts are quick to note that the economic landscape two years ago was markedly different. Higher interest rates and a weak dollar had the effect of `` creating expectations of a big economic slowdown'' and looming inflation, <PERSON> Tierney </PERSON> said. But lower interest rates, a strong dollar and continued growth are providing a firmer foundation this time around. `` People -LRB- have had -RRB- two days to sober to the fact that the economy is not falling apart,'' said <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Johnson </PERSON>, senior vice president at <ORGANIZATION> First </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Albany </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp </ORGANIZATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0109EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WorldSeries-Newspage     10-15 0285</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-World Series-Newspage,0299</SECOND>
<HEAD>Athletics 5, Giants 0 in Series Game 1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BEN WALKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Baseball Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>OAKLAND, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION>, showing the pitching and power that made them baseball's winningest team, dismissed the <ORGANIZATION> San </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Francisco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Giants </ORGANIZATION> 5-0 Saturday night in the World Series opener. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> pitched a five-hitter for his third postseason victory this year. He walked one and struck out six. <ORGANIZATION> Oakland </ORGANIZATION> roughed up National League earned run average leader <PERSON> Scott </PERSON> <PERSON> Garrelts </PERSON> for five runs in four innings. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Walt </PERSON> <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> each homered and the <ORGANIZATION> Athletics </ORGANIZATION> finished with 11 hits, including three by <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> McGwire </PERSON>. <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON>, the most valuable player in the American League playoffs, went 2-for-5 with a run-scoring single but did not steal a base after swiping a record eight in the playoffs. <PERSON> Will </PERSON> <PERSON> Clark </PERSON>, the National League playoff MVP, went 2-for-4. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON>, throwing 95 mph fastballs at twilight, had trouble only on balls hit back to him. <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> made a two-base throwing error on <PERSON> Robby </PERSON> <PERSON> Thompson </PERSON>'s comebacker in the first inning In the third, <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Uribe </PERSON> got an infield hit when <PERSON> Stewart </PERSON> failed to cleanly catch the ball and threw a shade late to first base. <PERSON> Dave </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> walked on five pitches to start the second and one-out singles by <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Steinbach </PERSON> and <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON> made it 1-0. With runners at first and third, <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> nubbed a slow grounder to first that <PERSON> Clark </PERSON> fielded, double-pumped and threw home to <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Kennedy </PERSON>. <PERSON> Steinbach </PERSON>, however, kicked the ball loose from his rival catcher's mitt for an error and was safe. <PERSON> Rickey </PERSON> <PERSON> Henderson </PERSON> singled home another run for a 3-0 lead. <PERSON> Parker </PERSON> homered to open the third and <PERSON> Weiss </PERSON> homered to lead off the fourth.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0139EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-NewYorkStorm     10-15 0286</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New York Storm,0295</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thurderstorms, Wind Rip Upstate New York, Kill 1</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRIS CAROLA</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ALBANY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Violent thunderstorms ripped across upstate <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Saturday with heavy rain, hail and wind up to 85 mph, knocking out power to thousands of homes and killing at least one person. A man was killed and three other people, including two boys, were slightly injured when their mobile home was blown several hundred feet from its foundation in McDonough, police said. A <ORGANIZATION> Canfield </ORGANIZATION>, <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>, man escaped injury when a gust of wind blew his single-engine <ORGANIZATION> Cessna </ORGANIZATION> aircraft onto its side as he was preparing for takeoff from <LOCATION> Niagara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Falls </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION>, police said. A sky diver who was aloft when the storm hit was yanked upward 1,500 feet in three seconds, said <LOCATION> Niagara </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Sheriff's Deputy <PERSON> Duane </PERSON> <PERSON> Jacobs </PERSON>. The parachutist, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Konstabel </PERSON>, 32, of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Seneca </LOCATION>, told police that when he hit the ground, he was dragged 300 feet across a barbed-wire fence and into some trees in the town of <LOCATION> Newfane </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Konstabel </PERSON> was reported in stable condition with injuries to his right leg in <ORGANIZATION> Erie </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Medical </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Buffalo </LOCATION>. After <PERSON> Konstabel </PERSON> began ascending he cut his main parachute away and descended using his reserve chute, said <PERSON> Henry </PERSON> <PERSON> Szczepanski </PERSON>, sky-diving instructor for <PERSON> Konstabel </PERSON>'s group. `` This thing just came across the lake and whacked us,'' <PERSON> Szczepanski </PERSON> said of the storm. Thousands of homes were left without electricity when power lines were downed from the <ORGANIZATION> Niagara </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Frontier </ORGANIZATION> to the <LOCATION> Vermont </LOCATION> state line. Winds reached as much as 85 mph in <LOCATION> Ithaca </LOCATION>, and in nearby Lansing the roof was blown off an apartment building, said <ORGANIZATION> Tompkins </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION>'s dispatcher <PERSON> Julie </PERSON> <PERSON> Morehouse </PERSON>. Two people were hurt.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0227EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-BusCrash 1stLd-Writethru a0617 10-15 0313</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Bus Crash, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0617,0319</SECOND>
<HEAD>Bus Crashes in Las Vegas, 42 Injured</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: NEW throughout with 42 injured, details. ADDS byline.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By TIM DAHLBERG</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LAS VEGAS (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A tour bus full of weekend gamblers flipped on its side on a rain-slickened highway in downtown <LOCATION> Las </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Vegas </LOCATION> on Saturday. Forty-two people were injured, none seriously, authorities said. The Scorpio Tours bus was carrying passengers from <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> when it crashed in the northbound lane of Interstate 15 at about 4 p.m. Driver <PERSON> Jose </PERSON> <PERSON> Luis </PERSON> <PERSON> Figuearera </PERSON>, 51, said through an interpreter he lost control when he braked for a car in front of him, officials said. They said the bus fell on its left side. `` I just saw a lot of cars getting tangled up. Then I saw a cloud of dust and the bus was in the middle of the cloud of dust and then it just went over on its side,'' said <PERSON> Malcolm </PERSON> <PERSON> Turner </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Clark </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> firefighter who was driving home when he saw the crash. A tractor-trailer rig following the bus also swerved out of control and collided with a car, but no injuries were reported. It was raining lightly. Passengers escaped through a rooftop escape hatch and the driver's broken windshield. The driver and 41 passengers were taken to five hospitals. The worst injury reported was a broken pelvis, said <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Forbuss </PERSON>, president of Mercy Ambulance. Listed on the back of the bus were two <LOCATION> Southern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> phone numbers for Scorpio Tours. <PERSON> Victor </PERSON> <PERSON> Enciso </PERSON>, who answered a phone call made to a <LOCATION> Claremont </LOCATION> number, said <ORGANIZATION> Scorpio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tours </ORGANIZATION> was owned by his aunt, <PERSON> Angelina </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>. A woman who answered at the number he gave said <PERSON> Angelina </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON> had been in a traffic accident in the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> area and was unavailable. There were no phone listings for Scorpio Tours in <LOCATION> Glendora </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Claremont </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0246EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u p AM-Hatfield     10-15 0272</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Hatfield,0283</SECOND>
<HEAD>Oregon Senator Will Seek Fifth Term</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRAD CAIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SILVERTON, Ore. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Declaring that he has an `` unfinished agenda,'' <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> Sen. <PERSON> Mark </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said Saturday night that he would run for a fifth term. The announcement by the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Republican </ORGANIZATION> ended months of speculation about the plans of the state's most popular politician. `` I've come to the conclusion that ours is an unfinished agenda,'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said told about 350 supporters. <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said he played a key role in fashioning the recent congressional compromise on harvest of old growth timber. Environmentalists had initally opposed harvesting any virgin timber on federal land; the compromise allows some logging. `` I will not rest until we have secured a long-term solution to our timber supply problems,'' <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, 67, also said that if re-elected he would work to provide better health care to Oregonians, to step up the fight against drugs, and to slow the nuclear arms race. Following a long-standing tradition, <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> made the announcement in <LOCATION> Silverton </LOCATION>, where he's launched all of his previous campaigns. Friends and political supporters of <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, including President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>, had encouraged the senator to run again. Gov. <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldschmidt </PERSON>, a Democrat, also asked him to run again. <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> won a seat in the <ORGANIZATION> Oregon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> in 1950 and was elected secretary of state in 1956. After two terms as governor, he was elected to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> in 1966. A formal Naval officer who was one of the first Americans to witness firsthand the aftermath of the atomic bombing of <LOCATION> Hiroshima </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> earned a reputation as a staunch foe of the <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> war.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0305EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-AgentsArrests     10-15 0305</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Agents Arrests,0318</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Official Charges ``Witch Hunt'' By Airline</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A union official said Saturday that allegations that <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Airways </ORGANIZATION> ticket agents kept ticket money are part of a `` witch hunt'' by the airline. Four ticket agents at <LOCATION> Kennedy </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> have been charged with stealing about $ 1,400, said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON>, a spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, which runs the airport. `` The <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> have determined that $ 48,000 is in fact missing,'' said <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON>. He said <ORGANIZATION> Port </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Authority </ORGANIZATION> detectives are investigating the four agents and and possibly others in the disappearance of the $ 48,000. <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON> had previously indicated that the four arrested were charged with stealing the total $ 48,000, but he said Saturday he was mistaken. The four agents were charged Friday with falsifying records and larceny for allegedly selling one-way tickets and keeping the cash instead of putting the money in the register, <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON> said. One of the agents, <PERSON> Cathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Alam </PERSON>, is charged with taking just $ 38, <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON> said. An official of the union that represents the agents blasted the charges, calling it part of a scheme by <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> to get rid of some union employees. `` I think this is just a witch hunt,'' said <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON>, vice president of Local 732 of the airline division of the <ORGANIZATION> Teamsters </ORGANIZATION>. `` I do n't think these people were involved in a sophisticated scam involving that amount of money,'' <PERSON> Miranda </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON> said $ 48,000 is missing in receipts for August and September and that <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Authority </LOCATION> detectives believe ticket agents may have been keeping cash payments for about a year. The investigation, conducted at the request of the airline, will continue and more arrests are expected, <PERSON> Cahill </PERSON> said. A <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Am </ORGANIZATION> spokesman did n't immediately respond to a telephone request for comment.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-US-Noriega     10-15 0464</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-US-Noriega,0484</SECOND>
<HEAD>British Daily Reports U.S. Soft On Noriega</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> administration is unable to get rid of <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>'s Gen. <PERSON> Manuel </PERSON> <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> because the military strongman has compromising films involving senior <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> officials, a British newspaper reported Sunday. The Sunday Correspondent, a new independent weekly, also said the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> asked <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> for help shipping arms to <LOCATION> Nicaragua </LOCATION>'s Contra rebels, according to secret documents declassified during the Iran-Contra investigation. `` The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>' relationship with the general is curious and raises disturbing questions,'' the paper said. The newspaper said that for years <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> invited senior officials from <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and administration to his <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> villa on the <LOCATION> Azuero </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. It did n't name any officials. There, he supplied his guests with girls or boys in bedrooms wired for sound and equipped with hidden cameras, the paper said. <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> stored the films `` as an insurance policy for the future,'' according to the newspaper. The weekly quoted <PERSON> Curtin </PERSON> <PERSON> Winsor </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Costa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Rica </LOCATION> from 1983 to 1985, as saying he received such an invitation from <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s brother in 1985. <PERSON> Winsor </PERSON> told the paper he checked out the invitation with <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Briggs </PERSON>, <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador to <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION>, who told him he would be spending the weekend in `` one of the most notorious ` honey-traps' in <LOCATION> Latin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> America </LOCATION>. The report said <PERSON> Winsor </PERSON> turned down his invitation but many other <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> officials accepted. `` I ca n't give you names, but look around,'' the weekly quoted <PERSON> Winsor </PERSON> as saying. `` Who's soft on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>? That's where you should look.'' The newspaper quoted <PERSON> Dick </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregorie </PERSON>, the former <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> prosecutor who brough drug-trafficking charges against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>, as saying he was disgusted by what he called the sham nature of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> war on drugs. The newspaper said documents released during the Iran-Contra trials showed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> wanted permission to use <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON>'s `` secret drugs and arms airfields.'' <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Blum </PERSON>, former counsel to the <ORGANIZATION> Senate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Relations </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION>, was quoted by the paper as saying, `` If drugs came back to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> as a result then the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> administration turned a blind eye.'' The paper also quoted <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> as saying the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> gave <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> `` all kinds of mixed signals,'' a mixture of public condemnation and private encouragement. <PERSON> Blum </PERSON> told the paper that a 1986 <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> policy review recommending strong action against <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> was shelved after `` higher levels'' told the department to forget it. The paper said Sen. <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Kerry </PERSON>, D-Mass., requested last year that the <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Accounting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> ask government agencies for information on <PERSON> Noriega </PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Security </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, however, banned any agency from giving out information, the paper said. The Sunday Correspondent is only five weeks old. It is not connected with any other British newspaper group but the <ORGANIZATION> Chicago </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Tribune </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Company </ORGANIZATION> is among its financial backers.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0342EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Keating-Babbitt     10-15 0259</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Keating-Babbitt,0267</SECOND>
<HEAD>Babbitt Says Keating Called for Aid in 1985</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PHOENIX (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Former Gov. <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> said Saturday that <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>. Chairman <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> contacted him in 1985 to ask him to intercede on <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>'s behalf against the nation's top thrift regulator `` Keating called me and said, ` <PERSON> Edwin </PERSON> <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> -LRB- then chairman of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Home </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- is getting on my back ... I want you to intervene,''' <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> said. `` I refused.'' <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> declined to comment on the matter involving <ORGANIZATION> Lincoln </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Savings </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Loan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Irvine </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>, an <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> subsidiary that was at the time at odds with the <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON>, who left office early in 1987 to seek the Democratic nomination for president, said <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> called only once. He said he was unaware at the time that other <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> politicians had received similar requests from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON>. <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> made his remarks to about 100 people at a <LOCATION> Phoenix </LOCATION> meeting sponsored by the citizens lobby Common Cause. American <ORGANIZATION> Continental </ORGANIZATION> filed for federal bankruptcy protection April 13, and the government took over <PERSON> Lincoln </PERSON> the next day. The thrift's failure, which regulators blame in part on risky ventures, eventually could cost taxpayers $ 1.1 billion to $ 2.5 billion. In 1985, <PERSON> Gray </PERSON> and <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> were battling over <PERSON> Gray </PERSON>'s support for a regulation that put strict limits on the amount of assets thrifts were allowed to invest directly in real estate, securities and other risky ventures without regulators' approval. <PERSON> Babbitt </PERSON> said he received one political contribution from <PERSON> Keating </PERSON> in 1982 but none during his presidential candidacy.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0345EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-BRF--TeenKilled     10-15 0160</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-BRF--Teen Killed,0165</SECOND>
<HEAD>Teen-ager Shot When Gun Accidentally Discharges</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CLAY, N.Y. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 14-year-old boy was killed Saturday when a friend holding a handgun accidently fired the weapon into the youth's chest, police said. <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Steber </PERSON> of <PERSON> Clay </PERSON> died at about 6:15 p.m. from a gunshot wound to the chest, according to <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Onondaga </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sheriff </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION>. Detectives said <PERSON> Steber </PERSON> and two friends were alone at a home owned by <PERSON> Gordon </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> when the shooting occurred shortly after 6 p.m. <PERSON> Steber </PERSON> was shot once with a .38 - caliber automatic handgun in a bedroom the private two-story house, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> <PERSON> Steber </PERSON> was dead at the scene when fire officials and paramedics arrived, police said. The two other youths who were with <PERSON> Steber </PERSON> were questioned, <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said, but no charges have been filed. <PERSON> Burns </PERSON> said the shooting was accidental. Police refused release the names of the two friends, their relationship with <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> or say who owned the weapon.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0348EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-CaponeHotel 1stLd-Writethru a0574 10-15 0660</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Capone Hotel, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0574,0676</SECOND>
<HEAD>Developer Plans to Restore Capone Hotel to Past Splendor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 2nd graf to delete INCORRECT reference to Alcatraz; pickup
3rd graf, `Today, the ...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotoCX2</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHARLES J. GANS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CHICAGO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A real estate developer is getting some help from the <ORGANIZATION> Feds </ORGANIZATION> in his quest to transform <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s former headquarters, once an opulent palace of sin, into a respectable hotel for business travelers. The Lexington Hotel, on <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>'s Near South Side, was the plush Prohibition Era haven where <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> ruled his criminal empire in the late 1920s and early'30s, before he was sent to federal prison on an income tax-evasion rap. Today, the abandoned building is a neighborhood eyesore, despite its city and federal landmark status. Broken liquor bottles litter the boarded-up main entrance, next to an abandoned blues bar. The masonry exterior is dotted with cracked terra cotta decorations and broken bay windows. Real estate developer <PERSON> Ganesan </PERSON> <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> wants to change all that. The Indian-born Visvabharathy plans to transform the 10-story building into a 258-suite hotel geared to business people attending events at the nearby McCormick Place exhibition center. <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> said he did n't know about the hotel's past when he responded to a real estate ad in June 1988. He bought the property for $ 600,000 from the <ORGANIZATION> Sunbow </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION>, a non-profit group that trains women for construction jobs. But <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> said <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s legacy was an added incentive for him to proceed with plans for the $ 28.6 million rehabiliation project. `` A lot of people would consider <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> something like a negative, but in my opinion that's exactly why you should use it as a positive thing to market the hotel,'' said <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> in a recent interview. `` If you go anywhere in the world, people may not know anything about <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION>, but they know <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>,'' said <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON>, 41, who left <LOCATION> India </LOCATION> in 1974 to study for his doctorate in business administration at the <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Illinois </ORGANIZATION>. Last month, the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Housing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Urban </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION> awarded an Urban Development Action <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> to the <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> rehab project. The $ 2.6 million grant will be used by the city to make a low-interest loan to <ORGANIZATION> Vilas </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Investment </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Properties </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION>, the real estate development company <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> started in 1982. A partnership formed by <PERSON> Vilas </PERSON>' company is investing $ 3 million and the remainder of the money will come from bank loans and city development bonds. Visvabharathy plans to begin construction in late November, and the restoration should be completed by November 1991. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> J. </PERSON> <PERSON> James </PERSON>, the commissioner of the city's <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Economic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Development </ORGANIZATION>, says he's excited about the project. `` It will breathe some new life into a neighborhood that we are very interested in,'' <PERSON> James </PERSON> said. `` If we can facilitate some tourism and interest using one of our more notorious former residents ... I can certainly live with that.'' The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> opened in 1892 and was one of the city's first high-rises. President <PERSON> Grover </PERSON> <PERSON> Cleveland </PERSON> honeymooned there and society's elite once danced on the lavish ballroom's tiled floors. When <PERSON> Capone </PERSON> made the hotel his headquarters, he occupied the fourth and fifth floors. Part of the hotel was converted to a brothel, and there was a network of underground tunnels and secret stairways. The <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> was renamed the New Michigan Hotel after World War II. A bordello and finally a flophouse, it was closed by court order in 1980. <PERSON> Visvabharathy </PERSON> says little is salvagable inside _ except for some tile flooring from the ballroom and tiles in the bathroom of <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s four-room suite. He plans to faithfully restore <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s suite, including its lavender bathtub, but it wo n't be rented out to guests. Instead, it will be a tourist attraction. In 1986, the <LOCATION> Lexington </LOCATION> drew attention when television's <PERSON> Geraldo </PERSON> <PERSON> Rivera </PERSON> blasted open a sealed basement chamber billed as <PERSON> Capone </PERSON>'s secret vault in a live TV broadcast All that was found were a few empty whiskey bottles and an old sign.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0401EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-SouthAfrica 6thLd-Writethru a0651 10-15 0683</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa, 6th Ld-Writethru, a0651,0702</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede JOHANNESBURG</HEAD>
<HEAD>ANC Leader Sisulu and 7 Others Freed From Prison</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS thruout to UPDATE with more Sisulu comment, color; CORRECTS
duration of Sisulu's imprisonment; Changes byline; No Pickup</HEAD>
<HEAD>By GREG MYRE</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SOWETO, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, senior leader of the <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and colleague of <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, was freed at dawn Sunday after 26 years in prison. Seven other political prisoners also were freed. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, the most prominent jailed leader of the outlawed guerrilla movement, remains in prison, although his release within the next months is widely expected. <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, 77, arrived under police escort at his home in <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION> and embraced his wife, <PERSON> Albertina </PERSON>, an activist who was under severe police restrictions until Friday. Youths who had been waiting for <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> lifted the white-haired, bespectacled black nationalist atop their shoulders before he went inside. `` I feel very well,'' <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> told reporters. `` I am inspired.'' Also freed early Sunday were the seven other prisoners whose impending unconditional release was announced Tuesday by President F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>. These include four other men arrested in 1963 and sentenced to life prison terms in 1964 along with <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Mandela </LOCATION> _ <PERSON> Andrew </PERSON> <PERSON> Mlangeni </PERSON>, 63, <PERSON> Elias </PERSON> <PERSON> Mostsoaledi </PERSON>, 65, <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Kathrada </PERSON>, 60, and <PERSON> Raymond </PERSON> <PERSON> Mhlaba </PERSON>, 68, as well as <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leader, <PERSON> Wilton </PERSON> <PERSON> Mkwayi </PERSON>, 67, who was sentenced to life in prison in a separate 1964 trial. The group also includes 80-year-year <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> activist <PERSON> Oscar </PERSON> <PERSON> Mpetha </PERSON>, who had been hospitalized in <LOCATION> Cape </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Town </LOCATION>, and <PERSON> Jafta </PERSON> <PERSON> Masemola </PERSON>, 58, a member of the <ORGANIZATION> Pan </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Africanist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> guerrilla movement who lives outside <LOCATION> Pretoria </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mpetha </PERSON> was serving a five-year prison term for terrorism. <PERSON> Masemola </PERSON> was sentenced to life imprisonment in 1963. <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, who arrived home in a gray suit and blue tie, emerged after about three hours to speak to reporters and give a clenched-fist salute to a crowd of 300 well-wishers outside his home, some waving <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> flags. Asked if he had feared he might die in prison, <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> said: `` I was quite prepared for death. But I knew the pressure was building for our release, and I never despaired.'' <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> conferred at his home with several anti-apartheid leaders. The freed <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leaders are expected to apply for passports to travel to <LOCATION> Lusaka </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Zambia </LOCATION>, for consultations with the guerrilla movement's exiled leadership. Although the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> remains outlawed, the release of <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> and his colleagues has been widely viewed as a tacit acknowledgement by the government of the movement's influence and popularity among <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s black majority. Even relatively conservative black leaders have said they will reject any negotiations with the government unless the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> is legalized and its jailed leaders freed. In recent weeks, the government has permitted <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> flags and posters to be displayed openly at mass protests, something not allowed before <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> took power in mid-August. Symbols of the guerrilla movement were in evidence Saturday, when more than 100,000 blacks joined in marches mationwide protesting government policy and celebrating the imminent release of the eight prisoners. Organizers said never before had so many large anti-government marches been held in the country simultaneously. <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>, 71, conferred with Justice Minister <PERSON> Kobie </PERSON> <PERSON> Coetsee </PERSON> and other government officials before the announcement of the prisoner releases. There has been increasing speculation that <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> does not want to go free until the government takes further steps to legalize <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> political activity. `` The <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> leader clearly understands the power he wields,'' wrote political analysist <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> Van </PERSON> <PERSON> Staden </PERSON> in The Star newspaper of <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> on Sunday. `` If, by remaining in jail, he can achieve the unbanning of his and other organizations and strengthen the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>'s position in the negotiation process, then his own history suggests he will opt for the tough choice.'' <PERSON> De </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON> has offered to negotiate a new constitution within five years that would extend political rights to the disenfranchised black majority, but he envisions some arrangement in which whites would retain veto power over major decisions. Black leaders say meaningful talks can not begin until the state of emergency is lifted, the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION> is legalized and all political prisoners are freed.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0527EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-MarcosMass     10-15 0362</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Marcos Mass,0369</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hawaii Bishop Calls Marcos Eulogy Absurd and Insulting</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CHRISTINE DONNELLY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>HONOLULU (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A eulogy comparing <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> was `` ridiculous, absurd and an insult to the Filipino people,'' <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION>'s top Roman Catholic official said Saturday. `` I sincerely regret the gross abuse of the Catholic Mass as a forum to make yet another blatantly political statement regarding the late <PERSON> Ferdinand </PERSON> <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>, former president of the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>,'' the Roman Catholic Bishop of <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ferrario </PERSON>, said in a written statement. During a funeral Mass Friday at the Co-Cathedral of <LOCATION> St. </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Theresa </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Monsignor </PERSON> <PERSON> Domingo </PERSON> <PERSON> Nebres </PERSON>, a priest from the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>, eulogized his longtime friend as a man who suffered like <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Christ </PERSON> and forgave those who betrayed him. `` Christ was a victim of the people's power, so <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> was a victim of the people's power,'' he said, referring to the 1986 `` people power'' revolt that ended <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' 20-year rule in the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION>. After the Mass, <PERSON> Nebres </PERSON> told reporters he was not comparing <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> in terms of power, but in suffering. <PERSON> Ferrario </PERSON> said <PERSON> Nebres </PERSON>, who does n't have a <LOCATION> Honolulu </LOCATION> parish, was allowed to say the Mass only after agreeing he would n't to give a eulogy or say anything political. `` He gave us his word that he would follow these directions. His comments at the Mass violated these instructions,'' said <PERSON> Ferrario </PERSON>. `` Furthermore, we consider his comparison of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> to <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> as ridiculous, absurd and an insult to the Filipino people.'' <PERSON> Nebres </PERSON> defended himself Saturday, saying his comments were personal, not political, and that he spoke only of <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON>' suffering, especially during his three-year exile As for the instructions against giving a eulogy, <PERSON> Nebres </PERSON> said, `` When someone is dead in front of you, you must give him a little glory as a comfort to his family and those who loved him.'' <PERSON> Marcos </PERSON> died Sept. 28 at age 72 after being hospitalized for nearly nine months. His body was to be entombed Sunday at the Valley of the Temples Memorial Park in what his family called `` a temporary resting place.'' His widow, <PERSON> Imelda </PERSON>, has vowed to return the body to the <LOCATION> Philippines </LOCATION> someday for burial.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0733EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i BC-Britain-Waite     10-15 0319</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Waite,0329</SECOND>
<HEAD>Church Assured Terry Waite is Alive</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Church of <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> said Sunday it has been assured by a reliable Iranian informant that missing church envoy <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Waite </PERSON> is alive on his 1,000 th day in captivity The unidentified source also provided assurances that two other Britons missing in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, journalist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> and Northern Irish teacher <PERSON> Brian </PERSON> <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON>, are alive, said <PERSON> Eve </PERSON> <PERSON> Keatley </PERSON>, a spokeswoman for Archbishop of Canterbury <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Runcie </PERSON>. <PERSON> Waite </PERSON>, 50, the archbishop's personal emissary, vanished in <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> on Jan. 20, 1987, while trying to negotiate the release of two <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> hostages. He was on his fifth mission to <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and is widely believed to have been taken captive by Iranian-backed Shiite Moslem extremists. `` We have had further assurances this weekend from Iranian sources that the three British hostages are alive,'' Ms. <PERSON> Keatley </PERSON> said. `` We still have no concrete proof of this,'' she said. `` The information comes via a channel that we think is reliable but which we do not wish to identify.'' A prayer by the archbishop was being said Sunday at churches across <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>. `` Give <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> a sense of your abiding presence and the assurance that fellow believers are one with him in spirit; encourage him and all other hostages to face each new day in confidence and hope; and grant that they may soon be restored to those whom they love,'' it said. On Sunday, <PERSON> McCarthy </PERSON> had been missing for 1,278 days and <PERSON> Keenan </PERSON> for 1,283 days. No group has claimed to hold them or <PERSON> Waite </PERSON> and there have been no photographs or videotapes to prove they are alive. The British government says no demands have been made for their freedom. Thirteen other Westerners, including eight Americans, are missing. All Americans are believed held by Shiite factions. The longest held hostage is American <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, chief <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> correspondent for <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION>. He was kidnapped March 16, 1985.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 0900EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w BC-Fed-Market     10-15 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Fed-Market,300</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fed Reprted Ready to Cool Market Fears</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> is ready to move large amounts of cash into the American banking system on Monday if the money is needed to prevent a financial crisis sparked by a sharp drop in stock prices, it was reported Sunday. Flooding the banking system with money could reduce the risk that Friday's 190-point fall in the Dow Jones average will turn into a more serious financial disaster on Monday, the <ORGANIZATION> Washington </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> reported. `` Markets will be able to count on us to make sure the financial system stays fluid,'' the Times quoted an unidentified official of the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Reserve </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> as saying. On Monday, `` it should be quite evident to the market that we will satisfy liquidity needs. Our action in the market should make it clear,'' an unnamed <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION> official told the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. Liquidity refers to the ready availability of cash. The <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s promise is aimed at preventing a repeat of the Wall Street situation two years ago, when the market fell 508 points in a single day. On the day before that fall, the stock index had fallen 108 points, leading mutual fund shareholders to cash in their shares. As the mutual funds ran low, they had to sell more shares to raise money, which in turn caused stock prices to drop even lower. `` To calm the markets it's important that institutions know there are adequate funds available,'' the official told the Times. `` Once the markets realize there will be no credit crunch, we can resume normal business.'' According to the unnamed official quoted by the Times, the <ORGANIZATION> Fed </ORGANIZATION>'s decision was taken at a meeting late Friday and was being communicated to officials in <LOCATION> Asia </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Western </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> this weekend
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1013EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-StormJerry 1stLd-Writethru a0666 10-15 0300</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Storm Jerry, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0666,0302</SECOND>
<HEAD>Storm Watch Shifts Westward on Texas Gulf Coast</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 8th graf, `Astronomical tides...', to DELETE redundant
first reference to Sheets.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tropical Storm <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> picked up strength and shifted a bit westward Sunday, and forecasters said the storm's center should make landfall in <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> or <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> by early Monday and could bring dangerous flooding and near-hurricane-force wind. Storm watches were posted from <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> La. </LOCATION>, on the central <LOCATION> Louisiana </LOCATION> coast, westward to <LOCATION> Port </LOCATION> <LOCATION> O'Connor </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>, on the central <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> coast. Watches east of <LOCATION> Morgan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> were withdrawn. Earlier, the storm watch had covered most of the <LOCATION> Lousiana </LOCATION> coast but only small parts of <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. Storm winds were clocked at 65 mph this morning, up from 60 mph overnight. `` Some slight increase in strength is likely before landfall, possibly bringing the winds to near hurricane force,'' Bb Sheets, director of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hurricane </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in suburban <LOCATION> Coral </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Gables </LOCATION>, said in an advisory. Tropical storms become hurricanes when sustained winds reach 74 mph. A storm warning was expected to be issued later Sunday for part of the watch area, forecasters said. They warned of severe coastal flooding because of the combination of coastal tides, which are expected to reach a peak this weekend, and the storm's surge. `` Astronomical tides are expected to be the highest of the year this weekend, and in combination with storm-surge water levels this could produce dangerous coastal flooding, depending on the exact path of the storm,'' Sheets said. At 9 a.m. EDT, the center was located near latitude 27.7 north, longitude 94.0 west, or about 115 miles south-southeast of <LOCATION> Galveston </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION>. The storm was moving north-northwest at about 10 mph, bringing the center near the upper <LOCATION> Texas </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Coast </LOCATION> late Sunday or early Monday, said Sheets.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1046EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-AmmoniaLeak     10-15 0366</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Ammonia Leak,0378</SECOND>
<HEAD>Residents Allowed To Return Home After Ammonia Leak</HEAD>
<DATELINE>WELLSTON, Ohio (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Most of the 6,500 residents forced to flee when a frozen pizza plant leaked deadly ammonia gas were allowed back into their homes early Sunday, but people with breathing problems were told to wait. Authorities ordered a complete evacuation of the town Saturday night when the gas, used for refrigeration, began leaking and spread quickly over an area of about half a mile, said Fire Department Lt. <PERSON> Ron </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON>. Twenty-four people affected by the gas were taken to hospitals and four were admitted, officials said. Many others were given oxygen by paramedics who rushed to the scene from around the largely rural southeastern quarter of <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION>. The anhydrous ammonia leak at the <ORGANIZATION> Pillsbury </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Jeno </PERSON>'s plant was brought under control by 10:55 p.m., said Mayor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> Assistant Fire Chief <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said people started returning to their homes just after 5 a.m. Sunday. `` The fog is still heavy. It's starting to lift up a little and it smells kind of funny. You get a little odor of it,'' <PERSON> Long </PERSON> said. The mayor warned that the elderly, people with breathing problems and small children could be affected by remaining vapor and should remain away from the town until the ammonia dissipated completely. Police had ordered people to evacuate a seven-block area near the plant, then expanded the order to cover the entire town as the gas spread, said Highway Patrol Dispatcher <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Riley </PERSON>. Sheriff's deputies went door-to-door ordering people out of their homes. Resident <PERSON> Vicki </PERSON> <PERSON> Dailey </PERSON> said she, her husband and two children fled choking fumes about 9 p.m. `` We were out in the driveway and at first could not smell anything,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Dailey </PERSON> said. `` But within about two minutes, we started smelling it and decided to get out. We were choking.'' Repair crews working breathing bottled oxygen reported the leak came from a ruptured 16-inch pipe, but the cause of the break was n't known, said <LOCATION> Vinton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> Deputy Sheriff <PERSON> Marc </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>. Anhydrous ammonia fumes can be fatal if inhaled, according to an emergency guidebook by the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION>. Calls to the plant were not answered Sunday morning.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1143EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-SouthAfrica-Changes     10-15 0657</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-South Africa-Changes,0672</SECOND>
<HEAD>Prisoners Returning to Different Political Arena</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-South Africa, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Blacks remain disenfranchised and the white minority remains in charge, but other aspects of South African politics have changed markedly in the quarter-century since <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> and his colleagues went to jail. Black trade unions, banned at the time <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON> and other <ORGANIZATION> African </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> leaders received life prison terms in 1964, now claim more than 2 million members and have the power to cripple the biggest industries. A network of militant anti-apartheid groups has formed in black townships across <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, linking churches, students, women and workers in an organizational framework that was not available to <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> and <PERSON> Mandela </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON>'s hometown, the vast black township of <LOCATION> Soweto </LOCATION>, remains an all-black ghetto providing a work force for <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>, but it now includes posh two-story homes as well as cramped matchbox houses and shanties. More Sowetans commute to work in black-owned taxis than in white-owned buses. In <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> itself, several inner-city neighborhoods have become thoroughly multiracial, even though laws mandating residential segregation remain on the books. When <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> went to jail, virtually every type of public facility in <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> was segregated _ toilets, elevators, parks, libraries, theaters, restaurants. Blacks and whites waited in separate lines at post offices. Those segregation policies crumbled one by one, and the city's final segregated amenities were opened up last month <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> now can ride buses, swim in swimming pools and patronize recreation centers that formerly were reserved for whites. Segregated facilities remain in some other parts of the country, but the government has hinted that the law allowing such segregation may be headed for abolition. Public hospitals and schools remain segregated, but the number of multiracial private schools has mushroomed since 1964. Many more blacks have moved into professional and technical jobs, including skilled mining jobs that until two years ago were exclusively for whites. <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>'s international isolation has intensified steadily since 1964. That was the first year the country was barred from the Olympics, and it now is excluded from international competition in almost every sport. A cultural boycott also is in effect, as are numerous trade embargoes, and <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> has been excluded from the <ORGANIZATION> U.N. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> General </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Assembly </ORGANIZATION> since 1974. Anti-apartheid activism among South African whites was rare in 1964, outside a small ciricle of communist-oriented intellectuals aligned to the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>. There was one anti-apartheid legislator, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON>, in Parliament. Now there are 34, with the anti-apartheid <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> having won 20 percent of the votes in the Sept. 6 general election. Whites produce lively anti-apartheid newspapers, perform in anti-apartheid rock bands and, in increasing numbers, journey abroad to confer with the <ORGANIZATION> ANC </ORGANIZATION>'s exiled leaders. Major changes also have taken place within the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. In 1964, it unashamedly touted its `` grand apartheid'' policy of relocating blacks into rural tribal homelands, theorizing that the blacks could satisfy their desire for political rights in the homelands while whites tightened control over the other 87 percent of the country. The homelands still exist, but the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> now acknowledges that the blacks in `` white'' <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> are permanent residents who must be given a political role. Efforts to stem the flow of blacks into urban areas have eased, and the government abolished the so-called pass laws that required blacks in `` white'' areas to have permits. The new president, F.W. <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, also is different from the government leaders of the 1950s and early 60s. Since taking power, he has pledged to eliminate discriminatory laws and negotiate a new constitution within five years that would extend political rights to blacks. However, <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Klerk </PERSON>, like his predecessors, opposes a one-person, one-vote system that would lead to black majority rule. He envisions some mechanism through which whites would maintain a veto power over major decisions, something <PERSON> Sisulu </PERSON> and his freed colleagues are likely to find unacceptable.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1145EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-PLOMeeting     10-15 0398</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-PLO Meeting,0410</SECOND>
<HEAD>PLO Central Council Opens Crucial Debate on Peace Proposals</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By SALAH NASRAWI</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BAGHDAD, Iraq (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Palestinian leaders met Sunday in the <LOCATION> Iraqi </LOCATION> capital seeking a common strategy toward <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Egyptian proposals for direct <LOCATION> Palestinian-Israeli </LOCATION> negotiations. <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON> Yasser </PERSON> <PERSON> Arafat </PERSON> was expected to come under pressure from hard-liners to reject recent peace proposals by <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>, which have either ruled out <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> participation in peace talks or left its role vague. The <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION> convened at the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s `` embassy'' in downtown <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> under tight security. The council, comprising 80 members, acts as an intermediary between the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>'s policy-making body, the <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Council </ORGANIZATION>, and the 15-man Executive Committee. <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Ahmed </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdul-Rahman </PERSON> said it will discuss `` all peace ideas that have been floating in recent months and will issue a policy statement.'' He did not say how long the meeting would last. <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> Prime Minister <PERSON> Yitzhak </PERSON> <PERSON> Shamir </PERSON> proposed in May that elections be held in the occupied <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Bank </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Gaza </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strip </LOCATION> to allow Palestinians to choose their own representatives under a plan for limited self-rule. But he ruled out <LOCATION> Israeli </LOCATION> withdrawal from the territories, the creation of a <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> state, or participation of Palestinians outside the occupied territories in the elections. Egyptian President <PERSON> Hosni </PERSON> <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> proposed a modified 10-point election plan that urged <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> to accept the concept of trading land for peace and enter into direct talks with the Palestinians. <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> did not mention the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Secretary of State <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> <PERSON> III </PERSON> invited the foreign ministers of <LOCATION> Egypt </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Esmat </PERSON> <PERSON> Abdel-Meguid </PERSON> and <PERSON> Moshe </PERSON> <PERSON> Arens </PERSON>, for talks in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> but also ignored the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION>. Radical Palestinians, mainly <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Habash </PERSON> and <PERSON> Nayef </PERSON> <PERSON> Hawatmeh </PERSON>, have been pushing for outright condemnation of the proposals. <PERSON> Habash </PERSON>, head of the <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Palestine </ORGANIZATION> faction, has warned <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> he could suffer the same fate as his predecessor <PERSON> Anwar </PERSON> <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON>. <PERSON> Sadat </PERSON> was killed by Egyptian radicals in October 1981, two years after he signed the Camp David peace treaty with <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hawatmeh </PERSON>, who leads the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> for the Liberation of <LOCATION> Palestine </LOCATION>, said: `` We are totally opposed to the <PERSON> Mubarak </PERSON> and <PERSON> Baker </PERSON> plans which are only a new version of the ill-fated Camp David accords.'' `` Only the <ORGANIZATION> PLO </ORGANIZATION> can choose <LOCATION> Palestinian </LOCATION> representatives to any dialogue,'' he told The <ORGANIZATION> Associated </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Press </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Baghdad </LOCATION> before the meeting began.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1146EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Thatcherism Bjt   10-15 0729</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Thatcherism, Bjt,0752</SECOND>
<HEAD>Thatcherism in Trouble, Looking for Change</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARCUS ELIASON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Last week's annual Conservative Party convention revealed Thatcherism to be in trouble and striving for a kinder, more caring image. Conservative conventions traditionally are designed less to thrash out policies than to cheer the leader and unite the troops. But this one seemed jinxed. With the pound sagging and inflation resurgent, interest rates were pushed up to 15 percent, an eight-year high, just five days before the convention opened in the seaside town of <LOCATION> Blackpool </LOCATION>. Then, as Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> was winding up the convention with a rousing defense of her record, it was announced that the annual inflation rate had crept up from 7.3 percent to 7.6 percent. Finally, as the delegates headed home Friday, Wall Street slumped and left British business facing a jittery weekend. To compound Conservative worries, the opposition <ORGANIZATION> Labor </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> has been topping the opinion polls for the past four months, and its lead averages seven points. That's normal against a government in midterm, say Conservative loyalists. But after a decade in the wilderness, the socialists under <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinnock </PERSON> are beginning to look like credible challengers again. At Labor's convention the previous week, vote-losing doctrines like unilateral nuclear disarmament were formally dumped, and the militant left, which had frightened off many voters in the past, was thoroughly sidelined. Moreover, the centrist bloc in Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s party that has helped keep her in power by garnering votes from Labor has disintegrated, and <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> is back to straight two-party politics. None of this means an imminent end to Thatcherism, with its hatred for socialism, distrust of trade unions and faith in market forces. No election need be held until mid-1992, and Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, who turned 64 last week, looked her usual vigorous, combative self. Even after 10 years in office _ an eternity by British standards _ she remains securely in charge, revered by her supporters as the warrior who slew the trade union dragon, liberated the marketplace from socialist regulation and restored <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s self-esteem. But even her best friends are telling her she's in trouble. When interest rates rose yet again, the conservative Daily Mail demanded the resignation of Chancellor of the Exchequer <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawson </PERSON>, who only a year earlier was being hailed by Conservatives as a miracle worker. The pro-Thatcher Sunday Times reversed its past assessments and concluded bluntly that `` There was no British economic miracle in the 1980s after all.'' Once again, it said, the country faced `` the perennial problems of the British economy _ rising prices, balance of payments deficits ... inflationary wage demands, slow growth and the huge structural rigidities which hold <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> back.'' At the convention, many delegates were asking why, after 10 years of Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>'s harsh medicine, inflation and high interest rates are still around. `` Many people are feeling rather let down,'' delegate <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Brown </PERSON> said Thursday. `` They are rather upset that after 10 years of Conservative rule we should have got into these rather difficult times.'' In the longer term, the convention was significant for the signals it sent out that Thatcherism is preparing for change. Speakers seemed at pains to present a more compassionate brand of Conservativism, even though that implies spending more taxpayers' money on public services and would have been regarded with suspicion by Thatcherite purists. There was an unexpected government pledge of $ 1.6 billion to cushion Britons against an unpopular new property tax. Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> assured delegates that the cherished <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Health </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> was not going to be `` privatized'' on <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> lines, as some had feared. An expected promise to sell off the state-owned railroads never materialized. The volatile issue of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s place in a united <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> failed to stir any fuss. Promises to protect the environment and enhance the quality of life got big cheers. Former <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Heseltine </PERSON>, a leading contender to succeed Mrs. <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON>, railed against `` polluted rivers, filthy streets, bodies bedded down in doorways -LRB- which -RRB- are no advertisement for a prosperous and caring society.'' The overall theme, said the liberal Guardian newspaper, was the need to adjust to `` a coming decade where the old tunes have lost their resonance.'' The more conservative Times said that with Conservatives and Labor both moving to the center, <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> might have `` a quite different political landscape in the 1990s.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1149EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Pope     10-15 0420</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Pope,0431</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pope Condemns Modern Influences, Says They Endanger Families</HEAD>
<HEAD>By LAURINDA KEYS</HEAD>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>PORT LOUIS, Mauritius (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Pope <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> II </PERSON> said Sunday that technological advancements such as television are threatening traditional family life on this <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island nation. `` Modern life has reached the shores of the island. Asphalt roads and electricity arrive the same time as the means of social communication'' such as television and videos, the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> told a stadium full of Roman Catholics on the tiny island of <LOCATION> Rodrigues </LOCATION>, 390 miles east of the main island of <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION>. `` In itself, this is praiseworthy progress, but, as in other societies, <PERSON> Rodrigues </PERSON> suffers in full from influences such as those of the video that threaten stability in the family,'' the pontiff said. The 36,500 French-speaking inhabitants of <PERSON> Rodrigues </PERSON> are mainly African-descended farmers and farm workers. About 97 percent are <ORGANIZATION> Catholic </ORGANIZATION>. The pope expressed concern about the growing number of islanders leaving to seek jobs in the booming economy on the main island, where he arrived Saturday after eight days in <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Indonesia </LOCATION>. He returns to <LOCATION> Rome </LOCATION> on Monday. `` For a long time, <PERSON> Rodrigues </PERSON> seemed to be living tranquilly as one big united family in which everyone knew everyone else and no one was an outcast,'' said the pope. `` And suddenly, there is worry about the future.'' He urged the islanders to safeguard traditional values in a country where tourism has doubled in the past six years to about 200,000 annually. Cardinal <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Margeot </PERSON> has warned that the influx of outsiders is creating serious `` moral'' problems for Mauritians. As the <PERSON> pope </PERSON> toured the island, topless European and South African women sunned themselves on beaches in a land where most native women wear long dresses and do n't smoke or drink alcohol. In the past six years, 90,000 jobs have been created on <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION>, a democracy where people of several races and religions coexist peacefully. The government of Prime Minister <PERSON> Anerood </PERSON> <PERSON> Jugnauth </PERSON> has actively courted foreign investment, creating a special export zone to diversify the economy from its centuries of dependence on sugarcane. But Mauritians have become concerned about pollution as factory smoke begins to cloud the sharp-edged mountains around the lagoons and gas stations appear alongside the palm trees. The government last year created a department to monitor the quality of life and financed it from liquor and cigarette taxes. <LOCATION> Mauritius </LOCATION> also has become a transit point for drug smugglers. Signs at the international airport warn of a death penalty for trafficking in narcotics.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Korea-US     10-15 0293</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Korea-US,0305</SECOND>
<HEAD>North Korea Condemns Arrest of Invaders of U.S. Ambassador's Home</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Communist <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> on Sunday denounced the arrests of six students who stormed the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador's residence in rival <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> last week. The official government newspaper <PERSON> Minju </PERSON> <PERSON> Choson </PERSON> declared: `` The action of the <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> students was an eruption of towering indignation at the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> imperialist aggressors who have established a colonial fascist rule over <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION>.'' On Friday, six students stormed the official residence of <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. Ambassador <PERSON> Donald </PERSON> <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION>. They hurled homemade bombs and smashed artwork with iron bars, but <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> and his wife, <PERSON> Meg </PERSON>, escaped unharmed through a side entrance. <PERSON> Minju </PERSON> <PERSON> Choson </PERSON>'s commentary, broadcast by the North's <ORGANIZATION> Korean </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, said the arrest of the students `` is a repressive outrage which could be done only by the pro-U.S. flunky-ist traitors who can not live a day without the patronage of the <LOCATION> U.S </LOCATION>. imperialists.'' It added: `` The <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> students took over the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> ambassador's residence and held an anti-U.S. sit-in, strongly demanding a negotiation with the ambassador, a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> agent, cancellation of the traitor <PERSON> Roh </PERSON> <PERSON> Tae-woo </PERSON>'s planned trip to the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> states </LOCATION> and stop to the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> pressure on <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> to import its agricultural and aquatic products `` This was an entirely just act,'' the newspaper said. <PERSON> Roh </PERSON>, the South Korean president, left Sunday for the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> to confer with President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> and address a joint session of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> was a <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION> station chief in <LOCATION> Seoul </LOCATION> in the 1970s. Radical students in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Korea </LOCATION> oppose the presence of 43,000 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military troops, stationed there under a mutual defense pact, saying they hamper reunification of the <LOCATION> Korean </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Peninsula </LOCATION>. The peninsula has been divided since 1945 into the Communist North and capitalist South.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0022 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1153EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--BalloonCrash     10-15 0150</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Balloon Crash,0153</SECOND>
<HEAD>Two Die in Hot Air Balloon Crash</HEAD>
<DATELINE>SYDNEY, Australia (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A hot air balloon carrying sightseers struck some power lines north of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION> on Sunday and crashed, killing the pilot and a passenger, police said. The pilot was a electrocuted and a female passenger died of internal injuries, said a police spokesman who did not identify himself. He said three other passengers escaped uninjured. The balloon was flying over the <LOCATION> Hunter </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> vineyards, about 80 miles north of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>, when it crashed. The accident was the fourth involving hot air balloons in <LOCATION> Australia </LOCATION> in the past two months. Thirteen people died Aug. 13 when their balloon collided with another and and two people died Wednesday when a balloon hit power lines near <LOCATION> Mudgee </LOCATION>, 112 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Sydney </LOCATION>. Six passengers were hurt a week ago when a balloon crashed into a hillside north of <LOCATION> Melbourne </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0023 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1150EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PotatoMuseum Bjt   10-15 0770</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Potato Museum, Bjt,720</SECOND>
<HEAD>At Potato Museum, The Eyes Have It</HEAD>
<HEAD>With LaserPhoto WX9</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 If visitors to this museum get the feeling they're being watched by hundreds of eyes, they're right. After all, they're standing in the Potato Museum. Surely one of the smallest museums in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, if not anywhere in the world, the Potato Museum occupies the basement of a yellow-brick rowhouse on <LOCATION> Capitol </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hill </LOCATION> that is the home of <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> and <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, a fun-loving couple of spud fanatics, and their 5-year-old son, <PERSON> Gulliver </PERSON>. Gulliver's nickname, naturally, is `` Tater Tot.'' Filling the two tiny basement rooms are 400 items from the <ORGANIZATION> Hugheses </ORGANIZATION>' collection of 2,000 potato artifacts, from a bronzed, heart-shaped potato donated by a Canadian woman to a <LOCATION> North </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Carolina </LOCATION> inventor's digital `` Tater Time Clock'' which runs _ believe it or not _ on electrical current supplied by the acids in two attached potatoes. `` The goodness of the potato knows no bounds,'' the couple gushed in a tuber tome they wrote in 1986, titled `` The Great Potato Book,'' extolling the virtues of their favorite vegetable. Visitors to the private, non-profit museum are welcomed by Mrs. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> with a slide show of potato folklore, accompanied by tapes of such top tuber tunes as `` Cold Tater Stomp'' or Weird <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Yanokovich </PERSON>'s `` Addicted to Spuds.'' Then her husband, a schoolteacher in suburban <PERSON> McLean </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, invites guests to become couch potatoes and enjoy his videotape of `` great moments in potatoes'' from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> movies. The scenes include <PERSON> Marilyn </PERSON> <PERSON> Monroe </PERSON> snacking on potato chips in `` The Seven-Year Itch'' and <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Dreyfuss </PERSON> making a mountain of his mashed potatoes at the dinner table in `` Close Encounters of the Third Kind.'' Q: What was the biggest potato ever grown? A. An Englishman named <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Seddal </PERSON> is reputed to have harvested a monster spud weighing 18 pounds, 4 ounces on Feb. 17, 1795. Q. What was the biggest single serving of mashed potatoes in history? A. An 18,260-pound mound of instant mashed potatoes, prepared in a cement mixer truck for the annual Potato Bowl football game at Grand Forks, <LOCATION> N.D. </LOCATION>, in 1982. The museum's shelves are stuffed with potato toys -LRB- including a `` Spudomatic'' air pistol that shoots potato pellets -RRB-, a burlap potato sack jacket, potato posters, dolls and postage stamps, a 1948 <LOCATION> Idaho </LOCATION> `` World Famous Potatoes'' license plate and some 4,000-year-old potatoes preserved in a jar. There's also a cluster of antique potato chip cans, a basket of deep-fried potato skins woven by the chef at <PERSON> Antoine </PERSON>'s Restaurant in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, and a staggering assortment of implements and kitchen appliances _ potato mashers, slicers, peelers, scrubbers, hoes, rakes, planters, baskets, diggers and beetle sprayers. One rack displays sample products made from potatoes _ Polish vodka, hand lotion, ice cream, bread, a sheet of paper, a necklace and `` autochromes,'' an early color photographic process using potato starch _ which also is used to make candy and glue. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> says potatoes fueled German rockets in World War II, and once were used as money by the island people of Tristan da <PERSON> Cunha </PERSON>. They're good for treating acne, sunburn and toothaches, he claims, and they make great chicken feed. The Potato Museum began in 1975, when <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> asked his fifth-grade pupils at the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> School </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Brussels </ORGANIZATION> to prepare an exhibit showing why potatoes are so important in <LOCATION> Belgium </LOCATION>. The Belgians grow potatoes in backyard gardens the way Americans grow tomatoes, he says, and their `` frites'' _ which Americans mistakenly call French fries _ are the most delicious in the world. Artifacts from that classroom project formed the nucleus of the museum, which moved to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> with the <ORGANIZATION> Hugheses </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. The independent, tax-exempt museum gets most of its financial support from membership dues, souvenir sales and a grant from a potato research center in <LOCATION> Lima </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Peru </LOCATION>. For $ 20 a year, members receive six issues of the museum's newsletter, `` Peelings,'' and invitations to occasional potluck dinners where the all-potato menu ranges from pickled potato hors d'oeuvres to a dessert made of chocolate-laced mashed potatoes <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON> says he and <PERSON> Meredith </PERSON> have two ambitions: to visit the Chilean island where Spanish explorers found potatoes and introduced them to <LOCATION> Europe </LOCATION> in 1570, and to take a cruise on a newly built Japanese potato tanker. The <ORGANIZATION> Hugheses </ORGANIZATION> love potatoes because they're not only good eating, but they're fun and friendly. `` They are a comfort food when we feel lonely, sick or sad, but we also see something of ourselves in them,'' said Mrs. <PERSON> Hughes </PERSON>, cuddling a spud in her hand. `` Look, it has eyes, a head, a face. It's somehow almost human.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0024 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1154EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-WallBomber     10-15 0424</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Wall Bomber,0433</SECOND>
<HEAD>Group Saves Old Mural of B-17</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By GRAHAM HEATHCOTE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 While World War II still raged, an <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> serviceman had a burst of inspiration and painted a giant picture of the famed B-17 bomber on a brick wall at a <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> airfield. The B-17 is ancient aviation history now, and the airfield is used as a drag-racing strip. The name of the fatigue-clad artist is barely remembered. But the mural that stood in obscurity since 1944 has been taken down as part of a plan to restore it and move it to a permanent place of honor. `` It was a thrill to see something that has been in the dark for more than 40 years come into the light again and be saved for posterity,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nimmo </PERSON>, one of a group of English enthusiasts who seek to perserve such relics. The picture _ which shows the famous `` Flying Fortress'' unloading its bombs while anti-aircraft shells burst around it _ was taken down Saturday from its place at <LOCATION> Podington </LOCATION> airfield, an old base of the World War II-era <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> 8th <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Podington </LOCATION> airfield, 65 miles north of <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>, was one of about 130 8th <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> bases for bombers and fighters in the eastern <LOCATION> England </LOCATION> flatlands. They were established to raid <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> and German-occupied territory. After the war, most of the <LOCATION> Podington </LOCATION> field reverted to farming. The brick huts used by the crews have remained as workshops for drag-racing on the airfield runway, and the control tower has been converted into a house. The mural was on a piece of wall on farmland. The removal team had to get permission from the farmer to take down the painting, and they will have to rebuild the wall. A benefactor has given them 750 red bricks for the task. With help from the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> air base at <LOCATION> Alconbury </LOCATION> near <LOCATION> Cambridge </LOCATION>, the mural is to soon be transported to <LOCATION> Duxford </LOCATION>, another old <ORGANIZATION> 8th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> field about 35 miles east of <LOCATION> Podington </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> Imperial </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> War </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Museum </ORGANIZATION> maintains <LOCATION> Duxford </LOCATION> for its collection of historic aircraft and will set up the B-17 mural as part of its display about the <ORGANIZATION> 8th </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>. The 12-by-8 foot painting was done in about 1944 by a staff sergeant named <PERSON> Walderschmidt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nimmo </PERSON> said. `` We think he was on the ground crew,'' he said. `` We do n't know anything else about him except that we heard he is still alive in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. We do n't know his first name or where he lives.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0025 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1156EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--SriLanka-Song     10-15 0174</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Sri Lanka-Song,0176</SECOND>
<HEAD>Song Asks Sri Lankans To `Give Peace A Chance'</HEAD>
<DATELINE>COLOMBO, Sri Lanka (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Forty of the country's top singers have pooled their talents to record a song that pleads for peace on this ethnically torn <LOCATION> Indian </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> island. The new song was titled `` Give Peace A Chance'' and sung in the Tamil, Sinhalese and English languages. It was played this weekend on state-run radio and television. `` Our song, the first sung jointly by 40 top vocalists, is to achieve peace in our country, where everybody cries for just that,'' said composer <PERSON> Sunil </PERSON> <PERSON> Perera </PERSON>. Tamils, who are mostly Hindus, make up 18 percent of the island's 16 million people. Militant Tamils have been fighting since 1983 for an independent homeland in the northeast. They allege they are denied jobs and education by the predominantly <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Sinhalese </ORGANIZATION>, who make up 75 percent of the population. More than 11,000 people have died in the Tamil rebellion. Another 5,000 have been killed in the backlash by Sinhalese extremists that started two years ago.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0026 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1217EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Cambodia-Fighting Bjt   10-15 0713</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Cambodia-Fighting, Bjt,0736</SECOND>
<HEAD>Guerrillas Advance to Strategic Town in Coordinated Attack</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDITOR'S NOTE _ Associated Press reporter Nate Thayer was the first
to travel in an area of Cambodia where guerrillas have claimed recent victories.
Returning, he was wounded by shrapnel from a land mine that destroyed the
truck in which he was riding and killed the driver.</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto BK4</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By NATE THAYER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
 ROUTE 69, <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- _ Following their capture of three towns, <LOCATION> Cambodian </LOCATION> guerrillas have begun a coordinated attack on the only big town blocking their advance to the strategic city of <LOCATION> Sisophon </LOCATION>, which is controlled by the Vietnam-installed government. The guerrillas claim they already have taken frontline positions at <LOCATION> Svey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chek </LOCATION>. The offensive began Saturday, and all day the area reverberated with hundreds of artillery blasts. More than 1,000 guerrillas were seen Saturday trekking on the roads to <LOCATION> Svey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chek </LOCATION> from the recently captured towns of <PERSON> Thmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Puok </PERSON>, <PERSON> Banteay </PERSON> <PERSON> Chmar </PERSON> and <LOCATION> Kandoul </LOCATION>. Following them were convoys of people carrying ammunition and more than 50 ox carts full of ammunition, mortars, rockets and anti-tank weapons. The <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> claimed it seized <PERSON> Thmar </PERSON> <PERSON> Puok </PERSON> and <PERSON> Banteay </PERSON> <PERSON> Chmar </PERSON>, along Highway 69 leading to <LOCATION> Sisophon </LOCATION>, and <LOCATION> Kandoul </LOCATION>, just west of the highway, days after launching a `` general offensive'' on Sept. 30. A 16-hour, 94-mile tour Saturday of the towns and several captured artillery bases showed they were firmly under the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s control. Field commanders said the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> was attacking <LOCATION> Svey </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chek </LOCATION> in uncommon coordination with its two partners in the resistance coalition, the <ORGANIZATION> Khmer </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Rouge </ORGANIZATION> and the forces of Prince <PERSON> Norodom </PERSON> <PERSON> Sihanouk </PERSON>. The guerrillas are trying to topple the government <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> installed after it invaded <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> in late 1978. Their attacks intensified after <LOCATION> Vietnam </LOCATION> made what it called the pullout of its last troops from <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> on Sept. 26. Capturing <LOCATION> Sisophon </LOCATION>, a major military base for operations in northwestern <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION>, would be a major victory for the guerrillas, who have not seized any areas of such significance. The tour began at a <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> base along the <LOCATION> Thai </LOCATION> border south of the <LOCATION> Dong </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ruk </LOCATION> <LOCATION> mountains </LOCATION>, where the guerrillas showed off captured equipment _ more than 1,000 automatic rifles, heavy machine guns, mortars, many cases of anti-personnel mines and teletype machines with Soviet lettering. The journey into <LOCATION> Cambodia </LOCATION> was on motorcyles, with about 20 <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> guerrillas. It was slow and grueling, covering roads drenched by monsoon rains. Everywhere were captured artillery positions, virtually all capable of hitting Site 2, the <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION>'s major civilian base just inside <LOCATION> Thailand </LOCATION>. Three destroyed tanks, four destroyed heavy trucks and heavy artillery guns were abandoned on the roads. Everywhere were former government soldiers who had defected to the guerrilla side. The three captured towns appeared only lightly defended and there were no signs the guerrillas expected a counteroffensive. Civilians farmed in the fields, seeming to go about their lives normally. The twisted remants of two tanks sat at the edge of <LOCATION> Banteay </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Chmar </LOCATION>, blasted by anti-tank weapons the guerrillas recently acquired. Some guerrillas have said the weapons may change the course of the war the way the acquisition of Stinger missiles did for the guerrillas in <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. Children played around the destroyed tanks. Hundreds of residents greeted the guerrillas arriving in the town with a religious ceremony, and <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> division commander Gen. <PERSON> Koh </PERSON> <PERSON> Chien </PERSON> made a speech and gave money to a village headman and to <ORGANIZATION> Buddhist </ORGANIZATION> monks. The town had been guarded by 300 or 400 government soldiers, said village head Ta Rah, 64. `` The -LRB- <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Front </ORGANIZATION> -RRB- attacked and they all left right away,'' he said, laughing. The guerrillas radioed for a car after one motorcyle in the convoy broke down. The driver of the Soviet-made military transport truck that arrived was a former government soldier who brought the vehicle when he defected. Asked if he missed home, he said: `` No. We want to stay with the KPNLF.'' The truck's left front wheel struck a land mine just after passing a guerrilla base at <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Lo </LOCATION>. The mine apparently had been planted by government troops as they abandoned the base in a recent guerrilla attack. Both of the driver's legs were blown off, and he later died. Several passengers, including this reporter, were wounded. The vehicle burned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP891015-0027 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-10-15-89 1223EDT</FILEID>
<FIRST>r e AM-Opera 1stLd-Writethru a0682 10-15 0523</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Opera, 1st Ld - Writethru, a0682,0531</SECOND>
<HEAD>Alessandra Marc Makes Debut in `Aida'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 12th graf pvs, `The rest ...' to CORRECT Radames to hero
sted heroine.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE SILVERMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
