<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DogvsPig     03-03 0202</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dog vs Pig,0207</SECOND>
<HEAD>Doctor Cleared in Dog-Pig Spat</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOUNT LEBANON, Pa. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A doctor committed no crime when he brandished a pistol at a dog that went after his miniature pig in his backyard, a judge ruled. District Justice <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Ivill </PERSON> on Wednesday dismissed charges against Dr. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>, 36, who was charged with recklessly endangering another person, simple assault and disorderly conduct in the incident. <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>'s neighbor, <PERSON> Melvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON>, testified he and his wife were caring for a stray dog, a young Siberian husky weighing about 40 pounds, when the dog got away from him and went after <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON>'s miniature pig next door <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON> started waving a pistol at the dog but `` did not point the gun directly at me,'' <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said. But, <PERSON> Kelly </PERSON> said, `` I felt like I was being intimidated.'' Testimony showed that neither animal was injured and no shots were fired in this <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> suburb. <PERSON> Ivill </PERSON> said <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON> was on his own property and was licensed to carry a gun. He ruled <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON> was a man `` preparing to defend his pet from a trespassing animal.'' <PERSON> Barrera </PERSON> said he obtained the gun for protection and the pig because `` I'm asthmatic and allergic to dogs and cats.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0144EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-SpaceShuttle     03-03 0178</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Space Shuttle,0181</SECOND>
<HEAD>Space Shuttle Managers To Set Discovery Launch Date</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Late afternoon announcement expected.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Launch of the Discovery and its five-astronaut crew could be scheduled for late next week as <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> prepares for the third post-Challenger shuttle mission. <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> officials, who planned to announce a launch date today, said Wednesday the liftoff would occur no sooner than March 11 because of the need to replace a failed electrical part in one of the shuttle's three main engines The target date had been March 9, but the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> told <ORGANIZATION> NASA </ORGANIZATION> Monday that it planned to launch a high-priority military rocket on that day and could not support a shuttle flight with <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> tracking facilities. The electrical part problem apparently took care of that potential conflict. But a delay in the military flight could affect the shuttle launch on a day-by-day basis. The <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> mission has priority for national security reasons. During five days in orbit, Discovery's astronauts are to deploy a large communications satellite and conduct scientific experiments.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0145EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-Networks-Sweep     03-03 0600</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Networks-Sweep,0618</SECOND>
<HEAD>NBC, CBS Rebound from Strike; ABC Still Struggling</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHRYN BAKER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Television Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The so-called February ratings sweep indicate <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> have rebounded from last year's writers' strike, but network executives say the September-April `` season'' used to track the ratings race should be yearlong. `` I know you guys love races,'' said <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Poltrack </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> vice president for marketing, `` but any discussion of full-season results is a historical curiosity and not a marketing issue, and a disservice to us.'' <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s senior vice president for marketing and research, said the season race is now `` a spectator sport'' and means nothing except for bragging rights. `` In 1989, to say there is a ` season' is so antiquated,'' said <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>. `` That means we would be abdicating the audience five months of the year, and that's not something we can afford to do.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Entertainment </ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON> Brandon </PERSON> <PERSON> Tartikoff </PERSON> has long held that the ratings race season should be year-round, too, but such talk did n't come up at Thursday's <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> briefing on the February sweep rating period _ one of four months a year when local TV ratings are measured to determine advertising rates. But then, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> is winning another season hands-down. Ten years ago when the average viewer had few channels available, the networks did n't have to worry about losing their audience to competition from cable or videocassettes over the summer, but times have changed. The audience that has access to an average of 25 channels will go elsewhere if the networks fail to offer them what they want to watch. In February, the networks did. The <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> miniseries `` Lonesome Dove'' and the heated competition it encouraged boosted the networks' aggregate rating after a more than yearlong decline. The four-night `` Lonesome Dove'' boosted third-place CBS above <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> in the February sweep and makes second place for the season a tossup. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> won the sweep with an average <ORGANIZATION> A.C. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Nielsen </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> rating of 16.3. <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> had a 14.7 and <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> a 12.4. The rating is a percentage of 90.4 million <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> homes with televisions. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> had a 28 percent decline in February compared to February 1988, when it had the Winter Olympics. <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> showed increases this February over last. <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> was forced, because of the writers' strike, to run the first 18-hour stretch of its 32-hour miniseries `` War and Remembrance'' in November. Hardly a ratings blockbuster, it still did better than <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION>'s regular programming. The decision to run the program then came back to haunt the network in February when `` War and Remembrance'' was to have run. `` Clearly we had a disappointing sweeps,'' said <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>. `` We did not have an enormous inventory, because we had to play ` War and Remembrance' early, and we had planned to play it in February,'' he said. `` The other two networks knew that and planned accordingly.'' CBS got a big push, both in ratings and morale, from the critically acclaimed `` Lonesome Dove,'' the highest-rated network miniseries in more than four years. But the miniseries' success pleased <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>, too. `` I think ` Lonesome Dove' was beneficial to everybody,'' said <PERSON> Wurtzel </PERSON>. `` Network television needs to have exciting, well-made programming.'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> even used figures from the week of `` Lonesome Dove'' to contend that network `` reach'' has not declined in the past decade, even if ratings have. `` Say we -LRB- the networks -RRB- are all throwing a party,'' explained <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Jaffe </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>'s vice president for research projects. `` The same number of people come to the party, but instead of staying 2 -LCB- hours, maybe they stay two hours, then they go to someone else's party.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0150EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-APArts:PrisonMovies     03-03 0833</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-AP Arts: Prison Movies,0854</SECOND>
<HEAD>Hard Time and a Hard Rain</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOE McDONALD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Where drivers passing the maximum-security <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> State Prison see a grim, century-old building of hand-hewn granite blocks and iron window bars, Disney production people saw a set for <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Selleck </PERSON>'s next movie. They wanted a building with a forbidden look for `` Hard Rain,'' a story set in a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> prison in the early 1900s. Producer <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Cort </PERSON> and director <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Yates </PERSON> considered about 60 prisons and visited 15 sites before deciding to film outdoor scenes at the prison, located on the outskirts of the state capital in the high desert of northwest <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>. The <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> facility was chosen because it had two yards, and `` we could be guaranteed that their security would not interfere with our work and our work would n't interfere with their security,'' said <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pasternak </PERSON>, the movie's unit publicist. <PERSON> Robin </PERSON> <PERSON> Holabird </PERSON>, deputy director of <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION>'s film office, said while the Disney movie is the most recent planned for the prison, her office receives a steady stream of requests for information and visits from producers interested in filming at the historic building. `` When they come scouting, we tell them we're interested and will take extra steps so they know we're serious about making a movie,'' she said. `` If all we could offer them was a new jail, it could not have been done.'' With `` Hard Rain,'' <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> joins a growing number of governments marketing prisons as movie sets to attract the millions of dollars local economies can generate from <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> movie-makers looking beyond <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> for new locations and lower production costs. `` We've got lots of competition when it comes to prisons,'' said <PERSON> Bill </PERSON> <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Culture </ORGANIZATION> film board in <LOCATION> Alberta </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Canada </LOCATION>, which tried unsuccessfully to attract the <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> by offering a vacant 19th century prison and prisoners from a neighboring jail as extras for `` Hard Rain.'' `` Now there are so many film commissions that when producers send out circulars saying they're looking for a prison, they're sorting through photos for weeks,'' <PERSON> Marsden </PERSON> said. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> caught the attention of filmmakers by featuring the vacant state penitentiary in <LOCATION> Columbus </LOCATION> in a `` Prison for Rent'' advertising campaign that ran in movie catalogs and magazines. `` It described it almost like a real estate dialogue on a piece of property: ` complete with electric chair,''' said <PERSON> R.J. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavallaro </PERSON>, assistant manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION>. <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> stopped running the `` Prison for Rent'' advertisement a year ago, <PERSON> Cavallaro </PERSON> said, partly because the campaign's success stereotyped the state as a location for making prison movies. `` We do have a lot of prisons and we really are grateful that filmmakers think of us when they think of prison movies, but we also have to promote the rest of a very diverse state,'' he said. <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> state officials recently began an aggressive campaign promoting two state prisons by mailing out color fliers to 9,000 movie makers, according to <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Iowa </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Film </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. `` We've had a couple of feature films shot here recently and they brought in several million dollars in a short period of time. We want to open the doors up to bring in more of that money and work for <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> people,'' he said. <PERSON> Jarvis </PERSON> said <LOCATION> Iowa </LOCATION> wardens were enthusiastic about advertising their prisons and have agreed to let crews film in working prisons. `` They realize they're part of our economic development effort just like anyone else,'' he said. <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>'s chief warden no longer allows movie-makers in the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Prison </ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION>, once a popular location for films, because of security and discipline concerns, according to <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McCallum </PERSON>, director of the <ORGANIZATION> Arizona </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Motion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Picture </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> McCallum </PERSON> now passes requests for the <LOCATION> Florence </LOCATION> prison, featured in `` Stir Crazy'' and `` Raising <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION>,'' on to states with available prisons. `` We've probably lost millions of dollars because we ca n't get the business,'' he said. In addition to money the local <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> economy can expect to make from `` Hard Rain'' when <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> hires local workers and buys supplies, the <LOCATION> Nevada </LOCATION> State Prison itself will get economic benefits from the movie, according to Lt. <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> Budge </PERSON>, a prison official and consultant for the movie. `` They had to give something to the inmates, and they're donating money to the inmate welfare fund, and with that money we're purchasing recreational equipment,'' he said Budge said the prison will get to keep a truck and 350 sets of inmate denims Disney is supplying for the movie. `` They're also building a permanent guard post and adding fencing and razor wire because they want it to look more confining, and that only adds to our security,'' he said. The announcement that <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> planned to make a movie at the prison also improved discipline among inmates, 300 of whom will be hired as extras, <PERSON> Budge </PERSON> said. `` Nobody wants to get locked up and miss their chance to be in the movie,'' he said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0152EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Gorbachev     03-03 1012</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Gorbachev,1037</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Still Seeks `Better Life' After 4 Years In Power</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 It will be four years on March 11 that <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> came to power in the <LOCATION> Kremlin </LOCATION>, instituting a policy of restructuring to the Soviet system and bringing about a greater openess of that closed society. Following is the first of a series of reports by <ORGANIZATION> AP </ORGANIZATION> correspondents in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> assaying those four years.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By MICHAEL PUTZEL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> says he was once asked by a farmer what he was trying to accomplish with all his reforms. `` Simply, we want, in spite of everything ... for working people to lead a better life,'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> said he replied. `` I thought it was enough to say.'' Perhaps it's as simple as that: the quaint wish of a Russian peasant's son who grew up in such hardship that at one point he was kept out of school for want of shoes. But he was taught to dream in the time of <PERSON> Nikita </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Khrushchev </PERSON>, another reformist Soviet leader of humble origins, and indications are <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> dreams of grander, more profound changes not just for the people but for the state. Seventy years after the Russian Revolution, the Soviet economy is in serious trouble and communism has not provided a better life for workers who yearn for bigger apartments, better working conditions, more nourishing and varied food. And an economy ruled from the center has not kept pace with the technology of the West. In what would by American measure be a full presidential term, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has made wholesale changes in the way the world perceives him and the nation he leads. He has thrown open prisons and labor camps and, in some cases, borders to free thousands of political prisoners and permit tens of thousands of people to leave the country. He has eased, although certainly not eliminated, the fear of foreigners. Under `` glasnost'' he has converted the mass media from a tightly controlled propaganda organ to a braying calliope of complaints, debates, exposes and experiments testing just how far the new openness may go _ and to what purpose. Yet for all his effort, the changes at home have been largely atmospheric. His plans for `` perestroika,'' or restructuring Soviet society, have faltered. The forces that keep this vast nation a drab, monolithic parody of the communist state envisioned by its founders resist each tangible step toward that `` better life'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seeks for those he calls `` the simple people who are the salt of our countries.'' Store shelves are barren. Meat, butter, cheese and sugar are widely rationed. Such simple necessities as winter boots and windshield wipers are perpetually unavailable, and consumers may wait for years to buy long-outdated models of `` modern conveniences'' such as washing machines, cars or even electric irons. The air in urban areas is filthy, the water unreliable, living quarters poorly planned and filled far beyond capacity. Crash construction programs produce instant ruins: crumbling high rises barely habitable by the time they are occupied years after their first cracked concrete slabs were laid to start them on their way. One of the imponderables of this tumultuous time is how long even a remarkably dynamic and politically astute leader has to accomplish the goals he has set for himself, fighting the shortcomings of the system and inertia-bound bureaucrats. One simple measure of how long the road is and how much time progress takes: Last summer, the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Committee </ORGANIZATION> set as a national goal the installation of a telephone in just one-half of all Soviet homes by 1995. People in urban areas wait years for a phone, and many rural districts do n't have any service. Villagers five miles from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> draw their water from community wells. It is a fundamental tenet of official <LOCATION> American </LOCATION> analysis that the `` better life'' <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> seeks for his countrymen is not an end in itself but the means of maintaining his nation's superpower status in a fast-changing world. The <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, according to that view, can no longer afford its own military might and ca n't use its power to keep pace with _ or even steal _ the technology that is quickly increasing the gulf between the industrialized West and the long-stagnant East. As <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> has pressed for more discussion of problems, modernization of services, development of private initiative and greater public participation in the political process, Westerners have been tempted to think he is trying to fashion a nation resembling the world's other great superpower, the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION>. A pragmatic leader who calls himself a realist, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> repeatedly insists he intends to work within the framework of socialism. Both he and <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Yakovlev </PERSON>, said to be his closest adviser, have written books critical of the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and what they said was its intolerance for other ways of life and thought. Regardless of any personal vision, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> is pushed by economic reality to reorder Soviet priorities. `` He does n't have the resources to sustain the investments the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> is making in foreign policy and defense,'' said one Western analyst who discussed the issue on condition he not be identified. <ORGANIZATION> NATO </ORGANIZATION> estimates the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> devotes 15 percent to 25 percent of its gross national product to the military. `` Even the lower end of that range would be enormous by world standards,'' the analyst said. `` The upper end is truly staggering. But that's not all, because that same 15 to 25 percent monopolizes the country's scientific and technological resources and people.'' To begin reducing those figures, <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> already has negotiated the first treaty reducing <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> nuclear arsenals and has announced substantial unilateral reductions in Soviet grounds forces at home and abroad, including this month's completion of the withdrawal from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION>. `` Part of the reordering of priorities is to work on what <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> calls the ` enemy image,''' the analyst said. `` He has to persuade other leaders he's serious and lower the perception of risk in the rest of the world.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0200EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a P-PorkRinds     03-03 0840</FIRST>
<SECOND>P-Pork Rinds,0864</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pork Rinds Stem From South's `Waste Not, Want Not' Tradition</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAHUNTA, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even in good times it's hard for Southerners to trash anything that comes from a hog, hence the presidential snack, pork rinds. `` You do n't throw nothing away,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Nahunta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` You use everything from a hog but the squeal.'' `` It's the finest food substance available on the planet,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Duplin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> hog farmer and one of the largest pork producers in the nation. Hogs provide hams, pork chops, bacon and sausage. Their feet are pickled, the intestines are used as casings for sausage, the tails are used for seasoning and the hide ends up in fancy driving gloves, <ORGANIZATION> Hush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Puppy </ORGANIZATION> shoes and President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s favorite munchie. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, who produces pork rinds, thinks it's great that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> prefers them with Tabasco sauce. But if the president wants some of <LOCATION> Nahunta </LOCATION>'s home-style skins, he'll have to come to this crossroads 50 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION> to get them. `` It will probably be good for the pork industry, but there's not much way for it to help our business,'' said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, whose father founded the company 24 years ago. `` We process 100 skins a week and ca n't meet the demand from our customers as it is.'' The pork company, which makes up most of <LOCATION> Nahunta </LOCATION>, started as a slaughterhouse in 1955 and added retail pork sales in 1975. It does not distribute its products, but more than 3,000 people a week come by to pick out fresh pork and cured hams. They also grab up 99-cent bags of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s salted and deep-fried pork skins. `` We process about 500 hogs a week,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said, `` but we're real particular about the skins we use If they are n't quite up to snuff, we wo n't use them. That's why we only turn about 100 skins a week into pork rinds.'' A special machine slices the skin off of pork pieces. The skin pieces are cooked for four hours in vats to dry out the fat. Then the hard, shriveled skins are deep fried. The pieces of skin swell and pop, turning into puffy slabs of rind in minutes. `` This is our scientific measuring process,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said as he dipped a handful of salt from a bucket and spread it over the fried rinds. `` Ones that come out like this, we throw away,'' he said, plucking a dark, hard chunk from among the beige sheets of fried skin. `` And we've got two grades of rinds. `` The ones that come out really nice and thin are No. Ones,'' he said. `` Your thicker skins that come out a little tougher are No. Twos.'' A bag of No. Ones, which weighs a little more than 3 ounces, and a 12-ounce bag of No. Twos go for the same price _ 99 cents. `` We actually sell more of the No. Twos,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. `` People seem to like to gnaw on them a little bit.'' A half-ounce serving of pork rinds provides little in the way of nutrition; potato chips and peanuts have more nutrients, but also more fat and cholesterol. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> analysis showed a two-ounce package of rinds contains 315 calories; 32.5 grams of protein; 18.9 grams of fat; 58 milligrams of cholesterol; and 1,054 milligrams of salt. The <ORGANIZATION> Snack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said pork rind sales nationally totaled $ 195 million in 1987, a figure dwarfed by potato chips, which had $ 3.8 billion in sales the same year. <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON>, a professor of food science at <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said the origin of pork rinds is lost in history. `` I do n't know when people started popping skins or why,'' <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if it's a takeoff from the old days of crackling or what.'' Crackling, or cracklin', is hog fat that has the lard squeezed out of it and is then cooked. In some areas, the layer of fat was ground up with the skin to make the crisp treat. `` It could be that somebody had a piece of skin left over from cracklin', put it on a stove and it popped, sort of an accidental discovery,'' <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he is n't sure why pork rinds have remained a regional delicacy, limited mainly to the South. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, who raises a million hogs a year, said other areas of the country have just lagged behind the South in realizing how good pork rinds are. `` Anybody that does n't like them has just never tasted them,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a Democrat, said he was aware of the Republican president's use of symbolism in the 1988 campaign, but he did not believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used pork rinds as a populist snack to fight a less-than-macho image. `` I really think he ate them before the presidential campaign,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. `` But maybe nobody paid much attention to what he ate when he was n't the president. The office sure changes that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0207EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-BeringBridge     03-03 0670</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bering Bridge,0686</SECOND>
<HEAD>US Adventurers Meet Soviet Counterparts, Prepare Siberian Trek</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEAN FOSDICK</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANADYR, U.S.S.R. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A 60-day, 1,200-mile ski and dog sled trek from <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> will be more celebration than exploration for a dozen <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet adventurers setting out this weekend. Aside from cold-weather research, the primary object of the Bering Bridge Expedition across seldom-visited sections of the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Far </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION> and arctic <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> is good will, said <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON>, 33, of <LOCATION> Ely </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Minn. </LOCATION>, who describes the trip as adventure diplomacy. `` My pocket is full of cross-flagged -LRB- U.S.-Soviet -RRB- pins,'' <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said. `` We'll be leaving a full-sized American flag in each Soviet village; a Soviet flag in each <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> village.'' The expedition is an attempt to call attention to the common cultural heritage of the indigenous population of the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> region, <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said. Some of the team members have relatives on opposite sides of the border, and it is hoped the trek will result in a relaxation of rules barring visits by natives _ some of whom live within 2 -LCB- miles of one another on islands in the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION>, separated only by sea ice and Cold War politics. The six-member <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> team arrived in this Siberian city of 16,000 Wednesday, after two weather delays. They joined their six Soviet counterparts for a news conference, a VIP dinner and the beginning of several days of medical experiments. It was the first visit in decades by Americans to this treeless city built of locally produced concrete blocks set atop permafrost. Three Soviets and three Americans on the journey are natives, and speak several local dialects including Yupik, a language common to Eskimos in both countries. The trek across ancient trade and migration routes up the Siberian side of the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Strait </LOCATION> and down the Alaskan side is to stop in 16 villages in the <LOCATION> Chukotka </LOCATION> district of <LOCATION> Siberia </LOCATION> and 14 in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, organizers said. It will end about April 1 in <LOCATION> Kotzebue </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION>, just above the <LOCATION> Arctic </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Circle </LOCATION> and about 550 miles northwest of <LOCATION> Anchorage </LOCATION>. `` Youth groups have arranged for festivities which will include receptions and sharing of native dances and, hopefully, some native foods,'' <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said. `` We expect we will come up with some sort of goodwill ceremony that we'll stick with for each of our visits, and then let it roll spontaneously.'' Negotiations began a week ago between the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> and the Soviets on re-opening the border closed by the Soviets during the <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION> blockade in 1948. <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON> said he hoped a treaty might be ready for signing as early as April 1 on the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Sea </LOCATION> ice. `` What marks this trip is the sheer volume of human contact,'' said <PERSON> Schurke </PERSON>, veteran of an unsupplied sled dog expedition to the North Pole in 1986. `` The populations of the villages we will be visiting totals close to 50,000.'' Most of the journey will be on relatively smooth coastal ice, with detours around pressure ridges and open water. There was concern about huge stretches of open water reported near the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> island of Little <PERSON> Diomede </PERSON> and the Soviet island of Big Diomede which flank the <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Dateline </ORGANIZATION> and the border dividing the two countries. `` There is big water in the <LOCATION> Bering </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Straits </LOCATION>,'' said <PERSON> Dimitri </PERSON> <PERSON> Shparo </PERSON>, the Soviet co-leader of the expedition who was speaking through an interpreter. `` That could force us to detour several hundred miles north to find ice. `` The farther we go into March, the more the sun will work on the ice,'' the 47-year-old polar explorer said. `` The -LRB- ocean -RRB- current moving through those two islands also is fierce.'' The expedition is only the latest attempt to warm the climate in superpower relations at the point where the nations are closest. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> and Soviet officials and <PERSON> Eskimos </PERSON> flew from <LOCATION> Nome </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Siberian </LOCATION> port of <LOCATION> Provideniya </LOCATION> for a one-day visit last spring, and a group of Soviets spent the last week of February in <LOCATION> Alaska </LOCATION> for talks with government and industry leaders.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0545EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-FutureFood     03-03 0588</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Future Food,0608</SECOND>
<HEAD>Food of the Future Heavy on the Microwave</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DANA KENNEDY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BOSTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The Pilgrims were happy with venison and beef jerky. Yuppies turned to blackened redfish and quiche. But are you ready for the meal of choice in the 21st century? Try gas flushed chicken. That entree was among an array of culinary choices outlined Thursday that food experts believe may comprise our menus in the future. More encouraging, however, is the ease with which we may buy such items. Video shopping, according to experts, is one possibility. Robot checkout cashiers is another. `` Fast food is too damn slow,'' said <PERSON> Marty </PERSON> <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>, editor of New Product News. `` No one has time for fast food anymore.'' But if the food writers and product spokesmen at the 11th annual <ORGANIZATION> International </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cooking </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Professionals </ORGANIZATION> are correct, we do n't have much to look forward to. They foresee a world where `` cooking becomes something few understand while heating becomes something everyone does.'' Fast food home delivery, triple packaged, resealable potato chips, oat bran popcorn, and `` melting pot ethnic foods'' like the `` burritski'' _ a burrito filled with Polish sausage _ are almost upon us. The real villain, they said, can be summed up in one word: microwave. Because today's busy career people want food on demand, the microwave is threatening to reshape the way we cook and eat, according to <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, director of marketing research for the <ORGANIZATION> Campbell </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Soup </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> `` They'll probably be one microwave per person in the future,'' said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>, who used a slide show to accompany his address at the convention. `` That way, no one will have to wait to eat.'' <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON> flashed a slide he said symbolized the microwave's impact on society. The picture showed a haughty waiter at a fancy restaurant asking a well-dressed patron, `` How would you like your steak done, sir?'' The customer responded: `` Three minutes on high, turned every 30 seconds.'' But countering the trend toward heavily packaged, microwave food has been the public's demand for fresh food without preservatives. `` The freshly prepared game was started by small entrepreneurs in major urban markets,'' said <PERSON> Nelson </PERSON>. `` Now the big boys want to play.'' The challenge facing food manufacturers in the future will be how to create fresh foods with a shelf life while keeping up with continual demands for products to use in the microwave, the panelists said. One example is gas flushed chicken, the term for a high-tech packaging process in which the bird is precooked without preservatives in a vacuum-sealed bag; the end result does n't require refrigeration. `` Convenience, health, indulgence _ those will be the major issues in the future,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gerstman </PERSON>, a food consultant with <PERSON> Gerstman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Myers </PERSON>. The current tendency toward `` cocooning,'' the panelists said, will play a major role in how food is purchased in the future. `` People are just going to want to put on their slippers and turn on the VCR. They wo n't want to go out,'' said <PERSON> Friedman </PERSON>. Stores in <LOCATION> Chicago </LOCATION> are already testing a cable home food shopping program and a chain in <LOCATION> Atlanta </LOCATION> is testing automated checkers, the panelists said. But for those who like an occasional foray to the supermarket, they may also find the shopping cart of the future has changed. `` Video carts'' will come with a flashing screen promoting various products. Among harried husbands and wives of the future, the experts predicted, the greeting upon returning home will be `` whose turn is it to heat?''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0021EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-SundayPost 1stLd-Writethru a0632 03-03 0810</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Sunday Post, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0632,0829</SECOND>
<HEAD>New York City Tabloid War Gets New Sunday Competitor</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: INSERTS 3 grafs after 5th graf, ``The sections ..., to UPDATE
with Post ad in NYTimes; picks up 6th graf: `Industry analysts ...</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By LARRY McSHANE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 NEW SUNDAY TABLOID IN NAKED CITY! This weekend, the <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> joins the crowd at the city's Sunday newsstands, its Fleet Street tilt a fading memory as it challenges the Daily News and <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Newsday for tabloid supremacy on the week's highest-stakes advertising day The Post is confident about its debut Sunday; its competitors are ready and waiting. `` When you see this paper on Saturday night, it's going to look like a Sunday paper that's been around for 30, 40 years,'' promised <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON>, the real estate magnate who saved the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> from extinction one year ago with a $ 37 million takeover. `` The sections are right, the comics are right, the magazine is right. It's really there.'' To let the public know its plans, the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> put commercials on television and a clever full-page advertisement Friday in one of its competitors, The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION>. The Times ad, in the form of two tabloid-size pages on the back of Times' front section, could be folded to simulate the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>'s front and back pages A banner news headline in the ad said it was `` Announcing A Cure For The Common Sunday.'' Another headline over what would be the sports page reads, `` Post Goes To Game 7!'' Industry analysts question if the financing and the market are right. They predict the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>'s move to Sunday _ where a successful newspaper makes 40 percent to 50 percent of its advertising money _ could mean the demise of at least one of the tabloids. `` The question is whether this market is capable of supporting three daily tabloids. Ask God and the readers,'' said Daily News Editor <PERSON> F. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gilman </PERSON> <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON>. `` This one is in stable shape, without any question. ... We're in good shape to take on all comers.'' <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON>, on the eve of running out 575,000 copies of the Sunday Post, believes three tabloids can live happily ever after in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Ad space for the first three weeks in the 128-page paper is sold out, including space in the pull-out book and travel sections, <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> said. He also cites changes recently made in the competition's Sunday editions as evidence his paper is already a factor: the News' expanded sports page, <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION>'s additional color pages <PERSON> Spencer </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Newsday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associate </ORGANIZATION> Publisher <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Isenberg </PERSON> said those moves were in works before the Post went weekend. None of this is expected to affect <ORGANIZATION> The </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> or its massive Sunday edition. The Times can `` stand back and wait, and then see who's left,'' said industry analyst <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>. But while <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> is confident, others in the industry remain skeptical. The last time the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION> had a Sunday edition was during a newspaper strike in 1978. It was scrapped when the strike ended. `` So far, there does not appear to be room for three profitable daily tabloids; that's certainly the same for Sunday,'' said newspaper analyst <PERSON> Bruce </PERSON> <PERSON> Thorp </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Provident </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bank </ORGANIZATION>. `` I'm not convinced there's room for two profitable daily tabloids. Agreed <PERSON> Morton </PERSON>, `` The problem is you've got a town that probably ca n't support that many newspapers. <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> is probably the last remaining city with the market segmentation to support two newspapers. `` But three or four, in the long run, is probably not do-able.'' The Post runs third in the city circulation race, trailing the Daily News -LRB- 1,281,706 -RRB- and The <ORGANIZATION> New </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> York </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> -LRB- 1,038,829 -RRB- and leading <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> Newsday -LRB- 176,043 -RRB-, according to the <ORGANIZATION> Audit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Bureau </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Circulations </ORGANIZATION> figures from Sept 30, 1988. <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> anticipates a similar Sunday showing. <PERSON> Morton </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thorp </PERSON> cited other problems the Post faces: lack of home delivery -LRB- <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> says a major push to change that is under way. -RRB-; overcoming Sunday readership loyalty -LRB- <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> believes the paper's 550,473 weekday readers will buy the <ORGANIZATION> Post </ORGANIZATION>. -RRB-; tremendous start-up costs -LRB- <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON>, without mentioning figures, says the Sunday paper is here to stay. -RRB-. Here for the paper's first 12 weeks is a reader inducement _ a $ 1 million stock market game which also will run in weekdays. More likely to draw readers are the changes wrought at the Post under editor <PERSON> Jane </PERSON> <PERSON> Amsterdam </PERSON> in the year since <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON>'s purchase of the paper, which was founded in 1801 by <PERSON> Alexander </PERSON> <PERSON> Hamilton </PERSON>. Gone are many of the <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Murdoch </PERSON> flourishes which marked his reign at the Post: no more `` HEADLESS BODY IN TOPLESS BAR'' headlines, no unchallenged liberal-bashing, no jam-packed pages desperate for space. `` Things have improved on a financial basis, the morale has improved, the quality of the paper has improved,'' <PERSON> Kalikow </PERSON> said. `` Things have really improved far beyond what we had ever expected.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0447EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-CDC--Flu     03-03 0570</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-CDC--Flu,0585</SECOND>
<HEAD>New Survey Shows Most Americans _ Even The Old _ Ignore Flu Shots</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BYRD</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ATLANTA (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Millions of Americans age 65 and over should get flu shots every year but most do n't bother, in part because of unfounded fears of the vaccine, federal health experts say. The national <ORGANIZATION> Centers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Disease </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Control </ORGANIZATION> said Thursday that only 12 percent of Americans in a recent survey said they had received an influenza vaccination in the preceding year. That included only 32 percent of those 65 and over, a group at increased risk for death or severe complications from the flu. An official 1990 <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> health objective calling for at least 60 percent of older Americans to receive annual flu shots `` is not likely to be met,'' the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> conceded in its report. `` Unfortunately, there are a lot of fears of side effects from the vaccine, and a lot of misconceptions that the vaccine can cause influenza _ neither of which is true,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Ann </PERSON> <PERSON> Sprauer </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> immunization specialist. Current flu vaccines do not cause influenza themselves, and they cause a day or two of fever and aches in fewer than 10 percent of those who take the shot, she said. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s survey on health risks and behavior patterns was conducted in 1987 in 31 participating states and <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>, D.C. Only 7 percent of those 18-44, 11 percent of those 45-64 and 32 percent of those 65 and up said they had received flu vaccine in the previous 12 months. The <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> especially recommends flu vaccine for people at increased risk of severe complications from influenza, including older people and those already suffering from certain chronic medical problems such as heart disease. Other surveys have shown that `` only about 20 percent of high-risk individuals get the shot in a typical year,'' said Dr. <PERSON> Walter </PERSON> <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON>, a CDC flu specialist. In addition to fears about the vaccine, he said, many people `` just do n't know that flu typically kills 20,000 Americans in the average year.'' Adding to the problem, Ms. <PERSON> Sprauer </PERSON> said, is the fact that `` often, health care providers do n't recommend the vaccine. A lot of -LRB- patients -RRB- would be willing to get it if it were offered to them.'' Among the states participating in the health-risk survey, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> had the worst rate of flu vaccination, only 9 percent. <LOCATION> Hawaii </LOCATION> was highest at 19 percent. Among older people in particular, percentages ranged from 24 percent in <LOCATION> Rhode </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Island </LOCATION> to 41 percent in <LOCATION> Montana </LOCATION>. Flu vaccine is believed to be about 90 percent effective in preventing illness in healthy younger people and about 75 percent effective in preventing serious illness or death in high-risk elderly populations, the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> reported. The Atlanta-based <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION> also reported Thursday that the 1988-89 flu season is continuing at serious levels. A key indicator of severe flu activity _ the <ORGANIZATION> CDC </ORGANIZATION>'s tracking of deaths from either pneumonia or flu in selected cities _ was at higher-than-expected levels last week for the fifth week in a row, <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON> said. That indicator now has reached its highest point this winter, `` as bad as anything we've had in the past several years,'' he said. <PERSON> Gunn </PERSON> said the predominant flu strains circulating in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> are those known as the <LOCATION> Victoria </LOCATION> flu, the <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION> flu and the <LOCATION> Sichuan </LOCATION> flu, all of which are protected against by the recommended 1988-89 flu vaccine.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0219EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-PorkRinds     03-03 0844</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Pork Rinds,0868</SECOND>
<HEAD>Pork Rinds Stem From South's `Waste Not, Want Not' Tradition</HEAD>
<HEAD>RETRANSMITTING a0408, fixing cycle designator.</HEAD>
<HEAD>Also in Friday AMs report.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DENNIS PATTERSON</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NAHUNTA, N.C. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Even in good times it's hard for Southerners to trash anything that comes from a hog, hence the presidential snack, pork rinds. `` You do n't throw nothing away,'' said <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, manager of the <ORGANIZATION> Nahunta </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pork </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION>. `` You use everything from a hog but the squeal.'' `` It's the finest food substance available on the planet,'' said state Sen. <PERSON> Wendell </PERSON> <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Duplin </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> hog farmer and one of the largest pork producers in the nation. Hogs provide hams, pork chops, bacon and sausage. Their feet are pickled, the intestines are used as casings for sausage, the tails are used for seasoning and the hide ends up in fancy driving gloves, <ORGANIZATION> Hush </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Puppy </ORGANIZATION> shoes and President <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s favorite munchie. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, who produces pork rinds, thinks it's great that <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> prefers them with Tabasco sauce. But if the president wants some of <LOCATION> Nahunta </LOCATION>'s home-style skins, he'll have to come to this crossroads 50 miles southeast of <LOCATION> Raleigh </LOCATION> to get them. `` It will probably be good for the pork industry, but there's not much way for it to help our business,'' said <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>, whose father founded the company 24 years ago. `` We process 100 skins a week and ca n't meet the demand from our customers as it is.'' The pork company, which makes up most of <LOCATION> Nahunta </LOCATION>, started as a slaughterhouse in 1955 and added retail pork sales in 1975. It does not distribute its products, but more than 3,000 people a week come by to pick out fresh pork and cured hams. They also grab up 99-cent bags of <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON>'s salted and deep-fried pork skins. `` We process about 500 hogs a week,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said, `` but we're real particular about the skins we use If they are n't quite up to snuff, we wo n't use them. That's why we only turn about 100 skins a week into pork rinds.'' A special machine slices the skin off of pork pieces. The skin pieces are cooked for four hours in vats to dry out the fat. Then the hard, shriveled skins are deep fried. The pieces of skin swell and pop, turning into puffy slabs of rind in minutes. `` This is our scientific measuring process,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said as he dipped a handful of salt from a bucket and spread it over the fried rinds. `` Ones that come out like this, we throw away,'' he said, plucking a dark, hard chunk from among the beige sheets of fried skin. `` And we've got two grades of rinds. `` The ones that come out really nice and thin are No. Ones,'' he said. `` Your thicker skins that come out a little tougher are No. Twos.'' A bag of No. Ones, which weighs a little more than 3 ounces, and a 12-ounce bag of No. Twos go for the same price _ 99 cents. `` We actually sell more of the No. Twos,'' <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said. `` People seem to like to gnaw on them a little bit.'' A half-ounce serving of pork rinds provides little in the way of nutrition; potato chips and peanuts have more nutrients, but also more fat and cholesterol. A <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agriculture </ORGANIZATION> analysis showed a two-ounce package of rinds contains 315 calories; 32.5 grams of protein; 18.9 grams of fat; 58 milligrams of cholesterol; and 1,054 milligrams of salt. The <ORGANIZATION> Snack </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> said pork rind sales nationally totaled $ 195 million in 1987, a figure dwarfed by potato chips, which had $ 3.8 billion in sales the same year. <PERSON> Dwayne </PERSON> <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON>, a professor of food science at <ORGANIZATION> North </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Carolina </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> State </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION>, said the origin of pork rinds is lost in history. `` I do n't know when people started popping skins or why,'' <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON> said. `` I do n't know if it's a takeoff from the old days of crackling or what.'' Crackling, or cracklin', is hog fat that has the lard squeezed out of it and is then cooked. In some areas, the layer of fat was ground up with the skin to make the crisp treat. `` It could be that somebody had a piece of skin left over from cracklin', put it on a stove and it popped, sort of an accidental discovery,'' <PERSON> Pilkington </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Pierce </PERSON> said he is n't sure why pork rinds have remained a regional delicacy, limited mainly to the South. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, who raises a million hogs a year, said other areas of the country have just lagged behind the South in realizing how good pork rinds are. `` Anybody that does n't like them has just never tasted them,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON>, a Democrat, said he was aware of the Republican president's use of symbolism in the 1988 campaign, but he did not believe <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> used pork rinds as a populist snack to fight a less-than-macho image. `` I really think he ate them before the presidential campaign,'' <PERSON> Murphy </PERSON> said. `` But maybe nobody paid much attention to what he ate when he was n't the president. The office sure changes that.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a PM-DynamiteWine     03-03 0378</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Dynamite Wine,0389</SECOND>
<HEAD>Beirut Vintner Dodges Bombs To Make Great Wine</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JACK SCHREIBMAN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>SAN FRANCISCO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Winemaker <PERSON> Serge </PERSON> <PERSON> Hochar </PERSON>, like some of his competitors, likes to sell no wine before its time. But in war-torn <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, it's not always up to him to decide. `` You never know if you'll be hit,'' <PERSON> Hochar </PERSON> said Wednesday, adding that he's missed some vintages when fighting broke out near his Chateau Musar, the best-known of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s five wineries. `` I must say, I have been very lucky,'' said the vintner, whose products are internationally rated among the top wines of the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>. `` My home, 200 yards from the fire line between east and west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, has been bombed only three times in the last 14 years, and I managed to escape.'' The Beirut-born winemaker, who is in his 50s, styles his wine for cosmopolitan tastes. He was in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> on Wednesday on a seven-city <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> tour to market his wines, which ranged from 1959 to 1980. Despite his unpredictable environment, <PERSON> Hochar </PERSON> says he will not release a vintage if he does n't like it, and he insists on holding his wines in cellars for at least eight years. `` I am not a political man. I am a wine man, and a wine man is a human person because I work with life. I keep my vines and my wines alive,'' he said. Hochar makes 15,000 to 20,000 cases of wine a year at the 30-year-old winery founded by his father, <PERSON> Gaston </PERSON>. The star is his <ORGANIZATION> Bordeaux </ORGANIZATION> red, a blend of cabernet sauvignon, cinsault and syrah. It can take weeks for <LOCATION> Hochar </LOCATION> to get grapes from the <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION>, 40 miles south of <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION>, to his winery in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s embattled capital city. `` We have to cross five or six checkpoints, many borders ... sometimes we have to go south from the vineyard and sail back by boat.'' And everywhere, he said, he must pay duty, at each border and to whomever has the power _ or a gun. `` You get used to it after a while,'' he said. `` You do n't realize you are in a war situation You live with it. ... In <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, you can always manage to find a few friends to make things easier.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0237EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a BC-Opera     03-03 0303</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Opera,0317</SECOND>
<HEAD>Neil Shicoff Triumphs in `Werther'</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: No PMs Planned</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MARY CAMPBELL</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>NEW YORK (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Tenor <PERSON> Neil </PERSON> <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON> triumphed in the title role of `` Werther'' on Thursday night as the Metropolitan Opera performed the Massenet opera for the first time this season. In the first scene, when <PERSON> Werther </PERSON> is marveling at a garden, the emotionalism of the <PERSON> Goethe </PERSON> hero was in his voice. Later, <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON>'s voice shimmered, without any of the Italian sound which would be wrong for this French opera After an exceptionally long second intermission, an announcement was made that <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON> had been suffering from flu for a week but would continue. This was a surprise, since neither vocal difficulty nor the added resonance that a cold sometimes gives were heard. <PERSON> Shicoff </PERSON>'s final act was as splendid as the two before. He even managed to create sympathy for Werther, longing for <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>, who is married. We have n't great patience for Werther's romanticism these days. Mezzo-soprano <PERSON> Kathleen </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuhlmann </PERSON>, who was born in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, was making her Met debut as <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>. She get fulls marks for vocal production and preparation of the role but her voice is n't attractive It is n't shrill or harsh; it just is n't appealing in tone. She sang <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION> in a new production in <LOCATION> Cologne </LOCATION> and will sing the part in a new production in <LOCATION> Hamburg </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Dawn </PERSON> <PERSON> Upshaw </PERSON>, as <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>'s sister, <PERSON> Sophie </PERSON>, has a clear but creamy soprano. Instead of getting by on being pert as some Sophies do, the Nashville-born soprano sang it beautifully. <PERSON> Bernd </PERSON> <PERSON> Weikl </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION> sang <PERSON> Albert </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Charlotte </LOCATION>'s husband, for the first time at the Met, with a warmly inflected voice. The four are all attractive on stage. <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Fournet </PERSON> from <LOCATION> Rouen </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> France </LOCATION>, conducted. He made his Met debut in 1987 with another <LOCATION> French </LOCATION> opera, `` <PERSON> Samson </PERSON> and Dalila.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-ReactorBarge     03-03 0358</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Reactor Barge,0366</SECOND>
<HEAD>Barge Moving Decommissioned Reactor On 8,100-Mile Water Trip</HEAD>
<DATELINE>CINCINNATI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 An <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> barge carrying a 1,000-ton nuclear reactor from the nation's first decommissioned commercial nuclear power plant passed this city Thursday on its two-month, 8,100-mile trip to burial at <LOCATION> Hanford </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Wash. </LOCATION> `` There's a bit of history here,'' said <PERSON> Mike </PERSON> <PERSON> McKerman </PERSON>, a consultant to the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Department </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Energy </ORGANIZATION> on the project. `` I like to think of it as the end of the beginning of nuclear power.'' <PERSON> McKernan </PERSON> said the nuclear plant at <LOCATION> Shippingport </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Pa. </LOCATION>, was the first commercial nuclear plant to be commissioned in the <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and the first to be decommissioned. It is the first in the world to be dismantled. <ORGANIZATION> Duquesne </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Light </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> began operating the plant in 1957 and closed it down in 1982. <ORGANIZATION> Duquesne </ORGANIZATION> operates two other nuclear power plants at <LOCATION> Shippingport </LOCATION>, about 35 miles southwest of <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION> along the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>. Earlier this month, the reactor was mounted on the barge <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunyan </PERSON>. The barge, pushed by the motor vessel <PERSON> Pere </PERSON> <PERSON> Marquette </PERSON>, left <LOCATION> Shippingport </LOCATION> on Tuesday for <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Orleans </LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION> DOE </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Bauman </PERSON> said. `` The DOE has spent a lot of money on this thing to make sure it is safe,'' said <PERSON> Al </PERSON> <PERSON> Zupon </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Engineers </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>. `` You could sit on top of this thing and ride it down the river with no threat of radiation.'' `` We are being updated on the tow's progress twice a day,'' <PERSON> McKerman </PERSON> said. `` So far, there have been no problems. It is moving along just as it was planned.'' The reactor, which is 35 feet long and 25 feet high and encased in concrete, is being shipped to an Energy Department disposal site for burial, <PERSON> Bauman </PERSON> said. The vessel will take the <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> to the <LOCATION> Mississippi </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION>, to the <LOCATION> Gulf </LOCATION> <LOCATION> of </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>, to the <LOCATION> Panama </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Canal </LOCATION>, and the <LOCATION> Pacific </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Ocean </LOCATION> north to <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> state. The journey is expected to take about 60 days, officials said. The reactor parts were packed in concrete before being loaded onto the <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Bunyan </PERSON> last month, but the trip was delayed because of bad weather, <PERSON> Bauman </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0231EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-WritingAwards 1stLd-Writethru a0692 03-03 0999</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Writing Awards, 1st Ld-Writethru, a0692,1072</SECOND>
<HEAD>Writers Guild of America Announces Nominations For Writing Awards</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: SUBS 15th graf, `_Richard Alfieri, ... to CORRECT title of teleplay
to ``A Friendship in Vienna,'' sted ``The Devil in Vienna;'' the title
of the book ``Devil in Vienna'' is CQ.</HEAD>
<DATELINE>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> announced its nominees for achievement in television and radio writing Thursday, giving writers of <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> television shows a slight edge over writers for <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>. Writers for shows appearing on <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> received 15 nominations, while writers for shows featured on <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> received 14 and writers of shows shown on <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> received 11 nominations. In the radio division, with only two categories, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> writers received four nominations; <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> writers received three nods. Winners of the 41st annual <ORGANIZATION> Writers </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guild </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> America </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Awards </ORGANIZATION> will be announced March 20 in joint ceremonies on both coasts. WGA West ceremonies will be held at the Beverly Hilton Hotel here and <ORGANIZATION> WGA </ORGANIZATION> East ceremonies will take place at the <ORGANIZATION> World </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Trade </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Center </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION>. Screen awards will also be presented at that time. Nominations for those awards were announced earlier. The television and radio nominations are: Original Long Form: _ <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Feather </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidler </PERSON>, `` My Father, My Son,'' CBS Movie of the Week _ <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> and <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, teleplay, `` The Murder of <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Phagan </PERSON>, Part 1,'' story by <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> McMurtry </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> mini-series _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Luce </PERSON>, `` The Woman He Loved,'' CBS Movie of the Week _ <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Morrill </PERSON>, `` The Taking of Flight 847: The <PERSON> Uli </PERSON> <PERSON> Derickson </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> Movie of the Week _ <PERSON> Dennis </PERSON> <PERSON> Nemec </PERSON>, `` God Bless the Child,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Movie of the Week _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Sacret </PERSON> <PERSON> Young </PERSON>, `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> pilot Adapted Long Form: _ <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Alfieri </PERSON>, teleplay, `` A Friendship in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>,'' based on the book `` Devil in <LOCATION> Vienna </LOCATION>'' by <PERSON> Doris </PERSON> <PERSON> Orgel </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> Disney </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Channel </ORGANIZATION> movie premiere _ <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Foxfire,'' based on the play by <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Cooper </PERSON> and <PERSON> Hume </PERSON> <PERSON> Cronyn </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> Movie of the Week _ <PERSON> Jacqueline </PERSON> <PERSON> Feather </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Seidler </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Onassis: The Richest Man in the World, Part 1,'' based on the book `` Ari: The Life and <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aristotle </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Onassis </ORGANIZATION>'' by <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Evans </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> movie premiere _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gay </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Inherit the Wind,'' based on the play by <PERSON> Jerome </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> and <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> movie premiere _ <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> McGreevey </PERSON>, teleplay, `` The Fortunate Pilgrim, Part 1,'' based on the book by <PERSON> Mario </PERSON> <PERSON> Puzo </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> mini-series Anthology Episode-Single Program: _ <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Grant </PERSON> <PERSON> Craig </PERSON>, `` Daddy's Girl,'' `` <PERSON> Alfred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitchcock </PERSON> Presents,'' <ORGANIZATION> USA </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cable </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Knopf </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Simons </PERSON>, `` Mad Adventure,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> pilot _ <PERSON> Andy </PERSON> <PERSON> Wolk </PERSON>, teleplay, `` <PERSON> Natica </PERSON> <PERSON> Jackson </PERSON>'' -LRB- `` Tales from the <LOCATION> Hollywood </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Hills </LOCATION>'' -RRB- based on a story by <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> O'Hara </PERSON>, WNET-Thirteen Episodic Drama: _ <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Broyles </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, `` Home,'' for `` <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Beach </LOCATION>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON> and <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kelley </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Full Marital Jacket'' for `` L.A. Law,'' story by <PERSON> Steven </PERSON> <PERSON> Bochco </PERSON> and <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Louise </PERSON> <PERSON> Fisher </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontana </PERSON>, teleplay, `` A Moon for the Misbegotten'' for `` St Elsewhere,'' story by <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Fontana </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Tinker </PERSON> and <PERSON> Channing </PERSON> <PERSON> Gibson </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION>. _ <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Haggis </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Nice Work if You Can Get It'' for `` thirtysomething,'' story by <PERSON> Jean </PERSON> <PERSON> Vallely </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Marshall </PERSON> <PERSON> Herskovitz </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edward </PERSON> <PERSON> Zwick </PERSON>, `` thirtysomething'' pilot, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Shilliday </PERSON>, `` Therapy'' for `` thirtysomething,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Episodic Comedy: _ <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON> and <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlens </PERSON>, `` My Father's Office'' for `` The Wonder Years,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Gary </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Goldberg </PERSON>, `` The Way We Were'' for `` Family Ties,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Neal </PERSON> <PERSON> Marlens </PERSON> and <PERSON> Carol </PERSON> <PERSON> Black </PERSON>, `` The Wonder Years'' pilot, <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Kathy </PERSON> <PERSON> Speer </PERSON> and <PERSON> Terry </PERSON> <PERSON> Grossman </PERSON>, `` Old Friends'' for `` The Golden Girls,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Tom </PERSON> <PERSON> Straw </PERSON>, `` No Hard Feelings'' for `` Night Court,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Tarses </PERSON>, `` The ` Slap' Maxwell Story, Part 1,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> Variety _ Musical, Award, Tribute, Special Event: _ <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Elinson </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON>, <PERSON> Marvin </PERSON> <PERSON> Silbermintz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Teitzell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Hermann </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Leno </PERSON>'s Family Comedy Hour,'' <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> comedy-variety special _ <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Juhl </PERSON>, `` A Muppet Family Christmas,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> special _ <PERSON> Matt </PERSON> <PERSON> Neuman </PERSON>, <PERSON> Larry </PERSON> <PERSON> Arnstein </PERSON>, <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Barker </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> <PERSON> Hall </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Hurwitz </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Kramer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Elaine </PERSON> <PERSON> Pope </PERSON>, <PERSON> Lane </PERSON> <PERSON> Sarasohn </PERSON>, `` Not Necessarily the News of the World,'' HBO comedy-variety special _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jeffrey </PERSON> <PERSON> Lane </PERSON>, `` AFI Life Achievement Award: A Salute to <PERSON> Jack </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemmon </PERSON>,'' CBS variety special _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Lukinson </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bob </PERSON> <PERSON> Shrum </PERSON>, `` The Kennedy Center Honors: A Celebration of the Performing Arts,'' CBS variety special Children's Script: _ <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenbaum </PERSON> and <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, teleplay, `` A Mouse, A Mystery and Me,'' story by <PERSON> Everett </PERSON> <PERSON> Greenbaum </PERSON>, <PERSON> Harvey </PERSON> <PERSON> Bullock </PERSON>, <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Shorts </PERSON> and <PERSON> Chris </PERSON> <PERSON> Solada </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> NBC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Blanche </PERSON> <PERSON> Hanalis </PERSON>, teleplay, `` The Secret Garden,'' based on the book by <PERSON> Frances </PERSON> <PERSON> Hodgson </PERSON> <PERSON> Burnett </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Victoria </PERSON> <PERSON> Hochberg </PERSON>, `` Just a Regular Kid: An AIDS Story,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Joanna </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON>, `` The Kid Who Would n't Quit _ The <PERSON> Brad </PERSON> <PERSON> Silverman </PERSON> <PERSON> Story </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Kathryn </PERSON> <PERSON> Montgomery </PERSON>, teleplay, `` Home Sweet Homeless,'' story by <PERSON> Steve </PERSON> <PERSON> Falgenbaum </PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> Documentary _ Current Events: _ <PERSON> Laura </PERSON> <PERSON> Carter </PERSON>, `` Inside <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION>: The Power, Poverty and Pride,'' <ORGANIZATION> KCBS-TV </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Irv </PERSON> <PERSON> Drasnin </PERSON>, `` Apartheid _ Part V,'' PBS _ <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, `` Who Pays for AIDS,'' PBS Documentary _ Other than Current Events: _ <PERSON> Theodore </PERSON> <PERSON> Bogosian </PERSON>, `` An Armenian Journey,'' WGBH-PBS _ <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Jampel </PERSON>, `` Mysteries of <LOCATION> Mankind </LOCATION>,'' WQED-PBS _ <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Smith </PERSON>, `` How Good is Soviet Science,'' PBS _ <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Stevens </PERSON>: A Filmmaker's Journey,'' PBS _ <PERSON> Susan </PERSON> <PERSON> Yankowitz </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Sylvia </PERSON> <PERSON> Plath </PERSON>: Arrow to the Sun,'' PBS Television Spot News: _ <PERSON> Jerry </PERSON> <PERSON> Cipriano </PERSON>, <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Fischer </PERSON>, <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON>, <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mosedale </PERSON>, <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, `` <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> Summit,'' CBS Evening News _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> Cobin </PERSON>, `` Airshow Crash,'' WCBS-TV _ <PERSON> Hugh </PERSON> <PERSON> Heckman </PERSON> and <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Phillips </PERSON>, `` The Crash of'87,'' CBS _ <PERSON> Leonard </PERSON> <PERSON> Lipton </PERSON>, `` Entertainment Week in Review,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Mary </PERSON> <PERSON> Munford </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Heifetz </PERSON> <PERSON> Obituary </PERSON>,'' CBS Daytime Serials: _ <PERSON> Claire </PERSON> <PERSON> Labine </PERSON>, <PERSON> Eleanor </PERSON> <PERSON> Mancusi </PERSON>, <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Burritt </PERSON>, <PERSON> Madeline </PERSON> <PERSON> B. </PERSON> <PERSON> David </PERSON>, <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> Appell </PERSON>, <PERSON> Rocco </PERSON> <PERSON> Bufano </PERSON> and <PERSON> Matthew </PERSON> <PERSON> Labine </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>'s Hope,'' _ <PERSON> Pamela </PERSON> <PERSON> J </PERSON> Long, <PERSON> Trent </PERSON> <PERSON> Jones </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Curlee </PERSON>, <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Demorest </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Williams </PERSON>, <PERSON> Nancy </PERSON> <PERSON> Franklin </PERSON>, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Culliton </PERSON>, <PERSON> Gail </PERSON> <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON>, <PERSON> Pete </PERSON> <PERSON> Rich </PERSON> and <PERSON> Melissa </PERSON> <PERSON> Salmons </PERSON>, `` Guiding Light,'' CBS. Radio Documentary: _ <PERSON> Jill </PERSON> <PERSON> Landes </PERSON>, `` Where Valor Proudly Sleeps,'' Newsmark, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Norman </PERSON> <PERSON> Morris </PERSON>, `` Exploring America 1988: Footprints of Spring,'' <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Pam </PERSON> <PERSON> Rauscher </PERSON>, `` President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> Goes to <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>,'' Newsmark, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Ryan </PERSON>, `` Children as Consumers,'' <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> States </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Networks </ORGANIZATION> Radio Spot News: _ <PERSON> Les </PERSON> <PERSON> Blatt </PERSON>, `` <PERSON> Peter </PERSON> <PERSON> Jennings </PERSON> <PERSON> Journal </PERSON>,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Stu </PERSON> <PERSON> Chamberlain </PERSON>, `` World News This Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> Gil </PERSON> <PERSON> Longin </PERSON>, `` World News This Week,'' <ORGANIZATION> ABC </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> _ <PERSON> David </PERSON> <PERSON> P. </PERSON> <PERSON> Ysals </PERSON>, `` News of the Day,'' Aug. 22, 1988, <ORGANIZATION> CBS </ORGANIZATION>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-TheMonthly'sFolly Bjt   03-03 0718</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-The Monthly's Folly, Bjt,730</SECOND>
<HEAD>Magazine Boss Asks Former Employees to Set Him Straight</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MIKE FEINSILBER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Randolph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hearst </PERSON> could n't have put it clearer. `` Why,'' asked editor <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, summing up the philosophy that has guided his magazine for 20 years, `` should I publish something I do n't agree with?'' Nonetheless, to celebrate a survival that was never a sure thing, the March issue of <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>' skinny magazine, the <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> Monthly, violates his own premise. `` What's Wrong With This Magazine?'' asks the cover. Inside, 11 former editors are allowed to take issue with the boss, one of <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>'s enduring curmudgeons. The result: the reader gets to watch liberalism argue with itself. None of March's contributors quarrels with the Monthly's fundamental liberal philosophy _ one it is no more likely to abandon than Popular Mechanics would question the utility of the basement workbench But, like <ORGANIZATION> Popular </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mechanics </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>' magazine has been concerned with the way things actually work and why they do n't if they do n't. His view is that they often do n't; his goal is `` to expose and correct the follies of liberalism.'' He calls it neoliberalism. `` We were not trying to move the <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> to the right,'' recalls former Monthly writer <PERSON> Nicholas </PERSON> <PERSON> Lemann </PERSON>. `` We were trying to make liberalism even better and stronger than it already was.'' Like scores of other onetime Monthly writers, <PERSON> Lemann </PERSON> moved on to better pay, in his case at the <LOCATION> Atlantic </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> paid his editors $ 10,000 a year _ himself $ 24,000 _ but gave them the chance to write and be read in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. The magazine has 33,000 subscribers and, after a long struggle, is in the black. <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>, a former <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION> legislator and <ORGANIZATION> Peace </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corps </ORGANIZATION> executive, founded it with some help from investors including Sen. <PERSON> Jay </PERSON> <PERSON> Rockefeller </PERSON>, D-W. <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, a fellow former Peace <PERSON> Arthur </PERSON> <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>, now with <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> & </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> amp </ORGANIZATION>; World Report, takes the Monthly to task for not coming to grips with the full consequences of its advocacy of a less greedy way of life. `` If we're to be less materialistic ... it means that we'll buy fewer products and there will be less revenue for business. The hard question that neoliberals and others have n't asked is: Can we have more time for families and volunteerism, less materialism, and still have high economic growth? I do n't think so.'' <PERSON> Gregg </PERSON> <PERSON> Easterbrook </PERSON>, now a contributing editor of <ORGANIZATION> Newsweek </ORGANIZATION>, accuses the Monthly of harboring an unwholesome suspicion of profits. `` Occasionally companies make big profits via fraud, monopoly or other chicanery,'' he writes. `` Usually they make big profits because they deserve to _ the market is pretty effective in distributing that reward.'' Anyway, asks <PERSON> Easterbrook </PERSON>, what's so bad about the `` service-yuppie-paper economy'' that <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> is becoming? `` The Monthly often laments that the backbreaking, dangerous, soul-draining jobs in heavy industrial production are being replaced by highly paid white-collar desk jobs. Sounds pretty good to me.'' <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON>, now editor of The <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Republic </LOCATION>, attacks <PERSON> Peters </PERSON>' perennial crusade for a peacetime draft `` Telling people they must give up two years of their lives is a major infringement on freedom,'' <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON> argues. Moreover, if rich people were drafted into the Army they would push out poor people who are there because they want to be, he says. `` It's no favor to would-be volunteers to shut off this option in order to put others unwillingly in their place.'' <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> gives himself the last word, accepting many of the criticisms but taking issue with others. To <PERSON> Easterbrook </PERSON>, he says that what's wrong with maximizing profits `` is that it encourages corporations to take chances with worker safety, to pollute the air, to attempt to gain monopoly control of markets.'' To <PERSON> Levine </PERSON>'s growth arguments, he says, `` Without economic growth, we wo n't have the tax revenues necessary to clear up the environmental mess that already exists.'' And to <PERSON> Kinsley </PERSON> he says a draft would give <LOCATION> America </LOCATION> at least one social institution where rich and poor could come to know and understand one another. `` Upper-class participation in the military would give people with clout a compelling interest in avoiding war and, in case war turns out to be unavoidable, in being equipped with weapons that work,'' <PERSON> Peters </PERSON> writes. `` Thus a draft of the wealthy would both aid military reformers and enhance the prospect for peace.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0238EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-NorthTrial Bjt   03-03 0595</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-North Trial, Bjt,600</SECOND>
<HEAD>Censorship Issue Argued in North Trial</HEAD>
<HEAD>EDs: hearing at 10 a.m. EST; will be led.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By PETE YOST</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 The jury in <PERSON> Oliver </PERSON> <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s Iran-Contra trial had the day off today so the former <ORGANIZATION> White </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> aide's lawyers could detail complaints that the government is censoring material to hamstring the defense. <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> District Judge <PERSON> Gerhard </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> is hearing arguments from <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s attorneys that the Classified Information Procedures Act governing the handling of classified material in criminal trials should not be applied in this case. North is accused of lying to <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> and the attorney general about the <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> administration's secret attempts to aid the Nicaraguan Contras during a period in which <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> aid to the rebels was banned. The government has made repeated attempts to censor evidence in the case. The defense said in a court filing that the office of independent counsel <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Walsh </PERSON> `` has knowingly obstructed the conduct of this trial'' as well as the cross-examination of a witness `` by imposing entirely unnecessary secrecy demands on information already in the public domain.'' Prosecutor <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Keker </PERSON> responded: `` Far from manipulating the process to its advantage, the government is trying to declassify the information that is necessary to permit this trial to reach a conclusion.'' The latest fight erupted when <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s lawyers discovered that memos the government was trying to censor in court had been made public eight months earlier in a separate legal case. Defense lawyers said they found out Monday night that classified memos written by <PERSON> North </PERSON>'s courier to the Contras, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Owen </PERSON>, had been turned over earlier to the <ORGANIZATION> Christic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, which opposes <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> policy in Central America. Confronted with that information, the government said it would no longer consider the memos to be classified. <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON>, however, said he would review his rulings on secrecy in light of the problem. North's lawyers filed a motion to dismiss the indictment on grounds of prosecutorial misconduct, but <PERSON> Gesell </PERSON> said he was n't looking for `` sanctions'' against anyone He said his primary goal is to see that the trial is conducted properly. On Thursday, two people involved in the Contra supply network testified that <PERSON> North </PERSON> appeared to be the man in charge. <PERSON> Rafael </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON>, a Cuban who had done work for the <ORGANIZATION> CIA </ORGANIZATION>, said <PERSON> North </PERSON> sought to reassure a high Salvadoran air force official that President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> supported the Contra resupply effort. <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> said that at a 1986 meeting in <LOCATION> El </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Salvador </LOCATION>, the official expressed concern about joining with <PERSON> North </PERSON> and others in assisting the Contras and then possibly being `` left out in the cold'' after a few weeks or months. North, <PERSON> Quintero </PERSON> said, responded that `` Mr. <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> was totally behind this program and behind helping the Contras and all we needed was more time for <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> to approve ... aid.'' In another instance, retired <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> Lt. Col. <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON>, who helped arrange for airplanes to carry supplies to the Contras, described a meeting with <PERSON> North </PERSON> in December 1985 at a <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION> hotel. <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON> said <PERSON> North </PERSON> turned to another <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION> retiree involved in the resupply operation, <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Secord </PERSON>, and directed him to `` advance Mr. <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON> $ 150,000'' for parachutes and other items the Contras wanted. <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON> subsequently got $ 100,000. <PERSON> Gadd </PERSON> arranged to provide airplanes for the covert Contra supply operation at a time when <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military aid to the Contras was banned by <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION>. North is accused of 12 crimes, including five counts that he made false statements and obstructed <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> in 1985 and 1986 by denying any involvement in the Contra resupply operation.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0317EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i PM-Britain-Spies     03-03 0704</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Britain-Spies,0726</SECOND>
<HEAD>Gorbachev Era Alters The Face Of British Spy Novels</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By MATT WOLF</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>LONDON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 As glasnost and perestroika unfold in <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>'s <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, British spy novelists are looking beyond the Evil Empire rhetoric to a more complicated approach that blurs enemy lines. `` What we've lost is the natural assumption that if you say Russians, you're talking about a certain character,'' says <PERSON> Gavin </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyall </PERSON>, creator of the popular cloak-and-dagger character <PERSON> Harry </PERSON> <PERSON> Maxim </PERSON>. `` You ca n't be as simplistic anymore; you move in a direction of possibly more subtlety,'' said <PERSON> Lyall </PERSON>, 57. <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Sampson </PERSON> remarked in The Independent newspaper recently that `` those beloved villains -LRB- the Soviets -RRB- are losing their villainy.'' `` They've all been undermined by that exasperatingly soft-spoken <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON>, as he insists on retreating from every filmic battleground from <LOCATION> Afghanistan </LOCATION> to <LOCATION> Angola </LOCATION>.'' Comments Sunday Times TV critic <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Stoddart </PERSON>: `` If we are no longer to be scared of Reds under the bed, what on earth are we going to read before we turn out the light?'' The drawing power of Cold War drama remains strong, however, as shown by `` Game, Set and Match,'' a 13-part television adaptation of spy novelist <PERSON> Len </PERSON> <PERSON> Deighton </PERSON>'s trilogy. Aired in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> last fall, it won critical acclaim and high ratings. The <PERSON> Deighton </PERSON> trilogy, about a <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> intelligence agent whose wife turns out to be a Soviet plant, was written before glasnost became a household word. But in interviews on the TV set, co-director <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Lau </PERSON> insisted the work was glasnost-inspired in that `` the enemy is no longer drawn in broadstroke cartoon characters.'' <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>, publishing director of Century-Hutchinson books and former editor of famed spy novelist <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Le </PERSON> <PERSON> Carre </PERSON>, said: `` Writers are having to be a bit more sophisticated. Certain simplistic political maneuverings as the background to thrillers ca n't be used now.'' He said glasnost is `` wiping the slate clean,'' leaving open the question of `` where to locate the enemy.'' <PERSON> Rupert </PERSON> <PERSON> Allason </PERSON>, a <ORGANIZATION> Conservative </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> lawmaker and espionage historian, suggests the <LOCATION> Middle </LOCATION> <LOCATION> East </LOCATION>, whose secret services `` have a deep grounding and are every bit as challenging as the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> was 10 to 20 years ago.'' <PERSON> Lyall </PERSON>'s recently published `` Uncle Target'' is set largely in <LOCATION> Jordan </LOCATION>, while his next book will take readers to <LOCATION> Morocco </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Bermuda </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ted </PERSON> <PERSON> Allbeury </PERSON>, 70, a British former intelligence officer who now writes high-quality spy novels, said the thaw accompanying <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION>'s `` openness'' offered richer fodder `` It opens one more door,'' he said in an interview, `` if you can imagine the war that must be going on ... between the old <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> operators and the brighter people they're using more.'' <PERSON> Allason </PERSON>, who writes under the pseudonym <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> West </PERSON>, told <ORGANIZATION> BBC </ORGANIZATION> radio last month: `` It's very difficult in this period to try and go back to the sinister figure of running spies all around the world.'' `` The fact is, the newspapers show us every day that they have failed, and the <ORGANIZATION> KGB </ORGANIZATION> defections have in effect put <PERSON> Karla </PERSON> -LRB- le <PERSON> Carre </PERSON>'s fictional Soviet spymaster -RRB- out of business. Not that the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> as a topic of interest is likely to go away. `` The basic structure is as old as story-telling,'' said <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> Cohen </PERSON>. `` It does have a certain form to it.'' <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON>, who writes <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> novels by arrangement with the estate of <PERSON> Bond </PERSON> creator <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Fleming </PERSON>, does n't see glasnost and perestroika putting Western intelligence out of business. `` People say we must find a new evil, and my response to that is the old one ai n't gone away; it's very much still there,'' he said in an interview. `` Just because we have <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> saying wonderful things does n't mean we relax any vigilance,'' <PERSON> Gardner </PERSON> said in an interview Former <LOCATION> British </LOCATION> spy <PERSON> Anthony </PERSON> <PERSON> Cavendish </PERSON> worries that new British official secrets legislation, which imposes a lifetime ban on secret agents describing their work, will dry up the source material that helps spy novelists give their work authenticity. <PERSON> Cavendish </PERSON>'s memoir, `` Inside Intelligence,'' is already banned in <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> But he sees glasnost opening new territory for the spy novel _ `` the view from the other side.'' `` With glasnost in full flood in the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>,'' he wrote, `` it may not be long before the trickle of spy books appearing there turns into a flood.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0718EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>d a PM-BRF--PittsburghSaved     03-03 0104</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-BRF--Pittsburgh Saved,0107</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fish Give Lives to Save Pittsburgh City Building</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PITTSBURGH (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Call it `` The Fish That Saved <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>, Part II.'' A weekend fire in the office of <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Pokora </PERSON> in the downtown City-County Building caused his aquarium to shatter. The water doused the blaze, but his two fish died. `` They gave their lives to save the City-County Building,'' said <PERSON> Pokora </PERSON>, an aide to the city controller. The fire, which apparently was started by an electrical malfunction, ruined carpeting and scorched a wall. `` The Fish That Saved <LOCATION> Pittsburgh </LOCATION>,'' an R-rated 1979 United Artists film release, starred <PERSON> Julius </PERSON> <PERSON> Erving </PERSON> and <PERSON> Jonathan </PERSON> <PERSON> Winters </PERSON>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890303-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-03-03-89 0256EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w PM-BugZoo Bjt   03-03 0638</FIRST>
<SECOND>PM-Bug Zoo, Bjt,620</SECOND>
<HEAD>National Bug Zoo Features Creepiest, Crawliest _ and Biggest</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto WX6</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT M. ANDREWS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
