<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0001 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 2347EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-LATeachers     05-21 0296</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-LA Teachers,0304</SECOND>
<HEAD>Union Awaits Negotiators For School District</HEAD>
<DATELINE>LOS ANGELES (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Negotiators for the 22,000-member teachers' union met again Sunday with school district representatives to seek a solution to a week-old teacher walkout that has caused chaos in city classrooms Representatives of the <LOCATION> Los </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Angeles </LOCATION> Unified School District arrived around 8:15 p.m., more than two hours after <ORGANIZATION> United </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Teacher-Los </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Angeles </ORGANIZATION> negotiators showed up for talks set to begin at 6 p.m., said <ORGANIZATION> UTLA </ORGANIZATION> spokesman <PERSON> Catherine </PERSON> <PERSON> Carey </PERSON>. `` It looks like the other side is dragging its feet and trying to prolong this thing,'' Ms. <PERSON> Carey </PERSON> said before they arrived. She added that teachers were prepared for a second week in the walkout that began May 15. `` We'll have our teachers out on the line again,'' she said. `` They've invested too much at this point.'' Details of developments in recent talks have been sketchy because of a news blackout imposed by state mediator <PERSON> Draz </PERSON> <PERSON> Mrvichin </PERSON>. The walkout last week played havoc with education in the nearly 600,000 - student district Many students walked out of classes and some joined teachers on picket lines. In some cases, students were housed in auditoriums because the district was unable to hire enough substitute teachers to fill classrooms. During the 16-month-long labor dispute, teachers have sought higher salaries and more say in how the district's 600-plus schools are run. Teachers earn between $ 23,440 and $ 43,319 a year, depending on experience and level of education. The union wants a three-year contract with a 26 percent raise, including a 10 percent raise the first year. The district, the second largest in the nation, has refused to go higher than a 21.5 percent raise over three years. The strike, which began May 15, is the district's first since a 23-day walkout in 1970.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0002 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 2355EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-BRF--PlaneCrash     05-21 0127</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Plane Crash,0130</SECOND>
<HEAD>2 Killed When Homemade Plane Plunges</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-Planes Collide</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NILES, Mich. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A homebuilt airplane crashed after performing in an air show Sunday, killing its owner-pilot and a passenger, authorities said. <PERSON> Charles </PERSON> <PERSON> E. </PERSON> <PERSON> White </PERSON>, 49, of <LOCATION> Berrien </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Springs </LOCATION> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> O. </PERSON> <PERSON> Billings </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, 45, of <ORGANIZATION> St. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Joseph </ORGANIZATION> were pronounced dead at the scene of the crash, said state police dispatcher <PERSON> Suzi </PERSON> <PERSON> Hibberd </PERSON>. The single-engine, two-seat plane built by <PERSON> White </PERSON> crashed at 3:06 p.m. in <LOCATION> Howard </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Township </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Hibberd </PERSON> said. Witnesses said the plane made a sudden left turn and plummeted about 300 feet into a field. White and Billings had participated earlier Sunday in an air show in <LOCATION> Benton </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Harbor </LOCATION>. The <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Aviation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> was investigating the cause of the crash, <PERSON> Hibberd </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0003 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 2356EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-RitualSlayings     05-21 0264</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Ritual Slayings,0271</SECOND>
<HEAD>Family Holds Quiet Funeral For Accused Cult Leader</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MIAMI (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Family members and a handful of friends attended funeral services Sunday for the man authorities say was the `` godfather'' of a cult linked to at least 15 slayings on the U.S.-Mexican border, a relative said. The body of <PERSON> Adolfo </PERSON> <PERSON> de </PERSON> <PERSON> Jesus </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, 26, arrived in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> late Saturday night and was cremated for the funeral Sunday, <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>'s brother <PERSON> Fausto </PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION> WQBA </ORGANIZATION> radio in <LOCATION> Miami </LOCATION> `` It was always his wish to be cremated,'' said <PERSON> Fausto </PERSON> <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON>, who said only that relatives and close friends were invited to the funeral. He revealed no other details about the services. `` It was a decision of ours to be so private,'' he said. `` We do n't want anyone there that does n't belong there to curse the funeral.'' <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> has been described as the leader of a sect that authorities blame for at least 15 killings outside the border city of <LOCATION> Matamoros </LOCATION>. Sect members have said some slayings were ritual killings while others were drug-related. Authorities had sought <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> and his female companion <PERSON> Sara </PERSON> <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> <PERSON> Villarreal </PERSON>, 24, since the discovery of the first of the bodies on a border ranch in April. Some bodies had been mutilated, with brains and organs removed. <PERSON> Aldrete </PERSON> and other sect members have said publicly that <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> ordered his own execution and the killing of his right-hand man, <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Quintana </PERSON> <PERSON> Rodriguez </PERSON>, on May 6 when police moved in on their <LOCATION> Mexico </LOCATION> <LOCATION> City </LOCATION> apartment earlier this month. An autopsy showed <PERSON> Constanzo </PERSON> died from multiple gunshot wounds to the head and upper body.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0004 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 0050EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China 7thLd-Writethru   05-21 0875</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China, 7th Ld-Writethru,a0623,0903</SECOND>
<HEAD>Soldiers Set Up Roadblocks, Masses Defy Martial Law</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: Leads with 23 grafs to move up other demonstrations, only reported
clash, hunger strike over, EDITS to TRIM. Pickup 30th graf `Britain on...'</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhotos TOK3,TOK5-7,BEJ1,BEJ18,BEJ20</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Soldiers on Sunday set up roadblocks to <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>'s center and moved into its train station, but hundreds of thousands of students defied martial law and remained in Tiananmen Square despite fears of an army crackdown Large pro-democracy demonstrations also were reported in several other cities. In <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, more than 300,000 people rallied on the waterfront of the <LOCATION> Huangpu </LOCATION> <LOCATION> River </LOCATION> and 200,000 more gathered in the city's People's Square. The only violence reported was a clash between armed police and students in western <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Saturday in which students said they were attacked with electric cattle prods. One student injured in the attack said 45 students were hospitalized. The thousands of students staging a week-old hunger strike in the 100-acre Tiananmen Square ended their fast Saturday, saying they needed to regain their strength in case troops moved in. Students and their supporters in the square early Sunday numbered about 200,000. Protests since the hunger strike began have drawn hundreds of thousands. The hunger strikers initially demanded a dialogue with the government on reform, to be broadcast live, and an apology for an initial official declaration that the student democracy movement was a plot against the party. But after Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> declared martial law in parts of the capital Saturday to put an end to the protests, most students and their supporters demanded <PERSON> Li </PERSON> resign. The army's move Sunday apparently was aimed at stopping the flow of tens of thousands of people to the capital to join the protests. Citizens blockaded the station by parking coal trucks across the road and hundreds of students sat in front of it as a further barrier. The army set up roadblocks around the capital about 12 miles from the city center, said a <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> source who spoke on condition of anonymity. The source said 60,000 to 70,000 troops moved into the city center by subway Sunday and followed connecting tunnels to the walled palace, the history museum and the Great Hall of the People on three sides of Tiananmen Square. The subway was closed to regular traffic as of noon Saturday. There was no outward sign of the reported troop presence in the city center and it could not be confirmed. Inside Tiananmen Square, the sun rose Sunday on a triumphant but weary and bedraggled crowd of at least 200,000 students, medical workers and ordinary citizens. The students spent the night sitting in rows with gauze wound around their mouths and noses for protection against a possible tear gas attack. Around the square and on roads throughout the city, citizens barricaded the way with buses, trucks and anything available. Thousands also surrounded tanks and trucks filled with soldiers at several points in the suburbs, immobilizing them. `` The people are strong,'' an elderly woman marveled as the long night ended peacefully. But soon after, five army helicopters swooped twice over the square as they did repeatedly Saturday, reminding the protesters the standoff was not over. The students waved and cheered defiantly. `` The danger is not over,'' said a medical student who was helping care for about 3,000 of the students who were weakened by the hunger strike. Student leaders had said over a loudspeaker Saturday night that the protesters should not resist if the army came. `` Our principle is peaceful non-resistance,'' they said. On Sunday, the student leaders held lengthy, private meetings to discuss their next step. Nothing was immediately announced. Some reportedly favored staying in the square while others wanted to join citizens confronting army vehicles. The widely ignored martial law regulations include bans on marches, class boycotts, distribution of pamphlets, speeches, the spreading of rumors, attacks on party, government or military organs and `` any other destructive actions.'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s hard-line stand toward the students appears to have forced the resignation of the more liberal Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>. Chinese sources said <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>, highly respected for his pioneering work in economic reforms, resigned his post after failing to persuade <PERSON> Li </PERSON> and senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> to compromise with the students. There has been no official word on <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON>'s future. <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s political victory could be brief, however, if the military refuses to cooperate in the crackdown. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> on Saturday urged that the <LOCATION> Chinese </LOCATION> government and demonstrators use `` restraint and moderation'' in the crisis. The <LOCATION> United </LOCATION> <LOCATION> States </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> France </LOCATION> recommended that their citizens not travel to the country. Protesters in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> have demanded <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> retire. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, 84, is widely admired for initiating market-oriented reforms in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. But he has come under sharp attack by students for holding onto power too long and letting political reform lag behind his economic reforms. The students began the protests on April 15 after the death of former <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, a leading reformer who was ousted from his post for not cracking down on earlier student protests. The rallies gradually grew in size as workers and others joined in and evolved into the biggest show of defiance in <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s 40 years of communist rule.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0005 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 0837EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-Britain-SovietExpulsions 1stLd-Writethru   05-21 0467</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-Britain-Soviet Expulsions, 1st Ld - Writethru,a0627,0475</SECOND>
<HEAD>Precede LONDON</HEAD>
<HEAD>Journalists, Diplomats Expelled From Britain, Soviet Union</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: LEADS throughout to UPDATE with Moscow British Embassy comment,
identification of Britons, other details; no pickup</HEAD>
<DATELINE>MOSCOW (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> ordered the expulsion of 11 Soviets, and the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION> responded by ordering eight British diplomats and three journalists out of the country for alleged espionage, the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Embassy </ORGANIZATION> said Sunday. `` It's a mirror-image act of retaliation,'' British Ambassador <PERSON> Rodric </PERSON> <PERSON> Q. </PERSON> <PERSON> Braithwaite </PERSON> told a news conference. <PERSON> Roderic </PERSON> <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON>, the embassy's political counselor, said <PERSON> Braithwaite </PERSON> was summoned to the <ORGANIZATION> Soviet </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> on Saturday night and told that 11 Britons would have to leave <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> within 14 days. The previous day, Soviet Ambassador <PERSON> Leonid </PERSON> <PERSON> Zamyatin </PERSON> was called to the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> and told by Sir <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Fretwell </PERSON>, the deputy permanent undersecretary, that 11 Soviets were engaged in `` activities incompatible with their status'' and must leave in 14 days, a <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> spokesman said in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION>. The spokesman, speaking anonymously in keeping with British custom, said <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> had not planned to make public the expulsions and did so only after the Soviets retalitated. The spokesman refused to say what the Soviets were accused of doing, but the charge he used of `` incompatible activities'' is diplomatic jargon for espionage. <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON> said the Britons ordered expelled from <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> were Embassy Second Secretary <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Anderson </PERSON>, Second Secretary <PERSON> Adam </PERSON> <PERSON> Noble </PERSON>, Third Secretary <PERSON> Paul </PERSON> <PERSON> Sharp </PERSON>, Vice Consul <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Pickering </PERSON>, Naval Attache Capt. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Meyer </PERSON>, Assistant Naval Attache Lt. Cmdr. <PERSON> Christopher </PERSON> <PERSON> Watson </PERSON>, Assistant Military Attache Maj. <PERSON> Nigel </PERSON> <PERSON> Shakespear </PERSON> and Warrant Officer Laing Purfit of the <ORGANIZATION> Defense </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Ministry </ORGANIZATION> staff. <PERSON> Jeremy </PERSON> <PERSON> Harris </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> British </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Broadcasting </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Corp. </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Ian </PERSON> <PERSON> Glover-James </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Independent </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON> Angus </PERSON> <PERSON> Roxburgh </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Sunday </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Times </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> London </ORGANIZATION> also were give two weeks to leave the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Union </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON> said. <PERSON> Roxburgh </PERSON> called the action `` ludicrous, almost too silly to comment on.'' The <ORGANIZATION> Foreign </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Office </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> refused to identify the Soviets expelled. <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> ITN </ORGANIZATION> radio reported the Soviets were caught spying on military installations. Press Association, the domestic British news agency, quoted unidentified diplomats as saying those expelled from <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> include Soviet journalists. The expulsions of British and Soviet nationals are the first since the two countries expelled 31 of each other's citizens four years ago. The 1985 dispute began when <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> ordered 25 Soviets to leave after they were identified as secret agents by Soviet defector <PERSON> Oleg </PERSON> <PERSON> Gordievsky </PERSON>. In addition to the 11 Britons ordered expelled Saturday, <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON> said three British diplomats who had already completed their tours of assignment in <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> last year were declared `` persona non grata'' by the Soviets, meaning they can not return. <PERSON> Zamyatin </PERSON> also was told Friday that three former staff members at the <LOCATION> Soviet </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Embassy </LOCATION> in <LOCATION> London </LOCATION> could not come back to <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION>, <PERSON> Lyne </PERSON> said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0006 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 0847EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i BC-China 1stLd-Writethru   05-21 0656</FIRST>
<SECOND>BC-China, 1st Ld-Writethru,a0628,0675</SECOND>
<HEAD>URGENT</HEAD>
<HEAD>Students Say Government Issues Ultimatum To Leave Square</HEAD>
<HEAD>Eds: New thruout to ADD background, details. No pickup.</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Students occupying <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> in violation of martial law said Sunday Premier <PERSON> Li </PERSON> <PERSON> Peng </PERSON> ordered them to leave the square by dawn Monday or face a military attack. Troops occupied major state-run news organizations. Soldiers set up roadblocks around <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, presumably to prevent more demonstrators from reaching the capital, and about 1,500 troops armed with automatic weapons moved into the train station. Troops occupied the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION>, <ORGANIZATION> Xinhua </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Radio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Television </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Station </ORGANIZATION>, a <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Daily </ORGANIZATION> reporter said. Soldiers will be sent to major universities, which have been the center of the monthlong protests for democratic change, to `` keep order,'' <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> television reported. <PERSON> Li </PERSON> called the 27th and 28th armies into the capital Friday night and declared martial law in central <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> on Saturday to put down the student-led protests that have drawn hundreds of thousands of people and caused major demonstrations in other cities. He did not say how many troops were called in. <PERSON> Li </PERSON>, in a message to the independent student union that has led the protests for a free press, an end to official corruption and other reforms, said the military would clear <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> by force by 5 a.m. Monday if the students refused to leave, according to an announcement by the union. In a broadcast over the student loudspeaker system in the square, they also claimed <PERSON> Li </PERSON> told <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> jails to be ready to accept a large number of students. `` We call on all of you to come stand with us,'' a student said after the announcement. `` The students are very weak and they need the people of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to help them. Even 200,000 people can not withstand the army.'' A Chinese source said 60,000 to 70,000 troops moved into the city center by subway and followed connecting tunnels to the walled palace, the history museum and the Great Hall of the People on three sides of <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION>. The subway was closed to regular traffic as of noon Saturday and remained closed Sunday. There was no outward sign of the reported troop presence and it could not be confirmed. Official media repeatedly broadcast a statement that troops were in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to restore order, not to suppress the students. But it was clear order could not be restored without moving the students from <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION>. The widely ignored martial law regulations include bans on marches, class boycotts, distribution of pamphlets, speeches, the spreading of rumors, attacks on party, government or military organs and `` any other destructive actions.'' <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s hard-line stand toward the students appears to have forced the resignation of the more liberal Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Zhao </PERSON> <PERSON> Ziyang </PERSON>. Demonstrations in other cities continued Sunday. Tens of thousands of people marched in <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>, according to a Western resident, and police diverted traffic. Several hundred marched in the coastal city of <LOCATION> Tianjin </LOCATION>, a reporter at a local newspaper said. The military failed to make an expected attack Saturday night on 200,000 students and supporters who kept all-night vigil in Tiananmen Square. Many spent the night with gauze wound around their mouths and noses for protection against a tear gas attack and others slept on the hard stone pavement. Around the square and on roads citywide, citizens barricaded the way to <LOCATION> Tianamen </LOCATION> with buses, trucks, lightposts and anything else available. Thousands surrounded and immobilized tanks and trucks filled with soldiers throughout the city and in the suburbs. Local residents gave the soldiers cigarettes, food and water, and at one point Sunday 600 soldiers retreated several hundred yards. Troops set up blockades on highways into <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to prevent more people from moving into the capital. Crowds in <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> and the surrounding area thinned substantially Sunday, but people began flocking toward the square in the evening after <PERSON> Li </PERSON>'s ultimatum was announced.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0007 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF--Iran-Executions     05-21 0120</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF--Iran-Executions,0123</SECOND>
<HEAD>Fourteen Drug Traffickers Hanged</HEAD>
<DATELINE>NICOSIA, Cyprus (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Fourteen drug traffickers convicted by Islamic courts were hanged in two Iranian cities Sunday, raising the number of such executions since January to 637, <LOCATION> Tehran </LOCATION> radio reported. The broadcast, monitored in <LOCATION> Nicosia </LOCATION>, said the hangings took place in northwestern <LOCATION> Lahijan </LOCATION> and central <LOCATION> Birjand </LOCATION>. In January, Iranian authorities launched a nationwide crackdown on drug abuse. Under a new law, anyone caught in possession of even small amounts of any drug receives the death penalty. In the last nine days alone, 79 drug traffickers were hanged. The government has said that about 1 million of <LOCATION> Iran </LOCATION>'s 50 million people are drug abusers, but unofficial estimates put the figure at twice that.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0008 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1132EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-BRF-Taiwan-Premier     05-21 0139</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-BRF-Taiwan-Premier,0143</SECOND>
<HEAD>President Reportedly Approves Premier's Resignation</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TAIPEI, Taiwan (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Teng-hui </PERSON> on Sunday accepted the resignation of Premier <PERSON> Yu </PERSON> <PERSON> Kuo-hwa </PERSON> after failing to persuade him to remain in office, the official <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> News </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Agency </ORGANIZATION> reported. <PERSON> Yu </PERSON>, 75, announced Wednesday he had submitted his resignation to <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> to make way for a younger person and also to preserve unity within the governing <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Yu </PERSON>, <LOCATION> Taiwan </LOCATION>'s premier since 1984, has been criticized for his cautious approach to economic and political reforms. Younger members of the party consider him a liability in a December parliamentary election. The <ORGANIZATION> CNA </ORGANIZATION> report made no mention of <PERSON> Yu </PERSON>'s successor. But newspapers said earlier the probable candidate is <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Huan </PERSON>, 72, the <ORGANIZATION> Nationalist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s popular secretary-general. A decision will be made at a meeting Wednesday of the policy-making central committee, newspapers said.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0009 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1133EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Lebanon     05-21 0546</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Lebanon,0562</SECOND>
<HEAD>Syrian Gunboats Intercept Lebanese Cargo Ship</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By RIMA SALAMEH</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIRUT, Lebanon (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Five Syrian gunboats intercepted a freighter carrying supplies for <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s besieged Christians and forced it to return to <LOCATION> Cyprus </LOCATION>, an army spokesman said Sunday. The Syrians' use of their naval forces, along with intensified weekend shelling, marked a tightening of the blockade on the Christians' coastal enclave. The spokesman, who can not be named under standing regulations, identified the Lebanese-owned vessel as the Cedars and said it was intercepted at dawn Saturday as it was heading to a harbor near the northern city of <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>. <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> sources say <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> has based a flotilla of gunboats in <LOCATION> Tripoli </LOCATION>, which is Syrian-controlled, despite <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s traditional control of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s <LOCATION> Mediterranean </LOCATION> coastline. It was the first known Syrian interception of a ship heading for the Christian enclave. Despite daily shelling of the Christian ports, several small freighters have made it through. Police said Syrian artillery in and around Moslem west <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> pounded the enclave's coastline with 200 shells and rockets Saturday and Sunday in another violation of an Arab League cease-fire declared May 11. The bombardment, the heaviest since the cease-fire was called, targeted a 10-mile-long stretch of beach between the ports of <LOCATION> Jounieh </LOCATION> and Byblos, police reported. The Syrians and their Druse Moslem militia allies have been shelling the Christian ports to prevent ships with food or weapons from reaching the enclave. No casualties were reported in the latest attacks. At least 359 people have been killed and 1,393 wounded since fighting began March 8 between army commander Gen. <PERSON> Michel </PERSON> <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>'s mainly Christian troops and the alliance of Syrian and Druse forces <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON>, who heads a <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cabinet </ORGANIZATION> vying for power with a rival Moslem government, accused <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> of sending reconnaissance jets on `` provocative runs'' over the enclave for the first time during the confrontation. He charged that <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s failure to challenge the Syrian penetration of what the Israelis consider their air force's preserve was `` evidence of a backstage understanding between <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> on maintaining their occupation of <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. The Syrians have 40,000 troops with tanks deployed in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, mostly in Moslem territory, under an increasingly discredited 1976 Arab League peacekeeping mandate. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> occupies a border strip in south <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> contends the Syrians have lost their credibility as peacekeepers by siding with the Moslem side. He has declared a `` war of liberation'' to drive out the Syrians, whose forces outnumber his troops 4-to-1. The last known Syrian air force flights over <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> were in the early days of <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION>'s 1982 invasion. <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> claimed it shot down 80 Syrian jets over the Syrian-controlled <LOCATION> Bekaa </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Valley </LOCATION> in east <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> then. <PERSON> Aoun </PERSON> also charged that <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> and its allies were bent on `` detonating a new security blowup in <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'' before an Arab summit Tuesday to discuss ways of ending <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>'s 14-year-old civil war. He said <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> heads of state must not allow <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION> to `` swallow'' <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION>, and he urged Soviet leader <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> S. </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> to intervene to stop the bombardment of the Christian enclave. <LOCATION> Moscow </LOCATION> is <LOCATION> Syria </LOCATION>'s main arms supplier. Acting Prime Minister <PERSON> Salim </PERSON> <PERSON> Hoss </PERSON>, who heads the pro-Syrian Cabinet, messaged <PERSON> Arab </PERSON> leaders gathering for the summit that a Syrian pullout from <LOCATION> Lebanon </LOCATION> can only be demanded by a unified Lebanese government.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0010 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1135EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-China-Scene Bjt   05-21 0717</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Scene, Bjt,0740</SECOND>
<HEAD>Waiting for the Army: Beijing Residents Seek Safety in Numbers</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By KATHY WILHELM</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 They huddled together, marched, debated and waited restlessly for an attack by their own army. When the sun rose Sunday, it showed a city physically and emotionally taxed by the first nervous night of martial law. Tiananmen Square, the majestic 100-acre expanse at the heart of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>, was a garbage-strewn squatter camp for 200,000 students and supporters who spent the night in fear. Broad, tree-lined <LOCATION> Changan </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Avenue </LOCATION>, the main east-west street, was littered with garbage and broken glass. Empty buses were parked across main intersections. Colorful flags that had been hung over the street to welcome Soviet President <PERSON> Mikhail </PERSON> <PERSON> Gorbachev </PERSON> last week were ripped or torn down. All over the city, residents who spent the night guarding their streets against an expected troop advance began going home to rest. `` They'll come back at night,'' said a student who was among the students, medical workers and supporters occupying Tiananmen Square. Some curled up on the ground and tried to sleep, but most spent the night in anxious activity _ marching around the square, listening to student speeches and preparing for an attack. `` Obey the orders of the broadcast station,'' student leaders urged repeatedly over the loudspeaker system rigged in the square. `` Do not take any action without hearing it on the broadcast.'' Another broadcast warned to be careful when stepping on subway grates _ `` they might be electrified.'' Several thousand students from the <ORGANIZATION> Inner </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mongolian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> sat outside a nearby subway stop in case soldiers emerged from it. Students walked around with rolls of gauze hanging around their necks or around their heads, ready to be pulled over their noses and mouths in case of tear gas assaults. Despite the knowledge that troops had entered the city and were carrying tear gas, many people said they could not believe soldiers of the <ORGANIZATION> People </ORGANIZATION><ORGANIZATION> 's </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Liberation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Army </ORGANIZATION> would attack their own countrymen. `` I do n't think anything bad will happen,'' said a student from the <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> Medical University No. 3 Hospital, who was in the square with hundreds of other medical workers to treat students who had been on a hunger strike. `` No one wants violence, the soldiers especially,'' he said. Student leaders announced that `` latest information'' said the troops would arrive at 2 a.m. Sunday. When the hour arrived, the students sat in rows facing outward and pulled their gauze into place. `` We ca n't fear for ourselves, we are fighting for the future of democracy,'' one student said through the mask. Off to one side, a woman with a megaphone tried to organize local residents to gather around the students. A man ran up crying, `` The soldiers are already in <LOCATION> Northern </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Pond </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Road </LOCATION>.'' Someone else reported tanks in his home district, about six miles from <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION>. More than 300 motocyclists, many riding double, roared around the square every hour, honking their horns and leaving a cloud of exhaust fumes. Rumors flew. When no troops appeared at 2 a.m., the woman announced they were now expected at 4 a.m. The students, sensing they would not come, played <PERSON> Beethoven </PERSON>'s `` Ode to Joy'' over the loudspeaker system at 3 a.m. to express their relief. The sky lightened, and residents on nearby streets who had sat outside all night picked up their stools and went in. People who spent the night at intersections barricaded with lane dividers, street signs and anything else available began rubbing sleepy eyes and hopping on their bicycles to go home. `` We've won again,'' said one. In the square, students broke formation and began shoveling garbage into piles and nibbling on steamed bread. The loudspeaker played the official radio station's 6:30 a.m. newscast, which repeated the martial law order that took effect Saturday. When the newscast reported that <LOCATION> Italy </LOCATION>'s government had resigned, some students cheered _ that is what they want their own government to do. Most regarded the rising sun as a temporary form of protection, but one <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> student warned that soldiers could come by day, too. `` We ca n't relax, there's still danger,'' he said. As if to illustrate, five military helicopters swept into view and circled the square twice. The students stood, waved their arms and cheered. `` We're welcoming them,'' one said sarcastically.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0011 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1137EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Weizsaecker Bjt   05-21 0799</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Weizsaecker, Bjt,0822</SECOND>
<HEAD>Weizsaecker Fills the Bill as President</HEAD>
<HEAD>An AP Extra</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By CAROL J. WILLIAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BONN, West Germany (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 President <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON>'s patrician lineage and eloquent oratory satisfy a longing of his countrymen for a royal statesman who can skillfully temper their past sins with postwar achievements His rise from the shadow of his father's role in the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> leadership to what is now the most respected federal office mirrors the stunning West German recovery from wartime ruin and testifies to the resilience of a modern family dynasty. <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> will be re-elected without opposition Tuesday to a second term as head of state by the <ORGANIZATION> Federal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Convention </ORGANIZATION>, which meets every five years to elect a president. Each of the five political parties represented in the federal <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> is entitled to nominate a candidate, but for the first time in the nation's 40-year history, the vote will be uncontested. <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON>, a member of Chancellor <PERSON> Helmut </PERSON> <PERSON> Kohl </PERSON>'s conservative <ORGANIZATION> Christian </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Union </ORGANIZATION>, has won endorsement of all but the far-left <ORGANIZATION> Greens </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>, which nonetheless decided against running a challenger. The unusual unity displayed by <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>'s diverse and fractious political parties reflects the respect the 69-year-old <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> has won during his first term as president. In the latest nationwide poll, conducted by the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> in </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allensbach </ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> drew an approval rating of more than 85 percent. A man who by nature keeps above the political fray, <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> has transformed the mostly ceremonial office of president into an influential post of elder statesman and curator of a national conscience. His articulate address on the 40th anniversary of the end of World War II won praise worldwide as an effort to bring fellow Germans to terms with the Holocaust they perpetrated. `` Guilt is, like innocence, not collective, but personal,'' the president said. `` All of us, whether guilty or not, whether young or old, must accept the past. We are all affected by its consequences and liable for it.'' But striking a chord of balance with West Germans weary of the shame bequeathed by their forebears, <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> also has called for a fair assessment of the accomplishments of his state built on the smoldering ruins of the Third Reich. Chapters of his own past have been a burden borne unflinchingly. Born in <LOCATION> Stuttgart </LOCATION> on April 15, 1920, to a titled family of intellectuals, <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> began his studies in 1937 at <LOCATION> Oxford </LOCATION>, where he perfected the English he speaks fluently today, then joined <PERSON> Adolf </PERSON> <PERSON> Hitler </PERSON>'s army in 1938. He marched into <LOCATION> Poland </LOCATION> with his infantry regiment on the first day of World War II, lost a brother in the invasion and continued to serve until the German capitulation May 8, 1945. After resuming his law studies, he served as deputy defense council for his father, <PERSON> Ernst </PERSON> <PERSON> von </PERSON> <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON>, who was sentenced at the 1947 <LOCATION> Nuremberg </LOCATION> trials to eight years in prison for his role as a deputy foreign minister in the <ORGANIZATION> Nazi </ORGANIZATION> leadership. While <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> is generally revered by West Germans, critics can be found at both political extremes. Ultra-rightist leader <PERSON> Franz </PERSON> <PERSON> Schoenhuber </PERSON>, whose service in the Waffen SS continues to haunt his political career, complained recently that he is called to account repeatedly for the Nazi period while <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> `` has remained virtually untouched.'' Greens spokesman <PERSON> Michael </PERSON> <PERSON> Schroerer </PERSON> said his party, which polls less than 10 percent, declined to support <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> `` more for what he has n't done than for any misdeed,'' contending the president could more actively address residual problems of discrimination and injustice. Some prominent Greens like <PERSON> Otto </PERSON> <PERSON> Schily </PERSON>, however, have said they plan to vote for <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON>. <PERSON> Ingeborg </PERSON> <PERSON> Menz </PERSON> of the federal <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> office explained that the Federal Convention at which the president will be elected for a second and final term is made up of the 519 federal <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> members and an equal number of delegates from the 11 state legislatures. An avid sportsman frequently pictured skiing or mountain-climbing, Weiszaecker is chosen most often as a model for young Germans, said spokesman <PERSON> Edgar </PERSON> <PERSON> Piel </PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Opinion </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Piel </PERSON> said West Germans respect <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> because of his image as a moral and noble statesman, allowing them to maintain an ersatz monarchy. The `` von'' in the family name stems from the title of baron bestowed on his grandfather in 1916 by the royal family of <LOCATION> Wuerttemberg </LOCATION>. After managerial stints in steel, banking and pharmaceuticals, <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> was head of the German <ORGANIZATION> Protestant </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Church </ORGANIZATION> from 1964 to 1970. He served in the federal <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> from 1969 through his election as mayor of <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Berlin </LOCATION>, a high-profile post that propelled him into the presidency in 1984. <PERSON> Weizsaecker </PERSON> has traveled frequently since his election, including making the first West German presidential visit to <LOCATION> Israel </LOCATION> in 1985, helping to mold the nation's affluent and sophisticated postwar image.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0012 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1139EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u i AM-Suzman Bjt   05-21 0777</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Suzman, Bjt,0800</SECOND>
<HEAD>Anti-Apartheid Legislator Ending 36-Year Career With Head High</HEAD>
<HEAD>LaserPhoto JOH1</HEAD>
<NOTE>EDITOR'S NOTE </NOTE>
<TEXT>
 For much of her life, <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> has fought apartheid in <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>, sometimes the single lonely voice calling for reform. Last week she announced she will retire from <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> after 36 years. Here is a look at her work.
</TEXT>
<BYLINE>By DAVID CRARY</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Back in 1963, a legislator of the governing <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> said of <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON>, who single-handedly represented the anti-apartheid opposition: `` Her days in Parliament are numbered.'' That would-be prophet, <PERSON> Cas </PERSON> <PERSON> Greyling </PERSON>, has since left <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>, as has every one of his contemporaries except the indomitable woman he derided. Her days in office number some 13,200. Last week Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON>, 71, announced she will not seek re-election in September, ending a 36-year parliamentary career. Few politicians anywhere have served so long, in opposition to such an entrenched governing party, and fought so determinedly for their convictions. For 13 of those years, from 1961 to 1974, she was the only member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> speaking out against apartheid and campaigning for black rights. During a 15-week session in 1961, she made 66 speeches, offered 26 amendments and submitted 137 questions to parliamentary leaders. `` I do n't know how I made so many speeches,'' she said. `` I wrote every one myself _ that's why they were so lousy. They were not flowing speeches, but the contents have pleased me. When I look back at these speeches, I still think I have taken the right line.'' She has been lauded as `` the conscience of white <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION>.'' Prime Minister <PERSON> Margaret </PERSON> <PERSON> Thatcher </PERSON> of <LOCATION> Britain </LOCATION> was among those saluting her last week. Yet despite the accolades, Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> departed only slightly from her customary modesty. `` Without actually saying, ` I told you so,' it has been a source of considerable satisfaction to have been in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> over the past 10 years, when many of the laws I opposed when they were introduced have been repealed,'' she told her colleagues Thursday. She referred to the repeal of laws prohibiting interracial marriages, reserving certain jobs for whites and requiring blacks to have permits to be in whites-only areas. The Sowetan, the country's largest black-oriented daily newspaper, said many blacks `` owe her gratitude for the battles she has fought.'' `` The great pity is that <LOCATION> South </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Africa </LOCATION> simply was not good enough to have a person such as herself as the head of state,'' The <ORGANIZATION> Sowetan </ORGANIZATION> said. Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> says her worst moment in Parliament came in 1966 when Prime Minister <PERSON> Hendrik </PERSON> <PERSON> Verwoerd </PERSON> was fatally stabbed by a deranged assassin, a few yards away from her. P.W. <PERSON> Botha </PERSON>, defense minister at the time and now president, told her as he rushed past: `` You liberals did this. Now we will get you.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> did not speak to <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> for several years, and their relationship remains distant. They served together in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> from 1953 until <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> became president in 1985. In one exchange in 1981, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> warned her not to break the law, and she replied: `` I am not frightened of you. I never have been and never will be. I think nothing of you.'' <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> also will retire in September. One of Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON>'s roles has been that of prophet. In 1981, referring to the unrest, she said: `` If it gets really bad, the government might suspend the law and rule by edict.'' In 1986, <PERSON> Botha </PERSON> imposed a national state of emergency that remains in force. Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> predicted last week that blacks eventually will gain political rights and that remaining segregation laws will `` waste away'' or be repealed, `` though, alas, I will not be here to welcome their disappearance.'' Mrs. <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> was born <PERSON> Helen </PERSON> <PERSON> Gavronksy </PERSON>, daughter of Jewish immigrants from <LOCATION> Lithuania </LOCATION>. She enrolled at <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> the </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Witwatersrand </ORGANIZATION> at 16, married physician <PERSON> Moses </PERSON> <PERSON> Suzman </PERSON> at 19, and later taught at <LOCATION> Witwatersrand </LOCATION> before running for <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> in 1952 from <LOCATION> Houghton </LOCATION>, a wealthy <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> district she has served ever since Militants in later years urged her to quit, saying a <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION> that excluded blacks was no place for a genuine foe of apartheid. But she is convinced she played a vital role by `` keeping certain values alive.'' Her approach to politics was simple, she said last week: `` If you stick to basic principles, you do n't ever have to regret what you said.'' Other assessments of her career were less restrained. `` Only an extraordinary commitment to her political ideas could have carried her through the long years when she, alone, upheld the banner of civilization in <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>,'' said Business Day, a <LOCATION> Johannesburg </LOCATION> newspaper. `` She held a torch aloft in time of darkness.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0013 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1146EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-China-Dissent     05-21 0630</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-China-Dissent,0649</SECOND>
<HEAD>Student Unrest in China Has Built up Over Decade</HEAD>
<HEAD>With AM-China, Bjt</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JIM ABRAMS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>BEIJING (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s students repeatedly have called for reforms over the past decade, but current pro-democracy demonstrations in <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> and other cities are by far the largest and boldest communist <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> has faced. Student dissent has been gathering strength since senior leader <PERSON> Deng </PERSON> <PERSON> Xiaoping </PERSON> took power and initiated his policies of reform in the late 1970s. The first open challenge to the government came in the Democracy Wall movement of 1978-79. The movement was so named because protesters wrote posters demanding freedom and complaining about a wide range of social ills and tacked them to a wall in western <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Deng </PERSON>, seeking to wrest power held by leftists left over from the 1966-76 Cultural Revolution, allowed the movement as long as it focused on the wrongs of the past. When criticisms began to hit closer to home, he cracked down. Dozens of dissidents were arrested, including <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> <PERSON> Jingsheng </PERSON>, who was sentenced to 15 years in prison for counterrevolutionary activities. <PERSON> Wei </PERSON> remains behind bars. The harsh measures effectively muffled democratic dissent for about five years. During the 1980s, students occasionally launched protests on their abysmal living conditions, the presence of factories and army troops on campuses, and crime, but they stayed away from political issues. In December 1984, for example, 5,000 <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students marched on the university president's home to complain about unheated dormitories and an 11 p.m. lights-out policy. Dissent took a political turn in September 1985 when 1,000 students congregated at <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to condemn what they said was <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s `` economic invasion'' of <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>. The authorities, disturbed when students shifted from criticizing <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION> to talking about rising food prices and government corruption, launched a propaganda campaign that stifled the unrest. But a little more than a year later, in December 1986, the students rose up again. In demonstrations and protests that spread to dozens of cities, students demanded greater campus autonomy, less bureaucratic control over their lives and a more democratic society. Tens of thousands flooded the streets of <LOCATION> Shanghai </LOCATION>. <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> students staged all-night marches to Tiananmen Square. The demonstrations ran their course in a month, and the government responded with a chilling campaign against `` bourgeois liberalization,'' or the attraction to Western liberal thinking. Three leading intellectuals, including astrophysicist <PERSON> Fang </PERSON> <PERSON> Lizhi </PERSON>, were purged from the <ORGANIZATION> Communist </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> for allegedly fomenting the unrest, and Communist Party General Secretary <PERSON> Hu </PERSON> <PERSON> Yaobang </PERSON>, regarded as sympathetic to the students, was ousted by party conservatives. The pro-democracy movement again went underground. It surfaced in June 1988 when 1,000 <ORGANIZATION> Beijing </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> University </ORGANIZATION> students marched to <LOCATION> Tiananmen </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Square </LOCATION> to protest the slaying of a fellow student by a gang of ruffians. Activists took advantage of the student anger to put up posters denouncing official corruption and demanding democratic reforms. The current explosion of protest was triggered by the death April 15 of former party chief Hu. Students took to the streets to mourn the man they feel was wronged by the party, but more importantly, to express again all they felt was wrong with <LOCATION> China </LOCATION>'s political system Mass protests have not been confined to students in the past decade. Farmers have protested pollution and official profiteering; unemployed youth have marched for jobs; and people sent to the countryside during the Cultural Revolution have demanded to be allowed to return to their city homes. Tibetans seeking independence from <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have protested violently three times since October 1987, and the minority Uyghurs of far western <LOCATION> China </LOCATION> have demonstrated against nuclear testing in their region. This month, 2,500 Chinese Moslems, emboldened by the pro-democracy demonstrators, marched through the streets of <LOCATION> Beijing </LOCATION> to demand the banning of a Chinese book they said blasphemed their religion. It was banned.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0014 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1154EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-PoweringDown Bjt   05-21 0959</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Powering Down, Bjt,920</SECOND>
<HEAD>Consumers Urged to Use Electricity More Efficiently, Not Less</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By ROBERT BURNS</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 In <LOCATION> Virginia </LOCATION>, you can earn a $ 4 monthly credit on your electric bill by letting the utility cut power to your water heater for a few hours a few times a month. In southern <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION>, you can get a one-time cash rebate from the utility of up to $ 619 for replacing your air conditioner with a more efficient one. An <LOCATION> Arizona </LOCATION> utility offers to knock $ 75 off your bill if you put a reflective film on your home's windows to block out the ultraviolet rays of the desert sun. Across the country _ with some stark exceptions _ electric utilities are pouring money into programs aimed at encouraging energy efficiency and shifting the use of electricity from the peak periods of demand to other times. `` There's a big move starting up,'' says <PERSON> Stephen </PERSON> <PERSON> Wiel </PERSON>, chairman of the energy conservation committee of the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Association </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Regulatory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Utility </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Commissioners </ORGANIZATION>. The main reason: Demands on the power supply system are growing so rapidly that utilities are nearing the point of having to invest in new sources of supply. The colossal failure of many past investments in nuclear power plants is a powerful disincentive to risk the billions needed for new construction. Virginia Power figures its program of interrupting power to 145,000 residential water heaters has saved it the need to add 150 megawatts of generating capacity _ the equivalent of a small power plant, says spokesman <PERSON> Carl </PERSON> <PERSON> Baab </PERSON>. Utilities in some parts of the country have been tinkering with electricity demand _ mainly to even out the daily and seasonal peaks and valleys _ for several years. But the trend is now accelerating as the utilities realize `` load management'' _ as it's called in the business _ can mean more profits Here's how: By encouraging customers to use less power in the peak periods of summer and winter and to use more the rest of the time, a utility can boost its overall electricity sales without having to add to its maximum generating capacity. `` The reason we're doing this is that it's just good business,'' says <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Morron </PERSON>, a vice president of <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION>, an industry association. For consumers, these programs can mean lower electric bills. The savings come not only from using more efficient appliances and heating and cooling systems but also from avoiding the rate increases that plant construction can bring. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> McCollam </PERSON> <PERSON> Jr. </PERSON>, president of <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Electric </ORGANIZATION>, recently estimated the number of utility-sponsored energy efficiency programs had grown from 134 in 1977 to nearly 1,300 last year. He said this has allowed the industry to avoid adding 21,000 megawatts of new capacity over the past decade _ the equivalent of about 21 large generating plants. A single plant that size would be expected to cost at least $ 1 billion. After a decade of slow growth, electricity sales in the past two years jumped by about 5 percent a year. Experts differ on the outlook for future growth, but most agree demand could outstrip supply in the 1990s unless new generating capacity is added. This is a key reason for the emphasis now on efficiency gains and programs that can postpone the day when a utility must decide how to supplement its power supply. The trend is not uniform, however. Some utilities have a surplus of power and are aggressively peddling it. <ORGANIZATION> Ohio </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Edison </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION> is offering financial incentives for natural gas customers to convert their water heaters to electric and to buy heaters that will run electric as well as on oil or gas. `` We're loaded with power; the idea is to sell it,'' said <PERSON> D.W. </PERSON> <PERSON> Bettiker </PERSON>, coordinator of residential sales for <LOCATION> Ohio </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Edison </LOCATION>. `` We've never had a conservation program. Some of the utility programs are billed as conservation efforts, but increasingly the term `` efficiency'' is substituted to reflect the goal of stretching the use of each kilowatt-hour of power, rather than eliminating some uses. `` One of the tough nuts to crack is the customer's perception that conservation means deprivation,'' said <PERSON> Morron </PERSON>. `` Conservation does n't mean you have to put on a hair shirt and go live in a cave.'' Rather than being urged to turn down the thermostat in winter, consumers are being told they can save money and still stay warm by getting a more efficient heater. One of the most innovative utility programs is at <ORGANIZATION> Central </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Maine </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Power </ORGANIZATION>. It hired an energy services company, <ORGANIZATION> Sesco </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Inc. </ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION> Springfield </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Mass. </LOCATION>, to make efficiency improvements in about 11,000 residences. <PERSON> Sesco </PERSON> pays for the improvements _ such as attic insulation, window calking and lighting changes _ and the utility pays <PERSON> Sesco </PERSON> for measurable reductions in each home's electricity use. The deal is set so the utility is assured of paying less for the conservation than it would have paid to buy that amount of energy from an outside supplier, or to build a new power plant to generate the additional electricity. The utility customers pay nothing for the efficiency improvements and are expected to save $ 2 million in charges in the first year of the program. `` If all goes well, it's a win-win situation,'' said <PERSON> Frank </PERSON> <PERSON> Chiaravalloti </PERSON>, a <LOCATION> Central </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Maine </LOCATION> spokesman. Although a growing number of utilities are starting or expanding conservation and efficiency programs, some experts say regulatory changes will be needed before the industry taps fully into the deep reservoir of savings potential. The key problem from the utilities' viewpoint is that most state regulatory agencies do not allow the industry to earn a profit on their investment in conservation. They are allowed to recover the cost, but no more. The result is that utilities may view increased conservation as decreased profits.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0015 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u a AM-TankerSpill Bjt   05-21 0709</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Tanker Spill, Bjt,0727</SECOND>
<HEAD>Evidence Points to Booze, Inexperience, Complacency as Spill Causes</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By BRIAN S. AKRE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>ANCHORAGE, Alaska (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Booze, inexperience and complacency conspired to cause the nation's worst oil spill, evidence and testimony suggest after a five-day federal investigative hearing that found plenty of blame to spread around. The <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Transportation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Safety </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Board </ORGANIZATION> hearing on the <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Valdez </ORGANIZATION> oil spill concluded Saturday. Board member <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said the agency's report probably will be issued in early 1990. The hearing came nearly two months after the tanker ran aground on a charted reef and ripped its hull open, bleeding nearly 11 million gallons of crude oil into biologically rich Prince <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Sound </PERSON>. The oil has coated hundreds of miles of coast and killed birds and marine mammals. `` There are any number of things that may have occurred, some mistakes that were made, and all those together may have been what led to the grounding of the Exxon Valdez,'' <PERSON> Dickinson </PERSON> said. The 987-foot tanker was heading south from <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> the night of March 23 with a load of Alaskan crude when Capt. <PERSON> Joseph </PERSON> <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> directed it across a northbound shipping lane to avoid chunks of ice from a glacier. The captain received <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> permission for the diversion. But without approval the ship continued beyond the traffic lanes. <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> handed over control to <ORGANIZATION> Third </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Mate </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Gregory </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Cousins </ORGANIZATION> and left the bridge several minutes before the tanker ran aground at 12:04 a.m. March 24. In nearly 45 hours of testimony, not one of the 28 witnesses admitted doing anything wrong. But their testimony and more than 1,000 pages of evidence implicate the following players: _ <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>, who has been charged with operating the ship while drunk and declined to testify because of his pending criminal trial Testimony indicated he may have had a blood-alcohol level of 0.22 percent at the time of the wreck, five times the legal limit. Witnesses said they smelled alcohol on his breath before and after the wreck. The captain also left Cousins in charge, knowing he was not certified to pilot the ship through the sound. And <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON> had the tanker on automatic pilot although company policy restricts use of the device to open water. _ Cousins, who took the ship off automatic pilot 12 minutes before the crash but failed to turn the vessel away from <LOCATION> Bligh </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Reef </LOCATION> He testified that the ship did n't respond to his rudder changes, but an on-board recorder indicated his turns were simply too late. _ <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Shipping </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, which was aware of <PERSON> Hazelwood </PERSON>'s alcoholism but said it was unaware he had resumed drinking after undergoing hospital treatment in 1985 Although the company president said <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> has a strict anti-drinking policy, employees testified they rarely saw evidence that the policy was enforced. Testimony also revealed that <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> had reduced its tanker crews in favor of increased automation. _ <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Pipeline </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Service </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, operator of the Alaskan oil pipeline and the <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> terminal, which failed to respond as quickly to the disaster as it had estimated it would in its spill-contingency plan A barge used to carry equipment to the spill was empty when the ship ran aground, and it took 10 hours to load it. _ The <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>'s radar ship-monitoring system Traffic controllers in <LOCATION> Valdez </LOCATION> testified the ship was not visible on radar after it left <PERSON> Valdez </PERSON> <PERSON> Narrows </PERSON>. They blamed weather for decreasing the radar's range that night. Witnesses were questioned by <ORGANIZATION> NTSB </ORGANIZATION> staffers and representatives of the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION>, state, <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION>. Participants were aware their testimony may be admitted in court, where <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION> face potentially huge liability costs. Government and industry officials tried to use the hearing to their best legal and political advantage. <ORGANIZATION> Exxon </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Deppe </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Alyeska </ORGANIZATION>'s <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Howitt </PERSON> worked to elicit testimony that would show their companies did everything possible to avoid and then respond to the disaster. Through their questions they suggested that the spill was beyond containment, that government got in the way and that the spill might have been avoided if the <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> radar had been working properly. State officials alleged the industry was unprepared for a large spill, failed to follow its contingency plans and allowed conditions that led to the spill to go unchecked.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0016 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1157EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r p AM-NewJerseyGovernor     05-21 0693</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-New Jersey Governor,0714</SECOND>
<HEAD>Eleven Vie To Succeed New Jersey's Popular Governor</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JO ASTRID GLADING</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>TRENTON, N.J. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Eight Republicans and three Democrats are fighting in party primaries to emerge from the shadow of Gov. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> H. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>, widely credited with pumping pride into a state that was long a favored target of standup comics. But <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>, a Republican who is barred by law from seeking a third consecutive term, remains a central figure in the campaign, especially among <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> candidates who vying to inherit his mantle. A millionaire from an old and influential <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> family, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> won office in 1981 by the narrowest margin in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> history, defeating Democratic Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Florio </PERSON> by less than one-twelfth of 1 percent of the vote. By 1985, his popularity had soared and he won a second term by the widest margin in state history, getting 62 percent of the black vote and widespread support among labor and Democrats. While the national Republican party grew more conservative under <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> advanced a moderate doctrine and urged the <ORGANIZATION> GOP </ORGANIZATION> to bring women, blacks and other minorities into its fold. He rose to national prominence, delivering the keynote address at the Republican National Convention last year and winning praise from Presidents <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON> and <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> for his education initiatives. And he has been an unabashed <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> booster, appearing on television commercials that tout the Garden State as an exciting place to visit _ a novel thought for most Americans. His popularity in a state where Democrats far outnumber Republicans makes him a tough act to follow. `` It's just like <PERSON> George </PERSON> <PERSON> Bush </PERSON> trying to succeed <PERSON> Ronald </PERSON> <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>. You have enormously huge shoes to fill,'' said <PERSON> Roger </PERSON> <PERSON> Stone </PERSON>, a Washington-based consultant who is running Republican Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>'s campaign. <PERSON> Stone </PERSON> said <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> was the first <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> governor to use television to build a public image that reached beyond the state's borders Television is playing a crucial role in the primary, and candidates are spending millions to broadcast their messages in the nation's most expensive television markets. Although only about 400,000 members of each party are expected to cast primary ballots, candidates will pour more than $ 7 million into television advertising during the three weeks before the June 6 primary. When <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> took office, <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Jersey </LOCATION> staggered under economic stagnation, high unemployment rates and serious budget problems. For most of his term, <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> rode an economic boom. He doubled the size of the state budget during years when the treasury overflowed with $ 1 billion surpluses. But the good times came to an abrupt halt before the primary season. A predicted shortfall for next year grew to $ 500 million. Some budget analysts believe the gap could be as wide as $ 700 million. Soaring auto insurance rates have dominated the primary race, followed by debates over how to lower high local property tax rates and whether state taxes should be increased to solve the budget crisis. Growing traffic problems, congestion and the problems of managing rapid growth in the nation's most densely populated state also are big issues. Several of the candidates have likened themselves to <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>. <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, former Attorney General <PERSON> Cary </PERSON> <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> William </PERSON> <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON> are close <PERSON> Kean </PERSON> allies. <PERSON> Courter </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> use <PERSON> Kean </PERSON>'s name in slogans that appear below their ballot lines, calling themselves `` Tom Kean Republicans.'' <PERSON> Gormley </PERSON> and <PERSON> Edwards </PERSON> are the most moderate candidates in the race. <PERSON> Courter </PERSON>, Assembly Speaker <PERSON> Chuck </PERSON> <PERSON> Hadwick </PERSON> and Sen. <PERSON> Gerald </PERSON> <PERSON> Cardinale </PERSON> have carved images as conservative Republicans. Among the Democrats, <PERSON> Florio </PERSON>, author of the federal Superfund law, is widely considered the virtually unbeatable frontrunner. Now in his third bid for the statehouse, he has run a low profile campaign, drawing criticism from his opponents for remaining silent on many key issues. In spite of the stacked political odds, liberal Assemblyman <PERSON> Alan </PERSON> <PERSON> Karcher </PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION> Princeton </ORGANIZATION> Mayor <PERSON> Barbara </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON> <PERSON> Sigmund </PERSON>, daughter of Rep. <PERSON> Lindy </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-La </LOCATION>., and the late <PERSON> Hale </PERSON> <PERSON> Boggs </PERSON>, are running spirited Democratic campaigns Three other Republicans are running low-budget campaigns. They are former state tourism official <PERSON> Lois </PERSON> <PERSON> Rand </PERSON>, retired <ORGANIZATION> Coast </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Guard </ORGANIZATION> Capt. <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Blomquist </PERSON> and <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Kolyer </PERSON>, an industrial arts teacher from <LOCATION> Matawan </LOCATION>.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0017 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1223EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>u w AM-Coelho-Dairy Bjt   05-21 0700</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Coelho-Dairy, Bjt,670</SECOND>
<HEAD>House Democrat Had Dairy Industry Investment While Pushing Dairy
Legislation</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JOAN MOWER</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 Rep. <PERSON> Tony </PERSON> <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> owned an interest in a dairy management company at the same time he was pushing legislation to help maintain the profitability of some dairy farms, a review of records shows. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> majority whip and third-ranking Democrat in the chamber, became a limited partner in <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> in December 1983, according to his financial disclosure forms. When he bought into the partnership with an investment valued at between $ 5,000 and $ 15,000, the <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> congressman was a member of the <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> livestock, dairy and poultry subcommittee. He became chairman in 1985, a position he held for two years during the time the controversial 1985 farm bill was passed. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s financial dealings have been the subject of public interest since recent disclosures that a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> savings and loan official purchased a $ 100,000 bond for <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> when the congressman was unable to come up with the money. Dairy Management Associates developed a computer software program for managing dairy herds, allowing farmers to determine things such as how much milk a cow produces and how much it eats, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s aides said. The program also is used by veterinarians. <PERSON> Fred </PERSON> <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, a <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> aide, said the congressman was `` comfortable enough in his mind to realize there was no potential for anything that he dairy or agriculture committee was going to pass that was going to impact directly on that investment.'' No law or rule prevents members of <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from holding assets that might conflict with their official duties. They are free to craft and vote on legislation that could affect their financial interests. White House officials and other executive branch employees, on the other hand, are barred under the basic federal conflict of interest law from taking government action in which they or their immediate family has a financial interest unless they obtain a waiver. The top penalty is two years in prison and a $ 10,000 fine. In 1985, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> and then-Rep. <PERSON> James </PERSON> <PERSON> Jeffords </PERSON>, R-Vt., introduced a bill that, among other things, would pay farmers not to produce milk at a time the industry was beset with The legislation, which drew the ire of consumer and milk-user groups, was described by <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> as a way to ease some producers out of dairying while retaining profitability for the rest. Ultimately, <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> passed legislation that called for modest cuts in the price support program, but authorized federally subsidized buy-outs of entire dairy herds. <PERSON> Ellen </PERSON> <PERSON> Haas </PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION> Public </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Voice </ORGANIZATION>, a self-styled consumer lobby who fought <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> on dairy price support measures in 1985, said it stood to reason that if dairy farmers stay healthy they might be able to afford to buy computer software programs to manage herds. She said she had no idea of <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s investment at the time. One argument for exempting <ORGANIZATION> Congress </ORGANIZATION> from conflict-of-interest statutes is that lawmakers must publicly disclose their holdings so voters can decide whether an official is acting for personal enrichment. <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> listed his holding as <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> in 1983. In four following years, the entry was less descriptive. He simply stated on his financial disclosure forms that he had an interest in `` DMA -LRB- a <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> limited partnership -RRB-.'' <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> put his assets, including his <ORGANIZATION> DMA </ORGANIZATION> interest, in a blind trust last June. <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON> said <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON> does not fill out his forms personally and speculated that an aide called the company by its acronym, a pattern repeated annually. Partnership records on file in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION> _ the most recent was Jan. 18, 1985 _ show <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s general partner in <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> was <PERSON> Samuel </PERSON> <PERSON> A. </PERSON> <PERSON> Nash </PERSON>, who formerly worked for <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s accountant The company address was the same as the accountant's office in <LOCATION> Merced </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Calif. </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Hatfield </PERSON>, <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s aide, said the congressman knew <PERSON> Nash </PERSON>, but not He said <ORGANIZATION> Dairy </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Management </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Associates </ORGANIZATION> has not had an office for several years. Another limited partner in Dairy Management is <PERSON> John </PERSON> <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, the former aide to <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> Speaker <PERSON> Jim </PERSON> <PERSON> Wright </PERSON>, <LOCATION> D-Texas </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Mack </PERSON>, a close friend of <PERSON> Coelho </PERSON>'s, resigned last week after an outpouring of criticism over a newspaper story detailing his attack on a woman in 1973.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0018 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1226EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r w AM-AIDSDrugs     05-21 0931</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-AIDS Drugs,890</SECOND>
<HEAD>Grassroots Concept Gaining Momentum in AIDS Drug Testing</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By DEBORAH MESCE</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>Associated Press Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>WASHINGTON (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 A novel, grassroots concept in drug testing pioneered by AIDS victims and their doctors is gaining momentum and soon may see its first victory with widely expected government approval of a treatment for a lethal AIDS-related pneumonia. Far from the ivory towers of academic medical centers, the testing is being conducted in a few inner cities hard hit by the disease where local AIDS doctors and their patients search together to find treatments that work and disgard those that do n't. These community programs _ the two major ones are in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> _ were begun by AIDS patients and physicians frustrated by the slow pace of academic and government research to turn out a cure for acquired immune deficiency syndrome and its deadly complications. `` People with AIDS just decided to do it themselves,'' said <PERSON> Thomas </PERSON> <PERSON> Hannon </PERSON>, associate director of the <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Initiative </ORGANIZATION>, which operates out of an old loft building in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> where participating doctors administer experimental therapies to AIDS patients. Research data gathered by the <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> group and the <ORGANIZATION> County </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Community </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Consortium </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION> on an aerosol version of the drug pentamidine pursuaded a <ORGANIZATION> Food </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> and </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Drug </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Administration </ORGANIZATION> advisory committee earlier this month to recommend approval of the treatment to prevent pneumocystis carinii pneumonia. The lung ailment kills 60 percent of all AIDS victims. The <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> is widely expected to approve aerosol-administered pentamidine shortly. Pentamidine was approved by the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> as an injectable drug five years ago to treat those already suffering from pneumocystis. Many doctors, though, administered it as a spray. In February, the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> expanded pentamidine's use in aerosol form as an experimental medication under government review. As a spray, the drug is delivered directly into the lungs where the pneumonia infection first shows up. In this form, pentamidine has been shown to help prevent pneumocystis infection. Advocates of the grassroots programs say the <ORGANIZATION> FDA </ORGANIZATION> advisory committee's action represents a major breakthrough for the concept of community-based research and recognition that primary-care doctors can produce solid, clinical data in the routine delivery of medical services to their patients. The result, they hope, will be to help get effective therapies to AIDS victims faster. Community programs reach more people, they say, and so will be able to bring more AIDS patients into clinical trials, and with more participation, there will be more information with which to assess the effectiveness of drugs. The concept has won the backing of many scientists, drug companies and the federal government, which is preparing to award $ 6 million in grants to develop community-based research programs throughout the country. In addition to the federal money, the <ORGANIZATION> American </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Foundation </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> AIDS </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Research </ORGANIZATION> in April gave $ 1.4 million to 16 community organizations starting reseach programs. Dr. <PERSON> Burton </PERSON> <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> _ a cancer researcher, member of former President <PERSON> Reagan </PERSON>'s AIDS commission and now President <PERSON> Bush </PERSON>'s personal physician _ avidly supports community-based research as an extension of the work going on in university and government centers. These programs, he said, are free of the `` inherent biases'' of academic studies to exclude the sickest patients. A more representative sampling, which community programs provide, produces better results and without any slippage in quality, since many academic researchers sit on the advisory boards of the community programs, he said. He credits AIDS activists for pointing out the weaknesses in traditional research. `` The communities have stepped up to bat and they have tried to speed up the system. They came up with a constructive idea and I think it's a good one,'' <PERSON> Lee </PERSON> said. He added: `` I hope they -LRB- community-research programs -RRB- spread out into other diseases. I think it's an excellent model for testing cancer drugs, diabetes drugs, heart disease drugs and others.'' <PERSON> Martin </PERSON> <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON>, co-founder of Project Inform, a San Francisco-based AIDS education group, was an early proponent of community-based research and still supports it, but he says the movement has been `` romanticized.'' Few clinical trials are being done by community groups other than those in <LOCATION> New </LOCATION> <LOCATION> York </LOCATION> and <LOCATION> San </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Francisco </LOCATION>, and most of the efforts are spearheaded by doctors _ not AIDS patients _ and so are not really the symbols of patient empowerment that advocates describe them to be, he said. `` It's an important part of a broader puzzle,'' <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> said. `` I do n't think it's ever going to replace university-based research, and there's a limit to how big it can get because of the time it takes for doctors to participate.'' One mistake AIDS activists have made is in equating research with treatment, he said. `` The more pressure we put on the research process as being a way for treatment, the more we confound the research process, and the politicians find it a nice easy way out, instead of providing the money for health care,'' <PERSON> Delaney </PERSON> said. Yet, the movement is generating `` overwhelming'' interest, said <PERSON> Lawrence </PERSON> <PERSON> Deyton </PERSON>, assistant director for community research at the <ORGANIZATION> National </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Institute </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> for </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Allergy </ORGANIZATION> and Infectious Diseases. When the government announced its $ 6 million program, it got more than 700 requests for information about it. <PERSON> Deyton </PERSON> declined to say how many applied by the April deadline, but a <ORGANIZATION> Capitol </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Hill </ORGANIZATION> source who spoke on the condition of anonymity said it was more than 60. <PERSON> Deyton </PERSON> estimated that as many as a dozen community-based groups are now involved in clinical trials for AIDS therapies. With more trials, he said, there would likely be more participation by Hispanics, blacks, intravenous drug users and women, who are now underrepresented in clinical testing.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0019 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1230EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r i AM-Japan     05-21 0364</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Japan,0377</SECOND>
<HEAD>Ishida Elected Head of No. 2 Opposition Party</HEAD>
<DATELINE>TOKYO (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <LOCATION> Japan </LOCATION>'s second-largest opposition party elected a new chairman Sunday to succeed the party leader who resigned in an influence-peddling scandal. <PERSON> Koshiro </PERSON> <PERSON> Ishida </PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION> Komeito </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION>'s new leader, told members, `` I will fight to make the <ORGANIZATION> Komeito </ORGANIZATION> once more a party that is clean and trustworthy.'' <PERSON> Ishida </PERSON>, 58, previously one of four party vice chairmen, was elected to succeed <PERSON> Junya </PERSON> <PERSON> Yano </PERSON>, who resigned last week when prosecutors began formal questioning of a Komeito member of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. <PERSON> Katsuya </PERSON> <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON> of Komeito and <PERSON> Takeo </PERSON> <PERSON> Fujinami </PERSON> of the governing <ORGANIZATION> Liberal </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Democratic </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Party </ORGANIZATION> were interrogated by police last week. They are suspected of taking bribes from <ORGANIZATION> Recruit </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Co. </ORGANIZATION>, an information and publishing conglomerate. The so-called Recruit scandal has resulted in 14 bureaucrats and businessmen being arrested on bribery and securities law violation charges. Prime Minister <PERSON> Noboru </PERSON> <PERSON> Takeshita </PERSON>, who has acknowledged receiving political contributions from Recruit, announced last month he was resigning to take responsibility for the scandal. But his party has yet to find a successor who commands widespread respect and is untainted by the scandal. <PERSON> Yano </PERSON> himself was under fire in <LOCATION> Komeito </LOCATION>, the second-largest opposition party after the Socialists, for links to an earlier insider-trading scandal. More than 600 party members, including 56 members of the 512-seat <ORGANIZATION> House </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Representatives </ORGANIZATION> and 23 members of the 252-seat House of Councilors, attended the special party convention in downtown <LOCATION> Tokyo </LOCATION>. <PERSON> Ishida </PERSON> urged fellow party members to reflect on a `` lack of seriousness'' among members of <ORGANIZATION> Parliament </ORGANIZATION>. The new party leaders, he said, must examine the scandal and reform the party. `` I believe this is the way to win public confidence,'' he said. Though as an opposition legislator <PERSON> Ikeda </PERSON> had no official power, he repeatedly lodged questions in Parliament that prosecutors saw as helpful to Recruit, and he gained financial benefits from Recruit share transactions. Recruit sold bargain-priced, unlisted shares in a subsidiary to about 160 influential politicians, aides, bureaucrats and businessmen, allegedly in an attempt to gain influence in the government. When public trading in the shares began, their prices soared and buyers made large profits. <PERSON> Ishida </PERSON> was first elected to the House of Representatives in 1967.
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0020 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1233EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Diver'sParents     05-21 0642</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Diver's Parents,0661</SECOND>
<HEAD>Parents of Slain Navy Diver Return Home</HEAD>
<DATELINE>PORT TOBACCO, Md. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
 <PERSON> Richard </PERSON> and <PERSON> Patricia </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> have finally come home after nearly a year in <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, now that a man has been convicted and sentenced to life in prison for the 1985 terrorist murder of their son. <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON>, 23, a <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> diver, was shot and his body dumped onto the pavement at <LOCATION> Beirut </LOCATION> <LOCATION> International </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Airport </LOCATION> during the 17-day hijacking of <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> Flight 847. The Stethems, both 53, attended 65 court sessions in <LOCATION> Frankfurt </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> West </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION>, beginning last July, for the trial of <PERSON> Muhammad </PERSON> <PERSON> Ali </PERSON> <PERSON> Hammadi </PERSON>. `` Nearly a year out of my grandchildren's lives,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said. The Stethems returned to their <LOCATION> Charles </LOCATION> <LOCATION> County </LOCATION> home Thursday night after <PERSON> Hammadi </PERSON>'s sentencing. `` We're very confident and really feel he'll stay behind bars,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said of <PERSON> Hammadi </PERSON>. `` So we feel our trip was worth it.'' `` They say time heals all wounds,'' <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said. `` The pain has n't healed yet. And I do n't see it happening at this point. But this verdict has helped a lot.'' The first order of business was working in their yard and tending the rose garden Mrs. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> maintains to harvest flowers for her son's grave at Arlington National Cemetery. A neighbor mowed the lawn while the Stethems were away, but a three-week lapse and abundant rain have given it time to grow knee-high. `` We must get on with our lives now,'' said <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON>, a civilian <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> employee. `` We do n't feel in any danger. We've been victims already ... We'll never have <PERSON> Rob </PERSON> back.'' In the garage is their son's car, with a vanity license plate <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> obtained after his son was killed. `` ROBBIES,'' it says. `` We do n't drive it much,'' <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said. The elder <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> joined the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> in 1953 when he was 17. He retired in 1979 but later returned as a civilian employee. Mrs. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> also was in the <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION>, in <LOCATION> California </LOCATION>, when they met. She now is a secretary at the <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Court </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> of </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Military </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Appeals </ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION> Washington </LOCATION>. There are three other children: <PERSON> Cheryl </PERSON>, 31, a mother of two, and two <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sons, <PERSON> Kenneth </PERSON>, 29, and <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON>, 23. `` I had actually tried to talk all of them into joining the <ORGANIZATION> Air </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Force </ORGANIZATION>,'' their father said. When the <ORGANIZATION> TWA </ORGANIZATION> airplane was hijacked in June 1985, <PERSON> Robert </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> was part of a crew of <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> divers returning from a routine maintenance job at a <ORGANIZATION> U.S. </ORGANIZATION> <ORGANIZATION> Navy </ORGANIZATION> sewage treatment plant in <LOCATION> Greece </LOCATION>. They were on their way back to <LOCATION> Little </LOCATION> <LOCATION> Creek </LOCATION>, <LOCATION> Va. </LOCATION>, where <PERSON> Patrick </PERSON> <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> now holds the same job his brother did. Why <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> was chosen for execution by the Shiite Moslem terrorists remains unknown. Another diver, severely beaten at the same time, lived to testify at <PERSON> Hammadi </PERSON>'s trial. Two terrorists involved in the hijacking remain at large. Although the time they spent at the trial in <LOCATION> Germany </LOCATION> did not provide answers to all their questions, the Stethems derived a certain solace. `` I had to be there,'' Ms. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said. `` I had to know what was happening. I would've climbed the walls wondering what was happening if I stayed at home.'' During breaks in the trial, she did volunteer work, typing at the dental clinic of the <LOCATION> U.S. </LOCATION> military base where they stayed. `` A lot of nights, I did n't sleep and walked around and called my daughter'' in <LOCATION> Maryland </LOCATION>, she said. Her husband said he read a lot of books about terrorism. A security detail whisked them into the courtroom, which was inside a prison, and they sat with the prosecutor behind bulletproof glass. An interpreter translated. Now that they're home, the <PERSON> Stethems </PERSON> plan to visit their son's grave, taking newly cut roses from the garden and news of what happened to <PERSON> Hammadi </PERSON> `` This is going to be great, going this time,'' Mrs. <PERSON> Stethem </PERSON> said, `` because I can tell him we just got one.''
</TEXT>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO> AP890521-0021 </DOCNO>
<FILEID>AP-NR-05-21-89 1239EST</FILEID>
<FIRST>r a AM-Chrysler-Kenosha     05-21 0641</FIRST>
<SECOND>AM-Chrysler-Kenosha,0660</SECOND>
<HEAD>Former Autoworkers Rebuild Their Lives</HEAD>
<BYLINE>By JONATHAN YENKIN</BYLINE>
<BYLINE>AP Business Writer</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>KENOSHA, Wis. (AP) </DATELINE>
<TEXT>
